<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37548112</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1522-2586</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>59</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of magnetic resonance imaging : JMRI</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Magn Reson Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Review of Hyperpolarized Pulmonary Functional <sup>129</sup> Xe MR for Long-COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1120</StartPage><EndPage>1134</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1120-1134</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmri.28940</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The respiratory consequences of acute COVID-19 infection and related symptoms tend to resolve 4&#x2009;weeks post-infection. However, for some patients, new, recurrent, or persisting symptoms remain beyond the acute phase and persist for months, post-infection. The symptoms that remain have been referred to as long-COVID. A number of research sites employed <sup>129</sup> Xe magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) during the pandemic and evaluated patients post-infection, months after hospitalization or home-based care as a way to better understand the consequences of infection on <sup>129</sup> Xe MR gas-exchange and ventilation imaging. A systematic review and comprehensive search were employed using MEDLINE via PubMed (April 2023) using the National Library of Medicine's Medical Subject Headings and key words: post-COVID-19, MRI, <sup>129</sup> Xe, long-COVID, COVID pneumonia, and post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Fifteen peer-reviewed manuscripts were identified including four editorials, a single letter to the editor, one review article, and nine original research manuscripts (2020-2023). MRI and MR spectroscopy results are summarized from these prospective, controlled studies, which involved small sample sizes ranging from 9 to 76 participants. Key findings included: 1) <sup>129</sup> Xe MRI gas-exchange and ventilation abnormalities, 3&#x2009;months post-COVID-19 infection, and 2) a combination of MRI gas-exchange and ventilation abnormalities alongside persistent symptoms in patients hospitalized and not hospitalized for COVID-19, 1-year post-infection. The persistence of respiratory symptoms and <sup>129</sup> Xe MRI abnormalities in the context of normal or nearly normal pulmonary function test results and chest computed tomography (CT) was consistent. Longitudinal improvements were observed in long-term follow-up of long-COVID patients but mean <sup>129</sup> Xe gas-exchange, ventilation heterogeneity values and symptoms remained abnormal, 1-year post-infection. Pulmonary functional MRI using inhaled hyperpolarized <sup>129</sup> Xe gas has played a role in detecting gas-exchange and ventilation abnormalities providing complementary information that may help develop our understanding of the root causes of long-COVID. LEVEL OF EVIDENCE: 1 TECHNICAL EFFICACY: Stage 5.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Journal of Magnetic Resonance Imaging published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wild</LastName><ForeName>Jim M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7246-8660</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>POLARIS, Department of Infection, Immunity and Cardiovascular Disease, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gleeson</LastName><ForeName>Fergus V</ForeName><Initials>FV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5121-3917</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Oxford University Hospitals, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Svenningsen</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6225-1863</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Firestone Institute for Respiratory Health, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grist</LastName><ForeName>James T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7223-4031</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Oxford University Hospitals, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saunders</LastName><ForeName>Laura C</ForeName><Initials>LC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1080-9861</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>POLARIS, Department of Infection, Immunity and Cardiovascular Disease, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Collier</LastName><ForeName>Guilhem J</ForeName><Initials>GJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1874-4775</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>POLARIS, Department of Infection, Immunity and Cardiovascular Disease, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Maksym</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8380-9440</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robarts Research Institute, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biophysics, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tcherner</LastName><ForeName>Sam</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8728-0428</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robarts Research Institute, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biophysics, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mozaffaripour</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-0497-9830</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robarts Research Institute, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biophysics, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matheson</LastName><ForeName>Alexander M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6022-9507</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robarts Research Institute, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biophysics, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parraga</LastName><ForeName>Grace</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5619-4145</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robarts Research Institute, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biophysics, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respirology, Department of Medicine, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MR/M008894/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Magn Reson Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9105850</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1053-1807</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014979">Xenon Isotopes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000614971">Xenon-129</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="Y">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014979" MajorTopicYN="Y">Xenon Isotopes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011659" MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary Gas Exchange</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">129Xe MRI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dissolved phase MRI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gas-exchange MRI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyperpolarized</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ventilation defects</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37548112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.28940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Estimated COVID-19 burden. Vol 2022. Atlanta, GA: United States Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong E, Du H, Gardner L. An interactive web-based dashboard to track COVID-19 in real time. Lancet Infect Dis 2020;20(5):533-534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Liu X, Zhou Y, et al. 3-month, 6-month, 9-month, and 12-month respiratory outcomes in patients following COVID-19-related hospitalisation: A prospective study. Lancet Respir Med 2021;9(7):747-754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon JJ, Heyman B, Ko JP, Condos R, Lynch DA. CT of post-acute lung complications of COVID-19. Radiology 2021;301(2):E383-E395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Chen L, Fan Y, et al. Longitudinal assessment of chest CT findings and pulmonary function after COVID-19 infection. Radiology 2023;307(2):e222888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Fan Y, Alwalid O, et al. Fibrotic interstitial lung abnormalities at 1-year follow-up CT after severe COVID-19. Radiology 2021;301(3):E438-E440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe A, So M, Iwagami M, et al. One-year follow-up CT findings in COVID-19 patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Respirology 2022;27(8):605-616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings G, Monaghan A, Xue F, Mockler D, Romero-Ortu&#xf1;o R. A systematic review of persistent symptoms and residual abnormal functioning following acute COVID-19: Ongoing symptomatic phase vs. post-COVID-19 syndrome. J Clin Med 2021;10(24):5913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): An overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front Microbiol 2021;12:698169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med 2021;27(4):601-615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Health and Care Excellence. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing COVID-19. London: NICE; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-COVID conditions. COVID-19. Vol 2022. Atlanta, GA: Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV, Condition WHOCCDWGoP-C. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis 2021;22:e102-e107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. NICE guidance. 1.8 ed. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: Major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol 2023;21:1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Burden of Disease Long CC, Wulf Hanson S, Abbafati C, et al. Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA 2022;328(16):1604-1615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or Long COVID: A meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis 2022;226(9):1593-1607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Pawelek P. In: Statistics OfN, editor. Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK: 1 June 2022; 2022. The United Kingdom: Office for National Statistics.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: Putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond) 2021;53(10):737-754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellan M, Baricich A, Patrucco F, et al. Long-term sequelae are highly prevalent one year after hospitalization for severe COVID-19. Sci Rep 2021;11(1):22666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra V, Flanders SA, O'Malley M, Malani AN, Prescott HC. Sixty-day outcomes among patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Ann Intern Med 2021;174(4):576-578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-de-las-Penas C, Palacios-Cena D, Gomez-Mayordomo V, et al. Long-term post-COVID symptoms and associated risk factors in previously hospitalized patients: A multicenter study. J Infect 2021;83(2):271-274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell ML, Catalfamo CJ, Farland LV, et al. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 in a non-hospitalized cohort: Results from the Arizona CoVHORT. PLoS One 2021;16(8):e0254347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bliddal S, Banasik K, Pedersen OB, et al. Acute and persistent symptoms in non-hospitalized PCR-confirmed COVID-19 patients. Sci Rep 2021;11(1):13153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulay A, Konda B, Garcia G Jr, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection of primary human lung epithelium for COVID-19 modeling and drug discovery. Cell Rep 2021;35(5):109055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scialo F, Daniele A, Amato F, et al. ACE2: The major cell entry receptor for SARS-CoV-2. Lung 2020;198(6):867-877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gursoy B, Surmeli CD, Alkan M, et al. Cytokine storm in severe COVID-19 pneumonia. J Med Virol 2021;93(9):5474-5480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B, Huang S, Yin L. The cytokine storm and COVID-19. J Med Virol 2021;93(1):250-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanne JP, Little BP, Schulte JJ, Haramati A, Haramati LB. Long-term lung abnormalities associated with COVID-19 pneumonia. Radiology 2022;221806:e221806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhawan RT, Gopalan D, Howard L, et al. Beyond the clot: Perfusion imaging of the pulmonary vasculature after COVID-19. Lancet Respir Med 2021;9(1):107-116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojo AS, Balogun SA, Williams OT, Ojo OS. Pulmonary fibrosis in COVID-19 survivors: Predictive factors and risk reduction strategies. Pulm Med 2020;2020:6175964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishna Murthy P, Sivashanmugam K, Kandasamy M, Subbiah R, Ravikumar V. Repurposing of histone deacetylase inhibitors: A promising strategy to combat pulmonary fibrosis promoted by TGF-beta signalling in COVID-19 survivors. Life Sci 2021;266:118883.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabbri L, Moss S, Khan FA, et al. Parenchymal lung abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19 and viral pneumonitis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Thorax 2023;78(2):191-201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luger AK, Sonnweber T, Gruber L, et al. Chest CT of lung injury 1 year after COVID-19 pneumonia: The CovILD study. Radiology 2022;304(2):462-470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart I, Jacob J, George PM, et al. Residual lung abnormalities after COVID-19 hospitalization: Interim analysis of the UKILD post-COVID-19 study. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2023;207(6):693-703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones PW. St. George's respiratory questionnaire: MCID. COPD 2005;2(1):75-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroder L. Xenon for NMR biosensing - Inert but alert. Phys Med 2013;29(1):3-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolber J, Cherubini A, Dzik-Jurasz AS, Leach MO, Bifone A. Spin-lattice relaxation of laser-polarized xenon in human blood. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 1999;96(7):3664-3669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall H, Stewart NJ, Chan HF, Rao M, Norquay G, Wild JM. In vivo methods and applications of xenon-129 magnetic resonance. Prog Nucl Magn Reson Spectrosc 2021;122:42-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert MS, Cates GD, Driehuys B, et al. Biological magnetic resonance imaging using laser-polarized 129Xe. Nature 1994;370(6486):199-201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svenningsen S, Kirby M, Starr D, et al. What are ventilation defects in asthma? Thorax 2014;69(1):63-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eddy RL, Svenningsen S, Kirby M, et al. Is computed tomography airway count related to asthma severity and airway structure and function? Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2020;201(8):923-933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svenningsen S, Haider E, Boylan C, et al. CT and functional MRI to evaluate airway mucus in severe asthma. Chest 2019;155(6):1178-1189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaushik SS, Freeman MS, Yoon SW, et al. Measuring diffusion limitation with a perfusion-limited gas-hyperpolarized 129Xe gas-transfer spectroscopy in patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2014;117(6):577-585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaushik SS, Robertson SH, Freeman MS, et al. Single-breath clinical imaging of hyperpolarized (129)Xe in the airspaces, barrier, and red blood cells using an interleaved 3D radial 1-point Dixon acquisition. Magn Reson Med 2016;75(4):1434-1443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bier EA, Robertson SH, Schrank GM, et al. A protocol for quantifying cardiogenic oscillations in dynamic (129) Xe gas exchange spectroscopy: The effects of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. NMR Biomed 2019;32(1):e4029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willmering MM, Walkup LL, Niedbalski PJ, et al. Pediatric (129) Xe gas-transfer MRI-feasibility and applicability. J Magn Reson Imaging 2022;56(4):1207-1219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weatherley ND, Stewart NJ, Chan HF, et al. Hyperpolarised xenon magnetic resonance spectroscopy for the longitudinal assessment of changes in gas diffusion in IPF. Thorax 2019;74(5):500-502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lange EE, Altes TA, Patrie JT, et al. Changes in regional airflow obstruction over time in the lungs of patients with asthma: Evaluation with 3He MR imaging. Radiology 2009;250(2):567-575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lange EE, Altes TA, Patrie JT, et al. The variability of regional airflow obstruction within the lungs of patients with asthma: Assessment with hyperpolarized helium-3 magnetic resonance imaging. J Allergy Clin Immunol 2007;119(5):1072-1078.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fain SB, Gonzalez-Fernandez G, Peterson ET, et al. Evaluation of structure-function relationships in asthma using multidetector CT and hyperpolarized He-3 MRI. Acad Radiol 2008;15(6):753-762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly LF, MacFall JR, McAdams HP, et al. Cystic fibrosis: Combined hyperpolarized 3He-enhanced and conventional proton MR imaging in the lung-preliminary observations. Radiology 1999;212(3):885-889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodhouse N, Wild JM, Paley MN, et al. Combined helium-3/proton magnetic resonance imaging measurement of ventilated lung volumes in smokers compared to never-smokers. J Magn Reson Imaging 2005;21(4):365-369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby M, Heydarian M, Svenningsen S, et al. Hyperpolarized 3He magnetic resonance functional imaging semiautomated segmentation. Acad Radiol 2012;19(2):141-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleveland ZI, Cofer GP, Metz G, et al. Hyperpolarized Xe MR imaging of alveolar gas uptake in humans. PLoS One 2010;5(8):e12192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hersman FW, Ruset IC, Ketel S, et al. Large production system for hyperpolarized 129Xe for human lung imaging studies. Acad Radiol 2008;15(6):683-692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman MS, Emami K, Driehuys B. Characterizing and modeling the efficiency limits in large-scale production of hyperpolarized 129Xe. Phys Rev A 2014;90(2):023406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norquay G, Collier GJ, Rodgers OI, Gill AB, Screaton NJ, Wild J. Standalone portable xenon-129 hyperpolariser for multicentre clinical magnetic resonance imaging of the lungs. Br J Radiol 2022;95(1132):20210872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driehuys B, Cofer GP, Pollaro J, Mackel JB, Hedlund LW, Johnson GA. Imaging alveolar-capillary gas transfer using hyperpolarized 129Xe MRI. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2006;103(48):18278-18283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruppert K, Brookeman JR, Hagspiel KD, Driehuys B, Mugler JP 3rd. NMR of hyperpolarized (129)Xe in the canine chest: Spectral dynamics during a breath-hold. NMR Biomed 2000;13(4):220-228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collier GJ, Eaden JA, Hughes PJC, et al. Dissolved (129) Xe lung MRI with four-echo 3D radial spectroscopic imaging: Quantification of regional gas transfer in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Magn Reson Med 2021;85(5):2622-2633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qing K, Ruppert K, Jiang Y, et al. Regional mapping of gas uptake by blood and tissue in the human lung using hyperpolarized xenon-129 MRI. J Magn Reson Imaging 2014;39(2):346-359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kammerman J, Hahn AD, Cadman RV, Malkus A, Mummy D, Fain SB. Transverse relaxation rates of pulmonary dissolved-phase hyperpolarized (129) Xe as a biomarker of lung injury in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Magn Reson Med 2020;84(4):1857-1867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon WT. Simple proton spectroscopic imaging. Radiology 1984;153(1):189-194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doganay O, Wade T, Hegarty E, McKenzie C, Schulte RF, Santyr GE. Hyperpolarized (129) Xe imaging of the rat lung using spiral IDEAL. Magn Reson Med 2016;76(2):566-576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muradian I, Patz S, Butler JP, et al. Hyperpolarized 129Xe human pulmonary gas exchange with 3-point Dixon technique. Proc Int Soc Magn Reson Med 2006;14:1297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niedbalski PJ, Hall CS, Castro M, et al. Protocols for multi-site trials using hyperpolarized (129) Xe MRI for imaging of ventilation, alveolar-airspace size, and gas exchange: A position paper from the (129) Xe MRI clinical trials consortium. Magn Reson Med 2021;86(6):2966-2986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JM, Robertson SH, Wang Z, et al. Using hyperpolarized (129)Xe MRI to quantify regional gas transfer in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Thorax 2018;73(1):21-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mummy DG, Bier EA, Wang Z, et al. Hyperpolarized (129)Xe MRI and spectroscopy of gas-exchange abnormalities in nonspecific interstitial pneumonia. Radiology 2021;301(1):211-220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Zhao X, Wang Y, et al. Damaged lung gas exchange function of discharged COVID-19 patients detected by hyperpolarized (129)Xe MRI. Sci Adv 2021;7(1):eabc8180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matheson AM, McIntosh MJ, Kooner HK, et al. Persistent (129)Xe MRI pulmonary and CT vascular abnormalities in symptomatic individuals with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Radiology 2022;220492:466-476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooner HK, McIntosh MJ, Matheson AM, et al. (129)Xe MRI ventilation defects in ever-hospitalised and never-hospitalised people with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. BMJ Open Respir Res 2022;9(1):e001235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grist JT, Chen M, Collier GJ, et al. Hyperpolarized (129)Xe MRI abnormalities in dyspneic patients 3 months after COVID-19 pneumonia: Preliminary results. Radiology 2021;301(1):E353-E360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grist JT, Collier GJ, Walters H, et al. Lung abnormalities detected with hyperpolarized (129)Xe MRI in patients with long COVID. Radiology 2022;305(3):709-717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matheson AM, McIntosh MJ, Kooner HK, et al. Longitudinal follow-up of postacute COVID-19 syndrome: DL(CO), quality-of-life and MRI pulmonary gas-exchange abnormalities. Thorax 2023;78:418-421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooner HK. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome: 129Xe MRI ventilation defects and respiratory outcomes one year later. Radiology 2023;307:e222557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooner HK, McIntosh MJ, Matheson AM, Svenningsen S, Parraga G. More data about (129)Xe MRI ventilation defects in Long COVID-19. Radiology 2023;307(4):e230479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders LC, Collier GJ, Chan HF, et al. Longitudinal lung function assessment of patients hospitalized with COVID-19 using (1)H and (129)Xe lung MRI. Chest 2023.1-17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hon KLE, Leung CW, Cheng WTF, et al. Clinical presentations and outcome of severe acute respiratory syndrome in children. Lancet 2003;361(9370):1701-1703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart NJ, Leung G, Norquay G, et al. Experimental validation of the hyperpolarized (129) Xe chemical shift saturation recovery technique in healthy volunteers and subjects with interstitial lung disease. Magn Reson Med 2015;74(1):196-207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dowds J, O'Brien K, et al. Persistent poor health after COVID-19 is not associated with respiratory complications or initial disease severity. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2021;18(6):997-1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFann K, Baxter BA, LaVergne SM, et al. Quality of life (QoL) is reduced in those with severe COVID-19 disease, post-acute sequelae of COVID-19, and hospitalization in United States adults from northern Colorado. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021;18(21):1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrer M, Villasante C, Alonso J, et al. Interpretation of quality of life scores from the St George's respiratory questionnaire. Eur Respir J 2002;19(3):405-413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currow DC, Plummer JL, Crockett A, Abernethy AP. A community population survey of prevalence and severity of dyspnea in adults. J Pain Symptom Manage 2009;38(4):533-545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Rankine L, Bier EA, et al. Using hyperpolarized (129)Xe gas-exchange MRI to model the regional airspace, membrane, and capillary contributions to diffusing capacity. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2021;130(5):1398-1409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villalba JA, Hilburn CF, Garlin MA, et al. Vasculopathy and increased vascular congestion in fatal COVID-19 and ARDS. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2022;206:857-873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooner HK, McIntosh MJ, Desaigoudar V, et al. Pulmonary functional MRI: Detecting the structure-function pathologies that drive asthma symptoms and quality of life. Respirology 2022;27(2):114-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogel-Claussen J. Ventilation defects at (129)Xe MRI in postacute COVID-19 syndrome: Back to normal after 1 year? Radiology 2023;307(2):e230113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeloye D, Elneima O, Daines L, et al. The long-term sequelae of COVID-19: An international consensus on research priorities for patients with pre-existing and new-onset airways disease. Lancet Respir Med 2021;9(12):1467-1478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou IY, Mascia M, Alba GA, et al. Dynamic contrast-enhanced MRI demonstrates pulmonary microvascular abnormalities months after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2023;207(12):1636-1639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pizzuto DA, Buonsenso D, Morello R, et al. Lung perfusion assessment in children with long-COVID: A pilot study. Pediatr Pulmonol 2023;58(7):2059-2067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurek M, Rayner C, Freyer A, et al. Recommendations for the recognition, diagnosis, and management of long COVID: A Delphi study. Br J Gen Pract 2021;71(712):e815-e825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lins M, Vandevenne J, Thillai M, et al. Assessment of small pulmonary blood vessels in COVID-19 patients using HRCT. Acad Radiol 2020;27(10):1449-1455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh CL, Tafforeau P, Wagner WL, et al. Imaging intact human organs with local resolution of cellular structures using hierarchical phase-contrast tomography. Nat Methods 2021;18:1532-1541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackermann M, Verleden SE, Kuehnel M, et al. Pulmonary vascular endothelialitis, thrombosis, and angiogenesis in Covid-19. N Engl J Med 2020;383(2):120-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brito-Azevedo A, Pinto EC, de Cata Preta Corr&#xea;a GA, Bouskela E. SARS-CoV-2 infection causes pulmonary shunt by vasodilatation. J Med Virol 2021;93(1):573-575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature 2021;594(7862):259-264.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>