<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35505733</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Microbial Profile and Resistance Pattern of Pathogens Isolated From Long COVID Pneumonia Patients and Their Correlation to Clinical Outcome: Our Experience From a Tertiary Care Hospital.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e23644</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e23644</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e23644</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.23644</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) patients with persistent symptoms for at least four weeks in spite of being reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction (RTPCR) negative for COVID infection are defined as long COVID (wherein pulmonary involvement is seen in a significant proportion of cases). The history of prolonged use of corticosteroids, broad-spectrum antibiotics, and associated comorbid conditions in these patients increases the possibility of infection with multidrug-resistant&#xa0;microbial strains. It may lead to a grave prognosis, hence appropriate microbiological evaluation and management at the earliest can have a better outcome. Methods A retrospective observational study was carried out among long COVID patients admitted to the Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences, Bhubaneswar, Odisha, India, a tertiary care hospital. Eighty-four patients admitted to the ICU or non-ICU ward in the hospital from April to October 2021 were included in the study. Antibiotics, as prescribed by our hospital antibiotic policy, were administered wherever required and were subsequently changed according to culture and sensitivity reports of the samples (sputum, endotracheal aspirates, or blood). An analysis of the antibiotic sensitivity patterns of the pathogens isolated was performed. The outcome after optimum medical management was assessed for survivors, discharge, or death. Results Out of the total of 84 patients, 41&#xa0;samples (sputum, endotracheal aspirates or blood) were collected and sent for culture, of which 32 (78.1%)&#xa0;were found to be culture positive for pathogens.&#xa0;Among the pathogens isolated, there were&#xa0;22 (69%) drug-resistant&#xa0;and 10 (31%) sensitive organisms. Among the 22 resistant&#xa0;pathogen&#xa0;isolates, 18 were Gram-negative species, the most common species being <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae, Pseudomonas aeruginosa,</i> and <i>Acinetobacter baumanii;</i> two were Gram-positive species, one each from&#xa0;<i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> and <i>Enterococcus faecalis,</i> and three were <i>Candida tropicalis</i>. Of five deaths reported among 22 cases with resistant isolates, extensively drug-resistant (XDR), multi-drug resistance (MDR), and pan drug resistance (PDR) strains were detected in three, one, and one cases, respectively, and were harboured by&#xa0;<i>K.&#xa0;</i> <i>pneumoniae, P. aeruginosa,</i> and <i>A. baumanii</i>.&#xa0;Of the total&#xa0;eight deaths, there were two deaths among the 43 patients who received an empiric antibiotic in the wards, and six deaths were reported in the ICU.&#xa0;Despite raised biomarkers of inflammation, comorbid illnesses, renal impairment, and immunocompromised states, there was 91% survival and discharge, which was statistically significant (p-value = 0.00). Conclusion To conclude,&#xa0;<i>K. pneumoniae, P. aeruginosa, A. baumanii, C. tropicalis, S. aureus, and E. faecalis</i> were the most commonly isolated organisms among long COVID pneumonia cases, of which some were MDR, PDR and XDR strains.&#xa0;Early microbiological evaluation with targeted, proper antimicrobial usage along with optimized medical management and, wherever needed, critical care support in the ICU may lead to a better prognostic outcome in those groups of patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022, Rao et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rao</LastName><ForeName>C Mohan</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary Medicine Deparment, Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences, Bhubaneswar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rout</LastName><ForeName>Pragyan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary Medicine Department, Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences, Bhubneswar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pattnaik</LastName><ForeName>Ashwini P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nephrology Department, Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences, Bhubaneswar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Nipa</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Microbiology Department, Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences, Bhubaneswar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajendran</LastName><ForeName>Aarthi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary Medicine Department, Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences, Bhubaneswar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patro</LastName><ForeName>Shubhransu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine Department, Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences, Bhubaneswar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mdr</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microbial profile</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pdr</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">xdr</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35505733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9053113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.23644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>An interactive web-based dashboard to track COVID-19 in real time. Dong E, Du H, Gardner L. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20:533&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32087114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: "and the fire rages on". Tripathi AK, Pinto LM. Lung India. 2021;38:564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8614604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34747740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Insights in the management of long COVID-19: preliminary observations. Goel N, Goyal N, Kumar R. https://www.researchgate.net/publication/355058469_Insights_in_the_Management_of_Long_COVID-19_Preliminary_Observations Indian J Chest Dis Allied Sci. 2021;63:65&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen K. Philadelphia: Elsevier/Saunders. 51(5) Philadelphia: Elsevier/Saunders; 2010. Mandell, Douglas, and Bennett's Principles and Practice of Infectious Diseases; pp. 636&#x2013;637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute. Wayne: Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute; 2019. Performace Standards for Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VITEK 2&#xae; compact.  [
Mar;
2022 
];https://www.biomerieux-diagnostics.com/vitekr-2-compact-0 2022 </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multidrug-resistant, extensively drug-resistant and pandrug-resistant bacteria: an international expert proposal for interim standard definitions for acquired resistance. Magiorakos AP, Srinivasan A, Carey RB, et al. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2012;18:268&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21793988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacterial superinfection in adults with COVID-19 hospitalized in two clinics in Medell&#xed;n-Colombia, 2020. Cata&#xf1;o-Correa JC, Cardona-Arias JA, Porras Mancilla JP, Garc&#xed;a MT. PLoS One. 2021;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8277025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34255801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacterial and viral co-infections in patients with severe SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia admitted to a French ICU. Contou D, Claudinon A, Pajot O, et al. Ann Intensive Care. 2020;10:119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7475952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32894364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secondary infections in hospitalized COVID-19 patients: Indian experience. Vijay S, Bansal N, Rao BK, et al. Infect Drug Resist. 2021;14:1893&#x2013;1903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8164345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34079300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Co-infections in people with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lansbury L, Lim B, Baskaran V, Lim WS. J Infect. 2020;81:266&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32473235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Six-month follow-up chest CT findings after severe COVID- 19 pneumonia. Han X, Fan Y, Alwalid O, et al. Radiology. 2021;299:0&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7841877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Follow-up study of the pulmonary function and related physiological characteristics of COVID-19 survivors three months after recovery. Zhao YM, Shang YM, Song WB, et al. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>'Long-COVID': a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, et al. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medium-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on multiple vital organs, exercise capacity, cognition, quality of life and mental health, post-hospital discharge. Raman B, Cassar MP, Tunnicliffe EM, et al. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;31:100683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33490928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The pathogenesis and treatment of the 'Cytokine Storm' in COVID-19. Ye Q, Wang B, Mao J. J Infect. 2020;80:607&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32283152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Current concepts on the virulence mechanisms of meticillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus. Watkins RR, David MZ, Salata RA. J Med Microbiol. 2012;61:1179&#x2013;1193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4080747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22745137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>