<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37336480</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1305-7456</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of dentistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Dent</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Potential Impact of Long COVID-19 on Orthodontic Treatment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>387</StartPage><EndPage>391</EndPage><MedlinePgn>387-391</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/s-0043-1768467</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Pooled estimates indicate about 226 million individuals are currently experiencing or have experienced persistent symptoms from COVID-19. Long COVID-19 (LC) has been associated with a prolonged inflammatory and stress responses in affected individuals. Due to common pathways, LC could impact the biological mechanisms of orthodontic tooth movement, orthodontically-induced inflammatory root resorption and periodontal tissue response of patients undergoing orthodontic treatment. The authors of the present report discussed potential biological mechanisms through which LC may influence orthodontic treatment highlighting the need for further research in this area.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>The Author(s). This is an open access article published by Thieme under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, permitting unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction so long as the original work is properly cited. (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Jewair</LastName><ForeName>Thikriat</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6857-747X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthodontics, School of Dental Medicine, University at Buffalo, Buffalo, New York, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michelogiannakis</LastName><ForeName>Dimitrios</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthodontics and Dentofacial Orthopedics, Eastman Institute for Oral Health, University of Rochester, New York, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khoo</LastName><ForeName>Edmund</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthodontics and Dentofacial Orthopedics, Eastman Institute for Oral Health, University of Rochester, New York, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthodontics and Oral Facial Genetics, Indiana University School of Dentistry, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Dentistry, Eastman Institute for Oral Health, University of Rochester, New York, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prevost</LastName><ForeName>Ryan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthodontics, School of Dental Medicine, University at Buffalo, Buffalo, New York, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Dent</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101303672</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>T. A.-J. reported the following roles: Chair role in ADEA Council of Advanced Education Programs. Site visitor role in Commission on Dental Accreditation. Scientific committee member role in American Academy of Dental Sleep Medicine and examiner for the American Board of Orthodontics. E. K. reported Consulting fees received from Verywell.com. E. K. also reported following roles: Committee member and partners in research sub-committee member role in American Association of Orthodontists, Council on Orthodontic Education (COE). Councilor role in ADEA Council on Sections. Site Visitor role in Commission on Dental Accreditation. R. P. reported following roles: Chair role in Wellness taskforce. President role in Orthodontics Interest Group. All other authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37336480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10959594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0043-1768467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baig A M. Chronic COVID syndrome: need for an appropriate medical terminology for long-COVID and COVID long-haulers. J Med Virol. 2021;93(05):2555&#x2013;2556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33095459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert S R, Zimmermann L et al.Global prevalence of post COVID-19 condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis. 2022;226(09):1593&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi O L, Hughes S E, Turner G et al.Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med. 2021;114(09):428&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burn E, Teb&#xe9; C, Fernandez-Bertolin S et al.The natural history of symptomatic COVID-19 during the first wave in Catalonia. Nat Commun. 2021;12(01):777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7858639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33536436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A et al.Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27(04):601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkodaymi M S, Omrani O A, Fawzy N A et al.Prevalence of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome symptoms at different follow-up periods: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28(05):657&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8812092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P.Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management BMJ 2021374(1648):n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes D L, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice A H, Crooks M G. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;199(02):113&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Ling S, Lui L MW et al.Fatigue and cognitive impairment in post-COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun. 2022;101:93&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen N N, Hoang V T, Dao T L, Dudouet P, Eldin C, Gautret P. Clinical patterns of somatic symptoms in patients suffering from post-acute long COVID: a systematic review. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2022;41(04):515&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8830952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre C H, Murray B, Varsavsky T et al.Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27(04):626&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman Cet al.More than 50 long-termeffects of COVID-19: a systematic review and metaanalysismedRxiv2021;2021.01.27.21250617</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Yet al.6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study Lancet 2021397(10270):220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra V, Flanders S A, O'Malley M, Malani A N, Prescott H C. Sixty-day outcomes among patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174(04):576&#x2013;578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7707210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourmistrova N W, Solomon T, Braude P, Strawbridge R, Carter B. Long-term effects of COVID-19 on mental health: a systematic review. J Affect Disord. 2022;299:118&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8758130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34798148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bektas A, Schurman S H, Franceschi C, Ferrucci L. A public health perspective of aging: do hyper-inflammatory syndromes such as COVID-19, SARS, ARDS, cytokine storm syndrome, and post-ICU syndrome accelerate short- and long-term inflammaging? Immun Ageing. 2020;17:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7443812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32849908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai P, Kumar B K, Deekshit V K, Karunasagar I, Karunasagar I. Detection technologies and recent developments in the diagnosis of COVID-19 infection. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol. 2021;105(02):441&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7780074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33394144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaimayo C, Kaewnaphan B, Tanlieng N et al.Rapid SARS-CoV-2 antigen detection assay in comparison with real-time RT-PCR assay for laboratory diagnosis of COVID-19 in Thailand. Virol J. 2020;17(01):177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33187528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandler C X, Wyller V BB, Moss-Morris R et al.Long COVID and post-infective fatigue syndrome: a review. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8(10):ofab440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8496765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34631916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behnood S A, Shafran R, Bennett S D et al.Persistent symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection amongst children and young people: a meta-analysis of controlled and uncontrolled studies. J Infect. 2022;84(02):158&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8604800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34813820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q, Zheng B, Daines L, Sheikh A. Long-term sequelae of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of one-year follow-up studies on post-COVID symptoms. Pathogens. 2022;11(02):269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8875269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35215212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vulugundam S, Abreu L G, Bernab&#xe9; E. Is orthodontic treatment associated with changes in self-esteem during adolescence? A longitudinal study. J Orthod. 2021;48(04):352&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8652369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33860695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horani S, El-Bialy T, Barmak A B, Rossouw P E, Michelogiannakis D. Changes in airway dimensions following non-extraction clear aligner therapy in adult patients with mild-to-moderate crowding. J Contemp Dent Pract. 2021;22(03):224&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34210919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doykov I, H&#xe4;llqvist J, Gilmour K C, Grandjean L, Mills K, Heywood W E. &#x2018;The long tail of Covid-19&#x2019; - the detection of a prolonged inflammatory response after a SARS-CoV-2 infection in asymptomatic and mildly affected patients. F1000 Res. 2020;9:1349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7745182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33391730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suri S, Vandersluis Y R, Kochhar A S, Bhasin R, Abdallah M N. Clinical orthodontic management during the COVID-19 pandemic. Angle Orthod. 2020;90(04):473&#x2013;484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8028467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32396601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan S, Guo Y, Zhou J et al.Orthodontic emergencies and mental state of Chinese orthodontic patients during the COVID-19 pandemic. BMC Oral Health. 2021;21(01):477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34579698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhanasekaran M, Shaga I B, Ponniah H, Sankaranarayanan P, Nagappan N, Parameswaran T M. The pandemic impact of COVID 19 on orthodontic practice: a cross sectional study. J Pharm Bioallied Sci. 2021;13 02:S1024&#x2013;S1028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8686886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35017922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wise G E, King G J. Mechanisms of tooth eruption and orthodontic tooth movement. J Dent Res. 2008;87(05):414&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2387248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18434571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murrell E F, Yen E H, Johnson R B. Vascular changes in the periodontal ligament after removal of orthodontic forces. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 1996;110(03):280&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8814029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamaguchi M, Kasai K. Inflammation in periodontal tissues in response to mechanical forces. Arch Immunol Ther Exp (Warsz) 2005;53(05):388&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16314823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Jacox L A, Little S H, Ko C C. Orthodontic tooth movement: the biology and clinical implications. Kaohsiung J Med Sci. 2018;34(04):207&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29655409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meikle M C. The tissue, cellular, and molecular regulation of orthodontic tooth movement: 100 years after Carl Sandstedt. Eur J Orthod. 2006;28(03):221&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16687469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry S, Javed F, Rossouw P E, Barmak A B, Kalogirou E M, Michelogiannakis D. Influence of thyroxine supplementation on orthodontically induced tooth movement and/or inflammatory root resorption: a systematic review. Orthod Craniofac Res. 2021;24(02):206&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelogiannakis D, Rossouw P E, Al-Shammery D et al.Influence of nicotine on orthodontic tooth movement: a systematic review of experimental studies in rats. Arch Oral Biol. 2018;93:66&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29843070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelogiannakis D, Rossouw P E, Khan J, Akram Z, Menenakos E, Javed F. Influence of increased body mass index on orthodontic tooth movement and related parameters in children and adolescents: a systematic review of longitudinal controlled clinical studies. J Orthod. 2019;46(04):323&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31522589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Shammery D, Michelogiannakis D, Rossouw E, Romanos G E, Javed F. Influence of psychological stress exposure on orthodontic therapy: a comprehensive review. J Investig Clin Dent. 2019;10(02):e12388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30618117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almadih A, Al-Zayer M, Dabel S et al.Orthodontic treatment consideration in diabetic patients. J Clin Med Res. 2018;10(02):77&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5755646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29317952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra G P, Mulani J. Corticosteroids for COVID-19: the search for an optimum duration of therapy. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9(01):e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33248469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvio G, Gianfelice C, Firmani F, Lunetti S, Balercia G, Giacchetti G. Bone metabolism in SARS-CoV-2 disease: possible osteoimmunology and gender implications. Clin Rev Bone Miner Metab. 2020;18(04):51&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7459260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32904892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaushu S, Klein Y, Mandelboim O, Barenholz Y, Fleissig O. Immune changes induced by orthodontic forces: a critical review. J Dent Res. 2022;101(01):11&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34105404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamaguchi M, Fukasawa S. Is inflammation a friend or foe for orthodontic treatment?: inflammation in orthodontically induced inflammatory root resorption and accelerating tooth movement. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(05):2388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7957544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33673606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arias O R, Marquez-Orozco M C. Aspirin, acetaminophen, and ibuprofen: their effects on orthodontic tooth movement. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 2006;130(03):364&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16979495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weltman B, Vig K W, Fields H W, Shanker S, Kaizar E E.Root resorption associated with orthodontic tooth movement: a systematic review Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop 201013704462&#x2013;476., discussion 12A</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20362905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saloom H F, Papageorgiou S N, Carpenter G H, Cobourne M T. Impact of obesity on orthodontic tooth movement in adolescents: a prospective clinical cohort study. J Dent Res. 2017;96(05):547&#x2013;554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28113000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNab S, Battistutta D, Taverne A, Symons A L. External apical root resorption of posterior teeth in asthmatics after orthodontic treatment. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 1999;116(05):545&#x2013;551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10547515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haran J P, Bradley E, Zeamer A L et al.Inflammation-type dysbiosis of the oral microbiome associates with the duration of COVID-19 symptoms and long COVID. JCI Insight. 2021;6(20):e152346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8564890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34403368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>