<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33398279</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2692-8205</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>bioRxiv : the preprint server for biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>bioRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Analyzing the vast coronavirus literature with CoronaCentral.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2020.12.21.423860</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1101/2020.12.21.423860</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The global SARS-CoV-2 pandemic has caused a surge in research exploring all aspects of the virus and its effects on human health. The overwhelming rate of publications means that human researchers are unable to keep abreast of the research. To ameliorate this, we present the CoronaCentral resource which uses machine learning to process the research literature on SARS-CoV-2 along with articles on SARS-CoV and MERS-CoV. We break the literature down into useful categories and enable analysis of the contents, pace, and emphasis of research during the crisis. These categories cover therapeutics, forecasting as well as growing areas such as "Long Covid" and studies of inequality and misinformation. Using this data, we compare topics that appear in original research articles compared to commentaries and other article types. Finally, using Altmetric data, we identify the topics that have gained the most media attention. This resource, available at https://coronacentral.ai , is updated multiple times per day and provides an easy-to-navigate system to find papers in different categories, focussing on different aspects of the virus along with currently trending articles.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lever</LastName><ForeName>Jake</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, Stanford University, 443 Via Ortega, Stanford, CA 94305.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Altman</LastName><ForeName>Russ B</ForeName><Initials>RB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, Stanford University, 443 Via Ortega, Stanford, CA 94305.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 LM005652</GrantID><Acronym>LM</Acronym><Agency>NLM NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>bioRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101680187</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2692-8205</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateIn"><RefSource>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2021 Jun 8;118(23):e2100766118. doi: 10.1073/pnas.2100766118</RefSource><PMID Version="1">34016708</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33398279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7781314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.12.21.423860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2020.12.21.423860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Allot A, Lu Z. Keep up with the latest coronavirus research. Nature. 2020;579: 193&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32157233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang E, Gupta N, Tang R, Han X, Pradeep R, Lu K, et al. Covidex: Neural ranking models and keyword search infrastructure for the covid-19 open research dataset. arXiv preprint arXiv:200707846. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doanvo A, Qian X, Ramjee D, Piontkivska H, Desai A, Majumder M. Machine learning maps research needs in covid-19 literature. Patterns. 2020; 100123. doi:10.1016/j.patter.2020.100123</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.patter.2020.100123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7494306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32959032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verspoor K, &#x160;uster S, Otmakhova Y, Mendis S, Zhai Z, Fang B, et al. COVID-see: Scientific evidence explorer for covid-19 related research. arXiv preprint arXiv:200807880. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts K, Alam T, Bedrick S, Demner-Fushman D, Lo K, Soboroff I, et al. TREC-covid: Rationale and structure of an information retrieval shared task for covid-19. Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association. 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7239098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32365190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiekens C, Boldrini P, Andreoli A, Avesani R, Gamna F, Grandi M, et al. Rehabilitation and respiratory management in the acute and early post-acute phase.&#x201c;Instant paper from the field&#x201d; on rehabilitation answers to the covid-19 emergency. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2020; 06305&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32293817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Wilde AH, Jochmans D, Posthuma CC, Zevenhoven-Dobbe JC, Van Nieuwkoop S, Bestebroer TM, et al. Screening of an fda-approved compound library identifies four small-molecule inhibitors of middle east respiratory syndrome coronavirus replication in cell culture. Antimicrobial agents and chemotherapy. 2014;58: 4875&#x2013;4884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4136071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24841269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou N, Pan T, Zhang J, Li Q, Zhang X, Bai C, et al. Glycopeptide antibiotics potently inhibit cathepsin l in the late endosome/lysosome and block the entry of ebola virus, middle east respiratory syndrome coronavirus (mers-cov), and severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (sars-cov). Journal of Biological Chemistry. 2016;291: 9218&#x2013;9232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4861487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26953343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LL, Lo K, Chandrasekhar Y, Reas R, Yang J, Burdick D, et al.
CORD-19: The COVID-19 open research dataset. Proceedings of the 1st workshop on NLP for COVID-19 at ACL 2020. Online: Association for Computational Linguistics; 2020. 
Available: https://www.aclweb.org/anthology/2020.nlpcovid19-acl.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiya AS. Ktrain: A low-code library for augmented machine learning. arXiv. 2020;arXiv:2004.10703 [cs.LG].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedregosa F, Varoquaux G, Gramfort A, Michel V, Thirion B, Grisel O, et al. Scikit-learn: Machine learning in Python. Journal of Machine Learning Research. 2011;12: 2825&#x2013;2830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Y, Tinn R, Cheng H, Lucas M, Usuyama N, Liu X, et al. Domain-specific language model pretraining for biomedical natural language processing. arXiv preprint arXiv:200715779. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei C-H, Allot A, Leaman R, Lu Z. PubTator central: Automated concept annotation for biomedical full text articles. Nucleic acids research. 2019;47: W587&#x2013;W593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6602571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31114887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>