<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39478711</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1735-9066</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Season>Sep-Oct</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Iranian journal of nursing and midwifery research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence and Predictors of Fatigue among Thai Women after COVID-19 Infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>563</StartPage><EndPage>567</EndPage><MedlinePgn>563-567</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/ijnmr.ijnmr_285_23</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Several people suffered from fatigue after recovering from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). However, limited studies focused on fatigue in women who recovered from COVID-19 infection. This study aimed to investigate the prevalence of fatigue among Thai women after COVID-19 infection and to identify predictive factors, including depression, anxiety, fear, and insomnia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A cross-sectional research design using convenience sampling was conducted from October 2022 to January 2023. A total of 142 Thai women after COVID-19 infection were recruited from two urban communities located in the Bangkok Metropolitan area, Thailand. The participants completed self-reported questionnaires, including the demographic and illness-related data questionnaire, the Depress Anxiety Stress Scales, the Insomnia Severity Index, the Fear of Progression Questionnaire, and the Fatigue Severity Scale. Data were analyzed using mean, standard deviation, range, Pearson's product-moment correlations, and stepwise multiple regression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">All (100%) participants returned the questionnaires. After recovering from COVID-19 infection for at least 1 month or longer, 39.40% of the participants reported fatigue. The multiple regression analysis revealed that fear, anxiety, and insomnia collectively contributed to 47% of the variance in the participants' fatigue (R<sup>2</sup> = 0.47; <i>p</i> &lt; 0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Nearly two-quarters of Thai women after recovering from COVID-19 infection experienced fatigue. To prevent fatigue among Thai women after COVID-19 infection, it is necessary to help them overcome feelings of fear and anxiety. Furthermore, nursing interventions aiming to alleviate insomnia should be implemented.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2024 Iranian Journal of Nursing and Midwifery Research.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jitpanya</LastName><ForeName>Chanokporn</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Nursing, Suan Dusit University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maninet</LastName><ForeName>Surachai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Nursing, Ubon Ratchathani University, Ubon Ratchathani, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saengkham</LastName><ForeName>Pannita</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Nursing, Huachiew Chalermprakiet University, Samut Prakan, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101558775</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1735-9066</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insomnia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">women and health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Nothing to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39478711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11521130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijnmr.ijnmr_285_23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJNMR-29-563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Thailand Convention &amp; Exhibition Bureau  Thailand: Situation Update Coronavirus COVID-19. 2024 Available from: https://www.businesseventsthailand.com/en/situation-update-coronavirus-COVID-19.  [Last accessed on 2024 Jan 18]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Florencio LL, Cuadrado ML, Plaza-Manzano G, Navarro-Santana M. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Intern Med. 2021;92:55&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34167876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: A cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, Palladini M, Villa G, De Lorenzo R, Querini PR, Benedetti F. Prevalence, trajectory over time, and risk factor of post-COVID-19 fatigue. J Psychiatr Res. 2022;155:112&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9391361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36029623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joli J, Buck P, Zipfel S, Stengel A. Post-COVID-19 fatigue: A systematic review. Front Psychiatry. 2022;13:947973. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt. 2022.947973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9403611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36032234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, Ghanima W, Olsen MK, Gilboe HM, Einvik G. Prevalence and determinants of fatigue after COVID-19 in non-hospitalized subjects: A population-based study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:2030. doi: 10.3390/ijerph 18042030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7921928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33669714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilgin A, Kesik G, Ozdemir L. &#x2018;The body seems to have no life&#x2019;: The experiences and perceptions of fatigue among patients after COVID-19. J Clin Nurs. 2021:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34845774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zkeskin M, &#xd6;zden F, Karaman B, Ekmek&#xe7;i &#xd6;, Y&#xfc;ceyar N. The comparison of fatigue, sleep quality, physical activity, quality of life, and psychological status in multiple sclerosis patients with or without COVID-19. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2021;55:103180. doi: 10.1016/j.msard. 2021.103180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8324500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34352513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsharawy A, Spoon R, Smith A, Ball S. Gender differences in fear and risk perception during the COVID-19 pandemic. Front Psychol. 2021;12:689467. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg. 2021.689467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8375576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34421741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudroff T, Workman CD, Bryant AD. Potential factors that contribute to post-COVID-19 fatigue in women. Brain Sci. 2022;12:556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9139370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35624943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oei TP, Sawang S, Goh YW, Mukhtar F. Using the depression anxiety stress scale 21 (DASS-21) across cultures. Int J Psychol. 2013;48:1018&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23425257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suwanbamrung C, Pongtalung P, Trang LTT, Phu DH, Nam TT. Levels and risk factors associated with depression, anxiety, and stress among COVID-19 infected adults after hospital discharge in a Southern Province of Thailand. J Public Health Dev. 2023;21:72&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keawphang P, Jitpanya C. Relationship between selected factors related to insomnia in adult cancer patients. J Nurs Sci Chula Uni. 2006;18:33&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wongkuan D, Jitpanya C, Chimluang J. Master&#x2019;s thesis, Faculty of Nursing. Chulalongkorn University; 2017. Factors predicting sleep disturbances in acute myocardial infarction survivors.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawasdee A, Preechawong S, Jitpanya C. Master&#x2019;s thesis, Faculty of Nursing. Bangkok: Chulalongkorn University; 2014. Factors associated with fatigue in post-stroke patients.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarte KI, Catahay JA, Velasco JV, Pastrana A, Ver AT, Pangilinan FC, et al. Impact of COVID-19 vaccination on the risk of developing long-COVID and on existing long-COVID symptoms: A systematic review. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;53:101624. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm. 2022.101624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9417563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36051247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maamar M, Artime A, Pariente E, Fierro P, Ruiz Y, Guti&#xe9;rrez S, et al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome, low-grade inflammation and inflammatory markers: A cross-sectional study. Curr Med Res Opin. 2022;38:901&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8935459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35166141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shroff R, Talwar J, Ray M. Prevalence of post COVID-19 syndrome. Int J Community Med Public Health. 2022;9:3551&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namwong A, Chaijundee W. A social stigma toward people with COVID-19 or people who may have COVID-19 and its consequences: A qualitative study. J Nurs Health Res. 2022;23:80&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ketunuti V, Chittangwong S. Against the Odds: Stories from women in Thailand during COVID19.  Available from: https://thailand.un.org/en/51835-against-odds-stories-women-thailand-during-covid-19 . [Last accessed on 2024 Jan 20]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin CM, Bjorvatn B, Chung F, Holzinger B, Partinen M, Penzel T, et al. Insomnia, anxiety, and depression during the COVID-19 pandemic: An international collaborative study. Sleep Med. 2021;87:38&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8425785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34508986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pudlo R, Jaworska I, Szczegielniak A, Niedziela J, Ku&#x142;aczkowska Z, Nowowiejska-Wiewi&#xf3;ra A, et al. Prevalence of insomnia in the early post-COVID-19 recovery period. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:14224. doi: 10.3390/ijerph 192114224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9654654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36361102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15a;redniawa A, Drwi&#x142;a D, Krotos A, Wojta&#x15b; D, Kostecka N, Tomasik T. Insomnia and the level of stress among students in Krakow, Poland. Trends Psychiatry Psychother. 2019;41:60&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30994780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheshmehzangi A, Chen H, Su Z, Zou T, Xiang YT, Dawodu A. How does the COVID-19 fuel insomnia? Brain Behav Immun Health. 2022;21:100426. doi: 10.1016/j.bbih. 2022.100426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8824358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35156064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>