<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35677013</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19 Infection: Its Lingering Symptoms in Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e24736</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e24736</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e24736</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.24736</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Recent studies showed that a significant percentage of people who recovered from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) had lingering symptoms. Among patients diagnosed with COVID-19 infection, studies showed persistent symptoms both in patients hospitalized and in outpatient settings. In the studies done in the outpatient setting involving mild to moderate COVID-19 patients, there were significant variations regarding the exact percentage of people with lingering symptoms. Also, in the outpatient setting, not many studies were done on COVID-19 patients that assessed risk factors for having lingering symptoms. Given that a large percentage of people infected with COVID-19 infection do not get hospitalized, it is imperative that this lacuna be filled. We believe knowing the details of long-term symptoms of COVID-19 infection both from prevalence and predictors point of view, could allow the physicians, healthcare system and community to better prepare for managing and following these patients. Materials and methods Our study period was within 12 months after the first documented case of COVID-19 occurred in the State of Alabama. Our study population included patients who were diagnosed with a documented case of COVID-19 in this time period and were under the care of a single primary care provider at an ambulatory clinic.&#xa0;Among 80 patients who had documented COVID-19, three left the practice, two declined to participate in the study and three were deceased (two due to COVID-19 and one for other reasons). Therefore, the study population constituted 72 patients. A questionnaire was mailed to all 72 patients to see how many of them had symptoms three months and beyond of having COVID-19 infection. A chart review was conducted for the study participants to assess for "Comorbid conditions", health conditions that were considered conclusively high risk for acute COVID-19 infection by US Center for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Results Fifty-three patients responded to the questionnaire; 27 patients (50.9%) reported lingering symptoms beyond three months of diagnosis with COVID-19 infection. The three most common symptoms reported were fatigue (56%), brain fog (48%), and shortness of breath (41%). The results also showed that women are more likely than men to have lingering symptoms. "Elderly" (&#x2265;65 years) patients were as likely as 18-64 years old patients to have lingering symptoms and the presence of one or more of the "Comorbid conditions" does not have any bearing on the occurrence of lingering symptoms. Conclusion Future studies should be done in a larger population to assess the findings that our study showed regarding "elderly" age and the presence of one or more "comorbid conditions" being independent variables of the occurrence of prolonged COVID-19 symptoms. We recommend studies be done assessing the prevalence and predictors for the long-term effects of the COVID-19 infection. This knowledge could help in preventing those long-term symptoms from occurring in the first place and also in preparing the patient, the physician and the community in managing the outcomes effectively.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022, Yellumahanthi et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yellumahanthi</LastName><ForeName>Durgamani Kishore</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Huntsville, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barnett</LastName><ForeName>Bethany</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Family Medicine of Huntsville, Huntsville, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barnett</LastName><ForeName>Sarabeth</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>None, Ardmore High School, Ardmore, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yellumahanthi</LastName><ForeName>Shushruth</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>None, New Century Technology High School, Huntsville, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lingering symptoms covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long term side effects covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-haul covid</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35677013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9166577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.24736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Persistent Symptoms in Patients After Acute COVID-19. Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. The. Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, et al. Lancet. 397:220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Symptoms: Longitudinal Evolution and Persistence in Outpatient Settings. Nehme M, Braillard O, Alcoba G, Aebischer Perone S, Courvoisier D, Chappuis F, Guessous I. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174:723&#x2013;725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7741180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33284676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID in the Faroe Islands: A Longitudinal Study Among Nonhospitalized Patients. Petersen MS, Kristiansen MF, Hanusson KD, et al. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:0&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7799340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33252665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toward understanding COVID-19 recovery: National Institutes of Health workshop on postacute COVID-19. Lerner AM, Robinson DA, Yang L, et al. Ann Intern Med. 2021;33780290</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8025940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33780290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19: Evaluation and Care of Patients With Persistent Symptoms Following Acute SARS-CoV-2 Infection. Laine C, Cotton D. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174:1159&#x2013;1160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8276272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34115532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covid-19: What do we know about "long covid"? Mahase E. BMJ. 2020;370:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32665317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long Covid: how to define it and how to manage it. Nabavi N. BMJ. 2020370;3489:32895219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32895219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, Villapol S. Sci Rep. 2021;11:16144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of coronavirus disease 2019 on pulmonary function in early convalescence phase. Huang Y, Tan C, Wu J, et al. Respir Res. 2020;21:163&#x2013;32600344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32600344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characteristics of Adult Outpatients and Inpatients with COVID-19 &#x2014; 11 Academic Medical Centers, United States, March-May. Tenforde MW, Rose EB, Lindsell CJ, et al.  http://dx.doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm6926e3external 20202020;69:841&#x2013;846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7332092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32614810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection in individuals not requiring hospital admission: a Danish population-based cohort study. Lund LC, Hallas J, Nielsen H, et al. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21:1373&#x2013;1382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8110209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33984263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment of the Frequency and Variety of Persistent Symptoms Among Patients With COVID-19: A Systematic Review. Nasserie T, Hittle M, Goodman SN. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8155823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34037731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The impact of Post-COVID-Syndrome on functioning - results from a community survey in patients after mild and moderate SARS-CoV-2-infections in Germany. Lemh&#xf6;fer C, Sturm C, Loudovici-Krug D, Best N, Gutenbrunner C. J Occup Med Toxicol. 2021;16:45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8495185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34620202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirulli E., Kelly M., Barrett S, et al. 2020100720208702. Long-term COVID-19 symptoms in a large unselected population, medRxiv.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of Symptoms More Than Seven Months After Diagnosis of Symptomatic COVID-19 in an Outpatient Setting. Nehme M, Braillard O, Chappuis F, Courvoisier DS, Guessous I. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174:1252&#x2013;1260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34224254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-COVID syndrome in non-hospitalised patients with COVID-19: a longitudinal prospective cohort study. Augustin M, Schommers P, Stecher M, et al. Lancet Reg Health Eur. 2021;6:100122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8129613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34027514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>