<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37344737</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1568-5608</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Inflammopharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Inflammopharmacology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID and possible preventive options.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2807</StartPage><EndPage>2817</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2807-2817</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10787-023-01204-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Most of the people who suffered from COVID-19 fully recovered, but approximately 10-20% of them developed a wide variety of symptoms after they recover from their initial illness. Long COVID can develop at any patient; however, several studies suggest that the development of Long Covid syndrome may be linked to severity of acute illness. Some of the risk factors are hospitalization (with mechanical ventilation), Intensive Care Unit admission, age (over 50&#xa0;years), gender (female) and comorbidities. Since the precise mechanism of Long COVID has not been clarified, neither the management of Long COVID-19 syndrome has been solved yet. Promising results have been published with vaccines as they effectively reduced the risk of Long COVID; however, other data suggest that vaccination results only partial protection in the post-acute phase of the disease. Recently, the orally effective antiviral agents (Paxlovid, molnupiravir) are preferred for outpatient management, and they highly reduce the progression of mild-to-moderate COVID-19 to severe one, and consequently, might reduce the development of Long COVID. Finally, recently, several clinical trials are in progress with either dietary supplements or drugs with different mechanisms of action. Additional information on the precise mechanisms, risk factors of Long COVID may result in successful preventive and therapeutic management of Long Covid 19 syndrome.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seb&#x151;k</LastName><ForeName>Szilvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Pharmacy Department of Pharmacy Administration, Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Semmelweis University, H&#x151;gyes Endre U. 7-9., Budapest, 1092, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gyires</LastName><ForeName>Klara</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4718-2345</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmacotherapy, Faculty of Medicine, Semmelweis University, Nagyv&#xe1;rad t&#xe9;r 4., Budapest, 1089, Hungary. gyires.klara@med.semmelweis-univ.hu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Inflammopharmacology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112626</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0925-4692</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000719967">nirmatrelvir and ritonavir drug combination</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>O3J8G9O825</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019438">Ritonavir</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019438" MajorTopicYN="N">Ritonavir</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Potential managements</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk factors</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no relevant financial or non-financial interests to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37344737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10692252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10787-023-01204-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10787-023-01204-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Bowe B, Xie Y. Long COVID after breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med. 2022;28:1461&#x2013;1467. doi: 10.1038/s41591-022-01840-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01840-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9307472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35614233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali K, Azher T, Baqi M, Binnie A, Borgia S, Carrier FM, Cavayas YA, Chagnon N, Cheng MP, Conly J, Costiniuk C, Daley P, Daneman N, Douglas J, Downey C, Duan E, Duceppe E, Durand M, English S, Farjou G, Fera E, Fontela P, Fowler R, Fralick M, Geagea A, Grant J, Harrison LB, Havey T, Hoang H, Kelly LE, Keynan Y, Khwaja K, Klein G, Klein M, Kolan C, Kronfli N, Lamontagne F, Lau R, Fralick M, Lee TC, Lee N, Lim R, Longo S, Lostun A, Macintyre E, Malham&#xe9; I, Mangof K, McGuinty M, Mergler S, Munan MP, Murthy S, O'Neil C, Ovakim D, Papenburg J, Parhar K, Parvathy SN, Patel C, Perez-Patrigeon S, Pinto R, Rajakumaran S, Rishu A, Roba-Oshin M, Rushton M, Saleem M, Salvadori M, Scherr K, Schwartz K, Semret M, Silverman M, Singh A, Sligl W, Smith S, Somayaji R, Tan DHS, Tobin S, Todd M, Tran TV, Tremblay A, Tsang J, Turgeon A, Vakil E, Weatherald J, Yansouni C, Zarychanski R. Remdesivir for the treatment of patients in hospital with COVID-19 in Canada: a randomized controlled trial. CMAJ. 2022;194:E242&#x2013;e251. doi: 10.1503/cmaj.211698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/cmaj.211698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8863204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35045989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Penfold RS, Merino J, Sudre CH, Molteni E, Berry S, Canas LS, Graham MS, Klaser K, Modat M, Murray B, Kerfoot E, Chen L, Deng J, &#xd6;sterdahl MF, Cheetham NJ, Drew DA, Nguyen LH, Pujol JC, Hu C, Selvachandran S, Polidori L, May A, Wolf J, Chan AT, Hammers A, Duncan EL, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk factors and disease profile of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection in UK users of the COVID Symptom Study app: a prospective, community-based, nested, case-control study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:43&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00460-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00460-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34480857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballering AV, Van Zon SKR, Olde Hartman TC, Rosmalen JGM. Persistence of somatic symptoms after COVID-19 in the Netherlands: an observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022;400:452&#x2013;461. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(22)01214-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(22)01214-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9352274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35934007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baratta JM, Tompary A, Siano S, Floris-Moore M, Weber DJ. Postacute sequelae of COVID-19 infection and development of a physiatry-led recovery clinic. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;100:633&#x2013;634. doi: 10.1097/PHM.0000000000001778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000001778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8186261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34131092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.12603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.12603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carod-Artal FJ. Post-COVID-19 syndrome: epidemiology, diagnostic criteria and pathogenic mechanisms involved. Rev Neurol. 2021;72:384&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34042167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 RAPID GUIDELINE: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. NICE Guideline [NG188]. See https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188. Accessed on 08 December 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n1648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Cruz RF, Waller MD, Perrin F, Periselneris J, Norton S, Smith LJ, Patrick T, Walder D, Heitmann A, Lee K, Madula R, Mcnulty W, Macedo P, Lyall R, Warwick G, Galloway JB, Birring SS, Patel A, Patel I, Jolley CJ. Chest radiography is a poor predictor of respiratory symptoms and functional impairment in survivors of severe COVID-19 pneumonia. ERJ Open Res. 2021;7(1):00655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7585700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33575312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datta SD, Talwar A, Lee JT. A proposed framework and timeline of the spectrum of disease due to SARS-CoV-2 infection: illness beyond acute infection and public health implications. JAMA. 2020;324:2251&#x2013;2252. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.22717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.22717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33206133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Leeuw E, Van Damme KFA, Declercq J, Bosteels C, Maes B, Tavernier SJ, Detalle L, Smart T, Glatt S, Debeuf N, Deckers J, Lameire S, Vandecasteele SJ, de Neve N, Demedts IK, Govaerts E, Knoop C, Vanhove K, Moutschen M, Terryn W, Depuydt P, Van Braeckel E, Haerynck F, Hendrickx TCJ, Parrein V, Lalla M, Brittain C, Lambrecht BN. Efficacy and safety of the investigational complement C5 inhibitor zilucoplan in patients hospitalized with COVID-19: an open-label randomized controlled trial. Respir Res. 2022 doi: 10.1186/s12931-022-02126-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-022-02126-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9361275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35945604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Alberts J, Oben J, Cuthbertson DJ, Wootton D, Crooks M, Gabbay M, Brady M, Hishmeh L, Attree E, Heightman M, Banerjee R, Banerjee A. Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e048391. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2020-048391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-048391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-De-las-pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Florencio LL. Defining post-COVID symptoms (post-acute COVID, long COVID, persistent post-COVID): an integrative classification. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(5):2621. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18052621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18052621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-De-las-pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Florencio LL, Cuadrado ML, Plaza-Manzano G, Navarro-Santana M. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Intern Med. 2021;92:55&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1016/j.ejim.2021.06.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejim.2021.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34167876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C. Long COVID: current definition. Infection. 2022;50:285&#x2013;286. doi: 10.1007/s15010-021-01696-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s15010-021-01696-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8438555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34519974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaylis NB, Ritter A, Kelly SA, Pourhassan NZ, Tiwary M, Sacha JB, Hansen SG, Recknor C, Yang OO. Reduced cell surface levels of C-C chemokine receptor 5 and immunosuppression in long coronavirus disease 2019 syndrome. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;75:1232&#x2013;1234. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciac226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciac226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9383814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35452519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, Walshaw C, Kemp S, Corrado J, Singh R, Collins T, O'Connor RJ, Sivan M. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93(2):1013&#x2013;1022. doi: 10.1002/jmv.26368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammond J, Leister-Tebbe H, Gardner A, Abreu P, Bao W, Wisemandle W, Baniecki M, Hendrick VM, Damle B, Sim&#xf3;n-Campos A, Pypstra R, Rusnak JM. Oral nirmatrelvir for high-risk, nonhospitalized adults with Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2022;386:1397&#x2013;1408. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2118542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2118542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8908851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35172054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayk Bernal A, da GomesSilva MM, Musungaie DB, Kovalchuk E, Gonzalez A, Delos Reyes V, Mart&#xed;n-Quir&#xf3;s A, Caraco Y, Williams-Diaz A, Brown ML, Du J, Pedley A, Assaid C, Strizki J, Grobler JA, Shamsuddin HH, Tipping R, Wan H, Paschke A, Butterton JR, Johnson MG, de Anda C. Molnupiravir for oral treatment of Covid-19 in nonhospitalized patients. N Engl J Med. 2022;386:509&#x2013;520. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2116044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2116044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8693688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34914868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labos C (2022) How to Reduce Risk of Getting Long COVID A new study suggests that having had two or three COVID vaccinations helps protect those who get COVID from developing persistent symptoms. Montreal Gazette. https://montrealgazette.com/opinion/columnists/christopher-labos-how-to-reduce-risk-of-getting-long-covid. Accessed on 11 February 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledford H. Do vaccines protect against long COVID? What the data say. Nature. 2021;599:546&#x2013;548. doi: 10.1038/d41586-021-03495-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/d41586-021-03495-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34815580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledford H. Long-COVID treatments: why the world is still waiting. Nature. 2022;608:258&#x2013;260. doi: 10.1038/d41586-022-02140-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/d41586-022-02140-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35945375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, Villapol S. More than 50 Long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. medRxiv. 2021;11(1):16144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milne A, Maskell S, Sharp C, Hamilton FW, Arnold DT. Impact of dexamethasone on persistent symptoms of COVID-19: an observational study. medRxiv. 2021 doi: 10.1101/2021.11.17.21266392NICE.2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.11.17.21266392NICE.2021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence: Clinical Guidelines. (2020) COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) Copyright &#xa9; NICE 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah AS, Wong AW, Hague CJ, Murphy DT, Johnston JC, Ryerson CJ, Carlsten C. A prospective study of 12-week respiratory outcomes in COVID-19-related hospitalisations. Thorax. 2021;76:402&#x2013;404. doi: 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:e102&#x2013;e107. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416&#x2013;427. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00084-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00084-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Recovery Collaborative Group Dexamethasone in Hospitalized Patients with Covid-19. New Engl J Med. 2021;384:693&#x2013;704. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2021436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2021436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32678530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasoni D, Bai F, Castoldi R, Barbanotti D, Falcinella C, Mul&#xe8; G, Mondatore D, Tavelli A, Vegni E, Marchetti G, D&#x2019;arminio Monforte A. Anxiety and depression symptoms after virological clearance of COVID-19: a cross-sectional study in Milan Italy. J Med Virol. 2021;93:1175&#x2013;1179. doi: 10.1002/jmv.26459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32841387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Burdens of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 by severity of acute infection, demographics and health status. Nat Commun. 2021;12:6571. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-26513-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-26513-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8589966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34772922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond) 2021;53:737&#x2013;754. doi: 10.1080/23744235.2021.1924397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23744235.2021.1924397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo SM, Liu TC, Motwani Y, Sim MS, Viswanathan N, Samras N, Hsu F, Wenger NS. Factors associated with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (PASC) after diagnosis of symptomatic COVID-19 in the inpatient and outpatient setting in a diverse cohort. J Gen Intern Med. 2022;37:1988&#x2013;1995. doi: 10.1007/s11606-022-07523-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-022-07523-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8989256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35391623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young TP, Erickson JS, Hattan SL, Guzy S, Hershkowitz F, Steward MD. A Single-Blind, Randomized, Placebo Controlled Study to Evaluate the Benefits and Safety of Endourage Targeted Wellness Formula C Sublingual +Drops in People with Post-Acute Coronavirus Disease 2019 Syndrome. Cannabis Cannabinoid Res. 2022 doi: 10.1089/can.2022.0135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/can.2022.0135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36252151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>