<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">34033370</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK570608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042">Postacute Coronavirus (COVID-19) Syndrome</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chippa</LastName><ForeName>Venu</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Indiana university</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aleem</LastName><ForeName>Abdul</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lehigh Valley Health Network, Allentown, USA</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anjum</LastName><ForeName>Fatima</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Temple University, Lewis Katz School of Medicine</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), the viral illness caused by the novel coronavirus SARS-CoV-2, has resulted in significant morbidity and mortality worldwide following the identification of the first cases in Wuhan, China, in December 2019. Since the evolution of the COVID-19 pandemic, significant progress has been made that has led to a better understanding of this viral illness and resulted in the development of novel therapeutics and vaccines that have changed the course of this highly transmissible viral illness. A substantial proportion of patients who recover from SARS-CoV-2-induced viral illness often report various clinical symptoms of physical, psychological, and cognitive natures despite biochemical evidence indicating the cessation of replication of SARS-CoV-2 four weeks after the initial infection.&#xa0;These symptoms were initially described by many different terms (eg, post-acute COVID-19, long-haul COVID-19, chronic COVID-19 syndrome, post-acute sequelae of COVID-19). However, with emerging data frequently describing these symptoms in patients recovering from COVID-19 across different countries, the term "long COVID" has been internationally recognized and is widely accepted to describe these symptoms. Long COVID has been reported in at least 10% of patients recovering from SARS-CoV-2 infections and possibly up to 50% to 70% of hospitalized cases.&#xa0;This condition is seen in all levels of disease severity, from asymptomatic to critically ill, but the likelihood of this condition is highly correlated with the severity of symptoms. More than 200 symptoms have been associated with this illness, with the most commonly reported clinical symptoms being malaise, dyspnea, fatigue, brain fogginess, autonomic dysfunction, headache, persistent loss of smell or taste, cough, depression, low-grade fevers, palpitations, dizziness, muscle pain, and joint pains.&#xa0;This article describes the prevalence, system-based manifestations, relevant clinical investigations, treatment, and importance of an interprofessional team approach in managing long COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s6">Histopathology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s7">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s8">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s9">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s10">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s11">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s12">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s13">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s14">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s15">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-133042" sec="article-133042.s16">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ballering AV, van Zon SKR, Olde Hartman TC, Rosmalen JGM, Lifelines Corona Research Initiative Persistence of somatic symptoms after COVID-19 in the Netherlands: an observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022 Aug 06;400(10350):452-461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9352274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35934007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Mahoney LL, Routen A, Gillies C, Ekezie W, Welford A, Zhang A, Karamchandani U, Simms-Williams N, Cassambai S, Ardavani A, Wilkinson TJ, Hawthorne G, Curtis F, Kingsnorth AP, Almaqhawi A, Ward T, Ayoubkhani D, Banerjee A, Calvert M, Shafran R, Stephenson T, Sterne J, Ward H, Evans RA, Zaccardi F, Wright S, Khunti K. The prevalence and long-term health effects of Long Covid among hospitalised and non-hospitalised populations: A systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2023 Jan;55:101762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9714474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36474804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023 Mar;21(3):133-146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonilla H, Peluso MJ, Rodgers K, Aberg JA, Patterson TF, Tamburro R, Baizer L, Goldman JD, Rouphael N, Deitchman A, Fine J, Fontelo P, Kim AY, Shaw G, Stratford J, Ceger P, Costantine MM, Fisher L, O'Brien L, Maughan C, Quigley JG, Gabbay V, Mohandas S, Williams D, McComsey GA. Therapeutic trials for long COVID-19: A call to action from the interventions taskforce of the RECOVER initiative. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1129459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10034329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36969241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perumal R, Shunmugam L, Naidoo K, Abdool Karim SS, Wilkins D, Garzino-Demo A, Brechot C, Parthasarathy S, Vahlne A, Nikolich J&#x17d;. Long COVID: a review and proposed visualization of the complexity of long COVID. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1117464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10157068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37153597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song WJ, Hui CKM, Hull JH, Birring SS, McGarvey L, Mazzone SB, Chung KF. Confronting COVID-19-associated cough and the post-COVID syndrome: role of viral neurotropism, neuroinflammation, and neuroimmune responses. Lancet Respir Med. 2021 May;9(5):533-544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8041436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33857435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlis RH, Santillana M, Ognyanova K, Safarpour A, Lunz Trujillo K, Simonson MD, Green J, Quintana A, Druckman J, Baum MA, Lazer D. Prevalence and Correlates of Long COVID Symptoms Among US Adults. JAMA Netw Open. 2022 Oct 03;5(10):e2238804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9614581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36301542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oronsky B, Larson C, Hammond TC, Oronsky A, Kesari S, Lybeck M, Reid TR. A Review of Persistent Post-COVID Syndrome (PPCS). Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2023 Feb;64(1):66-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33609255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;ncsa S, Dembrovszky F, Farkas N, Szak&#xf3; L, Teutsch B, Bunduc S, Nagy R, P&#xe1;rniczky A, Er&#x151;ss B, P&#xe9;terfi Z, Hegyi P. Repeated SARS-CoV-2 Positivity: Analysis of 123 Cases. Viruses. 2021 Mar 19;13(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8003803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33808867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A'Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020 Aug 11;370:m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghu G, Wilson KC. COVID-19 interstitial pneumonia: monitoring the clinical course in survivors. Lancet Respir Med. 2020 Sep;8(9):839-842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7398671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32758440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y, Guo Y, Zhang Y, Li F, Yu J, Zhang Y, Shen Z, Mao R, Zhu H, Zhang J. Factors affecting prolonged SARS-CoV-2 infection and development and validation of predictive nomograms. J Med Virol. 2023 Feb;95(2):e28550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36734068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoian M, Procopiescu B, &#x218;eitan S, Scarlat G. Post-COVID-19 syndrome: Insights into a novel post-infectious systemic disorder. J Med Life. 2023 Feb;16(2):195-202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10015558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36937488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders C, Sperling S, Bendstrup E. Concerns regarding a suggested long COVID paradigm - Authors' reply. Lancet Respir Med. 2023 Apr;11(4):e36-e37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36997265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Sullivan O. Long-term sequelae following previous coronavirus epidemics. Clin Med (Lond) 2021 Jan;21(1):e68-e70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33144403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>