<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36196612</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2093-2340</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Infection &amp; chemotherapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Infect Chemother</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Preliminary Guidelines for the Clinical Evaluation and Management of Long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>566</StartPage><EndPage>597</EndPage><MedlinePgn>566-597</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3947/ic.2022.0141</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long-lasting coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) symptoms beyond 12 weeks, the so-called 'long COVID' have been increasingly reported worldwide. Long COVID can be manifested in various forms, and there is an increasing demand for proper assessment and management. However, it is challenging when trying to determine the best-practice standards of care based on the current evidence because there is no internationally agreed clinical definition or clear treatment pathway. Therefore, the present guidelines have been drafted to provide advice on diagnosis and management based on the latest updated available evidence and the consensus of expert opinion. So far, no standard test and drug treatment can be strongly recommended for patients with long COVID because of a lack of evidence. The present guidelines provide advice based on 12 key questions, including appropriate interventions for long COVID that can be used in clinical practice. Continuous careful observation and studies related to long COVID are needed for the long-term impact of COVID-19 and proper management for long COVID to be determined.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 by The Korean Society of Infectious Diseases, Korean Society for Antimicrobial Therapy, and The Korean Society for AIDS.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Yoonjung</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7454-4014</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, School of Medicine, Kyungpook National University, Kyungpook National University Hospital, Daegu, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Seong Eun</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0162-6155</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Chonnam National University Medical School, Gwangju, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Tark</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8829-4183</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Divison of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Soonchunhyang University Bucheon Hospital, Bucheon, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yun</LastName><ForeName>Ki Wook</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0798-6779</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>So Hee</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9005-3207</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, National Medical Center, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Eunjung</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7724-8288</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Soonchunhyang University Seoul Hospital, Soonchunhyang University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seo</LastName><ForeName>Jun-Won</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2806-1863</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, College of Medicine, Chosun University, Gwangju, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jung</LastName><ForeName>Young Hee</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8945-2200</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Myongji Hospital, Hanyang University College of Medicine, Goyang, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chong</LastName><ForeName>Yong Pil</ForeName><Initials>YP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1672-3185</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, Asan Medical Center, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea. drchong@amc.seoul.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Infect Chemother</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101531537</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1598-8112</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Persistent symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-COVID condition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36196612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9533168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3947/ic.2022.0141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">54.566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard.  [Accessed 15 June 2022].  Available at:  https://covid19.who.int/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19.  [Accessed 15 June 2022].  Available at:  https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin D, Moschopoulos CD, Margalit I, Gkrania-Klotsas E, Landi F, Stahl JP, Yahav D. ESCMID rapid guidelines for assessment and management of long COVID. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28:955&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8849856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35182760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health (NIH) NIH launches new initiative to study &#x201c;Long COVID&#x201d;.  [Accessed 13 June 2022].  Available at:  https://covid19.nih.gov/covid-19-topics/long-covid.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re&#x2019;em Y, Redfield S, Austin JP, Akrami A. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorna R, MacDermott N, Rayner C, O&#x2019;Hara M, Evans S, Agyen L, Nutland W, Rogers N, Hastie C. Long COVID guidelines need to reflect lived experience. Lancet. 2021;397:455&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33357467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D. Office for National Statistics. Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK: 1 April 2021.  [Accessed 13 June 2022].  Available at:  https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/1april2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings G, Monaghan A, Xue F, Mockler D, Romero-Ortu&#xf1;o R. A systematic review of persistent symptoms and residual abnormal functioning following acute COVID-19: ongoing symptomatic phase vs. post-COVID-19 syndrome. J Clin Med. 2021;10:5913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8708187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34945213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacobucci G. Long covid: damage to multiple organs presents in young, low risk patients. BMJ. 2020;371:m4470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziauddeen N, Gurdasani D, O&#x2019;Hara ME, Hastie C, Roderick P, Yao G, Alwan NA. Characteristics and impact of long Covid: findings from an online survey. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0264331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8903286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35259179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Kim SW, Chang HH, Kwon KT, Bae S, Hwang S. Significance and associated factors of long-term sequelae in patients after acute COVID-19 infection in Korea. Infect Chemother. 2021;53:463&#x2013;476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8511373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34405592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Bitna-Ha, Kim SW, Chang HH, Kwon KT, Bae S, Hwang S. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome in patients after 12 months from COVID-19 infection in Korea. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22:93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8793328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35086489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Kim SW, Chang HH, Kwon KT, Hwang S, Bae S. One year follow-up of COVID-19 related symptoms and patient quality of life: a prospective cohort study. Yonsei Med J. 2022;63:499&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9171672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35619573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, Cheng V, Dagens A, Hastie C, O&#x2019;Hara M, Suett J, Dahmash D, Bugaeva P, Rigby I, Munblit D, Harriss E, Burls A, Foote C, Scott J, Carson G, Olliaro P, Sigfrid L, Stavropoulou C. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6:e005427</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera Martimbianco AL, Pacheco RL, Bagattini &#xc2;M, Riera R. Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID-19: a systematic review. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:e14357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8236920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33977626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodin P. Immune determinants of COVID-19 disease presentation and severity. Nat Med. 2021;27:28&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33442016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logue JK, Franko NM, McCulloch DJ, McDonald D, Magedson A, Wolf CR, Chu HY. Sequelae in adults at 6 months after COVID-19 infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e210830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33606031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund LC, Hallas J, Nielsen H, Koch A, Mogensen SH, Brun NC, Christiansen CF, Thomsen RW, Potteg&#xe5;rd A. Post-acute effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection in individuals not requiring hospital admission: a Danish population-based cohort study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21:1373&#x2013;1382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8110209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33984263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Bosworth ML, King S, Pouwels KB, Glickman M, Nafilyan V, Zaccardi F, Khunti K, Alwan NA, Walker AS. Risk of long Covid in people infected with SARS-CoV-2 after two doses of a COVID-19 vaccine: community-based, matched cohort study. medRxiv. 2022:2022.02.23.22271388</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9494414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36168555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Husain M, Harrison PJ. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: A 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 2021;18:e1003773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao YM, Shang YM, Song WB, Li QQ, Xie H, Xu QF, Jia JL, Li LM, Mao HL, Zhou XM, Luo H, Gao YF, Xu AG. Follow-up study of the pulmonary function and related physiological characteristics of COVID-19 survivors three months after recovery. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frija-Masson J, Debray MP, Gilbert M, Lescure FX, Travert F, Borie R, Khalil A, Crestani B, d&#x2019;Ortho MP, Bancal C. Functional characteristics of patients with SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia at 30\xe2\x80\x85days post-infection. Eur Respir J. 2020;56:2001754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32554533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo X, Jian W, Su Z, Chen M, Peng H, Peng P, Lei C, Chen R, Zhong N, Li S. Abnormal pulmonary function in COVID-19 patients at time of hospital discharge. Eur Respir J. 2020;55:2001217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32381497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B, Peters JB, Brink M, Schoon Y, Bleeker-Rovers CP, Schers H, van Hees HWH, van Helvoort H, van den Boogaard M, van der Hoeven H, Reijers MH, Prokop M, Vercoulen J, van den Heuvel M. Comprehensive health assessment 3 months after recovery from acute coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e1089&#x2013;e1098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao C, Liu X, Zhang H, Li Y, Liu J. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) CT findings: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Coll Radiol. 2020;17:701&#x2013;709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7151282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32283052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J, Zhong Z, Li H, Ji P, Pang J, Li B, Zhang J. CT imaging features of 4121 patients with COVID-19: a meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2020;92:891&#x2013;902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32314805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Casals M, Brito-Zer&#xf3;n P, Mariette X. Systemic and organ-specific immune-related manifestations of COVID-19. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2021;17:315&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33903743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patell R, Bogue T, Koshy A, Bindal P, Merrill M, Aird WC, Bauer KA, Zwicker JI. Postdischarge thrombosis and hemorrhage in patients with COVID-19. Blood. 2020;136:1342&#x2013;1346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32766883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts LN, Whyte MB, Georgiou L, Giron G, Czuprynska J, Rea C, Vadher B, Patel RK, Gee E, Arya R. Postdischarge venous thromboembolism following hospital admission with COVID-19. Blood. 2020;136:1347&#x2013;1350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32746455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C, Liu Y, Cai X, Zhang W, Li Y, Fu C. Prevalence of venous thromboembolism in critically ill patients with coronavirus disease 2019: a meta-analysis. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021;8:603558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8116594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33996843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puig-Domingo M, Marazuela M, Yildiz BO, Giustina A. COVID-19 and endocrine and metabolic diseases. An updated statement from the European Society of Endocrinology. Endocrine. 2021;72:301&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8105151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33963516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isidori AM, Arnaldi G, Boscaro M, Falorni A, Giordano C, Giordano R, Pivonello R, Pofi R, Hasenmajer V, Venneri MA, Sbardella E, Simeoli C, Scaroni C, Lenzi A. COVID-19 infection and glucocorticoids: update from the Italian Society of Endocrinology Expert Opinion on steroid replacement in adrenal insufficiency. J Endocrinol Invest. 2020;43:1141&#x2013;1147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7182741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32335855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carosi G, Morelli V, Del Sindaco G, Serban AL, Cremaschi A, Frigerio S, Rodari G, Profka E, Indirli R, Mungari R, Resi V, Orsi E, Ferrante E, Dolci A, Giavoli C, Arosio M, Mantovani G. Adrenal insufficiency at the time of COVID-19: a retrospective study in patients referring to a tertiary center. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2021;106:e1354&#x2013;e1361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33107576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubino F, Amiel SA, Zimmet P, Alberti G, Bornstein S, Eckel RH, Mingrone G, Boehm B, Cooper ME, Chai Z, Del Prato S, Ji L, Hopkins D, Herman WH, Khunti K, Mbanya JC, Renard E. New-onset diabetes in Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:789&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7304415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L, Formenti AM, Doga M, Frara S, Rovere-Querini P, Bosi E, Carlucci M, Giustina A. Hypocalcemia is a distinctive biochemical feature of hospitalized COVID-19 patients. Endocrine. 2021;71:9&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7649576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33165763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutchings N, Babalyan V, Baghdasaryan S, Qefoyan M, Sargsyants N, Aghajanova E, Martirosyan A, Harutyunyan R, Lesnyak O, Formenti AM, Giustina A, Bilezikian JP. Patients hospitalized with COVID-19 have low levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D. Endocrine. 2021;71:267&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7811339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33452994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller I, Cannavaro D, Dazzi D, Covelli D, Mantovani G, Muscatello A, Ferrante E, Orsi E, Resi V, Longari V, Cuzzocrea M, Bandera A, Lazzaroni E, Dolci A, Ceriotti F, Re TE, Gori A, Arosio M, Salvi M. SARS-CoV-2-related atypical thyroiditis. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2020;8:739&#x2013;741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brancatella A, Ricci D, Viola N, Sgr&#xf2; D, Santini F, Latrofa F. Subacute thyroiditis after Sars-COV-2 infection. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2020;105:dgaa276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7314004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32436948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236&#x2009;379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu YH, Chen Y, Wang QH, Wang LR, Jiang L, Yang Y, Chen X, Li Y, Cen Y, Xu C, Zhu J, Li W, Wang YR, Zhang LL, Liu J, Xu ZQ, Wang YJ. One-year trajectory of cognitive changes in older survivors of COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a longitudinal cohort study. JAMA Neurol. 2022;79:509&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8905512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35258587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cicco S, Vacca A, Cittadini A, Marra AM. Long-term follow-up may be useful in coronavirus disease 2019 survivors to rrevent chronic complications. Infect Chemother. 2020;52:407&#x2013;409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7533203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32757498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, Wang Q, Ren L, Wang Y, Hu P, Guo L, Liu M, Xu J, Zhang X, Qu Y, Fan Y, Li X, Li C, Yu T, Xia J, Wei M, Chen L, Li Y, Xiao F, Liu D, Wang J, Wang X, Cao B. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398:747&#x2013;758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Taylor S. NICE guideline on long covid. BMJ. 2020;371:m4938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33361141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sis&#xf3;-Almirall A, Brito-Zer&#xf3;n P, Conangla Ferr&#xed;n L, Kostov B, Moragas Moreno A, Mestres J, Sellar&#xe8;s J, Galindo G, Morera R, Basora J, Trilla A, Ramos-Casals M On Behalf Of The CAMFiC Long Covid-Study Group. Long Covid-19: proposed primary care clinical guidelines for diagnosis and disease management. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:4350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33923972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin W, Chen S, Zhang Y, Dong F, Zhang Z, Hu B, Zhu Z, Li F, Wang X, Wang Y, Zhen K, Wang J, Wan Y, Li H, Elalamy I, Li C, Zhai Z, Wang C. Diffusion capacity abnormalities for carbon monoxide in patients with COVID-19 at 3-month follow-up. Eur Respir J. 2021;58:2003677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7877322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33574077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, Kang L, Guo L, Liu M, Zhou X, Luo J, Huang Z, Tu S, Zhao Y, Chen L, Xu D, Li Y, Li C, Peng L, Li Y, Xie W, Cui D, Shang L, Fan G, Xu J, Wang G, Wang Y, Zhong J, Wang C, Wang J, Zhang D, Cao B. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallia P, Meghji J, Wong B, Kumar K, Pilkington V, Chhabra S, Russell B, Chen J, Srikanthan K, Park M, Owles H, Liew F, Alcada J, Martin L, Coleman M, Elkin S, Ross C, Agrawal S, Gardiner T, Bell A, White A, Hampson D, Vithlani G, Manalan K, Bramer S, Martin Segura A, Kucheria A, Ratnakumar P, Sheeka A, Anandan L, Copley S, Russell G, Bloom CI, Kon OM. Symptomatic, biochemical and radiographic recovery in patients with COVID-19. BMJ Open Respir Res. 2021;8:e000908</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8029037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33827856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Cruz RF, Waller MD, Perrin F, Periselneris J, Norton S, Smith LJ, Patrick T, Walder D, Heitmann A, Lee K, Madula R, McNulty W, Macedo P, Lyall R, Warwick G, Galloway JB, Birring SS, Patel A, Patel I, Jolley CJ. Chest radiography is a poor predictor of respiratory symptoms and functional impairment in survivors of severe COVID-19 pneumonia. ERJ Open Res. 2021;7:00655&#x2013;02020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7585700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33575312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT, Hamilton FW, Milne A, Morley AJ, Viner J, Attwood M, Noel A, Gunning S, Hatrick J, Hamilton S, Elvers KT, Hyams C, Bibby A, Moran E, Adamali HI, Dodd JW, Maskell NA, Barratt SL. Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up: results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax. 2021;76:399&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Froidure A, Mahsouli A, Liistro G, De Greef J, Belkhir L, G&#xe9;rard L, Bertrand A, Koenig S, Pothen L, Yildiz H, Mwenge B, Aboubakar F, Gohy S, Pilette C, Reychler G, Coche E, Yombi JC, Ghaye B. Integrative respiratory follow-up of severe COVID-19 reveals common functional and lung imaging sequelae. Respir Med. 2021;181:106383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8019490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33839588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Ramirez DC, Normand K, Zhaoyun Y, Torres-Castro R. Long-term impact of COVID-19: a systematic review of the literature and meta-analysis. Biomedicines. 2021;9:900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34440104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Cassar MP, Tunnicliffe EM, Filippini N, Griffanti L, Alfaro-Almagro F, Okell T, Sheerin F, Xie C, Mahmod M, M&#xf3;zes FE, Lewandowski AJ, Ohuma EO, Holdsworth D, Lamlum H, Woodman MJ, Krasopoulos C, Mills R, McConnell FAK, Wang C, Arthofer C, Lange FJ, Andersson J, Jenkinson M, Antoniades C, Channon KM, Shanmuganathan M, Ferreira VM, Piechnik SK, Klenerman P, Brightling C, Talbot NP, Petousi N, Rahman NM, Ho LP, Saunders K, Geddes JR, Harrison PJ, Pattinson K, Rowland MJ, Angus BJ, Gleeson F, Pavlides M, Koychev I, Miller KL, Mackay C, Jezzard P, Smith SM, Neubauer S. Medium-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on multiple vital organs, exercise capacity, cognition, quality of life and mental health, post-hospital discharge. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;31:100683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33490928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song WJ, Hui CKM, Hull JH, Birring SS, McGarvey L, Mazzone SB, Chung KF. Confronting COVID-19-associated cough and the post-COVID syndrome: role of viral neurotropism, neuroinflammation, and neuroimmune responses. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:533&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8041436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33857435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewek J, Jatczak-Pawlik I, Maciejewski M, Jankowski P, Banach M. COVID-19 and cardiovascular complications - preliminary results of the LATE-COVID study. Arch Med Sci. 2021;17:818&#x2013;822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8130484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34025853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tudoran C, Tudoran M, Pop GN, Giurgi-Oncu C, Cut TG, Lazureanu VE, Oancea C, Parv F, Ciocarlie T, Bende F. Associations between the severity of the post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and echocardiographic abnormalities in previously healthy outpatients following infection with SARS-CoV-2. Biology (Basel) 2021;10:469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8226755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34073342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayama H, Ide S, Moroi M, Kitami Y, Bekki N, Kubota S, Uemura Y, Hara H, Kutsuna S, Ohmagari N, Hiroi Y. Elevated high-sensitivity troponin is associated with subclinical cardiac dysfunction in patients recovered from coronavirus disease 2019. Glob Health Med. 2021;3:95&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8071685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33937572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnweber T, Sahanic S, Pizzini A, Luger A, Schwabl C, Sonnweber B, Kurz K, Koppelst&#xe4;tter S, Haschka D, Petzer V, Boehm A, Aichner M, Tymoszuk P, Lener D, Theurl M, Lorsbach-K&#xf6;hler A, Tancevski A, Schapfl A, Schaber M, Hilbe R, Nairz M, Puchner B, H&#xfc;ttenberger D, Tschurtschenthaler C, A&#xdf;hoff M, Peer A, Hartig F, Bellmann R, Joannidis M, Gollmann-Tepek&#xf6;yl&#xfc; C, Holfeld J, Feuchtner G, Egger A, Hoermann G, Schroll A, Fritsche G, Wildner S, Bellmann-Weiler R, Kirchmair R, Helbok R, Prosch H, Rieder D, Trajanoski Z, Kronenberg F, W&#xf6;ll E, Weiss G, Widmann G, L&#xf6;ffler-Ragg J, Tancevski I. Cardiopulmonary recovery after COVID-19: an observational prospective multicentre trial. Eur Respir J. 2021;57:2003481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma&#x142;ek &#x141;A, Marczak M, Mi&#x142;osz-Wieczorek B, Konopka M, Braksator W, Drygas W, Krzywa&#x144;ski J. Cardiac involvement in consecutive elite athletes recovered from Covid-19: a magnetic resonance study. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2021;53:1723&#x2013;1729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33474768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan C, Zhang Z, Luo L, Wu W, Jia T, Lu L, Liu WV, Qin Y, Hu F, Ding X, Qin P, Qian L, Chen J, Li S. Cardiac T1 and T2 mapping showed myocardial involvement in recovered COVID-19 patients initially considered devoid of cardiac damage. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2021;54:421&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33590944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joy G, Artico J, Kurdi H, Seraphim A, Lau C, Thornton GD, Oliveira MF, Adam RD, Aziminia N, Menacho K, Chacko L, Brown JT, Patel RK, Shiwani H, Bhuva A, Augusto JB, Andiapen M, McKnight A, Noursadeghi M, Pierce I, Evain T, Captur G, Davies RH, Greenwood JP, Fontana M, Kellman P, Schelbert EB, Treibel TA, Manisty C, Moon JC COVIDsortium investigators. Prospective case-control study of cardiovascular abnormalities 6 months following mild COVID-19 in healthcare workers. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2021;14:2155&#x2013;2166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8105493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33975819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, Billig Rose E, Shapiro NI, Files DC, Gibbs KW, Erickson HL, Steingrub JS, Smithline HA, Gong MN, Aboodi MS, Exline MC, Henning DJ, Wilson JG, Khan A, Qadir N, Brown SM, Peltan ID, Rice TW, Hager DN, Ginde AA, Stubblefield WB, Patel MM, Self WH, Feldstein LR IVY Network Investigators; CDC COVID-19 Response Team; IVY Network Investigators. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network - United States, March-June 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69:993&#x2013;998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher A, Balfanz P, Cornelissen C, M&#xfc;ller A, Bergs I, Marx N, M&#xfc;ller-Wieland D, Hartmann B, Dreher M, M&#xfc;ller T. Follow up of patients with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): Pulmonary and extrapulmonary disease sequelae. Respir Med. 2020;174:106197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33120193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosales-Castillo A, Garc&#xed;a de Los R&#xed;os C, Mediavilla Garc&#xed;a JD. Persistent symptoms after acute COVID-19 infection: importance of follow-up. Med Clin (Engl Ed) 2021;156:35&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33521308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Gemelli against COVID-19 post-acute care study group. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, Brown JS, Denneny EK, Hare SS, Heightman M, Hillman TE, Jacob J, Jarvis HC, Lipman MCI, Naidu SB, Nair A, Porter JC, Tomlinson GS, Hurst JR ARC Study Group. &#x2018;Long-COVID&#x2019;: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues E, Janvier P, Kherabi Y, Le Bot A, Hamon A, Gouze H, Doucet L, Berkani S, Oliosi E, Mallart E, Corre F, Zarrouk V, Moyer JD, Galy A, Honsel V, Fantin B, Nguyen Y. Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. J Infect. 2020;81:e4&#x2013;e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimmer A. Covid-19: impact of long term symptoms will be profound, warns BMA. BMJ. 2020;370:m3218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32816748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A&#x2019;Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020;370:m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung KI, Song CH. Clinical usefulness of fatigue severity scale for patients with fatigue, and anxiety or depression. Korean J Psychosom Med. 2001;9:164&#x2013;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, Dunne J, Mooney A, Gaffney F, O&#x2019;Connor L, Leavy D, O&#x2019;Brien K, Dowds J, Sugrue JA, Hopkins D, Martin-Loeches I, Ni Cheallaigh C, Nadarajan P, McLaughlin AM, Bourke NM, Bergin C, O&#x2019;Farrelly C, Bannan C, Conlon N. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alrubaye R, Choudhury H. Severe Rhabdomyolysis in a 35-year-old woman with COVID-19 due to SARS-CoV-2 infection: a case report. Am J Case Rep. 2020;21:e926733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7440748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32801291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan KH, Farouji I, Abu Hanoud A, Slim J. Weakness and elevated creatinine kinase as the initial presentation of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Am J Emerg Med. 2020;38:1548.e1&#x2013;1548.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32414522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husain R, Corcuera-Solano I, Dayan E, Jacobi AH, Huang M. Rhabdomyolysis as a manifestation of a severe case of COVID-19: a case report. Radiol Case Rep. 2020;15:1633&#x2013;1637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7340044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32690987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosla SG, Nylen ES, Khosla R. Rhabdomyolysis in patients hospitalized with COVID-19 infection: five case series. J Investig Med High Impact Case Rep. 2020;8:2324709620984603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7780065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33371733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sneller MC, Liang CJ, Marques AR, Chung JY, Shanbhag SM, Fontana JR, Raza H, Okeke O, Dewar RL, Higgins BP, Tolstenko K, Kwan RW, Gittens KR, Seamon CA, McCormack G, Shaw JS, Okpali GM, Law M, Trihemasava K, Kennedy BD, Shi V, Justement JS, Buckner CM, Blazkova J, Moir S, Chun TW, Lane HC. A longitudinal study of COVID-19 sequelae and immunity: baseline findings. Ann Intern Med. 2022;175:969&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9128805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35605238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos PK, Sigoli E, Bragan&#xe7;a LJG, Cornachione AS. The musculoskeletal involvement after mild to moderate COVID-19 infection. Front Physiol. 2022;13:813924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9040683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35492595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martelletti P, Bentivegna E, Spuntarelli V, Luciani M. Long-COVID headache. SN Compr Clin Med. 2021;3:1704&#x2013;1706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8136258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34036244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj L, Kannapadi NV, Briggs J, Seal SM, Battaglini D, Fanning J, Suen J, Robba C, Fraser J, Cho SM. Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: a meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci. 2022;434:120162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8798975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolay H, G&#xfc;l A, Baykan B. COVID-19 is a real headache! Headache. 2020;60:1415&#x2013;1421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32412101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Mitoma F, Vanast WJ, Tyrrell DL. Increased frequency of Epstein-Barr virus excretion in patients with new daily persistent headaches. Lancet. 1987;1:411&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2880216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozen TD. Daily persistent headache after a viral illness during a worldwide pandemic may not be a new occurrence: Lessons from the 1890 Russian/Asiatic flu. Cephalalgia. 2020;40:1406&#x2013;1409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7645599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33146034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurek M, Rayner C, Freyer A, Taylor S, J&#xe4;rte L, MacDermott N, Delaney BC Delphi panellists. Recommendations for the recognition, diagnosis, and management of long COVID: a Delphi study. Br J Gen Pract. 2021;71:e815&#x2013;e825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8510689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34607799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F, Arthofer C, Wang C, McCarthy P, Lange F, Andersson JLR, Griffanti L, Duff E, Jbabdi S, Taschler B, Keating P, Winkler AM, Collins R, Matthews PM, Allen N, Miller KL, Nichols TE, Smith SM. SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature. 2022;604:697&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9046077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Campion JY, Dudouet P, Kaphan E, Bregeon F, Tissot-Dupont H, Guis S, Barthelemy F, Habert P, Ceccaldi M, Million M, Raoult D, Cammilleri S, Eldin C. 18F-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in patients with long COVID. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48:2823&#x2013;2833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33501506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker JH, Lin JJ, Doernberg M, Stone K, Navis A, Festa JR, Wisnivesky JP. Assessment of cognitive function in patients after COVID-19 infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2130645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8536953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34677597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Thoracic Society. British Thoracic Society guidance on respiratory follow up of patients with a clinico-radiological diagnosis of COVID-19 pneumonia.  [Accessed 5 June 2022].  Available at:  https://www.brit-thoracic.org.uk/covid-19/covid-19-information-for-the-respiratory-community/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England. National commissioning guidance for post COVID services.  [Accessed 15 June 2022].  Available at:  https://allcatsrgrey.org.uk/wp/download/commissioning/C1248-national-guidance-post-covid-syndrome-assessment-clinics-v2.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonazza F, Borghi L, di San Marco EC, Piscopo K, Bai F, Monforte AD, Vegni E. Psychological outcomes after hospitalization for COVID-19: data from a multidisciplinary follow-up screening program for recovered patients. Res Psychother. 2021;23:491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33585298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong F, Liu HL, Dai N, Yang M, Liu JP. A living systematic review of the psychological problems in people suffering from COVID-19. J Affect Disord. 2021;292:172&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8169237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34126309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) Living guidance for clinical management of COVID-19.  [Accessed 10 June 2022].  Available at:  https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-clinical-2021-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Li F, Fortunati F, Krystal JH. Association of a prior psychiatric diagnosis with mortality among hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3:e2023282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7527869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32997123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourne RS, Mills GH. Sleep disruption in critically ill patients--pharmacological considerations. Anaesthesia. 2004;59:374&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15023109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosey MM, Needham DM. Survivorship after COVID-19 ICU stay. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2020;6:60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7362322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32669623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Campion JY, Horowitz T, Barthelemy F, Cammilleri S, Ceccaldi M. The impact of COVID-19 lockdown on brain metabolism. Hum Brain Mapp. 2022;43:593&#x2013;597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8720189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34636103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health (NIH) COVID-19 treatment guidelines panel. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) treatment guidelines.  [Accessed 10 June 2022].  Available at:  https://www.covid19treatmentguidelines.nih.gov/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramacciotti E, Barile Agati L, Calderaro D, Aguiar VCR, Spyropoulos AC, de Oliveira CCC, Lins Dos Santos J, Volpiani GG, Sobreira ML, Joviliano EE, Bohatch J&#xfa;nior MS, da Fonseca BAL, Ribeiro MS, Dusilek C, Itinose K, Sanches SMV, de Almeida Araujo Ramos K, de Moraes NF, Tierno PFGMM, de Oliveira ALML, Tachibana A, Chate RC, Santos MVB, de Menezes Cavalcante BB, Moreira RCR, Chang C, Tafur A, Fareed J, Lopes RD MICHELLE investigators. Rivaroxaban versus no anticoagulation for post-discharge thromboprophylaxis after hospitalisation for COVID-19 (MICHELLE): an open-label, multicentre, randomised, controlled trial. Lancet. 2022;399:50&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8673881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34921756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reina-Guti&#xe9;rrez S, Torres-Costoso A, Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no V, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez de Arenas-Arroyo S, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Rodr&#xed;guez R, Pozuelo-Carrascosa DP. Effectiveness of pulmonary rehabilitation in interstitial lung disease, including coronavirus diseases: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;102:1989&#x2013;97.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33932361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Zhang W, Yang Y, Zhang J, Li Y, Chen Y. Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: A randomized controlled study. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2020;39:101166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermann M, Pekacka-Egli AM, Witassek F, Baumgaertner R, Schoendorf S, Spielmanns M. Feasibility and efficacy of cardiopulmonary rehabilitation after COVID-19. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2020;99:865&#x2013;869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7406212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32732746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udina C, Ars J, Morandi A, Vilar&#xf3; J, C&#xe1;ceres C, Inzitari M. Rehabilitation in adult post-COVID-19 patients in post-acute care with therapeutic exercise. J Frailty Aging. 2021;10:297&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7876526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34105716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hameed F, Palatulan E, Jaywant A, Said R, Lau C, Sood V, Layton A, Gellhorn A. Outcomes of a COVID-19 recovery program for patients hospitalized with SARS-CoV-2 infection in New York City: a prospective cohort study. PM R. 2021;13:609&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33599057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Rehabilitation Center. Rehabilitation guide for patients with COVID-19 related illness.  [Accessed 20 June 2022].  Available at:  http://www.nrc.go.kr/portal/board/boardView.do?no=18152&amp;menu_cd=09_01_00_01&amp;board_id=NRC_NOTICE_BOARD&amp;bn=qnaView&amp;fno=40&amp;pageIndex=1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myall KJ, Mukherjee B, Castanheira AM, Lam JL, Benedetti G, Mak SM, Preston R, Thillai M, Dewar A, Molyneaux PL, West AG. Persistent post-COVID-19 interstitial lung disease. An observational study of corticosteroid treatment. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2021;18:799&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8086530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denneny EK, Garthwaite HS, Heightman MJ, Porter JC. A role for steroids in COVID-19-associated pneumonitis at six-week follow-up? Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2021;18:1082&#x2013;1083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8456732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33735603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P, Tahmasebi N, Gant V, Gupta R. Long COVID following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: characteristic T cell alterations and response to antihistamines. J Investig Med. 2022;70:61&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8494538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malaty J, Malaty IA. Smell and taste disorders in primary care. Am Fam Physician. 2013;88:852&#x2013;859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24364550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xydakis MS, Albers MW, Holbrook EH, Lyon DM, Shih RY, Frasnelli JA, Pagenstecher A, Kupke A, Enquist LW, Perlman S. Post-viral effects of COVID-19 in the olfactory system and their implications. Lancet Neurol. 2021;20:753&#x2013;761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8324113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addison AB, Wong B, Ahmed T, Macchi A, Konstantinidis I, Huart C, Frasnelli J, Fjaeldstad AW, Ramakrishnan VR, Rombaux P, Whitcroft KL, Holbrook EH, Poletti SC, Hsieh JW, Landis BN, Boardman J, Welge-L&#xfc;ssen A, Maru D, Hummel T, Philpott CM. Clinical Olfactory Working Group consensus statement on the treatment of postinfectious olfactory dysfunction. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2021;147:1704&#x2013;1719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelalim AA, Mohamady AA, Elsayed RA, Elawady MA, Ghallab AF. Corticosteroid nasal spray for recovery of smell sensation in COVID-19 patients: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Otolaryngol. 2021;42:102884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33429174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damm M, Pikart LK, Reimann H, Burkert S, G&#xf6;ktas &#xd6;, Haxel B, Frey S, Charalampakis I, Beule A, Renner B, Hummel T, H&#xfc;ttenbrink KB. Olfactory training is helpful in postinfectious olfactory loss: a randomized, controlled, multicenter study. Laryngoscope. 2014;124:826&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23929687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hura N, Xie DX, Choby GW, Schlosser RJ, Orlov CP, Seal SM, Rowan NR. Treatment of post-viral olfactory dysfunction: an evidence-based review with recommendations. Int Forum Allergy Rhinol. 2020;10:1065&#x2013;1086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32567798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DY, Ha JH, Lee JH, Kim HJ, Park DY. Comparing the effectiveness of olfactory training, according as type and preference of odorant. J Rhinol. 2019;26:92&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith ME, Haney E, McDonagh M, Pappas M, Daeges M, Wasson N, Fu R, Nelson HD. Treatment of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a systematic review for a National Institutes of Health pathways to prevention workshop. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162:841&#x2013;850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26075755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler-Davis S, Platts K, Thelwell M, Woodward A, Harrop D. A mixed-methods systematic review of post-viral fatigue interventions: are there lessons for long Covid? PLoS One. 2021;16:e0259533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8577752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34752489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Membrilla JA, Caronna E, Trigo-L&#xf3;pez J, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Mart&#xed;nez A, Layos-Romero A, Pozo-Rosich P, Guerrero-Peral &#xc1;, Gago-Veiga AB, Andr&#xe9;s-L&#xf3;pez A, de Ter&#xe1;n JD. Persistent headache after COVID-19: Pathophysioloy, clinic and treatment. Neurology Perspectives. 2021;1:S31&#x2013;S36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8669731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38620971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MaassenVanDenBrink A, de Vries T, Danser AHJ. Headache medication and the COVID-19 pandemic. J Headache Pain. 2020;21:38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7183387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32334535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim BS, Chung JM, Chung PW, Park KY, Ahn JY, Moon HS, Park HK, Bae DW, Seo JG, Sohn JH, Song TJ. Clinical practice guideline of pharmacologic treatment for migraine prevention in adults 2021: The committee of clinical practice guideline of the Korean Headache Society. Korean J Headache. 2021;21:56&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo Clinic. Chemo brain.  [Accessed 11 July 2022].  Available at:  https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/chemo-brain/diagnosis-treatment/drc-20351065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoharides TC, Cholevas C, Polyzoidis K, Politis A. Long-COVID syndrome-associated brain fog and chemofog: Luteolin to the rescue. Biofactors. 2021;47:232&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33847020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, Zanardi R, Palladini M, Rovere-Querini P, Benedetti F. Rapid response to selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors in post-COVID depression. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2022;54:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34634679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobile B, Durand M, Oli&#xe9; E, Guillaume S, Mol&#xe8;s JP, Haffen E, Courtet P. The anti-inflammatory effect of the tricyclic antidepressant clomipramine and its high penetration in the brain might be useful to prevent the psychiatric consequences of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Front Pharmacol. 2021;12:615695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7985338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33767623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khani E, Entezari-Maleki T. Fluvoxamine and long COVID-19; a new role for sigma-1 receptor (S1R) agonists. Mol Psychiatry. 2022 Epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8985056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35388182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo H, Kim H, Bae S, Park S, Chung H, Sung HS, Jung J, Kim MJ, Kim SH, Lee SO, Choi SH, Kim YS, Son KY, Chong YP. Fluvoxamine treatment of patients with symptomatic COVID-19 in a community treatment center: a preliminary result of randomized controlled trial. Infect Chemother. 2022;54:102&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8987178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35384422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sookaromdee P, Wiwanitkit V. Correspondence on fluvoxamine treatment of patients with symptomatic COVID-19. Infect Chemother. 2022;54:369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9259913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35706087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto Y, Suzuki T, Hashimoto K. Old drug fluvoxamine, new hope for COVID-19. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2022;272:161&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8412866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34476589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lionetto L, Ulivieri M, Capi M, De Bernardini D, Fazio F, Petrucca A, Pomes LM, De Luca O, Gentile G, Casolla B, Curto M, Salerno G, Schillizzi S, Torre MS, Santino I, Rocco M, Marchetti P, Aceti A, Ricci A, Bonfini R, Nicoletti F, Simmaco M, Borro M. Increased kynurenine-to-tryptophan ratio in the serum of patients infected with SARS-CoV2: An observational cohort study. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Basis Dis. 2021;1867:166042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33338598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas T, Stefanoni D, Reisz JA, Nemkov T, Bertolone L, Francis RO, Hudson KE, Zimring JC, Hansen KC, Hod EA, Spitalnik SL, D&#x2019;Alessandro A. COVID-19 infection alters kynurenine and fatty acid metabolism, correlating with IL-6 levels and renal status. JCI Insight. 2020;5:e140327</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7453907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32559180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ero&#x11f;lu &#x130;, Ero&#x11f;lu B&#xc7;, G&#xfc;ven GS. Altered tryptophan absorption and metabolism could underlie long-term symptoms in survivors of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Nutrition. 2021;90:111308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8087860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34111831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanares-Zapatero D, Chalon P, Kohn L, Dauvrin M, Detollenaere J, Maertens de Noordhout C, Primus-de Jong C, Cleemput I, Van den Heede K. Pathophysiology and mechanism of long COVID: a comprehensive review. Ann Med. 2022;54:1473&#x2013;1487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35594336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maamar M, Artime A, Pariente E, Fierro P, Ruiz Y, Guti&#xe9;rrez S, Tobalina M, D&#xed;az-Salazar S, Ramos C, Olmos JM, Hern&#xe1;ndez JL. Post-COVID-19 syndrome, low-grade inflammation and inflammatory markers: a cross-sectional study. Curr Med Res Opin. 2022;38:901&#x2013;909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8935459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35166141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwala SR, Vijayvargiya M, Pandey P. Avascular necrosis as a part of &#x2018;long COVID-19&#x2019;. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14:e242101</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8256728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34215639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhanuprasad K, Manesh A, Devasagayam E, Varghese L, Cherian LM, Kurien R, Karthik R, Deodhar D, Vanjare H, Peter J, Michael JS, Thomas M, Samuel P, Varghese GM. Risk factors associated with the mucormycosis epidemic during the COVID-19 pandemic. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;111:267&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8383616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34450284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossley CJ, Kavaliunaite E, Harman K, Cook J, Ruiz G, Gupta A. Post-acute COVID-19 outcomes in children requiring hospitalisation. Sci Rep. 2022;12:8208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9113067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35581348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Munblit D, Pazukhina E, Ricchiuto A, Sinatti D, Zona M, De Matteis A, D&#x2019;Ilario F, Gentili C, Lanni R, Rongai T, Del Balzo P, Fonte MT, Valente M, Zampino G, De Rose C, Sigfrid L, Valentini P FIMP-Roma. FIMP-Roma. Post-COVID condition in adults and children living in the same household in Italy: a prospective cohort study using the ISARIC global follow-up protocol. Front Pediatr. 2022;10:834875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9070551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35529336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikkenborg Berg S, Dam Nielsen S, Nygaard U, Bundgaard H, Palm P, Rotvig C, Vinggaard Christensen A. Long COVID symptoms in SARS-CoV-2-positive adolescents and matched controls (LongCOVIDKidsDK): a national, cross-sectional study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2022;6:240&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8820960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Pinto Pereira SM, Shafran R, de Stavola BL, Rojas N, McOwat K, Simmons R, Zavala M, O&#x2019;Mahoney L, Chalder T, Crawley E, Ford TJ, Harnden A, Heyman I, Swann O, Whittaker E CLoCk Consortium. Physical and mental health 3 months after SARS-CoV-2 infection (long COVID) among adolescents in England (CLoCk): a national matched cohort study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2022;6:230&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8820961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimes KA, Goodman R, Hotopf M, Wessely S, Meltzer H, Chalder T. Incidence, prognosis, and risk factors for fatigue and chronic fatigue syndrome in adolescents: a prospective community study. Pediatrics. 2007;119:e603&#x2013;e609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17332180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borch L, Holm M, Knudsen M, Ellermann-Eriksen S, Hagstroem S. Long COVID symptoms and duration in SARS-CoV-2 positive children - a nationwide cohort study. Eur J Pediatr. 2022;181:1597&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8742700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35000003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuodi P, Gorelik Y, Zayyad H, Wertheim O, Wiegler KB, Abu Jabal K, Dror AA, Nazzal S, Glikman D, Edelstein M. Association between BNT162b2 vaccination and reported incidence of post-COVID-19 symptoms: cross-sectional study 2020-21, Israel. NPJ Vaccines. 2022;7:101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9411827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36028498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>