<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36170723</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0353-5053</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>Suppl 8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Psychiatria Danubina</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Psychiatr Danub</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Educational Initiative about the COVID-19 Pandemic-Related Neuropsychiatry for Early Career Professionals in EU: The Impact of the Novel Virus on Brain, Mind, and Society.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>164</StartPage><EndPage>169</EndPage><MedlinePgn>164-169</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The COVID-19 pandemic brought challenges to governments, healthcare systems (including, mental healthcare services), clinicians and researchers in the EU and worldwide. A range of neurological (e.g., brain fog, encephalitis, myalgia) and psychiatric (e.g., affective disorders, delirium, cognitive disturbances) complications of a novel nature have been observed in patients during the acute phase of illness, which often persist as a Long-COVID state for months after the primary recovery. The pandemic has progressed to a psychodemic and syndemic, affecting communities with social distress, panic, fears, increased home violence, and protest movements that derive from conspiracy theories and hostile attitudes towards vaccination and lockdown measures. In response to this complex scenario of major social changes, universities must face the need to equip the new generation of doctors with novel special skills.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUBJECTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study course (50 hours duration; 20 lectures, three webinars, three e-discussion forums, five local seminars, two social events, three intermediate assessments and a final test for certification; bilingual Russian/English hybrid format, information materials, video-content, interactive web-page and social media) was developed by the team of the International Centre for Education and Research in Neuropsychiatry (ICERN), and is unique for the EU. The course integrates the most relevant data on SARS-Cov-2-related neuropsychiatry, and COVID-19' pandemic impact on mental health and society, including assignment of the vulnerable groups of students and healthcare professionals. The major topics covered during the course are (i) Novel virus, (ii) Brain, (iii) Society. The project takes place originally in Samara State Medical University. The ICERN Faculty includes academic staff from France, Hungary, Italy, Russia, Switzerland, invited speakers from the WHO Regional Office for Europe and World Psychiatric Association (EU Zones) members, some of them employed at ICERN by remote work contracts. The format of the educational process for students is hybrid suggesting both remote and face-to-face events. Distant learning participants and EU lecturers are to attend on-line via zoom platform, whereas local participants and staff work face-to-face in the ICERN video-conference room. The course is addressed to a broad audience of doctors, undergraduate and postgraduate students, and researchers from EU wishing to upgrade their knowledge in the pandemic-associated neuropsychiatry.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The evaluation process supposes three intermediate assessments and a final test for certification. On-line assessment is to be performed at the project web-page - 10 randomly selected questions with scoring from 1 to 10 each. The Pass Score is 70-100. At the end of the course all the participants receive certificates of Samara State Medical University according to the ERASMUS policy book, as planned in 2021.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We formatted this course as essential for the target audience to improve their resources of professional adaptability in the field of neuropsychiatry and mental healthcare management during challenging times. The ICERN course in pandemic-related neuropsychiatry is essential for early career health professionals and targets the principles of "academia without borders" in the context of international medical knowledge exchange. In the conditions of the changing social situation this educational content is necessary for the young doctors to acquire the add-on skills on flexibility to switch toward new professional approaches in the times of need. The long-term outcomes in pandemic-related neuropsychiatry are still to be seen, though the first feedback on the course content is already promising for the academic community.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kozina</LastName><ForeName>Tatiana</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Samara State Medical University, Samara, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonda</LastName><ForeName>Xenia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thibaut</LastName><ForeName>Florence</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tavormina</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borisova</LastName><ForeName>Natalia</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gorbatchev</LastName><ForeName>Dmitriy</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Protasov</LastName><ForeName>Andrey</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kolsanov</LastName><ForeName>Aleksandr</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smirnova</LastName><ForeName>Daria</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Croatia</Country><MedlineTA>Psychiatr Danub</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9424753</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0353-5053</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003140" MajorTopicYN="N">Communicable Disease Control</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058027" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuropsychiatry</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36170723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>