<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36449461</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>STIMULATE-ICP-Delphi (Symptoms, Trajectory, Inequalities and Management: Understanding Long-COVID to Address and Transform Existing Integrated Care Pathways Delphi): Study protocol.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0277936</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0277936</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0277936</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0277936</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">As mortality rates from COVID-19 disease fall, the high prevalence of long-term sequelae (Long COVID) is becoming increasingly widespread, challenging healthcare systems globally. Traditional pathways of care for Long Term Conditions (LTCs) have tended to be managed by disease-specific specialties, an approach that has been ineffective in delivering care for patients with multi-morbidity. The multi-system nature of Long COVID and its impact on physical and psychological health demands a more effective model of holistic, integrated care. The evolution of integrated care systems (ICSs) in the UK presents an important opportunity to explore areas of mutual benefit to LTC, multi-morbidity and Long COVID care. There may be benefits in comparing and contrasting ICPs for Long COVID with ICPs for other LTCs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS AND ANALYSIS">This study aims to evaluate health services requirements for ICPs for Long COVID and their applicability to other LTCs including multi-morbidity and the overlap with medically not yet explained symptoms (MNYES). The study will follow a Delphi design and involve an expert panel of stakeholders including people with lived experience, as well as clinicians with expertise in Long COVID and other LTCs. Study processes will include expert panel and moderator panel meetings, surveys, and interviews. The Delphi process is part of the overall STIMULATE-ICP programme, aimed at improving integrated care for people with Long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ETHICS AND DISSEMINATION">Ethical approval for this Delphi study has been obtained (Research Governance Board of the University of York) as have approvals for the other STIMULATE-ICP studies. Study outcomes are likely to inform policy for ICPs across LTCs. Results will be disseminated through scientific publication, conference presentation and communications with patients and stakeholders involved in care of other LTCs and Long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="REGISTRATION">Researchregistry: https://www.researchregistry.com/browse-the-registry#home/registrationdetails/6246bfeeeaaed6001f08dadc/.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2022 van der Feltz-Cornelis et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Feltz-Cornelis</LastName><ForeName>Christina M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6925-8956</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept of Health Sciences, University of York, York, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hull York Medical School, (HYMS), University of York, York, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Informatics, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sweetman</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1969-4586</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept of Health Sciences, University of York, York, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allsopp</LastName><ForeName>Gail</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal College of General Practitioners, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Health and Care Excellence, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Attree</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CCG NHS Camden, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crooks</LastName><ForeName>Michael G</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hull York Medical School, University of Hull, Hull, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hull University Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust, Hull, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cuthbertson</LastName><ForeName>Daniel J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Medicine, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forshaw</LastName><ForeName>Denise</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lancashire Clinical Trials Unit, University of Central Lancashire, Preston, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gabbay</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Primary Care &amp; Mental Health, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR ARC NWC, Liverpool, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Green</LastName><ForeName>Angela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hull University Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust, Hull, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heightman</LastName><ForeName>Melissa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, University College London Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hillman</LastName><ForeName>Toby</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, University College London Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCL Respiratory, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hishmeh</LastName><ForeName>Lyth</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5851-2904</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Long COVID SOS, Oxford, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khunti</LastName><ForeName>Kamlesh</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diabetes Research Centre, College of Life Sciences, University of Leicester, Leicester, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lip</LastName><ForeName>Gregory Y H</ForeName><Initials>GYH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liverpool Centre for Cardiovascular Science at University of Liverpool, Liverpool John Moores University and Liverpool Heart &amp; Chest Hospital, Liverpool, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Aalborg University, Aalborg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lorgelly</LastName><ForeName>Paula</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Population Health and Department of Economics, University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Epidemiology and Health Care, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Montgomery</LastName><ForeName>Hugh</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strain</LastName><ForeName>W David</ForeName><Initials>WD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diabetes and Vascular Medicine Research Centre, Institute of Biomedical and Clinical Science and College of Medicine and Health, University of Exeter, Exeter, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wall</LastName><ForeName>Emma</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2732-4497</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Francis Crick Institute, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Health Research (NIHR) University College London Hospitals (UCLH) Biomedical Research Centre and NIHR UCLH Clinical Research Facility, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watkins</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9403-3772</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lancashire Clinical Trials Unit, University of Central Lancashire, Preston, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Care, University of Central Lancashire, Preston, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Williams</LastName><ForeName>Nefyn</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8078-409X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Primary Care &amp; Mental Health, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wootton</LastName><ForeName>Dan G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Infection Veterinary and Ecological Sciences and NIHR HPRU in Emerging and Zoonotic Infections, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liverpool University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Liverpool, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banerjee</LastName><ForeName>Amitava</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Informatics, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University College London Hospitals NHS Trust, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>STIMULATE-ICP Consortium</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019091" MajorTopicYN="N">Critical Pathways</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008603" MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019033" MajorTopicYN="Y">Delivery of Health Care, Integrated</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>CFC received travel and accommodation in UK for lectures from The Lloyd Register Foundation and honoraries from Janssen UK. EA is clinical lead in a Quality Improvement Support Team for Central Camden PCN. MGC has received grants, fees and/or non-financial support from the National Institute for Health and Care Research, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, GlaxoSmithKline, Philips and Pfizer. As ARC director MG is funded by NIHR Applied Research Collaboration North West Coast. TH received travel and accommodation in UK to facilitate a talk for Multiple Sclerosis Debating Society and an honorarium payment related to the Acute and General Medicine Conference. GL is Consultant and speaker for BMS/Pfizer, Boehringer Ingelheim and Daiichi-Sankyo; no fees are received personally. HM has received funding from AstraZeneca related to use of monoclonal antibodies in acute COVID-19 treatment, from Millfield Medical in relation to the development of a new CPAP machine for use in hypoxic ventilatory failure, and from Axcella Health Inc about possible new therapeutics. He has delivered paid lectures to legal groups about Long Covid, received support to attend meetings as part of consultancy for AstraZeneca, participated on advisory boards for AstraZeneca and Axcella Health. HM has been involved as Chair, UK National Covid Critical Care Committee; Trustee, UK Intensive Care Society and has stock options with Millfield Medical Ltd. WDS has received research grants from AstraZeneca, Bayer, Novartis, Novo Nordisk and Takeda, and speaker and/or advisory board honoraria from AstraZeneca, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, Janssen, Merck, Mundi-Pharma, Napp, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Pfizer, Sanofi Aventis, Servier and Takeda. DJC has received investigator-initiated research funding, conference and/or consultancy fees from NovoNordisk, Astra Zeneca and Ipsen. CW has had recent involvement with nine UK-based grants, has contributed to five advisory boards and been involved with six project groups or committees in a leadership or fiduciary capacity. CW has been involved with six NIHR collaborations/projects, of which STIMULATE-ICP is one. NW is a member of NIHR HTA Programme Funding Committee (commissioned research). DGW is supported by an NIHR Advanced Fellowship; University of Liverpool receives an NHS hourly rate for his consultancy work with an NHS Advancing Quality Alliance programme; he has no conflicts of interest. All other authors have no conflicts of interest to report. This does not alter our adherence to PLOS ONE policies on sharing data and materials.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36449461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9710789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0277936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-22-23562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gerotziafas GT, Catalano M, Theodorou Y, Van Dreden P, Marechal V, Spyropoulos AC, et al.. The COVID-19 pandemic and the need for an integrated and equitable approach: an international expert consensus paper. Thrombosis and Haemostasis. 2021;121(08):992&#x2013;1007. doi: 10.1055/a-1535-8807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1535-8807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8322591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34169495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The King&#x2019;s Fund. Long-term conditions and multi-morbidity 2022 [Available from: https://www.kingsfund.org.uk/projects/time-think-differently/trends-disease-and-disability-long-term-conditions-multi-morbidity#:~:text=Long%2Dterm%20conditions%20or%20chronic,pulmonary%20disease%2C%20arthritis%20and%20hypertension.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19 2022 [Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188/resources/covid19-rapid-guideline-managing-the-longterm-effects-of-covid19-pdf-51035515742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021
2021.  [Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England, NHS Improvement. National Guidance for post-COVID syndrome assessment clinics: NHS England and NHS Improvement; 2021 [updated 26.04.2021. Version 2:[Available from: https://www.england.nhs.uk/coronavirus/wp-content/uploads/sites/52/2020/11/C1248-national-guidance-post-covid-syndrome-assessment-clinics-v2.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, McAuley H, Harrison EM, Shikotra A, Singapuri A, Sereno M, et al.. Physical, cognitive, and mental health impacts of COVID-19 after hospitalisation (PHOSP-COVID): a UK multicentre, prospective cohort study. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine. 2021;9(11):1275&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00383-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00383-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34627560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ONS. Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK: 3 March 2022 2022 [Available from: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/3march2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell H, Hotchkiss R, Bradshaw N, Porteous M. Integrated care pathways. British Medical Journal. 1998;316(7125):133&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1136/bmj.316.7125.133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.316.7125.133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2665398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9462322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plishka CT, Rotter T, Penz ED, Hansia MR, Fraser S-KA, Marciniuk DD, et al.. Effects of clinical pathways for COPD on patient, professional, and systems outcomes: a systematic review. Chest. 2019;156(5):864&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1016/j.chest.2019.04.131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2019.04.131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31150639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxter S, Johnson M, Chambers D, Sutton A, Goyder E, Booth A. Understanding new models of integrated care in developed countries: a systematic review. Health Services and Delivery Research. 2018;6(29).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30148581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell GK, Burridge L, Zhang J, Donald M, Scott IA, Dart J, et al.. Systematic review of integrated models of health care delivered at the primary&#x2013;secondary interface: how effective is it and what determines effectiveness? Australian Journal of Primary Health. 2015;21(4):391&#x2013;408. doi: 10.1071/PY14172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/PY14172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26329878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitty CJ, MacEwen C, Goddard A, Alderson D, Marshall M, Calderwood C, et al.. Rising to the challenge of multimorbidity. British Medical Journal; 2020; 368: l6964. doi: 10.1136/bmj.l6964</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.l6964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7190283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31907164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH, Crooks MG. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;199(2):113&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1007/s00408-021-00423-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00408-021-00423-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James Lind Alliance. Medically Not Yet Explained Symptoms 2022 [Available from: https://www.jla.nihr.ac.uk/priority-setting-partnerships/medically-not-yet-explained-symptoms/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefano GB. Historical insight into infections and disorders associated with neurological and psychiatric sequelae similar to long COVID. Medical Science Monitor. 2021;27:e931447&#x2013;1. doi: 10.12659/MSM.931447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.931447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7924007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33633106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miskowiak K, Johnsen S, Sattler S, Nielsen S, Kunalan K, Rungby J, et al.. Cognitive impairments four months after COVID-19 hospital discharge: pattern, severity and association with illness variables. European Neuropsychopharmacology. 2021;46:39&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.03.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.03.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33823427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoharides TC, Cholevas C, Polyzoidis K, Politis A. Long&#x2010;COVID syndrome&#x2010;associated brain fog and chemofog: Luteolin to the rescue. Biofactors. 2021;47(2):232&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1002/biof.1726</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/biof.1726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33847020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham EL, Clark JR, Orban ZS, Lim PH, Szymanski AL, Taylor C, et al.. Persistent neurologic symptoms and cognitive dysfunction in non&#x2010;hospitalized Covid&#x2010;19 &#x201c;long haulers&#x201d;. Annals of Clinical and Translational Neurology. 2021;8(5):1073&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33755344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varatharaj A, Thomas N, Ellul MA, Davies NW, Pollak TA, Tenorio EL, et al.. Neurological and neuropsychiatric complications of COVID-19 in 153 patients: a UK-wide surveillance study. The Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;7(10):875&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30287-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30287-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7316461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32593341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellul MA, Benjamin L, Singh B, Lant S, Michael BD, Easton A, et al.. Neurological associations of COVID-19. The Lancet Neurology. 2020;19(9):767&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30221-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30221-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7332267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32622375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Harrison PJ. Bidirectional associations between COVID-19 and psychiatric disorder: retrospective cohort studies of 62 354 COVID-19 cases in the USA. The Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8(2):130&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30462-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30462-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S, Gomes J. Neuropathogenesis of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Elife. 2020;9:e59136. doi: 10.7554/eLife.59136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.59136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo MS, Malsy J, P&#xf6;ttgen J, Seddiq Zai S, Ufer F, Hadjilaou A, et al.. Frequent neurocognitive deficits after recovery from mild COVID-19. Brain Communications. 2020;2(2):fcaa205. doi: 10.1093/braincomms/fcaa205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/braincomms/fcaa205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33376990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, Brown JS, Denneny EK, Hare SS, et al.. &#x2018;Long-COVID&#x2019;: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76(4):396&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-215818</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-215818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royal College of Physicians. Outpatients: the future&#x2014;adding value through sustainability. London: RCP; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Gonz&#xe1;lez NA, Berchtold P, Ullman K, Busato A, Egger M. Integrated care programmes for adults with chronic conditions: a meta-review. International Journal for Quality in Health Care. 2014;26(5):561&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1093/intqhc/mzu071</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzu071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4195469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25108537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin N, Smith J, Davies A, Perry C, Rosen R, Dixon A, et al.. Integrated care for patients and populations: improving outcomes by working together. London: King&#x2019;s Fund. 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS. Long COVID patients to get help at more than 60 clinics 2020 [Available from: https://www.england.nhs.uk/2020/12/long-covid-patients-to-get-help-at-more-than-60-clinics/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE. Scenario: Community-acquired pneumonia 2021 [Available from: https://cks.nice.org.uk/topics/chest-infections-adult/management/community-acquired-pneumonia/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidu S, Davies M, Farooqi A, Khunti K. Integrated primary care: is this the solution to the diabetes epidemic? Diabetic Medicine. 2017; 34(6):748&#x2013;750. doi: 10.1111/dme.13348</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dme.13348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28294386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wootton DG, Dickinson L, Pertinez H, Eneje O, Keogan L, Macfarlane L, et al.. A longitudinal modelling study estimates acute symptoms of community acquired pneumonia recover to baseline by 10 days. European Respiratory Journal. 2017;49(6). doi: 10.1183/13993003.02170-2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02170-2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5898948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28619956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel GL. The need for a new medical model: a challenge for biomedicine. Science. 1977;196(4286):129&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1126/science.847460</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.847460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">847460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>STIMULATE-ICP. STIMULATE-ICP 2022 [Available from: https://www.stimulate-icp.org/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NIHR. &#xa3;19.6 million awarded to new research studies to help diagnose and treat long COVID 2021 [Available from: https://www.nihr.ac.uk/news/196-million-awarded-to-new-research-studies-to-help-diagnose-and-treat-long-covid/28205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adler M, Ziglio E. Gazing into the oracle: The Delphi method and its application to social policy and public health: Jessica Kingsley Publishers; 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalkey N, Helmer O. An experimental application of the Delphi method to the use of experts. Management Science. 1963;9(3):458&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wykes T, Haro JM, Belli SR, Obradors-Tarrag&#xf3; C, Arango C, Ayuso-Mateos JL, et al.. Mental health research priorities for Europe. The Lancet Psychiatry. 2015;2(11):1036&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(15)00332-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(15)00332-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26404415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowe G, Wright G. Expert opinions in forecasting: the role of the Delphi technique. Principles of Forecasting: Springer; 2001. p. 125&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Meyrick J. The Delphi method and health research. Health Education. 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg D, Huxley P. Mental illness in the community: the pathway to psychiatric care London. New York, Tavistock. 1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon GE. Improving the filter between primary and secondary care for mental disorders. World Psychiatry. 2003;2(3):158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1525096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16946922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scordo KA, Richmond MM, Munro N. Post&#x2013;COVID-19 syndrome: theoretical basis, identification, and management. AACN Advanced Critical Care. 2021;32(2):188&#x2013;94. doi: 10.4037/aacnacc2021492</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4037/aacnacc2021492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33942071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Florencio LL, Cuadrado ML, Plaza-Manzano G, et al.. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: A systematic review and meta-analysis. European Journal of Internal Medicine. 2021;92:55&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1016/j.ejim.2021.06.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejim.2021.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34167876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menchetti M, Murri MB, Bertakis K, Bortolotti B, Berardi D. Recognition and treatment of depression in primary care: effect of patients&#x2019; presentation and frequency of consultation. Journal of Psychosomatic Research. 2009;66(4):335&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1016/j.jpsychores.2008.10.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2008.10.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19302892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutting PA, Rost K, Dickinson M, Werner JJ, Dickinson P, Smith JL, et al.. Barriers to initiating depression treatment in primary care practice. Journal of General Internal Medicine. 2002;17(2):103&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1046/j.1525-1497.2002.10128.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1525-1497.2002.10128.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1495010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11841525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaen CR, Stange KC, Nutting PA. Competing demands of primary care: a model for the delivery of clinical preventive services. Journal of Family Practice. 1994;38(2):166&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8308509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England. Long COVID: the NHS plan for 2021/22 2021 [Available from: https://www.england.nhs.uk/coronavirus/wp-content/uploads/sites/52/2021/06/C1312-long-covid-plan-june-2021.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS. The NHS Long Term Plan 2019 [Available from: https://www.longtermplan.nhs.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/nhs-long-term-plan-june-2019.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS. NHS England&#x2019;s work on stroke [Available from: https://www.england.nhs.uk/ourwork/clinical-policy/stroke/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS. Long term conditions 2022 [Available from: https://www.england.nhs.uk/ourwork/clinical-policy/ltc/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS. Cardiovascular disease (CVD) [Available from: https://www.england.nhs.uk/ourwork/clinical-policy/cvd/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS. Respiratory disease [Available from: https://www.england.nhs.uk/ourwork/clinical-policy/respiratory-disease/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EQ-5D. EQ-5D-5L User Guide, 2019 2019 [Available from: https://euroqol.org/publications/user-guides.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB. The PHQ&#x2010;9: validity of a brief depression severity measure. Journal of General Internal Medicine. 2001;16(9):606&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1495268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11556941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam RW, Lamy F-X, Danchenko N, Yarlas A, White MK, Rive B, et al.. Psychometric validation of the Perceived Deficits Questionnaire-Depression (PDQ-D) instrument in US and UK respondents with major depressive disorder. Neuropsychiatric Disease and Treatment. 2018;14:2861. doi: 10.2147/NDT.S175188</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S175188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6211374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30464471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michielsen HJ, De Vries J, Van Heck GL. Psychometric qualities of a brief self-rated fatigue measure: The Fatigue Assessment Scale. Journal of Psychosomatic Research. 2003;54(4):345&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1016/s0022-3999(02)00392-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0022-3999(02)00392-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12670612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mundt JC, Marks IM, Shear MK, Greist JM. The Work and Social Adjustment Scale: a simple measure of impairment in functioning. The British Journal of Psychiatry. 2002;180(5):461&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1192/bjp.180.5.461</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.180.5.461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11983645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JB, L&#xf6;we B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Archives of Internal Medicine. 2006;166(10):1092&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16717171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware JE, Kosinski M, Turner-Bowker D, Gandek B. How to score version 2 of the SF-12 (r) health survey. Lincoln, RI: Quality Metric. Inc, October. 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broadbent DE, Cooper PF, FitzGerald P, Parkes KR. The cognitive failures questionnaire (CFQ) and its correlates. British Journal of Clinical Psychology. 1982;21(1):1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1111/j.2044-8260.1982.tb01421.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.2044-8260.1982.tb01421.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7126941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qualtrics. Qualtrics. Provo, Utah, USA2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiCicco&#x2010;Bloom B, Crabtree BF. The qualitative research interview. Medical Education. 2006;40(4):314&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16573666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britten N. Qualitative research: qualitative interviews in medical research. British Medical Journal. 1995;311(6999):251&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2550292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7627048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archibald MM, Ambagtsheer RC, Casey MG, Lawless M. Using zoom videoconferencing for qualitative data collection: perceptions and experiences of researchers and participants. International Journal of Qualitative Methods. 2019;18:1609406919874596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qualitative Research in Psychology. 2006;3(2):77&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V, Hayfield N. &#x2018;A starting point for your journey, not a map&#x2019;: Nikki Hayfield in conversation with Virginia Braun and Victoria Clarke about thematic analysis. Qualitative Research in Psychology. 2019:1&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams S. Chronic illness as biographical disruption or biographical disruption as chronic illness? Reflections on a core concept. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness. 2000;22(1):40&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly MP, Field D. Medical sociology, chronic illness and the body. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness. 1996;18(2):241&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>