<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36606602</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>ACE2 PET to reveal the dynamic patterns of ACE2 recovery in an infection model with pseudocorona virus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e28470</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e28470</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.28470</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, a series of sequelae, such as fatigue, tachypnea, and ageusia, appeared in long COVID patients, but the pathological basis was still uncertain. The targeted radiopharmaceuticals were of potential to systemically and dynamically trace the pathological changes. For the key ACE2 protein in the virus-host interaction, <sup>68</sup> Ga-cyc-DX600 was developed on the basis of DX600 as a PET tracer of ACE2 fluctuation and maintained the ability in differentiating ACE and ACE2. In the temporary infection model inhaled with the radio-traceable pseudovirus in the upper respiratory tract of male humanized ACE2 (hACE2) mice, organ-specific ACE2 dysfunction in acute period and the following ACE2 recovery in a relatively long period was visualized and quantified by ACE2 PET, revealing a complex pattern of virus concentration-dependent degree and time period-dependent tendency of ACE2 recovery, mainly a sudden decrease of apparent ACE2 in the heart, liver, kidneys, lungs, and so on, but the liver was of a quick functional compensation on ACE2 expression after a temporary decrease. ACE2 expression of most organs has recovered to a normal level at 15 days post inhalation, with brain and genitals still of a decreased SUV<sub>ACE2</sub> ;&#xa0; meanwhile, kidneys were of an increased SUV<sub>ACE2</sub> . These findings on ACE2 PET were further verified by western blot. When compared with high-resolution computed tomography on structural changes and FDG PET on glycometabolism, ACE2 PET was superior in an earlier diagnostic window during infection and more comprehensive understanding of functional dysfunction post-infection. In the respective ACE2 PET/CT and ACE2 PET/MR scans of a volunteer, the repeatability of SUV<sub>ACE2</sub> and the ACE2 specificity were further confirmed. In conclusion, <sup>68</sup> Ga-cyc-DX600 was developed as an ACE2-specific tracer, and the corresponding ACE2 PET revealed the dynamic patterns of functional ACE2 recovery and provided a reference and approach to explore the ACE2-related pathological basis of sequelae in long COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Applied Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Shanghai Changhai Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Shanghai Changhai Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ao</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Shanghai Changhai Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Danni</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Shanghai Changhai Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Xiaolong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Luodian Hospital, Baoshan District, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ruizhi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Huadong Hospital, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Shanghai Changhai Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qiu</LastName><ForeName>Shuang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Shanghai Changhai Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Rou</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Shanghai Changhai Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Lina</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Applied Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Changjing</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Shanghai Changhai Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Lan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Applied Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Huadong Hospital, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.4.15.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007703">Peptidyl-Dipeptidase A</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.4.17.23</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000085962">Angiotensin-Converting Enzyme 2</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007703" MajorTopicYN="N">Peptidyl-Dipeptidase A</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000085962" MajorTopicYN="N">Angiotensin-Converting Enzyme 2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072078" MajorTopicYN="N">Positron Emission Tomography Computed Tomography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">68Ga-cyc-DX600</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACE2 PET</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corona virus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sequelae</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36606602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Priyanka, Choudhary OP, Singh I, Patra G. Aerosol transmission of SARS-CoV-2: The unresolved paradox. Travel Med Infect Dis. 2020;37:101869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daines L, Zheng B, Pfeffer P, Hurst JR, Sheikh A. A clinical review of long-COVID with a focus on the respiratory system. Curr Opin Pulm Med. 2022;28(3):174-179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KGI, Brokstad KA, et al. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med. 2021;27(9):1607-1613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Self-reported long COVID after infection with the Omicron variant in the UK.&#xa0;Office for National Statistics. 2022.&#xa0;Accessed June 7, 2022.&#xa0;https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/selfreportedlongcovidafterinfectionwiththeomicronvariant/6may2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK.&#xa0;Office for National Statistics. 2022.&#xa0;Accessed June 7, 2022.&#xa0;https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/6may2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull-Otterson L, Baca S, Saydah S, et al. Post-COVID conditions among adult COVID-19 survivors aged 18-64 and &#x2265;65 years-United States, March 2020-November 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71(21):713-717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M. Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nat&#xa0;Immunol. 2022;23(2):194-202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrotta F, Matera MG, Cazzola M, Bianco A. Severe respiratory SARS-CoV2 infection: does ACE2 receptor matter? Respir Med. 2020;168:105996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaddam R, Chambers S, Bhatia M. ACE and ACE2 in inflammation: a tale of two enzymes. Inflamm&#xa0;Allergy Drug Targets. 2014;13(4):224-234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong P, Xu J, Yang D, et al. COVID-19-associated gastrointestinal and liver injury: clinical features and potential mechanisms. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2020;5:256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickers C, Hales P, Kaushik V, et al. Hydrolysis of biological peptides by human angiotensin-converting enzyme-related carboxypeptidase. J Biol Chem. 2002;277(17):14838-14843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon J-Y. ACE2 and Angiotensin-(1-7) in hypertensive renal disease. Electrolyte&#xa0;Blood Press. 2011;9(2):41-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagil Y, Yagil C. Hypothesis: ACE2 modulates blood pressure in the mammalian organism. Hypertension. 2003;41(4):871-873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gheblawi M, Wang K, Viveiros A, et al. Angiotensin-converting enzyme 2: SARS-CoV-2 receptor and regulator of the renin-angiotensin system. Circ Res. 2020;126(10):1456-1474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morganstein T, Haidar Z, Trivlidis J, et al. Involvement of the ACE2/Ang-(1-7)/MasR axis in pulmonary fibrosis: implications for COVID-19. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(23):12955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F, et al. SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature. 2022;604(7907):697-707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousefi-Koma A, Haseli S, Bakhshayeshkaram M, Raad N, Karimi-Galougahi M. Multimodality imaging with PET/CT and MRI reveals hypometabolism in tertiary olfactory cortex in parosmia of COVID-19. Acad&#xa0;Radiol. 2021;28(5):749-751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morand A, Campion JY, Lepine A, et al. Similar patterns of [18F]-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in paediatric and adult patients with long COVID: a paediatric case series. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2022;49(3):913-920.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sollini M, Morbelli S, Ciccarelli M, et al. Long COVID hallmarks on [18F]FDG-PET/CT: a case-control study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48(10):3187-3197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontana IC, Souza DG, Pellerin L, Souza DO, Zimmer ER. About the source and consequences of 18F-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in short and long COVID-19. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48(9):2674-2675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontana IC, Bongarzone S, Gee A, Souza DO, Zimmer ER. PET imaging as a tool for assessing COVID-19 brain changes. Trends Neurosci. 2020;43(12):935-938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E, Zhang C, Israelow B, et al. Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 in human and mouse brain. J Exp Med. 2021;218(3):e20202135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi S, Balasubramanian N, Vasam G, Jarajapu YP. Angiotensin converting enzyme versus angiotensin converting enzyme-2 selectivity of MLN-4760 and DX600 in human and murine bone marrow-derived cells. Eur J Pharmacol. 2016;774:25-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dales NA, Gould AE, Brown JA, et al. Substrate-based design of the first class of angiotensin-converting enzyme-related carboxypeptidase (ACE2) inhibitors. J Am Chem Soc. 2002;124(40):11852-11853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao K, Sikkema D, Wang C, Lee TN. Development of an enzymatic assay for the detection of neutralizing antibodies against therapeutic angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2). J Immunol Methods. 2013;389(1-2):52-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rysz S, Al-Saadi J, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m A, et al. COVID-19 pathophysiology may be driven by an imbalance in the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):2417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat&#xa0;Med. 2022;28(3):583-590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Risks and burdens of incident diabetes in long COVID: a cohort study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2022;10(5):311-321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oronsky B, Larson C, Hammond TC, et al. A review of persistent post-COVID syndrome (PPCS). Clin&#xa0;Rev&#xa0;Allergy Immunol. 2021;20:1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khazaal S, Harb J, Rima M, et al. The pathophysiology of long COVID throughout the renin-angiotensin system. Molecules. 2022;27(9):2903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Y, Lv L, Li P, Zhang L. Inhibition of endocytic recycling of ACE2 by SARS-CoV-2 S protein partially explains multiple COVID-19 related diseases caused by ACE2 reduction. J Infect. 2022;85(1):e21-e23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields BKK, Demirjian NL, Dadgar H, Gholamrezanezhad A. Imaging of COVID-19: CT, MRI, and PET. Semin Nucl Med. 2021;51(4):312-320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruso D, Guido G, Zerunian M, et al. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 pneumonia: six-month chest CT follow-up. Radiology. 2021;301(2):E396-E405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vorster M, Sathekge MM, Bomanji J. Advances in imaging of tuberculosis: the role of 18F-FDG PET and PET/CT. Curr Opin Pulm Med. 2014;20(3):287-293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Victorio CBL, Ong J, Tham JY, et al. Preclinical evaluation of [18F]FDG-PET as a biomarker of lymphoid tissue disease and inflammation in Zika virus infection. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2022;49(13):4516-4528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katal S, Amini H, Gholamrezanezhad A. PET in the diagnostic management of infectious/inflammatory pulmonary pathologies: a revisit in the era of COVID-19. Nucl Med Commun. 2021;42(1):3-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eibschutz LS, Rabiee B, Asadollahi S, et al. FDG-PET/CT of COVID-19 and other lung infections. Semin Nucl Med. 2022;52(1):61-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M, Kleine-Weber H, Schroeder S, et al. SARS-CoV-2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and is blocked by a clinically proven protease inhibitor. Cell. 2020;181(2):271-280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung ML, Teng JLL, Jia L, et al. Soluble ACE2-mediated cell entry of SARS-CoV-2 via interaction with proteins related to the renin-angiotensin system. Cell. 2021;184(8):2212-2228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amor S, Fern&#xe1;ndez Blanco L, Baker D. Innate immunity during SARS-CoV-2: evasion strategies and activation trigger hypoxia and vascular damage. Clin Exp Immunol. 2020;202(2):193-209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen D, Krauthammer SH, Wolf I, Even-Sapir E. Hypermetabolic lymphadenopathy following administration of BNT162b2 mRNA Covid-19 vaccine: incidence assessed by [18F]FDG PET-CT and relevance to study interpretation. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48(6):1854-1863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshet Y, Tau N, Alhoubani Y, Kanana N, Domachevsky L, Eifer M. Prevalence of increased FDG PET/CT axillary lymph node uptake beyond 6 weeks after mRNA COVID-19 vaccination. Radiology. 2021;300(3):E345-E347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treglia G, Cuzzocrea M, Giovanella L, Elzi L, Muoio B. Prevalence and significance of hypermetabolic lymph nodes detected by 2-[18F]FDG PET/CT after COVID-19 vaccination: a systematic review and a meta-analysis. Pharmaceuticals. 2021;14(8):762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui DS, Tsang KW. SARS: sequelae and implications for rehabilitation. In: Hodgens A, Gupta V, eds. Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd; 2005:36-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V Jagtap S, S Jagtap S, Nagar V, Varshney K. Invasive mucormycosis in post COVID-19 infection: case report with review. IP Arch&#xa0;Cytol&#xa0;Histopathol&#xa0;Res. 2021;6(2):135-139.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>