<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36196947</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2561-8741</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of population therapeutics and clinical pharmacology = Journal de la therapeutique des populations et de la pharmacologie clinique</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Popul Ther Clin Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID-19 prevalence among a sample of infected people in Erbil city.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e123</StartPage><EndPage>e133</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e123-e133</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.47750/jptcp.2022.956</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Long-term effects of the disease were founded and described as post-COVID-19 syndrome post-COVID syndrome are the symptoms that develop and last for four weeks or even months and cannot be explained by an alternative diagnosis; symptoms may remain for &gt;3 months. The cause of persistent symptoms is unclear. Objectives: This study aimed to Estimate the prevalence of residual symptoms among a sample of people infected with COVID-19 who survived and recovered in Erbil city and to find out the relation between the severity of the disease and post-COVID-19 syndrome. And to know the incidence of post-COVID-19 syndrome in chronic disease patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS">This cross-sectional study was conducted in 6 primary health care centers in 6 municipalities in Erbil city, Kurdistan region, Iraq. A convenience sample of randomly selected 300 patients was involved in the study depending on inclusion criteria. For one year, starting from March 1, 2021, until the end of February 2022.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The prevalence of post-COVID syndrome among the 300 cases was 54.67%. Of these cases, 11.7% had one symptom, 26% had two signs, and 17% had with three or more symptoms. There was a significant statistical association between persistent symptoms and the severity of COVID-19. Also, there was a substantial statistical association between persistent symptoms and chronic disease, most (67.9%) respondents with post-COVID-19 syndromes suffered from chronic disease, and the p-value was 0.001. There was a significant statistical association between persistent symptoms and disease duration; most (73%) of cases with post-COVID-19 syndrome got the disease from 7 to 14 days, while 54.5% of them struggled with COVID-19 for &gt;14 days.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Most people who have recovered from COVID-19 have many long-lasting symptoms that make it hard to go about their daily lives. This is now called a post-COVID syndrome. Getting to this status could have been caused by several things. Age, gender, whether a person has a chronic disease, disease severity, and duration are all things to consider, Even though all COVID-19 victims should be kept an eye on for long-term evaluation and treatment of post-COVID symptoms.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hawar</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed Sabah</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Medicine, College of Medicine, Hawler Medical University; Erbil, Iraq; drnihadkhalawe@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dauod</LastName><ForeName>Ali Shakir</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Medicine, College of Medicine, Hawler Medical University; Erbil, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>J Popul Ther Clin Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101530023</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2561-8741</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002947" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Cities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36196947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47750/jptcp.2022.956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>1. Cucinotta D, and Vanelli M. WHO declares COVID-19 a pandemic. Acta Biomed. Ateneo Parmense. 2020; 91(1): 157. 10.23750/abm.v91i1.9397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23750/abm.v91i1.9397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2. McCorkell L, Assaf GS, Davis HE, Wei H, and Akrami A. Patient-led research collaborative: embedding patients in the long COVID narrative. Pain Rep. 2021; 6(1): e913. 10.1097/PR9.0000000000000913</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PR9.0000000000000913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>3. Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, and Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020; 324(6): 603&#x2013;605. 10.1001/jama.2020.12603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.12603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>4. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. (2020). COVID-19 and your health. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. February, 11, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi"/></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>5. Greenhalgh T, Knight M, Buxton M, and Husain L. Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ, 2020; 370: m3026. 10.1136/bmj.m3026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m3026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>6. Ladds E, Rushforth A, Wieringa S, Taylor S, Rayner C, Husain L, and Greenhalgh T. Persistent symptoms after Covid-19: qualitative study of 114 &#x201c;long Covid&#x201d; patients and draft quality principles for services. BMC Health Serv Res. 2020; 20(1): 1&#x2013;13. 10.1186/s12913-020-06001-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-020-06001-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>7. Pormohammad A, Ghorbani S, Khatami A, Farzi R, Baradaran B, Turner DL, et al. Comparison of confirmed COVID-19 with SARS and MERS cases-Clinical characteristics, laboratory findings, radiographic signs and outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Rev Med Virol. 2020; 30(4): e2112. 10.1002/rmv.2112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rmv.2112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>8. Amin M, Hasan M, and Bhuiya NM. Prevalence of Covid-19 associated symptoms, their onset and duration, and variations among different groups of patients in Bangladesh. Front Public Health. 2021; 9: 738352. 10.3389/fpubh.2021.738352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2021.738352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>9. Khalaf M, Alboraie M, Abdel-Gawad M, Abdelmalek M, Abu-Elfatth A, Abdelhamed W, et al. Prevalence and predictors of persistent symptoms after clearance of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a multicenter study from Egypt. Infect Drug Resist. 2022; 15: 2575. 10.2147/IDR.S355064</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IDR.S355064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>10. Garner P. Covid-19 at 14 weeks&#x2014;phantom speed cameras, unknown limits, and harsh penalties. BMJ Opinion. 2020. https://blogs.bmj.com/bmj/2020/06/23/paul-garner-c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi"/></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>11. Bliddal S, Banasik K, Pedersen OB, Nissen J, Cantwell L, and Schwinn M. Acute and persistent symptoms in non-hospitalized PCR-confirmed COVID-19 patients. Sci Rep. 2021; 11(1): 1&#x2013;11. 10.1038/s41598-021-92045-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-92045-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>12. Balachandar V, Mahalaxmi I, Subramaniam M, Kaavya J, Kumar NS, and Laldinmawii G. Follow-up studies in COVID-19 recovered patients-is it mandatory?. Sci Total Environ. 2020; 729: 139021. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.139021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.139021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>13. Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, and McLean L. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021; 93(2): 1013&#x2013;1022. 10.1002/jmv.26368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>14. Gebhard CE, S&#xfc;tsch C, Bengs S, Todorov A, Deforth M, Buehler KP, et al. Understanding the impact of sociocultural gender on post-acute sequelae of covid-19: A bayesian approach. 2021. Preprint.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi"/></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>15. Zhao YM, Shang YM, Song WB, Li QQ, Xie H, Xu QF, et al. Follow-up study of the pulmonary function and related physiological characteristics of COVID-19 survivors three months after recovery. EClinicalMedicine. 2020; 25: 100463. 10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100463</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>16. Nachimuthu S, Vijayalakshmi R, Sudha M, and Viswanathan V. Coping with diabetes during the COVID&#x2013;19 lockdown in India: results of an online pilot survey. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2020; 14(4): 579&#x2013;582. 10.1016/j.dsx.2020.04.053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsx.2020.04.053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>17. Saqib MAN, Siddiqui S, Qasim M, Jamil MA, Rafique I, Awan UA, et al. Effect of COVID-19 lockdown on patients with chronic diseases. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2020; 14(6): 1621&#x2013;1623. 10.1016/j.dsx.2020.08.028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsx.2020.08.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>18. Alsaied T, Aboulhosn JA, Cotts TB, Daniels CJ, Etheridge SP, Feltes TF, et al. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic implications in pediatric and adult congenital heart disease. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020; 9(12): e017224. 10.1161/JAHA.120.017224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.120.017224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>19. Raveendran AV, and Misra A. Post COVID-19 syndrome (&#x201c;Long COVID&#x201d;) and diabetes: challenges in diagnosis and management. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021; 15(5): 102235. 10.1016/j.dsx.2021.102235</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsx.2021.102235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>20. Hopkinson NS, Rossi N, El-Sayed_Moustafa J, Laverty AA, Quint JK, Freidin M, et al. Current smoking and COVID-19 risk: results from a population symptom app in over 2.4 million people.Thorax. 2021; 76(7): 714&#x2013;722. 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216422</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>21. Cavezzi A, Troiani E, and Corrao S. COVID-19: hemoglobin, iron, and hypoxia beyond inflammation. A narrative review. Clin Pract. 2020; 10(2): 1271. 10.4081/cp.2020.1271</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/cp.2020.1271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>22. Edeas M, Saleh J, and Peyssonnaux C. Iron: Innocent bystander or vicious culprit in COVID-19 pathogenesis?. Int J Infect Dis. 2020; 97: 303&#x2013;305. 10.1016/j.ijid.2020.05.110</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2020.05.110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>23. Agalya, ME, Aishwarya V, Lakshmi AA, Ezhilarasi A, Indhumathi S. A smart college management system using MongoDB. IJCCTS. 2022; 10(2): 73&#x2013;78. 10.31838/ijccts/10.02.08</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31838/ijccts/10.02.08</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>24. Alhazmi W, Almutairi A, Alsaud J, Aladhyani A, Almutairi A, Alsweed M, et al. Prevalence, pattern, and severity of allergic rhinitis among children and teenagers in qassim region, saudi arabia: a cross-sectional study. J Pharm Negat Results. 2022; 13(1): 60&#x2013;67. 10.47750/pnr.2022.13.01.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47750/pnr.2022.13.01.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>25. Paramesh G, Vanga R, Siva R, Sekaran S, and Ganapathy D. Assessment of femur geometry for the implant fabrication using x-ray assistance of PACS system. Eur Chem Bull. 2022; 11(4): 16&#x2013;21. 10.31838/ecb/2022.11.04.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31838/ecb/2022.11.04.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>