<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35862681</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>96</Volume><Issue>15</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Host Response to Influenza A Virus Interferes with SARS-CoV-2 Replication during Coinfection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0076522</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0076522</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e00765-22</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/jvi.00765-22</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) and influenza A virus (IAV) represent two highly transmissible airborne pathogens with pandemic capabilities. Although these viruses belong to separate virus families-SARS-CoV-2 is a member of the family <i>Coronaviridae</i>, while IAV is a member of the family <i>Orthomyxoviridae</i>-both have shown zoonotic potential, with significant animal reservoirs in species in close contact with humans. The two viruses are similar in their capacity to infect human airways, and coinfections resulting in significant morbidity and mortality have been documented. Here, we investigate the interaction between SARS-CoV-2 USA-WA1/2020 and influenza H1N1 A/California/04/2009 virus during coinfection. Competition assays <i>in vitro</i> were performed in susceptible cells that were either interferon type I/III (IFN-I/-III) nonresponsive or IFN-I/-III responsive, in addition to an <i>in vivo</i> golden hamster model. We find that SARS-CoV-2 infection does not interfere with IAV biology <i>in vivo</i>, regardless of timing between the infections. In contrast, we observe a significant loss of SARS-CoV-2 replication following IAV infection. The latter phenotype correlates with increased levels of IFN-I/-III and immune priming that interferes with the kinetics of SARS-CoV-2 replication. Together, these data suggest that cocirculation of SARS-CoV-2 and IAV is unlikely to result in increased severity of disease. <b>IMPORTANCE</b> The human population now has two circulating respiratory RNA viruses with high pandemic potential, namely, SARS-CoV-2 and influenza A virus. As both viruses infect the airways and can result in significant morbidity and mortality, it is imperative that we also understand the consequences of getting coinfected. Here, we demonstrate that the host response to influenza A virus uniquely interferes with SARS-CoV-2 biology although the inverse relationship is not evident. Overall, we find that the host response to both viruses is comparable to that to SARS-CoV-2 infection alone.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oishi</LastName><ForeName>Kohei</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2995-7856</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, New York University, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horiuchi</LastName><ForeName>Shu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, New York University, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Minkoff</LastName><ForeName>Judith M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, New York University, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>tenOever</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin R</ForeName><Initials>BR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0324-3078</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, New York University, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9008-11-1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007372">Interferons</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060085" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coinfection</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045142" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cross-Priming</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053118" MajorTopicYN="Y">Influenza A Virus, H1N1 Subtype</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007251" MajorTopicYN="Y">Influenza, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007372" MajorTopicYN="N">Interferons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008647" MajorTopicYN="N">Mesocricetus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014779" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Replication</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">H1N1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RNA sequencing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anosmia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endemic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">host response</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interference</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interferon</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pandemic</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35862681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9364782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jvi.00765-22</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wu F, Zhao S, Yu B, Chen YM, Wang W, Song ZG, Hu Y, Tao ZW, Tian JH, Pei YY, Yuan ML, Zhang YL, Dai FH, Liu Y, Wang QM, Zheng JJ, Xu L, Holmes EC, Zhang YZ. 2020. A new coronavirus associated with human respiratory disease in China. Nature 579:265&#x2013;269. 10.1038/s41586-020-2008-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-020-2008-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu N, Zhang D, Wang W, Li X, Yang B, Song J, Zhao X, Huang B, Shi W, Lu R, Niu P, Zhan F, Ma X, Wang D, Xu W, Wu G, Gao GF, Tan W, China Novel Coronavirus Investigating and Research Team . 2020. A novel coronavirus from patients with pneumonia in China, 2019. N Engl J Med 382:727&#x2013;733. 10.1056/NEJMoa2001017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2001017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31978945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carre&#xf1;o JM, Alshammary H, Tcheou J, Singh G, Raskin AJ, Kawabata H, Sominsky LA, Clark JJ, Adelsberg DC, Bielak DA, Gonzalez-Reiche AS, Dambrauskas N, Vigdorovich V, PSP-PARIS Study Group, Srivastava K, Sather DN, Sordillo EM, Bajic G, van Bakel H, Simon V, Krammer F. 2022. Activity of convalescent and vaccine serum against SARS-CoV-2 Omicron. Nature 602:682&#x2013;688. 10.1038/d41586-021-03846-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/d41586-021-03846-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35016197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si L, Bai H, Rodas M, Cao W, Oh CY, Jiang A, Moller R, Hoagland D, Oishi K, Horiuchi S, Uhl S, Blanco-Melo D, Albrecht RA, Liu WC, Jordan T, Nilsson-Payant BE, Golynker I, Frere J, Logue J, Haupt R, McGrath M, Weston S, Zhang T, Plebani R, Soong M, Nurani A, Kim SM, Zhu DY, Benam KH, Goyal G, Gilpin SE, Prantil-Baun R, Gygi SP, Powers RK, Carlson KE, Frieman M, tenOever BR, Ingber DE. 2021. A human-airway-on-a-chip for the rapid identification of candidate antiviral therapeutics and prophylactics. Nat Biomed Eng 5:815&#x2013;829. 10.1038/s41551-021-00718-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41551-021-00718-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8387338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33941899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho JSY, Mok BW-Y, Campisi L, Jordan T, Yildiz S, Parameswaran S, Wayman JA, Gaudreault NN, Meekins DA, Indran SV, Morozov I, Trujillo JD, Fstkchyan YS, Rathnasinghe R, Zhu Z, Zheng S, Zhao N, White K, Ray-Jones H, Malysheva V, Thiecke MJ, Lau S-Y, Liu H, Zhang AJ, Lee AC-Y, Liu W-C, Jangra S, Escalera A, Aydillo T, Melo BS, Guccione E, Sebra R, Shum E, Bakker J, Kaufman DA, Moreira AL, Carossino M, Balasuriya UBR, Byun M, Albrecht RA, Schotsaert M, Garcia-Sastre A, Chanda SK, Miraldi ER, Jeyasekharan AD, TenOever BR, Spivakov M, Weirauch MT, Heinz S, Chen H, Benner C, Richt JA, Marazzi I. 2021. TOP1 inhibition therapy protects against SARS-CoV-2-induced lethal inflammation. Cell 184:2618&#x2013;2632.e17. 10.1016/j.cell.2021.03.051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2021.03.051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou YJ, Okuda K, Edwards CE, Martinez DR, Asakura T, Dinnon KH, III, Kato T, Lee RE, Yount BL, Mascenik TM, Chen G, Olivier KN, Ghio A, Tse LV, Leist SR, Gralinski LE, Schafer A, Dang H, Gilmore R, Nakano S, Sun L, Fulcher ML, Livraghi-Butrico A, Nicely NI, Cameron M, Cameron C, Kelvin DJ, de Silva A, Margolis DM, Markmann A, Bartelt L, Zumwalt R, Martinez FJ, Salvatore SP, Borczuk A, Tata PR, Sontake V, Kimple A, Jaspers I, O&#x2019;Neal WK, Randell SH, Boucher RC, Baric RS. 2020. SARS-CoV-2 reverse genetics reveals a variable infection gradient in the respiratory tract. Cell 182:429&#x2013;446.e14. 10.1016/j.cell.2020.05.042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.05.042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7250779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32526206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N, Zhou M, Dong X, Qu J, Gong F, Han Y, Qiu Y, Wang J, Liu Y, Wei Y, Xia J, Yu T, Zhang X, Zhang L. 2020. Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of 99 cases of 2019 novel coronavirus pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a descriptive study. Lancet 395:507&#x2013;513. 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30211-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30211-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7135076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32007143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco-Melo D, Nilsson-Payant BE, Liu WC, Uhl S, Hoagland D, Moller R, Jordan TX, Oishi K, Panis M, Sachs D, Wang TT, Schwartz RE, Lim JK, Albrecht RA, tenOever BR. 2020. Imbalanced host response to SARS-CoV-2 drives development of COVID-19. Cell 181:1036&#x2013;1045.e9. 10.1016/j.cell.2020.04.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.04.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7227586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32416070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rydyznski Moderbacher C, Ramirez SI, Dan JM, Grifoni A, Hastie KM, Weiskopf D, Belanger S, Abbott RK, Kim C, Choi J, Kato Y, Crotty EG, Kim C, Rawlings SA, Mateus J, Tse LPV, Frazier A, Baric R, Peters B, Greenbaum J, Ollmann Saphire E, Smith DM, Sette A, Crotty S. 2020. Antigen-specific adaptive immunity to SARS-CoV-2 in acute COVID-19 and associations with age and disease severity. Cell 183:996&#x2013;1012.e19. 10.1016/j.cell.2020.09.038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.09.038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7494270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33010815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi T, Yale IMPACT Research Team, Ellingson MK, Wong P, Israelow B, Lucas C, Klein J, Silva J, Mao T, Oh JE, Tokuyama M, Lu P, Venkataraman A, Park A, Liu F, Meir A, Sun J, Wang EY, Casanovas-Massana A, Wyllie AL, Vogels CBF, Earnest R, Lapidus S, Ott IM, Moore AJ, Yale IRT, Shaw A, Fournier JB, Odio CD, Farhadian S, Dela Cruz C, Grubaugh ND, Schulz WL, Ring AM, Ko AI, Omer SB, Iwasaki A. 2020. Sex differences in immune responses that underlie COVID-19 disease outcomes. Nature 588:315&#x2013;320. 10.1038/s41586-020-2700-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-020-2700-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7725931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32846427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jesus RP, de Carvalho JF, de Oliveira LPM, Cunha CM, Alves T, Vieira STB, Figueiredo VM, Bueno AA. 2022. Metabolic and nutritional triggers associated with increased risk of liver complications in SARS-CoV-2. World J Hepatol 14:80&#x2013;97. 10.4254/wjh.v14.i1.80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4254/wjh.v14.i1.80</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8790394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35126841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JH, Koepke L, Kirchhoff F, Sparrer KMJ. 2022. Interferon antagonists encoded by SARS-CoV-2 at a glance. Med Microbiol Immunol 10.1007/s00430-022-00734-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00430-022-00734-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8976456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35366686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrd KM, Beckwith CG, Garland JM, Johnson JE, Aung S, Cu-Uvin S, Farmakiotis D, Flanigan T, Gillani FS, Macias-Gil R, Mileno M, Ramratnam B, Rybak NR, Sanchez M, Tashima K, Mylonakis E, Kantor R. 2020. SARS-CoV-2 and HIV coinfection: clinical experience from Rhode Island, United States. J Int AIDS Soc 23:e25573. 10.1002/jia2.25573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jia2.25573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7357287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32657527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nomah DK, Reyes-Uruena J, Llibre JM, Ambrosioni J, Ganem FS, Miro JM, Casabona J. 2022. HIV and SARS-CoV-2 co-infection: epidemiological, clinical features, and future implications for clinical care and public health for people living with HIV (PLWH) and HIV most-at-risk groups. Curr HIV/AIDS Rep 19:17&#x2013;25. 10.1007/s11904-021-00596-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11904-021-00596-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8810339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35113346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y, Yuan J, Long Q, Hu J, Deng H, Zhao Z, Chen J, Lu M, Huang A. 2021. Patients with SARS-CoV-2 and HBV co-infection are at risk of greater liver injury. Genes Dis 8:484&#x2013;492. 10.1016/j.gendis.2020.11.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gendis.2020.11.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7672332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33225036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon FJF, da Silva LL, Santos AC, Duarte da Costa V, Miguel JC, Marques JT, Nascimento GP, Ferreira da Silva E, Lewis-Ximenez LL, Villar LM, de Paula VS. 2022. Immunological and virological aspects of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) and hepatitis C virus. J Med Virol 94:2296&#x2013;2301. 10.1002/jmv.27614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.27614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9015401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35064576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue H, Zhang M, Xing L, Wang K, Rao X, Liu H, Tian J, Zhou P, Deng Y, Shang J. 2020. The epidemiology and clinical characteristics of co-infection of SARS-CoV-2 and influenza viruses in patients during COVID-19 outbreak. J Med Virol 92:2870&#x2013;2873. 10.1002/jmv.26163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7307028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lew S, Manes P, Smith B. 2020. Coinfection with SARS-CoV-2 and influenza A virus in a 32-year-old man. Am J Case Rep 21:e926092. 10.12659/AJCR.926092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/AJCR.926092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7672510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33188162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowak MD, Sordillo EM, Gitman MR, Paniz Mondolfi AE. 2020. Coinfection in SARS-CoV-2 infected patients: where are influenza virus and rhinovirus/enterovirus? J Med Virol 92:1699&#x2013;1700. 10.1002/jmv.25953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.25953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32352574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dao TL, Hoang VT, Colson P, Million M, Gautret P. 2021. Co-infection of SARS-CoV-2 and influenza viruses: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Virol Plus 1:100036. 10.1016/j.jcvp.2021.100036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcvp.2021.100036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8349735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35262019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lansbury L, Lim B, Baskaran V, Lim WS. 2020. Co-infections in people with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Infect 81:266&#x2013;275. 10.1016/j.jinf.2020.05.046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2020.05.046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32473235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M, Kleine-Weber H, Schroeder S, Kruger N, Herrler T, Erichsen S, Schiergens TS, Herrler G, Wu NH, Nitsche A, Muller MA, Drosten C, Pohlmann S. 2020. SARS-CoV-2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and is blocked by a clinically proven protease inhibitor. Cell 181:271&#x2013;280.e8. 10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weis W, Brown JH, Cusack S, Paulson JC, Skehel JJ, Wiley DC. 1988. Structure of the influenza virus haemagglutinin complexed with its receptor, sialic acid. Nature 333:426&#x2013;431. 10.1038/333426a0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/333426a0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3374584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traylor ZP, Aeffner F, Davis IC. 2013. Influenza A H1N1 induces declines in alveolar gas exchange in mice consistent with rapid post-infection progression from acute lung injury to ARDS. Influenza Other Respir Viruses 7:472&#x2013;479. 10.1111/j.1750-2659.2012.00414.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1750-2659.2012.00414.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3494753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22862736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govorkova EA, Murti G, Meignier B, de Taisne C, Webster RG. 1996. African green monkey kidney (Vero) cells provide an alternative host cell system for influenza A and B viruses. J Virol 70:5519&#x2013;5524. 10.1128/JVI.70.8.5519-5524.1996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.70.8.5519-5524.1996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC190510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8764064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horiuchi S, Oishi K, Carrau L, Frere J, Moller R, Panis M, tenOever BR. 2021. Immune memory from SARS-CoV-2 infection in hamsters provides variant-independent protection but still allows virus transmission. Sci Immunol 6:eabm3131. 10.1126/sciimmunol.abm3131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciimmunol.abm3131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34699266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emeny JM, Morgan MJ. 1979. Regulation of the interferon system: evidence that Vero cells have a genetic defect in interferon production. J Gen Virol 43:247&#x2013;252. 10.1099/0022-1317-43-1-247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/0022-1317-43-1-247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">113494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Renner DM, Comar CE, Whelan JN, Reyes HM, Cardenas-Diaz FL, Truitt R, Tan LH, Dong B, Alysandratos KD, Huang J, Palmer JN, Adappa ND, Kohanski MA, Kotton DN, Silverman RH, Yang W, Morrisey EE, Cohen NA, Weiss SR. 2021. SARS-CoV-2 induces double-stranded RNA-mediated innate immune responses in respiratory epithelial-derived cells and cardiomyocytes. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 118:e2022643118. 10.1073/pnas.2022643118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2022643118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33811184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imai M, Iwatsuki-Horimoto K, Hatta M, Loeber S, Halfmann PJ, Nakajima N, Watanabe T, Ujie M, Takahashi K, Ito M, Yamada S, Fan S, Chiba S, Kuroda M, Guan L, Takada K, Armbrust T, Balogh A, Furusawa Y, Okuda M, Ueki H, Yasuhara A, Sakai-Tagawa Y, Lopes TJS, Kiso M, Yamayoshi S, Kinoshita N, Ohmagari N, Hattori SI, Takeda M, Mitsuya H, Krammer F, Suzuki T, Kawaoka Y. 2020. Syrian hamsters as a small animal model for SARS-CoV-2 infection and countermeasure development. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 117:16587&#x2013;16595. 10.1073/pnas.2009799117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2009799117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7368255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32571934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwatsuki-Horimoto K, Nakajima N, Ichiko Y, Sakai-Tagawa Y, Noda T, Hasegawa H, Kawaoka Y. 2018. Syrian hamster as an animal model for the study of human influenza virus infection. J Virol 92:e01693-17. 10.1128/JVI.01693-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.01693-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5790951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29212926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoagland DA, Moller R, Uhl SA, Oishi K, Frere J, Golynker I, Horiuchi S, Panis M, Blanco-Melo D, Sachs D, Arkun K, Lim JK, tenOever BR. 2021. Leveraging the antiviral type I interferon system as a first line of defense against SARS-CoV-2 pathogenicity. Immunity 54:557&#x2013;570.e5. 10.1016/j.immuni.2021.01.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2021.01.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7846242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frere JJ, Serafini RA, Pryce KD, Zazhytska M, Oishi K, Golynker I, Panis M, Zimering J, Horiuchi S, Hoagland DA, M&#xf8;ller R, Ruiz A, Overdevest JB, Kodra A, Canoll PD, Goldman JE, Borczuk AC, Chandar V, Bram Y, Schwartz R, Lomvardas S, Zachariou V, tenOever BR. 2022. SARS-CoV-2 infection results in lasting and systemic perturbations post recovery. bioRxiv. 10.1101/2022.01.18.476786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2022.01.18.476786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9210449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35857629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsson-Payant BE, Uhl S, Grimont A, Doane AS, Cohen P, Patel RS, Higgins CA, Acklin JA, Bram Y, Chandar V, Blanco-Melo D, Panis M, Lim JK, Elemento O, Schwartz RE, Rosenberg BR, Chandwani R, tenOever BR. 2021. The NF-&#x3ba;B transcriptional footprint is essential for SARS-CoV-2 replication. J Virol 95:e01257-21. 10.1128/JVI.01257-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.01257-21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8577386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34523966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X, Wang H, Su Z, Li W, Yang D, Deng F, Chen J. 2020. Co-infection of SARS-CoV-2 and influenza virus in early stage of the COVID-19 epidemic in Wuhan, China. J Infect 81:e128&#x2013;e129. 10.1016/j.jinf.2020.05.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2020.05.041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32474045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Abramo A, Lepore L, Palazzolo C, Barreca F, Liuzzi G, Lalle E, Nicastri E. 2020. Acute respiratory distress syndrome due to SARS-CoV-2 and influenza A co-infection in an Italian patient: mini-review of the literature. Int J Infect Dis 97:236&#x2013;239. 10.1016/j.ijid.2020.06.056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2020.06.056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32565366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahim M, Ghonim H, Roshdy WH, Naguib A, Elguindy N, AbdelFatah M, Hassany M, Mohsen A, Afifi S, Eid A. 2021. Coinfection with SARS-CoV-2 and influenza A(H1N1) in a patient seen at an influenza-like illness surveillance site in Egypt: case report. JMIR Public Health Surveill 7:e27433. 10.2196/27433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/27433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8081026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33784634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashemi SA, Safamanesh S, Ghasemzadeh-Moghaddam H, Ghafouri M, Azimian A. 2021. High prevalence of SARS-CoV-2 and influenza A virus (H1N1) coinfection in dead patients in Northeastern Iran. J Med Virol 93:1008&#x2013;1012. 10.1002/jmv.26364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32720703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achdout H, Vitner EB, Politi B, Melamed S, Yahalom-Ronen Y, Tamir H, Erez N, Avraham R, Weiss S, Cherry L, Bar-Haim E, Makdasi E, Gur D, Aftalion M, Chitlaru T, Vagima Y, Paran N, Israely T. 2021. Increased lethality in influenza and SARS-CoV-2 coinfection is prevented by influenza immunity but not SARS-CoV-2 immunity. Nat Commun 12:5819. 10.1038/s41467-021-26113-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-26113-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8492774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai L, Zhao Y, Dong J, Liang S, Guo M, Liu X, Wang X, Huang Z, Sun X, Zhang Z, Dong L, Liu Q, Zheng Y, Niu D, Xiang M, Song K, Ye J, Zheng W, Tang Z, Tang M, Zhou Y, Shen C, Dai M, Zhou L, Chen Y, Yan H, Lan K, Xu K. 2021. Coinfection with influenza A virus enhances SARS-CoV-2 infectivity. Cell Res 31:395&#x2013;403. 10.1038/s41422-021-00473-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41422-021-00473-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7890106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33603116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halfmann PJ, Nakajima N, Sato Y, Takahashi K, Accola M, Chiba S, Fan S, Neumann G, Rehrauer W, Suzuki T, Kawaoka Y. 2022. SARS-CoV-2 interference of influenza virus replication in Syrian hamsters. J Infect Dis 225:282&#x2013;286. 10.1093/infdis/jiab587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiab587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8689717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34875072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang AJ, Lee AC, Chan JF, Liu F, Li C, Chen Y, Chu H, Lau SY, Wang P, Chan CC, Poon VK, Yuan S, To KK, Chen H, Yuen KY. 2021. Coinfection by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 and influenza A(H1N1)pdm09 virus enhances the severity of pneumonia in golden Syrian hamsters. Clin Infect Dis 72:e978&#x2013;e992. 10.1093/cid/ciaa1747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciaa1747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33216851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim EH, Nguyen TQ, Casel MAB, Rollon R, Kim SM, Kim YI, Yu KM, Jang SG, Yang J, Poo H, Jung JU, Choi YK. 2022. Coinfection with SARS-CoV-2 and influenza A virus increases disease severity and impairs neutralizing antibody and CD4(+) T cell responses. J Virol 96:e0187321. 10.1128/jvi.01873-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jvi.01873-21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8941868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35107382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varble A, Albrecht RA, Backes S, Crumiller M, Bouvier NM, Sachs D, Garc&#xed;a-Sastre A, tenOever BR. 2014. Influenza A virus transmission bottlenecks are defined by infection route and recipient host. Cell Host Microbe 16:691&#x2013;700. 10.1016/j.chom.2014.09.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chom.2014.09.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4272616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25456074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>