<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35861926</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-7479</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurotherapeutics : the journal of the American Society for Experimental NeuroTherapeutics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurotherapeutics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Therapeutic Approaches to the Neurologic Manifestations of COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1435</StartPage><EndPage>1466</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1435-1466</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13311-022-01267-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As of May 2022, there have been more than 527 million infections with severe acute respiratory disease coronavirus type 2 (SARS-CoV-2) and over 6.2 million deaths from Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) worldwide. COVID-19 is a multisystem illness with important neurologic consequences that impact long-term morbidity and mortality. In the acutely ill, the neurologic manifestations of COVID-19 can include distressing but relatively benign symptoms such as headache, myalgias, and anosmia; however, entities such as encephalopathy, stroke, seizures, encephalitis, and Guillain-Barre Syndrome can cause neurologic injury and resulting disability that persists long after the acute pulmonary illness. Furthermore, as many as one-third of patients may experience persistent neurologic symptoms as part of a Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (Neuro-PASC) syndrome. This Neuro-PASC syndrome can affect patients who required hospitalization for COVID-19 or patients who did not require hospitalization and who may have had minor or no pulmonary symptoms. Given the large number of individuals affected and the ability of neurologic complications to impair quality of life and productivity, the neurologic manifestations of COVID-19 are likely to have major and long-lasting personal, public health, and economic consequences. While knowledge of disease mechanisms and therapies acquired prior to the pandemic can inform us on how to manage patients with the neurologic manifestations of COVID-19, there is a critical need for improved understanding of specific COVID-19 disease mechanisms and development of therapies that target the neurologic morbidities of COVID-19. This current perspective reviews evidence for proposed disease mechanisms as they inform the neurologic management of COVID-19 in adult patients while also identifying areas in need of further research.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The American Society for Experimental NeuroTherapeutics, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Graham</LastName><ForeName>Edith L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6862-5531</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ken and Ruth Davee Department of Neurology, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, 625 N. Michigan Ave Suite 1150, Chicago, IL, 60611, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koralnik</LastName><ForeName>Igor J</ForeName><Initials>IJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6836-1468</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ken and Ruth Davee Department of Neurology, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, 625 N. Michigan Ave Suite 1150, Chicago, IL, 60611, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liotta</LastName><ForeName>Eric M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3182-585X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ken and Ruth Davee Department of Neurology, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, 625 N. Michigan Ave Suite 1150, Chicago, IL, 60611, USA. Eric.Liotta@northwestern.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neurotherapeutics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101290381</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1878-7479</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012640" MajorTopicYN="N">Seizures</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Encephalopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35861926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9302225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-022-01267-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1878-7479(23)00180-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dong E, Du H, Gardner L. An interactive web-based dashboard to track COVID-19 in real time. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20:533&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32087114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC COVID-NET: COVID-10-Associated Hospitalization Surveillance Network [online]. 2021. Available at: https://gis.cdc.gov/grasp/covidnet/covid19_3.html. Accessed 27 Apr 2022.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M, et al. Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:683&#x2013;690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7149362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Sanchez CM, Diaz-Maroto I, Fernandez-Diaz E, et al. Neurologic manifestations in hospitalized patients with COVID-19: the ALBACOVID registry. Neurology. 2020;95:e1060&#x2013;e1070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7668545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32482845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liotta EM, Batra A, Clark JR, et al. Frequent neurologic manifestations and encephalopathy-associated morbidity in Covid-19 patients. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7664279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33016619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siepmann T, Kitzler HH, Lueck C, Platzek I, Reichmann H, Barlinn K. Neuralgic amyotrophy following infection with SARS-CoV-2. Muscle Nerve. 2020;62:E68&#x2013;E70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32710672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh Y, Beh DLL, Makmur A, Somani J, Chan ACY. Pearls &amp; Oy-sters: facial nerve palsy in COVID-19 infection. Neurology. 2020;95:364&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32439822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik GR, Wolfe AR, Soriano R, et al. Injury-prone: peripheral nerve injuries associated with prone positioning for COVID-19-related acute respiratory distress syndrome. Br J Anaesth. 2020;125:e478&#x2013;e480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7473147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32948295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark JR, Liotta EM, Reish NJ, et al. Abnormal movements in hospitalized COVID-19 patients: a case series. J Neurol Sci. 2021;423:117377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7908881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33676146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aschman T, Schneider J, Greuel S, et al. Association between SARS-CoV-2 infection and immune-mediated myopathy in patients who have died. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78:948&#x2013;960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34115106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choksi T, Agrawal A, Date P, et al. Cumulative mortality and factors associated with outcomes of mucormycosis after COVID-19 at a multispecialty tertiary care center in India. JAMA Ophthalmol. 2022;140:66&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34882192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharyya A, Sarma P, Sharma DJ, et al. Rhino-orbital-cerebral-mucormycosis in COVID-19: a systematic review. Indian J Pharmacol. 2021;53:317&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8411962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34414911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gofton TE, Young GB. Sepsis-associated encephalopathy. Nat Rev Neurol. 2012;8:557&#x2013;566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22986430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazeraud A, Righy C, Bouchereau E, Benghanem S, Bozza FA, Sharshar T. Septic-associated encephalopathy: a comprehensive review. Neurotherapeutics. 2020;17:392&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7283452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32378026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oddo M, Carrera E, Claassen J, Mayer SA, Hirsch LJ. Continuous electroencephalography in the medical intensive care unit. Crit Care Med. 2009;37:2051&#x2013;2056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19384197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fajgenbaum DC, June CH. Cytokine storm. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:2255&#x2013;2273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33264547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pensato U, Muccioli L, Cani I, et al. Brain dysfunction in COVID-19 and CAR-T therapy: cytokine storm-associated encephalopathy. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2021;8:968&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8045903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33780166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu SX, Tyagi T, Jain K, et al. Thrombocytopathy and endotheliopathy: crucial contributors to COVID-19 thromboinflammation. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2021;18:194&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33214651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard-Valnet R, Perriot S, Canales M, et al. Encephalopathies associated with severe COVID-19 present neurovascular unit alterations without evidence for strong neuroinflammation. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2021;8. PMC8210172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8210172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34135107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia MA, Barreras PV, Lewis A, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid in COVID-19 neurological complications: neuroaxonal damage, anti-SARS-Cov2 antibodies but no evidence of cytokine storm. J Neurol Sci. 2021;427:117517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8166041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34090021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leisman DE, Ronner L, Pinotti R, et al. Cytokine elevation in severe and critical COVID-19: a rapid systematic review, meta-analysis, and comparison with other inflammatory syndromes. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8:1233&#x2013;1244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7567529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33075298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenzel J, Lampe J, Muller-Fielitz H, et al. The SARS-CoV-2 main protease M(pro) causes microvascular brain pathology by cleaving NEMO in brain endothelial cells. Nat Neurosci. 2021;24:1522&#x2013;1533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8553622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34675436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E, Zhang C, Israelow B, et al. Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 in human and mouse brain. J Exp Med 2021;218. PMC7808299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkai I, Mayer MG, Hellmers LM, et al. Neuropathology and virus in brain of SARS-CoV-2 infected non-human primates. Nat Commun. 2022;13:1745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8975902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35365631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteil V, Kwon H, Prado P, et al. Inhibition of SARS-CoV-2 infections in engineered human tissues using clinical-grade soluble human ACE2. Cell. 2020;181:905&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7181998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32333836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabioni L, De Lorenzo A, Lamas C, et al. Systemic microvascular endothelial dysfunction and disease severity in COVID-19 patients: evaluation by laser Doppler perfusion monitoring and cytokine/chemokine analysis. Microvasc Res. 2021;134:104119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7710468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33278457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruhl L, Pink I, Kuhne JF, et al. Endothelial dysfunction contributes to severe COVID-19 in combination with dysregulated lymphocyte responses and cytokine networks. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6:418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34893580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jud P, Gressenberger P, Muster V, et al. Evaluation of endothelial dysfunction and inflammatory vasculopathy after SARS-CoV-2 infection-a cross-sectional study. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2021;8:750887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8549830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34722682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejia-Renteria H, Travieso A, Sagir A, et al. In-vivo evidence of systemic endothelial vascular dysfunction in COVID-19. Int J Cardiol. 2021;345:153&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8542397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34706286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moretta P, Maniscalco M, Papa A, Lanzillo A, Trojano L, Ambrosino P. Cognitive impairment and endothelial dysfunction in convalescent COVID-19 patients undergoing rehabilitation. Eur J Clin Invest. 2022;52:e13726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34921559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackermann M, Verleden SE, Kuehnel M, et al. Pulmonary vascular endothelialitis, thrombosis, and angiogenesis in Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:120&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7412750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga Z, Flammer AJ, Steiger P, et al. Endothelial cell infection and endotheliitis in COVID-19. Lancet. 2020;395:1417&#x2013;1418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryce C, Grimes Z, Pujadas E, et al. Pathophysiology of SARS-CoV-2: the Mount Sinai COVID-19 autopsy experience. Mod Pathol. 2021;34:1456&#x2013;1467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8015313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33795830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colmenero I, Santonja C, Alonso-Riano M, et al. SARS-CoV-2 endothelial infection causes COVID-19 chilblains: histopathological, immunohistochemical and ultrastructural study of seven paediatric cases. Br J Dermatol. 2020;183:729&#x2013;737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32562567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur KT, Miller EH, Glendinning MD, et al. COVID-19 neuropathology at Columbia University Irving Medical Center/New York Presbyterian Hospital. Brain. 2021;144:2696&#x2013;2708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8083258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33856027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J, Radke J, Dittmayer C, et al. Olfactory transmucosal SARS-CoV-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with COVID-19. Nat Neurosci. 2021;24:168&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Fernandez F, Sandoval Valencia H, Barbella-Aponte RA, et al. Cerebrovascular disease in patients with COVID-19: neuroimaging, histological and clinical description. Brain. 2020;143:3089&#x2013;3103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32645151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fara MG, Stein LK, Skliut M, Morgello S, Fifi JT, Dhamoon MS. Macrothrombosis and stroke in patients with mild Covid-19 infection. J Thromb Haemost. 2020;18:2031&#x2013;2033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7283879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32464707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paniz-Mondolfi A, Bryce C, Grimes Z, et al. Central nervous system involvement by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) J Med Virol. 2020;92:699&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32314810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullock HA, Goldsmith CS, Zaki SR, Martines RB, Miller SE. Difficulties in differentiating coronaviruses from subcellular structures in human tissues by electron microscopy. Emerg Infect Dis. 2021;27:1023&#x2013;1031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8007326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33600302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga Z, Flammer AJ, Steiger P, et al. Electron microscopy of SARS-CoV-2: a challenging task - Authors' reply. Lancet. 2020;395:e100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7237177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon IH, Normandin E, Bhattacharyya S, et al. Neuropathological features of Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:989&#x2013;992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7304421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uginet M, Breville G, Hofmeister J, et al. Cerebrovascular complications and vessel wall imaging in COVID-19 encephalopathy-a pilot study. Clin Neuroradiol. 2021. PMC7995679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7995679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33770199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siow I, Lee KS, Zhang JJY, Saffari SE, Ng A. Encephalitis as a neurological complication of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of incidence, outcomes, and predictors. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28:3491&#x2013;3502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33982853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho CY, Salimian M, Hegert J, et al. Postmortem assessment of olfactory tissue degeneration and microvasculopathy in patients with COVID-19. JAMA Neurol. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9002725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35404378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasilevska V, Guest PC, Bernstein HG, Schroeter ML, Geis C, Steiner J. Molecular mimicry of NMDA receptors may contribute to neuropsychiatric symptoms in severe COVID-19 cases. J Neuroinflammation. 2021;18:245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8551937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34711233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angileri F, Legare S, Gammazza AM, de Macario EC, Macario AJ, Cappello F. Molecular mimicry may explain multi-organ damage in COVID-19. Autoimmun Rev. 2020;19:102591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7289093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32535095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marino Gammazza A, Legare S, Lo Bosco G, et al. Human molecular chaperones share with SARS-CoV-2 antigenic epitopes potentially capable of eliciting autoimmunity against endothelial cells: possible role of molecular mimicry in COVID-19. Cell Stress Chaperones. 2020;25:737&#x2013;741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7402394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32754823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slooter AJC, Otte WM, Devlin JW, et al. Updated nomenclature of delirium and acute encephalopathy: statement of ten Societies. Intensive Care Med. 2020;46:1020&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7210231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32055887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pun BT, Badenes R, La Calle GH, et al. Prevalence and risk factors for delirium in critically ill patients with COVID-19 (COVID-D): a multicentre cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:239&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou SH, Beghi E, Helbok R, et al. Global incidence of neurological manifestations among patients hospitalized with COVID-19-a report for the GCS-NeuroCOVID Consortium and the ENERGY Consortium. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2112131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8114143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33974053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibb K, Seeley A, Quinn T, et al. The consistent burden in published estimates of delirium occurrence in medical inpatients over four decades: a systematic review and meta-analysis study. Age Ageing. 2020;49:352&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32239173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy M, Helfand BKI, Gou RY, et al. Delirium in older patients with COVID-19 presenting to the emergency department. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3:e2029540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7677760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33211114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krewulak KD, Stelfox HT, Leigh JP, Ely EW, Fiest KM. Incidence and prevalence of delirium subtypes in an adult ICU: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Care Med. 2018;46:2029&#x2013;2035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30234569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batra A, Clark JR, Kang AK, Ali S, Patel TR, Shlobin NA, Hoffman SC, Lim PH, Orban ZS, Visvabharathy L, Graham EL, Sullivan DP, Muller WA, Chou SH, Ungv&#xe1;ri Z, Koralnik IJ, Liotta EM. Persistent viral RNA shedding of SARS&#x2011;CoV&#x2011;2 is associated with delirium incidence and six&#x2011;month mortality in hospitalized COVID&#x2011;19 patients. Geroscience. 2022 Jun;44(3):1241&#x2013;1254. 10.1007/s11357-022-00561-z. Epub 2022 May 11. PMID: 35538386; PMCID: PMC9090540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9090540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35538386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sher Y, Rabkin B, Maldonado JR, Mohabir P. COVID-19-associated hyperactive intensive care unit delirium with proposed pathophysiology and treatment: a case report. Psychosomatics. 2020;61:544&#x2013;550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32591212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim B, Cho J, Park JY, Kim HE, Oh J. Delirium and anxiety outcomes related to visiting policy changes in the intensive care unit during the COVID-19 pandemic. Front Aging Neurosci. 2022;14:845105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8926309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragheb J, McKinney A, Zierau M, et al. Delirium and neuropsychological outcomes in critically Ill patients with COVID-19: a cohort study. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e050045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34535480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandharipande PP, Girard TD, Jackson JC, et al. Long-term cognitive impairment after critical illness. N Engl J Med. 2013;369:1306&#x2013;1316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3922401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24088092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard TD, Thompson JL, Pandharipande PP, et al. Clinical phenotypes of delirium during critical illness and severity of subsequent long-term cognitive impairment: a prospective cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2018;6:213&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6709878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29508705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham EL, Clark JR, Orban ZS, et al. Persistent neurologic symptoms and cognitive dysfunction in non-hospitalized Covid-19 "long haulers". Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33755344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouqui P, Amrane S, Million M, et al. Asymptomatic hypoxia in COVID-19 is associated with poor outcome. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;102:233&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7604151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33130200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stubbs DJ, Yamamoto AK, Menon DK. Imaging in sepsis-associated encephalopathy&#x2013;insights and opportunities. Nat Rev Neurol. 2013;9:551&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23999468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandemirli SG, Dogan L, Sarikaya ZT, et al. Brain MRI findings in patients in the intensive care unit with COVID-19 infection. Radiology. 2020;297:E232&#x2013;E235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7507997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32384020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal S, Jain R, Dogra S, et al. Cerebral microbleeds and leukoencephalopathy in critically ill patients with COVID-19. Stroke. 2020;51:2649&#x2013;2655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7434006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32755456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kremer S, Lersy F, Anheim M, et al. Neurologic and neuroimaging findings in patients with COVID-19: a retrospective multicenter study. Neurology. 2020;95:e1868&#x2013;e1882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32680942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kremer S, Lersy F, de Seze J, et al. Brain MRI findings in severe COVID-19: a retrospective observational study. Radiology. 2020;297:E242&#x2013;E251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32544034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke J, Lutgehetmann M, Hagel C, et al. Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19:919&#x2013;929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7535629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deigendesch N, Sironi L, Kutza M, et al. Correlates of critical illness-related encephalopathy predominate postmortem COVID-19 neuropathology. Acta Neuropathol. 2020;140:583&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7449525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32851506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fifth ed. Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders. Am Psychiatric Assoc. 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devlin JW, Skrobik Y, Gelinas C, et al. Clinical practice guidelines for the prevention and management of pain, agitation/sedation, delirium, immobility, and sleep disruption in adult patients in the ICU. Crit Care Med. 2018;46:e825&#x2013;e873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30113379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijdicks EF, Bamlet WR, Maramattom BV, Manno EM, McClelland RL. Validation of a new coma scale: The FOUR score. Ann Neurol. 2005;58:585&#x2013;593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16178024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teasdale G, Jennett B. Assessment of coma and impaired consciousness. A practical scale. Lancet. 1974;2:81&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4136544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel SB, Poston JT, Pohlman A, Hall JB, Kress JP. Rapidly reversible, sedation-related delirium versus persistent delirium in the intensive care unit. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2014;189:658&#x2013;665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24423152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharyya S, Darby RR, Raibagkar P, Gonzalez Castro LN, Berkowitz AL. Antibiotic-associated encephalopathy. Neurology. 2016;86:963&#x2013;971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26888997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salerno D, Marik PE, Daskalakis C, Kolm P, Leone F. The role of head computer tomographic scans on the management of MICU patients with neurological dysfunction. J Intensive Care Med. 2009;24:372&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19875389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radmanesh A, Raz E, Zan E, Derman A, Kaminetzky M. Brain imaging use and findings in COVID-19: a single academic center experience in the epicenter of disease in the United States. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2020;41:1179&#x2013;1183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7357666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32467191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antony AR, Haneef Z. Systematic review of EEG findings in 617 patients diagnosed with COVID-19. Seizure. 2020;83:234&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7569418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33121875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L, Al-Faraj A, Ayub N, et al. Electroencephalographic abnormalities are common in COVID-19 and are associated with outcomes. Ann Neurol. 2021;89:872&#x2013;883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8104061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33704826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellinen J, Carroll E, Friedman D, et al. Continuous EEG findings in patients with COVID-19 infection admitted to a New York academic hospital system. Epilepsia. 2020;61:2097&#x2013;2105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32875578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claassen J, Mayer SA, Kowalski RG, Emerson RG, Hirsch LJ. Detection of electrographic seizures with continuous EEG monitoring in critically ill patients. Neurology. 2004;62:1743&#x2013;1748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15159471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tandon M, Kataria S, Patel J, et al. A comprehensive systematic review of CSF analysis that defines neurological manifestations of COVID-19. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;104:390&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33434662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao A, Rohaut B, Le Guennec L, et al. Severe COVID-19-related encephalitis can respond to immunotherapy. Brain. 2020;143:e102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33064794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugin D, Vargas MI, Thieffry C, et al. COVID-19-related encephalopathy responsive to high-dose glucocorticoids. Neurology. 2020;95:543&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32680950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson RW, Brown RL, Benjamin L, et al. The emerging spectrum of COVID-19 neurology: clinical, radiological and laboratory findings. Brain. 2020;143:3104&#x2013;3120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32637987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group RC. Horby P, Lim WS, et al. Dexamethasone in hospitalized patients with Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:693&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32678530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health NIo. Therapeutic management of hospitalized adults With COVID-19 [online]. 2022. Available at: https://www.covid19treatmentguidelines.nih.gov/management/clinical-management/hospitalized-adults--therapeutic-management/. Accessed 20 May&#xa0;2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kojima Y, Nakakubo S, Takei N, et al. Comparative efficacy of tocilizumab and baricitinib administration in COVID-19 treatment: a retrospective cohort study. Medicina (Kaunas). 2022;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9030469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35454352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegler EL, Kenderian SS. Neurotoxicity and cytokine release syndrome after chimeric antigen receptor T cell therapy: insights into mechanisms and novel therapies. Front Immunol. 2020;11:1973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7485001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32983132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley MS, Smithburger PL, Wong A, et al. Dexmedetomidine for facilitating mechanical ventilation extubation in difficult-to-wean ICU patients: systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical trials. J Intensive Care Med. 2021;36:925&#x2013;936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32627672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groetzinger LM, Rivosecchi RM, Bain W, et al. Ketamine infusion for adjunct sedation in mechanically ventilated adults. Pharmacotherapy. 2018;38:181&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29193185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attaluri P, Castillo A, Edriss H, Nugent K. Thiamine deficiency: an important consideration in critically ill patients. Am J Med Sci. 2018;356:382&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30146080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harper CG, Giles M, Finlay-Jones R. Clinical signs in the Wernicke-Korsakoff complex: a retrospective analysis of 131 cases diagnosed at necropsy. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1986;49:341&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1028756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3701343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzano GS, McEntire CRS, Martinez-Lage M, Mateen FJ, Hutto SK. Acute disseminated encephalomyelitis and acute hemorrhagic leukoencephalitis following COVID-19: systematic review and meta-synthesis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2021;8. PMC8404207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8404207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34452974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriguchi T, Harii N, Goto J, et al. A first case of meningitis/encephalitis associated with SARS-Coronavirus-2. Int J Infect Dis. 2020;94:55&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valencia Sanchez C, Theel E, Binnicker M, Toledano M, McKeon A. Autoimmune encephalitis after SARS-CoV-2 infection: case frequency, findings, and outcomes. Neurology. 2021;97:e2262&#x2013;e2268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8671045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34635560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panariello A, Bassetti R, Radice A, et al. Anti-NMDA receptor encephalitis in a psychiatric Covid-19 patient: a case report. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:179&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32454137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durovic E, Bien C, Bien CG, Isenmann S. MOG antibody-associated encephalitis secondary to Covid-19: case report. BMC Neurol. 2021;21:414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8549422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34706651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patone M, Handunnetthi L, Saatci D, et al. Neurological complications after first dose of COVID-19 vaccines and SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med. 2021;27:2144&#x2013;2153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8629105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34697502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richie MB. Autoimmune meningitis and encephalitis. Neurol Clin. 2022;40:93&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34798977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trifan G, Goldenberg FD, Caprio FZ, et al. Characteristics of a diverse cohort of stroke patients with SARS-CoV-2 and outcome by sex. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2020;29:105314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32951959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekelis K, Missios S, Ahmad J, et al. Ischemic stroke occurs less frequently in patients with COVID-19: a multicenter cross-sectional study. Stroke. 2020;51:3570&#x2013;3576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7678670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33106109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qureshi AI, Baskett WI, Huang W, et al. Acute ischemic stroke and COVID-19: an analysis of 27 676 patients. Stroke. 2021;52:905&#x2013;912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33535779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaghi S, Ishida K, Torres J, et al. SARS-CoV-2 and stroke in a New York Healthcare System. Stroke. 2020;51:2002&#x2013;2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7258764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32432996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein A, Oldridge O, Schwennesen H, Do D, Cucchiara BL. Acute cerebrovascular events in hospitalized COVID-19 patients. Stroke. 2020;51:e219&#x2013;e222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7386677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32684145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fridman S, Bres Bullrich M, Jimenez-Ruiz A, et al. Stroke risk, phenotypes, and death in COVID-19: systematic review and newly reported cases. Neurology. 2020;95:e3373&#x2013;e3385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32934172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leasure AC, Khan YM, Iyer R, et al. Intracerebral hemorrhage in patients with COVID-19: an analysis from the COVID-19 Cardiovascular Disease Registry. Stroke. 2021;52:e321&#x2013;e323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8238884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34082576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mufti F, Amuluru K, Sahni R, et al. Cerebral venous thrombosis in COVID-19: a New York Metropolitan Cohort Study. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2021;42:1196&#x2013;1200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8324265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33888450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batra A, Clark JR, LaHaye K, et al. Transcranial doppler ultrasound evidence of active cerebral embolization in COVID-19. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2020;30:105542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33341023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxley TJ, Mocco J, Majidi S, et al. Large-vessel stroke as a presenting feature of Covid-19 in the young. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:e60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7207073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32343504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava PK, Zhang S, Xian Y, et al. Acute ischemic stroke in patients with COVID-19: an analysis from Get With The Guidelines-Stroke. Stroke. 2021;52:1826&#x2013;1829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33728926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsanos AH, Palaiodimou L, Zand R, et al. The impact of SARS-CoV-2 on stroke epidemiology and care: a meta-analysis. Ann Neurol. 2021;89:380&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33219563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liotta EM, Prabhakaran S, Sangha RS, et al. Magnesium, hemostasis, and outcomes in patients with intracerebral hemorrhage. Neurology. 2017;89:813&#x2013;819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5580864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28747450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkind MS, Carty CL, O'Meara ES, et al. Hospitalization for infection and risk of acute ischemic stroke: the Cardiovascular Health Study. Stroke. 2011;42:1851&#x2013;1856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3125478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21546476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowan LT, Alonso A, Pankow JS, et al. Hospitalized infection as a trigger for acute ischemic stroke: the Atherosclerosis Risk in Communities Study. Stroke. 2016;47:1612&#x2013;1617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4879064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27165961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng JH, Liu YX, Yuan J, et al. First case of COVID-19 complicated with fulminant myocarditis: a case report and insights. Infection. 2020;48:773&#x2013;777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32277408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long B, Brady WJ, Koyfman A, Gottlieb M. Cardiovascular complications in COVID-19. Am J Emerg Med. 2020;38:1504&#x2013;1507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7165109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32317203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dweck MR, Bularga A, Hahn RT, et al. Global evaluation of echocardiography in patients with COVID-19. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2020;21:949&#x2013;958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7337658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32556199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Shao W, Zhang J, et al. Prevalence of atrial fibrillation and associated mortality among hospitalized patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2021;8:720129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8548384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34722658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatla A, Mayer MM, Adusumalli S, et al. COVID-19 and cardiac arrhythmias. Heart Rhythm. 2020;17:1439&#x2013;1444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7307518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32585191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization ELS. ECMO in COVID-19 [online]. 2022. Available at: https://www.elso.org/Registry/FullCOVID19RegistryDashboard.aspx. Accessed 14 Jan 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher-Sandersjoo A, Thelin EP, Bartek J, Jr, et al. Incidence, outcome, and predictors of intracranial hemorrhage in adult patients on extracorporeal membrane oxygenation: a systematic and narrative review. Front Neurol. 2018;9:548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6043665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30034364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usman AA, Han J, Acker A, et al. A case series of devastating intracranial hemorrhage during venovenous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation for COVID-19. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2020;34:3006&#x2013;3012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32828653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bermea RS, Raz Y, Sertic F, et al. Increased intracranial hemorrhage amid elevated inflammatory markers in those with COVID-19 supported with extracorporeal membrane oxygenation. Shock. 2021;56:206&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10763976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33587724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz JM, Libman RB, Wang JJ, et al. Cerebrovascular complications of COVID-19. Stroke. 2020;51:e227&#x2013;e231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7467046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32757751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang A, Mandigo GK, Yim PD, Meyers PM, Lavine SD. Stroke and mechanical thrombectomy in patients with COVID-19: technical observations and patient characteristics. J Neurointerv Surg. 2020;12:648&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32451359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escalard S, Maier B, Redjem H, et al. Treatment of acute ischemic stroke due to large vessel occlusion with COVID-19: experience from Paris. Stroke. 2020;51:2540&#x2013;2543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7282400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32466736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RC Investigators. AC-a Investigators. A Investigators et al. Therapeutic anticoagulation with heparin in critically ill patients with Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:777&#x2013;789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8362592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34351722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A Investigators. AC-a Investigators. R-C Investigators et al. Therapeutic anticoagulation with heparin in noncritically ill patients with Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:790&#x2013;802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8362594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34351721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sholzberg M, Tang GH, Rahhal H, et al. Effectiveness of therapeutic heparin versus prophylactic heparin on death, mechanical ventilation, or intensive care unit admission in moderately ill patients with covid-19 admitted to hospital: RAPID randomised clinical trial. BMJ. 2021;375:n2400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34649864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spyropoulos AC, Goldin M, Giannis D, et al. Efficacy and safety of therapeutic-dose heparin vs standard prophylactic or intermediate-dose heparins for thromboprophylaxis in high-risk hospitalized patients with COVID-19: the HEP-COVID Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Intern Med. 2021;181:1612&#x2013;1620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8498934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34617959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RECOVERY Collaborative Group. Aspirin in patients admitted to hospital with COVID-19 (RECOVERY): a randomised, controlled, open-label, platform trial. Lancet. 2022;399:143&#x2013;151. PMC8598213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8598213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34800427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott NJ. Inflammatory mediators and modulation of blood-brain barrier permeability. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2000;20:131&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10696506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toscano G, Palmerini F, Ravaglia S, et al. Guillain-Barre syndrome associated with SARS-CoV-2. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:2574&#x2013;2576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7182017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32302082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aladawi M, Elfil M, Abu-Esheh B, et al. Guillain Barre syndrome as a complication of COVID-19: A SYSTEMATIC REView. Can J Neurol Sci. 2022;49:38&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8267336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33949300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keddie S, Pakpoor J, Mousele C, et al. Epidemiological and cohort study finds no association between COVID-19 and Guillain-Barre syndrome. Brain. 2021;144:682&#x2013;693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7799186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33313649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luijten LWG, Leonhard SE, van der Eijk AA, et al. Guillain-Barre syndrome after SARS-CoV-2 infection in an international prospective cohort study. Brain. 2021;144:3392&#x2013;3404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8677532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34553216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheikh KA. Guillain-Barre Syndrome. Continuum (Minneap Minn) 2020;26:1184&#x2013;1204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33002998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menni C, Valdes AM, Freidin MB, et al. Real-time tracking of self-reported symptoms to predict potential COVID-19. Nat Med. 2020;26:1037&#x2013;1040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7751267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32393804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Long COVID or post-COVID conditions [online]. 2022. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html. Accessed 19 May 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27:626&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE, et al. Short-term and long-term rates of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a systematic review. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2128568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34643720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Husain M, Harrison PJ. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 2021;18:e1003773. PMC8478214.&#xa0;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladds E, Rushforth A, Wieringa S, et al. Persistent symptoms after Covid-19: qualitative study of 114 "long Covid" patients and draft quality principles for services. BMC Health Serv Res. 2020;20:1144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7750006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33342437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Estimated COVID-19 Burden [online]. 2021. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/cases-updates/burden.html. Accessed 30 Jan 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Government Accountability Office. Science &amp; Tech Spotlight: Long COVID [online]. 2020. Available at: https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-22-105666. Accessed 27 May 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Bowe B, Xie Y. Long COVID after breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9307472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35614233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Penfold RS, Merino J, et al. Risk factors and disease profile of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection in UK users of the COVID Symptom Study app: a prospective, community-based, nested, case-control study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:43&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34480857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185(881&#x2013;895):e820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold JE, Okyay RA, Licht WE, Hurley DJ. Investigation of long COVID prevalence and its relationship to epstein-barr virus reactivation. Pathogens. 2021;10. PMC8233978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8233978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34204243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali ST, Kang AK, Patel TR, et al. Evolution of neurologic symptoms in non-hospitalized COVID-19 "long haulers". Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9268866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35607826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera JA, Yang D, Medicherla C, et al. Trajectories of neurologic recovery 12 Months after hospitalization for COVID-19: a prospective longitudinal study. Neurology. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9259089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35314503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampshire A, Chatfield DA, MPhil AM, et al. Multivariate profile and acute-phase correlates of cognitive deficits in a COVID-19 hospitalised cohort. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;47:101417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9048584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35505938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amalakanti S, Arepalli KVR, Jillella JP. Cognitive assessment in asymptomatic COVID-19 subjects. Virusdisease. 2021;32:146&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7883942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33614860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q, Zheng B, Daines L, Sheikh A. Long-term sequelae of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of one-year follow-up studies on post-COVID symptoms. Pathogens. 2022;11. PMC8875269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8875269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35215212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spudich S, Nath A. Nervous system consequences of COVID-19. Science. 2022;375:267&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35050660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batra A, Clark JR, Kang AK, et al. Persistent viral RNA shedding of SARS-CoV-2 is associated with delirium incidence and six-month mortality in hospitalized COVID-19 patients. Geroscience. 2022. PMC9090540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9090540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35538386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R, Wang K, Yu J, et al. The spatial and cell-type distribution of SARS-CoV-2 receptor ACE2 in the human and mouse brains. Front Neurol. 2020;11:573095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7855591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33551947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Persistent brainstem dysfunction in long-COVID: a hypothesis. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2021;12:573&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heming M, Li X, Rauber S, et al. Neurological manifestations of COVID-19 feature T cell exhaustion and dedifferentiated monocytes in cerebrospinal fluid. Immunity. 2021;54(164&#x2013;175):e166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7831653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33382973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hattori Y, Hattori K, Machida T, Matsuda N. Vascular endotheliitis associated with infections: Its pathogenetic role and therapeutic implication. Biochem Pharmacol. 2022;197:114909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8743392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35021044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F, et al. SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature. 2022;604:697&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9046077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Million M, Dudouet P, et al. (18)F-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in post-SARS-CoV-2 infection: substrate for persistent/delayed disorders? Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48:592&#x2013;595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7391029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32728799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apple AC, Oddi A, Peluso MJ, et al. Risk factors and abnormal cerebrospinal fluid associate with cognitive symptoms after mild COVID-19. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2022;9:221&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8862406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35043593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziff OJ, Ashton NJ, Mehta PR, et al. Amyloid processing in COVID-19-associated neurological syndromes. J Neurochem. 2022;161:146&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35137414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameres M, Brandstetter S, Toncheva AA, et al. Association of neuronal injury blood marker neurofilament light chain with mild-to-moderate COVID-19. J Neurol. 2020;267:3476&#x2013;3478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7345451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32647900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiello EN, Fiabane E, Manera MR, et al. Screening for cognitive sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a comparison between the Mini-Mental State Examination (MMSE) and the Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA) Neurol Sci. 2022;43:81&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8526352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34668124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, et al. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS ONE. 2020;15:e0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93:1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT, Hamilton FW, Milne A, et al. Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up: results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax. 2021;76:399&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afari N, Buchwald D. Chronic fatigue syndrome: a review. Am J Psychiatry. 2003;160:221&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12562565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrie J, Heitger M, Leathem J, Anderson T, Jones R, Flett R. Mild traumatic brain injury and fatigue: a prospective longitudinal study. Brain Inj. 2010;24:1528&#x2013;1538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21058899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall M. The lasting misery of coronavirus long-haulers. Nature. 2020;585:339&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32929257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai JS, Cella D, Choi S, et al. How item banks and their application can influence measurement practice in rehabilitation medicine: a PROMIS fatigue item bank example. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2011;92:S20&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3696589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21958919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherlinger M, Felten R, Gallais F, et al. Refining "long-COVID" by a prospective multimodal evaluation of patients with long-term symptoms attributed to SARS-CoV-2 infection. Infect Dis Ther. 2021;10:1747&#x2013;1763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8270770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34245450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannum ME, Ramirez VA, Lipson SJ, et al. Objective sensory testing methods reveal a higher prevalence of olfactory loss in COVID-19-positive patients compared to subjective methods: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Chem Senses. 2020;45:865&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33245136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Bartheld CS, Hagen MM, Butowt R. Prevalence of Chemosensory Dysfunction in COVID-19 Patients: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis Reveals Significant Ethnic Differences. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2020;11:2944&#x2013;2961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7571048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32870641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y, Li L, Feng Z, et al. Comparative genetic analysis of the novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV/SARS-CoV-2) receptor ACE2 in different populations. Cell Discov. 2020;6:11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7040011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32133153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schambeck SE, Crowell CS, Wagner KI, et al. Phantosmia, parosmia, and dysgeusia are prolonged and late-onset symptoms of COVID-19. J Clin Med. 2021;10. PMC8618742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8618742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34830550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aragao M, Leal MC, Cartaxo Filho OQ, Fonseca TM, Valenca MM. Anosmia in COVID-19 associated with injury to the olfactory bulbs evident on MRI. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2020;41:1703&#x2013;1706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7583088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32586960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M, Yoo SJ, Clijsters M, et al. Visualizing in deceased COVID-19 patients how SARS-CoV-2 attacks the respiratory and olfactory mucosae but spares the olfactory bulb. Cell. 2021;184(5932&#x2013;5949):e5915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8564600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34798069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butowt R, von Bartheld CS. Anosmia in COVID-19: underlying mechanisms and assessment of an olfactory route to brain infection. Neuroscientist. 2021;27:582&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7488171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32914699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel ZM. Olfactory loss and olfactory training. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2021;147:840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34264287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yom-Tov E, Lekkas D, Jacobson NC. Association of COVID19-induced anosmia and ageusia with depression and suicidal ideation. J Affect Disord Rep. 2021;5:100156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8154197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34075369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaira LA, Hopkins C, Petrocelli M, et al. Efficacy of corticosteroid therapy in the treatment of long- lasting olfactory disorders in COVID-19 patients. Rhinology. 2021;59:21&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33290446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh CV, Jain S, Parveen S, Deshmukh P. The outcome of fluticasone nasal spray on anosmia and triamcinolone oral paste in taste dysgeusia in COVID-19 patients. Am J Otolaryngol. 2021;42:103009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8019654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33846030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelalim AA, Mohamady AA, Elsayed RA, Elawady MA, Ghallab AF. Corticosteroid nasal spray for recovery of smell sensation in COVID-19 patients: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Otolaryngol. 2021;42:102884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33429174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S, Whitelaw S. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) and other autonomic disorders after COVID-19 infection: a case series of 20 patients. Immunol Res. 2021;69:205&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8009458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33786700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak P, Mukerji SS, Alabsi HS, et al. Multisystem involvement in post-acute sequelae of coronavirus disease 19. Ann Neurol. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9011495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34952975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson E, Hemenway AN. A scoping review of pharmacological management of postacute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection in 2021. Am J Ther. 2022;29:e305&#x2013;e321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35383586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P, et al. Autonomic dysfunction in 'long COVID': rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin Med (Lond) 2021;21:e63&#x2013;e67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-de-Las-Penas C, Navarro-Santana M, Gomez-Mayordomo V, et al. Headache as an acute and post-COVID-19 symptom in COVID-19 survivors: a meta-analysis of the current literature. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28:3820&#x2013;3825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34327787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caronna E, Alpuente A, Torres-Ferrus M, Pozo-Rosich P. Toward a better understanding of persistent headache after mild COVID-19: three migraine-like yet distinct scenarios. Headache. 2021;61:1277&#x2013;1280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34363619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uygun O, Ertas M, Ekizoglu E, et al. Headache characteristics in COVID-19 pandemic-a survey study. J Headache Pain. 2020;21:121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7552597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33050880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Azorin D, Layos-Romero A, Porta-Etessam J, et al. Post-COVID-19 persistent headache: a multicentric 9-months follow-up study of 905 patients. Cephalalgia. 2022:3331024211068074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35166156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goadsby PJ, Holland PR, Martins-Oliveira M, Hoffmann J, Schankin C, Akerman S. Pathophysiology of migraine: a disorder of sensory processing. Physiol Rev. 2017;97:553&#x2013;622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5539409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28179394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolay H, Gul A, Baykan B. COVID-19 is a real headache! Headache. 2020;60:1415&#x2013;1421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32412101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krymchantowski AV, Silva-Neto RP, Jevoux C, Krymchantowski AG. Indomethacin for refractory COVID or post-COVID headache: a retrospective study. Acta Neurol Belg. 2022;122:465&#x2013;469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8453033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34546559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oaklander AL, Mills AJ, Kelley M, et al. Peripheral neuropathy evaluations of patients with prolonged long COVID. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2022;9. PMC8889896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8889896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35232750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aksan F, Nelson EA, Swedish KA. A COVID-19 patient with intense burning pain. J Neurovirol. 2020;26:800&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7416991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32779108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almufarrij I, Munro KJ. One year on: an updated systematic review of SARS-CoV-2, COVID-19 and audio-vestibular symptoms. Int J Audiol. 2021;60:935&#x2013;945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33750252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motawea KR, Monib FA. New onset vertigo after COVID-19 infection. A case report. Indian J Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2021:1&#x2013;3. PMC8255056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8255056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34249665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picciotti PM, Passali GC, Sergi B, De Corso E. Benign paroxysmal positional vertigo (BPPV) in COVID-19. Audiol Res. 2021;11:418&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8395413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34449541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cree BA, Kornyeyeva E, Goodin DS. Pilot trial of low-dose naltrexone and quality of life in multiple sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2010;68:145&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20695007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patten DK, Schultz BG, Berlau DJ. The safety and efficacy of low-dose naltrexone in the management of chronic pain and inflammation in multiple sclerosis, fibromyalgia, Crohn's disease, and other chronic pain disorders. Pharmacotherapy. 2018;38:382&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29377216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters KB, Affronti ML, Woodring S, et al. Effects of low-dose naltrexone on quality of life in high-grade glioma patients: a placebo-controlled, double-blind randomized trial. Support Care Cancer. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35001215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Pilot study into LDN and NAD+ for treatment of patients with post-COVID-19 syndrome [online]. 2020. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04604704. Accessed 30 Jan 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto Y, Suzuki T, Hashimoto K. Mechanisms of action of fluvoxamine for COVID-19: a historical review. Mol Psychiatry. 2022. PMC8739627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8739627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34997196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>See I, Su JR, Lale A, et al. US case reports of cerebral venous sinus thrombosis with thrombocytopenia after Ad26.COV2.S Vaccination, March 2 to April 21, 2021. JAMA. 2021;325:2448&#x2013;2456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8087975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33929487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacNeil JR, Su JR, Broder KR, et al. Updated Recommendations from the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices for Use of the Janssen (Johnson &amp; Johnson) COVID-19 vaccine after reports of thrombosis with thrombocytopenia syndrome among vaccine recipients - United States, April 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2021;70:651&#x2013;656. PMC8084127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8084127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33914723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo EJ, Mba-Jonas A, Dimova RB, Alimchandani M, Zinderman CE, Nair N. Association of receipt of the Ad26.COV2.S COVID-19 vaccine with presumptive Guillain-Barre syndrome, February-July 2021. JAMA. 2021;326:1606&#x2013;1613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8498927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34617967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera JA, Tamborska AA, Doheim MF, et al. Neurological events reported after COVID-19 vaccines: an analysis of VAERS. Ann Neurol. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9082459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35233819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali ST, Kang AK, Patel TR, Clark JR, Perez-Giraldo GS, Orban ZS, Lim PH, Jimenez M, Graham EL, Batra A, Liotta EM, Koralnik I. Evolution of neurologic symptoms in non-hospitalized COVID-19 &#x201c;long haulers&#x201d;. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2022 May 24. 10.1002/acn3.51570. Epub ahead of print. PMID: 35607826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9268866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35607826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin R. As their numbers grow, COVID-19 "long haulers" stump experts. JAMA. 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32965460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asbring P, Narvanen AL. Women's experiences of stigma in relation to chronic fatigue syndrome and fibromyalgia. Qual Health Res. 2002;12:148&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11837367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner P. For 7 weeks I have been through a roller coaster of ill health, extreme emotions, and utter exhaustion. BMJ Opinion. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO COVID-19 Case definition [online]. 2020. Available at: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Surveillance_Case_Definition-2020.2. Accessed 24 May 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelhak A, Huss A, Kassubek J, Tumani H, Otto M. Serum GFAP as a biomarker for disease severity in multiple sclerosis. Sci Rep. 2018;8:14798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6172254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30287870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe M, Nakamura Y, Michalak Z, et al. Serum GFAP and neurofilament light as biomarkers of disease activity and disability in NMOSD. Neurology. 2019;93:e1299&#x2013;e1311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31471502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutter R, Hert L, De Marchis GM, et al. Serum neurofilament light chain levels in the intensive care unit: comparison between severely ill patients with and without coronavirus disease 2019. Ann Neurol. 2021;89:610&#x2013;616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33377539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung HY, Neu C, Wickel J, Kuckertz SL, Coldewey SM. Neurofilament light chain in patients with COVID-19 and bacterial pneumonia. Ann Neurol. 2021;90:174&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8222870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34036618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper J, Stukas S, Hoiland RL, et al. Quantification of neurological blood-based biomarkers in critically ill patients with coronavirus disease 2019. Crit Care Explor. 2020;2:e0238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7535554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33063038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanberg N, Simren J, Eden A, et al. Neurochemical signs of astrocytic and neuronal injury in acute COVID-19 normalizes during long-term follow-up. EBioMedicine. 2021;70:103512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8320425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34333238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson BA, Visvabharathy L, Ali ST, et al. Plasma biomarkers of neuropathogenesis in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 and those with postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflammation. 2022;9:e1151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8901169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35256481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geis T, Brandstetter S, Toncheva AA, et al. Serum neurofilament light chain (sNfL) values in a large cross-sectional population of children with asymptomatic to moderate COVID-19. J Neurol. 2021;268:3969&#x2013;3974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8064423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33893540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanberg N, Ashton NJ, Andersson LM, et al. Neurochemical evidence of astrocytic and neuronal injury commonly found in COVID-19. Neurology. 2020;95:e1754&#x2013;e1759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32546655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiskopf D, Schmitz KS, Raadsen MP, et al. Phenotype and kinetics of SARS-CoV-2-specific T cells in COVID-19 patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome. Sci Immunol. 2020;5. PMC7319493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7319493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32591408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-On YM, Goldberg Y, Mandel M, et al. Protection of BNT162b2 vaccine booster against Covid-19 in Israel. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:1393&#x2013;1400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8461568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34525275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visvabharathy L, Hanson B, Orban Z, et al. Neuro-COVID long-haulers exhibit broad dysfunction in T cell memory generation and responses to vaccination. Available at: https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.08.08.21261763v1?rss=1. medRxiv. 2021. PMC8366804.&#xa0;Accesed 20 May 2022. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.08.08.21261763v1?rss=1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khandia R, Singhal S, Alqahtani T, et al. Emergence of SARS-CoV-2 Omicron (B.1.1.529) variant, salient features, high global health concerns and strategies to counter it amid ongoing COVID-19 pandemic. Environ Res. 2022:112816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8798788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35093310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nortwestern Medicine. Northwestern Medicine Comprehensive COVID-19 Center [online]. 2020. Available at: https://www.nm.org/conditions-and-care-areas/infectious-disease/covid-19-overview/comprehensive-care-after-covid-19. Accessed 25 May 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health. Recover: Researching COVID to Enhance Recovery [online]. 2022. Available at: https://recovercovid.org/. Accessed 25 May /2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohrs R. &#x2018;A slow-moving glacier&#x2019;: NIH&#x2019;s sluggish and often opaque efforts to study long Covid draw patient, expert ire [online]. 2022. Available at: https://www.statnews.com/2022/03/29/nih-long-covid-sluggish-study/. Accessed 25 May 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issuu.com. Getting to and sustaining the next normal: a roadmap to living with COVID [online]. 2022. Available at: https://issuu.com/covidstrategy/docs/covidnextnormal_ee2307fb01e43f/2?ff. Accessed 24 May 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patient-Led Research Collaborative. Open Letter regarding the RECOVER initiative to study Long COVID [online]. 2021. Available at: https://patientresearchcovid19.com/open-letter-regarding-the-recover-initiative-to-study-long-covid/. Accessed 24 May 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Body Politic. Open letter to the NIH [online]. 2021. Available at: https://www.wearebodypolitic.com/bodytype/2021/4/22/open-letter-to-nih. Accessed 24 May 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collaborators GUND, Feigin VL, Vos T, et al. Burden of neurological disorders across the US From 1990&#x2013;2017: a global burden of disease study. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78:165&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7607495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33136137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balcom EF, Nath A, Power C. Acute and chronic neurological disorders in COVID-19: potential mechanisms of disease. Brain. 2021;144:3576&#x2013;3588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8719840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34398188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>