<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37719243</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1810-6838</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Breathe (Sheffield, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Breathe (Sheff)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Holistic management of patients with progressive pulmonary fibrosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>230101</StartPage><MedlinePgn>230101</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">230101</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1183/20734735.0101-2023</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Progressive pulmonary fibrosis (PF) is a complex interstitial lung disease that impacts substantially on patients' daily lives, requiring personalised and integrated care. We summarise the main needs of patients with PF and their caregivers, and suggest a supportive care approach. Individualised care, education, emotional and psychological support, specialised treatments, and better access to information and resources are necessary. Management should start at diagnosis, be tailored to the patient's needs, and consider end-of-life care. Pharmacological and non-pharmacological interventions should be individualised, including oxygen therapy and pulmonary rehabilitation, with digital healthcare utilised as appropriate. Further research is needed to address technical issues related to oxygen delivery and digital healthcare.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="EDUCATIONAL AIMS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To identify the main needs of patients with PF and their caregivers.To describe the components of a comprehensive approach to a supportive care programme for patients with PF.To identify further areas of research to address technical issues related to the management of patients with PF.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9;ERS 2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Ana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4516-6904</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lab 3R Respiratory Research and Rehabilitation Laboratory, School of Health Sciences, University of Aveiro (ESSUA), IBMED Aveiro PT, Aveiro, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Rehabilitation Science, Faculty of Health Science, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fabbri</LastName><ForeName>Gaia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Respiratory Diseases and Lung Transplantation Unit, Department of Medical and Surgical Sciences and Neuro-Sciences, University of Siena, Siena, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gille</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1577-6595</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inserm U1272 "Hypoxia &amp; the Lung", UFR SMBH L&#xe9;onard de Vinci, Universit&#xe9; Sorbonne Paris Nord, Bobigny, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service Physiologie et Explorations Fonctionnelles, H&#xf4;pitaux Universitaires de Paris Seine-Saint-Denis, Assistance Publique - H&#xf4;pitaux de Paris, Bobigny, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bargagli</LastName><ForeName>Elena</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Respiratory Diseases and Lung Transplantation Unit, Department of Medical and Surgical Sciences and Neuro-Sciences, University of Siena, Siena, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duchemann</LastName><ForeName>Boris</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0872-2983</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inserm U1272 "Hypoxia &amp; the Lung", UFR SMBH L&#xe9;onard de Vinci, Universit&#xe9; Sorbonne Paris Nord, Bobigny, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service d'oncologie m&#xe9;dicale et thoracique, H&#xf4;pitaux Universitaires de Paris Seine-Saint-Denis, Assistance Publique - H&#xf4;pitaux de Paris, Bobigny, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Evans</LastName><ForeName>Rachel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Sciences, University of Leicester, Glenfield Hospital, Leicester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinnock</LastName><ForeName>Hilary</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5976-8386</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Allergy and Respiratory Research Group, Usher Institute, The University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holland</LastName><ForeName>Anne E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2061-845X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Clinical School, Monash University and Department of Physiotherapy, Alfred Health, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Renzoni</LastName><ForeName>Elisabetta</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interstitial Lung Disease Unit, Royal Brompton and Harefield Clinical Group, Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Margaret Turner Warwick Centre for Fibrosing Lung Diseases, NHLI, Imperial College, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ekstr&#xf6;m</LastName><ForeName>Magnus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7227-5113</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lund University, Faculty of Medicine, Department of Clinical Sciences Lund, Respiratory Medicine, Allergology and Palliative Medicine, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Pulmonary Fibrosis Federation, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wijsenbeek</LastName><ForeName>Marlies</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Expertise for Interstitial Lung Disease and Sarcoidosis, Department of Respiratory Medicine, Erasmus MC, University Medical Centre, Rotterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dinh-Xuan</LastName><ForeName>Anh Tuan</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8651-5176</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service de Physiologie-Explorations Fonctionnelles, Assistance Publique-H&#xf4;pitaux de Paris, H&#xf4;pital Cochin, Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vagheggini</LastName><ForeName>Guido</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6733-2809</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine and Medical Specialties, Respiratory Failure Pathway, Azienda USL Toscana Nordovest, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fondazione Volterra Ricerche ONLUS, Volterra (PI), Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Breathe (Sheff)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101231007</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1810-6838</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Breathe (Sheff). 2023 Sep;19(3):230147. doi: 10.1183/20734735.0147-2023</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37732949</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest: T. Gille reports personal fees from Boehringer Ingelheim, personal fees from Roche, non-financial support from Oxyvie (oxygen provider), non-financial support from LVL Medical (oxygen provider), non-financial support from Vitalaire (oxygen provider), non-financial support from Asten (oxygen provider), outside the submitted work. B. Duchemann reports personal payments for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events for Roche, Pfizer, AstraZeneca, Chiesi, Amgen, Lilly, Medscape, MSD and Sanofi, outside the submitted work; and support for attending meetings and/or travel from AZ, Pfizer, Oxyvie and MSD, outside the submitted work. R. Evans reports grants or contract from NIHR, UKRI, Wolfson Foundation, Genentec, and Roche, outside the submitted work; consulting fees from AstraZeneca, and Evidera for Long COVID, outside the submitted work; speaker fees from Boehringer and Moderna, outside the submitted work; support received from Chiesi to attend BTS virtually 2021, outside the submitted work; and ERS Group 01.02 Pulmonary Rehabilitation and Chronic Care Secretary and ATS Pulmonary Rehabilitation Assembly Chair, both unpaid, outside the submitted work. H. Pinnock reports speaker fees from TEVA pharmaceuticals, and Sandoz, outside the submitted work. A.E. Holland is President, Thoracic Society of Australia and New Zealand, unpaid position, outside the submitted work. E. Renzoni reports grants or contracts from Boehringer Ingelheim, outside the submitted work; payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events from Boehringer Ingelheim and Chiesi, outside the submitted work; support for attending meetings and/or travel from Boehringer Ingelheim, outside the submitted work; and advisory boards for Boehringer Ingelheim and Roche, outside the submitted work. S. Jones reports payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events from various pharmaceutical companies for tasks and participation in patient organisation advisory groups. All payments made to either the European Pulmonary Fibrosis Federation (EU-PFF) or the UK charity Action for Pulmonary Fibrosis, outside the submitted work; participation on a Data Safety Monitoring Board or Advisory Board for Galecto, outside the submitted work; and President of European Pulmonary Fibrosis Federation, and Chair of Trustees for Action for Pulmonary Fibrosis, outside the submitted work. M. Wijsenbeek reports grants or contracts from Boehringer Ingelheim, Hoffman la Roche, The Netherlands Organisation for Health Research and Development, The Dutch Lung Foundation, The Dutch Pulmonary Fibrosis patient association, the sarcoidosis patient association, and Astra Zeneca/Daiichi, outside the submitted work; consulting fees from AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Boehringer Ingelheim, CSL Behring, Galapagos, Galecto, Hoffman La Roche, Horizon Therapeutics, Kinevant Sciences, Molecure, Nerre Therapeutics, Novartis, PureTech Health, Respivant, Thyron, Trevi and Vicore, outside the submitted work; payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events from Boehringer Ingelheim, CSL Behring, Galapagos, and Hoffman la Roche, outside the submitted work; support for attending meetings and/or travel from Boehringer Ingelheim, Galapagos and Hoffman la Roche, outside the submitted work; Monitoring Board or Advisory Board for Galapagos, outside the submitted work; Chair of the Idiopathic Interstitial Pneumonia group of the European Respiratory Society; Member of the board of the Netherlands Respiratory Society; Member of the scientific advisory board of the European Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis and related disorders federation; and Chair of the educational committee of the European Reference Network for Rare Lung Diseases, unpaid positions, outside the submitted work. G. Vagheggini reports unrestricted educational grants from Chiesi Farmaceutici S.p.A and from A. Menarini Industrie Farmaceutiche Riunite srl. The remaining authors have nothing to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37719243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10501708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/20734735.0101-2023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">EDU-0101-2023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Carvajalino S, Reigada C, Johnson MJ, et al. . Symptom prevalence of patients with fibrotic interstitial lung disease: a systematic literature review. BMC Pulm Med 2018; 18: 78. doi:10.1186/s12890-018-0651-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-018-0651-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5964639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29788938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijsenbeek MS, Holland AE, Swigris JJ, et al. . Comprehensive supportive care for patients with fibrosing interstitial lung disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2019; 200: 152&#x2013;159. doi:10.1164/rccm.201903-0614PP</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.201903-0614PP</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31051080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Respiratory Society . Symposium: Holistic management and rehabilitation of fibrosing interstitial lung diseases. ERS International Congress, Barcelona, 2022. Date last updated 4 September 2022.
www.ers-education.org/events/international-congress/barcelona-2022.aspx?idP=267558</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JYT, Tikellis G, Corte TJ, et al. . The supportive care needs of people living with pulmonary fibrosis and their caregivers: a systematic review. Eur Respir Rev 2020; 29: 190125. doi:10.1183/16000617.0125-2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/16000617.0125-2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9488682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32350085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spagnolo P, Ryerson CJ, Putman R, et al. . Early diagnosis of fibrotic interstitial lung disease: challenges and opportunities. Lancet Respir Med 2021; 9: 1065&#x2013;1076. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00017-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00017-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34331867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghu G, Remy-Jardin M, Richeldi L, et al. . Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (an Update) and Progressive Pulmonary Fibrosis in Adults: An Official ATS/ERS/JRS/ALAT Clinical Practice Guideline. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2022; 205: e18&#x2013;e47. doi:10.1164/rccm.202202-0399ST</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202202-0399ST</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9851481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35486072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flaherty KR, King TE, Jr, Raghu G, et al. . Idiopathic interstitial pneumonia: what is the effect of a multidisciplinary approach to diagnosis? Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2004; 170: 904&#x2013;910. doi:10.1164/rccm.200402-147OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.200402-147OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15256390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoyer N, Prior TS, Bendstrup E, et al. . Risk factors for diagnostic delay in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Respir Res 2019; 20: 103. doi:10.1186/s12931-019-1076-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-019-1076-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6534848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31126287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brereton CJ, Wallis T, Casey M, et al. . Time taken from primary care referral to a specialist centre diagnosis of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: an opportunity to improve patient outcomes? ERJ Open Res 2020; 6: 00120-2020. doi:10.1183/23120541.00120-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00120-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7369434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32714958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijsenbeek M, Bendstrup E, Valenzuela C, et al. . Design of a study assessing disease behaviour during the peri-diagnostic period in patients with interstitial lung disease: the STARLINER study. Adv Ther 2019; 36: 232&#x2013;243. doi:10.1007/s12325-018-0845-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12325-018-0845-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6318228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30506309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JH, Cottin V. Care delivery models and interstitial lung disease: the role of the specialized center. Clin Chest Med 2021; 42: 347&#x2013;355. doi:10.1016/j.ccm.2021.03.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccm.2021.03.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tikellis G, Corte TJ, Teoh AKY, et al. . Barriers and facilitators to best care for idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis in Australia. Respirology 2022; 27: 76&#x2013;84. doi:10.1111/resp.14185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.14185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34783108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moor CC, Wijsenbeek MS, Balestro E, et al. . Gaps in care of patients living with pulmonary fibrosis: a joint patient and expert statement on the results of a Europe-wide survey. ERJ Open Res 2019; 5: 00124-2019. doi:10.1183/23120541.00124-2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00124-2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6801215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31649949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonella F, Wijsenbeek M, Molina-Molina M, et al. . European IPF Patient Charter: unmet needs and a call to action for healthcare policymakers. Eur Respir J 2016; 47: 597&#x2013;606. doi:10.1183/13993003.01204-2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.01204-2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26585424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sgalla G, Iovene B, Calvello M, et al. . Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: pathogenesis and management. Respir Res 2018; 19: 32. doi:10.1186/s12931-018-0730-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-018-0730-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5824456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29471816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oshima A, Nishimura A, Chen-Yoshikawa TF, et al. . Nutrition-related factors associated with waiting list mortality in patients with interstitial lung disease: A retrospective cohort study. Clin Transplant 2019; 33: e13566. doi:10.1111/ctr.13566</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ctr.13566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31002178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanjrawi AA, Mathers L, Webster S, et al. . Nutritional status and quality of life in interstitial lung disease: a prospective cohort study. BMC Pulm Med 2021; 21: 51. doi:10.1186/s12890-021-01418-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-021-01418-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7863253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33546667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi S, Gilliland J, O'Connor C, et al. . Exercise capacity and its relationship with body composition and nutrition status in patients with interstitial lung disease. Nutr Clin Pract 2021; 36: 891&#x2013;898. doi:10.1002/ncp.10651</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ncp.10651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33786852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi S, Gilliland J, O'Connor C, et al. . Fat-free mass index controlled for age and sex and malnutrition are predictors of survival in interstitial lung disease. Respiration 2021; 100: 379&#x2013;386. doi:10.1159/000512732</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000512732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33721868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi S, Balsillie C, Truchon C, et al. . Nutrition implications of intrinsic restrictive lung disease. Nutr Clin Pract 2022; 37: 239&#x2013;255. doi:10.1002/ncp.10849</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ncp.10849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35253924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen DJA, Bajwah S, Boon MH, et al. . European Respiratory Society Clinical Practice Guideline: Palliative care for people with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease or interstitial lung disease. Eur Respir J 2023; 62: 2202014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37290789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein S, Logan A, Lindell KO. A scoping review of unmet needs of caregivers of patients with pulmonary fibrosis. Curr Opin Support Palliat Care 2021; 15: 226&#x2013;232. doi:10.1097/SPC.0000000000000571</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SPC.0000000000000571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34762072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillett M, Hope-Gill B. Telephone clinics during the COVID-19 pandemic-the experiences of interstitial lung disease patients and their carers. J Patient Exp 2022; 9: 23743735221133638. doi:10.1177/23743735221133638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23743735221133638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9623361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36330230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampson C, Gill BH, Harrison NK, et al. . The care needs of patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis and their carers (CaNoPy): results of a qualitative study. BMC Pulm Med 2015; 15: 155. doi:10.1186/s12890-015-0145-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-015-0145-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4670492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26637194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramadurai D, Corder S, Churney T, et al. . Understanding the informational needs of patients with IPF and their caregivers: &#x2018;You get diagnosed, and you ask this question right away, what does this mean?'. BMJ Open Qual 2018; 7: e000207. doi:10.1136/bmjoq-2017-000207</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjoq-2017-000207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5812387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29464212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell AM, Olive S, Lines S, et al. . Contemporary challenges for specialist nursing in interstitial lung disease. Breathe 2018; 14: 36&#x2013;41. doi:10.1183/20734735.014917</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/20734735.014917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5832013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29515666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almond H. Patient support groups are a lifeline for those with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Lancet Respir Med 2020; 8: 959&#x2013;961. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30067-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30067-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32059804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cottin V, Teague R, Nicholson L, et al. . The burden of progressive-fibrosing interstitial lung diseases. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022; 9: 799912. doi:10.3389/fmed.2022.799912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.799912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8843847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35178411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swigris JJ, Brown KK, Abdulqawi R, et al. . Patients&#x2019; perceptions and patient-reported outcomes in progressive-fibrosing interstitial lung diseases. Eur Respir Rev 2018; 27: 180075. doi:10.1183/16000617.0075-2018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/16000617.0075-2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9489034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30578334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wuyts WA, Papiris S, Manali E, et al. . The burden of progressive fibrosing interstitial lung disease: a DELPHI approach. Adv Ther 2020; 37: 3246&#x2013;3264. doi:10.1007/s12325-020-01384-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12325-020-01384-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7467418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32445186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swigris J, Cutts K, Male N, et al. . The Living with Pulmonary Fibrosis questionnaire in progressive fibrosing interstitial lung disease. ERJ Open Res 2021; 7: 00145-2020. doi:10.1183/23120541.00145-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00145-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8141833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34046493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podolanczuk AJ, Thomson CC, Remy-Jardin M, et al. . Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: state of the art for 2023. Eur Respir J 2023; 61: 2200957. doi:10.1183/13993003.00957-2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00957-2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36702498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Donnell DE, Ora J, Webb KA, et al. . Mechanisms of activity-related dyspnea in pulmonary diseases. Respir Physiol Neurobiol 2009; 167: 116&#x2013;132. doi:10.1016/j.resp.2009.01.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resp.2009.01.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19450767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaspole IN, Chapman SA, Cooper WA, et al. . Health-related quality of life in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: data from the Australian IPF Registry. Respirology 2017; 22: 950&#x2013;956. doi:10.1111/resp.12989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.12989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28166611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kronborg-White S, Andersen CU, Kohberg C, et al. . Palliation of chronic breathlessness with morphine in patients with fibrotic interstitial lung disease - a randomised placebo-controlled trial. Respir Res 2020; 21: 195. doi:10.1186/s12931-020-01452-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-020-01452-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7376842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32703194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verberkt CA, van den Beuken-van Everdingen MHJ, Schols J, et al. . Effect of sustained-release morphine for refractory breathlessness in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease on health status: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Intern Med 2020; 180: 1306&#x2013;1314. doi:10.1001/jamainternmed.2020.3134</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2020.3134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7432282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32804188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstr&#xf6;m M, Ferreira D, Chang S, et al. . Effect of regular, low-dose, extended-release morphine on chronic breathlessness in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: the BEAMS randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2022; 328: 2022&#x2013;2032. doi:10.1001/jama.2022.20206</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.20206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9682426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36413230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michele RS, Christopher JR, Andrew HR, et al. . Effects of hyperoxia on dyspnoea and exercise endurance in fibrotic interstitial lung disease. Eur Respir J 2017; 49: 1602494. doi:10.1183/13993003.02494-2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02494-2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28546272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khor YH, Gutman L, Abu Hussein N, et al. . Incidence and prognostic significance of hypoxemia in fibrotic interstitial lung disease: an international cohort study. Chest 2021; 160: 994&#x2013;1005. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2021.04.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2021.04.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33905679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng JZ, Wilcox PG, Glaspole I, et al. . Cough is less common and less severe in systemic sclerosis-associated interstitial lung disease compared to other fibrotic interstitial lung diseases. Respirology 2017; 22: 1592&#x2013;1597. doi:10.1111/resp.13084</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.13084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28544079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, White E, Freiheit E, et al. . Cough-specific quality of life predicts disease progression among patients with interstitial lung disease: data from the pulmonary fibrosis foundation patient registry. Chest 2022; 162: 603&#x2013;613. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2022.03.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2022.03.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9808640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35337809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algamdi M, Sadatsafavi M, Fisher JH, et al. . Costs of workplace productivity loss in patients with fibrotic interstitial lung disease. Chest 2019; 156: 887&#x2013;895. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2019.04.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2019.04.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31051170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birring SS, Kavanagh JE, Irwin RS, et al. . Treatment of interstitial lung disease associated cough: CHEST guideline and expert panel report. Chest 2018; 154: 904&#x2013;917. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2018.06.038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2018.06.038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30036496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed S, Steer J, Ellis J, et al. . Nonpharmacological cough control therapy for chronic refractory cough and cough associated with underlying lung disease. ERJ Open Res 2020; 6: 00243-2019. doi:10.1183/23120541.00243-2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00243-2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7073411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32201684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan NSH, Moore I, Lake F. Understanding cough in interstitial lung disease: a cross-sectional study on the adequacy of treatment. Intern Med J 2021; 51: 923&#x2013;929. doi:10.1111/imj.14837</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/imj.14837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32237099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satia I, Wahab M, Kum E, et al. . Chronic cough: Investigations, management, current and future treatments. Can J Respir Crit 2021; 5: 404&#x2013;416. doi:10.1080/24745332.2021.1979904</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24745332.2021.1979904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilicic AM, Oliveira A, Habash R, et al. . Non-pharmacological management of non-productive chronic cough in adults: a systematic review. Front Rehabil Sci 2022; 3: 905257. doi:10.3389/fresc.2022.905257</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fresc.2022.905257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9397766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36188925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasouki S, Quach S, Mancopes R, et al. . A non-pharmacological cough therapy for people with interstitial lung diseases: a case report. Physiother Can 2022; in press [10.3138/ptc-2021-0081].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3138/ptc-2021-0081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10686298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38037577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahlmann V, Moor CC, Wijsenbeek MS. Managing fatigue in patients with interstitial lung disease. Chest 2020; 158: 2026&#x2013;2033. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2020.04.047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2020.04.047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7674989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yohannes AM. Depression and anxiety in patients with interstitial lung disease. Expert Rev Respir Med 2020; 14: 859&#x2013;862. doi:10.1080/17476348.2020.1776118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17476348.2020.1776118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32460643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon CS, Waller JW, Cook RM, et al. . Effect of pulmonary rehabilitation on symptoms of anxiety and depression in COPD: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Chest 2019; 156: 80&#x2013;91. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2019.04.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2019.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31034818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghu G, Collard HR, Egan JJ, et al. . An official ATS/ERS/JRS/ALAT statement: idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: evidence-based guidelines for diagnosis and management. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2011; 183: 788&#x2013;824. doi:10.1164/rccm.2009-040GL</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.2009-040GL</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5450933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21471066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jo HE, Troy LK, Keir G, et al. . Treatment of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis in Australia and New Zealand: a position statement from the Thoracic Society of Australia and New Zealand and the Lung Foundation Australia. Respirology 2017; 22: 1436&#x2013;1458. doi:10.1111/resp.13146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.13146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28845557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Plessis JP, Fernandes S, Jamal R, et al. . Exertional hypoxemia is more severe in fibrotic interstitial lung disease than in COPD. Respirology 2018; 23: 392&#x2013;398. doi:10.1111/resp.13226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.13226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29193512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs SS, Krishnan JA, Lederer DJ, et al. . Home oxygen therapy for adults with chronic lung disease. An Official American Thoracic Society Clinical Practice Guideline. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2020; 202: e121&#x2013;e141. doi:10.1164/rccm.202009-3608ST</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202009-3608ST</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7667898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33185464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visca D, Mori L, Tsipouri V, et al. . Effect of ambulatory oxygen on quality of life for patients with fibrotic lung disease (AmbOx): a prospective, open-label, mixed-method, crossover randomised controlled trial. Lancet Respir Med 2018; 6: 759&#x2013;770. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(18)30289-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(18)30289-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30170904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardinge M, Annandale J, Bourne S, et al. . British Thoracic Society guidelines for home oxygen use in adults: accredited by NICE. Thorax 2015; 70: Suppl. 1, i1&#x2013;i43. doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2015-206865</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2015-206865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25870317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald CF, Whyte K, Jenkins S, et al. . Clinical practice guideline on adult domiciliary oxygen therapy: executive summary from the Thoracic Society of Australia and New Zealand. Respirology 2016; 21: 76&#x2013;78. doi:10.1111/resp.12678</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.12678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4738443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26599614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacasse Y, S&#xe9;ri&#xe8;s F, Corbeil F, et al. . Randomized trial of nocturnal oxygen in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. N Engl J Med 2020; 383: 1129&#x2013;1138. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2013219</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2013219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32937046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adir Y, Humbert M, Chaouat A. Sleep-related breathing disorders and pulmonary hypertension. Eur Respir J 2021; 57: 2002258. doi:10.1183/13993003.02258-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02258-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32747397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison AC, Robinson JF, Tu L, et al. . Multidisciplinary care and prognosis in patients with COPD and interstitial lung disease prescribed long-term oxygen therapy. Respir Care 2022; 67: 667&#x2013;675. doi:10.4187/respcare.09446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4187/respcare.09446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35504724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barratt SL, Morales M, Speirs T, et al. . Specialist palliative care, psychology, interstitial lung disease (ILD) multidisciplinary team meeting: a novel model to address palliative care needs. BMJ Open Respir Res 2018; 5: e000360. doi:10.1136/bmjresp-2018-000360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjresp-2018-000360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6307575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30622718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassidy N, Fox L, Love M, et al. . Fibrotic interstitial lung disease - palliative care needs: a World-Caf&#xe9; qualitative study. BMJ Support Palliat Care 2021; in press [10.1136/bmjspcare-2021-003249].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjspcare-2021-003249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34635541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowman L, Hill CJ, May A, et al. . Pulmonary rehabilitation for interstitial lung disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2021; 2: CD006322. doi:10.1002/14651858.CD006322.pub4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD006322.pub4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8094410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34559419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guler SA, Hur SA, Stickland MK, et al. . Survival after inpatient or outpatient pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with fibrotic interstitial lung disease: a multicentre retrospective cohort study. Thorax 2022; 77: 589&#x2013;595. doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2021-217361</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2021-217361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34462346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behr J, Kreuter M, Hoeper MM, et al. . Management of patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis in clinical practice: the INSIGHTS-IPF registry. Eur Respir J 2015; 46:186&#x2013;196. doi:10.1183/09031936.00217614</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00217614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4486374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25837040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Fabrellas E, Molina-Molina M, Soriano JB, et al. . Demographic and clinical profile of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis patients in Spain: the SEPAR National Registry. Respir Res 2019; 20: 127. doi:10.1186/s12931-019-1084-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-019-1084-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6580511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31208406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Andrade JA, Kulkarni T, Neely ML, et al. . Implementation of guideline recommendations and outcomes in patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: data from the IPF-PRO registry. Respir Med 2021; 189: 106637. doi:10.1016/j.rmed.2021.106637</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2021.106637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34656903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman M, Mellerick C, Symons K, et al. . Pulmonary rehabilitation for interstitial lung disease: Referral and patient experiences. Chron Respir Dis 2021; 18: 14799731211046022. doi:10.1177/14799731211046022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/14799731211046022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8516372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34637351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royal College of Physicians, National Asthma and Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease Audit Programme (NACAP) . Pulmonary rehabilitation 2021 organisational audit: summary report. London, Royal College of Physicians, 2022. www.nacap.org.uk/nacap/welcome.nsf/reportsPR.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox NS, Dal Corso S, Hansen H, et al. . Telerehabilitation for chronic respiratory disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2021; 1: CD013040. doi:10.1002/14651858.CD013040.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD013040.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8095032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33511633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickerson L, Helm D, Gottesman C, et al. . Telerehabilitation for lung transplant candidates and recipients during the COVID-19 pandemic: program evaluation. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth 2021; 9: e28708. doi:10.2196/28708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/28708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8213059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34048354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerd&#xe1;n-de-Las-Heras J, Balbino F, L&#xf8;kke A, et al. . Tele-rehabilitation program in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis-A single-center randomized trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021; 18: 10016. doi:10.3390/ijerph181910016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph181910016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8508000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34639313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerdan de Las Heras J, Balbino F, Catal&#xe1;n-Matamoros D, et al. . Effect of a telerehabilitation program in sarcoidosis. Sarcoidosis Vasc Diffuse Lung Dis 2022; 39: e2022003. doi:10.36141/svdld.v39i1.12526</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36141/svdld.v39i1.12526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9007024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35494172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijsenbeek MS, Moor CC, Johannson KA, et al. . Home monitoring in interstitial lung diseases. Lancet Respir Med 2023; 11: 97&#x2013;110. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(22)00228-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(22)00228-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36206780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gizal N, Catharina CM, Kerri AJ, et al. . Worldwide experiences and opinions of healthcare providers on eHealth for patients with interstitial lung diseases in the COVID-19 era. ERJ Open Res 2021; 7: 00405-2021. doi:10.1183/23120541.00405-2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00405-2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8256489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34471631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakshbandi G, Moor K, Vorselaars AD, et al. . Evaluation of home monitoring for patients with interstitial lung disease during the COVID-19 pandemic. Eur Respir J 2022; 60: Suppl. 66, 681. DOI:10.1183/13993003.congress-2022.681</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.congress-2022.681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noth I, Cottin V, Chaudhuri N, et al. . Home spirometry in patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: data from the INMARK trial. Eur Respir J 2021; 58: 2001518. doi:10.1183/13993003.01518-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.01518-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8264778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33419890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veit T, Barnikel M, Crispin A, et al. . Variability of forced vital capacity in progressive interstitial lung disease: a prospective observational study. Respir Res 2020; 21: 270. doi:10.1186/s12931-020-01524-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-020-01524-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7574190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33076914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caroline EB, Monique W, Caspar WNL, et al. . Daily home spirometry to detect early steroid treatment effects in newly treated pulmonary sarcoidosis. Eur Respir J 2018; 51: 1702089. doi:10.1183/13993003.02089-2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02089-2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29348185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahlmann V, Janssen Bon&#xe1;s M, Moor CC, et al. . Design of a randomized controlled trial to evaluate effectiveness of methotrexate versus prednisone as first-line treatment for pulmonary sarcoidosis: the PREDMETH study. BMC Pulm Med 2020; 20: 271. doi:10.1186/s12890-020-01290-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-020-01290-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7574228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33076885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell AM, Adamali H, Molyneaux PL, et al. . Daily home spirometry: an effective tool for detecting progression in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2016; 194: 989&#x2013;997. doi:10.1164/rccm.201511-2152OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.201511-2152OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5067818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27089018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johannson KA, Vittinghoff E, Morisset J, et al. . Home monitoring improves endpoint efficiency in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Eur Respir J 2017; 50: 1602406. doi:10.1183/13993003.02406-2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02406-2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6029860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28679608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moor CC, Wapenaar M, Miedema JR, et al. . A home monitoring program including real-time wireless home spirometry in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: a pilot study on experiences and barriers. Respir Res 2018; 19: 105. doi:10.1186/s12931-018-0810-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-018-0810-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5975585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29843728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijsenbeek MS, Bendstrup E, Valenzuela C, et al. . Disease behaviour during the peri-diagnostic period in patients with suspected interstitial lung disease: the STARLINER study. Adv Ther 2021; 38: 4040&#x2013;4056. doi:10.1007/s12325-021-01790-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12325-021-01790-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8195454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34117601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher TM, Schiffman C, Kreuter M, et al. . A review of the challenges, learnings and future directions of home handheld spirometry in interstitial lung disease. Respir Res 2022; 23: 307. doi:10.1186/s12931-022-02221-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-022-02221-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9651119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36369156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das N, Verstraete K, Stanojevic S, et al. . Deep-learning algorithm helps to standardise ATS/ERS spirometric acceptability and usability criteria. Eur Respir J 2020; 56: 2000603. doi:10.1183/13993003.00603-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00603-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32527741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahmer T, Kirsten A-M, Waschki B, et al. . Prognosis and longitudinal changes of physical activity in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. BMC Pulm Med 2017; 17: 104. doi:10.1186/s12890-017-0444-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-017-0444-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5526311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28743305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moor CC, Mostard RLM, Grutters JC, et al. . The use of online visual analogue scales in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Eur Respir J 2022; 59: 2101531. doi:10.1183/13993003.01531-2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.01531-2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8756292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34326190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scallan C, Strand L, Hayes J, et al. . R-scale for pulmonary fibrosis: a simple, visual tool for the assessment of health-related quality of life. Eur Respir J 2022; 59: 2100917. doi:10.1183/13993003.00917-2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00917-2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34112729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moor CC, Mostard RLM, Grutters JC, et al. . Home monitoring in patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. A randomized controlled trial. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2020; 202: 393&#x2013;401. doi:10.1164/rccm.202002-0328OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202002-0328OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bischoff KE, Choi S, Su A, et al. . Better together: a mixed-methods study of palliative care co-management for patients with interstitial lung disease. J Palliat Med 2021; 24: 1823&#x2013;1832. doi:10.1089/jpm.2020.0787</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jpm.2020.0787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34115958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakshbandi G, Moor CC, Antoniou K, et al. . Study protocol of an international patient-led registry in patients with pulmonary fibrosis using online home monitoring: I-FILE. BMC Pulm Med 2023; 23: 51. doi:10.1186/s12890-023-02336-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-023-02336-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9893651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36732734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma&#x142;ysiak-Szpond S, Mozga M, Mi&#x105;dlikowska E, et al. . Study protocol for connective tissue disease-associated interstitial lung disease trial (TEL-CTD-ILD): A randomized controlled trial of a home-based telemonitoring of treatment effects. PLoS ONE 2022; 17: e0278601. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0278601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0278601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9794074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36574413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S, Llinas EJ, Danoff SK, et al. . The telemedicine experience: using principles of clinical excellence to identify disparities and optimize care. Medicine 2022; 101: e29017. doi:10.1097/MD.0000000000029017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000029017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8913094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35451400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinnock H, Boven JV. CONNECT &#x2013; Moving multiple digital innovations towards connected respiratory care: addressing the over-arching challenges of whole systems implementation. www.ersnet.org/science-and-research/clinical-research-collaboration-application-programme/connect-moving-multiple-digital-innovations-towards-connected-respiratory-care-addressing-the-over-arching-challenges-of-whole-systems-implementation/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37945041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>