<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34091456</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1423-0356</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>100</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Respiration; international review of thoracic diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Respiration</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Swiss Recommendations for the Follow-Up and Treatment of Pulmonary Long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>826</StartPage><EndPage>841</EndPage><MedlinePgn>826-841</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000517255</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Emerging evidence suggests that long-term pulmonary symptoms and functional impairment occurs in a proportion of individuals following SARS-CoV-2 infection. Although the proportion of affected patients remains to be determined, physicians are increasingly being confronted with patients reporting respiratory symptoms and impairment beyond the acute phase of COVID-19. In face of limited evidence, the Swiss Society for Pulmonology established a working group to address this area of unmet need and formulated diagnostic and treatment recommendations for the care of patients with pulmonary long COVID (LC).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">The Swiss COVID Lung Study group and Swiss Society for Pulmonology (SSP) formulated 13 questions addressing the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary LC. A survey within the SSP special interest groups involved in care of LC patients was conducted in Switzerland. A CORE process/Delphi-like process was used to formulate recommendations. Forty experienced pulmonologists replied to the first survey and 22 completed the second follow-up survey. Agreement of &#x2265;70% consensus led to formulation of a recommendation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The participants in the survey reached consensus and formulated a strong recommendation for regarding the following points. Patients hospitalized for COVID-19 should have a pulmonary assessment including pulmonary function tests. Symptomatic subjects affected by COVID-19, including those with mild disease, should benefit from a pulmonary follow-up. Persistent respiratory symptoms after COVID-19 should be investigated by a pulmonary follow-up including plethysmography, diffusion capacity measurement, and blood gases analysis. Individuals having suffered from COVID-19 and who present with persistent respiratory symptoms should be offered a rehabilitation. Additional questions were given moderateor weak recommendations for. The panel did not reach sufficient consensus for pharmacological therapy (e.g., therapy specifically targeting lung fibrosis) to formulate recommendations for LC drug treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The formulated recommendations should serve as an interim guidance to facilitate diagnosis and treatment of patients with pulmonary LC. As new evidence emerges, these recommendations may need to be adapted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Author(s) Published by S. Karger AG, Basel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Funke-Chambour</LastName><ForeName>Manuela</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Pulmonary Medicine, Inselspital, Bern University Hospital, University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Pulmonary Medicine, BioMedical Research, University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bridevaux</LastName><ForeName>Pierre-Olivier</ForeName><Initials>PO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service de Pneumologie, H&#xf4;pital du Valais, Sion, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geneva Medical School, University of Geneva, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clarenbach</LastName><ForeName>Christian F</ForeName><Initials>CF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonology, University Hospital Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soccal</LastName><ForeName>Paola M</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geneva Medical School, University of Geneva, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary Medicine, Geneva University Hospitals, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nicod</LastName><ForeName>Laurent P</ForeName><Initials>LP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary Medicine, Clinique Cecil du groupe Hirslanden, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary Medicine, Lausanne University Hospital (CHUV), University of Lausanne, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>von Garnier</LastName><ForeName>Christophe</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary Medicine, Lausanne University Hospital (CHUV), University of Lausanne, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Swiss COVID Lung Study Group and the Swiss Society of Pulmonology</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017065">Practice Guideline</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Respiration</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0137356</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7931</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000359" MajorTopicYN="N">Aftercare</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="Y">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015272" MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary Medicine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="Y">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013902" MajorTopicYN="N">Radiography, Thoracic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000093485" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19 Drug Treatment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID sequelae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interim guidance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID recommendations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-COVID clinics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2 recommendations</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>M.F.C. has received unrestricted grants and/or speaker fees from Boehringer Ingelheim, Roche and Novartis unrelated to this work. C.F.C. has received payments for lectures/speaking, development of educational materials, and travel/accommodation/meeting expenses/ advisory boards from Roche, Novartis, Boehringer, GSK, Astra Zeneca, Sanofi, Vifor, OM Pharma, and Mundipharma. C.v.G. has received honoraria for consulting, advisory role, or lectures from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, GSK, Mundipharma, Novartis, OM Pharma, Pfizer, PneumRx, and Pulmonx Sanofi. The other authors have no conflicts of interest to declare in relation to this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34091456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8339046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000517255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">000517255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tsui PT, Kwok ML, Yuen H, Lai ST. Severe acute respiratory syndrome: clinical outcome and prognostic correlates. Emerg Infect Dis. 2003 Sep;9((9)):1064&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3016795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14519241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit E, van Doremalen N, Falzarano D, Munster VJ. SARS and MERS: recent insights into emerging coronaviruses. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2016 Aug;14((8)):523&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27344959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui DS, Wong KT, Ko FW, Tam LS, Chan DP, Woo J, et al. The 1-year impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome on pulmonary function, exercise capacity, and quality of life in a cohort of survivors. Chest. 2005 Oct;128((4)):2247&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16236881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngai JC, Ko FW, Ng SS, To KW, Tong M, Hui DS. The long-term impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome on pulmonary function, exercise capacity and health status. Respirology. 2010 Apr;15((3)):543&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7192220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20337995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y, et al. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020 Feb;395((10223)):497&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres Acosta MA, Singer BD. Pathogenesis of COVID-19-induced ARDS: implications for an ageing population. Eur Respir J. 2020 Sep;56((3)):2002049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7397945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32747391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herridge MS, Tansey CM, Matt&#xe9; A, Tomlinson G, Diaz-Granados N, Cooper A, et al. Canadian Critical Care Trials Group Functional disability 5 years after acute respiratory distress syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2011 Apr;364((14)):1293&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21470008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter G. Gibson, Ling Qin SHP. COVID-19 acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS): clinical features and differences from typical pre-COVID-19 ARDS. Med J Aust. 2020 Jul;213((2))</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32572965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlin DA, Gulick RM, Martinez FJ. Severe Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020 Dec;383((25)):2451&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32412710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F, Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA - JAMA. 2020 Aug;324((6)):603&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A'Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020 Aug;370:m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amenta EM, Spallone A, Rodriguez-Barradas MC, El Sahly HM, Atmar RL, Kulkarni PA. Postacute covid-19: an overview and approach to classification. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2020 Oct;7((12)):a509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33403218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodin P. Immune determinants of COVID-19 disease presentation and severity. Nat Med. 2021 Jan;27((1)):28&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33442016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Practitioners RC of G, Scotland HI COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. NICE Guidel. 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackermann M, Verleden SE, Kuehnel M, Haverich A, Welte T, Laenger F, et al. Pulmonary Vascular Endothelialitis, Thrombosis, and Angiogenesis in Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020 Jul;383((2)):120&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7412750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigham E, O'Toole J, Kim SY, Friedman M, Daly L, Kaplin A, et al. The Johns Hopkins Post-Acute COVID-19 Team (PACT): A Multidisciplinary, Collaborative, Ambulatory Framework Supporting COVID-19 Survivors. Am J Med. 2021 Apr;134((4)):462&#x2013;467.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7801819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33444589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorna R, MacDermott N, Rayner C, et al. Long COVID guidelines need to reflect lived experience. Lancet. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33357467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spruit MA, Holland AE, Singh SJ, Tonia T, Wilson KC, Troosters T. COVID-19: Interim Guidance on Rehabilitation in the Hospital and Post-Hospital Phase from a European Respiratory Society and American Thoracic Society-coordinated International Task Force. Eur Respir J. 2020 Aug;56((6)):2002197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32817258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guler SA, Ebner L, Aubry-Beigelman C, Bridevaux PO, Brutsche M, Clarenbach C, et al. Pulmonary function and radiological features 4 months after COVID-19: first results from the national prospective observational Swiss COVID-19 lung study. Eur Respir J. 2021 Apr;57((4)):2003690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8082329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33419891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson KC. Consensus-based recommendations in respiratory medicine. Eur Respir J. 2020;56((6)):200288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues E, Janvier P, Kherabi Y, Le Bot A, Hamon A, Gouze H, et al. Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. J Infect. 2020 Dec;81((6)):e4&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerum TV, Aal&#xf8;kken TM, Br&#xf8;nstad E, et al. Dyspnoea, lung function and CT findings three months after hospital admission for COVID-19. Eur Respir J. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnweber T, Sahanic S, Pizzini A, et al. Cardiopulmonary recovery after COVID-19 &#x2212; an observational prospective multi-center trial. Eur Respir J. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021 Jan;397((10270)):220&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George PM, Barratt SL, Condliffe R, Desai SR, Devaraj A, Forrest I, et al. Respiratory follow-up of patients with COVID-19 pneumonia. Thorax. 2020 Nov;75((11)):1009&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32839287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kluge Stefan, Janssens Uwe, Welte Tobias, Weber-Carstens Steffen, Sch&#xe4;lte Gereon, Spinner Christoph D., Malin Jakob J., Gastmeier Petra, Langer Florian, Wepler Martin, Westhoff Michael, Pfeifer Michael, Rabe Klaus F., Hoffmann Florian, B&#xf6;ttiger Bernd W. CK. S3-Leitlinie - Empfehlungen zur station&#xe4;ren Therapie von Patienten mit COVID-19. AWMF online. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trinkmann F, M&#xfc;ller M, Reif A, Kahn N, Kreuter M, Trudzinski F, et al. Lung Network Rhine-Neckar-Region Residual symptoms and lower lung function in patients recovering from SARS-CoV-2 infection. Eur Respir J. 2021 Feb;57((2)):2003002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7821834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33479105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo X, Jian W, Su Z, Chen M, Peng H, Peng P, et al. Abnormal pulmonary function in COVID-19 patients at time of hospital discharge. Eur Respir J. 2020 Jun;55((6)):2001217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32381497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park WB, Jun KI, Kim G, Choi JP, Rhee JY, Cheon S, et al. Correlation between pneumonia severity and pulmonary complications in Middle East respiratory syndrome. J Korean Med Sci. 2018 May;33((24)):e169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5990444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29892209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham BL, Steenbruggen I, Miller MR, Barjaktarevic IZ, Cooper BG, Hall GL, et al. Standardization of spirometry 2019 update an official American Thoracic Society and European Respiratory Society technical statement. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019 Oct;200((8)):e70&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6794117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31613151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frija-Masson J, Debray MP, Gilbert M, Lescure FX, Travert F, Borie R, et al. Functional characteristics of patients with SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia at 30 days post-infection. Eur Respir J. 2020 Aug;56((2)):2001754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32554533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nusair S. Abnormal carbon monoxide diffusion capacity in COVID-19 patients at time of hospital discharge. Eur Respir J. 2020 Jul;56((1)):2001832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7376285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32703822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R, Gao Y, Chen M, Jian W, Lei C, Zheng J, et al. Impaired pulmonary function in discharged patients with COVID-19: more work ahead. Eur Respir J. 2020 Jul;56((1)):2002194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7315814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32586883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman DG, Badal T, King GG, Thamrin C. Caution in interpretation of abnormal carbon monoxide diffusion capacity in COVID-19 patients. Eur Respir J. 2021 Jan;57((1)):2003263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7651835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33154026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George PM, Wells AU, Jenkins RG. Pulmonary fibrosis and COVID-19: the potential role for antifibrotic therapy. Lancet Respir Med. 2020 Aug;8((8)):807&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dowds J, O'Brien K, Sheill G, Dyer AH, O'Kelly B, et al. Persistent Poor Health Post-COVID-19 Is Not Associated with Respiratory Complications or Initial Disease Severity. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2021 Jan;1(AnnalsATS):202009&#x2013;1175OC.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8456724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karen B. Jacobson, Mallika Rao, Hector Bonilla, Aruna Subramanian, Isabelle Hack, Martina Madrigal, Upinder Singh, Prasanna Jagannathan PG. Patients with uncomplicated COVID-19 have long-term persistent symptoms and functional impairment similar to patients with severe COVID-19: a cautionary tale during a global pandemic. Clin Infect Dis. 2021 Feb</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33624010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crapo RO, Casaburi R, Coates AL, et al. ATS Committee on Proficiency Standards for Clinical Pulmonary Function Laboratories ATS statement: guidelines for the six-minute walk test. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2002 Jul;166((1)):111&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12091180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houchen-Wolloff L, Daynes E, Watt A, Chaplin E, Gardiner N, Singh S. Which functional outcome measures can we use as a surrogate for exercise capacity during remote cardiopulmonary rehabilitation assessments? A rapid narrative review. ERJ Open Res. 2020 Dec;6((4)):00526-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7720684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33313302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuglebjerg NJ, Jensen TO, Hoyer N, Ryrs&#xf8; CK, Lindegaard B, Harboe ZB. Silent hypoxia in patients with SARS CoV-2 infection before hospital discharge. Int J Infect Dis. 2020 Oct;99:100&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher A, Balfanz P, Cornelissen C, M&#xfc;ller A, Bergs I, Marx N, et al. Follow up of patients with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): pulmonary and extrapulmonary disease sequelae. Respir Med. 2020 Nov-Dec;174:106197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33120193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curci C, Negrini F, Ferrillo M, Bergonzi R, Bonacci E, Camozzi DM, et al. Functional outcome after inpatient rehabilitation in post-intensive care unit COVID-19 patients: findings and clinical implications from a real-practice retrospective study. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2021 Jan</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33393278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curci C, Pisano F, Bonacci E, Camozzi DM, Ceravolo C, Bergonzi R, et al. Early rehabilitation in post-acute COVID-19 patients: data from an Italian COVID-19 Rehabilitation Unit and proposal of a treatment protocol. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2020 Oct;56((5)):633&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32667150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebner L, Funke-Chambour M, von Garnier C, Ferretti G, Ghaye B, Beigelman-Aubry C. Imaging in the aftermath of COVID-19: what to expect. Eur Radiol. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7769564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33372242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B, Peters JB, Brink M, Schoon Y, Bleeker-Rovers CP, Schers H, et al. Comprehensive health assessment three months after recovery from acute COVID-19. Clin Infect Dis. 2020 Nov;4:ciaa1750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Fan Y, Alwalid O, Li N, Jia X, Yuan M, et al. Six-month Follow-up Chest CT Findings after Severe COVID-19 Pneumonia. Radiology. 2021 Apr;299((1)):E177&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7841877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy JM, Schnyder P, Verschakelen J, Leuenberger P, Flower CD. Linear opacities on HRCT in bronchiolitis obliterans organising pneumonia. Eur Radiol. 1999;9((9)):1813&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10602956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belli S, Balbi B, Prince I, Cattaneo D, Masocco F, Zaccaria S, et al. Low physical functioning and impaired performance of activities of daily life in COVID-19 patients who survived hospitalisation. Eur Respir J. 2020 Oct;56((4)):2002096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7411272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32764112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Chen R, Geng Q, Mo X, Zhan C, Jian W, et al. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing might be helpful for interpretation of impaired pulmonary function in recovered COVID-19 patients. Eur Respir J. 2021 Jan;57((1)):2004265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7758779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33361097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr A, Dannerbeck L, Lange TJ, Pfeifer M, Blaas S, Salzberger B, et al. Cardiopulmonary exercise pattern in patients with persistent dyspnoea after recovery from COVID-19. Multidiscip Respir Med. 2021 Jan;16((1)):732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7893311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33623700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, Billig Rose E, Shapiro NI, Files DC, et al. IVY Network Investigators. CDC COVID-19 Response Team. IVY Network Investigators Symptom Duration and Risk Factors for Delayed Return to Usual Health Among Outpatients with COVID-19 in a Multistate Health Care Systems Network - United States, March-June 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020 Jul;69((30)):993&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rovere Querini P, De Lorenzo R, Conte C, Brioni E, Lanzani C, Yacoub MR, et al. Post-COVID-19 follow-up clinic: depicting chronicity of a new disease. Acta Biomed. 2020 Jul;91(9-S):22&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32701913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National guidance for post-COVID syndrome assessment clinics.   https://www.england.nhs.uk/coronavirus/wp-content/uploads/sites/52/2020/11/C0840-national-guidance-for-post-covid-syndrome-assesment-clinics-111220.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi S, Al-Sayyed B, Gladfelter TR. Comparative epidemiology, hospital course, and outcomes of viral respiratory infections in hospitalized pediatric patients. Indian J Med Microbiol. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33610252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CF, Sun PT, Tay CK. Bronchiolitis and potential pathophysiological implications in coronavirus disease 2019 acute respiratory distress syndrome patients with near-normal respiratory compliance. Crit Care Med. 2020 Oct;48((10)):e993&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7314321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32541570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi JC, Jung SY, Yoon UA, You SH, Kim MS, Baek MS, et al. Inhaled Corticosteroids and COVID-19 Risk and Mortality: A Nationwide Cohort Study. J Clin Med. 2020 Oct;9((11)):E3406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7690894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33114246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avdeev S, Moiseev S, Brovko M, et al. Low prevalence of bronchial asthma and chronic obstructive lung disease among intensive care unit patients with COVID-19. Allergy Eur J Allergy Clin Immunol; 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7283669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32455491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Xu S, Yu M, Wang K, Tao Y, Zhou Y, et al. Risk factors for severity and mortality in adult COVID-19 inpatients in Wuhan. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2020 Jul;146((1)):110&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7152876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32294485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipworth B, Chan R, Kuo CR. Use of inhaled corticosteroids in asthma and coronavirus disease 2019: keep calm and carry on. Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2020 Nov;125((5)):503&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7329280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32585180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan NM, Vertigan AE, Ferguson J, Wark P, Gibson PG. Clinical and physiological features of postinfectious chronic cough associated with H1N1 infection. Respir Med. 2012 Jan;106((1)):138&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22056406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT, Hamilton FW, Milne A, Morley AJ, Viner J, Attwood M, et al. Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up: results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax. 2020 Dec 3;76((4)):399&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes PJ. How corticosteroids control inflammation: Quintiles Prize Lecture 2005. Br J Pharmacol. 2006 Jun;148((3)):245&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1751559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16604091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juniper EF, Kline PA, Vanzieleghem MA, Ramsdale EH, O'Byrne PM, Hargreave FE. Long-term effects of budesonide on airway responsiveness and clinical asthma severity in inhaled steroid-dependent asthmatics. Eur Respir J. 1990 Nov;3((10)):1122&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2090474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson P, Wang G, McGarvey L, Vertigan AE, Altman KW, Birring SS, et al. CHEST Expert Cough Panel Treatment of unexplained chronic cough chest guideline and expert panel report. Chest. 2016 Jan;149((1)):27&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5831652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26426314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morice AH, Millqvist E, Bieksiene K, Birring SS, Dicpinigaitis P, Domingo Ribas C, et al. ERS guidelines on the diagnosis and treatment of chronic cough in adults and children. Eur Respir J. 2020 Jan;55((1)):1901136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6942543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31515408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramakrishnan S, Nicolau DV, Langford B, et al. Inhaled Budesonide in the Treatment of Early COVID-19 Illness: A Randomised Controlled Trial. SSRN Electron J. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8040526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33844996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kory P, Kanne JP. SARS-CoV-2 organising pneumonia: &#x2018;Has there been a widespread failure to identify and treat this prevalent condition in COVID-19?&#x2019;. BMJ Open Respir Res. 2020 Sep;7((1)):e000724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7509945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32963028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vad&#xe1;sz I, Husain-Syed F, Dorfm&#xfc;ller P, Roller FC, Tello K, Hecker M, et al. Severe organising pneumonia following COVID-19. Thorax. 2020 Nov 11; horaxjnl-2020-216088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33177230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Jin C, Wu CC, Zhao H, Liang T, Liu Z, et al. Organizing pneumonia of COVID-19: time-dependent evolution and outcome in CT findings. PLoS One. 2020 Nov;15((11)):e0240347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7657520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horii H, Kamada K, Nakakubo S, Yamashita Y, Nakamura J, Nasuhara Y, et al. Rapidly progressive organizing pneumonia associated with COVID-19. Respir Med Case Rep. 2020;31:101295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7671928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33224726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myall KJ, Mukherjee B, Castanheira AM, Lam JL, Benedetti G, Mak SM, et al. Persistent Post-COVID-19 Interstitial Lung Disease. An Observational Study of Corticosteroid Treatment. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2021 May;18((5)):799&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8086530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flaherty KR, Wells AU, Cottin V, Devaraj A, Walsh SL, Inoue Y, et al. INBUILD Trial Investigators Nintedanib in progressive fibrosing interstitial lung diseases. N Engl J Med. 2019 Oct;381((18)):1718&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31566307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher TM, Corte TJ, Fischer A, Kreuter M, Lederer DJ, Molina-Molina M, et al. Pirfenidone in patients with unclassifiable progressive fibrosing interstitial lung disease: a double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 2 trial. Lancet Respir Med. 2020 Feb;8((2)):147&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31578169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picchi G, Mari A, Ricciardi A, Carucci AC, Sinatti G, Cosimini B, et al. Three cases of covid-19 pneumonia in female patients in italy who had pulmonary fibrosis on follow-up lung computed tomography imaging. Am J Case Rep. 2020 Nov;21:e926921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7690330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33219200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechowicz K, Dro&#x17c;d&#x17c;al S, Machaj F, Rosik J, Szostak B, Zegan-Bara&#x144;ska M, et al. COVID-19: The Potential Treatment of Pulmonary Fibrosis Associated with SARS-CoV-2 Infection. J Clin Med. 2020 Jun;9((6)):E1917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7356800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32575380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spagnolo P, Balestro E, Aliberti S, Cocconcelli E, Biondini D, Casa GD, Sverzellati N, Maher T. Pulmonary Fibrosis Secondary to COVID-19: A Call to Arms? Lancet Respir Med. 2020 May 15;S2213-2600((20)):30222&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negrini F, De Sire A, Andrenelli E, et al. Rehabilitation and COVID-19: a rapid living systematic review 2020 by Cochrane Rehabilitation Field. Update as of October 31st, 2020. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33263249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>