<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37180854</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1016-1430</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>37</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical journal of the Islamic Republic of Iran</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med J Islam Repub Iran</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Characterization of Long COVID and Its Contributing Factors among a Population of Health Care Workers in a 6-Month Follow-up.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>29</StartPage><MedlinePgn>29</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">29</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.47176/mjiri.37.29</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Health care workers (HCWs) are at the frontline of the fight against the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Long COVID is defined as "the persistence of some symptoms of COVID-19, more than 4 weeks after the initial infection." The aim of the present study was to investigate the prevalence of long COVID status among HCWs in the largest hospital complex of Iran.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In this cross-sectional study, all patients with COVID-19 who had taken sick leave were included in the study (n = 445). Data regarding sick leave characteristics were collected from the records of the nursing management department of the hospital. Study variables included demographic and occupational information, variables related to mental health assessment, organ systems involved in COVID-19, and duration of symptoms. Frequencies, percentage distributions, means, standard deviation, and range (minimum, maximum) were used as descriptive analysis methods. Associations between symptoms' persistency and clinical characteristics were assessed by logistic and linear regressions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Age, N95 mask use, and respiratory protection significantly contributed to the persistence of COVID-19 symptoms (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). The prevalence of long COVID among HCWs was 9.44% among 445 participants. The loss of taste persisted longer than the other symptoms before returning to normal. Among the postrecovery complications asked, anxiety was the most common persistent mental symptom (58.5%), followed by gloomy mood (46.3%) and low interest (46.2%), respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">HCWs with COVID-19 symptoms had prolonged symptoms of COVID-19 that can affect their work performance, thus, we recommend evaluating COVID-19 symptoms in HCWs with infection history.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Iran University of Medical Sciences.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Izadi</LastName><ForeName>Nazanin</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research on Occupational Disease, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Najafi</LastName><ForeName>Arezu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Occupational Sleep Research Center, Baharloo Hospital, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sadeghniiat-Haghighi</LastName><ForeName>Khosro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Occupational Sleep Research Center, Baharloo Hospital, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammadi</LastName><ForeName>Hosein</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9978-5028</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Med J Islam Repub Iran</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8910777</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1016-1430</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health Care Workers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37180854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10167639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47176/mjiri.37.29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Novel Coronavirus (2019-nCoV): situation report, November. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization (WHO). WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard. 
2022. 

Aguest

27, 2022. Available from: 
https://covid19.who.int. </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai X, Wang M, Qin C, Tan L, Ran L, Chen D. et al. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-2019) infection among health care workers and implications for prevention measures in a tertiary hospital in Wuhan, China. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3(5):e209666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sikkema RS, Pas SD, Nieuwenhuijse DF, O'Toole &#xc1;, Verweij J, van der. et al. COVID-19 in health-care workers in three hospitals in the south of the Netherlands: a cross-sectional study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20(11):1273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7332281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32622380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covid C, Team R, COVID C, Team R, COVID C, Team R. et al. Characteristics of health care personnel with COVID-19&#x2014;United States, February 12&#x2013;April 9, 2020. MMWR. 2020;69(15):477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kluytmans-van Den, Buiting AG, Pas SD, Bentvelsen RG, Van Den, Van Oudheusden. et al. Prevalence and clinical presentation of health care workers with symptoms of coronavirus disease 2019 in 2 Dutch hospitals during an early phase of the pandemic. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3(5):e209673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perego E, Callard F, Stras L, Melville-J&#xf3;hannesson B, Pope R, Alwan NA. Why the patient-made term'long covid'is needed. Wellcome Open Res. 2020;5(224):224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid&#x2014;mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malenfant JH, Newhouse CN, Kuo AA. Frequency of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) symptoms in healthcare workers in a large health system. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2021;42(11):1403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7683811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33100258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JJ, Dong X, Cao YY, Yuan YD, Yang YB, Yan YQ. et al. Clinical characteristics of 140 patients infected with SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 in Wuhan, China. Allergy. 2020;75(7):1730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32077115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dev N, Meena RC, Gupta D, Gupta N, Sankar J. Risk factors and frequency of COVID-19 among healthcare workers at a tertiary care centre in India: a case&#x2013;control study. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 2021;115(5):551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8083760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33763687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez-Ochoa SA, Franco OH, Rojas LZ, Raguindin PF, Roa-D&#xed;az ZM, Wyssmann BM. et al. COVID-19 in health-care workers: a living systematic review and meta-analysis of prevalence, risk factors, clinical characteristics, and outcomes. Am J Epidemiol. 2021;190(1):161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7499478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32870978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ran L, Chen X, Wang Y, Wu W, Zhang L, Tan X. Risk factors of healthcare workers with corona virus disease 2019: a retrospective cohort study in a designated hospital of Wuhan in China. Clin Infect Dis. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32179890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu DK, Akl EA, Duda S, Solo K, Yaacoub S, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ. et al. Physical distancing, face masks, and eye protection to prevent person-to-person transmission of SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet. 2020;395(10242):1973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7263814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32497510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner P. Paul Garner: For 7 weeks I have been through a roller coaster of ill health, extreme emotions, and utter exhaustion. BMJ. 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datta SD, Talwar A, Lee JT. A proposed framework and timeline of the spectrum of disease due to SARS-CoV-2 infection: illness beyond acute infection and public health implications. JAMA. 2020;324(22):2251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33206133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otte MS, Eckel HNC, Poluschkin L, Klussmann JP, Luers JC. Olfactory dysfunction in patients after recovering from COVID-19. Acta Otolaryngol. 2020;140(12):1032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32852240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L. et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID&#x2010;19 infection: A cross&#x2010;sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93(2):1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, Dunne J, Mooney A, Gaffney F. et al. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. Plos one. 2020;15(11):e0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Cruz RF, Waller MD, Perrin F, Periselneris J, Norton S, Smith L-J. et al. Chest radiography is a poor predictor of respiratory symptoms and functional impairment in survivors of severe COVID-19 pneumonia. ERJ Open Res. 2021;7(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7585700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33575312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, Rose EB, Shapiro NI, Files DC. et al. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network&#x2014;United States, March&#x2013;June 2020. MMWR. 2020;69(30):993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Perez O, Merino E, Leon-Ramirez J, Andres M, Ramos J, Arenas-Jimenez J. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: A Mediterranean cohort study. J Infect. 2021;82(3):378&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7802523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC. et al. Attributes and predictors of Long-COVID: analysis of COVID cases and their symptoms collected by the Covid Symptoms Study App. . Medrxiv . 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 clinical management: living guidance. WHO. 25 January 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baigent C, Windecker S, Andreini D, Arbelo E, Barbato E, Bartorelli AL. et al. ESC guidance for the diagnosis and management of cardiovascular disease during the COVID-19 pandemic: part 2-care pathways, treatment, and follow-up. Cardiovasc Res. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8690236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34864876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty AM, Colleran GC, Durcan L, Irvine AD, Barrett E. A pilot study of burnout and long covid in senior specialist doctors. Ir J Med Sci. 2022 Feb;191(1):133&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7955691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33713306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>