<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37052043</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2037-7452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of translational myology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Transl Myol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long-term outcomes of different rehabilitation programs in patients with long COVID syndrome: a cohort prospective study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11063</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4081/ejtm.2023.11063</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>After the resolution of the acute SARS-COV-2 infection, an important percentage of patients do not fully recover and continue to present several symptoms. Nevertheless, there is a lack of data in the literature on the effects of rehabilitation programs on medium- and long-term long COVID symptoms. Therefore, the aim of this study was to evaluate the long-term outcomes after rehabilitation programs in long COVID syndrome patients. A prospective cohort study was conducted from August 2021 to March 2022, involving 113 patients with long COVID syndrome. The patients in the experimental group (EG, n=25) received a tailored and multidisciplinary rehabilitative program, involving aquatic exercises, respiratory and motor exercises, social integration training and neuropsychologic sessions, LASER therapy and magnetotherapy. Patients in the other three comparison groups received eastern medicine techniques (CG1), balneotherapy and physiotherapy (group CG2), self-training and home-based physical exercise (CG3). Once the several rehabilitation protocols had been performed, a structured telephone contact was made with the patients after 6 months &#xb1; 7 days from the end of the rehabilitation treatment, in order to record the frequency of hospital ad-missions due to exacerbation of post-exacerbation syndrome, death or disability, and the need for other types of care or drugs. The patients in the comparison groups were more likely to request therapeutic care for emerging long COVID symptoms (&#x3c7;2=6.635, p=0.001; &#x3c7;2=13.463, p=0.001; &#x3c7;2=10.949, p=0.001, respectively), as well as more likely to be hospitalized (&#x3c7;2=5.357, p=0.021; &#x3c7;2=0.125, p=0.724; &#x3c7;2=0.856, p=0.355, respectively) when compared to the patients of the EG. The relative risk (RR) of hospital admissions in the observed cohort was 0.143 &#xb1;1,031 (&#x421;I: 0.019; 1.078); 0.580&#xb1;1,194 (CI: 0.056; 6.022); 0,340&#xb1;1,087 (CI: 0.040; 2.860). The RR of hospital admissions for patients with long COVID syndrome was reduced by 85.7%; 42.0% and 66.0%, respectively, when the experimental rehabilitation technique was employed. In conclusion, a tailored and multidisciplinary rehabilitative program seems to have a better preventive effect not only in the short term, but also over the next 6 months, avoiding the new onset of disabilities and the use of medicines and specialist advice, than other rehabilitative programs. Future studies will need to further investigate these aspects to identify the best rehabilitation therapy, also in terms of cost-effectiveness, for these patients.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grishechkina</LastName><ForeName>Irina A</ForeName><Initials>IA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Research Center, Moscow. GrishechkinaIA@nmicrk.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lobanov</LastName><ForeName>Andrey A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Research Center, Moscow. alobanov89@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andronov</LastName><ForeName>Sergei V</ForeName><Initials>SV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Research Center, Moscow. sergius198010@mail.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rachin</LastName><ForeName>Andrey P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Research Center, Moscow. RachinAP@nmicrk.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fesyun</LastName><ForeName>Anatoliy D</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Research Center, Moscow, Russia; Moscow State University of Food Production, Moscow. fad68@yandex.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ivanova</LastName><ForeName>Elena P</ForeName><Initials>EP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Research Center, Moscow. IvanovaEP@nmicrk.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masiero</LastName><ForeName>Stefano</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation School, Department of Neuroscience, University of Padova, Padua, Italy; Department of Neuroscience, Rehabilitation Unit, University of Padova, Padua. stef.masiero@unipd.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maccarone</LastName><ForeName>Maria Chiara</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation School, Department of Neuroscience, University of Padova, Padua. mariachiara.maccarone@phd.unipd.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Transl Myol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2037-7452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>We confirm that we have read the Journal&#x2019;s position on issues involved in ethical publication and affirm that this report is consistent with those guidelines. <b>A</b>fter resolution of the acute SARS-COV-2 infection, an important percentage of patients does not fully recover and continue to present several symptoms. This condition of persistence of signs and symptoms that continue or develop after acute SARS CoV-2 infection has been called long COVID syndrome. The syndrome is characterized by the presence of symptoms for at least 2 months and the impossibility to e-plain them with an alternative diagnosis. Common symptoms include fatigue, breath-lessness, cognitive dysfunction, as well as a number of other symptoms that can lead to the impairment in carrying out daily activities and self-care. These symptoms can be intermittent or recurrent over time. The pathogenetic mechanisms of long COVID syndrome are still debated, but long-term tissue damage and pathological inflammation (related to virus persistence, immune dysregulation and autoimmune reactions) seem to play a role in the medium- and long-term persistence of symptoms.<sup>,,</sup> Additionally, patients in the early stages of rehabilitation after the acute COVID-19 infection can present impaired microcirculation and reduced capacity to maintain an upright posture, which are largely accountable for symptoms such as fatigue, shortness of breath and low tolerance to physical exertion. Based on these findings, a rehabilitation program for patients with Long COVID syndrome was developed in the &#x201c;National Medical Research Centre for Rehabilitation and Balneology&#x201d; of the Ministry of Health of Russia (Patent Application # 2022113192-17 May 2022), incorporating the main components of respiratory rehabilitation for chronic lung diseases,<sup>,</sup> balance and motor training, and a tailored aquatic exercise intervention. The results of this preliminary study seemed to confirm the effectiveness of physical exercise in ameliorating impaired upright posture and normalizing walking patterns. In addition, aquatic exercise carried out in mineral-rich water seemed to add a protective effect on the microcirculatory system, in the lymph flow and in tissue metabolism. Nevertheless, the lack of data in the literature on the effects of rehabilitation programs on medium- and long-term long COVID symptoms,<sup>,</sup> and the heterogeneity in durations and contents of the few existing studies, determined the need for further investigations. Therefore, with this further analysis we aim to increasing knowledge on rehabilitation programs in patients with long COVID syndrome, evaluating also clinical outcomes in the long-term.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37052043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10388602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/ejtm.2023.11063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO: Clinical case definition post-COVID-19 by Delphi consensus. 06.10.2021. Available online: URL https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/345824/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post-COVID-19-condition-Clinical-case-definition-2021.1-rus.pdf (accessed on 29 May 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asly M, Hazim A. Rehabilitation of post-COVID-19 patients. Pan Afr Med J. 2020. Jul 9;36:168. doi: 10.11604/pamj.2020.36.168.23823. PMID: 32952812; PMCID: PMC7467884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7467884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32952812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker-Davies RM, O'Sullivan O, Senaratne KPP, Baker P, Cranley M, Dharm-Datta S, Ellis H, Goodall D, Gough M, Lewis S, Norman J, Papadopoulou T, Roscoe D, Sherwood D, Turner P, Walker T, Mistlin A, Phillip R, Nicol AM, Bennett AN, Bahadur S. The Stanford Hall consensus statement for post-COVID-19 rehabilitation. Br J Sports Med. 2020. Aug;54(16):949-959. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2020-102596. Epub 2020 May 31. PMID: 32475821; PMCID: PMC7418628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7418628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32475821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. lCOVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond). 2021. Oct;53(10):737-754. doi: 10.1080/23744235.2021. 1924397. Epub 2021 May 22. PMID: 34024217; PMCID: PMC8146298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, Walshaw C, Kemp S, Corrado J, Singh R, Collins T, O'Connor RJ, Sivan M. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021. Feb;93(2):1013-1022. doi: 10.1002/jmv.26368. Epub 2020 Aug 17. PMID: 32729939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemp HI, Corner E, Colvin LA. Chronic pain after COVID-19: implications for rehabilitation. Br J Anaesth. 2020. Oct;125(4):436-440. doi: 10.1016/j.bja.2020.05.021. Epub 2020 May 31. PMID: 32560913; PMCID: PMC7261464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7261464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32560913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weerahandi H, Hochman KA, Simon E, Blaum C, Chodosh J, Duan E, Garry K, Kahan T, Karmen-Tuohy SL, Karpel HC, Mendoza F, Prete AM, Quintana L, Rutishauser J, Santos Martinez L, Shah K, Sharma S, Simon E, Stirniman AZ, Horwitz LI. Post-Discharge Health Status and Symptoms in Patients with Severe COVID-19. J Gen Intern Med. 2021. Mar;36(3):738-745. doi: 10.1007/s11606-020-06338-4. Epub 2021 Jan 14. PMID: 33443703; PMCID: PMC7808113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33443703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgson CL, Higgins AM, Bailey MJ, Mather AM, Beach L, Bellomo R, Bissett B, Boden IJ, Bradley S, Burrell A, Cooper DJ, Fulcher BJ, Haines KJ, Hopkins J, Jones AYM, Lane S, Lawrence D, van der Lee L, Liacos J, Linke NJ, Gomes LM, Nickels M, Ntoumenopoulos G, Myles PS, Patman S, Paton M, Pound G, Rai S, Rix A, Rollinson TC, Sivasuthan J, Tipping CJ, Thomas P, Trapani T, Udy AA, Whitehead C, Hodgson IT, Anderson S, Neto AS; COVID-Recovery Study Investigators and the ANZICS Clinical Trials Group. The impact of COVID-19 critical illness on new disability, functional outcomes and return to work at 6 months: a prospective cohort study. Crit Care. 2021. Nov 8;25(1):382. doi: 10.1186/s13054-021-03794-0. PMID: 34749756; PMCID: PMC8575157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34749756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidorov VV, Lobanov AA, Grishechkina IA, Fesyun AD, Yakovlev MYU, Andronov SV, Barashkov GN, Popov AI. Narushenie mikrocirkulyacii i kletochnogo metabolizma u patientov s post-COVID-sindromom [Violation of microcirculation and cellular metabolism in patients with post-COVID syndrome]. Vestnik novyh medicinskih tekhnologij. 2022, Volume 29(2), P. 64-68 [in Russian].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das S. Microcirculatory changes and thrombotic complications in COVID-19. Br J Community Nurs. 2021. Oct 2;26(10):474-480. doi: 10.12968/bjcn.2021.26.10.474. PMID: 34632792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34632792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandolfi S, Chirumbolo S. Home therapy of COVID-19 at the earliest may greatly prevent hospitalization. Basic Clin Pharmacol Toxicol. 2021. Dec;129(6):395-396. doi: 10.1111/bcpt. 13650. Epub 2021 Sep 26. PMID: 34494369; PMCID: PMC8652880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8652880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34494369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hohberger B, Mardin CY. OCT Angiography as an Interdisciplinary Diagnostic Tool for Systemic Diseases. Klin Monbl Augenheilkd. 2021. Dec;238(12):1294-1298. English, German. doi: 10.1055/a-1654-0504. Epub 2021 Dec 8. PMID: 34879428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34879428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, Walshaw C, Kemp S, Corrado J, Singh R, Collins T, O'Connor RJ, Sivan M. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021. Feb;93(2):1013-1022. doi: 10.1002/jmv.26368. Epub 2020 Aug 17. PMID: 32729939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobanov AA, Irina A Grishechkina, Andronov SV, Gleb N Barashkov, Andrey I Popov, Anatoliy D Fesyun, Elena P Ivanova, Maccarone MC, Stefano Masiero. Can aquatic exercises contribute to the improvement of the gait stereotype function in patients with Long COVID outcomes? Eur J Transl Myol. 2022. Jul 14;32(3):10698. doi: 10.4081/ejtm.2022.10698. PMID: 35833897; PMCID: PMC9580543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35833897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meshcheryakova NN, Belevskij AS, Kuleshov AV.
Metodicheskie rekomendacii provedenie legochnoj reabilitacii u pacientov s novoj koronavirusnoj infekciej (COVID-19) vnebol'nichnoj dvuhstoronnej pnevmoniej [Guidelines for pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with novel coronavirus infection (COVID-19) community-acquired bilateral pneumonia]. Moscow, 2020. 22 p. Available online: URL https://www.spulmo.ru/upload/metodichka_po_reabilitacii_covid.pdf (accessed on: 3 March 2022) [in Russian].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belevskij AS, Meshcheryakova NN. Legochnaya reabilitaciya [Pulmonary rehabilitation], Atmosphere: Moscow, Russian Federation,. 2018; 76 p. [in Russian] ISBN: 978-5-902123-71-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobanov AA, Grishechkina IA, Fesyun AD, Rachin AP, Yakovlev MYu, Andronov SV, Barashkov GN, Lebedeva OD, Popov AI, Styazhkina EM, Ansokova MA, Vasil&#x2019;eva VA. Investigation of the Effectiveness and Safety of a Rehabilitation Program for Patients with Long Covid Using Aquatic Training. Bulletin of Rehabilitation Medi-cine 2022, Volume 21(3), P. 45-57. 10.38025/2078-1962-2022-21-3-45-57 [in Russian].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.38025/2078-1962-2022-21-3-45-57</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F; Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Persistent Symptoms in Patients After Acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020. Aug 11;324(6):603-605. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.12603. PMID: 32644129; PMCID: PMC7349096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King&#x2019;s College London. ZOE Global Limited. How long does COVID-19 last?
2020. Available online: URL https://www.kcl.ac.uk/news/spotlight/zoe-covid-study-app-kings-researchers-slowed-the-spread-COVID-19 (accessed on: 12 May 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutsch M, Frommhold J, Buhr-Schinner H, Djeiranachvili L, Gross T, Sch&#xfc;ller PO, Katalinic A, Deck R. Study protocol medical rehabilitation after COVID-19 disease: an observational study with a comparison group with obstructive airway disease / Re_Co. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021. Apr 22;21(1):373. doi: 10.1186/s12913-021-06378-4. PMID: 33888104; PMCID: PMC8061875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8061875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33888104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gl&#xf6;ckl R., Buhr-Schinner H, Koczulla AR, Schipmann R, Schultz K, Spielmanns M, Stenzel N, Dewey S. DGP-Empfehlungen zur pneumologischen Rehabilitation bei COVID-19 [Recommendations from the German Res-piratory Society for Pulmonary Rehabilitation in Patients with COVID-19]. Pneumologie. 2020, Volume 74(8), P. 496-504. [German.] doi:10.1055/a-1193-9315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7516360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32583378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nesina IA, Golovko EA, Shakula AV, Figurenko NN, Zhilina IG, Khomchenko TN, Smirnova EL, Chursina VS, Koroleva AV. Experience of Outpatient Rehabilitation of Patients after Pneumonia Associated with the New Coronavirus Infection COVID-19. Bulletin of Rehabilitation Medicine. 2021, Volume 20(5), P. 4-11. doi: 10.38025/2078-1962-2021-20-5-4-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bek LM, Berentschot JC, Hellemons ME, Huijts SM, Aerts JGJV, van Bommel J, van Genderen ME, Gommers DAMPJ, Ribbers GM, Heijenbrok-Kal MH, van den Berg-Emons RJG. CO-FLOW Collaboration Group. CO-FLOW: COvid-19 Follow-up care paths and Long-term Outcomes Within the Dutch health care system: study protocol of a multicenter prospective cohort study following patients 2 years after hospital discharge. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021. Aug 21;21(1):847. doi: 10.1186/s12913-021-06813-6. PMID: 34419032; PMCID: PMC837959624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8379596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34419032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrie A, Sabin C. Medical Statistics at a Glance, 4th ed.; Wiley-Blackwell: USA, 2019; 208p. ISBN: 978-1-119-16781-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vremennye metodicheskie rekomendacii. Medicinskaya reabilitaciya pri novoj koronovirusnoj infekcii (COVID-19). [Temporary guidelines. Medical rehabilitation for new coronovirus infection (COVID-19)]. Available online: URL xn&#x2013;80aesfpebagmfblc0a.xn&#x2013;p1ai/ai/doc/461/attach/28052020_Preg_COVID-19_v1.pdf (accessed on 12 Feb 2022) [in Russian].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogolyubov VM. Physiotherapy and balneology. BINOM: Russian Federation, &#x41c;oscow,. 2021; 999 p. [in Russian].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Understanding of guidance for acupuncture and moxibustion interventions on COVID-19 (Second edition) issued by CAAM. World Journal of Acupuncture - Moxibustion. 2020, Volume 30(1), P. 1&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1016/j.wjam.2020.03.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32292259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlova IV. Mnogomernyjstatisticheskijanaliz v ekonomicheskihzadachah: komp'yuternoemodeliro vanie v SPSS: Uchebnoeposobie [Multivariate Statistical Analysis in Economics: Computer Simulation in SPSS: A Tutorial]; Vuzovskijuchebnik: Moscow, Russian Federation,. 2014; 310 p. Available online: URL https://r-analytics.blogspot.com/2013/01/2-2-k.html [in Russian].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO European Regional Technical Briefing. Rehabilitation after COVID-19: what we know and what resources we have. Virtual meeting hosted by the WHO Regional Office for Europe. Copenhagen: WHO Regional Office for Europe, 2022. Available online: URL: https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/ handle/10665/351043/WHO-EURO-2022-3995-43754-62897-rus.pdf?sequence=1&amp;isAllowed=y (accessed on 04 April 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilmutdinova IR, Kolyshenkov VA, Lapickaya KA, Trepova AS, Vasileva VA, Prosvirnin AN, Marchenkova LA, Terentev KV, Yakovlev MY, Rachin AP, Fesyun AD, Reverchuk IV. Telemedicine platform COVIDREHAB for remote rehabilitation of patients after COVID-19. Eur J Transl Myol. 2021. May 13;31(2):9783. doi: 10.4081/ejtm.2021.9783. PMID: 33985320; PMCID: PMC8274224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8274224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33985320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant MS, Fedson SE, Sharafkhaneh A. Using Telehealth Cardiopulmonary Rehabilitation during the COVID-19 Pandemic. J Med Syst. 2020. May 28;44(7):125. doi: 10.1007/s10916-020-01593-8. PMID: 32462352; PMCID: PMC7253228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7253228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32462352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansokova MA, Vasil&#x2019;eva VA. Rehabilitation of a patient with acute cerebral circulation disturbance due to COVID-19. Materials of the Russian scientific-practical conference with international participation, Kursk Russian Federation, 2022. pp. 44-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchenkova LA, Makarova EV, Yurova OV. [The role of micronutrients in the comprehensive rehabilitation of patients with the novel coronavirus infection COVID-19]. Vopr Pitan. 2021;90(2):40-49. [in Russian]. doi: 10.33029/0042-8833-2021-90-2-40-49. Epub 2021 Mar 11. PMID: 34019347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34019347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Haastregt JCM, Everink IHJ, Schols JMGA, Grund S, Gordon AL, Poot EP, Martin FC, O'Neill D, Petrovic M, Bachmann S, van Balen R, van Dam van Isselt L, Dockery F, Holstege MS, Landi F, P&#xe9;rez LM, Roquer E, Smalbrugge M, Achterberg WP. Management of post-acute COVID-19 patients in geriatric rehabilitation: EuGMS guidance. Eur Geriatr Med. 2022. Feb;13(1):291-304. doi: 10.1007/s41999-021-00575-4. Epub 2021 Nov 20. PMID: 34800286; PMCID: PMC8605452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8605452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34800286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei N. Coronavirus Disease-COVID-19: E-book; Springer, Switzerland,. 2019; 964 pp. doi: 10.1007/978-3-030-63761-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, Kang L, Guo L, Liu M, Zhou X, Luo J, Huang Z, Tu S, Zhao Y, Chen L, Xu D, Li Y, Li C, Peng L, Li Y, Xie W, Cui D, Shang L, Fan G, Xu J, Wang G, Wang Y, Zhong J, Wang C, Wang J, Zhang D, Cao B. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021. Jan 16;397(10270):220-232. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8. Epub 2021 Jan 8. PMID: 33428867; PMCID: PMC7833295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Fan Y, Alwalid O, Li N, Jia X, Yuan M, Li Y, Cao Y, Gu J, Wu H, Shi H. Six-month Follow-up Chest CT Findings after Severe COVID-19 Pneumonia. Radiology 2021; Volume 299(1), p. E177-E186. doi:10.1148/radiol.2021203153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7841877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taboada M, Cari&#xf1;ena A, Moreno E, Rodr&#xed;guez N, Dom&#xed;nguez MJ, Casal A, Riveiro V, Diaz-Vieito M, Vald&#xe9;s L, &#xc1;lvarez J, Seoane-Pillado T. Post-COVID-19 functional status six-months after hospitalization. J Infect. 2021. Apr;82(4):e31-e33. doi: 10.1016/j.jinf.2020.12.022. Epub 2020 Dec 26. PMID: 33373650; PMCID: PMC7834022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33373650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X, Huang H, Wang C, Jin Z, Zhang Z, He J, Yin S, Fan M, Huang J, Chen F, Zeng Y, Han X, Zhu Y. Follow-up study of pulmonary function among COVID-19 survivors 1 year after recovery. J Infect. 2021. Sep;83(3):381-412. doi: 10.1016/j.jinf.2021.05.034. Epub 2021 May 29. PMID: 34062186; PMCID: PMC8164517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8164517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34062186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T, Hittle M, Goodman SN. Assessment of the Frequency and Variety of Persistent Symptoms Among Patients With COVID-19: A Systematic Review. JAMA Netw Open. 2021. May 3;4(5):e2111417. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.11417. PMID: 34037731; PMCID: PMC8155823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8155823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34037731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho AC, Moreira J, Cubelo P, Cantista P, Branco CA, Guimar&#xe3;es B. Therapeutic respiratory and functional rehabilitation protocol for intensive care unit patients affected by COVID-19: a structured summary of a study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials. 2021. Apr 12;22(1):268. doi: 10.1186/s13063-021-05210-y. PMID: 33845878; PMCID: PMC8039799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8039799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33845878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho AC, Moreira J, Cubelo P, Cantista P, Branco CA, Guimar&#xe3;es B. Therapeutic respiratory and functional rehabilitation protocol for intensive care unit patients affected by COVID-19: a structured summary of a study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials. 2021. Apr 12;22(1):268. doi: 10.1186/s13063-021-05210-y. PMID: 33845878; PMCID: PMC8039799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8039799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33845878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stam HJ, Stucki G, Bickenbach J; European Academy of Rehabilitation Medicine. COVID-19 and Post Intensive Care Syndrome: A Call for Action. J Rehabil Med. 2020. Apr 15;52(4):jrm00044. doi: 10.2340/16501977-2677. PMID: 32286675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32286675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maniscalco M, Fuschillo S, Ambrosino P, Martucci M, Papa A, Matera MG, Cazzola M. Preexisting cardiorespiratory comorbidity does not preclude the success of multidisciplinary rehabilitation in post-COVID-19 patients. Respir Med. 2021. Aug;184:106470. doi: 10.1016/j.rmed.2021. 106470. Epub 2021 May 15. PMID: 34022502; PMCID: PMC8123366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8123366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34022502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagudina RI, Kulikov AYu, Serpik VG. Farmakoekonomika: uchebnoeposobie [Pharmaco-economics: textbook]; Phoenix: Rostov-on-Don, Russian Federation, 2018; 237p. [in Russian].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maccarone MC, Kamioka H, Cheleschi S, Tenti S, Masiero S, Karde&#x15f; S. Italian and Japanese public attention toward balneotherapy in the COVID-19 era. Environ Sci Pollut Res Int. 2021. Nov;28(43):61781-61789. doi: 10.1007/s11356-021-15058-z. Epub 2021 Jun 29. PMID: 34185269; PMCID: PMC8239328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34185269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masiero S, Maccarone MC, Agostini F. Health resort medicine can be a suitable setting to recover disabilities in patients tested negative for COVID-19 discharged from hospital? A challenge for the future. Int J Biometeorol. 2020. Oct;64(10):1807-1809. doi: 10.1007/s00484-020-01947-4. Epub 2020 Jun 5. PMID: 32504142; PMCID: PMC7272594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32504142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masiero S, Maccarone MC. Health resort therapy interventions in the COVID-19 pandemic era: what next? Int J Biometeorol. 2021. Nov;65(11):1995-1997. doi: 10.1007/s00484-021-02134-9. Epub 2021 Apr 21. PMID: 33880643; PMCID: PMC8057917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8057917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33880643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agostini F, Mangone M, Ruiu P, Paolucci T, Santilli V, Bernetti A. Rehabilitation setting during and after COVID-19: An overview on recommendations. J Rehabil Med. 2021. Jan 5;53(1):jrm00141. doi: 10.2340/16501977-2776. PMID: 33284353; PMCID: PMC8772378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8772378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33284353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maccarone MC, Masiero S. Spa therapy interventions for post respiratory rehabilitation in COVID-19 subjects: does the review of recent evidence suggest a role? Environ Sci Pollut Res Int. 2021. Sep;28(33):46063-46066. doi: 10.1007/ s11356-021-15443-8. Epub 2021 Jul 17. PMID: 34273080; PMCID: PMC8286038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8286038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maccarone MC, Magro G, Tognolo L, Masiero S. Post COVID-19 persistent fatigue: a proposal for rehabilitative interventions in the spa setting. Int J Biometeorol. 2021. Dec;65(12):2241-2243. doi: 10.1007/s00484-021-02158-1. Epub 2021 Jun 4. PMID: 34086142; PMCID: PMC8175920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8175920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34086142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masiero S, Maccarone MC, Magro G. Balneotherapy and human immune function in the era of COVID-19. Int J Biometeorol. 2020. Aug;64(8):1433-1434. doi: 10.1007/s00484-020-01914-z. Epub 2020 Apr 16. PMID: 32300868; PMCID: PMC7160818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7160818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32300868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>