<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37530064</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-9657</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Dental traumatology : official publication of International Association for Dental Traumatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Dent Traumatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of characteristics of kick- and electric-scooter-related dental and maxillofacial injuries: A retrospective study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>565</StartPage><EndPage>574</EndPage><MedlinePgn>565-574</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/edt.12875</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND/AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Owing to the nearly three-year-long COVID-19 pandemic, small personal transportation devices that allow for greater freedom of movement within the cities have gained attention. Therefore, the number of people using kick or electric scooters has increased. This study aimed to compare the characteristics of kick and electric scooter-related dental and maxillofacial trauma and provide helpful information for preventing scooter accidents, appropriate treatment of patients with scooter-related trauma, and policy establishment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective observational study analysed the medical records of 310 patients who visited the emergency room of Ajou University Dental Hospital for kick and electric scooter-related oral and maxillofacial injuries between 1 January 2017 and 31 December 2022. Sex, age, scooter type, time, and mechanism of the accident, helmet use, alcohol consumption, dental and maxillofacial injury types, and treatment were analysed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The average age in the kick-scooter group (5.71&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.25) was lower than that in the electric-scooter group (28.24&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;10.02) (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.0001). There were more males in both groups. The helmet usage rates of the two groups were 2.80% and 7.88%, respectively. In the kick-scooter group, periodontal damage was more common than pulp injury, while in the electric-scooter group, pulp injury was more common than periodontal injury. There was no significant difference in soft-tissue damage between the two groups; however, bone fractures occurred significantly more frequently in the electric-scooter group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.0001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Electric scooters cause more crown and bone fractures than kick scooters and require more active treatment of dental and maxillofacial injuries. Riders should use protective equipment to prevent dental and maxillofacial injury. Although there are regulations related to scooters, the effectiveness of both kick- and electric-scooter related laws needs to be evaluated.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwak</LastName><ForeName>Misun</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-0689-906X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric Dentistry, Dental Hospital, Ajou University, Suwon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mah</LastName><ForeName>Yon-Joo</ForeName><Initials>YJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2278-1111</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric Dentistry, Dental Hospital, Ajou University, Suwon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Dent Traumatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101091305</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1600-4469</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050723" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fractures, Bone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006260" MajorTopicYN="N">Head Protective Devices</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008446" MajorTopicYN="Y">Maxillofacial Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dental and maxillofacial injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electric scooter</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kick scooter</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37530064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/edt.12875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Dias G, Arsenio E, Ribeiro P. The role of shared E-scooter systems in urban sustainability and resilience during the COVID-19 mobility restrictions. Sustainability. 2021;13:7084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman S, Webber C, O'Meara M. Scooter injuries in children. J Paediatr Child Health. 2001;37:567-570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine D. All-terrain vehicle, trampoline and scooter injuries and their prevention in children. Curr Opin Pediatr. 2006;18:260-265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner EN, Krastl G, K&#xfc;hl S, Filippi A. Dental injuries with kick-scooters in 6- to 12-year-old children. Dent Traumatol. 2012;28:148-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishmael CR, Hsiue PP, Zoller SD, Wang P, Hori KR, Gatto JD, et al. An early look at operative orthopaedic injuries associated with electric scooter accidents: bringing high-energy trauma to a wider audience. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2020;102:e18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korea consumer agency. beware of child safety accidents caused by micromobility (bicycles, kickboards, roller skates/in-line skates, skateboards, wheel sneakers). 2023 https://www.isafe.go.kr/children/selectBbsNttView.do?bbsNo=94&amp;nttNo=34768&amp;key=226</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Road traffic authority (koroad). monthly traffic accident statistics by vehicle type of offender driver. 2023 https://taas.koroad.or.kr/sta/acs/exs/typical.do?menuId=WEB_KMP_OVT_UAS_ASA</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berretta D. After the Paris ban, what's next for e-scooters? 2023 https://eurocities.eu/latest/after-the-paris-ban-whats-next-for-e-scooters/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keum M, Cho MJ. Unpowered scooter injury in children at a Korea level I trauma center. Front Pediatr. 2021;9:353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M, Lee S, Ko DR, Kim DH, Huh JK, Kim JY. Craniofacial and dental injuries associated with stand-up electric scooters. Dent Traumatol. 2021;37:229-233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwani M, Jones AJ, Sandelski M, Bandali E, Lancaster B, Sim MW, et al. Facing facts: facial injuries from stand-up electric scooters. Cureus. 2020;12:e6663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toofany M, Mohsenian S, Shum LK, Chan H, Brubacher JR. Injury patterns and circumstances associated with electric scooter collisions: a scoping review. Inj Prev. 2021;27:490-499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuschieri S. The STROBE guidelines. Saudi J Anaesth. 2019;13:S31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourguignon C, Cohenca N, Lauridsen E, Flores MT, O'Connell AC, Day PF, et al. International Association of Dental Traumatology guidelines for the management of traumatic dental injuries: 1 Fractures and luxations. Dent Traumatol. 2020;36:314-330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fouad AF, Abbott PV, Tsilingaridis G, Cohenca N, Lauridsen E, Bourguignon C, et al. International Association of Dental Traumatology guidelines for the management of traumatic dental injuries: 2 Avulsion of permanent teeth. Dent Traumatol. 2020;36:331-342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levin L, Day PF, Hicks L, O'Connell A, Fouad AF, Bourguignon C, et al. International Association of Dental Traumatology guidelines for the management of traumatic dental injuries: general introduction. Dent Traumatol. 2020;36:309-313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day PF, Flores MT, O'Connell AC, Abbott PV, Tsilingaridis G, Fouad AF, et al. International Association of Dental Traumatology guidelines for the management of traumatic dental injuries: 3. Injuries in the primary dentition. Dent Traumatol. 2020;36:343-359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreasen JO, Andreasen FM, Andersson L, editors. Classification, Epidemiology and etiology. In: Textbook and color atlas of traumatic injuries to the teeth. 5th ed. DaehanNarae publishing, Inc. 2022; 260-303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korea consumer insurveillance system (KCIS). children safety accident trend analysis. https://www.kca.go.kr/smartconsumer/synapviewer.do?menukey=7301&amp;fno=10038859&amp;bid=00000146&amp;did=1003511440</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korea consumer insurveillance system (KCIS). children safety accident trend analysis. 2023 https://www.kca.go.kr/smartconsumer/synapviewer.do?menukey=7301&amp;fno=10034133&amp;bid=00000146&amp;did=1003319632</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Boutray M, K&#xfc;n-Darbois JD, Sigaux N, Lutz JC, Veyssiere A, Sesque A, et al. Impact of the COVID-19 lockdown on the epidemiology of maxillofacial trauma activity: a French multicentre comparative study. Int J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2021;50:750-755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shichman I, Shaked O, Factor S, Weiss-Meilik A, Khoury A. Emergency department electric scooter injuries after the introduction of shared e-scooter services: a retrospective review of 3,331 cases. World J Emerg Med. 2022;13:5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stigson H, Malakuti I, Klingeg&#xe5;rd M. Electric scooters accidents: analyses of two Swedish accident data sets. Accid Anal Prev. 2021;163:106466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi LM, Williams E, Brown CV, Emigh BJ, Bansal V, Badiee J, et al. The e-merging e-pidemic of e-scooters. Trauma Surg Acute Care Open. 2019;4:e000337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi JH, Oh SS, Kim KS, Hwang JH, Lee SY. Electric scooter-related trauma in Korea. J Korean Med Sci. 2022;37:e181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauridsen E, Hermann NV, Gerds TA, Kreiborg S, Andreasen JO. Pattern of traumatic dental injuries in the permanent dentition among children, adolescents, and adults. Dent Traumatol. 2012;28:358-363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gassner R, Tuli T, H&#xe4;chl O, Moreira R, Ulmer H. Craniomaxillofacial trauma in children: a review of 3,385 cases with 6,060 injuries in 10&#x2009;years. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2004;62:399-407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KC, Naik K, Wu BW, Karlis V, Chuang SK, Eisig SB. Are motorized scooters associated with more severe craniomaxillofacial injuries? J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2020;78:1583-1589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ptak M, Fernandes FAO, Dymek M, Welter C, Brodzi&#x144;ski K, Chybowski L. Analysis of electric scooter user kinematics after a crash against SUV. PloS One. 2022;17:e0262682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahum AM. The biomechanics of facial bone fracture. Laryngoscope. 1975;85:140-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huelke DF, Compton CP. Facial injuries in automobile crashes. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 1983;41:241-244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraji F, Lee JH, Faraji F, MacDonald B, Oviedo P, Stuart E, et al. Electric scooter craniofacial trauma. Laryn Investi Otolaryngol. 2020;5:390-395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong BD. Lacerations of the mouth. Emerg Med Clin North Am. 2000;18:471-480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gassner R, Tuli T, H&#xe4;chl O, Rudisch A, Ulmer H. Cranio-maxillofacial trauma: a 10 year review of 9,543 cases with 21,067 injuries. J Craniomaxillofac Surg. 2003;31:51-61.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>