<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38560644</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2514-1775</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Rheumatology advances in practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rheumatol Adv Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Characteristics of long COVID in patients with autoimmune rheumatic diseases: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>rkae027</StartPage><MedlinePgn>rkae027</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">rkae027</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/rap/rkae027</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Numerous cases of long coronavirus disease (long COVID) have been reported in patients with autoimmune rheumatic diseases (ARDs). Despite the reviews on clinical manifestations of long COVID in the general population, systematic reviews on ARD patients are scarce. Herein, we conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis on the prevalence and characteristics of long COVID in ARD patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We searched the literature in PubMed and Embase as of 27 December 2022. Cohort, cross-sectional and case-control studies relevant to long COVID in ARD patients were collected. Stratification based on the severity of COVID infection and subtypes of rheumatic diseases [systemic autoimmune rheumatic disease (SARD) <i>vs</i> non-autoimmune rheumatic disease (NARD)] was also undertaken. A random-effects model was used in the meta-analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 15 relevant studies were identified from the literature. The prevalence of long COVID was 56% (95% CI 34, 76) in 2995 patients. Hospitalized COVID patients had a higher proportion of long COVID than non-hospitalized patients. The prevalence of long COVID was similar between SARD and NARD patients. In terms of symptoms, fatigue, arthralgia and pain were commonly reported in long COVID patients with ARDs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The characteristics of long COVID in ARD patients are generally similar to those in the general population despite a higher prevalence and a higher proportion of arthralgia and pain.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2024. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the British Society for Rheumatology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Der-Yuan</ForeName><Initials>DY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1266-1423</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology and Immunology Center, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine, National Chung Hsing University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Po-I</ForeName><Initials>PI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Taichung Veterans General Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Kuo-Tung</ForeName><Initials>KT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5468-1329</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Allergy, Immunology, and Rheumatology, Taichung Veterans General Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ph.D. Program in Translational Medicine and Rong Hsing Research Center for Translational Medicine, National Chung Hsing University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Rheumatol Adv Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101736676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2514-1775</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fibromyalgia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rheumatic disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic autoimmune rheumatic disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38560644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10980592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rap/rkae027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">rkae027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gandhi RT, Lynch JB, Del Rio C.. Mild or moderate covid-19. N Engl J Med 2020;383:1757&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32329974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan WJ, Ni ZY, Hu Y. et al. Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N Engl J Med 2020;382:1708&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32109013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerin PJ, McLean ARD, Rashan S. et al. Definitions matter: heterogeneity of COVID-19 disease severity criteria and incomplete reporting compromise meta-analysis. PLOS Glob Public Health 2022;2:e0000561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10021556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36962738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodebaugh TL, Frumkin MR, Reiersen AM. et al. Acute symptoms of mild to moderate COVID-19 are highly heterogeneous across individuals and over time. Open Forum Infect Dis 2021;8:ofab090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7989225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33796601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG. et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell 2022;185:881&#x2013;95 e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borchers A, Pieler T.. Programming pluripotent precursor cells derived from Xenopus embryos to generate specific tissues and organs. Genes (Basel) 2010;1:413&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3966229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24710095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P.. Long covid&#x2014;mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ 2021;374:n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scharf RE, Anaya JM.. Post-COVID syndrome in adults&#x2014;an overview. Viruses 2023;15:15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10056158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36992384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang R, Yen-Ting Chen T, Wang SI. et al. Risk of autoimmune diseases in patients with COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study. EClinicalMedicine 2023;56:101783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9830133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36643619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch F, Ehm F, Vivirito A. et al. Incident autoimmune diseases in association with SARS-CoV-2 infection: a matched cohort study. Clin Rheumatol 2023;42:2919&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10497688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37335408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang KT, Hsu BC, Chen DY.. Immunogenicity, effectiveness, and safety of COVID-19 vaccines in rheumatic patients: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Biomedicines 2022;10:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9030402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35453585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aronova E, Gridneva G, Belov B.. Characteristics of post-COVID syndrome in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Ann Rheum Dis 2022;81:1669&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbhaiya M, Jannat-Khah D, Levine J.. Risk factors for &#x201c;long haul&#x201d; COVID-19 in rheumatology outpatients in New York City. Arthritis Rheumatol 2021;73(Suppl 9):abstract 0095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bat&#x131;bay S, Kocak UR, Gunendi Z, Gogus F.. The prevalence and clinical spectrum of post-Covid syndrome in patients with rheumatic diseases: a single-center experience. Reumatismo 2022;74:1481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35506317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brito-Zer&#xf3;n P, Acar-Denizli N, Romao VC. et al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome in patients with primary Sjogren&#x2019;s syndrome after acute SARS-CoV-2 infection. Clin Exp Rheumatol 2021;39(Suppl 133):57&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34874821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;y&#xfc;k&#x15f;ireci DE, T&#xfc;rk A&#xc7;, Erden E, Erden E.. Evaluation of pain, disease activity, anxiety, depression, and neuropathic pain levels after COVID-19 infection in fibromyalgia patients. Ir J Med Sci 2023;192:1387&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9258456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35794340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox N, Raizada SR, Barkham N, Bateman J.. Long COVID is associated with poor mental health in patients with rheumatic disease: results from a 14-month longitudinal study. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2022;61(Suppl 1):keac133.074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Navarro-Pardo E. et al. The presence of rheumatological conditions is not a risk factor of long-term post-COVID symptoms after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a multicenter study. Clin Rheumatol 2022;41:585&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8475301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34561811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez CAG, Cosatti M, Coello VVC. et al. Prevalence of long COVID in rheumatic disease patients: analysis of SAR COVID registry. Ann Rheum Dis 2022;81:1668&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husni ECC, Lapin B, Kirchner E, Calabrese L.. Impact of COVID-19 infection on patient-reported outcomes in rheumatic disease patients: a cross sectional study. Arthritis Rheumatol 2021;73(Suppl 9):abstract 1537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Iorio M, Cook CE, Vanni KMM. et al. DMARD disruption, rheumatic disease flare, and prolonged COVID-19 symptom duration after acute COVID-19 among patients with rheumatic disease: a prospective study. Semin Arthritis Rheum 2022;55:152025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9116968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35617780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon L, Perez-Sancristobal I, Madrid A. et al. Persistent post-discharge symptoms after COVID-19 in rheumatic and musculoskeletal diseases. Rheumatol Adv Pract 2022;6:rkac008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8882379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35233480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukhamadieva V, Lapshina S, Shamsutdinova N. et al. Clinical characteristics of patients with spondyloarthritis with COVID-19 in anamnesis in the Republic of Tatarstan. Ann Rheum Dis 2022;81:1553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norgard BM, Zegers FD, Nielsen J, Kjeldsen J.. Post COVID-19 hospitalizations in patients with chronic inflammatory diseases&#x2014;a nationwide cohort study. J Autoimmun 2021;125:102739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8552550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34757259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera J, Rodriguez T, Pallares M. et al. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 in patients with fibromyalgia: a comparative study with other inflammatory and autoimmune rheumatic diseases. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2022;23:471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9117853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35590317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamsutdinova N, Lapshina S, Mukhamadieva V. et al. Clinical characteristics of patients with rheumatoid arthritis who underwent COVID-19 in the Republic of Tatarstan. Ann Rheum Dis 2022;81:1695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Hernan MA, Reeves BC. et al. ROBINS-I: a tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. BMJ 2016;355:i4919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5062054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schunemann HJ, Cuello C, Akl EA. et al. GRADE guidelines: 18. How ROBINS-I and other tools to assess risk of bias in nonrandomized studies should be used to rate the certainty of a body of evidence. J Clin Epidemiol 2019;111:105&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6692166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29432858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DerSimonian R, Laird N.. Meta-analysis in clinical trials. Control Clin Trials 1986;7:177&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3802833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delorme C, Paccoud O, Kas A. et al. COVID-19-related encephalopathy: a case series with brain FDG-positron-emission tomography/computed tomography findings. Eur J Neurol 2020;27:2651&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32881133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hakeim HK, Al-Rubaye HT, Al-Hadrawi DS, Almulla AF, Maes M.. Long-COVID post-viral chronic fatigue and affective symptoms are associated with oxidative damage, lowered antioxidant defenses and inflammation: a proof of concept and mechanism study. Mol Psychiatry 2023;28:564&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9589528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36280755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P. et al. Autonomic dysfunction in &#x2018;long COVID&#x2019;: rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin Med (Lond) 2021;21:e63&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passavanti M, Argentieri A, Barbieri DM. et al. The psychological impact of COVID-19 and restrictive measures in the world. J Affect Disord 2021;283:36&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33516085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang KT, Hsu BC, Chen DY.. Autoimmune and rheumatic manifestations associated with COVID-19 in adults: an updated systematic review. Front Immunol 2021;12:645013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7994612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33777042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acosta-Ampudia Y, Monsalve DM, Rojas M. et al. Persistent autoimmune activation and proinflammatory state in post-coronavirus disease 2019 syndrome. J Infect Dis 2022;225:2155&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8903340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35079804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB. et al. Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Immunol 2022;23:210&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparks JA, Wallace ZS, Seet AM. et al. Associations of baseline use of biologic or targeted synthetic DMARDs with COVID-19 severity in rheumatoid arthritis: results from the COVID-19 Global Rheumatology Alliance physician registry. Ann Rheum Dis 2021;80:1137&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8172266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34049860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L. et al. Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis 2022;226:1593&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips K, Clauw DJ.. Central pain mechanisms in the rheumatic diseases: future directions. Arthritis Rheum 2013;65:291&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3610409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23045168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauw DJ, Calabrese L.. Rheumatology and long COVID: lessons from the study of fibromyalgia. Ann Rheum Dis 2023;83:136&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10850638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37230736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang KT, Lin CC, Chen YH. et al. Direct-acting antiviral drugs reduce fibromyalgia symptoms in patients with chronic hepatitis C. J Clin Med 2022;11:5327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9500682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36142974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salaffi F, Giorgi V, Sirotti S. et al. The effect of novel coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19) on fibromyalgia syndrome. Clin Exp Rheumatol 2021;39(Suppl 130):72&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33200740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brannock MD, Chew RF, Preiss AJ. et al. Long COVID risk and pre-COVID vaccination in an EHR-based cohort study from the RECOVER program. Nat Commun 2023;14:2914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10201472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37217471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Choi T, Al-Aly Z.. Association of treatment with nirmatrelvir and the risk of post-COVID-19 condition. JAMA Intern Med 2023;183:554&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10037200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ.. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet 2022;399:2263&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35717982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>