<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39417730</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2702-3648</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of osteopathic medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Osteopath Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The negative effects of long COVID-19 on cardiovascular health and implications for the presurgical examination.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/jom-2024-0109</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CONTEXT" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In 2019, emergence of the novel and communicable severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection took scientific communities by surprise and imposed significant burden on healthcare systems globally. Although the advent of this disease piqued the interest of academic centers, healthcare systems, and the general public, there is still much yet to be elucidated regarding epidemiology, pathophysiology, and long-term impacts of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). It has been established that long COVID-19 can impact multiple organ systems, including the cardiovascular system, unfavorably. Although the pathophysiology of this damage is not well understood, adverse sequelae may range from chest pain and arrhythmias to heart failure (HF), myocardial infarction, or sudden cardiac death. For any postacute COVID-19 patient requiring a surgical procedure, the potential for cardiac injury secondary to long COVID-19 must be considered in the preoperative cardiac examination.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This literature review serves to add to the growing body of literature exploring postacute cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19, with a focus on presurgical cardiac clearance in the adult patient. Specifically, this review studies the prevalence of cardiovascular symptomatology including chest pain, arrhythmias, blood pressure changes, myo-/pericarditis, HF, cardiomyopathy, orthostatic intolerance, and thromboembolism. Although current evidence is scarce in both quality and quantity, it is the goal that this review will highlight the negative impacts of long COVID-19 on cardiovascular health and encourage providers to be cognizant of potential sequelae in the context of the presurgical examination.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">For this study, peer-reviewed and journal-published articles were selected based on established inclusion and exclusion criteria to address the question "How does long COVID-19 impact the presurgical cardiac examination of an adult scheduled to undergo a noncardiac procedure?" Inclusion criteria included human studies conducted in adult patients and published in peer-reviewed journals up until May 2024 examining the effects of long-COVID-19 infection on the cardiovascular system. Exclusion criteria eliminated unpublished reports, preprints, duplicate articles, literature regarding coronavirus strains other than COVID-19, studies regarding post-COVID-19 vaccination complications, animal studies, and studies conducted in people younger than 18 years of age. A total of 6,675 studies were retrieved from PubMed and Google Scholar. Following screening, 60 studies were included in final consideration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Cardiovascular symptoms of postacute COVID-19 infection were encountered with the following percentages prevalence (total numbers of articles mentioning symptom/total number of articles [60]): chest pain (83.3), arrhythmias (88.3), hypertension (40.0), hypotension (16.7), myocarditis (80.0), pericarditis (51.7), HF (70.0), cardiomyopathy (55.0), orthostatic intolerance (56.7), and thromboembolic events (85.0).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The presence of persisting COVID symptoms may negatively impact the patient's physical examination, blood tests, electrocardiogram (ECG), imaging, and/or echocardiogram. Cardiac conditions associated with long COVID require special attention in the context of the presurgical candidate due to an increased risk of sudden cardiac death, myocarditis, stroke, and myocardial infarction&#xa0;- even in those who were healthy prior to acute COVID-19 infection. Until more specific scientific evidence comes to light, care of these patients should be viewed through the prism of the best practices already in use and clinicians should maintain a low threshold to pursue more extensive cardiac workup prior to surgery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 the author(s), published by De Gruyter, Berlin/Boston.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stimart</LastName><ForeName>Hannah L</ForeName><Initials>HL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>447877 Edward Via College of Osteopathic Medicine , Spartanburg, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hipkins</LastName><ForeName>Brittany</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Blue Ridge Health Family Medicine, Sylva, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Osteopath Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101776472</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2702-3648</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">preoperative</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39417730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/jom-2024-0109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jom-2024-0109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Strong for surgery . ACS. https://www.facs.org/for-patients/preparing-for-surgery/strong-for-surgery/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karnath, B. Preoperative cardiac risk assessment. Am Fam Physician 2002;66:1889&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiovascular deaths saw steep rise in U.S. during first year of the COVID-19 pandemic. www.heart.org . 2023. Available from: https://www.heart.org/en/news/2023/01/25/cardiovascular-deaths-saw-steep-rise-in-us-during-first-year-of-the-covid-19-pandemic .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gy&#xf6;ngy&#xf6;si, M, Alcaide, P, Asselbergs, FW, Brundel, BJJM, Camici, GG, Martins, PC, et al.. Long COVID and the cardiovascular system&#xa0;&#x2013; elucidating causes and cellular mechanisms in order to develop targeted diagnostic and therapeutic strategies: a joint scientific statement of the esc working groups on cellular biology of the heart and myocardial and pericardial diseases. Cardiovasc Res 2022;119:336&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.1093/cvr/cvac115 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cvr/cvac115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopanczyk, R, Kumar, N, Papadimos, TJ. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome for anesthesiologists: a narrative review and a pragmatic approach to clinical care. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth 2021;36:2727&#x2013;37. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.jvca.2021.09.051 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jvca.2021.09.051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) Pandemic. www.who.int ; 2024. Available from: https://www.who.int/europe/emergencies/situations/covid-19 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umesh, A, Pranay, K, Pandey, RC, Gupta, MK. Evidence mapping and review of long-COVID and its underlying pathophysiological mechanism. Infection 2022;50. https://doi.org/10.1007/s15010-022-01835-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s15010-022-01835-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . Post COVID-19 condition (Long COVID). www.who.int ; 2022. Available from: https://www.who.int/europe/news-room/fact-sheets/item/post-covid-19-condition .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Affairs (ASPA) AS for P . About Long COVID. www.covid.gov ; 2023. Available from: https://www.covid.gov/be-informed/longcovid/about#term .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID, NHLBI, NIH. www.nhlbi.nih.gov . 2024. Available from: https://www.nhlbi.nih.gov/covid/long-covid#:&#x223c;:text=Long%20COVID%2C%20long%2Dhaul%20COVID .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis, A, Wamil, M, Alberts, J, Oben, J, Cuthbertson, DJ, Wootton, D, et al.. Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open 2021;11:e048391. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2020-048391 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-048391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouzzani, M, Hammady, H, Fedorowicz, Z, Elmagarmid, A. Rayyan&#xa0;&#x2013; a Web and Mobile app for systematic reviews. Syst Rev 2016;5. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13643-016-0384-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13643-016-0384-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddaway, NR, Page, MJ, Pritchard, CC, McGuinness, LA. PRISMA2020: an R package and Shiny app for producing PRISMA 2020-compliant flow diagrams, with interactivity for optimised digital transparency and open synthesis. Campbell Syst Rev 2022;18. https://doi.org/10.1002/cl2.1230 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cl2.1230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aden, D, Zaheer, S, Kumar, R, Raj, S, Khan, T, Varshney, S. Beyond COVID-19 and SARS-CoV-2, cardiovascular outcomes of &#x201c;long covid&#x201d; from a pathological perspective&#xa0;&#x2013; a look back and road ahead. Pathol Res Pract 2022;239. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prp.2022.154144 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prp.2022.154144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbarialiabad, H, Taghrir, MH, Abdollahi, A, Ghahramani, N, Kumar, M, Paydar, S, et al.. Long COVID, a comprehensive systematic scoping review. Infection 2021;49. https://doi.org/10.1007/s15010-021-01666-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s15010-021-01666-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly, Z, Xie, Y, Bowe, B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequalae of COVID-19. Nature 2021;594:1&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-021-03553-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-021-03553-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allendes, FJ, D&#xed;az, HS, Ortiz, FC, Marcus, NJ, Quintanilla, R, Inestrosa, NC, et al.. Cardiovascular and autonomic dysfunction in long-COVID syndrome and the potential role of non-invasive therapeutic strategies on cardiovascular outcomes. Front Med 2023;9. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2022.1095249 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.1095249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astin, R, Banerjee, A, Baker, MR, Dani, M, Ford, E, Hull, JH, et al.. Long COVID: mechanisms, risk factors and recovery. Exp Physiol 2022;108. https://doi.org/10.1113/ep090802 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/ep090802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baroni, C, Potito, J, Perticone, ME, Orausclio, P, Luna, CM. How does long-COVID impact prognosis and the long-term sequelae? Viruses 2023;15:1173. https://doi.org/10.3390/v15051173 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v15051173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharjee, N, Sarkar, P, Sarkar, T. Beyond the acute illness: exploring long COVID and its impact on multiple organ systems. Physiol Int 2023;1. https://doi.org/10.1556/2060.2023.00256 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1556/2060.2023.00256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, X, Ismail, NI, Rahman, A, Xu, D, Chan, RWY, Ong, SG, et al.. Long COVID-19 and the heart: is cardiac mitochondria the missing link? Antioxidants Redox Signal 2022;38. https://doi.org/10.1089/ars.2022.0126 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/ars.2022.0126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chee, YJ, Fan, BE, Young, BE, Dalan, R, Lye, DC. Clinical trials on the pharmacological treatment of long COVID: a systematic review. J Med Virol 2023;95:e28289. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.28289 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sideratou, C-M, Papaneophytou, C. Persisting shadows: unraveling the impact of long COVID-19 on respiratory, cardiovascular, and nervous systems. Infect Dis Rep 2023;15:806&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.3390/idr15060072 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/idr15060072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty, SE, Guo, Y, Heath, K, Dasmari&#xf1;as, MC, Jubilo, KG, Samranvedhya, J, et al.. Risk of clinical sequelae after the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection: retrospective cohort study. BMJ 2021;373:n1098. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n1098 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n1098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePace, NL, Colombo, J. Long-COVID syndrome and the cardiovascular system: a review of neurocardiologic effects on multiple systems. Curr Cardiol Rep 2022;24:1711&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11886-022-01786-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11886-022-01786-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eiros, R, Barreiro-P&#xe9;rez, M, Mart&#xed;n-Garc&#xed;a, A, Almeida, J, Villacorta, E, P&#xe9;rez-Pons, A, et al.. Pericardial and myocardial involvement after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a cross-sectional descriptive study in healthcare workers. Revista Espanola De Cardiologia (English Ed) 2022;75:734&#x2013;46. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rec.2021.11.001 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rec.2021.11.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Gennaro, F, Belati, A, Tulone, O, Diella, L, Fiore Bavaro, D, Bonica, R, et al.. Incidence of long COVID-19 in people with previous SARS-Cov2 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis of 120,970 patients. Intern Emerg Med 2023;18:1573&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11739-022-03164-w .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11739-022-03164-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gluckman, TJ, Bhave, NM, Allen, LA, Chung, EH, Spatz, ES, Ammirati, E, et al.. ACC expert consensus decision pathway on cardiovascular sequelae of COVID-19 in adults: myocarditis and other myocardial involvement, post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection, and return to play. J Am Coll Cardiol 2022;79:1717&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2022.02.003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2022.02.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grosse, C, Grosse, A, Salzer, HJF, D&#xfc;nser, MW, Motz, R, Langer, R. Analysis of cardiopulmonary findings in COVID-19 fatalities: high incidence of pulmonary artery thrombi and acute suppurative bronchopneumonia. Cardiovasc Pathol 2020;49:107263. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carpath.2020.107263 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carpath.2020.107263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, B, Zhao, C, He, MZ, Senter, C, Zhou, Z, Peng, J, et al.. Identifying patterns of reported findings on long-term cardiac complications of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Med 2023;21. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12916-023-03162-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-023-03162-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingul, CB, Grimsmo, J, Mecinaj, A, Trebinjac, D, Berger Nossen, M, Andrup, S, et al.. Cardiac dysfunction and arrhythmias 3&#xa0;months after hospitalization for COVID-19. J Am Heart Assoc 2022;11. https://doi.org/10.1161/jaha.121.023473 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/jaha.121.023473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itua, B, Chukwuka, C. Long COVID and its effects on the cardiovascular system: a literature review. Int J Res Med Sci 2022;10:2060. https://doi.org/10.18203/2320-6012.ijrms20222291 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18203/2320-6012.ijrms20222291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sk&#x142;adanek, J, Leskiewicz, M, Gumi&#x119;&#x17c;na, K, Baru&#x15b;, P, Piasecki, A, Klimczak, D, et al.. Long COVID and its cardiovascular consequences: what is known? Adv Clin Exp Med 2023;33. https://doi.org/10.17219/acem/167482 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17219/acem/167482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karina, CM, Juarez, L, Falc&#xe3;o, LFM. Cardiovascular autonomic dysfunction in &#x201c;Long COVID&#x201d;: pathophysiology, heart rate variability, and inflammatory markers. Front Cardiovasc Med 2023;10. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcvm.2023.1256512 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2023.1256512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khazaal, S, Harb, J, Rima, M, Annweiler, C, Wu, Y, Cao, Z, et al.. The pathophysiology of long COVID throughout the Renin-angiotensin system. Molecules 2022;27. https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules27092903 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules27092903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobusiak-Prokopowicz, M, Fu&#x142;ek, K, Fu&#x142;ek, M, Kaaz, K, Mysiak, A, Kurpas, D, et al.. Cardiovascular, pulmonary, and neuropsychiatric short- and long-term complications of COVID-19. Cells 2022;11:3882. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells11233882 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells11233882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai, CC, Hsu, CK, Yen, MY, Lee, PI, Ko, WC, Hsueh, PR. Long COVID: an inevitable sequela of SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Microbiol Immunol Infect 2023;56:1&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmii.2022.10.003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmii.2022.10.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J, Zhou, Y, Ma, J, Zhang, Q, Shao, J, Liang, S, et al.. The long-term health outcomes, pathophysiological mechanisms and multidisciplinary management of long COVID. Signal Transduct Targeted Ther 2023;8. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41392-023-01640-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41392-023-01640-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantovani, A, Morrone, MC, Patrono, C, Santoro, MG, Schiaffino, S, Remuzzi, G, et al.. Long covid: where we stand and challenges ahead.&#xa0; Cell Death Differ 2022. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41418-022-01052-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41418-022-01052-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto, C, Shibata, S, Kishi, T, Morimoto, S, Mogi, M, Yamamoto, K, et al.. Long COVID and hypertension-related disorders: a report from the Japanese society of hypertension project team on COVID-19. Hypertens Res 2023;46:601&#x2013;19. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41440-022-01145-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41440-022-01145-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitrani, RD, Dabas, N, Alfadhli, J, Lowery, MH, Best, TM, Hare, JM, et al.. Long-term cardiac surveillance and outcomes of COVID-19 patients. Trends Cardiovasc Med 2022;32:465&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tcm.2022.06.003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tcm.2022.06.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed, MO, Banerjee, A. Long COVID and cardiovascular disease: a learning health system approach. Nat Rev Cardiol 2022;19. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41569-022-00697-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41569-022-00697-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad, KO, Lin, A, Rodriguez, JBC. Cardiac manifestations of post-acute COVID-19 infection. Curr Cardiol Rep 2022;24. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11886-022-01793-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11886-022-01793-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, MS, Shaik, RA, Ahmad, R, Yusuf, M, Khan, M, Almutairi, AB, et al.. Long COVID: &#x201c;an insight.&#x201d; Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci 2021;25:5561&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.26355/eurrev_202109_26669 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26355/eurrev_202109_26669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moyo, E, Munashe, C, Moyo, P, Musuka, G, Mangoya, D, Murewanhema, G, et al.. Risk factors and clinical presentations of long COVID in Africa: a scoping review. J Infect Public Health 2023;16:1982&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiph.2023.09.021 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiph.2023.09.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vishwakarma, N, Goud, RB, Prakash Tirupattur, M, Katwa, LC. The eye of the storm: investigating the long-term cardiovascular effects of COVID-19 and variants. Cells 2023;12:2154. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells12172154 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells12172154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, NN, Dudouet, P, Dhiver, C, Gautret, P. Pericarditis related to post-acute COVID infection: a case report and review of the literature. Acta Microbiol Immunol Hung 2023;70:100&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.1556/030.2023.02055 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1556/030.2023.02055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parhizgar, P, Yazdankhah, N, Rzepka, A, Chung, KYC, Ali, I, Lai Fat Fur, R, et al.. Beyond acute COVID-19: a review of long-term cardiovascular outcomes. Can J Cardiol 2023;39:726&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjca.2023.01.031 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cjca.2023.01.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson, I, Ramanathan, K, Aurora, R, Bewick, D, Chow, CM, Clarke, B, et al.. Long COVID-19: a primer for cardiovascular health professionals, on behalf of the CCS rapid response team. Can J Cardiol 2021;37:1260&#x2013;2. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjca.2021.05.011 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cjca.2021.05.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntmann, VO, Martin, S, Shchendrygina, A, Hoffmann, J, Ka, MM, Giokoglu, E, et al.. Long-term cardiac pathology in individuals with mild initial COVID-19 illness. Nat Med 2022;28:2117&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-02000-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-02000-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn, KL, Lam, GY, Walsh, JF, Bh&#xe9;reur, A, Brown, AD, Chow, CW, et al.. Cardiovascular considerations in the management of people with suspected long COVID. Can J Cardiol 2023;39. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjca.2023.04.003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cjca.2023.04.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman, B, Bluemke, DA, L&#xfc;scher, TF, Neubauer, S. Long COVID: post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 with a cardiovascular focus. Eur Heart J 2022;43. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehac031 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehac031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roba, HM, Moustafa, A. Beyond acute infection: molecular mechanisms underpinning cardiovascular complications in long COVID. Front Cardiovasc Med 2024;11. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcvm.2024.1268571 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2024.1268571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Duarte, &#xc1;, Rivera-Izquierdo, M, Guerrero-Fern&#xe1;ndez de Alba, I, P&#xe9;rez-Contreras, M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Mart&#xed;nez, NF, Ruiz-Montero, R, et al.. Sequelae, persistent symptomatology and outcomes after COVID-19 hospitalization: the ANCOHVID multicentre 6-month follow-up study. BMC Med 2021;19:129. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12916-021-02003-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-021-02003-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabrina, I, Hairunisa, N, Yosif, E. Long covid: a review on cardiovascular disease (CVD) in post-acute sequalae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC). Biointerface Res Appl Chem 2021;12:3989&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.33263/briac123.39893995 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33263/briac123.39893995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santoro, L, Zaccone, V, Falsetti, L, Ruggieri, V, Danese, M, Miro, C, et al.. Role of endothelium in cardiovascular sequelae of long COVID. Biomedicines 2023;11:2239. https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines11082239 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines11082239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satterfield, BA, Bhatt, DL, Gersh, BJ. Cardiac involvement in the long-term implications of COVID-19. Nat Rev Cardiol 2021;19. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41569-021-00631-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41569-021-00631-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawar, U, Hussain, A, Bardia, N, Tahir, H, Raza, A, Talib, A. A brief overview of COVID-19 long-term effect on cardiovascular system. J Clin Images Med Case Rep 2021;2. https://doi.org/10.52768/2766-7820/1373 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52768/2766-7820/1373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scurati, R, Papini, N, Giussani, P, Alberti, G, Tringali, C. The challenge of long COVID-19 management: from disease molecular hallmarks to the proposal of exercise as therapy. Int J Mol Sci 2022;23:12311. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms232012311 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms232012311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha, AB, Mehta, A, Pokharel, P, Mishra, A, Adhikari, L, Shrestha, S, et al.. Long COVID syndrome and cardiovascular manifestations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Diagnostics 2023;13:491. https://doi.org/10.3390/diagnostics13030491 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics13030491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva Andrade, B, Siqueira, S, de Assis Soares, WR, de Souza Rangel, F, Santos, NO, dos Santos Freitas, A, et al.. Long-COVID and post-COVID health complications: an up-to-date review on clinical conditions and their possible molecular mechanisms. Viruses 2021;13:700. https://doi.org/10.3390/v13040700 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v13040700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siripanthong, B, Asatryan, B, Hanff, TC, Chatha, SR, Khanji, MY, Ricci, F, et al.. The pathogenesis and long-term consequences of COVID-19 cardiac injury. JACC: Basic Transl Sci 2022;7:294&#x2013;308. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacbts.2021.10.011 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacbts.2021.10.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobler, DL, Pruzansky, AJ, Naderi, S, Ambrosy, AP, Slade, JJ. Long-term cardiovascular effects of COVID-19: emerging data relevant to the cardiovascular clinician. Curr Atherosclerosis Rep 2022;24:563&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11883-022-01032-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11883-022-01032-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner, S, Asad Khan, M, Putrino, D, Woodcock, A, Kell, DB, Pretorius, E. Long COVID: pathophysiological factors and abnormalities of coagulation. Trends Endocrinol Metabol 2023;34. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tem.2023.03.002 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tem.2023.03.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khetpal, V, Berkowitz, J, Vijayakumar, S, Choudhary, G, Mukand, JA, Rudolph, JL, et al.. Long-term cardiovascular manifestations and complications of COVID-19: spectrum and approach to diagnosis and management. PubMed 2022;105:16&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, X, Deng, KQ, Li, C, Yang, Z, Hu, H, Cai, H, et al.. Cardiac involvement in recovered patients from COVID-19: a preliminary 6-month follow-up study. Front Cardiovasc Med 2021;8. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcvm.2021.654405 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2021.654405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, Y, Xu, E, Bowe, B, Al-Aly, Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med 2022;28:1&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-01689-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01689-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong, SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis 2021;53:1&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1080/23744235.2021.1924397 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23744235.2021.1924397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousif, E, Premraj, S. A review of long COVID with a special focus on its cardiovascular manifestations. Cureus 2022;14. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.31933 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.31933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Create graphs and charts. Ed.gov . 2020. Available from: https://nces.ed.gov/nceskids/graphing/classic/index.asp .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eagle, KA, Berger, PB, Calkins, H, Chaitman, BR, Ewy, GA, Fleischmann, KE, et al.. ACC/AHA guideline update for perioperative cardiovascular evaluation for noncardiac surgery&#xa0;&#x2013; executive summary a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on practice guidelines (Committee to update the 1996 guidelines on perioperative cardiovascular evaluation for noncardiac surgery). Circulation 2002;105:1257&#x2013;67. https://doi.org/10.1161/circ.105.10.1257 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circ.105.10.1257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halvorsen, S, Mehilli, J, Cassese, S, Hall, TS, Abdelhamid, M, Barbato, E, et al.. ESC guidelines on cardiovascular assessment and management of patients undergoing non-cardiac surgery. Eur Heart J . 2022;43. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehac270 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehac270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duceppe, E, Parlow, J, MacDonald, P, Lyons, K, McMullen, M, Srinathan, S, et al.. Canadian cardiovascular society guidelines on perioperative cardiac risk assessment and management for patients who undergo noncardiac surgery. Can J Cardiol 2017;33:17&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjca.2016.09.008 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cjca.2016.09.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collaborative, C, Collaborative, G. Timing of surgery following SARS-CoV-2 infection: an international prospective cohort study. Anaesthesia 2021;76. https://doi.org/10.1111/anae.15458 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleisher, LA, Fleischmann, KE, Auerbach, AD, Barnason, SA, Beckman, JA, Bozkurt, B, et al.. ACC/AHA guideline on perioperative cardiovascular evaluation and management of patients undergoing noncardiac surgery. Circulation . 2014;130. https://doi.org/10.1161/cir.0000000000000106 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/cir.0000000000000106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>