<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36832543</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Persistent effects of COVID-19 in patients hospitalized during the first wave of the pandemic: The impact of persistent fatigue on quality of life in a cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e28491</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e28491</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.28491</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>COVID-19 can affect physical and mental health long after acute infection.&#xa0;In this descriptive study, 48 individuals hospitalized for COVID-19 between April and May 2020 were interviewed regarding their experience with COVID-19 after hospitalization.&#xa0;The mean age of participants was 51.1 (&#xb1;11.91) years (range 25-65 years) and 26 (54.2%) were men. Individuals had a mean of 1.2 (&#xb1;0.94) comorbidities associated with more severe COVID-19, with hypertension (37.5%) being most common. Nineteen (39.6%) individuals required treatment in the intensive care unit. Participants were interviewed a median time of 553 days (IQR, 405.5-589.0) after discharge from the hospital. Thirty-seven&#xa0;(77.1%) individuals had 5 or more persistent symptoms at time of interview with only 3 (6.3%) experiencing none. The most reported persistent symptoms were fatigue (79.2%), difficulty breathing (68.8%), and muscle weakness (60.4%). Poor quality of life was experienced by 39 (81.3%) participants and 8 (16.7%) had a posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) score within the clinical range for diagnosis. For multivariable analyses, persistent fatigue was significantly predicted by number of symptoms during acute COVID-19 (t&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.4, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Number of symptoms during acute COVID-19 was also significantly associated with persistent dyspnea (t&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.4, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002). Higher scores on the Chalder fatigue scale after COVID-19 was significantly associated with poor quality of life (t&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.6, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01) and PTSD symptomatology (t&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.9, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.008).&#xa0;More research is needed to highlight the wide range of resources those suffering from Long COVID require long after discharge.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skinner</LastName><ForeName>Joseph P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9566-0287</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Psychotic Disorders, McLean Hospital, Belmont, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moran</LastName><ForeName>Lauren V</ForeName><Initials>LV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Psychotic Disorders, McLean Hospital, Belmont, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 MH122427</GrantID><Acronym>MH</Acronym><Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004417" MajorTopicYN="N">Dyspnea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-ICU syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36832543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F, Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603-605. doi:10.1001/jama.2020.12603</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestre-Mu&#xf1;iz MM, Arias &#xc1;, Mata-V&#xe1;zquez E, et al. Long-term outcomes of patients with coronavirus disease 2019 at one year after hospital discharge. J Clin Med. 2021;10(13):2945. doi:10.3390/jcm10132945</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go&#xeb;rtz YMJ, Van Herck M, Delbressine JM, et al. Persistent symptoms 3&#x2005;months after a SARS-CoV-2 infection: the post-COVID-19 syndrome? ERJ Open Res. 2020;6(4):542-2020. doi:10.1183/23120541.00542-2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93(2):1013-1022. doi:10.1002/jmv.26368</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, et al. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network-United States, March-June 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69(30):993-998. doi:10.15585/mmwr.mm6930e1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT, Hamilton FW, Milne A, et al. Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up: results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax. 2021;76(4):399-401. doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216086</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui DS, Joynt GM, Wong KT, et al. Impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) on pulmonary function, functional capacity and quality of life in a cohort of survivors. Thorax. 2005;60(5):401-409. doi:10.1136/thx.2004.030205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, McAuley H, Harrison EM, et al. Physical, cognitive, and mental health impacts of COVID-19 after hospitalisation (PHOSP-COVID): a UK multicentre, prospective cohort study. Lancet Resp&#xa0;Med. 2021;9(11):1275-1287. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00383-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220-232. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones R, Davis A, Stanley B, et al. Risk predictors and symptom features of long COVID within a broad primary care patient population including both tested and untested patients. Pragmat Obs Res. 2021;12:93-104. doi:10.2147/POR.S316186</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osikomaiya B, Erinoso O, Wright KO, et al. &#x201c;Long COVID&#x201d;: persistent COVID-19 symptoms in survivors managed in Lagos State, Nigeria. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):304. doi:10.1186/s12879-020-05716-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nature Med. 2021;27(4):626-631. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021; 374:n1648. doi:10.1136/bmj.n1648</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vindegaard N, Benros ME. COVID-19 pandemic and mental health consequences: systematic review of the current evidence. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;89:531-542. doi:10.1016/j.bbi.2020.05.048</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai X, Hu X, Ekumi IO, et al. Psychological distress and its correlates among COVID-19 survivors during early convalescence across age groups. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2020;28(10):1030-1039. doi:10.1016/j.jagp.2020.07.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, De Lorenzo R, Conte C, et al. Anxiety and depression in COVID-19 survivors: role of inflammatory and clinical predictors. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;89:594-600. doi:10.1016/j.bbi.2020.07.037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simani L, Ramezani M, Darazam IA, et al. Prevalence and correlates of chronic fatigue syndrome and post-traumatic stress disorder after the outbreak of the COVID-19. J Neurovirol. 2021;27(1):154-159. doi:10.1007/s13365-021-00949-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra V, Flanders SA, O'Malley M, Malani AN, Prescott HC. Sixty-day outcomes among patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174(4):576-578. doi:10.7326/M20-5661</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzaei A, Raesi R, Saghari S, Raei M. Evaluation of family caregiver burden among COVID-19 patients. Open Public Health J. 2020;13(1):808-814. doi:10.2174/1874944502013010808</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirhosseini S, Vaghee S, Nabavi F, Vashani H. Effect of online psychoeducational support on caring burden in family caregivers of COVID-19 patients: a parallel randomized controlled trial. Family Medicine&#xa0;Primary Care Rev. 2021;23(3):323-329. doi:10.5114/fmpcr.2021.108198</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weidman K, LaFond E, Hoffman KL, et al. Post-intensive care unit syndrome in a cohort of COVID-19 survivors in New York City. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2022;19(7):1158-1168. doi:10.1513/AnnalsATS.202104-520OC</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawal G, Yadav S, Kumar R. Post-intensive care syndrome: an overview. J Transl Int Med. 2017;5(2):90-92. doi:10.1515/jtim-2016-0016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Disease Control and Prevention.&#xa0;Long COVID or post-COVID conditions.&#xa0;2022. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html#:%7E:text=People%20with%20post%2DCOVID%20conditions%20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirulli ET, Schiabor Barrett KM, Riffle S, et al. Long-term COVID-19 symptoms in a large unselected population. Infec&#xa0;Dis&#xa0;(except HIV/AIDS). 2020.&#xa0;doi:10.1101/2020.10.07.20208702</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The COVID-19 host genetics initiative. 2022. https://www.covid19hg.org/about/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalder T, Berelowitz G, Pawlikowska T, et al. Development of a fatigue scale. J Psychosom Res. 1993;37(2):147-153. doi:10.1016/0022-3999(93)90081-p</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorke J, Moosavi SH, Shuldham C, Jones PW. Quantification of dyspnoea using descriptors: development and initial testing of the Dyspnoea-12. Thorax. 2010;65(1):21-26. doi:10.1136/thx.2009.118521</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herdman M, Gudex C, Lloyd A, et al. Development and preliminary testing of the new five-level version of EQ-5D (EQ-5D-5L). Qual Life Res. 2011;20(10):1727-1736. doi:10.1007/s11136-011-9903-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng YS, Kohlmann T, Janssen MF, Buchholz I. Psychometric properties of the EQ-5D-5L: a systematic review of the literature. Qual Life Res. 2021;30(3):647-673. doi:10.1007/s11136-020-02688-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig BM, Rand K. Choice defines QALYs: a US valuation of the EQ-5D-5L. Med Care. 2018;56(6):529-536. doi:10.1097/MLR.0000000000000912</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aljaberi MA, Alareqe NA, Qasem MA, et al. Rasch modeling and multilevel confirmatory factor analysis for the usability of the impact of event scale-revised (IES-R) during the COVID-19 pandemic. SSRN Electron J. 2021;10(10):1858. doi:10.2139/ssrn.3815681</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creamer M, Bell R, Failla S. Psychometric properties of the impact of event scale-revised. Behav Res Ther. 2003;41(12):1489-1496. doi:10.1016/j.brat.2003.07.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck JG, Grant DM, Read JP, et al. The impact of event scale-revised: psychometric properties in a sample of motor vehicle accident survivors. J Anxiety Disord. 2008;22(2):187-198. doi:10.1016/j.janxdis.2007.02.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Disease Control and Prevention. Underlying medical conditions associated with higher risk for severe COVID-19: information for healthcare professionals. 2022. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/underlyingconditions.html#more-information</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, et al. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med. 2021;114(9):428-442. doi:10.1177/01410768211032850</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkodaymi MS, Omrani OA, Fawzy NA, et al. Prevalence of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome symptoms at different follow-up periods: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28(5):657-666. doi:10.1016/j.cmi.2022.01.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Ling S, Lui LMW, et al. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in post-COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun. 2022;101:93-135. doi:10.1016/j.bbi.2021.12.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik P, Patel K, Pinto C, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PCS) and health-related quality of life (HRQoL)-a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2022;94(1):253-262. doi:10.1002/jmv.27309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Kessel SAM, Olde Hartman TC, Lucassen PLBJ, van Jaarsveld CHM. Post-acute and long-COVID-19 symptoms in patients with mild diseases: a systematic review. Fam Pract. 2022;39(1):159-167. doi:10.1093/fampra/cmab076</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz-Corona C, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Canales LG, Ortiz-Ledesma C, et al. Quality of life and persistence of COVID-19 symptoms 90 days after hospital discharge. J Int Med Res. 2022;50(7):030006052211104. doi:10.1177/03000605221110492</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schou TM, Joca S, Wegener G, Bay-Richter C. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19-a systematic review. Brain Behav Immun. 2021;97:328-348. doi:10.1016/j.bbi.2021.07.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarsitani L, Vassalini P, Koukopoulos A, et al. Post-traumatic stress disorder among COVID-19 survivors at 3-month follow-up after hospital discharge. J Gen Intern Med. 2021;36(6):1702-1707. doi:10.1007/s11606-021-06731-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannopoulou I, Galinaki S, Kollintza E, et al. COVID-19 and post-traumatic stress disorder: the perfect &#x2018;storm' for mental health (review). Exp Ther Med. 2021;22(4):1162. doi:10.3892/etm.2021.10596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannou GN, Baraff A, Fox A, et al. Rates and factors associated with documentation of diagnostic codes for long COVID in the National Veterans Affairs Health Care System. JAMA Net&#xa0;Open. 2022;5(7):e2224359. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.24359</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Righy C, Rosa RG, da Silva RTA, et al. Prevalence of post-traumatic stress disorder symptoms in adult critical care survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Care. 2019;23(1):213. doi:10.1186/s13054-019-2489-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, et al. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Intern Med. 2021;92:55-70. doi:10.1016/j.ejim.2021.06.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitaker M, Elliott J, Chadeau-Hyam M, et al. Persistent COVID-19 symptoms in a community study of 606,434 people in England. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):1957. doi:10.1038/s41467-022-29521-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassett IV, Triant VA, Bunda BA, et al. Massachusetts general hospital Covid-19 registry reveals two distinct populations of hospitalized patients by race and ethnicity. PLoS One. 2020;15(12):e0244270. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0244270</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contag CH, Chan SPK, Wietgrefe SW, Plagemann PGW. Correlation between presence of lactate dehydrogenase-elevating virus RNA and antigens in motor neurons and paralysis in infected C58 mice. Virus Res. 1986;6(3):195-209. doi:10.1016/0168-1702(86)90069-9</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>