<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38836048</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1179-1349</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical epidemiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Epidemiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Risk of Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection (PASC) Among Patients with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus on Anti-Hyperglycemic Medications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>379</StartPage><EndPage>393</EndPage><MedlinePgn>379-393</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/CLEP.S458901</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Observed activity of metformin in reducing the risk of severe COVID-19 suggests a potential use of the anti-hyperglycemic in the prevention of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC). We assessed the 3-month and 6-month risk of PASC among patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) comparing metformin users to sulfonylureas (SU) or dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitors (DPP4i) users.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We used de-identified patient level electronic health record data from the National Covid Cohort Collaborative (N3C) between October 2021 and April 2023. Participants were adults &#x2265; 18 years with T2DM who had at least one outpatient healthcare encounter in health institutions in the United States prior to COVID-19 diagnosis. The outcome of PASC was defined based on the presence of a diagnosis code for the illness or using a predicted probability based on a machine learning algorithm. We estimated the 3-month and 6-month risk of PASC and calculated crude and weighted risk ratios (RR), risk differences (RD), and differences in mean predicted probability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We identified 5596 (mean age: 61.1 years; SD: 12.6) and 1451 (mean age: 64.9 years; SD 12.5) eligible prevalent users of metformin and SU/DPP4i respectively. We did not find a significant difference in risk of PASC at 3 months (RR = 0.86 [0.56; 1.32], RD = -3.06 per 1000 [-12.14; 6.01]), or at 6 months (RR = 0.81 [0.55; 1.20], RD = -4.91 per 1000 [-14.75, 4.93]) comparing prevalent users of metformin to prevalent users of SU/ DPP4i. Similar observations were made for the outcome definition using the ML algorithm.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The observed estimates in our study are consistent with a reduced risk of PASC among prevalent users of metformin, however the uncertainty of our confidence intervals warrants cautious interpretations of the results. A standardized clinical definition of PASC is warranted for thorough evaluation of the effectiveness of therapies under assessment for the prevention of PASC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Olawore et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olawore</LastName><ForeName>Oluwasolape</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8954-6426</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, Gillings School of Global Public Health, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turner</LastName><ForeName>Lindsey E</ForeName><Initials>LE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Biostatistics and Health Data Science, University of Minnesota School of Public Health, Minneapolis, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical and Translational Science Institute, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Evans</LastName><ForeName>Michael D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7449-3993</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical and Translational Science Institute, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Steven G</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health Informatics, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huling</LastName><ForeName>Jared D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Biostatistics and Health Data Science, University of Minnesota School of Public Health, Minneapolis, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bramante</LastName><ForeName>Carolyn T</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Internal Medicine, Department of Medicine, University of Minnesota Medical School, Minneapolis, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buse</LastName><ForeName>John B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Endocrinology, Department of Medicine, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill School of Medicine, Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>St&#xfc;rmer</LastName><ForeName>Til</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9204-7177</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, Gillings School of Global Public Health, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>N3C Consortium</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K23 DK124654</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Epidemiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101531700</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1179-1349</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Previous research suggests that metformin, due to its anti-viral, anti-inflammatory, and anti-thrombotic properties may reduce the risk of severe COVID-19. Given the shared etiology of COVID-19 and the post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (PASC), and the proposed inflammatory processes of PASC, metformin may also be a beneficial preventive option. We investigated the benefit of metformin for PASC prevention in a population of type 2 diabetes mellitus patients with a COVID-19 diagnosis who were on metformin or two other anti-hyperglycemic medications prior to infection with SARS-CoV-2. Our results were consistent with a reduction in the risk of PASC with the use of metformin, however, the imprecise confidence intervals obtained warrants further investigation of this association of the potential beneficial effect of metformin for preventing PASC in patients with medication-managed diabetes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Olawore et al.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metformin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes Mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>JBB reports contracted fees and travel support for contracted activities for consulting work paid to the University of North Carolina by Novo Nordisk; grant support by Bayer, Boehringer-Ingelheim, Carmot, Corcept, Dexcom, Eli Lilly, Insulet, MannKind, Novo Nordisk, and vTv Therapeutics; consulting fees from Alkahest, Altimmune, Anji, Aqua Medical Inc, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Biomea Fusion Inc, Boehringer-Ingelheim, CeQur, Corcept Therapeutics, Eli Lilly, embecta, Fortress Biotech, GentiBio, Glycadia, Glyscend, Janssen, MannKind, Insulet, Mediflix, Medscape, Medtronic/MiniMed, Mellitus Health, Metsera, Moderna, Pendulum Therapeutics, Praetego, ReachMD, Sanofi, Stability Health, Tandem, Terns Inc, Valo, Vertex, and Zealand Pharma; expert witness compensation from Medtronic MiniMed; and stock options from Glyscend, Mellitus Health, Pendulum Therapeutics, Praetego, and Stability Health. TS receives salary support as Director of Comparative Effectiveness Research (CER), NC TraCS Institute, UNC Clinical and Translational Science Award (UL1TR002489), the Center for Pharmacoepidemiology, investigator-initiated research funding and support as Principal Investigator (R01AG056479) from the National Institute on Aging (NIA), and as Co-Investigator (R01CA277756) from the National Cancer Institute, National Institutes of Health (NIH). He also receives salary support as Director of Comparative Effectiveness Research (CER), NC TraCS Institute, UNC Clinical and Translational Science Award (UM1TR004406), co-Director of the Human Studies Consultation Core, NC Diabetes Research Center (P30DK124723), National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK), the Center for Pharmacoepidemiology (current members: GlaxoSmithKline, UCB BioSciences, Takeda, AbbVie, Boehringer Ingelheim, Astellas, and Sarepta). He owns stock in Novartis, Roche, and Novo Nordisk and from a generous contribution from Dr. Nancy A. Dreyer to the Department of Epidemiology, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. TS does not accept personal compensation of any kind from any pharmaceutical company. OO received funding from the Center for Pharmacoepidemiology (CPE) housed in the Department of Epidemiology at University of North Carolina Chapel Hill. AbbVie, Astellas, Boehringer Ingelheim, GlaxoSmithKline (GSK), Takeda, Sarepta, and UCB BioSciences have collaborative agreements with CPE. Other authors report no conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38836048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11149650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CLEP.S458901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">458901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cutler DM. The Costs of Long COVID. JAMA Health Forum. 2022;3(5):e221809&#x2013;e221809. doi:10.1001/jamahealthforum.2022.1809</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamahealthforum.2022.1809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36219031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Bowe B, Xie Y. Long COVID after breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med. 2022;28(7):1461&#x2013;1467. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-01840-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01840-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9307472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35614233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Bosworth ML, King S, et al. Risk of Long COVID in people infected with severe acute respiratory syndrome Coronavirus 2 After 2 Doses of a Coronavirus Disease 2019 Vaccine: community-based, matched cohort study. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2022;9(9). doi:10.1093/ofid/ofac464</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ofid/ofac464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9494414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36168555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon MA, Luginbuhl RD, Parker R. Reduced Incidence of Long-COVID Symptoms Related to Administration of COVID-19 Vaccines Both Before COVID-19 diagnosis and up to 12 weeks after. medRxiv. 2021;2021:21263608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, et al. Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nature Med. 2022;28(8):1706&#x2013;1714. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-01909-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01909-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE, et al. Short-term and Long-term Rates of Postacute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection: a Systematic Review. JAMA Net Open. 2021;4(10):e2128568&#x2013;e2128568. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.28568</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.28568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34643720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, et al. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med. 2021;114(9):428&#x2013;442. doi:10.1177/01410768211032850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/01410768211032850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Scientific Rep. 2021;11(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594(7862):259&#x2013;264. doi:10.1038/s41586-021-03553-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-021-03553-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brannock MD, Chew RF, Preiss AJ, et al. Long COVID risk and pre-COVID vaccination in an EHR-based cohort study from the RECOVER program. Nature Commun. 2023;14(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10201472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37217471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Ailshire JA, Crimmins EM, Mitrosz P, Szakiel J, Turek P. Long COVID and symptom trajectory in a representative sample of Americans in the first year of the pandemic. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):1&#x2013;11. doi:10.1038/s41598-021-99269-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-99269-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9264749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35804058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong R, Hall M, Vaddavalli R, et al. Glycemic control and clinical outcomes in U.S. Patients With COVID-19: data From the National COVID Cohort Collaborative (N3C) Database. Diab Care. 2022;45(5):1099. doi:10.2337/dc21-2186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc21-2186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9174972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35202458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassar M, Daoud A, Nso N, et al. Diabetes Mellitus and COVID-19: Review Article. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15(6):102268. doi:10.1016/j.dsx.2021.102268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsx.2021.102268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8416292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34562865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong R, Lam E, Bramante CT, et al. Does COVID-19 Infection Increase the Risk of Diabetes? Curr Evid Curr Diab Rep. 2023;23(8):207&#x2013;216. doi:10.1007/s11892-023-01515-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11892-023-01515-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10244847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37284921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunti K, Prato SD, Mathieu C, Kahn SE, Gabbay RA, Buse JB. COVID-19, Hyperglycemia, and New-Onset Diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2021;44(12):2645&#x2013;2655. doi:10.2337/dc21-1318</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc21-1318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8669536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34625431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizvi AA, Kathuria A, Al Mahmeed W, et al. Post-COVID syndrome, inflammation, and diabetes. J Diabetes Complicat. 2022;36(11):108336. doi:10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2022.108336</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2022.108336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9534783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36228563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xian H, Liu Y, Rundberg Nilsson A, et al. Metformin inhibition of mitochondrial ATP and DNA synthesis abrogates NLRP3 inflammasome activation and pulmonary inflammation. Immunity. 2021;54(7):1463&#x2013;1477.e11. doi:10.1016/j.immuni.2021.05.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2021.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8189765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34115964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parthasarathy H, Tandel D, Siddiqui AH, Harshan KH. Metformin suppresses SARS-CoV-2 in cell culture. Virus Res. 2023;323:199010. doi:10.1016/j.virusres.2022.199010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.virusres.2022.199010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9676078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36417940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ventura-L&#xf3;pez C, Cervantes-Luevano K, Aguirre-S&#xe1;nchez JS, et al. Treatment with metformin glycinate reduces SARS-CoV-2 viral load: an in vitro model and randomized, double-blind, Phase IIb clinical trial. Biomed Pharm. 2022;152:113223. doi:10.1016/j.biopha.2022.113223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2022.113223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9159967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35709650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramante CT, Beckman B. Metformin reduces SARS-CoV-2 in a Phase 3 randomized placebo controlled clinical trial. medRxiv. 2023;2023(06):23290989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramante CT, Buse JB, Liebovitz DM, et al. Outpatient treatment of COVID-19 and incidence of post-COVID-19 condition over 10 months (COVID-OUT): a multicentre, randomised, quadruple-blind, parallel-group, phase 3 trial. Lancet Infect Dis. 2023;23(10):1119&#x2013;1129. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(23)00299-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(23)00299-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11259948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37302406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson SM, Fenno SL, Barzilai N, et al. Metformin for Treatment of Acute COVID-19: Systematic review of clinical trial data against SARS-CoV-2. Diabetes Care. 2023;46(7):1432&#x2013;1442. doi:10.2337/dc22-2539</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc22-2539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10300519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37339345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MCCarthy MW. Metformin as a potential treatment for COVID-19. Expert Opin Pharm. 2023;24(10):1199&#x2013;1203. doi:10.1080/14656566.2023.2215385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14656566.2023.2215385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37194484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramante CT, Johnson SG, Garcia V, et al. Diabetes medications and associations with Covid-19 outcomes in the N3C database: a national retrospective cohort study. PLoS One. 2022;17(11):e0271574. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0271574</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0271574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9671347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36395143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parotto M, Gy&#xf6;ngy&#xf6;si M, Howe K, et al. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19: understanding and addressing the burden of multisystem manifestations. Lancet Respir Med. 2023;11(8):739&#x2013;754. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(23)00239-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(23)00239-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37475125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tandon P, Abrams ND, Avula LR, et al. Unraveling Links between Chronic Inflammation and Long COVID: workshop report. J Immunol. 2024;212(4):505&#x2013;512. doi:10.4049/jimmunol.2300804</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.2300804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38315950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan LE, Casiraghi E, Laraway B, et al. Metformin is associated with reduced COVID-19 severity in patients with prediabetes. Diabet Res Clin Pract. 2022;194:110157. doi:10.1016/j.diabres.2022.110157</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2022.110157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9663381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36400170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haendel MA, Chute CG, Bennett TD, et al. The National COVID Cohort Collaborative (N3C): Rationale, design, infrastructure, and deployment. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2021;28(3):427&#x2013;443. doi:10.1093/jamia/ocaa196</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jamia/ocaa196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32805036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaff ER, Girvin AT, Bennett TD, et al. Identifying who has long COVID in the USA: a machine learning approach using N3C data. Lancet Digit Health. 2022;4(7):e532&#x2013;e541. doi:10.1016/S2589-7500(22)00048-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2589-7500(22)00048-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9110014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35589549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hainmueller J. Entropy balancing for causal effects: A Multivariate reweighting method to produce balanced samples in observational studies. Political Anal. 2012;20(1):25&#x2013;46. doi:10.1093/pan/mpr025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/pan/mpr025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramante CT, Huling JD, Tignanelli CJ, et al. Randomized Trial of Metformin, Ivermectin, and Fluvoxamine for Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2022;387(7):599&#x2013;610. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2201662</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2201662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9945922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36070710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand KMG, Saarelainen L, Sonajalg J, et al. Metformin in pregnancy and risk of adverse long-term outcomes: a register-based cohort study. BMJ Open Diabetes Res Care. 2022;10(1):e002363. doi:10.1136/bmjdrc-2021-002363</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjdrc-2021-002363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8734020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34987051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feig DS, Donovan LE, Zinman B, et al. Metformin in women with type 2 diabetes in pregnancy (MiTy): a multicentre, international, randomised, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2020;8(10):834&#x2013;844. doi:10.1016/S2213-8587(20)30310-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(20)30310-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32946820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soliman A, De Sanctis V, Alaaraj N, Hamed N. The clinical application of metformin in children and adolescents: a short update. Acta Bio Medica. 2020;91(3).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32921782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus; 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley SE, Karlson EW, et al. Development of a definition of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection. JAMA. 2023;329(22):1934&#x2013;1946. doi:10.1001/jama.2023.8823</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2023.8823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10214179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khullar D, Zhang Y, Zang C, et al. Racial/Ethnic Disparities in Post-acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection in New York: an EHR-Based Cohort Study from the RECOVER Program. J Gen Intern Med. 2023;38(5):1127&#x2013;1136. doi:10.1007/s11606-022-07997-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-022-07997-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9933823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36795327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez L, Hart LH, Katz MH. Racial and Ethnic Health Disparities Related to COVID-19. JAMA. 2021;325(8):719&#x2013;720. doi:10.1001/jama.2020.26443</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.26443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33480972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray WA. Evaluating medication effects outside of clinical trials: New-user designs. Am J Epidemiol. 2003;158(9):915&#x2013;920. doi:10.1093/aje/kwg231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aje/kwg231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14585769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshua Lin K, Jin Y, Gagne J, et al. Longitudinal data discontinuity in electronic health records and consequences for medication effectiveness studies. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2022;111(1):243&#x2013;251. doi:10.1002/cpt.2400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpt.2400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8678205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34424534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>