<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37277879</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2047-0525</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Perioperative medicine (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Perioper Med (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pre-assessment and management of long COVID patients requiring elective surgery: challenges and guidance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13741-023-00305-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Whilst most patients infected with COVID-19 make a full recovery, around 1 in 33 patients in the UK report ongoing symptoms post-infection, termed 'long COVID'. Studies have demonstrated that infection with early COVID-19 variants increases postoperative mortality and pulmonary complications for around 7&#xa0;weeks after acute infection. Furthermore, this increased risk persists for those with ongoing symptoms beyond 7&#xa0;weeks. Patients with long COVID may therefore also be at increased postoperative risk, and despite the significant prevalence of long COVID, there are minimal guidelines on how best to assess and manage these patients perioperatively. Long COVID shares several clinical and pathophysiological similarities with conditions such as myalgic encephalitis/chronic fatigue syndrome and postural tachycardia syndrome; however, there are no current guidelines for the preoperative management of these patients to help develop something similar for long COVID patients. Developing guidelines for long COVID patients is further complicated by its heterogenous presentation and pathology. These patients can have persistent abnormalities on pulmonary function tests and echocardiography 3&#xa0;months after acute infection, correlating with a reduced functional capacity. Conversely, some long COVID patients can continue to experience symptoms of dyspnoea and fatigue despite normal pulmonary function tests and echocardiography, yet demonstrating significantly reduced aerobic capacity on cardiopulmonary exercise testing even a year after initial infection. How to comprehensively risk assess these patients is therefore challenging. Existing preoperative guidelines for elective patients with recent COVID-19 generally focus on the timing of surgery and recommendations for pre-assessment if surgery is required before this time interval has elapsed. How long to delay surgery in those with ongoing symptoms and how to manage them perioperatively are less clear. We suggest that multidisciplinary decision-making is required for these patients, using a systems-based approach to guide discussion with specialists and the need for further preoperative investigations. However, without a better understanding of the postoperative risks for long COVID patients, it is difficult to obtain a multidisciplinary consensus and obtain informed patient consent. Prospective studies of long COVID patients undergoing elective surgery are urgently required to help quantify their postoperative risk and develop comprehensive perioperative guidelines for this complex patient group.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boles</LastName><ForeName>Sophie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia and Intensive Care Medicine, Croydon University Hospital, Surrey, UK. sophieboles@nhs.net.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashok</LastName><ForeName>Sundar Raj</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia and Intensive Care Medicine, Croydon University Hospital, Surrey, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016422">Letter</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Perioper Med (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101609072</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2047-0525</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional capacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Guidelines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Perioperative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postoperative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Preoperative</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37277879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10241122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13741-023-00305-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13741-023-00305-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American Society of Anesthesiologists. Anesthesia Patient Safety Foundation . ASA and APSF Joint Statement on Elective Surgery/Procedures and Anesthesia for Patients after COVID-19 Infection. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ariza ME. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: the human herpesviruses are back! Biomolecules. 2021;11(2):185. doi: 10.3390/biom11020185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom11020185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7912523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33572802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Australian and New Zealand College of Anaesthetists . Guideline on surgical patient safety for SARS-CoV-2 infection and vaccination. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossone E, Cademartiri F, AlSergani H, Chianese S, Mehta R, Capone V, et al. Preoperative assessment and management of cardiovascular risk in patients undergoing non-cardiac surgery: implementing a systematic stepwise approach during the COVID-19 pandemic era. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis. 2021;8(10):126. doi: 10.3390/jcdd8100126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcdd8100126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8541645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34677195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortegiani A, Tripodi VF, Castioni CA, Esposito C, Galdieri N, Monzani R, et al. Timing of surgery and elective perioperative management of patients with previous SARS-CoV-2 infection: a SIAARTI expert consensus statement. J Anesth Anal Crit Care. 2022;2(1):29. doi: 10.1186/s44158-022-00058-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s44158-022-00058-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37386538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cort&#xe9;s-Telles A, L&#xf3;pez-Romero S, Figueroa-Hurtado E, Pou-Aguilar YN, Wong AW, Milne KM, et al. Pulmonary function and functional capacity in COVID-19 survivors with persistent dyspnoea. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2021;288:103644. doi: 10.1016/j.resp.2021.103644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resp.2021.103644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7910142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33647535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVIDSurg Collaborative. GlobalSurg Collaborative Timing of surgery following SARS-CoV-2 infection: an international prospective cohort study. Anaesthesia. 2021;76(6):748&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1111/anae.15458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33690889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVIDSurg Collaborative. GlobalSurg Collaborative SARS-CoV-2 infection and venous thromboembolism after surgery: an international prospective cohort study. Anaesthesia. 2022;77(1):28&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1111/anae.15563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8652887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34428858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Boghdadly K, Cook TM, Goodacre T, Kua J, Denmark S, McNally S, et al. Timing of elective surgery and risk assessment after SARS-CoV-2 infection: an update: a multidisciplinary consensus statement on behalf of the Association of Anaesthetists, Centre for Perioperative Care, Federation of Surgical Specialty Associations, Royal College of Anaesthetists, Royal College of Surgeons of England. Anaesthesia. 2022;77(5):580&#x2013;587. doi: 10.1111/anae.15699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9111236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35194788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrandis R, Llau JV, Afshari A, Douketis JD, G&#xf3;mez-Luque A, Samama CM. Management of perioperative thromboprophylaxis for surgery following COVID-19: an expert-panel survey. Br J Anaesth. 2021;127(4):e143&#x2013;e145. doi: 10.1016/j.bja.2021.06.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2021.06.041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8266509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34362558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haffke M, Freitag H, Rudolf G, Seifert M, Doehner W, Scherbakov N, et al. Endothelial dysfunction and altered endothelial biomarkers in patients with post-COVID-19 syndrome and chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) J Transl Med. 2022;20(1):138. doi: 10.1186/s12967-022-03346-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-022-03346-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35317812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsoularis I, Fonseca-Rodr&#xed;guez O, Farrington P, Jerndal H, Lundevaller EH, Sund M, et al. Risks of deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, and bleeding after covid-19: nationwide self-controlled cases series and matched cohort study. BMJ. 2022;377:e069590. doi: 10.1136/bmj-2021-069590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2021-069590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8984137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35387772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;nig RS, Albrich WC, Kahlert CR, Bahr LS, L&#xf6;ber U, Vernazza P, et al. The gut microbiome in myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME)/chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS) Front Immunol. 2021;12:628741. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2021.628741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.628741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8761622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35046929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieberman N, Racine A, Nair S, Semczuk P, Azimaraghi O, Freda J, et al. Should asymptomatic patients testing positive for SARS-CoV-2 wait for elective surgical procedures? Br J Anaesth. 2022;128(5):e311&#x2013;e314. doi: 10.1016/j.bja.2022.02.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2022.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8847097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35277245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Mak JWY, Su Q, Yeoh YK, Lui GCY, Ng SSS, et al. Gut microbiota dynamics in a prospective cohort of patients with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Gut. 2022;71(3):544&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2021-325989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2021-325989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):16144. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malhotra N, Bajwa SJS, Joshi M, Mehdiratta L, Hemantkumar I, Rani RA, et al. Perioperative management of post-COVID-19 surgical patients: Indian Society of Anaesthesiologists (ISA National) Advisory and Position Statement. Indian J Anaesth. 2021;65(7):499&#x2013;507. doi: 10.4103/ija.ija_662_21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ija.ija_662_21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8312391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34321679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence . Myalgic encephalomyelitis (or encephalopathy)/chronic fatigue syndrome: diagnosis and management. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. 2021. Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188/resources/covid19-rapid-guideline-managing-the-longterm-effects-of-covid19-pdf-51035515742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noll J, Reichert M, Dietrich M, Riedel JG, Hecker M, Padberg W, et al. When to operate after SARS-CoV-2 infection? A review on the recent consensus recommendation of the DGC/BDC and the DGAI/BDA. Langenbecks Arch Surg. 2022;407(4):1315&#x2013;1332. doi: 10.1007/s00423-022-02495-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00423-022-02495-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8934603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35307746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office For National Statistics. Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK: 2 February 2023. Estimates of the prevalence of self-reported long COVID and associated activity limitation, using UK Coronavirus (COVID-19) Infection Survey data. 2023. Available from: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/2february2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deveau TM, Munter SE, Ryder D, Buck A, Beck-Engeser G, et al. Chronic viral coinfections differentially affect the likelihood of developing long COVID. J Clin Invest. 2023;133(3):e163669. doi: 10.1172/JCI163669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI163669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9888380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36454631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB, Howe A, Munier CML, Patel SK, et al. Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Immunol. 2022;23(2):210&#x2013;216. doi: 10.1038/s41590-021-01113-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-021-01113-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruzieh M, Dziuba M, Hofmann JP, Grubb BP. Surgical and dental considerations in patients with postural tachycardia syndrome. Auton Neurosci. 2018;215:119&#x2013;120. doi: 10.1016/j.autneu.2018.04.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2018.04.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29678416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherbakov N, Szklarski M, Hartwig J, Sotzny F, Lorenz S, Meyer A, et al. Peripheral endothelial dysfunction in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. ESC Heart Fail. 2020;7(3):1064&#x2013;1071. doi: 10.1002/ehf2.12633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ehf2.12633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7261521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32154656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulthei&#xdf; C, Willscher E, Paschold L, Gottschick C, Klee B, Henkes SS, et al. The IL-1&#x3b2;, IL-6, and TNF cytokine triad is associated with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Cell Rep Med. 2022;3(6):100663. doi: 10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35732153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh I, Joseph P, Heerdt PM, Cullinan M, Lutchmansingh DD, Gulati M, et al. Persistent exertional intolerance after COVID-19: insights from invasive cardiopulmonary exercise testing. Chest. 2022;161(1):54&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1016/j.chest.2021.08.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2021.08.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8354807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34389297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swank Z, Senussi Y, Manickas-Hill Z, Yu XG, Li JZ, Alter G, et al. Persistent circulating severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 spike is associated with post-acute coronavirus disease 2019 sequelae. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;76(3):e487&#x2013;e490. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciac722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciac722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10169416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36052466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tudoran C, Tudoran M, Pop GN, Giurgi-Oncu C, Cut TG, Lazureanu VE, et al. Associations between the severity of the post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and echocardiographic abnormalities in previously healthy outpatients following infection with SARS-CoV-2. Biology (Basel) 2021;10(6):469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8226755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34073342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong DJN, Harris S, Sahni A, Bedford JR, Cortes L, Shawyer R, et al. Developing and validating subjective and objective risk-assessment measures for predicting mortality after major surgery: An international prospective cohort study. PLoS Med. 2020;17(10):e1003253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7561094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33057333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wynter-Blyth V, Moorthy K. Prehabilitation: preparing patients for surgery. BMJ. 2017;358:j3702. doi: 10.1136/bmj.j3702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.j3702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28790033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>