<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34906823</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-5347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>292</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Social science &amp; medicine (1982)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Soc Sci Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The contested meaning of "long COVID" - Patients, doctors, and the politics of subjective evidence.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>114619</StartPage><MedlinePgn>114619</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.socscimed.2021.114619</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0277-9536(21)00951-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In our article, we reconstruct how the patient-made term "long COVID" was able to become a widely accepted concept in public discourses. While the condition was initially invisible to the public eye, we show how the mobilization of subjective evidence online, i.e., the dissemination of reports on the different experiences of lasting symptoms, was able to transform the condition into a crucial feature of the coronavirus pandemic. We explore how stakeholders used the term "long COVID" in online media and in other channels to create their illness and group identity, but also to demarcate the personal experience and experiential knowledge of long COVID from that of other sources. Our exploratory study addresses two questions. Firstly, how the mobilization of subjective evidence leads to the recognition of long COVID and the development of treatment interventions in medicine; and secondly, what distinguishes these developments from other examples of subjective evidence mobilization. We argue that the long COVID movement was able to fill crucial knowledge gaps in the pandemic discourses, making long COVID a legitimate concern of official measures to counter the pandemic. By first showing how illness experiences were gathered that defied official classifications of COVID-19, we show how patients made the "long COVID" term. Then we compare the clinical and social identity of long COVID to that of chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS), before we examine the social and epistemic processes at work in the digital and medial discourses that have transformed how the pandemic is perceived through the lens of long COVID. Building on this, we finally demonstrate how the alignment of medical professionals as patients with the movement has challenged the normative role of clinical evidence, leading to new forms of medical action to tackle the pandemic.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roth</LastName><ForeName>Phillip H</ForeName><Initials>PH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RWTH Aachen University, K&#xe4;te Hamburger Kolleg: Cultures of Research, Theaterstr. 75, 52062, Aachen, Germany. Electronic address: phillip.roth@khk.rwth-aachen.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gadebusch-Bondio</LastName><ForeName>Mariacarla</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Hospital Bonn, Institute for Medical Humanities, Venusberg-Campus 1, 53127, Bonn, Germany. Electronic address: gadebusch.bondio@uni-bonn.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Soc Sci Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8303205</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0277-9536</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011057" MajorTopicYN="N">Politics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic fatigue syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Co-production</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Illness experience</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Social media</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Social movements</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Subjective evidence</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34906823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8629766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2021.114619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0277-9536(21)00951-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Altmann Daniel M., Boyton Rosemary J. Decoding the unknowns in long covid. BMJ. 2021;372:n132. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33541867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan Nisreen A. A negative COVID-19 text does not mean recovery. Nature. 2020;584:170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32782377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan Nisreen A. What exactly is mild covid-19? BMJ Opin. 2020 https://blogs.bmj.com/bmj/2020/07/28/nisreen-a-alwan-what-exactly-is-mild-covid-19/ July 28, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan Nisreen A., Attree Emily, Blair Jennifer Mary, Bogaert Debby, Bowen Mary-Ann, Boyle John, Bradman Madeleine, Briggs Tracy Ann, Burns Sarah, Campion Daniel, Cushing Katherine, Delaney Brendan, Dixon Chirs, Dolman Grace E., Dynan Caitriona, Frayling Ian M., Freeman-Romilly, Hammond Julia, Judge Jenny, J&#xe4;rte Linn, Lokugamage Amali, MacDremott Nathalie, MacKinnon Mairi, Majithia Visita, Northridge Tanya, Powell Laura, Rayner Clare, Read Ginevra, Sahu Ekta, Shand Claudia, Small Amy, Strachan Cara, Suett Jake, Sykes Becky, Taylor Sharon, Thomas Kevin, Thomson Margarita, Wiltshire Alexis, Woods Victoria. From doctors as patients: a manifesto for tackling persisting symptoms of covid-19. BMJ. 2020;370:m3565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32933949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aronowitz Robert A. Cambrdige University Press; Cambridge: 1998. Making sense of illness. Science, Society, and Disease.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson Sarah, Bradby Hannah, Gadebusch-Bondio Mariacarla, Anna Hallberg, Jane Macnaugthon, Ylva S&#xf6;derfeldt. Seeing the value of experiential knowledge through COVID&#x2010;19. History and Philosophy of the Life Sciences. HPLS. 2021;2021(43):85. doi: 10.1007/s40656-021-00438-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40656-021-00438-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8240427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34185187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig Abdul Mannan. Chronic COVID syndrome: need for an appropriate medical terminology for long-COVID and COVID long-haulers. J. Med. Virol. 2020 doi: 10.1002/jmv.26624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33095459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banda Juan M., Gurdas Viguruji Singh S.R., Alser Osaid H., Daniel Prieto-Alhambra. Long-term patient-reported symptoms of COVID-19: an analysis of social media data. medRxiv. 2020 doi: 10.1101/2020.07.29.20164418. Published online.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.07.29.20164418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett Deborah. In: Packard Randall M., Brown Peter J., Berkelman Ruth L., Frumkin Howard., editors. Johns Hopkins University Press; Baltimore/London: 2004. Illness Movements and the Medical Classification of Pain and Fatigue; pp. 139&#x2013;170. (Emerging Illness and Society. Negotiating the Public Health Agenda).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensaude Vincent Bernadette. The politics of buzzwords at the interface of technoscience, market and society: the case of &#x2018;public engagement in science. Publ. Understand. Sci. 2014;23(3):238&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24495899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callard Felicity. Very, very mild: covid-19 symptoms and illness classification. Somatosphere. 2020 http://somatosphere.net/2020/mild-covid.html/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callard Felicity. Epidemic time: thinking from the sickbed. Bull. Hist. Med. 2020;94(4):727&#x2013;743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33775950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callard Felicity, Perego Elisa. How and why patients made Long Covid. Soc. Sci. Med. 2021;268:113426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7539940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33199035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carfi Angelo, Bernabei Roberto, Landi Francesco. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. J. Am. Med. Assoc. 2020;324(6):603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee on the Diagnostic Criteria for Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome . National Academies Press; Washington, D.C.: 2015. Beyond Chronic Encephalomyelitis/Chornic Fatigue Syndrome. Redefining an Illness.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumit Joseph. Illnesses you have to fight to get: facts as forces in uncertain, emergent illnesses. Soc. Sci. Med. 2006;62:577&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16085344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein Steven. University of California Press; Berkley et al: 1996. Impure Science. AIDS, Activism, and the Politics of Knowledge.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11619509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadebusch-Bondio Mariacarla, Hermann Ingo F. In: Ethical Challenges in Cancer Diagnosis and Therapy. Bauer Axel W., Hofheinz Ralf-Dieter, Utikal Jochen S., editors. Springer Nature; Cham: 2021. Cancer and the life beyond it. Patient testimony as a contribution to subjective evidence; pp. 259&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadebusch-Bondio Mariacarla, Marloth Maria. The Realm of Corona Normativities. A Momentary Snapshot of a Dynamic Discourse. Vittorio Klostermann; Frankfurt a.M.: 2020. Clinical trials in pandemic settings. How corona unbinds science; pp. 29&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadebusch-Bondio Mariacarla, M&#xfc;nch Birgit Ulrike. In: In the Realm of Corona Normativities II. The Permanence of the Exception. Gephart Werner, Witte Daniel, Leko Jure., editors. Vittorio Klostermann; Frankfurt a.M.: 2022. Long covid &#x2013; unfortunately not &#x201c;past&#x201d;: mapping (in)visibility perspectives from the medical humantities and art history; pp. 157&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner Paul. Covid-19 and fatigue &#x2013; a game of snakes and ladders. BMJ Opin. 2020 https://blogs.bmj.com/bmj/2020/05/19/paul-garner-covid-19-and-fatigue-a-game-of-snakes-and-ladders/ May 19, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner Paul. On his recovery from long covid. BMJ Opin. Jan. 2021;25:2021. https://blogs.bmj.com/bmj/2021/01/25/paul-garner-on-his-recovery-from-long-covid/?utm_campaign=shareaholic&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_source=socialnetwork</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gieryn Thomas F. University of Chicago Press; Chicago/London: 1999. Cultural Boundaries of Science. Credibility on the Line.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorna Robin, MacDermott Nathalie, Rayner Clare, O'Hara Margaret, Evans Sophie, Agyen Lisa, Nutland Will, Rogers Natalie, Hastie Claire. Long COVID guidelines need to reflect lived experience. Lancet. 2020 doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32705-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32705-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33357467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh Trisha, Knight Matthew, A'Court Christine, Buxton Maria, Husain Laiba. Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020;370:m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jasanoff Sheila. Routledge; London/New York: 2004. States of Knowledge. The Co-production of Science and Social Order.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaldewey David, Schauz D&#xe9;sir&#xe9;e., editors. Basic and Applied Research. The Language of Science Policy in the Twentieth Century. Berghahn; New York/Oxford: 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karfakis Nikos. The biopolitics of CFS/ME. Stud. Hist. Philosophy Biol. Biomed. Sci. 2018;70:20&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29887516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latour Bruno. Why has critique run out of steam? From matters of fact to matters of concern. Crit. Inq. 2004;30(2)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenzen-Schulte, Martina. 2020. &#x201c;Der Lange Schatten von COVID-19.&#x201d; Dtsch. &#xc4;rztebl. 117(49): A2416&#x2013;A2420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LongCovidSOS  . 2020. Home.https://www.longcovidsos.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LongCovidSOS  . 2020. Stories.https://www.longcovidsos.org/stories</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murga &#xcd;&#xf1;igo, Jos&#xe9;-Vincente Lafuente. De la neurastenia a la enfermedad postesfuerzo: evoluci&#xf3;n de los criterios diagn&#xf3;sticos del s&#xed;ndrome de fatiga cr&#xf3;nica/encefalomielitis mi&#xe1;lgica [From neurasthenia to post-exertion disease: evolution of the diagnostic criteria of chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis] Atenci&#xf3;n Primaria. 2019;51(9):579&#x2013;585. doi: 10.1016/j.aprim.2019.04.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aprim.2019.04.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6945124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31182238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packard Randall M., Brown Peter J., Berkelman Ruth L., Frumkin Howard. In: Emerging Illness and Society. Negotiating The Public Health Agenda. Packard Randall M., Brown Peter J., Berkelman Ruth L., Frumkin Howard., editors. Johns Hopkins University Press; Baltimore/Londong: 2004. Emerging Illness as Social Process; pp. 1&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patient-Led Research Collaborative  . 2021. An analysis of the prolonged COVID-19 symptoms survey by patient-led research team.https://patientresearchcovid19.com/research/report-1/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul Bindu D., Lemle Marian D., Komaroff Anthony L., Snyder Solomon H. Redox imbalance links COVID-19 and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2021;118(34) doi: 10.1073/pnas.2024358118. Doi.org/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2024358118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8403932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34400495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perego Elisa, Callard Felicity. SocArXiv; 2021. Patient-made long covid changed COVID-19 (and the production of science, too). Analysis of Patients&#x2019; Epistemic Contributions to a New Illness.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31235/osf.io/n8yp6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perego Elisa, Callard Felicity, Stras Laurie, Melville-J&#xf3;hannesson, Barbara Pope, Rachel Alwan, Nisreen A. Why the patient-made term &#x2018;long covid&#x2019; is needed. Wellcome Open Res. 2020;5:224. https://doir.org/10.12688/wellcomeopenres.16307.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/wellcomeopenres.16307.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen Alan, Schermuly Allegra Clare, Anderson Alison. The shifting politics of patient activism: from bio-sociality to bio-digital citizenship. Health. 2019;23(4):478&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30526091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabeharisoa Vololona, Moreira Tiago, Akrich Madeleine. Evidence-based activism: patients', users' and activists' groups in knowledge society. BioSocieties. 2014;9(2):111&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabinow Paul. Princeton University Press; Princeton: 1996. Essays on the Anthropology of Reason.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajan Selina, Khunti Kamlesh, Alwan Nisreen, Setves Claire, Greenhalgh Trisha, MacDermott Nathalie, Sagan Anna, McKee Martine. World Health Organization; Copenhagen: 2021. In The Wake of the Pandemic. Preparing For Long COVID (Policy Brief 39)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33877759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg Charles E. Cambridge University Press; Cambridge: 1992. Explaining Epidemics and Other Studies in the History of Medicine.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth Phillip H., Bruni Tommaso. Participation, empowerment, and evidence in the current discourse on personalized medicine. A Critique of &#x2018;Democratizing Healthcare&#x2019;. Science, Technology, &amp; Human Values. 2021 doi: 10.1177/01622439211023568. (online first)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/01622439211023568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schermuly Allegra Clare, Petersen Alan, Anderson Alison. I&#x2019;m not an activist!&#x2018;: digital self-advocacy in online patient communities. Crit. Publ. Health. 2021;31(2):204&#x2013;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegleman Jeffrey N. Reflections of a COVID-19 long hauler. J. Am. Med. Assoc. 2020;324(20):2031&#x2013;2032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subbaraman Nidhi. NIH will invest $1 billion to study &#x2018;long COVID. Nature. 2021;591:356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33664445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twitter  . 2020. https://twitter.com/lindsaydemeola/status/1336141154258018305 n.a.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twitter  . 2020. https://twitter.com/Gronnet/status/1340559538555146242 n.a.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO)   2015. World Health Organization Best Practices for the Naming of New Human Infectious Diseases.https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/163636/WHO_HSE_FOS_15.1_eng.pdf New York.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO)   2020. Coronavirus.https://www.who.int/health-topics/coronavirus#tab=tab_1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO)   2021. Global COVID-19 clinical platform case report from (CRF) for post COVID condition (post COVID-19 CRF)https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/global-covid-19-clinical-platform-case-report-form-(crf)-for-post-covid-conditions-(post-covid-19-crf-)</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>