<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34611512</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2213-4220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>Suppl</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Integrative medicine research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Integr Med Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Honeybee products for the treatment and recovery from viral respiratory infections including SARS-COV-2: A rapid systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100779</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100779</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100779</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.imr.2021.100779</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This rapid review systematically evaluated the effects of honeybee products compared to controls for the prevention, duration, severity, and recovery of acute viral respiratory tract infections (RTIs), including SARS-CoV-2, in adults and children.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Cochrane rapid review methods were applied. Four English databases plus preprint servers and trial registries were searched for randomized controlled trials (RCTs). The evidence was appraised and synthesized using RoB 2.0 and GRADE.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">27 results were derived from 9&#xa0;RCTs that included 674 adults and 781 children. In hospitalized adults with SARS-CoV-2, propolis plus usual-care compared to usual-care alone reduced the risk of shock, respiratory failure and kidney injury and duration of hospital admission. Honey was less effective than Guaifenesin for&#xa0;reducing cough severity at 60-minutes in adults with non-specific acute viral RTIs. Compared to coffee, honey plus coffee, and honey alone reduced the severity of post-infectious cough in adults. Honey reduced the duration of cough in children compared to placebo and salbutamol; and the global impact&#xa0;of nocturnal cough after one night compared to usual-care alone and pharmaceutical cough medicines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">More studies are needed to robustly assess honeybee's role in SARS-CoV-2 and non-specific viral respiratory infections.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PROTOCOL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">PROSPERO: CRD42020193847.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Korea Institute of Oriental Medicine. Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arentz</LastName><ForeName>Susan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NICM Health Research Institute, Western Sydney University, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hunter</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NICM Health Research Institute, Western Sydney University, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khamba</LastName><ForeName>Baljit</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bastyr University, San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mravunac</LastName><ForeName>Michelle</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Torrens University, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Zemirah</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bastyr University, San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alexander</LastName><ForeName>Kristen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bastyr University, San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lauche</LastName><ForeName>Romy</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Naturopathic Medicine, Faculty of Health, Southern Cross University, Lismore, NSW Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldenberg</LastName><ForeName>Joshua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Helfgott Research Institute, National University of Natural Medicine, Portland, OR &amp; Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Myers</LastName><ForeName>Stephen P</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NICM Health Research Institute, Western Sydney University, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Naturopathic Medicine, Faculty of Health, Southern Cross University, Lismore, NSW Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Integr Med Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101612707</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-4220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Complementary medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus pandemic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TCIM</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest. SA and JH are editorial board members of this journal but had no role in the editorial process or decision of this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8483994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.imr.2021.100779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-4220(21)00066-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Steel A, Wardle J, Lloyd I. The potential contribution of traditional, complementary and integrative treatments in acute viral respiratory tract infections: Rapid Reviews in response to the COVID-19 pandemic. Adv Integr Med. 2020;7(4):181&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33520646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornara L, Biagi M, Xiao J, Burlando B. Therapeutic properties of bioactive compounds from different honeybee products. Front Pharmacol. 2017;8:412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5487425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28701955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Naggar Y, Giesy JP, Abdel-Daim MM, Javed Ansari M, Al-Kahtani SN, Yahya G. Fighting against the second wave of COVID-19: can honeybee products help protect against the pandemic? Saudi J Biol Sci. 2021;28(3):1519&#x2013;1527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33519274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hatamleh MAI, Hatmal MM, Sattar K, Ahmad S, Mustafa MZ, Bittencourt MC. Antiviral and immunomodulatory effects of phytochemicals from honey against COVID-19: potential mechanisms of action and future directions. Molecules. 2020;25(21)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7672575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33138197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima WG, Brito JCM, da Cruz, Nizer WS. Bee products as a source of promising therapeutic and chemoprophylaxis strategies against COVID-19 (SARS-CoV-2) Phytother Res. 2021;35(2):743&#x2013;750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32945590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain KS, Hossain MG, Moni A, Rahman MM, Rahman UH, Alam M. Prospects of honey in fighting against COVID-19: pharmacological insights and therapeutic promises. Heliyon. 2020;6(12):e05798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7750705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33363261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berretta AA, Silveira MAD, C&#xf3;ndor Capcha JM, De Jong D. Propolis and its potential against SARS-CoV-2 infection mechanisms and COVID-19 disease: running title: Propolis against SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19. Biomed Pharmacother. 2020;131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7430291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32890967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasupuleti VR, Sammugam L, Ramesh N, Gan SH. Honey, propolis, and royal jelly: a comprehensive review of their biological actions and health benefits. Oxidative Med Cellular Longevity. 2017:2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5549483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28814983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abuelgasim H, Albury C, Lee J. Effectiveness of honey for symptomatic relief in upper respiratory tract infections: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Evid-Based Med. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32817011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oduwole O, Udoh EE, Oyo-Ita A, Meremikwu MM. Honey for acute cough in children. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2018;(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6513626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29633783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC. Common Cold: How to Feel Better, &#x2329;https://www.cdc.gov/antibiotic-use/community/for-patients/common-illnesses/colds.html&#x232a;; Published 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE. Cough (acute): antimicrobial prescribing, &#x2329;https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng120/resources/visual-summary-pdf-6664861405&#x232a;; Published 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RACGP. The Handbook of Non-Drug interventions (HANDI): Honey and cough in children with URTI, &#x2329;https://www.racgp.org.au/clinical-resources/clinical-guidelines/handi/conditions/children/honey-and-cough-in-children-with-urti&#x232a;; Published 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garritty C, Gartlehner G, Nussbaumer-Streit B, King VJ, Hamel C, Kamel C. Cochrane rapid reviews methods group offers evidence-informed guidance to conduct rapid reviews. J Clin Epidemiol. 2020;130:13&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7557165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33068715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021:372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arentz S, Hunter J, Goldenberg J, Yang G, Beardsley J.  PROSPERO 2020 CRD42020182044. 2020. Protocol for a rapid review of zinc for the prevention or treatment of COVID-19 and other coronavirusrelated respiratory tract infections in humans. &lt; www.crd.york.ac.uk/prospero/display_record.php?ID=CRD42020182044&gt; Published.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter J, Arentz S, Goldenberg J, Yang G, Beardsley J, Lee MS. Choose your shortcuts wisely: COVID-19 rapid reviews of traditional, complementary and integrative medicine. Integrat Med Res. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7388820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32837904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu R, Zhao C, Liang T, Hao X, Huang Y, Zhang X. Core outcome set for clinical trials of COVID-19 based on traditional Chinese and western medicine. medRxiv. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7265660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32574235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall JC, Murthy S, Diaz J, Adhikari N, Angus DC, Arabi YM. A minimal common outcome measure set for COVID-19 clinical research. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20(8):e192. -e97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7292605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32539990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covidence systematic review software, &#x2329;www.covidence.org&#x232a;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019:366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT TJ, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ WV. John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2019. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Review Manager (RevMan). 5.3 ed. Copenhagen: The Nordic Cochrane Centre, The Cochrane Collaboration; 2014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handbook for grading the quality of evidence and the strength of recommendations using the GRADE approach: The GRADE Working Group; 2013. Available from: https://gradepro.org/cite/guidelinedevelopment.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayazi P. Comparison of the effect of two kinds of Iranian honey and diphenhydramine on nocturnal cough and sleep quality in coughing children and their parents. 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5245888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28103276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peixoto DM, Rizzo JA, Schor D, Silva AR, DCd Oliveira, Sol&#xe9; D. Use of honey associated with Ananas comosus (Bromelin) in the treatment of acute irritative cough. Revista Paulista de Pediatria. 2016;34(4):412&#x2013;417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5176060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27181342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences: Academic press; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Sutton AJ, Ioannidis JP, Terrin N, Jones DR, Lau J. Recommendations for examining and interpreting funnel plot asymmetry in meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d4002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21784880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silveira MAD, De Jong D, Berretta AA, dos Santos Galv&#xe3;o EB, Ribeiro JC, Cerqueira-Silva T. Efficacy of Brazilian green propolis (EPP-AF&#xae;) as an adjunct treatment for hospitalized COVID-19 patients: A randomized, controlled clinical trial. Biomed Pharmacother. 2021;138</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7980186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34311528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayazi P, Mahyar A, Yousef-Zanjani M, Allami A, Esmailzadehha N, Beyhaghi T. Comparison of the effect of two kinds of Iranian honey and diphenhydramine on nocturnal cough and the sleep quality in coughing children and their parents. PLoS One. 2017;12(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5245888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28103276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen HA, Rozen J, Kristal H, Laks Y, Berkovitch M, Uziel Y. Effect of honey on nocturnal cough and sleep quality: a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled study. Pediatrics. 2012;130(3):465&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22869830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul IM, Beiler J, McMonagle A, Shaffer ML, Duda L, Berlin CM. Effect of honey, dextromethorphan, and no treatment on nocturnal cough and sleep quality for coughing children and their parents. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2007;161(12):1140&#x2013;1146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18056558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadkam MN, Mozaffari-Khosravi H, Mozayan MR. A comparison of the effect of honey, dextromethorphan, and diphenhydramine on nightly cough and sleep quality in children and their parents. J Alternat Complement Med. 2010;16(7):787&#x2013;793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20618098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waris A, Macharia W, Njeru E, Essajee F. Randomised Double Blind study to compare effectiveness of honey, salbutamol and placebo in treatment of cough in children with common cold. East Afr Med J. 2014;91(2):50&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26859020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raeessi M-A, Aslani J, Gharaie H, Karimi Z, Raeessi N, Assari S. Honey with Coffee: A new finding in the treatment of Persistent Postinfectious Cough. 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanda MS, Mittal SP, Gupta V. Role of honey as adjuvant therapy in patients with sore throat. Nat J Physiol, Pharmacy Pharmacol. 2017;7(4):412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyeth_Pharmaceuticals Pty Ltd. Study of Count Coughs in Subjects With Acute Upper Respiratory Tract Infections NCT01062256, &#x2329;https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/results/NCT01062256?view=results&#x232a;; Published 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamidi GA. The effect of honey on duration of pediatric pneumonia, &#x2329;https://www.irct.ir/trial/11474&#x232a;; Published 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobahar M. Effect of Propolis mouthwash on incidence of Ventilator-Associated Pneumonia in hospitalized patient in critical care unit, &#x2329;https://en.irct.ir/trial/37046&#x232a;; Published 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tantawy M. Efficacy of Natural Honey Treatment in Patients With Novel Coronavirus, &#x2329;https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04323345&#x232a;; Published 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silveira MAD, Teles F, Berretta AA, Sanches TR, Rodrigues CE, Seguro AC. Effects of Brazilian green propolis on proteinuria and renal function in patients with chronic kidney disease: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. BMC Nephrol. 2019;20(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6485062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31023272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleimani D, Rezaie M, Rajabzadeh F, Gholizadeh Navashenaq J, Abbaspour M, Miryan M. Protective effects of propolis on hepatic steatosis and fibrosis among patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) evaluated by real-time two-dimensional shear wave elastography: A randomized clinical trial. Phytother Res. 2021;35(3):1669&#x2013;1679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta S, Coca SG, Chan L, Melamed ML, Brenner SK, Hayek SS. AKI treated with renal replacement therapy in critically ill patients with COVID-19. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;32(1):161&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7894677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33067383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takdehghan G, Dorchin M, Amin M, Ghorbanzadeh B, Assarian AR, Amirgholami N, et&#xa0;al. Efficacy of date palm (Phoenix Dactylifera L.) leaf extract in COVID-19 infection: a randomized double-blind clinical trial. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarrell EM, Wielunsky E, Cohen HA. Antipyretic treatment in young children with fever: acetaminophen, ibuprofen, or both alternating in a randomized, double-blind study. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2006;160(2):197&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16461878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen HA, Hoshen M, Gur S, Bahir A, Laks Y, Blau H. Efficacy and tolerability of a polysaccharide-resin-honey based cough syrup as compared to carbocysteine syrup for children with colds: a randomized, single-blinded, multicenter study. World J Pediatr. 2017;13(1):27&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27457790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen HA, Varsano I, Kahan E, Sarrell EM, Uziel Y. Effectiveness of an herbal preparation containing echinacea, propolis, and vitamin C in preventing respiratory tract infections in children: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter study. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2004;158(3):217&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14993078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sopo SM, Greco M, Monaco S, Varrasi G, Di Lorenzo G, Simeone G. Effect of multiple honey doses on non-specific acute cough in children. An open randomised study and literature review. Allergol Immunopathol (Madr) 2015;43(5):449&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25201759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashraf S, Ashraf S, Imran MA, Ashraf M, Kalsoom L, Siddiqui UN, et&#xa0;al. Efficacy of honey and Nigella sativa against COVID-19: HNS-COVID-PK Trial. medRxiv 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsh EJ, Bara A, Barley E, Cates CJ. Caffeine for asthma. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2010;(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7053252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20091514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi M, Moosavi S, Zakeri S. Comparison of the effect of honey and diphenhydramine on cough alleviation in 2-5-year-old children with viral upper respiratory tract infection. J Gorgan Univ Med Sci. 2013;15(2)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohkuma A, Kanno T, Asama T, Doi-Takaki S, Kawaguchi M, Tatefuji T. Effect of dietary supplement containing brazilian propolis on the common cold. Pharmacometrics. 2010;79(3-4):43&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>