<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38646658</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2471-2531</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pain reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pain Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigating the fluctuating nature of post-COVID pain symptoms in previously hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: the LONG-COVID-EXP multicenter study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e1153</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e1153</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e1153</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PR9.0000000000001153</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This cohort study used Sankey plots and exponential bar plots for visualizing the fluctuating nature and trajectory of post-COVID pain in previously hospitalized COVID-19 survivors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A cohort of 1266 subjects hospitalised because of COVID-19 during the first wave of the pandemic were scheduled for a telephone interview at 8.4 (T1), 13.2 (T2), and 18.3 (T3) months in average after hospitalization for collecting data about post-COVID pain. Patients were asked for about pain symptomatology that was attributed to the infection. Hospitalization and clinical data were collected from medical records.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The prevalence of myalgia as COVID-19-associated symptom was 29.82% (n = 389) at hospitalization (T0). The prevalence of post-COVID pain was 41.07% (n = 520) at T1, 34.29% (n = 434) at T2, and 28.47% (n = 360) at T3. The recovery exponential curve revealed a decrease trend visualizing that post-COVID pain improved over the time span investigated. Pain in the lower extremity and widespread pain were the most prevalent locations. Female sex (OR 1.507, 95% CI 1.047-2.169), pre-existing pain symptoms (OR 1.724, 95% CI 1.237-2.403), headache as onset-symptom (OR 2.374, 95% CI 1.550-3.639), days at hospital (OR 1.012, 95% CI 1.000-1.025), and presence of post-COVID pain at T1 (OR 13.243, 95% CI 9.428-18.601) were associated with post-COVID pain at T2. Only the presence of post-COVID pain at T1 (OR 5.383, 95% CI 3.896-7.439) was associated with post-COVID pain at T3.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Current results show a fluctuating evolution with a decreasing tendency of post-COVID pain during the first years after hospitalization. The development of post-COVID pain soon after SARS-CoV-2 infection predispose for long-lasting chronic pain.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of The International Association for the Study of Pain.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as</LastName><ForeName>C&#xe9;sar</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3772-9690</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Occupational Therapy, Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Universidad Rey Juan Carlos (URJC), Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Neuroplasticity and Pain (CNAP), SMI, Department of Health Science and Technology, Faculty of Medicine, Aalborg University, Aalborg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pellicer-Valero</LastName><ForeName>Oscar J</ForeName><Initials>OJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Image Processing Laboratory (IPL), Universitat de Val&#xe8;ncia, Parc Cient&#xed;fic, Paterna, Val&#xe8;ncia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9; D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Intelligent Data Analysis Laboratory, Department of Electronic Engineering, ETSE (Engineering School), Universitat de Val&#xe8;ncia (UV), Burjassot, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Valencian Graduate School and Research Network of Artificial Intelligence (ValgrAI), Val&#xe8;ncia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Barrera</LastName><ForeName>Valent&#xed;n</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Universidad Rey Juan Carlos (URJC), Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arendt-Nielsen</LastName><ForeName>Lars</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Neuroplasticity and Pain (CNAP), SMI, Department of Health Science and Technology, Faculty of Medicine, Aalborg University, Aalborg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology, Mech-Sense, Clinical Institute, Aalborg University Hospital, Aalborg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center North Denmark, Clinical Institute, Aalborg University Hospital, Aalborg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pain Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101683899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2471-2531</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Musculoskeletal pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk factors</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflict of interest to declare.Sponsorships or competing interests that may be relevant to content are disclosed at the end of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38646658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11029971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PR9.0000000000001153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PAINREPORTS-D-23-0123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bileviciute-Ljungar I, Norrefalk JR, Borg K. Pain burden in post-COVID-19 syndrome following mild COVID-19 infection. J Clin Med 2022;11:771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8836662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35160223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis 2022;226:1593&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C. Are patients exhibiting post-Coronavirus Disease (COVID) symptoms at 12 months the same at 5 or 9 months? The fluctuating nature of Post-COVID. Clin Infect Dis 2022;75:e1208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9383161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34989807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C. Long COVID: current definition. Infection 2022;50:285&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8438555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34519974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Cancela-Cilleruelo I, Moro-L&#xf3;pez-Menchero P, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Pellicer-Valero OJ, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Arendt-Nielsen L. Exploring the trajectory curve of long-term musculoskeletal post-COVID pain symptoms in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: a multicenter study. PAIN 2023;164:413&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35930390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, de-la-Llave-Rinc&#xf3;n AI, Ortega-Santiago R, Ambite-Quesada S, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Arias-Naval&#xf3;n JA, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Barrera V, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Pellicer-Valero OJ, Arendt-Nielsen L. Prevalence and risk factors of musculoskeletal pain symptoms as long-term post-COVID sequelae in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: a multicenter study. PAIN 2022;163:e989&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34913880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Florencio LL, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, Raveendran AV. Proposed integrative model for post-COVID symptoms. Diabetes Metab Syndr 2021;15:102159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8168334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34186367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, Plaza-Manzano G, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, Arendt-Nielsen L. Time course prevalence of post-COVID pain symptoms of musculoskeletal origin in patients who had survived severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PAIN 2022;163:1220&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34561390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Nijs J, Giordano R, Arendt-Nielsen L. Precision management of post-COVID pain: an evidence and clinical-based approach. Eur J Pain 2023;27:1107&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36852606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Nijs J, Neblett R, Polli A, Moens M, Goudman L, Shekhar Patil M, Knaggs RD, Pickering G, Arendt-Nielsen L. Phenotyping post-COVID pain as a nociceptive, neuropathic, or nociplastic pain condition. Biomedicines 2022;10:2562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9599440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36289827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Florencio LL, Cuadrado ML, Plaza-Manzano G, Navarro-Santana M. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Intern Med 2021;92:55&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34167876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Burden of Disease Long COVID Collaborators, Wulf Hanson S, Abbafati C, Aerts JG, Al-Aly Z, Ashbaugh C, Ballouz T, Blyuss O, Bobkova P, Bonsel G, Borzakova S, Buonsenso D, Butnaru D, Carter A, Chu H, De Rose C, Diab MM, Ekbom E, El Tantawi M, Fomin V, Frithiof R, Gamirova A, Glybochko PV, Haagsma JA, Haghjooy Javanmard S, Hamilton EB, Harris G, Heijenbrok-Kal MH, Helbok R, Hellemons ME, Hillus D, Huijts SM, Hultstr&#xf6;m M, Jassat W, Kurth F, Larsson IM, Lipcsey M, Liu C, Loflin CD, Malinovschi A, Mao W, Mazankova L, McCulloch D, Menges D, Mohammadifard N, Munblit D, Nekliudov NA, Ogbuoji O, Osmanov IM, Pe&#xf1;alvo JL, Petersen MS, Puhan MA, Rahman M, Rass V, Reinig N, Ribbers GM, Ricchiuto A, Rubertsson S, Samitova E, Sarrafzadegan N, Shikhaleva A, Simpson KE, Sinatti D, Soriano JB, Spiridonova E, Steinbeis F, Svistunov AA, Valentini P, van de Water BJ, van den Berg-Emons R, Wallin E, Witzenrath M, Wu Y, Xu H, Zoller T, Adolph C, Albright J, Amlag JO, Aravkin AY, Bang-Jensen BL, Bisignano C, Castellano R, Castro E, Chakrabarti S, Collins JK, Dai X, Daoud F, Dapper C, Deen A, Duncan BB, Erickson M, Ewald SB, Ferrari AJ, Flaxman AD, Fullman N, Gamkrelidze A, Giles JR, Guo G, Hay SI, He J, Helak M, Hulland EN, Kereselidze M, Krohn KJ, Lazzar-Atwood A, Lindstrom A, Lozano R, Malta DC, M&#xe5;nsson J, Mantilla Herrera AM, Mokdad AH, Monasta L, Nomura S, Pasovic M, Pigott DM, Reiner RC, Jr, Reinke G, Ribeiro ALP, Santomauro DF, Sholokhov A, Spurlock EE, Walcott R, Walker A, Wiysonge CS, Zheng P, Bettger JP, Murray CJL, Vos T. Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA 2022;328:1604&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q, Zheng B, Daines L, Sheikh A. Long-Term Sequelae of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of one-year follow-up studies on post-COVID symptoms. Pathogens 2022;11:269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8875269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35215212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes LD, Ingram J, Sculthorpe NF. More than 100 persistent symptoms of SARS-CoV-2 (long COVID): a scoping review. Front Med 2021;8:750378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8591053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34790680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerzhner O, Berla E, Har-Even M, Ratmansky M, Goor-Aryeh I. Consistency of inconsistency in long-COVID-19 pain symptoms persistency: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pain Pract 2024;24:120&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37475709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korompoki E, Gavriatopoulou M, Hicklen RS, Ntanasis-Stathopoulos I, Kastritis E, Fotiou D, Stamatelopoulos K, Terpos E, Kotanidou A, Hagberg CA, Dimopoulos MA, Kontoyiannis DP. Epidemiology and organ specific sequelae of post-acute COVID19: a narrative review. J Infect 2021;83:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8118709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33992686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubota GT, Soares FHC, da Fonseca AS, Rosa TDS, da Silva VA, Gouveia GR, Faria VG, da Cunha PHM, Brunoni AR, Teixeira MJ, de Andrade DC. Pain paths among post-COVID-19 condition subjects: a prospective cross-sectional study with in-person evaluation. Eur J Pain 2023;27:636&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36799447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JXL, Wang X, Henry A, Anderson CS, Hammond N, Harris K, Liu H, Loffler K, Myburgh J, Pandian J, Smyth B, Venkatesh B, Carcel C, Woodward M. Sex differences in pain expressed by patients across diverse disease states: individual patient data meta-analysis of 33,957 participants in 10 randomized controlled trials. PAIN 2023;164:1666&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36972472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu ST, Lin SC, Chang JP, Yang KJ, Chu CS, Yang CC, Liang CS, Sun CF, Wang SC, Satyanarayanan SK, Su KP. The clinical observation of inflammation theory for depression: the Initiative of the Formosa Long COVID Multicenter Study (FOCuS). Clin Psychopharmacol Neurosci 2023;21:10&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9889898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36700308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Lav&#xed;n M, Miguel-&#xc1;lvarez A. Hypothetical framework for post-COVID 19 condition based on a fibromyalgia pathogenetic model. Clin Rheumatol 2023;42:3167&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37707639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills SEE, Nicolson KP, Smith BH. Chronic pain: a review of its epidemiology and associated factors in population-based studies. Br J Anaesth 2019;123:e273&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6676152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31079836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Numan SM. Musculoskeletal symptoms and its associated factors among post-COVID- 19 patients attended in a rehabilitation centre. Int J Med Sci Clin Invention 2021;8:5251&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oguz-Akarsu E, Gullu G, Kilic E, Din&#xe7; Y, Ursavas A, Yilmaz E, Zarifoglu M, Karli N, Pandemic Study Team. Insight into pain syndromes in acute phase of mild-to-moderate COVID-19: frequency, clinical characteristics, and associated factors. Eur J Pain 2022;26:492&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8653127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34622527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otto E, Culakova E, Meng S, Zhang Z, Xu H, Mohile S, Flannery MA. Overview of Sankey flow diagrams: focusing on symptom trajectories in older adults with advanced cancer. J Geriatr Oncol 2022;13:742&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9232856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35000890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrot S, Cohen M, Barke A, Korwisi B, Rief W, Treede RD, IASP Taskforce for the Classification of Chronic Pain. The IASP classification of chronic pain for ICD-11: chronic secondary musculoskeletal pain. PAIN 2019;160:77&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30586074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmati M, Udeh R, Yon DK, Lee SW, Dolja-Gore X, McEVoy M, Kenna T, Jacob L, L&#xf3;pez S&#xe1;nchez GF, Koyanagi A, Shin JI, Smith L. A systematic review and meta-analysis of long-term sequelae of COVID-19 2-year after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a call to action for neurological, physical, and psychological sciences. J Med Virol 2023;95:e28852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37288652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubio-Rivas M, Corbella X, Mora-Luj&#xe1;n JM, Loureiro-Amigo J, L&#xf3;pez Sampalo A, Yera Bergua C, Esteve Ati&#xe9;nzar PJ, D&#xed;ez Garc&#xed;a LF, Gonzalez Ferrer R, Plaza Canteli S, P&#xe9;rez Pi&#xf1;eiro A, Cort&#xe9;s Rodr&#xed;guez B, Jorquer Vidal L, P&#xe9;rez Catal&#xe1;n I, Le&#xf3;n T&#xe9;llez M, Mart&#xed;n Oterino J&#xc1;, Mart&#xed;n Gonz&#xe1;lez MC, Serrano Carrillo de Albornoz JL, Garc&#xed;a Sardon E, Alcal&#xe1; Pedrajas JN, Martin-Urda Diez-Canseco A, Esteban Giner MJ, Teller&#xed;a G&#xf3;mez P, Ramos-Rinc&#xf3;n JM, G&#xf3;mez-Huelgas R. Predicting clinical outcome with phenotypic clusters in COVID-19 pneumonia: an analysis of 12,066 hospitalized patients from the Spanish registry SEMI-COVID-19. J Clin Med 2020;9:3488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7693215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33137919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;ahin T, Ayyildiz A, Gencer-Atalay K, Akg&#xfc;n C, &#xd6;zdemir HM, Kuran B. Pain symptoms in COVID-19. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 2021;100:307&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33480608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders C, Sperling S, Bendstrup E. A new paradigm is needed to explain long COVID. Lancet Respir Med 2023;11:e12&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36620963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares FHC, Kubota GT, Fernandes AM, Hojo B, Couras C, Costa BV, Lapa JDDS, Braga LM, Almeida MM, Cunha PHMD, Pereira VHH, Morais ADS, Teixeira MJ, Ciampi de Andrade D, &#x201c;Pain in the Pandemic Initiative Collaborators&#x201d;. Prevalence and characteristics of new-onset pain in COVID-19 survivours, a controlled study. Eur J Pain 2021;25:1342&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33619793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV, WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis 2022;22:e102&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struyf T, Deeks JJ, Dinnes J, Takwoingi Y, Davenport C, Leeflang MM, Spijker R, Hooft L, Emperador D, Dittrich S, Domen J, Horn SRA, Van den Bruel A, Cochrane COVID-19 Diagnostic Test Accuracy Group. Signs and symptoms to determine if a patient presenting in primary care or hospital outpatient settings has COVID-19 disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2020;7:CD013665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7386785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32633856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampasian V, Elghazaly H, Chattopadhyay R, Debski M, Naing TKP, Garg P, Clark A, Ntatsaki E, Vassiliou VS. Risk factors associated with post-COVID-19 condition: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Intern Med 2023;183:566&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10037203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ursini F, Ciaffi J, Mancarella L, Lisi L, Brusi V, Cavallari C, D'Onghia M, Mari A, Borlandelli E, Faranda Cordella J, La Regina M, Viola P, Ruscitti P, Miceli M, De Giorgio R, Baldini N, Borghi C, Gasbarrini A, Iagnocco A, Giacomelli R, Faldini C, Landini MP, Meliconi R. Fibromyalgia: a new facet of the post-COVID-19 syndrome spectrum? Results from a web-based survey. RMD Open 2021;7:e001735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8384499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34426540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin D, Margalit I, Nehme M, Bordas-Mart&#xed;nez J, Pistelli F, Yahav D, Guessous I, Dur&#xe0;-Miralles X, Carrozzi L, Shapira-Lichter I, Vetter P, Peleato-Catalan D, Tiseo G, Wirtheim E, Kaiser L, Gudiol C, Falcone M, Leibovici L, On Behalf of the LongCOV Research Group. Patterns of long COVID symptoms: a multi-center cross sectional study. J Clin Med 2022;11:898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8875229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35207171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zis P, Ioannou C, Artemiadis A, Christodoulou K, Kalampokini S, Hadjigeorgiou GM. Prevalence and determinants of chronic pain Post-COVID; cross-sectional study. J Clin Med 2022;11:5569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9573502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36233443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>