<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36861893</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>201</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British journal of haematology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Haematol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mortality and burden of post-COVID-19 syndrome have reduced with time across SARS-CoV-2 variants in haematology patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>640</StartPage><EndPage>644</EndPage><MedlinePgn>640-644</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/bjh.18700</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Haematology patients contracting SARS-CoV-2 were identified at the start of the pandemic to be at higher risk of death or of persistent symptoms (post-COVID-19 syndrome). As variants with altered pathogenicity have emerged, uncertainty remains around how that risk has changed. We prospectively set up a dedicated post-COVID-19 clinic to monitor haematology patients infected with COVID-19 from the start of the pandemic. In total, 128 patients were identified and telephone interviews were conducted with 94 of 95 survivors. Ninety-day mortality attributed to COVID-19 has fallen sequentially from 42% for the Original and Alpha strains to 9% and to 2% for the Delta and Omicron variants respectively. Furthermore, the risk of post-COVID-19 syndrome in survivors has fallen from 46% for the Original or Alpha strains to 35% for Delta and 14% for the Omicron strain. Since vaccine uptake has been nearly universal in haematology patients, it is not possible to determine whether improved outcomes reflect the reduced pathogenicity of the virus, or widespread vaccine deployment. Whilst mortality and morbidity remain higher in haematology patients than in the general population, our data suggest that the absolute risks are now significantly lower. Given this trend, we believe clinicians should initiate conversations about risk with their patients on whether to maintain any self-imposed social isolation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. British Journal of Haematology published by British Society for Haematology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willan</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8700-2073</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Haematology, Frimley Health NHS Foundation Trust, Slough, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Haematology, Oxford University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agarwal</LastName><ForeName>Gaurav</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Sciences Division, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bienz</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Haematology, Frimley Health NHS Foundation Trust, Slough, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Haematol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0372544</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0007-1048</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000711908">SARS-CoV-2 variants</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006405" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hematology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Omicron</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">haematological malignancy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36861893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjh.18700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Wood WA, Neuberg DS, Thompson JC, Tallman MS, Sekeres MA, Sehn LH, et al. Outcomes of patients with hematologic malignancies and COVID-19: a report from the ASH research collaborative data hub. Blood Advances. 2020;4:5966-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willan J, Hernandez L, Katz H, Gray N, Bienz N. Post-COVID-19 syndrome in patients with haematological disorders who have survived infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2. Br J Haematol. 2022;197:e19-23. https://doi.org/10.1111/bjh.18010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyberg T, Ferguson NM, Nash SG, Webster HH, Flaxman S, Andrews N, et al. Comparative analysis of the risks of hospitalisation and death associated with SARS-CoV-2 omicron (B.1.1.529) and delta (B.1.617.2) variants in England: a cohort study. Lancet. 2022;399:1303-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhawan A, Vimalesvaran S. Hunting down the cause of acute hepatitis in children. Lancet. 2022;399:2264. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(22)00946-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niemann C, Cunha-Bang C, Helleberg M, Ostrowski S, Brieghel C. Patients with CLL have a lower risk of death from COVID-19 in the Omicron era. Blood. 2022;140:445-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blennow O, Salmanton-Garc&#xed;a J, Nowak P, Itri F, van Doesum J, L&#xf3;pez-Garc&#xed;a A, et al. Outcome of infection with omicron SARS-CoV-2 variant in patients with hematological malignancies: an EPICOVIDEHA survey report. Am J Hematol. 2022;97:E312-7. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajh.26626</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taenaka R, Obara T, Kohno K, Aoki K, Ogawa R. Infections with the SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variant show a similar outcome as infections with the previous variants in patients with hematologic malignancies. Ann Hematol. 2022;101:1877-8. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00277-022-04833-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathieu E, Ritchie H, Rod&#xe9;s-Guirao L, Appel C, Gavrilov D, Giattino C, et al. Coronavirus Pandemic (COVID-19). Published online at OurWorldInData.org. Retrieved from: https://ourworldindata.org/coronavirus. Accessed on 12th December 2022. [Online Resource].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabrera G, Allen H, Zaidi A, Flannagan J, Twohig K, Thelwall S, et al. Assessment of mortality and hospital admissions associated with confirmed infection with SARS-CoV-2 alpha variant: a matched cohort and time-to-event analysis, England, October to December 2020. Eurosurveillance. 2022;27:2100377. https://doi.org/10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2022.27.20.2100377</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cattaneo C, Masina L, Pagani C, Cancelli V, Daffini R, Tucci A, et al. High mortality in fully vaccinated hematologic patients treated with anti-CD20 antibodies during the &#x201c;Omicron wave&#x201d; of COVID-19 pandemic. Hematol Oncol. 2022;41:205-7. https://doi.org/10.1002/hon.3064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullrich F, Hanoun C, Turki AT, Liebregts T, Breuckmann K, Alashkar F, et al. Early report on the severity of COVID-19 in hematologic patients infected with the SARS-CoV2 omicron variant. Eur J Haematol. 2022;109:364-72. https://doi.org/10.1111/ejh.13818</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>