<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37865841</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19 related headaches: epidemiology, pathophysiology, impacts, and management.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>609</StartPage><EndPage>614</EndPage><MedlinePgn>609-614</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001219</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">This is an expert overview of the recent literature on the nature, epidemiology, pathophysiology, impact, and management of COVID-19 related headache, in the acute phase of infection and in post-COVID-19 syndrome.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Headache is one of the commonest symptoms of COVID-19 during acute infection and it is often experienced by individuals who go on to develop long COVID. There is a higher prevalence of headache in individuals with long COVID who contracted the Delta variant than in those who were infected with the Wuhan or Alpha variants. Headaches related to COVID-19 infection are commoner and may be more intense in women.There are indications that presence of headache might indicate a more benign COVID-19 infection and a better chance of survival. However, the impact of COVID-19 related headache could be substantial leading to poor quality of life in individuals affected. Headache that changes in its nature in terms of frequency and severity should be investigated to exclude cerebrovascular complications. There are promising new therapies for its treatment, but further research is needed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">The findings of this review can promote a better understanding of COVID-19 related headache and guide clinicians in the management of patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aiyegbusi</LastName><ForeName>Olalekan Lee</ForeName><Initials>OL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Patient Reported Outcomes Research, University of Birmingham, Edgbaston.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Health Research (NIHR) Birmingham Biomedical Research Centre, University of Birmingham.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Applied Research Collaboration (ARC) West Midlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Blood and Transplant Research Unit (BTRU) in Precision Therapeutics, Birmingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000711908">SARS-CoV-2 variants</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006261" MajorTopicYN="N">Headache</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37865841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-990000000-00115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO. WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard: World Health Organization 2023. https://covid19.who.int . [Accessed 11 September 2023]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, et al. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J Royal Soc Med 2021; 114:428&#x2013;442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gen&#xe7;eli M, Metin Akcan &#xd6;, Pekcan S, et al. Outcomes of COVID-19 infections in children: a single-center retrospective study. Pediatr Pulmonol 2022; 57:2533&#x2013;2539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;ven D, Bulus AD. Clinical and laboratory predictors of long-COVID in children: a single center retrospective study. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci 2022; 26:7695&#x2013;7704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel P, DeCuir J, Abrams J, et al. Clinical characteristics of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in adults: a systematic review. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4:e2126456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousaf AR, Cortese MM, Taylor AW, et al. Reported cases of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children aged 12-20 years in the USA who received a COVID-19 vaccine, December, 2020, through August, 2021: a surveillance investigation. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2022; 6:303&#x2013;312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhedin S, Lundholm C, Horne A, et al. Risk factors for multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children; A population-based cohort study of over 2 million children. Lancet Reg Health 2022; 19:100443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed A, Ibrahim E, Isam Farah Hassan R, Abbasher Hussien Mohamed Ahmed K, et al. Neurological manifestations of COVID-19: a potential gate to the determinants of a poor prognosis. Brain Behav 2022; 12:e2587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hashel JY, Abokalawa F, Alenzi M, et al. Coronavirus disease-19 and headache; impact on preexisting and characteristics of de novo: a cross-sectional study. J Headache Pain 2021; 22:97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caronna E, Ballv&#xe9; A, Llaurad&#xf3; A, et al. Headache: a striking prodromal and persistent symptom, predictive of COVID-19 clinical evolution. Cephalalgia 2020; 40:1410&#x2013;1421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caronna E, Pozo-Rosich P. Headache as a symptom of COVID-19: narrative review of 1-year research. Curr Pain Headache Rep 2021; 25:73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim W. Neurological manifestations in coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) patients: a systematic review of literature. CNS Spectr 2022; 27:145&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi M, Salami Khaneshan A, Farahani AS, et al. Characteristics and outcomes of COVID-19 patients during the BA.5 omicron wave in Tehran, Iran: a prospective observational study. BMC Infect Dis 2023; 23:237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olumade TJ, Uzairue LI. Clinical characteristics of 4499 COVID-19 patients in Africa: a meta-analysis. J Med Virol 2021; 93:3055&#x2013;3061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadpour D, Kristoffersson A, Fredrikson M, et al. Inventory study of an early pandemic COVID-19 cohort in South-Eastern Sweden, focusing on neurological manifestations. PloS one 2023; 18:e0280376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osikomaiya B, Erinoso O, Wright KO, et al. &#x2019;Long COVID&#x2019;: persistent COVID-19 symptoms in survivors managed in Lagos State, Nigeria. BMC Infect Dis 2021; 21:304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honarvar MR, Roshandel G, Shirzad-Aski H, et al. Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of the COVID-19 epidemic and associated factors for mortality in Golestan province, Iran: a retrospective cohort study. J Prev Med Hyg 2021; 62:E298&#x2013;E304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Martinez A, Fanjul V, Ramos C, et al. Headache during SARS-CoV-2 infection as an early symptom associated with a more benign course of disease: a case-control study. Eur J Neurol 2021; 28:3426&#x2013;3436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallardo VJ, Shapiro RE, Caronna E, Pozo-Rosich P. The relationship of headache as a symptom to COVID-19 survival: a systematic review and meta-analysis of survival of 43,169 inpatients with COVID-19. Headache 2022; 62:1019&#x2013;1028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Anjos de Paula RC, de Maria Frota Vasconcelos T, da Costa FBS, et al. Characterization of headache in COVID-19: a retrospective multicenter study. Mol Neurobiol 2021; 58:4487&#x2013;4494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez JT, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Planchuelo-G&#xf3;mez &#xc1;, et al. Phenotypic characterization of acute headache attributed to SARS-CoV-2: An ICHD-3 validation study on 106 hospitalized patients. Cephalalgia 2020; 40:1432&#x2013;1442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahin BE, Celikbilek A, Kocak Y, Hizmali L. Patterns of COVID-19-related headache: a cross-sectional study. Clin Neurol Neurosurg 2022; 219:107339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magdy R, Hussein M, Ragaie C, et al. Characteristics of headache attributed to COVID-19 infection and predictors of its frequency and intensity: a cross sectional study. Cephalalgia 2020; 40:1422&#x2013;1431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tana C, Giamberardino MA, Martelletti P. Long COVID and especially headache syndromes. Curr Opin Neurol 2023; 36:168&#x2013;174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, et al. The presence of headache at onset in SARS-CoV-2 infection is associated with long-term post-COVID headache and fatigue: a case-control study. Cephalalgia 2021; 41:1332&#x2013;1341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung YH, Ha E-H, Park J, et al. Neurological and psychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 conditions. J Korean Med Sci 2023; 38:e83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacem I, Gharbi A, Harizi C, et al. Characteristics, onset, and evolution of neurological symptoms in patients with COVID-19. Neurol Sci 2021; 42:39&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha-Filho PAS, Magalh&#xe3;es JE. Headache associated with COVID-19: frequency, characteristics and association with anosmia and ageusia. Cephalalgia 2020; 40:1443&#x2013;1451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Grimshaw M, Flores-Silva FD, Chiquete E, et al. Characteristics and predictors for silent hypoxemia in a cohort of hospitalized COVID-19 patients. Auton Neurosci 2021; 235:102855.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Sierra &#xc1;, Trigo J, et al. Frequency and phenotype of headache in covid-19: a study of 2194 patients. Sci Rep 2021; 11:14674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein M, Fathy W, Eid RA, et al. Relative frequency and risk factors of COVID-19 related headache in a sample of Egyptian population: a hospital-based study. Pain Med 2021; 22:2092&#x2013;2099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechien JR, Chiesa-Estomba CM, Place S, et al. Clinical and epidemiological characteristics of 1420 European patients with mild-to-moderate coronavirus disease 2019. J Intern Med 2020; 288:335&#x2013;344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafari M, Pormohammad A, Sheikh Neshin SA, et al. Clinical characteristics and outcomes of pregnant women with COVID-19 and comparison with control patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Rev Med Virol 2021; 31:1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan DSA, Pirzada AN, Ali A, et al. The differences in clinical presentation, management, and prognosis of laboratory-confirmed COVID-19 between pregnant and non-pregnant women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health (Online) 2021; 18:11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khullar D, Zhang Y, Zang C, et al. Racial/ethnic disparities in postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection in New York: an EHR-based cohort study from the RECOVER Program. J Gen Intern Med 2023; 38:1127&#x2013;1136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xe8;nech-Montoliu S, Puig-Barber&#xe0; J, Pac-Sa MR, et al. ABO Blood Groups and the incidence of complications in COVID-19 patients: a population-based prospective cohort study. Int J Environ Res Public Health (Online) 2021; 18:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Cuadrado ML, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, et al. Headache as a COVID-19 onset symptom and post-COVID-19 symptom in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors infected with the Wuhan, Alpha, or Delta SARS-CoV-2 variants. Headache 2022; 62:1148&#x2013;1152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kl&#xe4;ser K, Molteni E, Graham M, et al. COVID-19 due to the B.1 617 2 (Delta) variant compared to B 1 1 7 (Alpha) variant of SARS-CoV-2: a prospective observational cohort study. Sci Rep 2022; 12:10904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirca F, Aydogan S, G&#xf6;zalan A, et al. Comparison of clinical characteristics of wild-type SARS-CoV-2 and Omicron. Rev Assoc Med Bras 2022; 68:1476&#x2013;1480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;fstr&#xf6;m E, Kunkel S, K&#xf6;tz A, et al. Health-related quality of life and long-term symptoms among patients with nonsevere covid-19 - a prospective cohort study. Infect Dis (Lond) 2023; 55:272&#x2013;281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep 2021; 11:16144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehme M, Braillard O, Chappuis F, et al. Prevalence of symptoms more than seven months after diagnosis of symptomatic COVID-19 in an outpatient setting. Ann Intern Med 2021; 174:1252&#x2013;1260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehme M, Braillard O, Chappuis F, et al. One-year persistent symptoms and functional impairment in SARS-CoV-2 positive and negative individuals. J Intern Med 2022; 292:103&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter RS, Nieters A, Kr&#xe4;usslich H-G, et al. Postacute sequelae of covid-19 six to 12&#x200a;months after infection: population based study. BMJ (Clinical research ed) 2022; 379:e071050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Kessel SAM, Olde Hartman TC, Lucassen PLBJ, van Jaarsveld CHM. Postacute and long-COVID-19 symptoms in patients with mild diseases: a systematic review. Fam Pract 2022; 39:159&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, et al. Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in nonhospitalized adults. Nat Med 2022; 28:1706&#x2013;1714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, et al. Headache as an acute and post-COVID-19 symptom in COVID-19 survivors: a meta-analysis of the current literature. Eur J Neurol 2021; 28:3820&#x2013;3825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caronna E, van den Hoek TC, Bolay H, et al. Headache attributed to SARS-CoV-2 infection, vaccination and the impact on primary headache disorders of the COVID-19 pandemic: a comprehensive review. Cephalalgia 2023; 43:3331024221131337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molteni E, Sudre CH, Canas LS, et al. Illness duration and symptom profile in symptomatic UK school-aged children tested for SARS-CoV-2. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2021; 5:708&#x2013;718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dilber B, Aydin ZGG, Yesilbas O, et al. Neurological manifestations of pediatric acute COVID infections: a single center experience. J Trop Pedriatr 2021; 67:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink EL, Robertson CL, Wainwright MS, et al. Prevalence and risk factors of neurologic manifestations in hospitalized children diagnosed with acute SARS-CoV-2 or MIS-C. Pediatr Neurol 2022; 128:33&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink TT, Marques HHS, Gualano B, et al. Persistent symptoms and decreased health-related quality of life after symptomatic pediatric COVID-19: a prospective study in a Latin American tertiary hospital. Clinics (Sao Paulo) 2021; 76:e3511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard LM, Garguilo K, Gillon J, et al. The first 1000 symptomatic pediatric SARS-CoV-2 infections in an integrated healthcare system: a prospective cohort study. BMC Pediatr 2021; 21:403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda PK, Sharawat IK, Panda P, et al. Neurological complications of SARS-CoV-2 infection in children: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Trop Pedriatr 2021; 67:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y-B, Zeng N, Yuan K, et al. Prevalence and risk factor for long COVID in children and adolescents: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Public Health 2023; 16:660&#x2013;672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Pinto Pereira SM, Shafran R, et al. Physical and mental health 3&#x200a;months after SARS-CoV-2 infection (long COVID) among adolescents in England (CLoCk): a national matched cohort study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2022; 6:230&#x2013;239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolay H, Karadas &#xd6;, Ozt&#xfc;rk B, et al. HMGB1, NLRP3, IL-6 and ACE2 levels are elevated in COVID-19 with headache: a window to the infection-related headache mechanism. J Headache Pain 2021; 22:94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic SS, Gajovic N, Jurisevic M, et al. Galectin-1 as the new player in staging and prognosis of COVID-19. Sci Rep 2022; 12:1272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutiawati E, Kusuma HI, Fahriani M, et al. Headache in post-COVID-19 patients: its characteristics and relationship with the quality of life. Medicina (Kaunas) 2022; 58:1500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandmann FG, Tessier E, Lacy J, et al. Long-term health-related quality of life in non-hospitalized Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) cases with confirmed severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection in England: longitudinal analysis and cross-sectional comparison with controls. Clin Infect Dis 2022; 75:e962&#x2013;e973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahin S, Karsidag S, Cinar N, et al. The impact of the COVID-19 lockdown on the quality of life in chronic neurological diseases: the results of a COVQoL-CND Study. Eur Neurol 2021; 84:450&#x2013;459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karadas &#xd6;, &#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk B, Sonkaya AR, et al. Latent class cluster analysis identified hidden headache phenotypes in COVID-19: impact of pulmonary infiltration and IL-6. Neurol Sci 2021; 42:1665&#x2013;1673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Martinez A, Guerrero-Peral &#xc1;L, Arias-Rivas S, et al. Amitriptyline for post-COVID headache: effectiveness, tolerability, and response predictors. J Neurol 2022; 269:5702&#x2013;5709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krymchantowski AV, Silva-N&#xe9;to RP, Jevoux C, Krymchantowski AG. Indomethacin for refractory COVID or post-COVID headache: a retrospective study. Acta Neurol Belg 2022; 122:465&#x2013;469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manchanda RK, Miglani A, Gupta M, et al. Homeopathic remedies in COVID-19: prognostic factor research. Homeopathy 2021; 110:160&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J-Y, Huang P-Y, Liu T-H, et al. Clinical efficacy of probiotics in the treatment of patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther 2023; 21:667&#x2013;674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vawter NL, Godino JG, Lewis SV, et al. COVID-19 monoclonal antibody treatment impact on symptoms and post-COVID conditions among high-risk patients at a Federally Qualified Health Center. BMC Infect Dis 2023; 23:105.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>