<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37389402</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2572-9292</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiology and cardiovascular medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiol Cardiovasc Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Thromboembolism in the Complications of Long COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>123</StartPage><EndPage>128</EndPage><MedlinePgn>123-128</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.26502/fccm.92920317</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>SARS-CoV-2 is a +ssRNA helical coronavirus responsible for the global pandemic caused by coronavirus disease 19 (COVID-19). Classical clinical symptoms from primary COVID-19 when symptomatic include cough, fever, pneumonia or even ARDS; however, they are limited primarily to the respiratory system. Long-COVID-19 sequalae is responsible for many pathologies in almost every organ system and may be present in up to 30% of patients who have developed COVID-19. Our review focuses on how long-COVID-19 (3 -24 weeks after primary symptoms) may lead to an increased risk for stroke and thromboembolism. Patients who were found to be primarily at risk for thrombotic events included critically ill and immunocompromised patients. Additional risk factors for thromboembolism and stroke included diabetes, hypertension, respiratory and cardiovascular disease, and obesity. The etiology of how long-COVID-19 leads to a hypercoagulable state are yet to be definitively elucidated. However, anti-phospholipid antibodies and elevated D-dimer are present in many patients who develop thromboembolism. In addition, chronic upregulation and exhaustion of the immune system may lead to a pro-inflammatory and hypercoagulable state, increasing the likelihood for induction of thromboembolism or stroke. This article provides an up-to-date review on the proposed etiologies for thromboembolism and stroke in patients with long-COVID-19 and to assist health care providers in examining patients who may be at a higher risk for developing these pathologies.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopes</LastName><ForeName>Leilani A</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Western University of Health Sciences, College of Osteopathic Medicine of the Pacific - Northwest, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agrawal</LastName><ForeName>Devendra K</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Western University of Health Sciences, College of Osteopathic Medicine of the Pacific, Pomona, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 HL144125</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 HL147662</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiol Cardiovasc Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101721428</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2572-9292</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">D-dimers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep venous thrombosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thromboembolism</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37389402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1895005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10310316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26502/fccm.92920317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cascella M, Rajnik M, Aleem A, et al. Features, Evaluation, and Treatment of Coronavirus (COVID-19). In: StatPearls. StatPearls Publishing; 3 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32150360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis G, Li K, Thankam FG, et al. Ocular Transmissibility of COVID-19: Possibilities and Perspectives. Mol Cell Biochem 477 (2022): 849&#x2013;864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8783769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35066705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thankam FG, Agrawal DK: Molecular chronicles of cytokine burst in COVID-19 patients with cardiovascular diseases. J Thoracic Cardiovasc Surg 161 (2021): e217&#x2013;e226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32631657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Ahmad Farouk I, Lal SK. COVID-19: A Review on the Novel Coronavirus Disease Evolution, Transmission, Detection, Control and Prevention. Viruses 13 (2021): 202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7911532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33572857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noothi S, Radwan MM, Agrawal DK: Residual risks and evolving atherosclerotic plaques. Molecular and Cellular Biochemistry 10 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10627922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36897542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loo J, Spittle DA, Newnham M. COVID-19, immunothrombosis and venous thromboembolism: biological mechanisms. Thorax 76 (2021): 412&#x2013;420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33408195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdani AN, DeMarco N, Patel P, et al. Adverse hematological effects of COVID-19 vaccination and pathomechanisms of low acquired immunity in patients with hematological malignancies Vaccines 11 (2023): 662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10058097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36992246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, et al. Global Prevalence of Post-Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Condition or Long COVID: A Meta-Analysis and Systematic Review. J Infect Dis 226 (2022): 1593&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings G, Monaghan A, Xue F, et al. A Systematic Review of Persistent Symptoms and Residual Abnormal Functioning following Acute COVID-19: Ongoing Symptomatic Phase vs. Post-COVID-19 Syndrome. J Clin Med 10 (2021): 5913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8708187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34945213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Pellicer-Valero OJ, Navarro-Pardo E, et al. Symptoms Experienced at the Acute Phase of SARS-CoV-2 Infection as Risk Factor of Long-term Post-COVID Symptoms: The LONG-COVID-EXP-CM Multicenter Study. Int J Infect Dis 116 (2022): 241&#x2013;244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8743274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35017102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satish M, Agrawal DK: Atherothrombosis and the NLRP3 inflammasome &#x2013; endogenous mechanisms of inhibition. Transl Res 215 (2020): 75&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6889001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31469975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritsche LG, Jin W, Admon AJ, et al. Characterizing and Predicting Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS CoV-2 infection (PASC) in a Large Academic Medical Center in the US. medRxiv. Published online 2022 (2022): 22281356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9967320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36835863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satish M, Saxena SK, Agrawal DK: Adipokine dysregulation and insulin resistance with atherosclerotic vascular disease: Metabolic syndrome or independent sequaelae? J Cardiovasc Translational Res 12 (2019): 415&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6728239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30835048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes LA, Agrawal DK: Post-operative atrial fibrillation: Current treatments and etiologies for a persistent surgical complication. J Surg Res (Houst) 5 (2022): 159&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9017863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35445200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wais T, Hasan M, Rai V, et al. Gut-brain communication in COVID-19: Potential biomarkers and interventional strategies. Expert Review of Clin Immunol 18 (2022): 947&#x2013;960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35868344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai V, Balters MW, Agrawal DK: Factors IX, XI, and XII: Potential therapeutic targets in atherothrombosis. Rev Cardiovasc Med 20 (2019): 245&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31912715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samra G, Rai V, Agrawal DK: Heterogeneous Population of Immune cells Associated with Early Thrombosis in Arteriovenous Fistula. J Surg Res. (Houst) 5 (2022a): 423&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9354142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35937643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samra G, Rai V, Agrawal DK: Innate and adaptive immune cells associate with arteriovenous fistula maturation and failure. Can J Physiol Pharmacol 100 (2022b): 716&#x2013;727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35671528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel P, Rai V, Agrawal DK: Role of oncostatin-M in ECM remodeling and plaque vulnerability. Mol Cell Biochem 1 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10579161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36856919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velpuri P, Rai V, Agrawal DK: Role of sirtuins in attenuating plaque vulnerability in atherosclerosis. Mol Cell Biochem 23(2023): 1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10034899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36952068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavoni V, Gianesello L, Horton A. Antiphospholipid antibodies in critically ill COVID-19 patients with thromboembolism: cause of disease or epiphenomenon? J Thromb Thrombolysis 52 (2021): 542&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8109223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33973157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J, Tacquard C, Severac F, et al. High risk of thrombosis in patients with severe SARS-CoV-2 infection: a multicenter prospective cohort study. Intensive Care Med 46 (2020): 1089&#x2013;1098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7197634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32367170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wichmann D, Sperhake JP, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, et al. Autopsy Findings and Venous Thromboembolism in Patients With COVID-19: A Prospective Cohort Study. Ann Intern Med 173 (2020): 268&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7240772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32374815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spyropoulos AC, Crawford JM, Chen YWC, et al. Occurrence of Thromboembolic Events and Mortality Among Hospitalized Coronavirus 2019 Patients: Large Observational Cohort Study of Electronic Health Records. TH Open 6 (2022): e408&#x2013;e420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9674436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36452205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumi T, Harada K. Immune response to SARS-CoV-2 in severe disease and long COVID-19. iScience 25 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9251893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35813874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anka AU, Tahir MI, Abubakar SD, et al. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): An overview of the immunopathology, serological diagnosis and management. Scand J Immunol 93 (2021): e12998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7744910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33190302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stelzer M, Henes J, Saur S. The Role of Antiphospholipid Antibodies in COVID-19. Curr Rheumatol Rep 23 (2021): 72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8278370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34259944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Kruip MJHA, van der Meer NJM, et al. Incidence of thrombotic complications in critically ill ICU patients with COVID-19. Thromb Res 191 (2020): 145&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32291094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao D, Zhou F, Luo L, et al. Haematological characteristics and risk factors in the classification and prognosis evaluation of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet Haematol 7 (2020): e671&#x2013;e678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7351397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32659214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asakura H, Ogawa H. COVID-19-associated coagulopathy and disseminated intravascular coagulation. Int J Hematol 113 (2021): 45&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7648664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33161508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang N, Li D, Wang X, Sun Z. Abnormal coagulation parameters are associated with poor prognosis in patients with novel coronavirus pneumonia. J Thromb Haemost 18 (2020): 844&#x2013;847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7166509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32073213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bustamante JG, Goyal A, Singhal M. Antiphospholipid Syndrome. In: StatPearls. StatPearls Publishing; 10 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28613698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sammaritano LR. Antiphospholipid syndrome. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol 34 (2020): 101463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31866276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Wahab N, Talathi S, Lopez-Olivo MA, et al. Risk of developing antiphospholipid antibodies following viral infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lupus 27 (2018): 572&#x2013;583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28945149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iba T, Levy JH. Sepsis-induced Coagulopathy and Disseminated Intravascular Coagulation. Anesthesiology. 132 (2020): 1238&#x2013;1245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32044801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva Andrade B, Siqueira S, de Assis Soares WR, et al. Long-COVID and Post-COVID Health Complications: An Up-to-Date Review on Clinical Conditions and Their Possible Molecular Mechanisms. Viruses 13 (2021): 700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustino G, Pinney SP, Lala A, et al. Coronavirus and Cardiovascular Disease, Myocardial Injury, and Arrhythmia: JACC Focus Seminar. J Am Coll Cardiol 76 (2020): 2011&#x2013;2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7572122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33092737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler F, Bengsch B. Use of Mass Cytometry to Profile Human T Cell Exhaustion. Frontiers in Immunology. 23 (2020): 10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6987473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32038613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaqinuddin A, Kashir J. Innate immunity in COVID-19 patients mediated by NKG2A receptors, and potential treatment using Monalizumab, Cholroquine, and antiviral agents. Med Hypotheses 140 (2020): 109777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32344314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasin MM, Shehata IH, Elsheikh NG, et al. Expression of NKG2A inhibitory receptor on cytotoxic lymphocytes as an indicator of severity in Corona Virus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) patients. Egypt J Immunol 28 (2021): 157&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34453787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E, Vlok M, Venter C, et al. Persistent clotting protein pathology in Long COVID/Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) is accompanied by increased levels of antiplasmin. Cardiovascular Diabetology 20 (2021): 172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8381139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34425843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skeik N, Smith JE, Patel L, et al. Risk and Management of Venous Thromboembolism in Patients with COVID-19. Ann Vasc Surg 73 (2021): 78&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33333197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demelo-Rodr&#xed;guez P, Ordieres-Ortega L, Ji Z, et al. Long-term follow-up of patients with venous thromboembolism and COVID-19: Analysis of risk factors for death and major bleeding. Eur J Haematol 106 (2021): 716&#x2013;723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33608914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M, et al. Neurologic Manifestations of Hospitalized Patients With Coronavirus Disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Neurology 77: 683&#x2013;690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7149362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saavedra JM. Brain angiotensin II: new developments, unanswered questions and therapeutic opportunities. Cell Mol Neurobiol 25: 485&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16075377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark IA. Chronic cerebral aspects of long COVID, post-stroke syndromes and similar states share their pathogenesis and perispinal etanercept treatment logic. Pharmacol Res Perspect 10 (2022): e00926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8850677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35174650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambertsen KL, Biber K, Finsen B. Inflammatory cytokines in experimental and human stroke. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 32 (2012): 1677&#x2013;1698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3434626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22739623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lab&#xf2; N, Ohnuki H, Tosato G. Vasculopathy and Coagulopathy Associated with SARS-CoV-2 Infection. Cells 9 (2020): 1583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7408139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32629875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nooti SK, Rai V, Singh H, et al. Delineating Health and Health System: Mechanistic Insights into Covid 19 Complications. Springer; (2021): 209&#x2013;231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thankam FG, Rai T, Liu J, et al. Minimally oxidized-LDL-driven alterations in the level of pathological mediators and biological processes in carotid atherosclerosis. Cardiol Cardiovasc Med 6 (2022): 137&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9075180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35531433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>