<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39428555</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1976-9148</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biomolecules &amp; therapeutics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biomol Ther (Seoul)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Is There such a Thing as Post-Viral Depression?: Implications for Precision Medicine.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>659</StartPage><EndPage>684</EndPage><MedlinePgn>659-684</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4062/biomolther.2024.170</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Viral infections are increasingly recognized as triggers for depressive disorders, particularly following the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic and the rise of long COVID. Viruses such as Herpes Simplex Virus (HSV), Epstein-Barr Virus (EBV), Cytomegalovirus (CMV), and Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) are linked to depression through complex neurobiological mechanisms. These include immune system dysregulation, chronic inflammation, and neurotransmitter imbalances that affect brain function and mood regulation. Viral activation of the immune system leads to the release of pro-inflammatory cytokines, resulting in neuroinflammation and associated depressive symptoms. Furthermore, specific viruses can disrupt neurotransmitter systems, including serotonin, dopamine, and glutamate, all of which are essential for mood stabilization. The unique interactions of different viruses with these systems underscore the need for virus-specific therapeutic approaches. Current broad-spectrum treatments often overlook the precise neurobiological pathways involved in post-viral depression, reducing their efficacy. This review emphasizes the need to understand these virus-specific interactions to create tailored interventions that directly address the neurobiological effects induced by each type of virus. These interventions may include immunomodulatory treatments that target persistent inflammation, antiviral therapies to reduce the viral load, or neuroprotective strategies that restore neurotransmitter balance. Precision medicine offers promising avenues for the effective management of virus-induced depression, providing patient-specific approaches that address the specific biological mechanisms involved. By focusing on the development of these targeted treatments, this review aims to pave the way for a new era in psychiatric care that fully addresses the root causes of depression induced by viral infections.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Eun-Sook</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Science and Technology, School of Medicine, Konkuk University, Seoul 05029, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Chan Young</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Center for Neuroscience Research, Konkuk University, Seoul 05029, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Department of Advanced Translational Medicine, School of Medicine, Konkuk University, Seoul 05029, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Sciences &amp; Technology, Konkuk University, Seoul 05029, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeon</LastName><ForeName>Se Jin</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, College of Medicine, Hallym University, Chuncheon 24252, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ham</LastName><ForeName>Byung-Joo</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Korea University Anam Hospital, Korea University College of Medicine, Seoul 02841, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Biomol Ther (Seoul)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101472832</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1976-9148</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epigenetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mitochondria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurotransmitter imbalance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Precision medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Viral infection</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>CONFLICT OF INTEREST </b>
. The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39428555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4062/biomolther.2024.170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">biomolther.2024.170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11535299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Acharjee S., Branton W. G., Vivithanaporn P., Maingat F., Paul A. M., Dickie P., Baker G. B., Power C. HIV-1 Nef expression in microglia disrupts dopaminergic and immune functions with associated mania-like behaviors. Brain Behav. Immun. 2014;40:74&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2014.02.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2014.02.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24607605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeoluwa O. A., Olayinka J. N., Adeoluwa G. O., Akinluyi E. T., Adeniyi F. R., Fafure A., Nebo K., Edem E. E., Eduviere A. T., Abubakar B. Quercetin abrogates lipopolysaccharide-induced depressive-like symptoms by inhibiting neuroinflammation via microglial NLRP3/NF&#x3ba;B/iNOS signaling pathway. Behav. Brain Res. 2023;450:114503. doi: 10.1016/j.bbr.2023.114503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbr.2023.114503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37209878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhya D., Basu A. Epigenetic modulation of host: new insights into immune evasion by viruses. J. Biosci. 2010;35:647&#x2013;663. doi: 10.1007/s12038-010-0072-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12038-010-0072-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21289446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adinolfi L. E., Nevola R., Lus G., Restivo L., Guerrera B., Romano C., Zampino R., Rinaldi L., Sellitto A., Giordano M., Marrone A. Chronic hepatitis C virus infection and neurological and psychiatric disorders: an overview. World J. Gastroenterol. 2015;21:2269&#x2013;2280. doi: 10.3748/wjg.v21.i8.2269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v21.i8.2269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4342902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25741133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamer E., Zhong C., Liu Z., Niu Q., Long F., Guo L., Gelman B. B., Soong L., Zhou J., Hu H. Epigenetic suppression of HIV in myeloid cells by the BRD4-selective small molecule modulator ZL0580. J. Virol. 2020;94:e01880. doi: 10.1128/JVI.01880-19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.01880-19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7269428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32188727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen A. D., Tilkian S. M. Depression correlated with cellular immunity in systemic immunodeficient Epstein-Barr virus syndrome (SIDES) J. Clin. Psychiatry. 1986;47:133&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3005245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen J., Romay-Tallon R., Brymer K. J., Caruncho H. J., Kalynchuk L. E. Mitochondria and mood: mitochondrial dysfunction as a key player in the manifestation of depression. Front. Neurosci. 2018;12:386. doi: 10.3389/fnins.2018.00386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2018.00386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5997778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29928190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allison D. J., Sharma B., Timmons B. W. The efficacy of anti-inflammatory treatment interventions on depression in individuals with major depressive disorder and high levels of inflammation: a systematic review of randomized clinical trials. Physiol. Behav. 2019;207:104&#x2013;112. doi: 10.1016/j.physbeh.2019.05.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physbeh.2019.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31078670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amendola-Pires M. M., Fakoury M. K., Salazar H., De Oliveira S. B., Brand&#xe3;o-Mello C. E., Schmidt S. L. Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) infection and neurocognitive impairment in subjects with mild liver disease. J. Clin. Med. 2023;12:3910. doi: 10.3390/jcm12123910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12123910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10298895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37373605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amsterdam J. D., Hernz W. J. Serum antibodies to herpes simplex virus types I and II in depressed patients. Biol. Psychiatry. 1993;34:417&#x2013;420. doi: 10.1016/0006-3223(93)90188-J.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0006-3223(93)90188-J</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8218610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anisman H., Ravindran A. V., Griffiths J., Merali Z. Endocrine and cytokine correlates of major depression and dysthymia with typical or atypical features. Mol. Psychiatry. 1999;4:182&#x2013;188. doi: 10.1038/sj.mp.4000436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.mp.4000436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10208451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atluri V. S., Kanthikeel S. P., Reddy P. V., Yndart A., Nair M. P. Human synaptic plasticity gene expression profile and dendritic spine density changes in HIV-infected human CNS cells: role in HIV-associated neurocognitive disorders (HAND) PLoS One. 2013;8:e61399. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0061399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0061399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3631205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23620748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avdoshina V., Bachis A., Mocchetti I. Synaptic dysfunction in human immunodeficiency virus type-1-positive subjects: inflammation or impaired neuronal plasticity? J. Intern. Med. 2013;273:454&#x2013;465. doi: 10.1111/joim.12050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joim.12050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3633109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23600400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Averill L. A., Jiang L., Purohit P., Coppoli A., Averill C. L., Roscoe J., Kelmendi B., De Feyter H. M., de Graaf R. A., Gueorguieva R., Sanacora G., Krystal J. H., Rothman D. L., Mason G. F., Abdallah C. G. Prefrontal glutamate neurotransmission in PTSD: a novel approach to estimate synaptic strength in vivo in humans. Chronic Stress (Thousand Oaks) 2022;6:24705470221092734. doi: 10.1177/24705470221092734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/24705470221092734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9008809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35434443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayano G., Demelash S., Abraha M., Tsegay L. The prevalence of depression among adolescent with HIV/AIDS: a systematic review and meta-analysis. AIDS Res. Ther. 2021;18:23. doi: 10.1186/s12981-021-00351-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12981-021-00351-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8077927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33906698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayano G., Solomon M., Abraha M. A systematic review and meta-analysis of epidemiology of depression in people living with HIV in East Africa. BMC Psychiatry. 2018;18:254. doi: 10.1186/s12888-018-1835-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-018-1835-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6094569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30111300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayling K., Jia R., Coupland C., Chalder T., Massey A., Broadbent E., Vedhara K. Psychological predictors of self-reported COVID-19 outcomes: results from a prospective cohort study. Ann. Behav. Med. 2022;56:484&#x2013;497. doi: 10.1093/abm/kaab106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/abm/kaab106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8755370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34979556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai S., Guo W., Feng Y., Deng H., Li G., Nie H., Guo G., Yu H., Ma Y., Wang J., Chen S., Jing J., Yang J., Tang Y., Tang Z. Efficacy and safety of anti-inflammatory agents for the treatment of major depressive disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2020;91:21&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1136/jnnp-2019-320912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2019-320912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31658959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barlow-Mosha L., Eckard A. R., McComsey G. A., Musoke P. M. Metabolic complications and treatment of perinatally HIV-infected children and adolescents. J. Int. AIDS Soc. 2013;16:18600. doi: 10.7448/IAS.16.1.18600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7448/IAS.16.1.18600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3691550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23782481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomeo C. S., Lemes R. M. R., Morais R. L., Pereria G. C., Nunes T. A., Costa A. J., de Barros Maciel R. M., Braconi C. T., Maricato J. T., Janini L. M. R., Okuda L. H., Lee K. S., Prado C. M., Ureshino R. P., Stilhano R. S. SARS-CoV-2 infection and replication kinetics in different human cell types: the role of autophagy, cellular metabolism and ACE2 expression. Life Sci. 2022;308:120930. doi: 10.1016/j.lfs.2022.120930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2022.120930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9444585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36075471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battaglia D. M., Sanchez-Pino M. D., Nichols C. D., Foster T. P. Herpes simplex virus-1 induced serotonin-associated metabolic pathways correlate with severity of virus- and inflammation-associated ocular disease. Front. Microbiol. 2022;13:859866. doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2022.859866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2022.859866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8982329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35391733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bavaresco D. V., Uggioni M. L. R., Ferraz S. D., Marques R. M. M., Simon C. S., Dagostin V. S., Grande A. J., da Rosa M. I. Efficacy of infliximab in treatment-resistant depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pharmacol. Biochem. Behav. 2020;188:172838. doi: 10.1016/j.pbb.2019.172838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pbb.2019.172838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31837338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayturan S., Sapmaz &#x15e;. Y., Uzun A. D., Kandemir H., Ecemi&#x15f; T. Relationship of herpesvirus (HSV1, EBV, CMV, HHV6) seropositivity with depressive disorder and its clinical aspects: the first study in children. J. Med. Virol. 2022;94:5484&#x2013;5491. doi: 10.1002/jmv.27995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.27995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35821494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beharry M. Pediatric anxiety and depression in the time of COVID-19. Pediatr. Ann. 2022;51:e154&#x2013;e160. doi: 10.3928/19382359-20220317-01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/19382359-20220317-01</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35417314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger J. R., Kumar M., Kumar A., Fernandez J. B., Levin B. Cerebrospinal fluid dopamine in HIV-1 infection. AIDS. 1994;8:67&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1097/00002030-199401000-00010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00002030-199401000-00010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8011238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bessa J. M., Ferreira D., Melo I., Marques F., Cerqueira J. J., Palha J. A., Almeida O. F., Sousa N. The mood-improving actions of antidepressants do not depend on neurogenesis but are associated with neuronal remodeling. Mol. Psychiatry. 2009;14:764&#x2013;773. 739. doi: 10.1038/mp.2008.119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2008.119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18982002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe9;tourn&#xe9; A., Szelechowski M., Thouard A., Abrial E., Jean A., Zaidi F., Foret C., Bonnaud E. M., Charlier C. M., Suberbielle E., Malnou C. E., Granon S., Rampon C., Gonzalez-Dunia D. Hippocampal expression of a virus-derived protein impairs memory in mice. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2018;115:1611&#x2013;1616. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1711977115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1711977115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5816149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29378968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beurel E., Toups M., Nemeroff C. B. The bidirectional relationship of depression and inflammation: double trouble. Neuron. 2020;107:234&#x2013;256. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2020.06.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2020.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7381373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32553197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya A., Jones D. N. C. Emerging role of the P2X7-NLRP3-IL1&#x3b2; pathway in mood disorders. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2018;98:95&#x2013;100. doi: 10.1016/j.psyneuen.2018.08.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psyneuen.2018.08.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30121550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya A., Lord B., Grigoleit J. S., He Y., Fraser I., Campbell S. N., Taylor N., Aluisio L., O'Connor J. C., Papp M., Chrovian C., Carruthers N., Lovenberg T. W., Letavic M. A. Neuropsychopharmacology of JNJ-55308942: evaluation of a clinical candidate targeting P2X7 ion channels in animal models of neuroinflammation and anhedonia. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2018;43:2586&#x2013;2596. doi: 10.1038/s41386-018-0141-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-018-0141-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6224414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30026598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bornand D., Toovey S., Jick S. S., Meier C. R. The risk of new onset depression in association with influenza--a population-based observational study. Brain Behav. Immun. 2016;53:131&#x2013;137. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2015.12.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2015.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26681501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;ttiker P., Stefano G. B., Weissenberger S., Ptacek R., Anders M., Raboch J., Kream R. M. HIV, HSV, SARS-CoV-2 and Ebola share long-term neuropsychiatric sequelae. Neuropsychiatr. Dis. Treat. 2022;18:2229&#x2013;2237. doi: 10.2147/NDT.S382308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S382308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9548297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36221293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucci M. Viral mechanisms: Tat modulates DAT. Nat. Chem. Biol. 2015;11:240. doi: 10.1038/nchembio.1779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nchembio.1779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4407678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25785419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burmeister A. R., Gordevicius J., Paul E. N., Houck C., George S., Escobar Galvis M. L., Sha Q., Brundin P., Pospisilik J. A., Racicot K., Brundin L. Maternal Herpesviridae infection during pregnancy alters midbrain dopaminergic signatures in adult offspring. Neurobiol. Dis. 2022;169:105720. doi: 10.1016/j.nbd.2022.105720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2022.105720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35417751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Q., Lan K., Verma S. C., Si H., Lin D., Robertson E. S. Kaposi's sarcoma-associated herpesvirus latent protein LANA interacts with HIF-1 alpha to upregulate RTA expression during hypoxia: latency control under low oxygen conditions. J. Virol. 2006;80:7965&#x2013;7975. doi: 10.1128/JVI.00689-06.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.00689-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1563785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16873253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalcante G. I., Chaves Filho A. J., Linhares M. I., de Carvalho Lima C. N., Ven&#xe2;ncio E. T., Rios E. R., de Souza F. C., Vasconcelos S. M., Mac&#xea;do D., de Fran&#xe7;a Fonteles M. M. HIV antiretroviral drug Efavirenz induces anxiety-like and depression-like behavior in rats: evaluation of neurotransmitter alterations in the striatum. Eur. J. Pharmacol. 2017;799:7&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1016/j.ejphar.2017.02.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejphar.2017.02.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28188763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F., Nogo D., Carvalho I. P., Lee Y., Nasri F., Xiong J., Lui L. M. W., Subramaniapillai M., Gill H., Liu R. N., Joseph P., Teopiz K. M., Cao B., Mansur R. B., Lin K., Rosenblat J. D., Ho R. C., McIntyre R. S. Association between mood disorders and risk of COVID-19 infection, hospitalization, and death: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatry. 2021;78:1079&#x2013;1091. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2021.1818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2021.1818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8319830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34319365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C. M., Hsieh M. S., Yang T. C., Hsieh V. C., Chiang J. H., Huang H. H., How C. K., Hu S. Y., Yen D. H. Selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors and the risk of hepatocellular carcinoma in hepatitis B virus-infected patients. Cancer Manag. Res. 2017;9:709&#x2013;720. doi: 10.2147/CMAR.S148097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CMAR.S148097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5713708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29238221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang D., Dela Cruz C., Sharma L. Beneficial and detrimental effects of cytokines during influenza and COVID-19. Viruses. 2024;16:308. doi: 10.3390/v16020308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v16020308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10892676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38400083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H. S., Wang F., Chen J. G. Epigenetic mechanisms in depression: implications for pathogenesis and treatment. Curr. Opin. Neurobiol. 2024;85:102854. doi: 10.1016/j.conb.2024.102854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conb.2024.102854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38401316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J. Y., Ren Y., Yan P., Belina M. E., Chung R. T., Butt A. A. Tricyclic antidepressant use and the risk of fibrosis progression in hepatitis C-infected persons: results from ERCHIVES. J. Viral. Hepat. 2018;25:825&#x2013;833. doi: 10.1111/jvh.12884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jvh.12884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6019114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29478294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M. H., Wei H. T., Su T. P., Li C. T., Lin W. C., Chang W. H., Chen T. J., Bai Y. M. Risk of depressive disorder among patients with herpes zoster: a nationwide population-based prospective study. Psychosom. Med. 2014;76:285&#x2013;291. doi: 10.1097/PSY.0000000000000051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PSY.0000000000000051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24804885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P. P., Wei X. Y., Tao L., Xin X., Xiao S. T., He N. Cerebral abnormalities in HIV-infected individuals with neurocognitive impairment revealed by fMRI. Sci. Rep. 2023;13:10331. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-37493-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-37493-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10293263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37365237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng S., Wang W., Zhu Z., Zhao M., Li H., Liu D., Pan F. Involvement of brain-derived neurotrophic factor methylation in the prefrontal cortex and hippocampus induced by chronic unpredictable mild stress in male mice. J. Neurochem. 2023;164:624&#x2013;642. doi: 10.1111/jnc.15735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnc.15735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36453259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng S. W., Li J. X., Chien Y. C., Chang J. P., Shityakov S., Huang S. Y., Galecki P., Su K. P. Genetic variations of ionotropic glutamate receptor pathways on interferon-&#x3b1;-induced depression in patients with Hepatitis C viral infection. Brain Behav. Immun. 2021;93:16&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2020.11.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2020.11.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33161164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi H. G., Kim E. J., Lee Y. K., Kim M. The risk of herpes zoster virus infection in patients with depression: a longitudinal follow-up study using a national sample cohort. Medicine (Baltimore) 2019;98:e17430. doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000017430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000017430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6783196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31577760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleaver J., Jeffery K., Klenerman P., Lim M., Handunnetthi L., Irani S. R., Handel A. The immunobiology of herpes simplex virus encephalitis and post-viral autoimmunity. Brain. 2024;147:1130&#x2013;1148. doi: 10.1093/brain/awad419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awad419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10994539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38092513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins M. L., Cheney G. A., Yehl J. L., Sullivan G. A., Stewart J. T., Catalano G. Postviral depression. J. Psychiatr. Pract. 2021;27:126&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1097/PRA.0000000000000508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PRA.0000000000000508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33656819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-, Mental Disorders Collaborators Global prevalence and burden of depressive and anxiety disorders in 204 countries and territories in 2020 due to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet. 2021;398:1700&#x2013;1712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34634250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cozzi A., Zignego A. L., Carpendo R., Biagiotti T., Aldinucci A., Monti M., Giannini C., Rosselli M., Laffi G., Moroni F. Low serum tryptophan levels, reduced macrophage IDO activity and high frequency of psychopathology in HCV patients. J. Viral Hepat. 2006;13:402&#x2013;408. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2893.2005.00706.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2893.2005.00706.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16842443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cymerys J., Chodkowski M., S&#x142;o&#x144;ska A., Krzy&#x17c;owska M., Ba&#x144;bura M. W. Disturbances of mitochondrial dynamics in cultured neurons infected with human herpesvirus type 1 and type 2. J. Neurovirol. 2019;25:765&#x2013;782. doi: 10.1007/s13365-019-00762-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13365-019-00762-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6920257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31161588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahm T., Rudolph H., Schwerk C., Schroten H., Tenenbaum T. Neuroinvasion and inflammation in viral central nervous system infections. Mediators Inflamm. 2016;2016:8562805. doi: 10.1155/2016/8562805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/8562805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4897715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27313404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai Y., Wei T., Shen Z., Bei Y., Lin H., Dai H. Classical HDACs in the regulation of neuroinflammation. Neurochem. Int. 2021;150:105182. doi: 10.1016/j.neuint.2021.105182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuint.2021.105182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34509559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalwadi D. A., Ozuna L., Harvey B. H., Viljoen M., Schetz J. A. Adverse neuropsychiatric events and recreational use of efavirenz and other HIV-1 antiretroviral drugs. Pharmacol. Rev. 2018;70:684&#x2013;711. doi: 10.1124/pr.117.013706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1124/pr.117.013706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29945900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danilenko O. V., Gavrilova N. Y., Churilov L. P. Chronic fatigue exhibits heterogeneous autoimmunity characteristics which reflect etiology. Pathophysiology. 2022;29:187&#x2013;199. doi: 10.3390/pathophysiology29020016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pathophysiology29020016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9231045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35736644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danilescu C. M., Sandulescu D. L., Pirlog M. C., Streba C. T., Rogoveanu I. Depressive and anxious symptoms in Hepatitis C virus infected patients receiving DAA-based therapy. Diagnostics (Basel) 2021;11:2237. doi: 10.3390/diagnostics11122237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics11122237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8700570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34943472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis D. A., Rinderknecht A. S., Zoeteweij J. P., Aoki Y., Read-Connole E. L., Tosato G., Blauvelt A., Yarchoan R. Hypoxia induces lytic replication of Kaposi sarcoma-associated herpesvirus. Blood. 2001;97:3244&#x2013;3250. doi: 10.1182/blood.V97.10.3244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.V97.10.3244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11342455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Francesco M. A. Herpesviridae, neurodegenerative disorders and autoimmune diseases: what is the relationship between them? Viruses. 2024;16:133. doi: 10.3390/v16010133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v16010133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10818483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38257833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Knegt R. J., Bezemer G., Van Gool A. R., Drenth J. P., Hansen B. E., Droogleever Fortuyn H. A., Weegink C. J., Hengeveld M. W., Janssen H. L. Randomised clinical trial: escitalopram for the prevention of psychiatric adverse events during treatment with peginterferon-alfa-2a and ribavirin for chronic hepatitis C. Aliment. Pharmacol. Ther. 2011;34:1306&#x2013;1317. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2036.2011.04867.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2036.2011.04867.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21999489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denton A. R., Mactutus C. F., Lateef A. U., Harrod S. B., Booze R. M. Chronic SSRI treatment reverses HIV-1 protein-mediated synaptodendritic damage. J. Neurovirol. 2021;27:403&#x2013;421. doi: 10.1007/s13365-021-00960-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13365-021-00960-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8504184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34003469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietrich D. E., Bode L., Spannhuth C. W., Hecker H., Ludwig H., Emrich H. M. Antiviral treatment perspective against Borna disease virus 1 infection in major depression: a double-blind placebo-controlled randomized clinical trial. BMC Pharmacol. Toxicol. 2020;21:12. doi: 10.1186/s40360-020-0391-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40360-020-0391-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7027224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32066504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dollish H. K., Tsyglakova M., McClung C. A. Circadian rhythms and mood disorders: time to see the light. Neuron. 2024;112:25&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2023.09.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2023.09.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10842077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37858331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xfc;sedau H. P., Steffen J., Figueiredo C. A., Boehme J. D., Schultz K., Erck C., Korte M., Faber-Zuschratter H., Smalla K. H., Dieterich D., Kr&#xf6;ger A., Bruder D., Dunay I. R. Influenza A virus (H1N1) infection induces microglial activation and temporal dysbalance in glutamatergic synaptic transmission. mBio. 2021;12:e0177621. doi: 10.1128/mBio.01776-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/mBio.01776-21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8546584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34700379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du L., Fan X., Yang Y., Wu S., Liu Y. Quercetin ameliorates cognitive impairment in depression by targeting HSP90 to inhibit NLRP3 inflammasome activation. Mol. Neurobiol. 2024a;61:6628&#x2013;6641. doi: 10.1007/s12035-024-03926-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-024-03926-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38329680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Y., Yan T., Wu B., He B., Jia Y. Research on the mechanism of antidepressive effect of Suanzaoren Decoction through TLR4/MyD88/NF-&#x3ba;B pathway and Wnt/&#x3b2;-catenin pathway. J. Ethnopharmacol. 2024b;319:117190. doi: 10.1016/j.jep.2023.117190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2023.117190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37739105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte L. F., Far&#xed;as M. A., &#xc1;lvarez D. M., Bueno S. M., Riedel C. A., Gonz&#xe1;lez P. A. Herpes simplex virus type 1 infection of the central nervous system: insights into proposed interrelationships with neurodegenerative disorders. Front. Cell. Neurosci. 2019;13:46. doi: 10.3389/fncel.2019.00046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fncel.2019.00046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6399123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30863282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwight M. M., Kowdley K. V., Russo J. E., Ciechanowski P. S., Larson A. M., Katon W. J. Depression, fatigue, and functional disability in patients with chronic hepatitis C. J. Psychosom. Res. 2000;49:311&#x2013;317. doi: 10.1016/S0022-3999(00)00155-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-3999(00)00155-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11164055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehret M., Sobieraj D. M. Prevention of interferon-alpha-associated depression with antidepressant medications in patients with hepatitis C virus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int. J. Clin. Pract. 2014;68:255&#x2013;261. doi: 10.1111/ijcp.12268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijcp.12268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24372654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serag H. B., Kunik M., Richardson P., Rabeneck L. Psychiatric disorders among veterans with hepatitis C infection. Gastroenterology. 2002;123:476&#x2013;482. doi: 10.1053/gast.2002.34750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/gast.2002.34750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12145801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott A. J., Russo J., Bergam K., Claypoole K., Uldall K. K., Roy-Byrne P. P. Antidepressant efficacy in HIV-seropositive outpatients with major depressive disorder: an open trial of nefazodone. J. Clin. Psychiatry. 1999;60:226&#x2013;231. doi: 10.4088/JCP.v60n0404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.v60n0404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10221282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis R. J., Fan Y., Grelotti D., Tang B., Letendre S., He J. J. Astrocyte activation is a potential mechanism underlying depressed mood and apathy in people with HIV. J. Neurol. Psychol. 2022;9:5. doi: 10.13188/2332-3469.1000048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13188/2332-3469.1000048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10194432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37205974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis R. J., Letendre S. L., Atkinson J. H., Clifford D., Collier A. C., Gelman B. B., Marra C., McCutchan J. A., Morgello S., Sacktor N., Tang B., Heaton R. K. Higher levels of plasma inflammation biomarkers are associated with depressed mood and quality of life in aging, virally suppressed men, but not women, with HIV. Brain Behav. Immun. Health. 2020;7:100121. doi: 10.1016/j.bbih.2020.100121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbih.2020.100121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34589877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabrazzo M., Cipolla S., Pisaturo M., Camerlengo A., Bucci P., Pezzella P., Coppola N., Galderisi S. Bidirectional relationship between HIV/HBV infection and comorbid depression and/or anxiety: a systematic review on shared biological mechanisms. J. Pers. Med. 2023;13:1689. doi: 10.3390/jpm13121689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jpm13121689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10744606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38138916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatma N., Zakaria S., Mourad Z., Samir B., Samia B. S. Atypical anti-NMDA receptor encephalitis associated with varicella zoster virus infection. J. Neurovirol. 2022;28:456&#x2013;459. doi: 10.1007/s13365-022-01080-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13365-022-01080-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35604574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fava M., Davidson K. G. Definition and epidemiology of treatment-resistant depression. Psychiatr. Clin. North Am. 1996;19:179&#x2013;200. doi: 10.1016/S0193-953X(05)70283-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0193-953X(05)70283-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8827185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedotova J., Bereza Z. SSRIs treatment did not completely restore affective state in patients with the initial clinically confirmed major depressive disorder/generalized anxiety disorder after COVID-19 disease. Eur. Psychiatry. 2022;65:S96. doi: 10.1192/j.eurpsy.2022.279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/j.eurpsy.2022.279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng S., Liu Y., Zhou Y., Shu Z., Cheng Z., Brenner C., Feng P. Mechanistic insights into the role of herpes simplex virus 1 in Alzheimer's disease. Front. Aging Neurosci. 2023;15:1245904. doi: 10.3389/fnagi.2023.1245904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2023.1245904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10512732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37744399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filgueira L., Larionov A., Lannes N. The influence of virus infection on microglia and accelerated brain aging. Cells. 2021;10:1836. doi: 10.3390/cells10071836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells10071836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8303900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34360004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firouzabadi D., Kheshti F., Abdollahifard S., Taherifard E., Kheshti M. R. The effect of selective serotonin and norepinephrine reuptake inhibitors on clinical outcome of COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Health Sci. Rep. 2022;5:e892. doi: 10.1002/hsr2.892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hsr2.892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9577115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36268458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer N. Infection-induced epigenetic changes and their impact on the pathogenesis of diseases. Semin. Immunopathol. 2020;42:127&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1007/s00281-020-00793-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00281-020-00793-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7174260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32318841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher N. F., McKeating J. A. Hepatitis C virus and the brain. J. Viral Hepat. 2012;19:301&#x2013;306. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2893.2012.01591.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2893.2012.01591.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22497808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher N. F., Wilson G. K., Murray J., Hu K., Lewis A., Reynolds G. M., Stamataki Z., Meredith L. W., Rowe I. A., Luo G., Lopez-Ramirez M. A., Baumert T. F., Weksler B., Couraud P. O., Kim K. S., Romero I. A., Jopling C., Morgello S., Balfe P., McKeating J. A. Hepatitis C virus infects the endothelial cells of the blood-brain barrier. Gastroenterology. 2012;142:634&#x2013;643.e6. doi: 10.1053/j.gastro.2011.11.028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2011.11.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3801216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22138189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fond G., Nemani K., Etchecopar-Etchart D., Loundou A., Goff D. C., Lee S. W., Lancon C., Auquier P., Baumstarck K., Llorca P. M., Yon D. K., Boyer L. Association between mental health disorders and mortality among patients With COVID-19 in 7 countries: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatry. 2021;78:1208&#x2013;1217. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2021.2274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2021.2274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8317055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34313711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontana R. J., Hussain K. B., Schwartz S. M., Moyer C. A., Su L., Lok A. S. Emotional distress in chronic hepatitis C patients not receiving antiviral therapy. J. Hepatol. 2002;36:401&#x2013;407. doi: 10.1016/S0168-8278(01)00280-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0168-8278(01)00280-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11867185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford B. N., Savitz J. Effect of cytomegalovirus on the immune system: implications for aging and mental health. Curr. Top. Behav. Neurosci. 2023;61:181&#x2013;214. doi: 10.1007/7854_2022_376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/7854_2022_376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35871707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frye M. A., Coombes B. J., McElroy S. L., Jones-Brando L., Bond D. J., Veldic M., Romo-Nava F., Bobo W. V., Singh B., Colby C., Skime M. K., Biernacka J. M., Yolken R. Association of cytomegalovirus and Toxoplasma gondii antibody titers with bipolar disorder. JAMA Psychiatry. 2019;76:1285&#x2013;1293. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2019.2499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2019.2499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6751798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31532468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu R., Jinnah H., McKay J. L., Miller A. H., Felger J. C., Farber E. W., Sharma S., Whicker N., Moore R. C., Franklin D., Letendre S. L., Anderson A. M. Cerebrospinal fluid levels of 5-HIAA and dopamine in people with HIV and depression. J. Neurovirol. 2023;29:440&#x2013;448. doi: 10.1007/s13365-023-01142-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13365-023-01142-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10766341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37289360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gale S. D., Berrett A. N., Erickson L. D., Brown B. L., Hedges D. W. Association between virus exposure and depression in US adults. Psychiatry Res. 2018;261:73&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2017.12.037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2017.12.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29287239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebara E., Zanoletti O., Ghosal S., Grosse J., Schneider B. L., Knott G., Astori S., Sandi C. Mitofusin-2 in the nucleus accumbens regulates anxiety and depression-like behaviors through mitochondrial and neuronal actions. Biol. Psychiatry. 2021;89:1033&#x2013;1044. doi: 10.1016/j.biopsych.2020.12.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2020.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33583561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelman B. B., Lisinicchia J. G., Chen T., Johnson K. M., Jennings K., Freeman D. H., Jr, Soukup V. M. Prefrontal dopaminergic and enkephalinergic synaptic accommodation in HIV-associated neurocognitive disorders and encephalitis. J. Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2012;7:686&#x2013;700. doi: 10.1007/s11481-012-9345-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11481-012-9345-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3419353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22391864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaffaripour Jahromi G., Razi S., Rezaei N. NLRP3 inflammatory pathway. Can we unlock depression? Brain Res. 2024;1822:148644. doi: 10.1016/j.brainres.2023.148644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2023.148644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37871673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gharbawy D., Tadrous M., Suda K. Does depression lead to influenza? - a systematic literature analysis. J. Affect. Disord. 2012;138:41&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2011.12.037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2011.12.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22335890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghassemi S., Asgari T., Mirzapour-Delavar H., Aliakbari S., Pourbadie H. G., Prehaud C., Lafon M., Gholami A., Azadmanesh K., Naderi N., Sayyah M. Lentiviral expression of rabies virus glycoprotein in the rat hippocampus strengthens synaptic plasticity. Cell. Mol. Neurobiol. 2022;42:1429&#x2013;1440. doi: 10.1007/s10571-020-01032-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10571-020-01032-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11421698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33462779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golden S. A., Christoffel D. J., Heshmati M., Hodes G. E., Magida J., Davis K., Cahill M. E., Dias C., Ribeiro E., Ables J. L., Kennedy P. J., Robison A. J., Gonzalez-Maeso J., Neve R. L., Turecki G., Ghose S., Tamminga C. A., Russo S. J. Epigenetic regulation of RAC1 induces synaptic remodeling in stress disorders and depression. Nat. Med. 2013;19:337&#x2013;344. doi: 10.1038/nm.3090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.3090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3594624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23416703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Dunia D., Volmer R., Mayer D., Schwemmle M. Borna disease virus interference with neuronal plasticity. Virus Res. 2005;111:224&#x2013;234. doi: 10.1016/j.virusres.2005.04.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.virusres.2005.04.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15885838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosztonyi G., Ludwig H. Interactions of viral proteins with neurotransmitter receptors may protect or destroy neurons. Curr. Top. Microbiol. Immunol. 2001;253:121&#x2013;144. doi: 10.1007/978-3-662-10356-2_6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-662-10356-2_6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11417131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greeson J. M., Gettes D. R., Spitsin S., Dub&#xe9; B., Benton T. D., Lynch K. G., Douglas S. D., Evans D. L. The selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor citalopram decreases human immunodeficiency virus receptor and coreceptor expression in immune cells. Biol. Psychiatry. 2016;80:33&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1016/j.biopsych.2015.11.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2015.11.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4862937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26725193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez F., Garc&#xed;a L., Padilla S., Alvarez D., Moreno S., Navarro G., G&#xf3;mez-Sirvent J., Vidal F., Asensi V., Masi&#xe1; M. Risk of clinically significant depression in HIV-infected patients: effect of antiretroviral drugs. HIV Med. 2014;15:213&#x2013;223. doi: 10.1111/hiv.12104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hiv.12104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24215356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hacohen Y., Deiva K., Pettingill P., Waters P., Siddiqui A., Chretien P., Menson E., Lin J. P., Tardieu M., Vincent A., Lim M. J. N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor antibodies in post-herpes simplex virus encephalitis neurological relapse. Mov. Disord. 2014;29:90&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1002/mds.25626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.25626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24014096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haeri S., Johnson N., Baker A. M., Stuebe A. M., Raines C., Barrow D. A., Boggess K. A. Maternal depression and Epstein-Barr virus reactivation in early pregnancy. Obstet. Gynecol. 2011;117:862&#x2013;866. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0b013e31820f3a30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0b013e31820f3a30</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21422857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q., Li W., Chen P., Wang L., Bao X., Huang R., Liu G., Chen X. Microglial NLRP3 inflammasome-mediated neuroinflammation and therapeutic strategies in depression. Neural Regen. Res. 2024;19:1890&#x2013;1898. doi: 10.4103/1673-5374.390964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.390964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11040318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38227513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaton N. S., Randall G. Dengue virus-induced autophagy regulates lipid metabolism. Cell Host Microbe. 2010;8:422&#x2013;432. doi: 10.1016/j.chom.2010.10.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chom.2010.10.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3026642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21075353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heeren M., Sojref F., Schuppner R., Worthmann H., Pflugrad H., Tryc A. B., Pasedag T., Weissenborn K. Active at night, sleepy all day--sleep disturbances in patients with hepatitis C virus infection. J. Hepatol. 2014;60:732&#x2013;740. doi: 10.1016/j.jhep.2013.11.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2013.11.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24308991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellmuth J., Colby D., Valcour V., Suttichom D., Spudich S., Ananworanich J., Prueksakaew P., Sailasuta N., Allen I., Jagodzinski L. L., Slike B., Ochi D., Paul R. Depression and anxiety are common in acute HIV infection and associate with plasma immune activation. AIDS Behav. 2017;21:3238&#x2013;3246. doi: 10.1007/s10461-017-1788-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10461-017-1788-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5830305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28484888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickie I., Bennett B., Mitchell P., Wilhelm K., Orlay W. Clinical and subclinical hypothyroidism in patients with chronic and treatment-resistant depression. Aust. N. Z. J. Psychiatry. 1996;30:246&#x2013;252. doi: 10.3109/00048679609076101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/00048679609076101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8811268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horowitz T., Pellerin L., Zimmer E., Guedj E. Brain fog in long COVID: a glutamatergic hypothesis with astrocyte dysfunction accounting for brain PET glucose hypometabolism. Med. Hypotheses. 2023;180:111186. doi: 10.1016/j.mehy.2023.111186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mehy.2023.111186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini S., Wilk E., Michaelsen-Preusse K., Gerhauser I., Baumg&#xe4;rtner W., Geffers R., Schughart K., Korte M. Long-term neuroinflammation induced by influenza A virus infection and the impact on hippocampal neuron morphology and function. J. Neurosci. 2018;38:3060&#x2013;3080. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1740-17.2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1740-17.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6596076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29487124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W., Wu X., Yao Z., Gu Y., Lai X., Meng L., Peng S. Investigating the relationship between hepatitis B virus infection and postpartum depression in Chinese women: a retrospective cohort study. Front. Public Health. 2023;11:1214151. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2023.1214151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1214151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10716447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38094232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X., Liu X., Yu Y. Depression and chronic liver diseases: are there shared underlying mechanisms? Front. Mol. Neurosci. 2017;10:134. doi: 10.3389/fnmol.2017.00134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnmol.2017.00134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5420567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28533742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hukkanen V., Broberg E., Salmi A., Er&#xe4;linna J. P. Cytokines in experimental herpes simplex virus infection. Int. Rev. Immunol. 2002;21:355&#x2013;371. doi: 10.1080/08830180213276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08830180213276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12486819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunsberger H. C., Wang D., Petrisko T. J., Alhowail A., Setti S. E., Suppiramaniam V., Konat G. W., Reed M. N. Peripherally restricted viral challenge elevates extracellular glutamate and enhances synaptic transmission in the hippocampus. J. Neurochem. 2016;138:307&#x2013;316. doi: 10.1111/jnc.13665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnc.13665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4936939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27168075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang J. H., Lee J. S., Oh H. M., Lee E. J., Lim E. J., Son C. G. Evaluation of viral infection as an etiology of ME/CFS: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J. Transl. Med. 2023;21:763. doi: 10.1186/s12967-023-04635-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-023-04635-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10612276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37898798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iosifescu A. L., Hoogenboom W. S., Buczek A. J., Fleysher R., Duong T. Q. New-onset and persistent neurological and psychiatric sequelae of COVID-19 compared to influenza: a retrospective cohort study in a large New York City healthcare network. Int. J. Methods Psychiatr. Res. 2022;31:e1914. doi: 10.1002/mpr.1914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mpr.1914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9349863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35706352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin M. R., Levin M. J., Carrillo C., Olmstead R., Lucko A., Lang N., Caulfield M. J., Weinberg A., Chan I. S., Clair J., Smith J. G., Marchese R. D., Williams H. M., Beck D. J., McCook P. T., Johnson G., Oxman M. N. Major depressive disorder and immunity to varicella-zoster virus in the elderly. Brain Behav. Immun. 2011;25:759&#x2013;766. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2011.02.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2011.02.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3081366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21329753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam M. R., Sohan M., Daria S., Masud A. A., Ahmed M. U., Roy A., Shahriar M. Evaluation of inflammatory cytokines in drug-na&#xef;ve major depressive disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int. J. Immunopathol. Pharmacol. 2023;37:3946320231198828. doi: 10.1177/03946320231198828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03946320231198828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10467201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37625799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang J., Yang M., Tian M., Chen Z., Xiao L., Gong Y. Intertwined associations between oxytocin, immune system and major depressive disorder. Biomed. Pharmacother. 2023;163:114852. doi: 10.1016/j.biopha.2023.114852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2023.114852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10165244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37163778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones-Brando L., Dickerson F., Ford G., Stallings C., Origoni A., Katsafanas E., Sweeney K., Squire A., Khushalani S., Yolken R. Atypical immune response to Epstein-Barr virus in major depressive disorder. J. Affect. Disord. 2020;264:221&#x2013;226. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2019.11.150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2019.11.150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7025817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32056754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kafali H. Y., Dasgin H., Sahin Cevik D., Sozan S. S., Oguz K. K., Mutlu M., Parlakay A. O., Toulopoulou T. The effect of SARS-CoV-2 virus on resting-state functional connectivity during adolescence: investigating brain correlates of psychotic-like experiences and SARS-CoV-2 related inflammation response. Psychiatry Res. Neuroimaging. 2023;336:111746. doi: 10.1016/j.pscychresns.2023.111746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pscychresns.2023.111746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37979347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaharuza F. M., Bunnell R., Moss S., Purcell D. W., Bikaako-Kajura W., Wamai N., Downing R., Solberg P., Coutinho A., Mermin J. Depression and CD4 cell count among persons with HIV infection in Uganda. AIDS Behav. 2006;10:S105&#x2013;S111. doi: 10.1007/s10461-006-9142-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10461-006-9142-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16802195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalkman H. O., Feuerbach D. Antidepressant therapies inhibit inflammation and microglial M1-polarization. Pharmacol. Ther. 2016;163:82&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1016/j.pharmthera.2016.04.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pharmthera.2016.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27101921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamyshna I. I., Pavlovych L. B., Kamyshnyi A. M. Association between NMDA gene polymorphism (rs4880213) and GRIN2B blood serum levels in thyroid pathology patients. J. Med. Life. 2022;15:109&#x2013;116. doi: 10.25122/jml-2021-0372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25122/jml-2021-0372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8852646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35186144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappelmann N., Lewis G., Dantzer R., Jones P. B., Khandaker G. M. Antidepressant activity of anti-cytokine treatment: a systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical trials of chronic inflammatory conditions. Mol. Psychiatry. 2018;23:335&#x2013;343. doi: 10.1038/mp.2016.167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2016.167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5794896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27752078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlovi&#x107; D., Serretti A., Vrki&#x107; N., Martinac M., Mar&#x10d;inko D. Serum concentrations of CRP, IL-6, TNF-&#x3b1; and cortisol in major depressive disorder with melancholic or atypical features. Psychiatry Res. 2012;198:74&#x2013;80. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2011.12.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2011.12.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22386567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley K. W., Kent S. The legacy of sickness behaviors. Front. Psychiatry. 2020;11:607269. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2020.607269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2020.607269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7744348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33343432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesby J. P., Markou A., Semenova S. Effects of HIV/TAT protein expression and chronic selegiline treatment on spatial memory, reversal learning and neurotransmitter levels in mice. Behav. Brain Res. 2016;311:131&#x2013;140. doi: 10.1016/j.bbr.2016.05.034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbr.2016.05.034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5198783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27211061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalefah M. M., Khalifah A. M. Determining the relationship between SARS-CoV-2 infection, dopamine, and COVID-19 complications. J. Taibah Univ. Med. Sci. 2020;15:550&#x2013;553. doi: 10.1016/j.jtumed.2020.10.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtumed.2020.10.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7646371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33173452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M., Baussan Y., Hebert-Chatelain E. Connecting dots between mitochondrial dysfunction and depression. Biomolecules. 2023;13:695. doi: 10.3390/biom13040695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom13040695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10135685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37189442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan N., Haughey N. J., Nath A., Geiger J. D. Involvement of organelles and inter-organellar signaling in the pathogenesis of HIV-1 associated neurocognitive disorder and Alzheimer's disease. Brain Res. 2019;1722:146389. doi: 10.1016/j.brainres.2019.146389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2019.146389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6755067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31425679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoodoruth M. A. S., Estudillo-Guerra M. A., Pacheco-Barrios K., Nyundo A., Chapa-Koloffon G., Ouanes S. Glutamatergic system in depression and its role in neuromodulatory techniques optimization. Front. Psychiatry. 2022;13:886918. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2022.886918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2022.886918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35492692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimera E., Vindevogel S., Reynaert D., Justice K. M., Rubaihayo J., De Maeyer J., Engelen A. M., Musanje K., Bilsen J. Experiences and effects of HIV-related stigma among youth living with HIV/AIDS in Western Uganda: a photovoice study. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0232359. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0232359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0232359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7182188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32330206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kircheis R., Planz O. The role of toll-like receptors (TLRs) and their related signaling pathways in viral infection and inflammation. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2023;24:6701. doi: 10.3390/ijms24076701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms24076701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10095430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37047674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjellman B. F., Thorell L. H., Orhagen T., Elia G., K&#xe5;gedal B. The hypothalamic-pituitary-thyroid axis in depressive patients and healthy subjects in relation to the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis. Psychiatry Res. 1993;47:7&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/0165-1781(93)90051-H.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0165-1781(93)90051-H</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8516419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klinedinst N. J., Regenold W. T. A mitochondrial bioenergetic basis of depression. J. Bioenerg. Biomembr. 2015;47:155&#x2013;171. doi: 10.1007/s10863-014-9584-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10863-014-9584-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25262287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi N., Oka N., Takahashi M., Shimada K., Ishii A., Tatebayashi Y., Shigeta M., Yanagisawa H., Kondo K. Human herpesvirus 6B greatly increases risk of depression by activating hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis during latent phase of infection. iScience. 2020;23:101187. doi: 10.1016/j.isci.2020.101187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isci.2020.101187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7298549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32534440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;hler-Forsberg O., Lydholm C. N., Hjorth&#xf8;j C., Nordentoft M., Mors O., Benros M. E. Efficacy of anti-inflammatory treatment on major depressive disorder or depressive symptoms: meta-analysis of clinical trials. Acta Psychiatr. Scand. 2019;139:404&#x2013;419. doi: 10.1111/acps.13016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acps.13016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30834514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;hler O., Benros M. E., Nordentoft M., Farkouh M. E., Iyengar R. L., Mors O., Krogh J. Effect of anti-inflammatory treatment on depression, depressive symptoms, and adverse effects: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. JAMA Psychiatry. 2014;71:1381&#x2013;1391. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2014.1611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2014.1611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25322082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konsman J. P. So many faces, phases, and facets, sickness behavior beyond disciplines. Front. Psychiatry. 2021;12:630331. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2021.630331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2021.630331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7947683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33716828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraus R. J., Yu X., Cordes B. A., Sathiamoorthi S., Iempridee T., Nawandar D. M., Ma S., Romero-Masters J. C., McChesney K. G., Lin Z., Makielski K. R., Lee D. L., Lambert P. F., Johannsen E. C., Kenney S. C., Mertz J. E. Hypoxia-inducible factor-1&#x3b1; plays roles in Epstein-Barr virus's natural life cycle and tumorigenesis by inducing lytic infection through direct binding to the immediate-early BZLF1 gene promoter. PLoS Pathog. 2017;13:e1006404. doi: 10.1371/journal.ppat.1006404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1006404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5487075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28617871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause C., Bergmann E., Schmidt S. V. Epigenetic modulation of myeloid cell functions in HIV and SARS-CoV-2 infection. Mol. Biol. Rep. 2024;51:342. doi: 10.1007/s11033-024-09266-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11033-024-09266-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10894183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38400997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kucukkarapinar M., Yay-Pence A., Yildiz Y., Buyukkoruk M., Yaz-Aydin G., Deveci-Bulut T. S., Gulbahar O., Senol E., Candansayar S. Psychological outcomes of COVID-19 survivors at sixth months after diagnose: the role of kynurenine pathway metabolites in depression, anxiety, and stress. J. Neural Transm. (Vienna) 2022;129:1077&#x2013;1089. doi: 10.1007/s00702-022-02525-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-022-02525-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9261222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35796878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon D. Y., Xu B., Hu P., Zhao Y. T., Beagan J. A., Nofziger J. H., Cui Y., Phillips-Cremins J. E., Blendy J. A., Wu H., Zhou Z. Neuronal Yin Yang1 in the prefrontal cortex regulates transcriptional and behavioral responses to chronic stress in mice. Nat. Commun. 2022;13:55. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-27571-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-27571-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8748737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35013139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai J. Y., Ho J. X., Kow A. S. F., Liang G., Tham C. L., Ho Y. C., Lee M. T. Interferon therapy and its association with depressive disorders - a review. Front. Immunol. 2023;14:1048592. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2023.1048592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1048592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9992192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36911685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamers F., Vogelzangs N., Merikangas K. R., de Jonge P., Beekman A. T., Penninx B. W. Evidence for a differential role of HPA-axis function, inflammation and metabolic syndrome in melancholic versus atypical depression. Mol. Psychiatry. 2013;18:692&#x2013;699. doi: 10.1038/mp.2012.144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2012.144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23089630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S., Ha H., Jang J., Byun Y. Recent advances in the development of antidepressants targeting the purinergic P2X7 receptor. Curr. Med. Chem. 2023;30:164&#x2013;177. doi: 10.2174/0929867329666220629141418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0929867329666220629141418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35770396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefkowitz R. B., Miller C. M., Martinez-Caballero J. D., Ramos I. Epigenetic control of innate immunity: consequences of acute respiratory virus infection. Viruses. 2024;16:197. doi: 10.3390/v16020197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v16020197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10893272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38399974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leng A., Shah M., Ahmad S. A., Premraj L., Wildi K., Li Bassi G., Pardo C. A., Choi A., Cho S. M. Pathogenesis underlying neurological manifestations of long COVID syndrome and potential therapeutics. Cells. 2023;12:816. doi: 10.3390/cells12050816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells12050816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10001044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36899952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung C. M. C., Ho M. K., Bharwani A. A., Cogo-Moreira H., Wang Y., Chow M. S. C., Fan X., Galea S., Leung G. M., Ni M. Y. Mental disorders following COVID-19 and other epidemics: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Transl. Psychiatry. 2022;12:205. doi: 10.1038/s41398-022-01946-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-022-01946-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9110635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35581186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C. W., Chen Y. C., Lee N. Y., Chen P. L., Li M. C., Li C. Y., Ko W. C., Ko N. Y. Efavirenz is not associated with an increased risk of depressive disorders in patients living with HIV: an 11-year population-based study in Taiwan. Healthcare (Basel) 2021a;9:1625. doi: 10.3390/healthcare9121625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare9121625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8701138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34946352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H., Zhu W., Zhang L., Lei H., Wu X., Guo L., Chen X., Wang Y., Tang H. The metabolic responses to hepatitis B virus infection shed new light on pathogenesis and targets for treatment. Sci. Rep. 2015;5:8421. doi: 10.1038/srep08421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep08421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4325332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25672227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Ma F., Yokota T., Garcia G., Jr, Palermo A., Wang Y., Farrell C., Wang Y. C., Wu R., Zhou Z., Pan C., Morselli M., Teitell M. A., Ryazantsev S., Fishbein G. A., Hoeve J. T., Arboleda V. A., Bloom J., Dillon B., Pellegrini M., Lusis A. J., Graeber T. G., Arumugaswami V., Deb A. Metabolic reprogramming and epigenetic changes of vital organs in SARS-CoV-2-induced systemic toxicity. JCI Insight. 2021b;6:e145027. doi: 10.1172/jci.insight.145027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci.insight.145027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7934846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33284134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Puma D. D., Colussi C., Bandiera B., Puliatti G., Rinaudo M., Cocco S., Paciello F., Re A., Ripoli C., De Chiara G., Bertozzi A., Palamara A. T., Piacentini R., Grassi C. Interleukin 1&#x3b2; triggers synaptic and memory deficits in Herpes simplex virus type-1-infected mice by downregulating the expression of synaptic plasticity-related genes via the epigenetic MeCP2/HDAC4 complex. Cell. Mol. Life Sci. 2023;80:172. doi: 10.1007/s00018-023-04817-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00018-023-04817-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10234878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37261502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao C. H., Chang C. S., Muo C. H., Kao C. H. High prevalence of herpes zoster in patients with depression. J. Clin. Psychiatry. 2015;76:e1099&#x2013;e1104. doi: 10.4088/JCP.14m09311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.14m09311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26455673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lier J., Stoll K., Obrig H., Baum P., Deterding L., Bernsdorff N., Hermsdorf F., Kunis I., Br&#xe4;secke A., Herzig S., Schroeter M. L., Th&#xf6;ne-Otto A., Riedel-Heller S. G., Laufs U., Wirtz H., Classen J., Saur D. Neuropsychiatric phenotype of post COVID-19 syndrome in non-hospitalized patients. Front. Neurol. 2022;13:988359. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2022.988359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2022.988359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36237627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limanaqi F., Zecchini S., Dino B., Strizzi S., Cappelletti G., Utyro O., Vanetti C., Garziano M., Saulle I., Clerici M., Biasin M. Dopamine reduces SARS-CoV-2 replication in vitro through downregulation of D2 receptors and upregulation of type-I interferons. Cells. 2022;11:1691. doi: 10.3390/cells11101691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells11101691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9139638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35626728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisnasari B., Ardianto C., Khotib J. Microglia as a potential target for antidepressant: a systematic review on preclinical studies. RJPT. 2022;15:3317&#x2013;3323. doi: 10.52711/0974-360X.2022.00555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52711/0974-360X.2022.00555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q., Zhang M. M., Guo M. X., Zhang Q. P., Li N. Z., Cheng J., Wang S. L., Xu G. H., Li C. F., Zhu J. X., Yi L. T. Inhibition of microglial NLRP3 with MCC950 attenuates microglial morphology and NLRP3/caspase-1/IL-1&#x3b2; signaling in stress-induced mice. J. Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2022a;17:503&#x2013;514. doi: 10.1007/s11481-021-10037-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11481-021-10037-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34978026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Hu P., Zheng Z., Zhong D., Xie W., Tang Z., Pan B., Luo J., Zhang W., Wang X. Photoresponsive vaccine-like CAR-M system with high-efficiency central immune regulation for inflammation-related depression. Adv. Mater. 2022b;34:e2108525. doi: 10.1002/adma.202108525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202108525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34897839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locatelli M., Faure-Dupuy S. Virus hijacking of host epigenetic machinery to impair immune response. J. Virol. 2023;97:e0065823. doi: 10.1128/jvi.00658-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jvi.00658-23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10537592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37656959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorkiewicz P., Waszkiewicz N. Biomarkers of post-COVID depression. J. Clin. Med. 2021;10:4142. doi: 10.3390/jcm10184142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm10184142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8470902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34575258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louie A. Y., Kim J. S., Drnevich J., Dibaeinia P., Koito H., Sinha S., McKim D. B., Soto-Diaz K., Nowak R. A., Das A., Steelman A. J. Influenza A virus infection disrupts oligodendrocyte homeostasis and alters the myelin lipidome in the adult mouse. J. Neuroinflammation. 2023;20:190. doi: 10.1186/s12974-023-02862-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12974-023-02862-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10439573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37596606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low-Beer S., Chan K., Yip B., Wood E., Montaner J. S., O'Shaughnessy M. V., Hogg R. S. Depressive symptoms decline among persons on HIV protease inhibitors. J. Acquir. Immune Defic. Syndr. 2000;23:295&#x2013;301. doi: 10.1097/00042560-200004010-00003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00042560-200004010-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10836751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu H., Surkan P. J., Irwin M. R., Treisman G. J., Breen E. C., Sacktor N., Stall R., Wolinsky S. M., Jacobson L. P., Abraham A. G. Inflammation and risk of depression in HIV: prospective findings from the multicenter AIDS cohort study. Am. J. Epidemiol. 2019;188:1994&#x2013;2003. doi: 10.1093/aje/kwz190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aje/kwz190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6825834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31642472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J., Liang J., Yang J., Mischoulon D., Nyer M. Does the association between Herpes Simplex 2 infection and depressive symptoms vary among different sexual minority statuses and sex groups? Findings from a nationally representative sample. J. Affect. Disord. 2023;327:226&#x2013;229. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2023.01.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2023.01.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36623565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y., Liu B. P., Tan C. T., Pan F., Larbi A., Ng T. P. Lifetime pathogen burden, inflammatory markers, and depression in community-dwelling older adults. Brain Behav. Immun. 2022;102:124&#x2013;134. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2022.02.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2022.02.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35202734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu D., Wang F., Zhang M., Yang W., Huang H., Huang Q., Wu C., Qian N., Wang M., Zhang H., Zheng S., Chen J., Fu Y., Zhang C., Li Z., Hong W. Ketamine induces rapid antidepressant effects via the autophagy-NLRP3 inflammasome pathway. Psychopharmacology (Berl.) 2022;239:3201&#x2013;3212. doi: 10.1007/s00213-022-06201-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-022-06201-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35925279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma L., Wang F., Li Y., Wang J., Chang Q., Du Y., Sadan J., Zhao Z., Fan G., Yao B., Chen J. F. Brain methylome remodeling selectively regulates neuronal activity genes linking to emotional behaviors in mice exposed to maternal immune activation. Nat. Commun. 2023;14:7829. doi: 10.1038/s41467-023-43497-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-43497-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10687003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38030616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M., Berk M., Goehler L., Song C., Anderson G., Ga&#x142;ecki P., Leonard B. Depression and sickness behavior are Janus-faced responses to shared inflammatory pathways. BMC Med. 2012;10:66. doi: 10.1186/1741-7015-10-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1741-7015-10-66</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3391987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22747645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maier H. B., Neyazi A., Bundies G. L., Meyer-Bockenkamp F., Bleich S., Pathak H., Ziert Y., Neuhaus B., M&#xfc;ller F. J., Pollmann I., Illig T., M&#xfc;cke S., M&#xfc;ller M., M&#xf6;ller B. K., Oeltze-Jafra S., Kacprowski T., Voges J., M&#xfc;ntefering F., Scheiber J., Reif A., Aichholzer M., Reif-Leonhard C., Schmidt-Kassow M., Hegerl U., Reich H., Unterecker S., Weber H., Deckert J., B&#xf6;ssel-Debbert N., Grabe H. J., Lucht M., Frieling H. Validation of the predictive value of BDNF -87 methylation for antidepressant treatment success in severely depressed patients-a randomized rater-blinded trial. Trials. 2024;25:247. doi: 10.1186/s13063-024-08061-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-024-08061-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11005235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38594753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangold C. A., Szpara M. L. Persistent infection with herpes simplex virus 1 and Alzheimer's disease-a call to study how variability in both virus and host may impact disease. Viruses. 2019;11:966. doi: 10.3390/v11100966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v11100966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6833100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31635156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marathe G., Moodie E. E. M., Brouillette M. J., Lani&#xe8;ce Delaunay C., Cox J., Martel-Laferri&#xe8;re V., Gill J., Cooper C., Pick N., Vachon M. L., Walmsley S., Klein M. B. Impact of hepatitis C virus cure on depressive symptoms in the human immunodeficiency virus-hepatitis C virus coinfected population in Canada. Clin. Infect. Dis. 2023;76:e702&#x2013;e709. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciac540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciac540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9907551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35789253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markkula N., Lindgren M., Yolken R. H., Suvisaari J. Association of exposure to Toxoplasma gondii, Epstein-Barr Virus, Herpes Simplex virus Type 1 and Cytomegalovirus with new-onset depressive and anxiety disorders: an 11-year follow-up study. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;87:238&#x2013;242. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2019.12.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2019.12.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31809804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattson M. P., Gleichmann M., Cheng A. Mitochondria in neuroplasticity and neurological disorders. Neuron. 2008;60:748&#x2013;766. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2008.10.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2008.10.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2692277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19081372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurya S. K., Baghel M. S., Gaurav, Chaudhary V., Kaushik A., Gautam A. Putative role of mitochondria in SARS-CoV-2 mediated brain dysfunctions: a prospect. Biotechnol. Genet. Eng. Rev. 2022;39:167&#x2013;192. doi: 10.1080/02648725.2022.2108998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02648725.2022.2108998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35934991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maximova O. A., Sturdevant D. E., Kash J. C., Kanakabandi K., Xiao Y., Minai M., Moore I. N., Taubenberger J., Martens C., Cohen J. I., Pletnev A. G. Virus infection of the CNS disrupts the immune-neural-synaptic axis via induction of pleiotropic gene regulation of host responses. Elife. 2021;10:e62273. doi: 10.7554/eLife.62273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.62273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7891934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33599611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza M. G., Zanardi R., Palladini M., Rovere-Querini P., Benedetti F. Rapid response to selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors in post-COVID depression. Eur. Neuropsychopharmacol. 2022;54:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.09.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.09.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34634679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFadden K., Hafez A. Y., Kishton R., Messinger J. E., Nikitin P. A., Rathmell J. C., Luftig M. A. Metabolic stress is a barrier to Epstein-Barr virus-mediated B-cell immortalization. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2016;113:E782&#x2013;E790. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1517141113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1517141113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4760815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26802124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaurin K. A., Harris M., Madormo V., Harrod S. B., Mactutus C. F., Booze R. M. HIV-associated apathy/depression and neurocognitive impairments reflect persistent dopamine deficits. Cells. 2021;10:2158. doi: 10.3390/cells10082158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells10082158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8392364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34440928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Y., Du J., Liu N., Qiang Y., Xiao L., Lan X., Ma L., Yang J., Yu J., Lu G. Epigenetic modulation: research progress on histone acetylation levels in major depressive disorders. J. Drug Target. 2023;31:142&#x2013;151. doi: 10.1080/1061186X.2022.2125978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1061186X.2022.2125978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36112185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke A. The HPA axis as target for depression. Curr. Neuropharmacol. 2024;22:904&#x2013;915. doi: 10.2174/1570159X21666230811141557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570159X21666230811141557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10845091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37581323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mertowska P., Smolak K., Mertowski S., Grywalska E. Immunomodulatory role of interferons in viral and bacterial infections. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2023;24:10115. doi: 10.3390/ijms241210115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms241210115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10298684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37373262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merz M. P., Seal S. V., Grova N., M&#xe9;riaux S., Guebels P., Kanli G., Mommaerts E., Nicot N., Kaoma T., Keunen O., Nazarov P. V., Turner J. D. Early-life influenza A (H1N1) infection independently programs brain connectivity, HPA AXIS and tissue-specific gene expression profiles. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:5898. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-56601-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-56601-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10928197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38467724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midde N. M., Gomez A. M., Zhu J. HIV-1 Tat protein decreases dopamine transporter cell surface expression and vesicular monoamine transporter-2 function in rat striatal synaptosomes. J. Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2012;7:629&#x2013;639. doi: 10.1007/s11481-012-9369-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11481-012-9369-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3688268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22570010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xed;guez-Burbano M. J., Rodriguez A., Vargas M., Tantalean G., Valiathan R., Chan W. Are serotonin alterations the link between thrombocytopenia and poor immune status among HIV infected individuals? J. AIDS Clin. Res. 2014;2:1000277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4610408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26491607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihaescu G., Chifiriuc M. C., Filip R., Bleotu C., Ditu L. M., Constantin M., Cristian R. E., Grigore R., Bertesteanu S. V., Bertesteanu G., Vrancianu C. O. Role of interferons in the antiviral battle: from virus-host crosstalk to prophylactic and therapeutic potential in SARS-CoV-2 infection. Front. Immunol. 2023;14:1273604. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2023.1273604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1273604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10822962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38288121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller G. E., Freedland K. E., Duntley S., Carney R. M. Relation of depressive symptoms to C-reactive protein and pathogen burden (cytomegalovirus, herpes simplex virus, Epstein-Barr virus) in patients with earlier acute coronary syndromes. Am. J. Cardiol. 2005;95:317&#x2013;321. doi: 10.1016/j.amjcard.2004.09.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2004.09.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15670537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min X., Wang G., Cui Y., Meng P., Hu X., Liu S., Wang Y. Association between inflammatory cytokines and symptoms of major depressive disorder in adults. Front. Immunol. 2023;14:1110775. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2023.1110775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1110775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9968963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36860860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misztak P., Pa&#x144;czyszyn-Trzewik P., Sowa-Ku&#x107;ma M. Histone deacetylases (HDACs) as therapeutic target for depressive disorders. Pharmacol. Rep. 2018;70:398&#x2013;408. doi: 10.1016/j.pharep.2017.08.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pharep.2017.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29456074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mocchetti I., Bachis A., Campbell L. A., Avdoshina V. Implementing neuronal plasticity in NeuroAIDS: the experience of brain-derived neurotrophic factor and other neurotrophic factors. J. Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2014;9:80&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1007/s11481-013-9488-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11481-013-9488-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3844100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23832285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad S. S., Sinclair K., Pillai S., Merheb V., Aumann T. D., Gill D., Dale R. C., Brilot F. Herpes simplex encephalitis relapse with chorea is associated with autoantibodies to N-Methyl-D-aspartate receptor or dopamine-2 receptor. Mov. Disord. 2014;29:117&#x2013;122. doi: 10.1002/mds.25623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.25623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24115338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno J. L., Kurita M., Holloway T., L&#xf3;pez J., Cadagan R., Mart&#xed;nez-Sobrido L., Garc&#xed;a-Sastre A., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Maeso J. Maternal influenza viral infection causes schizophrenia-like alterations of 5-HT2A and mGlu2 receptors in the adult offspring. J. Neurosci. 2011;31:1863&#x2013;1872. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4230-10.2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4230-10.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3037097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21289196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori I., Imai Y., Kohsaka S., Kimura Y. Upregulated expression of Iba1 molecules in the central nervous system of mice in response to neurovirulent influenza A virus infection. Microbiol. Immunol. 2000;44:729&#x2013;735. doi: 10.1111/j.1348-0421.2000.tb02556.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1348-0421.2000.tb02556.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11021405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori I., Kimura Y. Neuropathogenesis of influenza virus infection in mice. Microbes Infect. 2001;3:475&#x2013;479. doi: 10.1016/S1286-4579(01)01403-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1286-4579(01)01403-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11377209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin C. M., V&#xe9;zina-Im L. A., Ivers H., Micoulaud-Franchi J. A., Philip P., Lamy M., Savard Prevalent, incident, and persistent insomnia in a population-based cohort tested before (2018) and during the first-wave of COVID-19 pandemic (2020) Sleep. 2022;45:zsab258. doi: 10.1093/sleep/zsab258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/zsab258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8574325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34698868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motta C. S., Torices S., da Rosa B. G., Marcos A. C., Alvarez-Rosa L., Siqueira M., Moreno-Rodriguez T., Matos A. D. R., Caetano B. C., Martins J., Gladulich L., Loiola E., Bagshaw O. R. M., Stuart J. A., Siqueira M. M., Stipursky J., Toborek M., Adesse D. Human brain microvascular endothelial cells exposure to SARS-CoV-2 leads to inflammatory activation through NF-&#x3ba;B non-canonical pathway and mitochondrial remodeling. Viruses. 2023;15:745. doi: 10.3390/v15030745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v15030745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10056985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36992454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller A. C., Daya S. Acyclovir inhibits rat liver tryptophan-2,3-dioxygenase and induces a concomitant rise in brain serotonin and 5-hydroxyindole acetic acid levels. Metab. Brain Dis. 2008;23:351&#x2013;360. doi: 10.1007/s11011-008-9095-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11011-008-9095-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18665439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudra Rakshasa-Loots A., Bakewell N., Sharp D. J., Gissl&#xe9;n M., Zetterberg H., Alagaratnam J., Wit F., Kootstra N. A., Winston A., Reiss P., Sabin C. A., Vera J. H. Biomarkers of central and peripheral inflammation mediate the association between HIV and depressive symptoms. Transl. Psychiatry. 2023;13:190. doi: 10.1038/s41398-023-02489-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-023-02489-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10244452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37280232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munshi S., Alarbi A. M., Zheng H., Kuplicki R., Burrows K., Figueroa-Hall L. K., Victor T. A., Aupperle R. L., Khalsa S. S., Paulus M. P., Teague T. K., Savitz J. Increased expression of ER stress, inflammasome activation, and mitochondrial biogenesis-related genes in peripheral blood mononuclear cells in major depressive disorder. Mol. Psychiatry. 2024 doi: 10.1038/s41380-024-02695-2. doi: 10.1038/s41380-024-02695-2 [Online ahead of print]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-024-02695-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39174649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakhaee H., Zangiabadian M., Bayati R., Rahmanian M., Ghaffari Jolfayi A., Rakhshanderou S. The effect of antidepressants on the severity of COVID-19 in hospitalized patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0267423. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0267423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0267423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9536564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36201406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nami M., Mehrabi S., Kamali A. M., Kazemiha M., Carvalho J., Derman S., Lakey-Betia J., Vasquez V., Kosagisharaf R. A new hypothesis on anxiety, sleep insufficiency, and viral infections; reciprocal links to consider in today's "World vs. COVID-19" endeavors. Front. Psychiatry. 2020;11:585893. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2020.585893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2020.585893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7674554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33250794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narasimhappa K., Mamtani H., Jain K., Holla V. V., Ganjekar S., Manjunath N., Kulanthaivelu K., Desai G. Unmasking bipolarity in recurrent depressive disorder following herpes simplex virus triggered n-methyl-D-aspartate encephalitis. Bipolar. Disord. 2024;26:192&#x2013;195. doi: 10.1111/bdi.13393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bdi.13393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37973382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nataf S. An alteration of the dopamine synthetic pathway is possibly involved in the pathophysiology of COVID-19. J. Med. Virol. 2020;92:1743&#x2013;1744. doi: 10.1002/jmv.25826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.25826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32246784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nataf S., Pays L. Molecular insights into SARS-CoV2-induced alterations of the gut/brain axis. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2021;22:10440. doi: 10.3390/ijms221910440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms221910440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8508788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34638785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosadini M., Mohammad S. S., Corazza F., Ruga E. M., Kothur K., Perilongo G., Frigo A. C., Toldo I., Dale R. C., Sartori S. Herpes simplex virus-induced anti-N-methyl-d-aspartate receptor encephalitis: a systematic literature review with analysis of 43 cases. Dev. Med. Child Neurol. 2017;59:796&#x2013;805. doi: 10.1111/dmcn.13448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dmcn.13448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28439890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohkawara T., Katsuyama T., Ida-Eto M., Narita N., Narita M. Maternal viral infection during pregnancy impairs development of fetal serotonergic neurons. Brain Dev. 2015;37:88&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1016/j.braindev.2014.03.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.braindev.2014.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24780604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oriolo G., Blanco-Hinojo L., Navines R., Mari&#xf1;o Z., Mart&#xed;n-Hern&#xe1;ndez D., Cavero M., Gimenez D., Caso J., Capuron L., Forns X., Pujol J., Sola R., Martin-Santos R. Association of chronic inflammation and perceived stress with abnormal functional connectivity in brain areas involved with interoception in hepatitis C patients. Brain Behav. Immun. 2019;80:204&#x2013;218. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2019.03.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2019.03.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30872094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osei D., Baumgart-Vogt E., Ahlemeyer B., Herden C. Tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1; receptor 1 mediates Borna disease virus 1-induced changes in peroxisomal and mitochondrial dynamics in neurons. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2024;25:1849. doi: 10.3390/ijms25031849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms25031849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10855776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38339126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pender M. P. Hypothesis: bipolar disorder is an Epstein-Barr virus-driven chronic autoimmune disease - implications for immunotherapy. Clin. Transl. Immunology. 2020;9:e1116. doi: 10.1002/cti2.1116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cti2.1116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7133420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32257210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peron J. P. S. Direct and indirect impact of SARS-CoV-2 on the brain. Hum. Genet. 2023;142:1317&#x2013;1326. doi: 10.1007/s00439-023-02549-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00439-023-02549-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10066989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37004544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philippi C. L., Reyna L., Nedderman L., Chan P., Samboju V., Chang K., Phanuphak N., Ratnaratorn N., Hellmuth J., Benjapornpong K., Dumrongpisutikul N., Pothisri M., Robb M. L., Ananworanich J., Spudich S., Valcour V., Paul R. Resting-state neural signatures of depressive symptoms in acute HIV. J. Neurovirol. 2020;26:226&#x2013;240. doi: 10.1007/s13365-020-00826-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13365-020-00826-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7261250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31989446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips A. C., Carroll D., Khan N., Moss P. Cytomegalovirus is associated with depression and anxiety in older adults. Brain Behav. Immun. 2008;22:52&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2007.06.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2007.06.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17703915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piacentini R., Li Puma D. D., Ripoli C., Marcocci M. E., De Chiara G., Garaci E., Palamara A. T., Grassi C. Herpes Simplex Virus type-1 infection induces synaptic dysfunction in cultured cortical neurons via GSK-3 activation and intraneuronal amyloid-&#x3b2; protein accumulation. Sci. Rep. 2015;5:15444. doi: 10.1038/srep15444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep15444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4614347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26487282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto E. F., Andrade C. Interferon-related depression: a primer on mechanisms, treatment, and prevention of a common clinical problem. Curr. Neuropharmacol. 2016;14:743&#x2013;748. doi: 10.2174/1570159X14666160106155129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570159X14666160106155129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5050402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26733280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pratt L. A., Xu F., McQuillan G. M., Robitz R. The association of depression, risky sexual behaviours and herpes simplex virus type 2 in adults in NHANES, 2005-2008. Sex. Transm. Infect. 2012;88:40&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1136/sextrans-2011-050138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/sextrans-2011-050138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22057015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premachandra B. N., Kabir M. A., Williams I. K. Low T3 syndrome in psychiatric depression. J. Endocrinol. Invest. 2006;29:568&#x2013;572. doi: 10.1007/BF03344150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03344150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16840838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj L., Kannapadi N. V., Briggs J., Seal S. M., Battaglini D., Fanning J., Suen J., Robba C., Fraser J., Cho S. M. Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: a meta-analysis. J. Neurol. Sci. 2022;434:120162. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2022.120162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2022.120162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8798975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pr&#xfc;ss H., Finke C., H&#xf6;ltje M., Hofmann J., Klingbeil C., Probst C., Borowski K., Ahnert-Hilger G., Harms L., Schwab J. M., Ploner C. J., Komorowski L., Stoecker W., Dalmau J., Wandinger K. P. N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor antibodies in herpes simplex encephalitis. Ann. Neurol. 2012;72:902&#x2013;911. doi: 10.1002/ana.23689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.23689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3725636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23280840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rademacher L., Lasselin J., Karshikoff B., Hundt J. E., Engler H., Lange T. Editorial: the different faces of sickness. Front. Psychiatry. 2021;12:735337. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2021.735337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2021.735337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8438174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34531771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raison C. L. The promise and limitations of anti-inflammatory agents for the treatment of major depressive disorder. Curr. Top. Behav. Neurosci. 2017;31:287&#x2013;302. doi: 10.1007/7854_2016_26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/7854_2016_26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27278642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranger T. A., Clift A. K., Patone M., Coupland C. A. C., Hatch R., Thomas K., Watkinson P., Hippisley-Cox J. Preexisting neuropsychiatric conditions and associated risk of severe COVID-19 infection and other acute respiratory infections. JAMA Psychiatry. 2023;80:57&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.3614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.3614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9647578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36350602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rappeneau V., Wilmes L., Touma C. Molecular correlates of mitochondrial dysfunctions in major depression: evidence from clinical and rodent studies. Mol. Cell. Neurosci. 2020;109:103555. doi: 10.1016/j.mcn.2020.103555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mcn.2020.103555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32979495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmi Y., Shokati A., Hatamkhani S., Farnamian Y., Naderi R., Jalali L. Assessment of the relationship between the dopaminergic pathway and severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection, with related neuropathological features, and potential therapeutic approaches in COVID-19 infection. Rev. Med. Virol. 2024;34:e2506. doi: 10.1002/rmv.2506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rmv.2506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38282395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei S., Ahmadi S., Rahmati J., Hosseinifard H., Dehnad A., Aryankhesal A., Shabaninejad H., Ghasemyani S., Alihosseini S., Bragazzi N. L., Raoofi S., Kiaee Z. M., Ghashghaee A. Global prevalence of depression in HIV/AIDS: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Support. Palliat. Care. 2019;9:404&#x2013;412. doi: 10.1136/bmjspcare-2019-001952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjspcare-2019-001952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31537580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro D. E., Roncalho A. L., Glaser T., Ulrich H., Wegener G., Joca S. P2X7 receptor signaling in stress and depression. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2019;20:2778. doi: 10.3390/ijms20112778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms20112778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6600521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31174279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Righetto I., Gasparotto M., Casalino L., Vacca M., Filippini F. Exogenous players in mitochondria-related CNS disorders: viral pathogens and unbalanced microbiota in the gut-brain axis. Biomolecules. 2023;13:169. doi: 10.3390/biom13010169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom13010169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9855674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36671555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ru W., Tang S. J. HIV-associated synaptic degeneration. Mol. Brain. 2017;10:40. doi: 10.1186/s13041-017-0321-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13041-017-0321-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5576336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28851400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rus C. P., de Vries B. E. K., de Vries I. E. J., Nutma I., Kooij J. J. S. Treatment of 95 post-Covid patients with SSRIs. Sci. Rep. 2023;13:18599. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-45072-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-45072-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10622561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37919310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadasivan S., Zanin M., O'Brien K., Schultz-Cherry S., Smeyne R. J. Induction of microglia activation after infection with the non-neurotropic A/CA/04/2009 H1N1 influenza virus. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0124047. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0124047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0124047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4393251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25861024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagar V., Atluri V. S., Pilakka-Kanthikeel S., Nair M. Magnetic nanotherapeutics for dysregulated synaptic plasticity during neuroAIDS and drug abuse. Mol. Brain. 2016;9:57. doi: 10.1186/s13041-016-0236-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13041-016-0236-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4878083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27216740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saloner R., Cherner M., Grelotti D. J., Paolillo E. W., Moore D. J., Heaton R. K., Letendre S. L., Kumar A., Grant I., Ellis R. J. Lower CSF homovanillic acid relates to higher burden of neuroinflammation and depression in people with HIV disease. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;90:353&#x2013;363. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2020.09.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2020.09.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7544671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32966871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardar A. M., Czudek C., Reynolds G. P. Dopamine deficits in the brain: the neurochemical basis of parkinsonian symptoms in AIDS. Neuroreport. 1996;7:910&#x2013;912. doi: 10.1097/00001756-199603220-00015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00001756-199603220-00015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8724671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar S., Kemper J., Sarkar R., Brants L., Friebe A., Spengler U., Schl&#xe4;pfer T., Reimer J., Buggisch P., Ockenga J., Link R., Rentrop M., Weidenbach H., Fromm G., Lieb K., Baumert T. F., Discher T., Zeuzem S., Berg T., Schaefer M. Influence of gender on cytokine induced depression and treatment: Gender aspects of IFN-&#x3b1;-induced depression. J. Affect. Disord. 2021;292:766&#x2013;772. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2021.05.087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2021.05.087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34171555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schou T. M., Joca S., Wegener G., Bay-Richter C. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19 - a systematic review. Brain Behav. Immun. 2021;97:328&#x2013;348. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2021.07.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2021.07.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8363196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seegal R. F., McFarland D. J. Stereotaxic microinjection of HSV-1 selectively decreases striatal dopamine concentrations in mice. Brain Res. 1988;445:234&#x2013;240. doi: 10.1016/0006-8993(88)91184-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0006-8993(88)91184-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3285959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah S., Sinharay S., Matsuda K., Schreiber-Stainthorp W., Muthusamy S., Lee D., Wakim P., Hirsch V., Nath A., Di Mascio M., Hammoud D. A. Potential mechanism for HIV-associated depression: upregulation of serotonin transporters in SIV-infected macaques detected by 11C-DASB PET. Front. Psychiatry. 2019;10:362. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6543249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31178771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen A. A., Kaplan G. G., Sharkey K. A., Lethebe B. C., Swain M. G. Impact of depression and antidepressant use on clinical outcomes of hepatitis B and C: a population-based study. Hepatol. Commun. 2023;7:e0062. doi: 10.1097/HC9.0000000000000062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HC9.0000000000000062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9931033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36790342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Wang Q., Song R., Kong Y., Zhang Z. Non-coding RNAs in depression: promising diagnostic and therapeutic biomarkers. EBioMedicine. 2021;71:103569. doi: 10.1016/j.ebiom.2021.103569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2021.103569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8441067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34521053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Yang C., Xu L., He Y., Wang H., Cao J., Wen M., Chen W., Wu B., Chen S., Chen H. CD4+ T cell count, sleep, depression, and anxiety in people living with HIV: a growth curve mixture modeling. J. Assoc. Nurses AIDS Care. 2020;31:535&#x2013;543. doi: 10.1097/JNC.0000000000000112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JNC.0000000000000112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7497416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31335460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirayama Y., Iwata M., Miyano K., Hirose Y., Oda Y., Fujita Y., Hashimoto K. Infusions of beta-hydroxybutyrate, an endogenous NLRP3 inflammasome inhibitor, produce antidepressant-like effects on learned helplessness rats through BDNF-TrkB signaling and AMPA receptor activation, and strengthen learning ability. Brain Res. 2023;1821:148567. doi: 10.1016/j.brainres.2023.148567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2023.148567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37689333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu C., Jaffe A. E., Sabunciyan S., Ji H., Astemborski J., Sun J., Bakulski K. M., Mehta S. H., Kirk G. D., Maher B. S. Epigenome-wide association scan identifies methylation sites associated with HIV infection. Epigenomics. 2020;12:1917&#x2013;1927. doi: 10.2217/epi-2020-0123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/epi-2020-0123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7788472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33232214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva C., Fonseca C., Ferreira R., Weidner A., Morgado B., Lopes M. J., Moritz S., Jelinek L., Schneider B. C., Pinho L. G. Depression in older adults during the COVID-19 pandemic: a systematic review. J. Am. Geriatr. Soc. 2023;71:2308&#x2013;2325. doi: 10.1111/jgs.18363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgs.18363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37029710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvers J. M., Aksenov M. Y., Aksenova M. V., Beckley J., Olton P., Mactutus C. F., Booze R. M. Dopaminergic marker proteins in the substantia nigra of human immunodeficiency virus type 1-infected brains. J. Neurovirol. 2006;12:140&#x2013;145. doi: 10.1080/13550280600724319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13550280600724319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3710452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16798675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim&#xf5;es J. L. B., Galvan A. C. L., da Silva E. L. M., Ign&#xe1;cio Z. M., Bagatini M. D. Therapeutic potential of the purinergic system in major depressive disorder associated with COVID-19. Cell. Mol. Neurobiol. 2023;43:621&#x2013;637. doi: 10.1007/s10571-022-01215-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10571-022-01215-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8960668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35348977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simanek A. M., Cheng C., Yolken R., Uddin M., Galea S., Aiello A. E. Herpesviruses, inflammatory markers and incident depression in a longitudinal study of Detroit residents. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2014;50:139&#x2013;148. doi: 10.1016/j.psyneuen.2014.08.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psyneuen.2014.08.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4306348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25218654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simanek A. M., Zheng C., Yolken R., Haan M., Aiello A. E. A longitudinal study of the association between persistent pathogens and incident depression among older U.S. Latinos. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 2019;74:634&#x2013;641. doi: 10.1093/gerona/gly172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/gly172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6477673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30084944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinanan K., Hillary I. Post-influenzal depression. Br. J. Psychiatry. 1981;138:131&#x2013;133. doi: 10.1192/bjp.138.2.131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.138.2.131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7260492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slavuljica I., Kve&#x161;tak D., Huszthy P. C., Kosmac K., Britt W. J., Jonji&#x107; S. Immunobiology of congenital cytomegalovirus infection of the central nervous system-the murine cytomegalovirus model. Cell. Mol. Immunol. 2015;12:180&#x2013;191. doi: 10.1038/cmi.2014.51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/cmi.2014.51</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4654296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25042632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sol&#xed;s N., Salazar L., Hasbun R. Anti-NMDA receptor antibody encephalitis with concomitant detection of Varicella zoster virus. J. Clin. Virol. 2016;83:26&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1016/j.jcv.2016.08.292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcv.2016.08.292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27529308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souery D. Treatment-resistant depression: where to find hope? World Psychiatry. 2023;22:422&#x2013;423. doi: 10.1002/wps.21141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.21141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10503916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37713550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souery D., Papakostas G. I., Trivedi M. H. Treatment-resistant depression. J. Clin. Psychiatry. 2006;67(Suppl 6):16&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16848672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starace F., Bartoli L., Aloisi M. S., Antinori A., Narciso P., Ippolito G., Ravasio L., Moioli M. C., Vangi D., Gennero L., Coronado O. V., Giacometti A., Nappa S., Perulli M. L., Montesarchio V., La Gala A., Ricci F., Cristiano L., De Marco M., Izzo C., Pezzotti P., D'Arminio Monforte A. Cognitive and affective disorders associated to HIV infection in the HAART era: findings from the NeuroICONA study. Cognitive impairment and depression in HIV/AIDS. The NeuroICONA study. Acta Psychiatr. Scand. 2002;106:20&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1034/j.1600-0447.2002.02289.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1034/j.1600-0447.2002.02289.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12100344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefano G. B., B&#xfc;ttiker P., Weissenberger S., Ptacek R., Wang F., Esch T., Bilfinger T. V., Raboch J., Kream R. M. Biomedical perspectives of acute and chronic neurological and neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19. Curr. Neuropharmacol. 2022;20:1229&#x2013;1240. doi: 10.2174/1570159X20666211223130228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570159X20666211223130228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9886822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xfc;t B. B. Epigenetic Regulation Mechanisms in Viral Infections: a Special Focus on COVID-19. IntechOpen; London: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strauss M., O'Donovan B., Ma Y., Xiao Z., Lin S., Bardo M. T., Ortinski P. I., McLaughlin J. P., Zhu J. [(3)H]dopamine uptake through the dopamine and norepinephrine transporters is decreased in the prefrontal cortex of transgenic mice expressing HIV-1 transactivator of transcription protein. J. Pharmacol. Exp. Ther. 2020;374:241&#x2013;251. doi: 10.1124/jpet.120.266023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1124/jpet.120.266023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7366287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32461322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su K. P., Lai H. C., Peng C. Y., Su W. P., Chang J. P., Pariante C. M. Interferon-alpha-induced depression: comparisons between early- and late-onset subgroups and with patients with major depressive disorder. Brain Behav. Immun. 2019;80:512&#x2013;518. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2019.04.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2019.04.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31059806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su W. J., Li J. M., Zhang T., Cao Z. Y., Hu T., Zhong S. Y., Xu Z. Y., Gong H., Jiang C. L. Microglial NLRP3 inflammasome activation mediates diabetes-induced depression-like behavior via triggering neuroinflammation. Prog. Neuropsychopharmacol. Biol. Psychiatry. 2023;126:110796. doi: 10.1016/j.pnpbp.2023.110796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pnpbp.2023.110796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37209992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surendran H., Kumar S., Narasimhaiah S., Ananthamurthy A., Varghese P. S., D'Souza G. A., Medigeshi G., Pal R. SARS-CoV-2 infection of human-induced pluripotent stem cells-derived lung lineage cells evokes inflammatory and chemosensory responses by targeting mitochondrial pathways. J. Cell. Physiol. 2022;237:2913&#x2013;2928. doi: 10.1002/jcp.30755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcp.30755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9088312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35460571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabano S., Tassi L., Cannone M. G., Brescia G., Gaudioso G., Ferrara M., Colapietro P., Fontana L., Miozzo M. R., Croci G. A., Seia M., Piuma C., Solbiati M., Tobaldini E., Ferrero S., Montano N., Costantino G., Buoli M. Mental health and the effects on methylation of stress-related genes in front-line versus other health care professionals during the second wave of COVID-19 pandemic: an Italian pilot study. Eur. Arch. Psychiatry Clin. Neurosci. 2023;273:347&#x2013;356. doi: 10.1007/s00406-022-01472-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00406-022-01472-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9399986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36001138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M., Sillett R., Zhu L., Mendel J., Camplisson I., Dercon Q., Harrison P. J. Neurological and psychiatric risk trajectories after SARS-CoV-2 infection: an analysis of 2-year retrospective cohort studies including 1 284 437 patients. Lancet Psychiatry. 2022;9:815&#x2013;827. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(22)00260-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(22)00260-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9385200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35987197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng C. F., Wu H. C., Hsieh W. C., Tsai H. W., Su I. J. Activation of ATP citrate lyase by mTOR signal induces disturbed lipid metabolism in hepatitis B virus pre-S2 mutant tumorigenesis. J. Virol. 2015;89:605&#x2013;614. doi: 10.1128/JVI.02363-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.02363-14</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4301163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25339766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teodorof-Diedrich C., Spector S. A. Human immunodeficiency virus type 1 gp120 and Tat induce mitochondrial fragmentation and incomplete mitophagy in human neurons. J. Virol. 2018;92:e00993. doi: 10.1128/JVI.00993-18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.00993-18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6206485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30158296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tereshin A. E., Kiryanova V. V., Reshetnik D. A. Correction of mitochondrial dysfunction in the complex rehabilitation of COVID-19 patients. Neurosci. Behav. Physiol. 2022;52:511&#x2013;514. doi: 10.1007/s11055-022-01269-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11055-022-01269-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9304544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35892008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfaw G., Ayano G., Awoke T., Assefa D., Birhanu Z., Miheretie G., Abebe G. Prevalence and correlates of depression and anxiety among patients with HIV on-follow up at Alert Hospital, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. BMC Psychiatry. 2016;16:368. doi: 10.1186/s12888-016-1037-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-016-1037-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5094082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27806711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thai M., Graham N. A., Braas D., Nehil M., Komisopoulou E., Kurdistani S. K., McCormick F., Graeber T. G., Christofk H. R. Adenovirus E4ORF1-induced MYC activation promotes host cell anabolic glucose metabolism and virus replication. Cell Metab. 2014;19:694&#x2013;701. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2014.03.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2014.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4294542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24703700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaker S. K., Ch'ng J., Christofk H. R. Viral hijacking of cellular metabolism. BMC Biol. 2019;17:59. doi: 10.1186/s12915-019-0678-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12915-019-0678-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6637495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31319842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas P., Bhatia T., Gauba D., Wood J., Long C., Prasad K., Dickerson F. B., Gur R. E., Gur R. C., Yolken R. H., Nimgaonkar V. L., Deshpande S. N. Exposure to herpes simplex virus, type 1 and reduced cognitive function. J. Psychiatr. Res. 2013;47:1680&#x2013;1685. doi: 10.1016/j.jpsychires.2013.07.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2013.07.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3809147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23920011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai M. K., Sytwu H. K., Hsieh T. Y., Chien W. C., Lai C. H., Chen H. C. Association between depression or anxiety and the risk of hepatitis B flares: a nationwide population-based cohort study. J. Inflamm. Res. 2022;15:2983&#x2013;2993. doi: 10.2147/JIR.S355314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JIR.S355314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9126231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35615105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsegay L., Ayano G. The prevalence of suicidal ideation and attempt among young people with HIV/AIDS: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychiatr. Q. 2020;91:1291&#x2013;1304. doi: 10.1007/s11126-020-09851-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11126-020-09851-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32960412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsutsumi T., Matsuda M., Aizaki H., Moriya K., Miyoshi H., Fujie H., Shintani Y., Yotsuyanagi H., Miyamura T., Suzuki T., Koike K. Proteomics analysis of mitochondrial proteins reveals overexpression of a mitochondrial protein chaperon, prohibitin, in cells expressing hepatitis C virus core protein. Hepatology. 2009;50:378&#x2013;386. doi: 10.1002/hep.22998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.22998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19591124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turk M. C., Bakker C. J., Spencer S. M., Lofgren S. M. Systematic review of sex differences in the relationship between hormones and depression in HIV. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2022;138:105665. doi: 10.1016/j.psyneuen.2022.105665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psyneuen.2022.105665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8883851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35063687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udina M., Hidalgo D., Navin&#xe9;s R., Forns X., Sol&#xe0; R., Farr&#xe9; M., Capuron L., Vieta E., Mart&#xed;n-Santos R. Prophylactic antidepressant treatment of interferon-induced depression in chronic hepatitis C: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J. Clin. Psychiatry. 2014;75:e1113&#x2013;e1121. doi: 10.4088/JCP.13r08800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.13r08800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25373120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vadaq N., Zhang Y., Meeder E., Van, de Wijer L., Gasem M. H., Joosten L. A., Netea M. G., de Mast Q., Matzaraki V., Schellekens A., Fu J., van der Ven A. J. Microbiome-related indole and serotonin metabolites are linked to inflammation and psychiatric symptoms in people living with HIV. Int. J. Tryptophan Res. 2022;15:11786469221126888. doi: 10.1177/11786469221126888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/11786469221126888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9520182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36187510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vastag L., Koyuncu E., Grady S. L., Shenk T. E., Rabinowitz J. D. Divergent effects of human cytomegalovirus and herpes simplex virus-1 on cellular metabolism. PLoS Pathog. 2011;7:e1002124. doi: 10.1371/journal.ppat.1002124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1002124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3136460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21779165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vindegaard N., Petersen L. V., Lyng-Rasmussen B. I., Dalsgaard S., Benros M. E. Infectious mononucleosis as a risk factor for depression: a nationwide cohort study. Brain Behav. Immun. 2021;94:259&#x2013;265. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2021.01.035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2021.01.035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33571632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollmer-Conna U., Fazou C., Cameron B., Li H., Brennan C., Luck L., Davenport T., Wakefield D., Hickie I., Lloyd A. Production of pro-inflammatory cytokines correlates with the symptoms of acute sickness behaviour in humans. Psychol. Med. 2004;34:1289&#x2013;1297. doi: 10.1017/S0033291704001953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291704001953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15697055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volmer R., Prat C. M., Le Masson G., Garenne A., Gonzalez-Dunia D. Borna disease virus infection impairs synaptic plasticity. J. Virol. 2007;81:8833&#x2013;8837. doi: 10.1128/JVI.00612-07.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.00612-07</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1951342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17553893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vreeman R. C., McCoy B. M., Lee S. Mental health challenges among adolescents living with HIV. J. Int. AIDS Soc. 2017;20:21497. doi: 10.7448/IAS.20.4.21497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7448/IAS.20.4.21497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5577712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28530045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C., Cui C., Xie X., Chen B., Feng L., Jiang P. Calcitriol attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced neuroinflammation and depressive-like behaviors by suppressing the P2X7R/NLRP3/caspase-1 pathway. Psychopharmacology (Berl.) 2024a;241:1329&#x2013;1343. doi: 10.1007/s00213-024-06565-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-024-06565-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38411637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., He Y., Sun Z., Ren S., Liu M., Wang G., Yang J. Microglia in depression: an overview of microglia in the pathogenesis and treatment of depression. J. Neuroinflammation. 2022;19:132. doi: 10.1186/s12974-022-02492-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12974-022-02492-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9168645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35668399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Zhang H., Liu R., Han P., Yang Q., Cheng C., Chen Y., Rong Z., Su C., Li F., Wei G., Zhao M., Yang L. Influenza A virus PB1-F2 induces affective disorder by interfering synaptic plasticity in hippocampal dentate gyrus. Mol. Neurobiol. 2024b;61:8293&#x2013;8306. doi: 10.1007/s12035-024-04107-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-024-04107-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38488981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Zhang L., Lei Y., Liu X., Zhou X., Liu Y., Wang M., Yang L., Zhang L., Fan S., Xie P. Meta-analysis of infectious agents and depression. Sci. Rep. 2014;4:4530. doi: 10.1038/srep04530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep04530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5380112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24681753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Cai X., Ma Y., Yang Y., Pan C. W., Zhu X., Ke C. Metabolomics on depression: a comparison of clinical and animal research. J. Affect. Disord. 2024c;349:559&#x2013;568. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2024.01.053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2024.01.053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38211744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson A. M., Prasad K. M., Klei L., Wood J. A., Yolken R. H., Gur R. C., Bradford L. D., Calkins M. E., Richard J., Edwards N., Savage R. M., Allen T. B., Kwentus J., McEvoy J. P., Santos A. B., Wiener H. W., Go R. C., Perry R. T., Nasrallah H. A., Gur R. E., Devlin B., Nimgaonkar V. L. Persistent infection with neurotropic herpes viruses and cognitive impairment. Psychol. Med. 2013;43:1023&#x2013;1031. doi: 10.1017/S003329171200195X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S003329171200195X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22975221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson Z., Tang S. J. Aberrant synaptic pruning in CNS diseases: a critical player in HIV-associated neurological dysfunction? Cells. 2022;11:1943. doi: 10.3390/cells11121943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells11121943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9222069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35741071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams D. W., Li Y., Dastgheyb R., Fitzgerald K. C., Maki P. M., Spence A. B., Gustafson D. R., Milam J., Sharma A., Adimora A. A., Ofotokun I., Fischl M. A., Konkle-Parker D., Weber K. M., Xu Y., Rubin L. H. Associations between antiretroviral drugs on depressive symptomatology in homogenous subgroups of women with HIV. J. Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2021;16:181&#x2013;194. doi: 10.1007/s11481-019-09899-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11481-019-09899-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7430262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31933016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winter C., Reutiman T. J., Folsom T. D., Sohr R., Wolf R. J., Juckel G., Fatemi S. H. Dopamine and serotonin levels following prenatal viral infection in mouse--implications for psychiatric disorders such as schizophrenia and autism. Eur. Neuropsychopharmacol. 2008;18:712&#x2013;716. doi: 10.1016/j.euroneuro.2008.06.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2008.06.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2714699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18693086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong A. C., Devason A. S., Umana I. C., Cox T. O., Dohnalov&#xe1; L., Litichevskiy L., Perla J., Lundgren P., Etwebi Z., Izzo L. T., Kim J., Tetlak M., Descamps H. C., Park S. L., Wisser S., McKnight A. D., Pardy R. D., Kim J., Blank N., Patel S., Thum K., Mason S., Beltra J. C., Michieletto M. F., Ngiow S. F., Miller B. M., Liou M. J., Madhu B., Dmitrieva-Posocco O., Huber A. S., Hewins P., Petucci C., Chu C. P., Baraniecki-Zwil G., Giron L. B., Baxter A. E., Greenplate A. R., Kearns C., Montone K., Litzky L. A., Feldman M., Henao-Mejia J., Striepen B., Ramage H., Jurado K. A., Wellen K. E., O'Doherty U., Abdel-Mohsen M., Landay A. L., Keshavarzian A., Henrich T. J., Deeks S. G., Peluso M. J., Meyer N. J., Wherry E. J., Abramoff B. A., Cherry S., Thaiss C. A., Levy M. Serotonin reduction in post-acute sequelae of viral infection. Cell. 2023;186:4851&#x2013;4867.e20. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2023.09.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2023.09.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11227373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37848036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wouk J., Rechenchoski D. Z., Rodrigues B. C. D., Ribelato E. V., Faccin-Galhardi L. C. Viral infections and their relationship to neurological disorders. Arch. Virol. 2021;166:733&#x2013;753. doi: 10.1007/s00705-021-04959-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00705-021-04959-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7838016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33502593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu M. K., Huang T. L., Huang K. W., Huang Y. L., Hung Y. Y. Association between toll-like receptor 4 expression and symptoms of major depressive disorder. Neuropsychiatr. Dis. Treat. 2015;11:1853&#x2013;1857. doi: 10.2147/NDT.S88430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S88430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4525784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26257523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanashi H., Akabame S., Miyata J., Honda Y., Nonaka F., Shimizu Y., Nakamichi S., Kawashiri S. Y., Tamai M., Arima K., Kawakami A., Aoyagi K., Maeda T. Association between Epstein-Barr virus serological reactivation and psychological distress: a cross-sectional study of Japanese community-dwelling older adults. Aging (Albany N.Y.) 2022;14:8258&#x2013;8269. doi: 10.18632/aging.204345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.204345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9648801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36279393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao Y., Gu J., Li M., Li G., Ai J., Zhao L. WHSC1L1-mediated epigenetic downregulation of VMP1 participates in herpes simplex virus 1 infection-induced mitophagy impairment and neuroinflammation. Mol. Immunol. 2023;163:63&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1016/j.molimm.2023.09.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molimm.2023.09.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37748280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaow C. Y. L., Hong A. S. Y., Chong N. Z., Chong R. I. H., Mai A. S., Tan E. K. Risk of Parkinson's disease in hepatitis B and C populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J. Neural Transm. (Vienna) 2023;131:609&#x2013;616. doi: 10.1007/s00702-023-02705-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-023-02705-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37899363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye J., Wen Y., Chu X., Li P., Cheng B., Cheng S., Liu L., Zhang L., Ma M., Qi X., Liang C., Kafle O. P., Jia Y., Wu C., Wang S., Wang X., Ning Y., Zhang F. Association between herpes simplex virus 1 exposure and the risk of depression in UK Biobank. Clin. Transl. Med. 2020;10:e108. doi: 10.1002/ctm2.108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ctm2.108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7403656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32564518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yirmiya R., Rimmerman N., Reshef R. Depression as a microglial disease. Trends Neurosci. 2015;38:637&#x2013;658. doi: 10.1016/j.tins.2015.08.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tins.2015.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26442697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong S. J., Yong M. H., Teoh S. L., Soga T., Parhar I., Chew J., Lim W. L. The hippocampal vulnerability to herpes simplex virus type I infection: relevance to Alzheimer's disease and memory impairment. Front. Cell. Neurosci. 2021;15:695738. doi: 10.3389/fncel.2021.695738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fncel.2021.695738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8414573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34483839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu K., Qiu C. L., Yang G. B., Zong C. M., Xing H., Shao Y., Wei Q., Qin C. Alteration of serotonin transporter messenger RNA level in the peripheral blood mononuclear cells from simian/human immunodeficiency virus infected Chinese rhesus macaques (Macaca mulatta) Brain Behav. Immun. 2010;24:298&#x2013;305. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2009.10.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2009.10.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19854262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X., Wang S., Wu W., Chang H., Shan P., Yang L., Zhang W., Wang X. Exploring new mechanism of depression from the effects of virus on nerve cells. Cells. 2023;12:1767. doi: 10.3390/cells12131767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells12131767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10340315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37443801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan M., Yang B., Rothschild G., Mann J. J., Sanford L. D., Tang X., Huang C., Wang C., Zhang W. Epigenetic regulation in major depression and other stress-related disorders: molecular mechanisms, clinical relevance and therapeutic potential. Signal Transduct. Target. Ther. 2023;8:309. doi: 10.1038/s41392-023-01519-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41392-023-01519-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10465587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37644009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaletel I., Filipovi&#x107; D., Pu&#x161;ka&#x161; N. Hippocampal BDNF in physiological conditions and social isolation. Rev. Neurosci. 2017;28:675&#x2013;692. doi: 10.1515/revneuro-2016-0072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/revneuro-2016-0072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28593903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zareifopoulos N., Lagadinou M., Karela A., Kyriakopoulou O., Velissaris D. Neuropsychiatric effects of antiviral drugs. Cureus. 2020a;12:e9536. doi: 10.7759/cureus.9536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.9536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7465925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32905132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zareifopoulos N., Lagadinou M., Karela A., Pouliasi F., Economou I., Tsigkou A., Velissaris D. Efavirenz as a psychotropic drug. Eur. Rev. Med. Pharmacol. Sci. 2020b;24:10729&#x2013;10735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33155233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X. H., Shi J. Y., Zhan C., Zhang L., Chen H. J. Intrinsic brain abnormalities in patients with hepatitis C virus infection with cognitive impairment: a preliminary resting-state fMRI study. Biomed Res. Int. 2020;2020:1693043. doi: 10.1155/2020/1693043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/1693043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7655249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33204682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng H., Ford B. N., Kuplicki R., Burrows K., Hunt P. W., Bodurka J., Kent Teague T., Irwin M. R., Yolken R. H., Paulus M. P., Savitz J. Association between cytomegalovirus infection, reduced gray matter volume, and resting-state functional hypoconnectivity in major depressive disorder: a replication and extension. Transl. Psychiatry. 2021;11:464. doi: 10.1038/s41398-021-01558-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-021-01558-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8423754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34493708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng H., Savitz J. Effect of cytomegalovirus infection on the central nervous system: implications for psychiatric disorders. Curr. Top. Behav. Neurosci. 2023;61:215&#x2013;241. doi: 10.1007/7854_2022_361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/7854_2022_361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35505056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng H., Webster M. J., Weickert C. S., Beasley C. L., Paulus M. P., Yolken R. H., Savitz J. Cytomegalovirus antibodies are associated with mood disorders, suicide, markers of neuroinflammation, and microglia activation in postmortem brain samples. Mol. Psychiatry. 2023;28:5282&#x2013;5292. doi: 10.1038/s41380-023-02162-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-023-02162-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10756933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37391529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X. X., Zhang C. F., Li L. Q., Ye J. R., Ren S. Y., Zhang Z., He X., Chu S. F., Chen N. H. Improvement of astrocytic gap junction involves the anti-depressive effect of celecoxib through inhibition of NF-&#x3ba;B. Brain Res. Bull. 2024;207:110871. doi: 10.1016/j.brainresbull.2024.110871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainresbull.2024.110871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38211740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S., Liu Y., Xue B., Yuan P. Low-dose Esketamine suppresses NLRP3-mediated apoptotic and pyroptotic cell death in microglial cells to ameliorate LPS-induced depression via ablating GSK-3&#x3b2;. Behav. Brain Res. 2024;459:114782. doi: 10.1016/j.bbr.2023.114782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbr.2023.114782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38029844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu C., Zhang T., Li Q., Chen X., Wang K. Depression and anxiety during the COVID-19 pandemic: epidemiology, mechanism, and treatment. Neurosci. Bull. 2023;39:675&#x2013;684. doi: 10.1007/s12264-022-00970-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12264-022-00970-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9685018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36411394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J., Mactutus C. F., Wallace D. R., Booze R. M. HIV-1 Tat protein-induced rapid and reversible decrease in [3H]dopamine uptake: dissociation of [3H]dopamine uptake and [3H]2beta-carbomethoxy-3-beta-(4-fluorophenyl)tropane (WIN 35,428) binding in rat striatal synaptosomes. J. Pharmacol. Exp. Ther. 2009;329:1071&#x2013;1083. doi: 10.1124/jpet.108.150144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1124/jpet.108.150144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2683782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19325033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J., Yuan Y., Midde N. M., Gomez A. M., Sun W. L., Quizon P. M., Zhan C. G. HIV-1 transgenic rats display an increase in [(3)H]dopamine uptake in the prefrontal cortex and striatum. J. Neurovirol. 2016;22:282&#x2013;292. doi: 10.1007/s13365-015-0391-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13365-015-0391-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5330645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26501780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu P., Chen Y. J., Hao J. H., Ge J. F., Huang K., Tao R. X., Jiang X. M., Tao F. B. Maternal depressive symptoms related to Epstein-Barr virus reactivation in late pregnancy. Sci. Rep. 2013;3:3096. doi: 10.1038/srep03096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep03096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3813936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24172862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zignego A. L., Cozzi A., Carpenedo R., Giannini C., Rosselli M., Biagioli T., Aldinucci A., Laffi G., Moroni F. HCV patients, psychopathology and tryptophan metabolism: analysis of the effects of pegylated interferon plus ribavirin treatment. Dig. Liver Dis. 2007;39(Suppl 1):S107&#x2013;S111. doi: 10.1016/S1590-8658(07)80021-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1590-8658(07)80021-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17936210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z&#xfc;rcher S. J., Banzer C., Adamus C., Lehmann A. I., Richter D., Kerksieck P. Post-viral mental health sequelae in infected persons associated with COVID-19 and previous epidemics and pandemics: Systematic review and meta-analysis of prevalence estimates. J. Infect. Public Health. 2022;15:599&#x2013;608. doi: 10.1016/j.jiph.2022.04.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiph.2022.04.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9020842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35490117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>