<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39142509</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0631</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>354</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Life sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Life Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A practical framework for Long COVID treatment in primary care.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>122977</StartPage><MedlinePgn>122977</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.lfs.2024.122977</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0024-3205(24)00567-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long COVID is a complex, multisystem illness with a poorly understood pathophysiology, absence of specific diagnostic tests or criteria, or evidence-based treatments. With over 200 identified symptoms and approximately 10% of COVID-19 cases resulting in Long COVID, it is a challenge to provide comprehensive treatment at a scale commensurate with the illness burden. The diverse manifestations of Long COVID, encompassing numerous medical specialties, typically place primary care providers (PCPs) at the forefront of management, navigating an evolving landscape of research and lack of evidence-based guidelines. This paper presents a pragmatic, structured framework for Long COVID management in primary care, integrating current knowledge and best practices. The approach is individualized, addressing Long COVID's broad symptomatology through a four-step framework. The first step focuses on energy management strategies, emphasizing the prevention of post-exertional malaise, a cardinal feature of Long COVID. The second step, intentional rehabilitation, employs carefully titrated multidisciplinary modalities to address physical, cognitive, and emotional domains. The third step utilizes symptomatic management through both pharmacological and non-pharmacological interventions, targeting debilitating symptoms like fatigue, insomnia, and chronic pain. The fourth step outlines an approach to trialing experimental, targeted therapies that may impact Long COVID's underlying pathophysiology. These treatments, while experimental and lacking quality evidence in Long COVID, may be available off-label on an individual basis following a thorough risk-benefit discussion. This stepwise framework can equip PCPs to effectively address the most common and disabling symptoms of Long COVID, individualize care, and remain attuned to the evolving scientific understanding of the condition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brode</LastName><ForeName>W Michael</ForeName><Initials>WM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Dell Medical School, The University of Texas at Austin, 1601 Trinity St, Austin, TX 78712, USA. Electronic address: william.brode@austin.utexas.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Melamed</LastName><ForeName>Esther</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Dell Medical School, The University of Texas at Austin, 1601 Trinity St, Austin, TX 78712, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Life Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0375521</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0024-3205</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011320" MajorTopicYN="Y">Primary Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary care</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare there is no funding source for this manuscript, although the Post-COVID-19 at Program at UT Health Austin has been supported by the Ting Tsung and Wei Fong Chao Foundation. W. Michael Brode: has received honoraria for Long COVID presentations and served as a strategic advisor for Roon Healthcare. Esther Melamed: has received NIH funding for COVID-19 research and received honorarium from the National Center for Health Research for Long COVID presentation, has served on advisory boards of Genentech, Horizon, Teva and Viela Bio.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39142509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2024.122977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0024-3205(24)00567-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>