<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38389299</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2865</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physiotherapy research international : the journal for researchers and clinicians in physical therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Physiother Res Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The pulmonary rehabilitation effect on long covid-19 syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2077</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2077</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/pri.2077</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This systematic review and meta-analysis aims to evaluate the efficacy of pulmonary rehabilitation (PR) in improving dyspnea, fatigue, physical activity, quality of life, anxiety and depression in patients with Long COVID-19 (LC). The impact of PR on LC and a comparison of face-to-face and telerehabilitation approaches was explored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This systematic review and meta-analysis followed PRISMA guidelines and was registered in PROSPERO. A literature search included PubMed, Web of Science, and Cochrane Library until January 2023. No language filters were applied. Randomized controlled trials, non-randomized controlled trials, and observational studies were included. The risk of bias was assessed using appropriate tools. Descriptive analysis and meta-analysis were performed. Forest plots presented results. Statistical analyses were conducted using the Metafor Package in R v.3.4.2.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS/FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This systematic review and meta-analysis included 16 studies on PR in LC patients. A total of 1027 adults were included. The studies varied in design, with seven observational studies, three quasi-experimental studies, and six randomized controlled trials. Dyspnea, physical function, quality of life, psychological state, and fatigue were assessed as outcomes. The review found that pulmonary rehabilitation had a significant positive effect on dyspnea, physical function, quality of life (both global and physical domain), anxiety, and depression. However, the effect on fatigue was not significant. Heterogeneity was observed in some analyses, and publication bias was found in certain outcomes. Age and study design were identified as potential moderators. Both face-to-face and telerehabilitation interventions improved the studied outcomes, with only differences in the physical domain of quality of life favoring the face-to-face group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS ON PHYSIOTHERAPY PRACTICE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">PR improved dyspnea, physical function, quality of life, and psychological state in LC patients, but not fatigue. Face-to-face and telerehabilitation have similar effects, except for physical quality of life.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors. Physiotherapy Research International published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;nez-Pozas</LastName><ForeName>Oliver</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4804-550X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Occupational Therapy, Rehabilitation and Physical Medicine, Escuela Internacional de Doctorado, Universidad Rey Juan Carlos, Alcorc&#xf3;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Research Group on Musculoskeletal Disorders, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Universidad Europea de Madrid, Villaviciosa de Od&#xf3;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy and Orofacial Pain Working Group, Sociedad Espa&#xf1;ola de Disfunci&#xf3;n Craneomandibular y Dolor Orofacial (SEDCYDO), Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mel&#xe9;ndez-Oliva</LastName><ForeName>Erika</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9366-1614</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Research Group on Musculoskeletal Disorders, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Universidad Europea de Madrid, Villaviciosa de Od&#xf3;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy and Orofacial Pain Working Group, Sociedad Espa&#xf1;ola de Disfunci&#xf3;n Craneomandibular y Dolor Orofacial (SEDCYDO), Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Faculty of Sport Sciences, European University of Valencia, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rolando</LastName><ForeName>Lidia Mart&#xed;nez</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7140-1520</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rey Juan Carlos University Hospital of M&#xf3;stoles, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rico</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9; Antonio Quesada</ForeName><Initials>JAQ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6947-7531</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Miguel Hern&#xe1;ndez University, San Juan de Alicante, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Network for Research on Chronicity, Primary Care, and Health Promotion (RICAPPS), Tenerife, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Corbellini</LastName><ForeName>Camilo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7476-9301</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, LUNEX International University of Health, Exercise and Sports, Differdange, Luxembourg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Luxembourg Health &amp; Sport Sciences Research Institute A.S.B.L., Differdange, Luxembourg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xe1;nchez Romero</LastName><ForeName>Eleuterio A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0254-6501</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Research Group on Musculoskeletal Disorders, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Universidad Europea de Madrid, Villaviciosa de Od&#xf3;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy and Orofacial Pain Working Group, Sociedad Espa&#xf1;ola de Disfunci&#xf3;n Craneomandibular y Dolor Orofacial (SEDCYDO), Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Universidad Europea de Madrid, Villaviciosa de Od&#xf3;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Award for Best Research Project in post-COVID-19 sequelae</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>the Ilustre Colegio Profesional de Fisioterapeutas de la Comunidad de Madrid, December 2021</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Physiother Res Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9612022</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1358-2267</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004417" MajorTopicYN="N">Dyspnea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dyspnea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telerehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38389299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pri.2077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Acevedo, M., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Carnero, &#xc1;, S&#xe1;nchez-Romero, J., S&#xe1;nchez-Romero, E. A., Villafa&#xf1;e, J. H., &amp; Barrag&#xe1;n Carballar, C. (2022). Effects of a multicomponent exercise program on improving frailty in post-COVID-19 older adults after intensive care units: A single-group retrospective cohort study. Biology, 11(7), 1084. https://doi.org/10.3390/BIOLOGY11071084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, I., Mustafaoglu, R., Yeldan, I., Yasaci, Z., &amp; Erhan, B. (2022). Effect of pulmonary rehabilitation approaches on dyspnea, exercise capacity, fatigue, lung functions, and quality of life in patients with COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, 103(10), 2051-2062. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmr.2022.06.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albu, S., Rivas Zozaya, N., Murillo, N., Garc&#xed;a-Molina, A., Figueroa Chac&#xf3;n, C. A., &amp; Kumru, H. (2022). Multidisciplinary outpatient rehabilitation of physical and neurological sequelae and persistent symptoms of covid-19: A prospective, observational cohort study. Disability &amp; Rehabilitation, 44(22), 6833-6840. https://doi.org/10.1080/09638288.2021.1977398</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AL-Mhanna, S. B., Mohamed, M., Noor, N. M., Afolabi, H. A., Irekeola, A. A., Bello, K. E., Aldhahi, M. I., &amp; Wan Ghazali, W. S. (2022). Effectiveness of pulmonary rehabilitation among COVID-19 patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Health Care, 10(11), 2130. https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare10112130</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballesteros Reviriego, G., Planas Pascual, B., Rojo Ruiz, A., S&#xe1;nchez Romero, E. A., Corbelini, C., &amp; Villafa&#xf1;e, J. H. (2020). Spanish experience of pulmonary rehabilitation efficacy for patients affected by the novel SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19): A case report. Topics in Geriatric Rehabilitation, 36(4), 212-214. https://doi.org/10.1097/TGR.0000000000000283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker-Davies, R. M., O&#x2019;Sullivan, O., Senaratne, K. P. P., Baker, P., Cranley, M., Dharm-Datta, S., Ellis, H., Goodall, D., Gough, M., Lewis, S., Norman, J., Papadopoulou, T., Roscoe, D., Sherwood, D., Turner, P., Walker, T., Mistlin, A., Phillip, R., Nicol, A. M., &amp; Bahadur, S. (2020). The Stanford Hall consensus statement for post-COVID-19 rehabilitation. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 54(16), 949-959. https://doi.org/10.1136/BJSPORTS-2020-102596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barton, C. J., Webster, K. E., &amp; Menz, H. B. (2008). Evaluation of the scope and quality of systematic reviews on nonpharmacological conservative treatment for patellofemoral pain syndrome. Journal of Orthopaedic &amp; Sports Physical Therapy, 38(9), 529-541. https://doi.org/10.2519/JOSPT.2008.2861</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker, B. J. (1988). Synthesizing standardized mean-change measures. British Journal of Mathematical and Statistical Psychology, 41(2), 257-278. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.2044-8317.1988.tb00901.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belsley, D., Kuh, K., &amp; Welsch, R. (1980). Regression diagnostics: Identifying influential data and sources of collinearity. Wiley. Published online January 1. https://doi.org/10.1002/JAE.3950040108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolton, C. E., Bevan-Smith, E. F., Blakey, J. D., Crowe, P., Elkin, S. L., Garrod, R., Greening, N. J., Heslop, K., Hull, J. H., Man, W. D. C., Morgan, M. D., Proud, D., Roberts, C. M., Sewell, L., Singh, S. J., Walker, P. P., &amp; Walmsley, S. (2013). British thoracic society guideline on pulmonary rehabilitation in adults: Accredited by NICE. Thorax, 68(Suppl 2), ii1-ii30. https://doi.org/10.1136/THORAXJNL-2013-203808</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouteleux, B., Henrot, P., Ernst, R., Grassion, L., Raherison-Semjen, C., Beaufils, F., Zysman, M., &amp; Delorme, M. (2021). Respiratory rehabilitation for covid-19 related persistent dyspnoea: A one-year experience. Respiratory Medicine, 189, 189. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rmed.2021.106648</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cahalan, R. M., Meade, C., &amp; Mockler, S. (2022). SingStrong-A singing and breathing retraining intervention for respiratory and other common symptoms of long covid: A pilot study. Canadian Journal of Respiratory Therapy, 58, 20-27. https://doi.org/10.29390/cjrt-2021-074</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo-Paniagua, J., D&#xed;az-Arribas, M. J., Valera-Calero, J. A., Gallardo-Vidal, M. I., Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as, C., L&#xf3;pez-de-Uralde-Villanueva, I., del Corral, T., &amp; Plaza-Manzano, G. (2022). A tele-health primary care rehabilitation program improves self-perceived exertion in COVID-19 survivors experiencing post-COVID fatigue and dyspnea: A quasi-experimental study. PLoS One, 17(8 August), e0271802. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0271802</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanares-Zapatero, D., Chalon, P., Kohn, L., Dauvrin, M., Detollenaere, J., Maertens de Noordhout, C., Primus-de Jong, C., Cleemput, I., &amp; Van den Heede, K. (2022). Pathophysiology and mechanism of long COVID: A comprehensive review. Annals of Medicine, 54(1), 1473-1487. https://doi.org/10.1080/07853890.2022.2076901</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochran, W. G. (1954). The combination of estimates from different experiments. Biometrics, 10(1), 101. https://doi.org/10.2307/3001666</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compagno, S., Palermi, S., Pescatore, V., Brugin, E., Sarto, M., Marin, R., Calzavara, V., Nizzetto, M., Scevola, M., Aloi, A., Biffi, A., Zanella, C., Carretta, G., Gallo, S., &amp; Giada, F. (2022). Physical and psychological reconditioning in long COVID syndrome: Results of an out-of-hospital exercise and psychological - based rehabilitation program. IJC Heart and Vasculature, 41, 101080. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijcha.2022.101080</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbellini, C., Rossino, E., Massaccesi, R., Battaglino, A., Pedersini, P., &amp; Villafa&#xf1;e, J. H. (2022). Improvements in perimeter thoracic mobility on patients with COPD after pulmonary rehabilitation: A case series. Electronic Journal of General Medicine, 19(3), em361. https://doi.org/10.29333/EJGM/11671</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbellini, C., Tavella, S., Gugliotta, E., Zampese, S., Romero, E. A. S., &amp; Villafane, J. (2021). Hypercapnia and functional improvements during pulmonary rehabilitation. European Respiratory Journal, 58(suppl 65), PA1827. https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.CONGRESS-2021.PA1827</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbellini, C., Villafane, J., Gugliotta, E., Tavella, S., Zampese, S., Pessina, P., Monti, R., Carnuccio, C., Sanchez Romero, E. A., &amp; Meroni, R. (2021). Late Breaking Abstract - pulmonary rehabilitation in post - covid subjects with moderate lung restriction, a case series. European Respiratory Journal, 58(suppl 65), PA2003. https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.CONGRESS-2021.PA2003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox, N. S., Dal Corso, S., Hansen, H., McDonald, C. F., Hill, C. J., Zanaboni, P., Alison, J. A., O'Halloran, P., Macdonald, H., &amp; Holland, A. E. (2021). Telerehabilitation for chronic respiratory disease. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, 2021(1). https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD013040.PUB2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, H. E., McCorkell, L., Vogel, J. M., &amp; Topol, E. J. (2023). Long COVID: Major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nature Reviews Microbiology, 21(3), 133-146. https://doi.org/10.1038/S41579-022-00846-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daynes, E., Gerlis, C., Chaplin, E., Gardiner, N., &amp; Singh, S. J. (2021). Early experiences of rehabilitation for individuals post-COVID to improve fatigue, breathlessness exercise capacity and cognition - a cohort study. Chronic Respiratory Disease, 18, 147997312110156. https://doi.org/10.1177/14799731211015691</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Corral, T., Garrido, R. F., Plaza-Manzano, G., Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as, C., Navarro-Santana, M., &amp; L&#xf3;pez-de-Uralde-Villanueva, I. (2022). Home-based respiratory muscle training on quality of life and exercise tolerance in long-term post-COVID-19: Randomized controlled trial. Annals of Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine, 101709. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rehab.2022.101709</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowman, L., Hill, C. J., &amp; Holland, A. E. (2014). Pulmonary rehabilitation for interstitial lung disease. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, 2014(10). https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD006322.PUB3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger, M., Smith, G. D., Schneider, M., &amp; Minder, C. (1997). Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ, 315(7109), 629-634. https://doi.org/10.1136/BMJ.315.7109.629</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estebanez-P&#xe9;rez, M. J., Pastora-Bernal, J. M., &amp; Mart&#xed;n-Valero, R. (2022). The effectiveness of a four-week digital Physiotherapy intervention to improve functional capacity and adherence to intervention in patients with long COVID-19. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19(15), 9566. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19159566</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiore, E., Corbellini, C., Acucella, L., Gargano, S., S&#xe1;nchez Romero, E., Cotella, D., &amp; Villafa&#xf1;e, J. H. (2022). Dolor musculoesquel&#xe9;tico en supervivientes del COVID-19 tras la hospitalizaci&#xf3;n: Una breve revision (musculoskeletal pain related to COVID-19 survivors after hospitalization: A short review). RETOS, 44, 789-795. https://doi.org/10.47197/RETOS.V44I0.90361</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flannery, T., Brady-Sawant, H., Tarrant, R., Davison, J., Shardha, J., Halpin, S., Sivan, M., &amp; Ross, D. (2022). A mixed-methods evaluation of a virtual rehabilitation program for self-management in post-COVID-19 syndrome (long COVID). International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19(19), 12680. https://doi.org/10.3390/IJERPH191912680</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fugazzaro, S., Contri, A., Esseroukh, O., Kaleci, S., Croci, S., Massari, M., Facciolongo, N. C., Besutti, G., Iori, M., Salvarani, C., &amp; Costi, S. (2022). Rehabilitation interventions for post-acute COVID-19 syndrome: A systematic review. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19(9), 5185. https://doi.org/10.3390/IJERPH19095185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giacalone, A., Marin, L., Febbi, M., Franchi, T., &amp; Tovani-Palone, M. R. (2022). eHealth, telehealth, and telemedicine in the management of the COVID-19 pandemic and beyond: Lessons learned and future perspectives. World Journal Clinical Cases, 10(8), 2363-2368. https://doi.org/10.12998/WJCC.V10.I8.2363</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groenveld, T., Achttien, R., Smits, M., de Vries, M., van Heerde, R., Staal, B., &amp; van Goor, H. (2022). Feasibility of virtual reality exercises at home for post-COVID-19 condition: Cohort study. JMIR Rehabilitation Assistive Technology, 9(3), e36836. https://doi.org/10.2196/36836</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardy, R. J., &amp; Thompson, S. G. (1996). A Likelihood approach to meta-analysis with random effects. Statistics in Medicine, 15(6), 619-629. https://doi.org/10.1002/(sici)1097-0258(19960330)15:6&lt;619::aid-sim188&gt;3.0.co;2-a</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasenoehrl, T., Palma, S., Huber, D. F. X., Kastl, S., Steiner, M., Jordakieva, G., &amp; Crevenna, R. (2022). Post-COVID: Effects of physical exercise on functional status and work ability in health care personnel. Disability &amp; Rehabilitation, 45(18), 2872-2878. https://doi.org/10.1080/09638288.2022.2111467</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, J. P. T., &amp; Thompson, S. G. (2002). Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Statistics in Medicine, 21(11), 1539-1558. https://doi.org/10.1002/SIM.1186</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, J., Fan, Y., Zhao, K., Yang, C., Zhao, Z., Chen, Y., Yang, J., Wang, T., &amp; Qu, Y. (2022). Do patients with and survivors of COVID-19 benefit from telerehabilitation? A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Frontiers in Public Health, 10. https://doi.org/10.3389/FPUBH.2022.954754</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n, A., Buend&#xed;a-Romero, &#xc1;., Mart&#xed;nez-Cava, A., Franco-L&#xf3;pez, F., S&#xe1;nchez-Alcaraz, B. J., Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez, J., &amp; Pallar&#xe9;s, J. G. (2023). Effects of a concurrent training, respiratory muscle exercise, and self-management recommendations on recovery from post-COVID-19 conditions: The RECOVE trial. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 134(1), 95-104. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00489.2022. PMID: 36476156; PMCID: PMC9829459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n, A., Franco-L&#xf3;pez, F., Buend&#xed;a-Romero, &#xc1;., Mart&#xed;nez-Cava, A., S&#xe1;nchez-Agar, J. A., S&#xe1;nchez-Alcaraz Mart&#xed;nez, B. J., Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez, J., &amp; Pallar&#xe9;s, J. G. (2022). Rehabilitation for post-COVID-19 condition through a supervised exercise intervention: A randomized controlled trial. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 32(12), 1791-1801. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.14240. PMID: 36111386; PMCID: PMC9538729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n, A., Pallar&#xe9;s, J. G., Buend&#xed;a-Romero, &#xc1;., Mart&#xed;nez-Cava, A., Franco-L&#xf3;pez, F., S&#xe1;nchez-Alcaraz Mart&#xed;nez, B. J., Bernal-Morel, E., &amp; Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez, J. (2021). Post-covid-19 syndrome and the potential benefits of exercise. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 18(10), 5329. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18105329</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd-Evans, P. H. I., Baldwin, M. M., Daynes, E., Hong, A., Mills, G., Goddard, A. C. N., Chaplin, E., Gardiner, N., &amp; Singh, S. J. (2022). Early experiences of the Your COVID Recovery &#xae; digital programme for individuals with long COVID. BMJ Open Respiratory Research, 9(1), e001237. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjresp-2022-001237</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNarry, M. A., Berg, R. M. G., Shelley, J., Hudson, J., Saynor, Z. L., Duckers, J., Lewis, K., Davies, G. A., &amp; Mackintosh, K. A. (2022). Inspiratory muscle training enhances recovery post-COVID-19: A randomised controlled trial. European Respiratory Journal, 60(4), 2103101. https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.03101-2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menges, D., Ballouz, T., Anagnostopoulos, A., Aschmann, H. E., Domenghino, A., Fehr, J. S., &amp; Puhan, M. A. (2021). Burden of post-COVID-19 syndrome and implications for healthcare service planning: A population-based cohort study. PLoS One, 16(7), e0254523. https://doi.org/10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0254523</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micah, A. E., Cogswell, I. E., Cunningham, B., Ezoe, S., Harle, A. C., Maddison, E. R., McCracken, D., Nomura, S., Simpson, K. E., Stutzman, H. N., Tsakalos, G., Wallace, L. E., Zhao, Y., Zende, R. R., Abbafati, C., Abdelmasseh, M., Abedi, A., Abegaz, K. H., Abhilash, E. S., &amp; Dieleman, J. L. (2021). Tracking development assistance for health and for COVID-19: A review of development assistance, government, out-of-pocket, and other private spending on health for 204 countries and territories, 1990-2050. Lancet, 398(10308), 1317-1343. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(21)01258-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nici, L., Donner, C., Wouters, E., Zuwallack, R., Ambrosino, N., Bourbeau, J., Carone, M., Celli, B., Engelen, M., Fahy, B., Garvey, C., Goldstein, R., Gosselink, R., Lareau, S., MacIntyre, N., Maltais, F., Morgan, M., O'Donnell, D., Prefault, C., &amp; Troosters, T. (2006). American thoracic society/European respiratory society statement on pulmonary rehabilitation. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, 173(12), 1390-1413. https://doi.org/10.1164/RCCM.200508-1211ST</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nopp, S., Moik, F., Klok, F. A., Gattinger, D., Petrovic, M., Vonbank, K., Koczulla, A. R., Ay, C., &amp; Zwick, R. H. (2022). Outpatient pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with long COVID improves exercise capacity, functional status, dyspnea, fatigue, and quality of life. Respiration, 101(6), 593-601. https://doi.org/10.1159/000522118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okan, F., Okan, S., &amp; Duran Y&#xfc;cesoy, F. (2022). Evaluating the efficiency of breathing exercises via telemedicine in post-covid-19 patients: Randomized controlled study. Clinical Nursing Research, 31(5), 771-781. https://doi.org/10.1177/10547738221097241</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pancera, S., Bianchi, L. N. C., Porta, R., Galeri, S., Carrozza, M. C., &amp; Villafa&#xf1;e, J. H. (2021). Feasibility of subacute rehabilitation for mechanically ventilated patients with COVID-19 disease: A retrospective case series. International Journal of Rehabilitation Research, 44(1), 77-81. https://doi.org/10.1097/MRR.0000000000000450</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersini, P., Corbellini, C., &amp; Villafa&#xf1;e, J. H. (2020). Italian physical therapists&#x2019; response to the novel COVID-19 emergency. Physical Therapy, 100(7), 1049-1051. https://doi.org/10.1093/PTJ/PZAA060</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philip, K. E. J., Owles, H., McVey, S., Pagnuco, T., Bruce, K., Brunjes, H., Banya, W., Mollica, J., Lound, A., Zumpe, S., Abrahams, A. M., Padmanaban, V., Hardy, T. H., Lewis, A., Lalvani, A., Elkin, S., &amp; Hopkinson, N. S. (2022). An online breathing and wellbeing programme (ENO breathe) for people with persistent symptoms following COVID-19: A parallel-group, single-blind, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Respiratory Medicine, 10(9), 851-862. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-2600(22)00125-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj, L., Kannapadi, N. V., Briggs, J., Seal, S. M., Battaglini, D., Fanning, J., Suen, J., Robba, C., Fraser, J., &amp; Cho, S. M. (2022). Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: A meta-analysis. Journal of Neurological Sciences, 434, 434. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.JNS.2022.120162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puhan, M. A., Gimeno-Santos, E., Cates, C. J., &amp; Troosters, T. (2016). Pulmonary rehabilitation following exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, 12(12). https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD005305.PUB4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pw, S. (2002). Popping the (PICO) question in research and evidence-based practice. Applied Nursing Research, 15(3), 197-198. https://doi.org/10.1053/APNR.2002.34181</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reina-Guti&#xe9;rrez, S., Torres-Costoso, A., Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no, V., N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez de Arenas-Arroyo, S., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Rodr&#xed;guez, R., &amp; Pozuelo-Carrascosa, D. P. (2021). Effectiveness of pulmonary rehabilitation in interstitial lung disease, including coronavirus diseases: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, 102(10), 1989-1997.e3. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.APMR.2021.03.035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinert, G., M&#xfc;ller, D., Wagner, P., Mart&#xed;nez-Pozas, O., Cuenca-Z&#xe1;ldivar, J. N., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Carnero, J., S&#xe1;nchez Romero, E. A., &amp; Corbellini, C. (2022). Pulmonary rehabilitation in SARS-CoV-2: A systematic review and meta-analysis of post-acute patients. Diagnostics, 12(12), 3032. https://doi.org/10.3390/DIAGNOSTICS12123032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinn, R., Gao, L., Schoeneich, S. M., Dahmen, A., Anand Kumar, V., Becker, P., &amp; Lippke, S. (2023). Digital interventions for treating post-COVID or long-COVID symptoms: Scoping review. Journal of Medical Internet Research, 25, 25. https://doi.org/10.2196/45711</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolando, M., Garc&#xed;a, C., Arg&#xfc;ello, S., Sanz Arg&#xfc;ello, A., Villanueva Rosa, M., &amp; S&#xe1;nchez Romero, E. A. (2022). Multicomponent exercise program to improve the immediate sequelae of COVID-19: A prospective study with a Brief report of 2-year follow-up. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19(19), 12396. https://doi.org/10.3390/IJERPH191912396</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero, E. A. S., Rolando, L. M., &amp; Villafa&#xf1;e, J. H. (2022). Impact of lockdown on patients with fibromyalgia. Electronic Journal of General Medicine, 19(3), em366. https://doi.org/10.29333/EJGM/11798</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez Romero, E. A., Alonso P&#xe9;rez, J. L., Vinuesa Su&#xe1;rez, I., Corbellini, C., &amp; Villafa&#xf1;e, J. H. (2022). Spanish experience on the efficacy of airways clearance techniques in SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19) at intensive care unit: An editorial and case report. SAGE Open Medicine Case Report, 10, 2050313X2211125. https://doi.org/10.1177/2050313X221112507</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez Romero, E. A., Fern&#xe1;ndez Carnero, J., Luis Alonso P&#xe9;rez, J., Mart&#xed;nez Rolando, L., &amp; Villafa&#xf1;e, J. H. (2022). Addressing post-COVID-19 musculoskeletal symptoms through telemedicine: A study protocol. F1000 Research, 11, 898. https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.122843.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos, C. D., Rodrigues, F., Caneiras, C., &amp; B&#xe1;rbara, C. (2022). From inception to implementation: Strategies for setting up pulmonary telerehabilitation. Frontiers in Rehabilitation Sciences, 3. https://doi.org/10.3389/FRESC.2022.830115</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scurati, R., Papini, N., Giussani, P., Alberti, G., &amp; Tringali, C. (2022). The challenge of long COVID-19 management: From disease molecular hallmarks to the proposal of exercise as therapy. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 23(20), 12311. https://doi.org/10.3390/IJMS232012311</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shea, B. J., Reeves, B. C., Wells, G., Thuku, M., Hamel, C., Moran, J., Moher, D., Tugwell, P., Welch, V., Kristjansson, E., &amp; Henry, D. A. (2017). Amstar 2: A critical appraisal tool for systematic reviews that include randomised or non-randomised studies of healthcare interventions, or both. BMJ, 358, j4008. https://doi.org/10.1136/BMJ.J4008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehy, L. M. (2020). Considerations for postacute rehabilitation for survivors of COVID-19. JMIR Public Health Surveill, 6(2), e19462. https://doi.org/10.2196/19462</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spruit, M. A. (2014). Pulmonary rehabilitation. European Respiratory Review, 23(131), 55-63. https://doi.org/10.1183/09059180.00008013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spruit, M. A., Singh, S. J., Garvey, C., ZuWallack, R., Nici, L., Rochester, C., Hill, K., Holland, A. E., Lareau, S. C., Man, W. D. C., Pitta, F., Sewell, L., Raskin, J., Bourbeau, J., Crouch, R., Franssen, F. M. E., Casaburi, R., Vercoulen, J. H., Vogiatzis, I., &amp; Wouters, E. F. M. (2013). An official American thoracic society/European respiratory society statement: Key concepts and advances in pulmonary rehabilitation. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, 188(8), e13-e64. https://doi.org/10.1164/RCCM.201309-1634ST</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne, J. A., Hern&#xe1;n, M. A., Reeves, B. C., Savovi&#x107;, J., Berkman, N. D., Viswanathan, M., Henry, D., Altman, D. G., Ansari, M. T., Boutron, I., Carpenter, J. R., Chan, A. W., Churchill, R., Deeks, J. J., Hr&#xf3;bjartsson, A., Kirkham, J., J&#xfc;ni, P., Loke, Y. K., Pigott, T. D., &amp; Higgins, J. P. (2016). ROBINS-I: A tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. BMJ, 355, i4919. https://doi.org/10.1136/BMJ.I4919</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne, J. A. C., Savovi&#x107;, J., Page, M. J., Elbers, R. G., Blencowe, N. S., Boutron, I., Cates, C. J., Cheng, H. Y., Corbett, M. S., Eldridge, S. M., Emberson, J. R., Hern&#xe1;n, M. A., Hopewell, S., Hr&#xf3;bjartsson, A., Junqueira, D. R., J&#xfc;ni, P., Kirkham, J. J., Lasserson, T., Li, T., &amp; Higgins, J. P. T. (2019). RoB 2: A revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ, 366, l4898. https://doi.org/10.1136/BMJ.L4898</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suso-Mart&#xed;, L., La Touche, R., Herranz-G&#xf3;mez, A., Angulo-D&#xed;az-Parre&#xf1;o, S., Paris-Alemany, A., &amp; Cuenca-Mart&#xed;nez, F. (2021). Effectiveness of telerehabilitation in physical therapist practice: An umbrella and mapping review with meta-meta-analysis. Physical Therapy, 101(5). https://doi.org/10.1093/PTJ/PZAB075</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamburlani, M., Cuscito, R., Servadio, A., &amp; Galeoto, G. (2023). Effectiveness of respiratory rehabilitation in COVID-19&#x2019;s post-acute phase: A systematic review. Health Care, 11(8), 1071. https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare11081071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira, A. G. da S., Pinto, A. C. P. N., Garcia, B. M. S. P., Eid, R. A. C., M&#xf3;l, C. G., &amp; Nawa, R. K. (2022). Telerehabilitation improves physical function and reduces dyspnoea in people with COVID-19 and post-COVID-19 conditions: A systematic review. Journal of Physiotherapy, 68(2), 90-98. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.JPHYS.2022.03.011</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>