<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38088231</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-0496</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>59</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pediatric pulmonology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Pulmonol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lung function assessment in children with Long-Covid syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>472</StartPage><EndPage>481</EndPage><MedlinePgn>472-481</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ppul.26779</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">A significant percentage of patients who survived the Coronavirus Infection Disease 2019 (COVID-19) showed persistent general and respiratory symptoms even months after recovery. This condition, called Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19 or Long-Covid syndrome (LCS), has been described also in children with positive history for severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection. Little is known about the pathophysiologic mechanisms underlying this syndrome. The aim of this study was to investigate any difference between children with LCS and asymptomatic peers with previous COVID-19 in terms of lung function and lung ultrasound (LUS) patterns. Secondly, we tested associations between lung function abnormalities and LUS findings with Long-Covid.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We carried out a prospective, descriptive, observational study including 58 children aged 5-17 years: 28 with LCS compared to 30 asymptomatic children with previous COVID-19. We collected demographic data, history of asthma, allergy or smoke exposure, and acute COVID-19 symptoms. After a median period of 4.5 months (1%-95% range 2-21) since the infection, lung function was assessed by spirometry, body plethysmography, diffusion lung capacity for carbon monoxide (DLCO). Airways inflammation was investigated by fractional exhaled nitric oxide (FeNO). LUS was performed independently by two experienced clinicians.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We found that children with LCS were older than controls (mean (SD) 12 (4.1) vs. 9.7 (2.6); p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.04). Children with LCS complained more frequently fatigue (46.4%), cough (17.9%), exercise intolerance (14.3%) and dyspnea (14.3%). Lung function was normal and similar between the two groups. The frequency of LUS abnormalities was similar between the two groups (43.3% children with LCS vs. 56.7% controls; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.436). Children with LCS showed lower FeNO values (log difference -0.30 (CI 95% -0.50, -0.10)), but no association of LCS with a lower lung function and abnormal LUS findings was found.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">LCS seems to be more frequent in older age children. Lung functional and structural abnormalities were not different between children with LCS and asymptomatic subjects with previous COVID-19. In addition, children with LCS showed lower FeNO values than controls, suggesting its potential role as a marker in LCS. However, further and larger studies are needed to confirm our findings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Pediatric Pulmonology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sansone</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7158-7617</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Pediatric Allergy and Pulmonology Unit, University of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Filippo</LastName><ForeName>Paola</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Pediatric Allergy and Pulmonology Unit, University of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Russo</LastName><ForeName>Daniele</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Pediatric Allergy and Pulmonology Unit, University of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sgrazzutti</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Pediatric Allergy and Pulmonology Unit, University of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Pillo</LastName><ForeName>Sabrina</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Pediatric Allergy and Pulmonology Unit, University of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiarelli</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Pediatric Allergy and Pulmonology Unit, University of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Attanasi</LastName><ForeName>Marina</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6513-3160</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Pediatric Allergy and Pulmonology Unit, University of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>None</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Pulmonol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8510590</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1099-0496</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lung function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lung ultrasound</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric Long-Covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute sequelae of COVID-19</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38088231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ppul.26779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Worldometer CC. Worldometer. Published 2020. Accessed December 10, 2022. https://www.worldometers.info/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard. Accessed December 10, 2022. https://covid19.who.int/?mapFilter=;deaths</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Coronavirus disease (COVID-19): Schools. Accessed December 10, 2022. https://www.who.int/news-room/questions-and-answers/item/coronavirus-disease-covid-19-schools</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Academy of Pediatrics. Children and COVID-19: State-Level Data Report (aap.org). Accessed December 10, 2022. https://www.aap.org/en/pages/2019-novel-coronavirus-covid-19-infections/children-and-covid-19-state-level-data-report/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nature Med. 2021;27(4):601-615. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludvigsson JF. Case report and systematic review suggest that children may experience similar long-term effects to adults after clinical COVID-19. Acta Paediatr (Stockholm). 2021;110(3):914-921. doi:10.1111/apa.15673</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Say D, Crawford N, McNab S, Wurzel D, Steer A, Tosif S. Post-acute COVID-19 outcomes in children with mild and asymptomatic disease. Lancet Child &#xa0;Adoles&#xa0;Health. 2021;5(6):e22-e23. doi:10.1016/S2352-4642(21)00124-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Munblit D, De Rose C, et al. Preliminary evidence on long COVID in children. Acta Paediatr (Stockholm). 2021;110(7):2208-2211. doi:10.1111/apa.15870</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings G, Monaghan A, Xue F, Mockler D, Romero-Ortu&#xf1;o R. A systematic review of persistent symptoms and residual abnormal functioning following acute covid-19: ongoing symptomatic phase vs. post-covid-19 syndrome. J Clin Med. 2021;10(24):5913. doi:10.3390/jcm10245913</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dole&#x17e;alov&#xe1; K, Tukov&#xe1; J, Pohunek P. The respiratory consequences of COVID-19 lasted for a median of 4 months in a cohort of children aged 2-18 years of age. Acta Paediatr (Stockholm). 2022;111(6):1201-1206. doi:10.1111/apa.16297</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leftin Dobkin SC, Collaco JM, McGrath-Morrow SA. Protracted respiratory findings in children post-SARS-CoV-2 infection. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2021;56(12):3682-3687. doi:10.1002/ppul.25671</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sansone F, Attanasi M, Di Filippo P, Sferrazza Papa GF, Di Pillo S, Chiarelli F. Usefulness of lung ultrasound in paediatric respiratory diseases. Diagnostics. 2021;11(10):1783. doi:10.3390/diagnostics11101783</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Regina DP, Pepino D, Nenna R, et al. Pediatric COVID-19 Follow-Up with lung ultrasound: a prospective cohort study. Diagnostics. 2022;12(9):2202. doi:10.3390/diagnostics12092202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Allin B, Nugawela MD, et al. Long COVID (post-COVID-19 condition) in children: a modified Delphi process. Arch Dis Child. 2022;107:674-680. doi:10.1097/QCO.0000000000000854</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cacciari E, Milani S, Balsamo A, et al. Italian cross-sectional growth charts for height, weight and BMI (2 to 20 yr). J Endocrinol Invest. 2006;29(7):581-593. doi:10.1007/BF03344156</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller MR. Standardisation of spirometry. Eur Respir J. 2005;26(2):319-338. doi:10.1183/09031936.05.00034805</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quanjer PH, Stanojevic S, Cole TJ, et al. Multi-ethnic reference values for spirometry for the 3-95-yr age range: the global lung function 2012 equations. Eur Respir J. 2012;40(6):1324-1343. doi:10.1183/09031936.00080312</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham BL, Steenbruggen I, Miller MR, et al. Standardization of spirometry 2019 update. An official American Thoracic Society and European Respiratory Society Technical Statement. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019;200(8):e70-e88. doi:10.1164/rccm.201908-1590ST</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall GL, Filipow N, Ruppel G, et al. Official ERS technical standard: global lung function initiative reference values for static lung volumes in individuals of European ancestry. Eur Respir J. 2021;57(3):2000289. doi:10.1183/13993003.00289-2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham BL, Brusasco V, Burgos F, et al. 2017 ERS/ATS standards for single-breath carbon monoxide uptake in the lung. Eur Respir J. 2017;49(1):1600016. doi:10.1183/13993003.00016-2016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanojevic S, Graham BL, Cooper BG, et al. Official ERS technical standards: global lung function initiative reference values for the carbon monoxide transfer factor for Caucasians. Eur Respir J. 2017;50(3):1700010. doi:10.1183/13993003.00010-2017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Thoracic Society; European Respiratory Society. ATS/ERS recommendations for standardized procedures for the online and offline measurement of exhaled lower respiratory nitric oxide and nasal nitric oxide, 2005. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2005;171(8):912-930. doi:10.1164/rccm.200406-710ST</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrino R. Interpretative strategies for lung function tests. Eur Respir J. 2005;26(5):948-968. doi:10.1183/09031936.05.00035205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copetti R, Cattarossi L. Ultrasound diagnosis of pneumonia in children. Radiol Med (Torino). 2008;113(2):190-198. doi:10.1007/s11547-008-0247-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanderWeele TJ. Principles of confounder selection. Eur J Epidemiol. 2019;34(3):211-219. doi:10.1007/s10654-019-00494-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pate CA, Qin X, Johnson C, Zahran HS. Asthma disparities among U.S. children and adults. J Asthma. 2023;60(12):2214-2223. doi:10.1080/02770903.2023.2228915</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong M, Forno E, Celed&#xf3;n JC. Asthma interactions between obesity and other risk factors. Ann&#xa0;Allergy&#xa0;Asthma Immunol. 2022;129(3):301-306. doi:10.1016/j.anai.2022.04.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan EYF, Zhang R, Mathur S, et al. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 in older persons: multi-organ complications and mortality. J Travel Med. 2023;30(5):taad082. doi:10.1093/jtm/taad082</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loosen SH, Jensen BEO, Tanislav C, Luedde T, Roderburg C, Kostev K. Obesity and lipid metabolism disorders determine the risk for development of long COVID syndrome: a cross-sectional study from 50,402 COVID-19 patients. Infection. 2022;50(5):1165-1170. doi:10.1007/s15010-022-01784-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Pellicer-Valero &#xd3;J, et al. Female sex is a risk factor associated with long-term post-COVID related-symptoms but not with COVID-19 symptoms: the LONG-COVID-EXP-CM multicenter study. J Clin Med. 2022;11(2):413. doi:10.3390/jcm11020413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanojevic S, Kaminsky DA, Miller MR, et al. ERS/ATS technical standard on interpretive strategies for routine lung function tests. Eur Respir J. 2022;60(1):2101499. doi:10.1183/13993003.01499-2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Ayuzo del Valle NC, et al. Long-COVID in children and adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):9950. doi:10.1038/s41598-022-13495-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, Bobkova P, Spiridonova E, et al. Incidence and risk factors for persistent symptoms in adults previously hospitalized for COVID-19. Clin&#xa0;Exp&#xa0;Allergy. 2021;51(9):1107-1120. doi:10.1111/cea.13997</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam GY, Befus AD, Damant RW, et al. Exertional intolerance and dyspnea with preserved lung function: an emerging long COVID phenotype. Respir Res. 2021;22(1):222. doi:10.1186/s12931-021-01814-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldo RF, Mondoni M, Parazzini EM, et al. Deconditioning as main mechanism of impaired exercise response in COVID-19 survivors. Eur Respir J. 2021;58(2):2100870. doi:10.1183/13993003.01763-2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sansone F, Pellegrino GM, Caronni A, et al. Long COVID in children: a multidisciplinary review. Diagnostics. 2023;13(12):1990. doi:10.3390/diagnostics13121990</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osmanov IM, Spiridonova E, Bobkova P, et al. Risk factors for post-COVID-19 condition in previously hospitalised children using the ISARIC Global follow-up protocol: a prospective cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2022;59(2):2101341. doi:10.1183/13993003.01341-2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betancor D, Valverde-Mongue M, Gomez-Lopez A, et al. Evaluation of fractional exhaled nitric oxide during SARS-CoV-2 infection. J&#xa0;Invest&#xa0;Allergy &#xa0;Clin&#xa0;Immunol. 2022;32(4):301-303. doi:10.18176/jiaci.0762</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsoukias NM, Shin HW, Wilson AF, George SC. A single-breath technique with variable flow rate to characterize nitric oxide exchange dynamics in the lungs. J Appl Physiol. 2001;91(1):477-487. doi:10.1152/jappl.2001.91.1.477</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameli P, Bargagli E, Bergantini L, et al. Alveolar nitric oxide as a biomarker of COVID-19 lung sequelae: a pivotal study. Antioxidants. 2021;10(9):1350. doi:10.3390/antiox10091350</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua-Huy T, G&#xfc;nther S, Lorut C, et al. Distal lung inflammation assessed by alveolar concentration of nitric oxide is an individualised biomarker of severe COVID-19 pneumonia. J Pers Med. 2022;12(10):1631. doi:10.3390/jpm12101631</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindahl A, Reijula J, Malmberg LP, Aro M, Vasankari T, M&#xe4;kel&#xe4; MJ. Small airway function in Finnish COVID-19 survivors. Respir Res. 2021;22(1):237. doi:10.1186/s12931-021-01830-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kharitonov S, Yates D, Barnes P. Increased nitric oxide in exhaled air of normal human subjects with upper respiratory tract infections. Eur Respir J. 1995;8(2):295-297. doi:10.1183/09031936.95.08020295</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis. 2021;53(10):737-754. doi:10.1080/23744235.2021.1924397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Morello R, Mariani F, et al. Role of lung ultrasound in the follow-up of children with previous SARS-CoV-2 infection: A case-control assessment of children with long COVID or fully recovered. J Clin Med. 2023;12(9):3342. doi:10.3390/jcm12093342</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denina M, Scolfaro C, Silvestro E, et al. Lung ultrasound in children with COVID-19. Pediatrics. 2020;146(1):e20201157. doi:10.1542/peds.2020-1157</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attanasi M, Sferrazza Papa S, Porreca A, et al. Use of lung ultrasound in school-aged children with wheezing. Front Pediatr. 2023;10:926252. doi:10.3389/fped.2022.926252</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;ger S, Pfirschke R, Lorenz M, et al. Lung ultrasound in children and adolescents with long-term effects of COVID-19: initial results. Front Pediatr. 2023;11:1112881. doi:10.3389/fped.2023.1112881</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couzin-Frankel J. Clues to long COVID. Science (New York, N.Y.). 2022;376(6599):1261-1265. doi:10.1126/science.add4297</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>