<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37733584</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nervous system-related tropism of SARS-CoV-2 and autoimmunity in COVID-19 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2250230</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2250230</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/eji.202250230</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The effects of SARS-CoV-2 in COVID-19 on the nervous system are incompletely understood. SARS-CoV-2 can infect endothelial cells, neurons, astrocytes, and oligodendrocytes with consequences for the host. There are indications that infection of these CNS-resident cells may result in long-term effects, including emergence of neurodegenerative diseases. Indirect effects of infection with SARS-CoV-2 relate to the induction of autoimmune disease involving molecular mimicry or/and bystander activation of T- and B cells and emergence of autoantibodies against various self-antigens. Data obtained in preclinical models of coronavirus-induced disease gives important clues for the understanding of nervous system-related assault of SARS-CoV-2. The pathophysiology of long-COVID syndrome and post-COVID syndrome in which autoimmunity and immune dysregulation might be the driving forces are still incompletely understood. A better understanding of nervous-system-related immunity in COVID-19 might support the development of therapeutic approaches. In this review, the current understanding of SARS-CoV-2 tropism for the nervous system, the associated immune responses, and diseases are summarized. The data indicates that there is viral tropism of SARS-CoV-2 in the nervous system resulting in various disease conditions. Prevention of SARS-CoV-2 infection by means of vaccination is currently the best strategy for the prevention of subsequent tissue damage involving the nervous system.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. European Journal of Immunology published by Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weissert</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Regensburg Hospital, Regensburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1273201</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0014-2980</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015551" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmunity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042783" MajorTopicYN="N">Endothelial Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009420" MajorTopicYN="N">Nervous System</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018523" MajorTopicYN="N">Tropism</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lymphocyte</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37733584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eji.202250230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Wu, F., Zhao, S., Yu, B., Chen, Y. M., Wang, W., Song, Z. G., Hu, Y. et&#xa0;al., A new coronavirus associated with human respiratory disease in China. Nature 2020. 579: 265-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, P., Yang, X. L., Wang, X. G., Hu, B., Zhang, L., Zhang, W., Si, H. R. et&#xa0;al., A pneumonia outbreak associated with a new coronavirus of probable bat origin. Nature 2020. 579: 270-273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Despres, H. W., Mills, M. G., Shirley, D. J., Schmidt, M. M., Huang, M. L., Roychoudhury, P., Jerome, K. R. et&#xa0;al., Measuring infectious SARS-CoV-2 in clinical samples reveals a higher viral titer: RNA ratio for Delta and Epsilon vs. Alpha variants. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2022. 119: e2116518119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, H., Song, Y., Chen, Y., Wu, N., Xu, J., Sun, C., Zhang, J. et&#xa0;al., Molecular architecture of the SARS-CoV-2 virus. Cell 2020. 183: 730-738 e713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Q., Zhang, Y., Wu, L., Niu, S., Song, C., Zhang, Z., Lu, G. et&#xa0;al., Structural and functional basis of SARS-CoV-2 entry by using human ACE2. Cell 2020. 181: 894-904. e899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, R., Zhang, Y., Li, Y., Xia, L., Guo, Y. and Zhou, Q., Structural basis for the recognition of SARS-CoV-2 by full-length human ACE2. Science 2020. 367: 1444-1448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clausen, T. M., Sandoval, D. R., Spliid, C. B., Pihl, J., Perrett, H. R., Painter, C. D., Narayanan, A. et&#xa0;al., SARS-CoV-2 infection depends on cellular heparan sulfate and ACE2. Cell 2020. 183: 1043-1057. e1015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniloski, Z., Jordan, T. X., Wessels, H. H., Hoagland, D. A., Kasela, S., Legut, M., Maniatis, S. et&#xa0;al., Identification of required host factors for SARS-CoV-2 infection in human cells. Cell 2021. 184: 92-105. e116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantuti-Castelvetri, L., Ojha, R., Pedro, L. D., Djannatian, M., Franz, J., Kuivanen, S., van der Meer, F. et&#xa0;al., Neuropilin-1 facilitates SARS-CoV-2 cell entry and infectivity. Science 2020. 370: 856-860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, J., Alfajaro, M. M., DeWeirdt, P. C., Hanna, R. E., Lu-Culligan, W. J., Cai, W. L., Strine, M. S. et&#xa0;al., Genome-wide CRISPR screens reveal host factors critical for SARS-CoV-2 infection. Cell 2021. 184: 76-91. e13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, R., Simoneau, C. R., Kulsuptrakul, J., Bouhaddou, M., Travisano, K. A., Hayashi, J. M. et&#xa0;al., Genetic screens identify host factors for SARS-CoV-2 and common cold coronaviruses. Cell 2021. 184: 106-119. e114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamers, M. M., Beumer, J., van der Vaart, J., Knoops, K., Puschhof, J., Breugem, T. I., Ravelli, R. B. G. et&#xa0;al., SARS-CoV-2 productively infects human gut enterocytes. Science 2020. 369: 50-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, D., Lee, J. Y., Yang, J. S., Kim, J. W., Kim, V. N. and Chang, H., The architecture of SARS-CoV-2 transcriptome. Cell 2020. 181: 914-921. e910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L., Richards, A., Barrasa, M. I., Hughes, S. H., Young, R. A. and Jaenisch, R., Reverse-transcribed SARS-CoV-2 RNA can integrate into the genome of cultured human cells and can be expressed in patient-derived tissues. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2021. 118: e2105968118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L., Bisht, P., Flamier, A., Barrasa, M. I., Friesen, M., Richards, A., Hughes, S. H. et&#xa0;al., LINE1-mediated reverse transcription and genomic integration of SARS-CoV-2 mRNA detected in virus-infected but not in viral mRNA-transfected cells. Viruses 2023. 15: 629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, M., Yoo, S. J., Clijsters, M., Backaert, W., Vanstapel, A., Speleman, K., Lietaer, C. et&#xa0;al., Visualizing in deceased COVID-19 patients how SARS-CoV-2 attacks the respiratory and olfactory mucosae but spares the olfactory bulb. Cell 2021. 184: 5932-5949 e5915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flamier, A., Bisht, P., Richards, A., Tomasello, D.L. and Jaenisch, R. Human iPS cell-derived sensory neurons can be infected by SARS-CoV-2. iScience. 2023. 26: 107690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfel, R., Corman, V. M., Guggemos, W., Seilmaier, M., Zange, S., Muller, M. A., Niemeyer, D. et&#xa0;al., Virological assessment of hospitalized patients with COVID-2019. Nature 2020. 581: 465-469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, M., Clijsters, M., Choi, S., Backaert, W., Claerhout, M., Couvreur, F., Van Breda, L. et&#xa0;al., Anatomical barriers against SARS-CoV-2 neuroinvasion at vulnerable interfaces visualized in deceased COVID-19 patients. Neuron 2022. 110: 3919-3935 e3916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mele, D., Calastri, A., Maiorano, E., Cerino, A., Sachs, M., Oliviero, B., Mantovani, S. et&#xa0;al., High frequencies of functional virus-specific CD4(+) T cells in SARS-CoV-2 subjects with olfactory and taste disorders. Front Immunol 2021. 12: 748881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finlay, J. B., Brann, D. H., Abi Hachem, R., Jang, D. W., Oliva, A. D., Ko, T., Gupta, R. et&#xa0;al., Persistent post-COVID-19 smell loss is associated with immune cell infiltration and altered gene expression in olfactory epithelium. Sci Transl Med 2022. 14: eadd0484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Melo, G. D., Lazarini, F., Levallois, S., Hautefort, C., Michel, V., Larrous, F., Verillaud, B. et&#xa0;al., COVID-19-related anosmia is associated with viral persistence and inflammation in human olfactory epithelium and brain infection in hamsters. Sci Transl Med 2021. 13: eabf8396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyoo, K. S., Kim, H. M., Lee, B., Che, Y. H., Kim, S. J., Song, D., Hwang, W. et&#xa0;al., Direct neuronal infection of SARS-CoV-2 reveals cellular and molecular pathology of chemosensory impairment of COVID-19 patients. Emerg Microbes Infect 2022. 11: 406-411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga, Z., Flammer, A. J., Steiger, P., Haberecker, M., Andermatt, R., Zinkernagel, A. S., Mehra, M. R. et&#xa0;al., Endothelial cell infection and endotheliitis in COVID-19. Lancet 2020. 395: 1417-1418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirschenbaum, D., Imbach, L. L., Rushing, E. J., Frauenknecht, K. B. M., Gascho, D., Ineichen, B. V., Keller, E. et&#xa0;al., Intracerebral endotheliitis and microbleeds are neuropathological features of COVID-19. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2021. 47: 454-459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller, E., Brandi, G., Winklhofer, S., Imbach, L. L., Kirschenbaum, D., Frontzek, K., Steiger, P. et&#xa0;al., Large and small cerebral vessel involvement in severe COVID-19: detailed clinical workup of a case series. Stroke 2020. 51: 3719-3722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maccio, U., Zinkernagel, A. S., Shambat, S. M., Zeng, X., Cathomas, G., Ruschitzka, F., Schuepbach, R. A. et&#xa0;al., SARS-CoV-2 leads to a small vessel endotheliitis in the heart. EBioMedicine 2021. 63: 103182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenzel, J., Lampe, J., Muller-Fielitz, H., Schuster, R., Zille, M., Muller, K., Krohn, M. et&#xa0;al., The SARS-CoV-2 main protease M(pro) causes microvascular brain pathology by cleaving NEMO in brain endothelial cells. Nat Neurosci 2021. 24: 1522-1533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, M. H., Perl, D. P., Steiner, J., Pasternack, N., Li, W., Maric, D., Safavi, F. et&#xa0;al., Neurovascular injury with complement activation and inflammation in COVID-19. Brain 2022. 145: 2555-2568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peiris, S., Mesa, H., Aysola, A., Manivel, J., Toledo, J., Borges-Sa, M., Aldighieri, S. et&#xa0;al., Pathological findings in organs and tissues of patients with COVID-19: A systematic review. PLoS One 2021. 16: e0250708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon, I. H., Normandin, E., Bhattacharyya, S., Mukerji, S. S., Keller, K., Ali, A. S., Adams, G. et&#xa0;al., Neuropathological features of Covid-19. N Engl J Med 2020. 383: 989-992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichard, R. R., Kashani, K. B., Boire, N. A., Constantopoulos, E., Guo, Y. and Lucchinetti, C. F., Neuropathology of COVID-19: a spectrum of vascular and acute disseminated encephalomyelitis (ADEM)-like pathology. Acta Neuropathol 2020. 140: 1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke, J., Lutgehetmann, M., Hagel, C., Sperhake, J. P., Schroder, A. S., Edler, C., Mushumba, H. et&#xa0;al., Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol 2020. 19: 919-929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Weyhern, C. H., Kaufmann, I., Neff, F. and Kremer, M., Early evidence of pronounced brain involvement in fatal COVID-19 outcomes. Lancet 2020. 395: e109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, E., Zhang, C., Israelow, B., Lu-Culligan, A., Prado, A. V., Skriabine, S., Lu, P. et&#xa0;al., Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 in human and mouse brain. J Exp Med 2021. 218: e20202135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein, S. R., Ramelli, S. C., Grazioli, A., Chung, J. Y., Singh, M., Yinda, C. K., Winkler, C. W. et&#xa0;al., SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence in the human body and brain at autopsy. Nature 2022. 612: 758-763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwabenland, M., Salie, H., Tanevski, J., Killmer, S., Lago, M. S., Schlaak, A. E., Mayer, L. et&#xa0;al., Deep spatial profiling of human COVID-19 brains reveals neuroinflammation with distinct microanatomical microglia-T-cell interactions. Immunity 2021. 54: 1594-1610 e1511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pepe, A., Pietropaoli, S., Vos, M., Barba-Spaeth, G. and Zurzolo, C., Tunneling nanotubes provide a route for SARS-CoV-2 spreading. Sci Adv 2022. 8: eabo0171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray-Rodriguez, S., Jensen, M. P., Otero-Jimenez, M., Hanley, B., Swann, O. C., Ward, P. A., Salguero, F. J. et&#xa0;al., Multisystem screening reveals SARS-CoV-2 in neurons of the myenteric plexus and in megakaryocytes. J Pathol 2022. 257: 198-217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cama, V. F., Marin-Prida, J., Acosta-Rivero, N., Acosta, E. F., Diaz, L. O., Casadesus, A. V., Fernandez-Marrero, B. et&#xa0;al., The microglial NLRP3 inflammasome is involved in human SARS-CoV-2 cerebral pathogenicity: A report of three post-mortem cases. J Neuroimmunol 2021. 361: 577728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, W. B., Elahi, M., Logue, J., Yang, P., Baracco, L., Reece, E. A., Wang, B. et&#xa0;al., SARS-CoV-2 invades cognitive centers of the brain and induces Alzheimer's-like neuropathology. bioRxiv 2022. 6. 2022.01.31.478476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charnley, M., Islam, S., Bindra, G. K., Engwirda, J., Ratcliffe, J., Zhou, J., Mezzenga, R. et&#xa0;al., Neurotoxic amyloidogenic peptides in the proteome of SARS-COV2: potential implications for neurological symptoms in COVID-19. Nat Commun 2022. 13: 3387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nystrom, S. and Hammarstrom, P., Amyloidogenesis of SARS-CoV-2 spike protein. J Am Chem Soc 2022. 144: 8945-8950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philippens, I., Boszormenyi, K. P., Wubben, J. A. M., Fagrouch, Z. C., van Driel, N., Mayenburg, A. Q., Lozovagia, D. et&#xa0;al., Brain inflammation and intracellular alpha-synuclein aggregates in macaques after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Viruses 2022. 14: 776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brundin, P., Nath, A. and Beckham, J. D., Is COVID-19 a perfect storm for Parkinson's disease? Trends Neurosci 2020. 43: 931-933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Castaneda, A., Lu, P., Geraghty, A. C., Song, E., Lee, M. H., Wood, J., O'Dea, M. R. et&#xa0;al., Mild respiratory COVID can cause multi-lineage neural cell and myelin dysregulation. Cell 2022. 185: 2452-2468 e2416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, R., Zhang, Q., Anthony, S. M., Zhou, Y., Zou, X., Cassell, M. and Perlman, S., Oligodendrocytes that survive acute coronavirus infection induce prolonged inflammatory responses in the CNS. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2020. 117: 15902-15910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews, M. G., Mukhtar, T., Eze, U. C., Simoneau, C. R., Ross, J., Parikshak, N., Wang, S. et&#xa0;al., Tropism of SARS-CoV-2 for human cortical astrocytes. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2022. 119: e2122236119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vankadari, N. and Wilce, J. A., Emerging WuHan (COVID-19) coronavirus: glycan shield and structure prediction of spike glycoprotein and its interaction with human CD26. Emerg Microbes Infect 2020. 9: 601-604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proust, A., Queval, C. J., Harvey, R., Adams, L., Bennett, M. and Wilkinson, R. J., Differential effects of SARS-CoV-2 variants on central nervous system cells and blood-brain barrier functions. J Neuroinflammation 2023. 20: 184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaskar, S., Sinha, A., Banach, M., Mittoo, S., Weissert, R., Kass, J. S., Rajagopal, S. et&#xa0;al., Cytokine storm in COVID-19-immunopathological mechanisms, clinical considerations, and therapeutic approaches: the REPROGRAM consortium position paper. Front Immunol 2020. 11: 1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sefik, E., Qu, R., Junqueira, C., Kaffe, E., Mirza, H., Zhao, J., Brewer, J. R. et&#xa0;al., Inflammasome activation in infected macrophages drives COVID-19 pathology. Nature 2022. 606: 585-593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heming, M., Li, X., Rauber, S., Mausberg, A. K., Borsch, A. L., Hartlehnert, M., Singhal, A. et&#xa0;al., Neurological manifestations of COVID-19 feature T cell exhaustion and dedifferentiated monocytes in cerebrospinal fluid. Immunity 2021. 54: 164-175 e166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, A. C., Kern, F., Losada, P. M., Agam, M. R., Maat, C. A., Schmartz, G. P., Fehlmann, T. et&#xa0;al., Dysregulation of brain and choroid plexus cell types in severe COVID-19. Nature 2021. 595: 565-571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe, R., Wege, H. and ter Meulen, V., Adoptive transfer of EAE-like lesions from rats with coronavirus-induced demyelinating encephalomyelitis. Nature 1983. 305: 150-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbot, P. J., Paquette, J. S., Ciurli, C., Antel, J. P. and Ouellet, F., Myelin basic protein and human coronavirus 229E cross-reactive T cells in multiple sclerosis. Ann Neurol 1996. 39: 233-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong, S. J., Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond) 2021: 1-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salamanna, F., Veronesi, F., Martini, L., Landini, M. P. and Fini, M., Post-COVID-19 syndrome: the persistent symptoms at the post-viral stage of the disease. a systematic review of the current data. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021. 8: 653516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvakumar, J., Havdal, L. B., Drevvatne, M., Brodwall, E. M., Lund Berven, L., Stiansen-Sonerud, T., Einvik, G. et&#xa0;al., Prevalence and characteristics associated with post-COVID-19 condition among nonhospitalized adolescents and young adults. JAMA Netw Open 2023. 6: e235763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud, G., Lee, S., Alfaro-Almagro, F., Arthofer, C., Wang, C., McCarthy, P., Lange, F. et&#xa0;al., SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature 2022. 604: 697-707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandarano, A. H., Maya, J., Giloteaux, L., Peterson, D. L., Maynard, M., Gottschalk, C. G. and Hanson, M. R., Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients exhibit altered T cell metabolism and cytokine associations. J Clin Invest 2020. 130: 1491-1505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubankova, M., Hohberger, B., Hoffmanns, J., Furst, J., Herrmann, M., Guck, J. and Krater, M., Physical phenotype of blood cells is altered in COVID-19. Biophys J 2021. 120: 2838-2847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batiha, G. E., Al-Kuraishy, H. M., Al-Gareeb, A. I. and Welson, N. N., Pathophysiology of Post-COVID syndromes: a new perspective. Virol J 2022. 19: 158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, E. Y., Mao, T., Klein, J., Dai, Y., Huck, J. D., Jaycox, J. R., Liu, F. et&#xa0;al., Diverse functional autoantibodies in patients with COVID-19. Nature 2021. 595: 283-288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muri, J., Cecchinato, V., Cavalli, A., Shanbhag, A. A., Matkovic, M., Biggiogero, M., Maida, P. A. et&#xa0;al., Autoantibodies against chemokines post-SARS-CoV-2 infection correlate with disease course. Nat Immunol 2023. 24: 604-611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schweitzer, F., Goereci, Y., Franke, C., Silling, S., Bosl, F., Maier, F., Heger, E. et&#xa0;al., Cerebrospinal fluid analysis post-COVID-19 is not suggestive of persistent central nervous system infection. Ann Neurol 2022. 91: 150-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spatola, M., Nziza, N., Jung, W., Deng, Y., Yuan, D., Dinoto, A., Bozzetti, S. et&#xa0;al., Neurologic sequelae of COVID-19 are determined by immunologic imprinting from previous coronaviruses. Brain 2023. 10: awad155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheibenbogen, C., Bellmann-Strobl, J. T., Heindrich, C., Wittke, K., Stein, E., Franke, C., Pruss, H. et&#xa0;al., Fighting post-COVID and ME/CFS - development of curative therapies. Front Med 2023. 10: 1194754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Chen, Y., Li, Y., Huang, F., Luo, B., Yuan, Y., Xia, B. et&#xa0;al., The ORF8 protein of SARS-CoV-2 mediates immune evasion through down-regulating MHC-Iota. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2021. 118: e2024202118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, F., Zang, T. M., Stevenson, E. M., Lei, X., Copertino, D. C., Mota, T. M., Boucau, J. et&#xa0;al., Inhibition of major histocompatibility complex-I antigen presentation by sarbecovirus ORF7a proteins. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2022. 119: e2209042119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arshad, N., Laurent-Rolle, M., Ahmed, W. S., Hsu, J. C., Mitchell, S. M., Pawlak, J., Sengupta, D. et&#xa0;al., SARS-CoV-2 accessory proteins ORF7a and ORF3a use distinct mechanisms to down-regulate MHC-I surface expression. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2023. 120: e2208525120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo, J. S., Sasaki, M., Cho, S. X., Kasuga, Y., Zhu, B., Ouda, R., Orba, Y. et&#xa0;al., SARS-CoV-2 inhibits induction of the MHC class I pathway by targeting the STAT1-IRF1-NLRC5 axis. Nat Commun 2021. 12: 6602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onnis, A., Andreano, E., Cassioli, C., Finetti, F., Della Bella, C., Staufer, O., Pantano, E. et&#xa0;al., SARS-CoV-2 spike protein suppresses CTL-mediated killing by inhibiting immune synapse assembly. J Exp Med 2023. 220: e20220906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruchez, A., Sha, K., Johnson, J., Chen, L., Stefani, C., McConnell, H., Gaucherand, L. et&#xa0;al., MHC class II transactivator CIITA induces cell resistance to Ebola virus and SARS-like coronaviruses. Science 2020. 370: 241-247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagler, A., Kalaora, S., Barbolin, C., Gangaev, A., Ketelaars, S. L. C., Alon, M., Pai, J. et&#xa0;al., Identification of presented SARS-CoV-2 HLA class I and HLA class II peptides using HLA peptidomics. Cell Rep 2021. 35: 109305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weingarten-Gabbay, S., Klaeger, S., Sarkizova, S., Pearlman, L. R., Chen, D. Y., Gallagher, K. M. E., Bauer, M. R. et&#xa0;al., Profiling SARS-CoV-2 HLA-I peptidome reveals T cell epitopes from out-of-frame ORFs. Cell 2021. 184: 3962-3980 e3917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollenbach, J. A. and Srivastava, A., The immunogenetics of COVID-19. Immunogenetics 2022: 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parikh, V. N., Ioannidis, A. G., Jimenez-Morales, D., Gorzynski, J. E., De Jong, H. N., Liu, X., Roque, J. et&#xa0;al., Deconvoluting complex correlates of COVID-19 severity with a multi-omic pandemic tracking strategy. Nat Commun 2022. 13: 5107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastard, P., Rosen, L. B., Zhang, Q., Michailidis, E., Hoffmann, H. H., Zhang, Y., Dorgham, K. et&#xa0;al., Autoantibodies against type I IFNs in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science 2020. 370: eabd4585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manry, J., Bastard, P., Gervais, A., Le Voyer, T., Rosain, J., Philippot, Q., Michailidis, E. et&#xa0;al., The risk of COVID-19 death is much greater and age dependent with type I IFN autoantibodies. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2022. 119: e2200413119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Q., Bastard, P., Liu, Z., Le Pen, J., Moncada-Velez, M., Chen, J., Ogishi, M. et&#xa0;al., Inborn errors of type I IFN immunity in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science 2020. 370: eabd4570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Povysil, G., Butler-Laporte, G., Shang, N., Wang, C., Khan, A., Alaamery, M., Nakanishi, T. et&#xa0;al., Rare loss-of-function variants in type I IFN immunity genes are not associated with severe COVID-19. J Clin Invest 2021. 131: e147834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altmann, D. M. and Boyton, R. J., COVID-19 vaccination: The road ahead. Science 2022. 375: 1127-1132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Q., Iketani, S., Li, Z., Liu, L., Guo, Y., Huang, Y., Bowen, A. D. et&#xa0;al., Alarming antibody evasion properties of rising SARS-CoV-2 BQ and XBB subvariants. Cell 2022. 186: 279-286.e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greinacher, A., Thiele, T., Warkentin, T. E., Weisser, K., Kyrle, P. A. and Eichinger, S., Thrombotic thrombocytopenia after ChAdOx1 nCov-19 vaccination. N Engl J Med 2021. 384: 2092-2101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irure-Ventura, J., Belmar-Vega, L., Fernandez-Fresnedo, G., Gonzalez-Lopez, E., Castro-Hernandez, C., Rodrigo-Calabia, E., Heras-Vicario, M. et&#xa0;al., Increased induction of de novo serum ANCA and ANCA-associated vasculitis after mass vaccination against SARS-CoV-2. iScience 2022. 25: 104847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintanilla-Bordas, C., Gascon-Gimenez, F., Alcala, C., Paya, M., Mallada, J., Silla, R., Carratala-Bosca, S. et&#xa0;al., Case report: exacerbation of relapses following mRNA COVID-19 vaccination in multiple sclerosis: a case series. Front Neurol 2022. 13: 897275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegler, J. E., Klein, P., Yaghi, S., Vigilante, N., Abdalkader, M., Coutinho, J. M., Abdul Khalek, F. et&#xa0;al., Cerebral vein thrombosis with vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia. Stroke 2021. 52: 3045-3053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez van Kammen, M., Aguiar de Sousa, D., Poli, S., Cordonnier, C., Heldner, M. R., van de Munckhof, A., Krzywicka, K. et&#xa0;al., Characteristics and outcomes of patients with cerebral venous sinus thrombosis in SARS-CoV-2 vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia. JAMA Neurol 2021. 78: 1314-1323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnefeesi, Y., Siegel, A., Lui, L. M. W., Teopiz, K. M., Ho, R. C. M., Lee, Y., Nasri, F. et&#xa0;al., Impact of SARS-CoV-2 infection on cognitive function: a systematic review. Front Psychiatry 2020. 11: 621773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur, K. T., Miller, E. H., Glendinning, M. D., Al-Dalahmah, O., Banu, M. A., Boehme, A. K., Boubour, A. L. et&#xa0;al., COVID-19 neuropathology at Columbia University Irving Medical Center/New York Presbyterian Hospital. Brain 2021. 144: 2696-2708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, A., Rohaut, B., Le Guennec, L., Saheb, S., Marois, C., Altmayer, V., Carpentier, V. T. et&#xa0;al., Severe COVID-19-related encephalitis can respond to immunotherapy. Brain 2020. 143: e102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilotto, A., Odolini, S., Masciocchi, S., Comelli, A., Volonghi, I., Gazzina, S., Nocivelli, S. et&#xa0;al., Steroid-responsive encephalitis in coronavirus disease 2019. Ann Neurol 2020. 88: 423-427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kremer, S., Lersy, F., Anheim, M., Merdji, H., Schenck, M., Oesterle, H., Bolognini, F. et&#xa0;al., Neurologic and neuroimaging findings in patients with COVID-19: A retrospective multicenter study. Neurology 2020. 95: e1868-e1882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriguchi, T., Harii, N., Goto, J., Harada, D., Sugawara, H., Takamino, J., Ueno, M. et&#xa0;al., A first case of meningitis/encephalitis associated with SARS-Coronavirus-2. Int J Infect Dis 2020. 94: 55-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodamoradi, Z., Hosseini, S. A., Gholampoor Saadi, M. H., Mehrabi, Z., Sasani, M. R. and Yaghoubi, S., COVID-19 meningitis without pulmonary involvement with positive cerebrospinal fluid PCR. Eur J Neurol 2020. 27: 2668-2669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C., Wang, Y., Li, X., Ren, L., Zhao, J., Hu, Y., Zhang, L. et&#xa0;al., Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet 2020. 395: 497-506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotfis, K., Williams Roberson, S., Wilson, J. E., Dabrowski, W., Pun, B. T. and Ely, E. W., COVID-19: ICU delirium management during SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. Crit Care 2020. 24: 176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, L., Xiong, W., Liu, D., Liu, J., Yang, D., Li, N., Mu, J. et&#xa0;al., New onset acute symptomatic seizure and risk factors in coronavirus disease 2019: A retrospective multicenter study. Epilepsia 2020. 61: e49-e53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mithani, F., Poursheykhi, M., Ma, B., Smith, R. G., Hsu, S. H. and Gotur, D., New-onset seizures in three COVID-19 patients: a case series. J Clin Neurophysiol 2021. 38: e5-e10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyrouti, R., Adams, M. E., Benjamin, L., Cohen, H., Farmer, S. F., Goh, Y. Y., Humphries, F. et&#xa0;al., Characteristics of ischaemic stroke associated with COVID-19. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020. 91: 889-891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaghi, S., Ishida, K., Torres, J., Mac Grory, B., Raz, E., Humbert, K., Henninger, N. et&#xa0;al., SARS-CoV-2 and stroke in a New York Healthcare System. Stroke 2020. 51: 2002-2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalcanti, D. D., Raz, E., Shapiro, M., Dehkharghani, S., Yaghi, S., Lillemoe, K., Nossek, E. et&#xa0;al., Cerebral venous thrombosis associated with COVID-19. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol 2020. 41: 1370-1376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kishfy, L., Casasola, M., Banankhah, P., Parvez, A., Jan, Y. J., Shenoy, A. M., Thomson, C. et&#xa0;al. Posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome (PRES) as a neurological association in severe Covid-19. J Neurol Sci 2020. 414: 116943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coolen, T., Lolli, V., Sadeghi, N., Rovai, A., Trotta, N., Taccone, F. S., Creteur, J. et&#xa0;al., Early postmortem brain MRI findings in COVID-19 non-survivors. Neurology 2020. 95: e2016-e2027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huber, M., Rogozinski, S., Puppe, W., Framme, C., Hoglinger, G., Hufendiek, K. and Wegner, F., Postinfectious onset of myasthenia gravis in a COVID-19 patient. Front Neurol 2020. 11: 576153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Restivo, D. A., Centonze, D., Alesina, A. and Marchese-Ragona, R., Myasthenia gravis associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Ann Intern Med 2020. 173: 1027-1028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, H., Shen, D., Zhou, H., Liu, J. and Chen, S., Guillain-Barre syndrome associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection: causality or coincidence? Lancet Neurol 2020. 19: 383-384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toscano, G., Palmerini, F., Ravaglia, S., Ruiz, L., Invernizzi, P., Cuzzoni, M. G., Franciotta, D. et&#xa0;al., Guillain-Barre syndrome associated with SARS-CoV-2. N Engl J Med 2020. 382: 2574-2576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinkin, M., Gao, V., Kahan, J., Bobker, S., Simonetto, M., Wechsler, P., Harpe, J. et&#xa0;al., COVID-19 presenting with ophthalmoparesis from cranial nerve palsy. Neurology 2020. 95: 221-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutierrez-Ortiz, C., Mendez-Guerrero, A., Rodrigo-Rey, S., San Pedro-Murillo, E., Bermejo-Guerrero, L., Gordo-Manas, R., de Aragon-Gomez, F. et&#xa0;al., Miller Fisher syndrome and polyneuritis cranialis in COVID-19. Neurology 2020. 95: e601-e605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emamikhah, M., Babadi, M., Mehrabani, M., Jalili, M., Pouranian, M., Daraie, P., Mohaghegh, F. et&#xa0;al., Opsoclonus-myoclonus syndrome, a post-infectious neurologic complication of COVID-19: case series and review of literature. J Neurovirol 2021. 27: 26-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werner, J., Reichen, I., Huber, M., Abela, I. A., Weller, M. and Jelcic, I., Subacute cerebellar ataxia following respiratory symptoms of COVID-19: a case report. BMC Infect Dis 2021. 21: 298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, J. L., Murphy, K. A. and Sarna, J. R., Myoclonus and cerebellar ataxia associated with COVID-19: a case report and systematic review. J Neurol 2021. 68: 3517-3548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Escobar, M. C., Kataria, S., Khan, E., Subedi, R., Tandon, M., Peshwe, K., Kramer, J. et&#xa0;al., Acute transverse myelitis with Dysautonomia following SARS-CoV-2 infection: a case report and review of literature. J Neuroimmunol 2021. 353: 577523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pizzanelli, C., Milano, C., Canovetti, S., Tagliaferri, E., Turco, F., Verdenelli, S., Nesti, L. et&#xa0;al., Autoimmune limbic encephalitis related to SARS-CoV-2 infection: Case-report and review of the literature. Brain Behav Immun Health 2021. 12: 100210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valencia Sanchez, C., Theel, E., Binnicker, M., Toledano, M. and McKeon, A., Autoimmune encephalitis after SARS-CoV-2 infection: case frequency, findings, and outcomes. Neurology 2021. 97: e2262-e2268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palao, M., Fernandez-Diaz, E., Gracia-Gil, J., Romero-Sanchez, C. M., Diaz-Maroto, I. and Segura, T., Multiple sclerosis following SARS-CoV-2 infection. Mult Scler Relat Disord 2020. 45: 102377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jumah, M., Rahman, F., Figgie, M., Prasad, A., Zampino, A., Fadhil, A., Palmer, K. et&#xa0;al., COVID-19, HHV6 and MOG antibody: a perfect storm. J Neuroimmunol 2021. 353: 577521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahmirzaei, S. and Naser Moghadasi, A., Association of COVID-19 and acute disseminated encephalomyelitis (ADEM) in the absence of pulmonary involvement. Autoimmun Rev 2021. 20: 102753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delamarre, L., Gollion, C., Grouteau, G., Rousset, D., Jimena, G., Roustan, J., Gaussiat, F. et&#xa0;al., COVID-19-associated acute necrotising encephalopathy successfully treated with steroids and polyvalent immunoglobulin with unusual IgG targeting the cerebral fibre network. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020. 91: 1004-1006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llorente Ayuso, L., Torres Rubio, P., Beijinho do Rosario, R. F., Giganto Arroyo, M. L. and Sierra-Hidalgo, F., Bickerstaff encephalitis after COVID-19. J Neurol 2020. 268: 2035-2037.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>