<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37209039</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1520-7560</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Diabetes/metabolism research and reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Diabetes Metab Res Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Diabetes, COVID-19, and questions unsolved.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e3666</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e3666</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/dmrr.3666</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recent evidence suggests a role for Diabetes Mellitus in adverse outcomes from COVID-19 infection; yet the underlying mechanisms are not clear. Moreover, attention has turned to prophylactic vaccination to protect the population from COVID-19-related illness and mortality. We performed a comprehensive peer-reviewed literature search on an array of key terms concerning diabetes and COVID-19 seeking to address the following questions: 1. What role does diabetes play as an accelerator for adverse outcomes in COVID-19?; 2. What mechanisms underlie the differences in outcomes seen in people with diabetes?; 3. Are vaccines against COVID-19 efficacious in people with diabetes? The current literature demonstrates that diabetes is associated with an increased risk of adverse outcomes from COVID-19 infection, and post-COVID sequelae. Potential mechanisms include dysregulation of Angiotensin Converting Enzyme 2, Furin, CD147, and impaired immune cell responses. Hyperglycaemia is a key exacerbator of these mechanisms. Limited studies are available on COVID-19 vaccination in people with diabetes; however, the current literature suggests that vaccination is protective against adverse outcomes for this population. In summary, people with diabetes are a high-risk group that should be prioritised in vaccination efforts. Glycaemic optimisation is paramount to protecting this group from COVID-19-associated risk. Unsolved questions remain as to the molecular mechanisms underlying the adverse outcomes seen in people with diabetes; the functional impact of post-COVID symptoms on people with diabetes, their persistence, and management; how long-term vaccine efficacy is affected by diabetes, and the antibody levels that confer protection from adverse outcomes in COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Diabetes/Metabolism Research and Reviews published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D'Souza</LastName><ForeName>Felecia</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3405-4213</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University College London Hospitals NHS Trust, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barts and the London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buzzetti</LastName><ForeName>Raffaella</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1490-6041</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Experimental Medicine, Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pozzilli</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5090-636X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology &amp; Diabetes, University Campus Bio-Medico, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Immunobiology, Barts and the London School of Medicine, Queen Mary University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Diabetes Metab Res Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883450</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1520-7552</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000086663">COVID-19 Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086663" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003920" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hyperglycemia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37209039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dmrr.3666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Zhu N, Zhang D, Wang W, et&#xa0;al. A novel coronavirus from patients with pneumonia in China, 2019. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(8):727-733. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa2001017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geneva: World Health Organization. WHO COVID-19 Dashboard. Published 2023. Accessed April 7, 2023. https://covid19.who.int/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Health Topics: Diabetes. Published 2021. Accessed April 7, 2023. https://www.who.int/health-topics/diabetes</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinedo-Torres I, Flores-Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Yovera-Aldana M, et&#xa0;al. Prevalence of diabetes mellitus and its associated unfavorable outcomes in patients with acute respiratory syndromes due to Coronaviruses infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Med Insights Endocrinol Diabetes. 2020;13:1179551420962495. https://doi.org/10.1177/1179551420962495</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddaloni E, Coraggio L, Pieralice S, Carlone A, Pozzilli P, Buzzetti R. Effects of Covid-19 lockdown on glucose control: continuous glucose monitoring data from people with diabetes on intensive insulin therapy. Diabetes Care. 2020;43(8):e86-e87. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc20-0954</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Alberts J, et&#xa0;al. Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open. 2021;11(3):e048391. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2020-048391</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng C, Shao W, Chen X, Zhang B, Wang G, Zhang W. Real-world effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccines: a literature review and meta-analysis. Int J Infect Dis. 2022;114:252-260. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2021.11.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal R, Bhadada SK, Misra A. COVID-19 vaccination in patients with diabetes mellitus: current concepts, uncertainties and challenges. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15(2):505-508. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dsx.2021.02.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, et&#xa0;al. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020;395(10223):497-506. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Yu T, Du R, et&#xa0;al. Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet. 2020;395(10229):1054-1062. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30566-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson S, Hirsch JS, Narasimhan M, et&#xa0;al. Presenting characteristics, comorbidities, and outcomes among 5700 patients hospitalized with COVID-19 in the New York city area. JAMA, J Am Med Assoc. 2020;323(20):2052-2059. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.6775</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailly L, Fabre R, Courjon J, Carles M, Dellamonica J, Pradier C. Obesity, diabetes, hypertension and severe outcomes among inpatients with coronavirus disease 2019: a nationwide study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28(1):114-123. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2021.09.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheshah E, Sabico S, Albakr RM, et&#xa0;al. Prevalence of diabetes, management and outcomes among Covid-19 adult patients admitted in a specialized tertiary hospital in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2021;172:108538. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2020.108538</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan W, Ni Z, Hu Y, et&#xa0;al. Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(18):1708-1720. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa2002032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantovani A, Byrne CD, Zheng MH, Targher G. Diabetes as a risk factor for greater COVID-19 severity and in-hospital death: a meta-analysis of observational studies. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis.&#xa0;2020;30(8):1236-1248. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.numecd.2020.05.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang I, Lim MA, Pranata R. Diabetes mellitus is associated with increased mortality and severity of disease in COVID-19 pneumonia - a systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression: diabetes and COVID-19. Diabetes Metab Syndr Clin Res Rev. 2020;14(4):395-403. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dsx.2020.04.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Arora A, Sharma P, et&#xa0;al. Is diabetes mellitus associated with mortality and severity of COVID-19? A meta-analysis. Diabetes Metab Syndr Clin Res Rev. 2020;14(4):535-545. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dsx.2020.04.044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varikasuvu SR, Dutt N, Thangappazham B, Varshney S. Diabetes and COVID-19: a pooled analysis related to disease severity and mortality. Prim Care Diabetes. 2021;15(1):24-27. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pcd.2020.08.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puri A, He L, Giri M, Wu C, Zhao Q. Comparison of comorbidities among severe and non-severe COVID-19 patients in Asian versus non-Asian populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nurs Open. 2022;9(1):733-751. https://doi.org/10.1002/nop2.1126</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Yang J, Zhao F, et&#xa0;al. Prevalence and impact of cardiovascular metabolic diseases on COVID-19 in China. Clin Res Cardiol. 2020;109(5):531-538. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00392-020-01626-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley SA, Banach M, Alvarado N, Smokovski I, Bhaskar SMM. Prevalence and impact of diabetes in hospitalized COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Diabetes. 2022;14(2):144-157. https://doi.org/10.1111/1753-0407.13243</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Sabah S, Al-Haddad M, Al-Youha S, Jamal M, Almazeedi S. COVID-19: impact of obesity and diabetes on disease severity. Clin Obes. 2020;10(6):e12414. https://doi.org/10.1111/cob.12414</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiglie J, Platt J, Cromer SJ, et&#xa0;al. Diabetes as a risk factor for poor early outcomes in patients hospitalized with Covid-19. Diabetes Care. 2020;43(12):2938-2944. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc20-1506</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei M, Lin K, Pi Y, et&#xa0;al. Clinical features and risk factors of ICU admission for COVID-19 patients with diabetes. Saisho Y. J Diabetes Res. 2020;2020:5237840 https://doi.org/10.1155/2020/5237840</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palaiodimos L, Chamorro-Pareja N, Karamanis D, et&#xa0;al. Diabetes is associated with increased risk for in-hospital mortality in patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis comprising 18,506 patients. Hormones (Basel). 2021;20(2):305-314. https://doi.org/10.1007/s42000-020-00246-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corona G, Pizzocaro A, Vena W, et&#xa0;al. Diabetes is most important cause for mortality in COVID-19 hospitalized patients: systematic review and meta-analysis. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2021;22(2):275-296. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11154-021-09630-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller LE, Bhattacharyya R, Miller AL. Diabetes mellitus increases the risk of hospital mortality in patients with Covid-19: systematic review with meta-analysis. Medicine (Baltim). 2020;99(40):e22439. https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000022439</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolcott OO, Castilla-Bancay&#xe1;n JP. The effect of age on the association between diabetes and mortality in adult patients with COVID-19 in Mexico. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):8386. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-88014-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddaloni E, D&#x2019;Onofrio L, Alessandri F, et&#xa0;al. Cardiometabolic multimorbidity is associated with a worse Covid-19 prognosis than individual cardiometabolic risk factors: a multicentre retrospective study (CoViDiab II). Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2020;19(1):1-11. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-020-01140-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddaloni E, D&#x2019;Onofrio L, Siena A, et&#xa0;al. Impact of cardiovascular disease on clinical outcomes in hospitalized patients with Covid-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Intern Emerg Med. 2021;16(7):1975-1985. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11739-021-02804-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masana L, Correig E, Rodr&#xed;guez-Borjabad C, et&#xa0;al. Effect of statin therapy on SARS-CoV-2 infection-related mortality in hospitalized patients. Eur Hear J - Cardiovasc Pharmacother. 2022;8(2):157-164. https://doi.org/10.1093/ehjcvp/pvaa128</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Madhavan MV, Poterucha TJ, et&#xa0;al. Association between antecedent statin use and decreased mortality in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):1325. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-21553-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels LB, Ren J, Kumar K, et&#xa0;al. Relation of prior statin and anti-hypertensive use to severity of disease among patients hospitalized with COVID-19: findings from the American Heart Association&#x2019;s COVID-19 Cardiovascular Disease Registry. PLoS One. 2021;16(7 July):e0254635. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0254635</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holman N, Knighton P, Kar P, et&#xa0;al. Risk factors for COVID-19-related mortality in people with type 1 and type 2 diabetes in England: a population-based cohort study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2020;8(10):823-833. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-8587(20)30271-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cariou B, Goronflot T, Rimbert A, et&#xa0;al. Routine use of statins and increased COVID-19 related mortality in inpatients with type 2 diabetes: results from the CORONADO study. Diabetes Metab. 2021;47(2):101202. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabet.2020.10.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kollias A, Kyriakoulis KG, Kyriakoulis IG, et&#xa0;al. Statin use and mortality in COVID-19 patients: updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Atherosclerosis. 2021;330:114-121. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2021.06.911</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zein AFMZ, Sulistiyana CS, Khasanah U, Wibowo A, Lim MA, Pranata R. Statin and mortality in COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of pooled adjusted effect estimates from propensity-matched cohorts. Postgrad Med J. 2022;98(1161):503-508. https://doi.org/10.1136/postgradmedj-2021-140409</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha S, Al-Rifai RH, Saha S. Diabetes prevalence and mortality in COVID-19 patients: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression. J Diabetes Metab Disord. 2021;20(1):939-950. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40200-021-00779-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett CE, Park J, Kompaniyets L, et&#xa0;al. Intensive care unit admission, mechanical ventilation, and mortality among patients with type 1 diabetes hospitalized for COVID-19 in the U.S. Diabetes Care. 2021;44(8):1788-1796. https://doi.org/10.2337/DC21-0604</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory JM, Slaughter JC, Duffus SH, et&#xa0;al. COVID-19 severity is tripled in the diabetes community: a prospective analysis of the pandemic&#x2019;s impact in type 1 and type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2021;44(2):526-532. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc20-2260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wargny M, Gourdy P, Ludwig L, et&#xa0;al. Type 1 diabetes in people hospitalized for COVID-19: new insights from the CORONADO study. Diabetes Care. 2020;43(11):e174-e177. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc20-1217</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawshani A, Kj&#xf6;lhede EA, Rawshani A, et&#xa0;al. Severe COVID-19 in people with type 1 and type 2 diabetes in Sweden: a nationwide retrospective cohort study. Lancet Reg Heal - Eur. 2021;4:100105. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGurnaghan SJ, Weir A, Bishop J, et&#xa0;al. Risks of and risk factors for COVID-19 disease in people with diabetes: a cohort study of the total population of Scotland. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2021;9(2):82-93. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-8587(20)30405-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barron E, Bakhai C, Kar P, et&#xa0;al. Associations of type 1 and type 2 diabetes with COVID-19-related mortality in England: a whole-population study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2020;8(10):813-822. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-8587(20)30272-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Desai AD, Wan EY. Post-COVID-19 condition. Annu Rev Med. 2023;74(1):55-64. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-med-043021-030635</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Florencio LL, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, Raveendran AV. Proposed integrative model for post-COVID symptoms. Diabetes Metab Syndr Clin Res Rev. 2021;15(4):102159. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dsx.2021.05.032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavli A, Theodoridou M, Maltezou HC. Post-COVID syndrome: incidence, clinical spectrum, and challenges for primary healthcare professionals. Arch Med Res. 2021;52(6):575-581. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arcmed.2021.03.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;22(October):e102-e107. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1473-3099(21)00703-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Insitute for Health and Care Excellence, SIGN, Royal College of General Practitioners. COVID-19 Guideline Scope: Management of the Long-Term Effects of COVID-19; 2020. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188/documents/final-scope?fbclid=IwAR2r4aijadQXZVFuSp5Wcyf9F1AwTFGRAADgq9zRSaxeoGdCCllyUqLP8tY</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England. Post-COVID Syndrome (Long COVID). Accessed 4 April 2023. https://www.england.nhs.uk/coronavirus/post-covid-syndrome-long-covid/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potere N, Valeriani E, Candeloro M, et&#xa0;al. Acute complications and mortality in hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Care. 2020;24(1):389. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-020-03022-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebbard C, Lee B, Katare R, Garikipati VNS. Diabetes, heart failure, and COVID-19: an update. Front Physiol. 2021;12. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2021.706185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et&#xa0;al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):626-631. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilev M, Kristensen KB, Potteg&#xe5;rd A, et&#xa0;al. Characteristics and predictors of hospitalization and death in the first 11 122 cases with a positive RT-PCR test for SARS-CoV-2 in Denmark: a nationwide cohort. Int J Epidemiol. 2020;49(5):1468-1481. https://doi.org/10.1093/ije/dyaa140</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding JL, Oviedo SA, Ali MK, et&#xa0;al. The bidirectional association&#xa0;between diabetes and long-COVID-19 - a systematic review.&#xa0;Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2023;195(November 2022):110202. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2022.110202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nesan GSCQ, Keerthana D, Yamini R, et&#xa0;al. 3-Month symptom-based ambidirectional follow-up study among recovered COVID-19 patients from a tertiary care hospital using telehealth in Chennai, India. Inq (United States). 2021;58:1-8. https://doi.org/10.1177/00469580211060165</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechi A, Al-Khalidi A, AL-Darraji R, et&#xa0;al. Long-term persistent symptoms of COVID-19 infection in patients with diabetes mellitus. Int J Diabetes Dev Ctries. 2022;42(1):49-52. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13410-021-00994-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV, Misra A. Post COVID-19 syndrome (&#x201c;Long COVID&#x201d;) and diabetes: challenges in diagnosis and management. Diabetes Metab Syndr Clin Res Rev. 2021;15(5):102235. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dsx.2021.102235</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittal J, Ghosh A, Bhatt SP, Anoop S, Ansari IA, Misra A. High&#xa0;prevalence of post COVID-19 fatigue in patients with type 2&#xa0;diabetes: a case-control study. Diabetes Metab Syndr Clin Res Rev.&#xa0;2021;15(6):102302. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dsx.2021.102302</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathish T, Kapoor N, Cao Y, Tapp RJ, Zimmet P. Proportion of newly diagnosed diabetes in COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2021;23(3):870-874. https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.14269</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha DB, Budhathoki P, Raut S, et&#xa0;al. New-onset diabetes in COVID-19 and clinical outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. World J Virol. 2021;10(5):275-287. https://doi.org/10.5501/wjv.v10.i5.275</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh Z, Baradaran HR, Kohansal K, Hadaegh F, Azizi F, Khalili D. Are the determinants of the progression to type 2 diabetes and regression to normoglycemia in the populations with pre-diabetes the same? Front Endocrinol. 2022;13:1041808. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2022.1041808</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L, Girgis CM, Cheung NW. COVID-19 and diabetes: insulin requirements parallel illness severity in critically unwell patients. Clin Endocrinol. 2020;93(4):390-393. https://doi.org/10.1111/cen.14288</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasbinder A, Anderson E, Shadid H, et&#xa0;al. Inflammation, hyperglycemia, and adverse outcomes in individuals with diabetes mellitus hospitalized for COVID-19. Diabetes Care. 2022;45(3):692-700. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc21-2102</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathish T, Tapp RJ, Cooper ME, Zimmet P. Potential metabolic and inflammatory pathways between COVID-19 and new-onset diabetes. Diabetes Metab. 2021;47(2):101204. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabet.2020.10.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie L, Zhang Z, Wang Q, Chen Y, Lu D, Wu W. COVID-19 and diabetes: a comprehensive review of angiotensin converting enzyme 2, mutual effects and pharmacotherapy. Front Endocrinol. 2021;12. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2021.772865</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li MY, Li L, Zhang Y, Wang XS. Expression of the SARS-CoV-2 cell&#xa0;receptor gene ACE2 in a wide variety of human tissues. Infect Dis Poverty. 2020;9(1):45. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40249-020-00662-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Onofrio N, Scisciola L, Sardu C, et&#xa0;al. Glycated ACE2 receptor in diabetes: open door for SARS-COV-2 entry in cardiomyocyte. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2021;20(1):99. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-021-01286-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung ML, Teng JLL, Jia L, et&#xa0;al. Soluble ACE2-mediated cell entry of SARS-CoV-2 via interaction with proteins related to the renin-angiotensin system. Cell. 2021;184(8):2212-2228.e12. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2021.02.053</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Zhao H, An Y. ACE2 shedding and the role in COVID-19. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2022;11. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcimb.2021.789180</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahrooz A, Muscogiuri G, Buzzetti R, Maddaloni E. The complex combination of COVID-19 and diabetes: pleiotropic changes in glucose metabolism. Endocrine. 2021;72(2):317-325. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12020-021-02729-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye M, Wysocki J, Naaz P, Salabat MR, LaPointe MS, Batlle D. Increased ACE 2 and decreased ACE protein in renal tubules from diabetic mice: a renoprotective combination? Hypertension. 2004;43(5):1120-1125. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.HYP.0000126192.27644.76</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye M, Wysocki J, William J, Soler MJ, Cokic I, Batlle D. Glomerular localization and expression of angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 and angiotensin-converting enzyme: implications for albuminuria in diabetes. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2006;17(11):3067-3075. https://doi.org/10.1681/ASN.2006050423</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reich HN, Oudit GY, Penninger JM, Scholey JW, Herzenberg AM. Decreased glomerular and tubular expression of ACE2 in patients with type 2 diabetes and kidney disease. Kidney Int. 2008;74(12):1610-1616. https://doi.org/10.1038/ki.2008.497</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garreta E, Prado P, Stanifer ML, et&#xa0;al. A diabetic milieu increases ACE2 expression and cellular susceptibility to SARS-CoV-2 infections in human kidney organoids and patient cells. Cell Metab. 2022;34(6):857-873.e9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2022.04.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tretter F, Peters EMJ, Sturmberg J, et&#xa0;al. Perspectives of (/memorandum for) systems thinking on COVID-19 pandemic and pathology. J Eval Clin Pract. 2022;29(3):415-429. https://doi.org/10.1111/jep.13772</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#xf6;lfel R, Corman VM, Guggemos W, et&#xa0;al. Virological assessment&#xa0;of hospitalized patients with COVID-2019. Nature. 2020;581(7809):465-469. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2196-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fajnzylber J, Regan J, Coxen K, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 viral load is associated with increased disease severity and mortality. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):1-9. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-19057-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apicella M, Campopiano MC, Mantuano M, Mazoni L, Coppelli A, Del Prato S. COVID-19 in people with diabetes: understanding the reasons for worse outcomes. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2020;8(9):782-792. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-8587(20)30238-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Perez AI, Labandeira CM, Pedrosa MA, et&#xa0;al. Autoantibodies against ACE2 and angiotensin type-1 receptors increase severity of COVID-19. J Autoimmun. 2021;122:102683. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaut.2021.102683</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur JM, Forrest JC, Boehme KW, et&#xa0;al. Development of ACE2 autoantibodies after SARS-CoV-2 infection. PLoS One. 2021;16(9 September):e0257016. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0257016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sfera A, Osorio C, Jafri N, Diaz EL, Campo Maldonado JE. Intoxication with endogenous angiotensin II: a COVID-19 hypothesis.&#xa0;Front Immunol. 2020;11. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2020.01472</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMillan P, Dexhiemer T, Neubig RR, Uhal BD. COVID-19-a theory of autoimmunity against ACE-2 explained. Front Immunol. 2021;12. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.582166</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adu-Agyeiwaah Y, Grant MB, Obukhov AG. The potential role of osteopontin and furin in worsening disease outcomes in COVID-19 patients with pre-existing diabetes. Cells. 2020;9(11):2528. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells9112528</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesan SK, Venkatratnam P, Mahendra J, Devarajan N. Increased mortality of COVID-19 infected diabetes patients: role of furin proteases. Int J Obes. 2020;44(12):2486-2488. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41366-020-00670-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando W, Horii T, Uematsu T, Hanaki H, Atsuda K, Otori K. Impact of overlapping risks of type 2 diabetes and obesity on coronavirus disease severity in the United States. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):17968. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-96720-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez C, Rys&#xe4; J, Almgren P, et&#xa0;al. Plasma levels of the proprotein convertase furin and incidence of diabetes and mortality. J&#xa0;Intern Med. 2018;284(4):377-387. https://doi.org/10.1111/joim.12783</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah H, Khan MSH, Dhurandhar NV, Hegde V. The triumvirate: why hypertension, obesity, and diabetes are risk factors for adverse effects in patients with COVID-19. Acta Diabetol. 2021;58(7):831-843. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00592-020-01636-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, Chen W, Zhang Z, et&#xa0;al. CD147-spike protein is a novel route for SARS-CoV-2 infection to host cells. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2020;5(1):283. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41392-020-00426-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghizlane EA, Manal M, Abderrahim EK, et&#xa0;al. Lymphopenia in Covid-19: a single center retrospective study of 589 cases. Ann Med Surg. 2021;69:102816. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amsu.2021.102816</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud AM, Ali MM. High glucose and advanced glycation end products induce cd147-mediated mmp activity in human adipocytes. Cells. 2021;10(8):2098. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells10082098</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao W, Min D, Twigg SM, et&#xa0;al. Monocyte CD147 is induced by advanced glycation end products and high glucose concentration: possible role in diabetic complications. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2010;299(5):C1212-C1219. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpcell.00228.2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berrou J, Fougeray S, Venot M, et&#xa0;al. Erratum: natural killer cell function, an important target for infection and tumor protection, is impaired in type 2 diabetes. PLoS One. 2014;9(1):e62418. PLoS ONE (2014) 9:1. https://doi.org/10.1371/annotation/c6fd65ca-7ab4-4407-ac23-2b9144073dce</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Park K, Lee SB, et&#xa0;al. Relationship between natural killer&#xa0;cell activity and glucose control in patients with type 2 diabetes and prediabetes. J Diabetes Investig. 2019;10(5):1223-1228. https://doi.org/10.1111/jdi.13002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao YC, Shen J, He L, et&#xa0;al. Changes of regulatory T cells and of proinflammatory and immunosuppressive cytokines in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Diabetes Res. 2016;2016:3694957. https://doi.org/10.1155/2016/3694957</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hull CM, Peakman M, Tree TIM. Regulatory T cell dysfunction in type 1 diabetes: what&#x2019;s broken and how can we fix it? Diabetologia. 2017;60(10):1839-1850. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-017-4377-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Chen F, Wang J, Zeng Z, Yang Q, Shao S. Th17 and Treg lymphocytes in obesity and Type 2 diabetic patients. Clin Immunol. 2018;197:77-85. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clim.2018.09.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzm&#xe1;n-Flores JM, Ram&#xed;rez-Emiliano J, P&#xe9;rez-V&#xe1;zquez V, L&#xf3;pez-Briones S. Th17 and regulatory T cells in patients with different time of progression of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Cent J Immunol. 2020;45(1):29-36. https://doi.org/10.5114/ceji.2020.94670</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar M, Roe K, Nerurkar PV, et&#xa0;al. Reduced immune cell infiltration and increased pro-inflammatory mediators in the brain of Type 2 diabetic mouse model infected with West Nile virus. J Neuroinflammation. 2014;11(1):80. https://doi.org/10.1186/1742-2094-11-80</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nojima I, Eikawa S, Tomonobu N, et&#xa0;al. Dysfunction of CD8 + PD-1 + T cells in type 2 diabetes caused by the impairment of metabolism-immune axis. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):14928. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-71946-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaminska H, Szarpak L, Kosior D, et&#xa0;al. Impact of diabetes mellitus on in-hospital mortality in adult patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Acta Diabetol. 2021;58(8):1101-1110. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00592-021-01701-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon C, Tokarev A, Bouchnita A, Volpert V. Modelling of the innate and adaptive immune response to SARS viral infection, cytokine storm and vaccination. Vaccines. 2023;11(1):127. https://doi.org/10.3390/vaccines11010127</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lecube A, Pach&#xf3;n G, Petriz J, Hern&#xe1;ndez C, Sim&#xf3; R. Phagocytic activity is impaired in type 2 diabetes mellitus and increases after metabolic improvement. PLoS One. 2011;6(8):e23366. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0023366</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlou S, Lindsay J, Ingram R, Xu H, Chen M. Sustained high glucose exposure sensitizes macrophage responses to cytokine stimuli but reduces their phagocytic activity. BMC Immunol. 2018;19(1):24. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12865-018-0261-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamer M, Gale CR, Batty GD. Diabetes, glycaemic control, and risk of COVID-19 hospitalisation: population-based, prospective cohort study. Metabolism. 2020;112:154344. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.metabol.2020.154344</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson EJ, Walker AJ, Bhaskaran K, et&#xa0;al. Factors associated&#xa0;with COVID-19-related death using OpenSAFELY. Nature. 2020;584(7821):430-436. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2521-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, She ZG, Cheng X, et&#xa0;al. Association of blood glucose control and outcomes in patients with COVID-19 and pre-existing type 2 diabetes. Cell Metab. 2020;31(6):1068-1077.e3. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2020.04.021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse J, Gay W, Korwek KM, et&#xa0;al. Hyperglycaemia increases mortality risk in non-diabetic patients with COVID-19 even more than in diabetic patients. Endocrinol Diabetes Metab. 2021;4(4):e00291. https://doi.org/10.1002/edm2.291</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhamar G, Maddaloni E, Al Shukry A, et&#xa0;al. Development of a clinical risk score to predict death in patients with COVID-19. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2022;38(5):e3526. https://doi.org/10.1002/dmrr.3526</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dispinseri S, Lampasona V, Secchi M, et&#xa0;al. Robust neutralizing antibodies to SARS-CoV-2 develop and persist in subjects with diabetes and COVID-19 pneumonia. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2021;106(5):1472-1481. https://doi.org/10.1210/clinem/dgab055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lampasona V, Secchi M, Scavini M, et&#xa0;al. Antibody response to multiple antigens of SARS-CoV-2 in patients with diabetes: an observational cohort study. Diabetologia. 2020;63(12):2548-2558. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-020-05284-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secchi M, Bazzigaluppi E, Brigatti C, et&#xa0;al. COVID-19 survival associates with the immunoglobulin response to the SARS-CoV-2 spike receptor binding domain. J Clin Invest. 2020;130(12):6366-6378. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI142804</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dispinseri S, Secchi M, Pirillo MF, et&#xa0;al. Neutralizing antibody responses to SARS-CoV-2 in symptomatic COVID-19 is persistent and critical for survival. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):2670. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-22958-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sourij C, Tripolt NJ, Aziz F, et&#xa0;al. Humoral immune response to COVID-19 vaccination in diabetes is age-dependent but independent of type of diabetes and glycaemic control: the prospective COVAC-DM cohort study. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2022;24(5):849-858. https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.14643</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marfella R, D&#x2019;Onofrio N, Sardu C, et&#xa0;al. Does poor glycaemic control affect the immunogenicity of the COVID-19 vaccination in patients with type 2 diabetes: the CAVEAT study. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2022;24(1):160-165. https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.14547</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billany RE, Selvaskandan H, Adenwalla SF, et&#xa0;al. Seroprevalence of antibody to S1 spike protein following vaccination against COVID-19 in patients receiving hemodialysis: a call to arms. Kidney Int. 2021;99(6):1492-1494. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.kint.2021.04.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitaker HJ, Tsang RSM, Byford R, et&#xa0;al. Pfizer-BioNTech and Oxford AstraZeneca COVID-19 vaccine effectiveness and immune response amongst individuals in clinical risk groups. J Infect. 2022;84(5):675-683. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2021.12.044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cromer D, Steain M, Reynaldi A, et&#xa0;al. Neutralising antibody titres as predictors of protection against SARS-CoV-2 variants and the impact of boosting: a meta-analysis. Lancet Microbe. 2022;3(1):e52-e61. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2666-5247(21)00267-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Berg JM, Remmelzwaal S, Blom MT, et&#xa0;al. Effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccines in adults with diabetes mellitus: a systematic review. Vaccines. 2023;11(1). https://doi.org/10.3390/vaccines11010024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali H, Alterki A, Sindhu S, et&#xa0;al. Robust antibody levels in both diabetic and non-diabetic individuals after BNT162b2 mRNA COVID-19 vaccination. Front Immunol. 2021;12. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.752233</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieralice S, D&#x2019;Onofrio L, Pozzilli P, Buzzetti R. Third dose of COVID-19 vaccine in diabetes: relevance of good metabolic control to improve its efficacy. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2022;38(5):e3533. https://doi.org/10.1002/dmrr.3533</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piotrowicz K, G&#x105;sowski J, Michel JP, Veronese N. Post-COVID-19 acute sarcopenia: physiopathology and management. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2021;33(10):2887-2898. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40520-021-01942-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Boon GJAM, Barco S, et&#xa0;al. The post-COVID-19 functional status scale: a tool to measure functional status over time after COVID-19. Eur Respir J. 2020;56(1):2001494. https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.01494-2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado FVC, Meys R, Delbressine JM, et&#xa0;al. Construct validity of the post-COVID-19 functional status scale in adult subjects with COVID-19. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2021;19(1):40. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12955-021-01691-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi B, Sudry T, Flaks-Manov N, et&#xa0;al. Long Covid outcomes at one year after mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: nationwide cohort study. Bmj. 2023:380. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj-2022-072529</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>