<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37324057</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1179-173X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Tobacco use insights</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Tob Use Insights</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Associations of Combustible Cigarette, Electronic Cigarette, and Dual Use With COVID Infection and Severity in the U.S.: A Cross-sectional Analysis of the 2021 National Health Information Survey.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1179173X231179675</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1179173X231179675</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1179173X231179675</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/1179173X231179675</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Given the potential respiratory health risks, the association of COVID infection and the use of combustible cigarettes, electronic nicotine delivery systems (ENDS), and concurrent dual use is a priority for public health. Many published reports have not accounted for known covarying factors. This study sought to calculate adjusted odds ratios for self-reported COVID infection and disease severity as a function of smoking and ENDS use, while accounting for factors known to influence COVID infection and disease severity (i.e., age, sex, race and ethnicity, socioeconomic status and educational attainment, rural or urban environment, self-reported diabetes, COPD, coronary heart disease, and obesity status). Data from the 2021 U.S. National Health Interview Survey, a cross-sectional questionnaire design, were used to calculate both unadjusted and adjusted odds ratios for self-reported COVID infection and severity of symptoms. Results indicate that combustible cigarette use is associated with a lower likelihood of self-reported COVID infection relative to non-use of tobacco products (AOR = .64; 95% CI [.55, .74]), whereas ENDS use is associated with a higher likelihood of self-reported COVID infection (AOR = 1.30; 95% CI [1.04, 1.63]). There was no significant difference in COVID infection among dual users (ENDS and combustible use) when compared with non-users. Adjusting for covarying factors did not substantially change the results. There were no significant differences in COVID disease severity between those of varying smoking status. Future research should examine the relationship between smoking status and COVID infection and disease severity utilizing longitudinal study designs and non-self-report measures of smoking status (e.g., the biomarker cotinine), COVID infection (e.g., positive tests), and disease severity (e.g., hospitalizations, ventilator assistance, mortality, and ongoing symptoms of long COVID).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moyers</LastName><ForeName>Susette A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Rural Health, Oklahoma State University Center for Health Sciences, Tulsa, OK, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">33264</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hartwell</LastName><ForeName>Micah</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Oklahoma State University Center for Health Sciences, Tulsa, OK, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">33264</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Office of Medical Student Research, Oklahoma State University College of Osteopathic Medicine, Tulsa, OK, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">33264</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiaf</LastName><ForeName>Ashleigh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Rural Health, Oklahoma State University Center for Health Sciences, Tulsa, OK, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">33264</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greiner</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12338</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliver</LastName><ForeName>Jason A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Oklahoma State University Center for Health Sciences, Tulsa, OK, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">33264</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>TSET Health Promotion Research Center, Stephenson Cancer Center, Oklahoma City, OK, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family and Preventive Medicine, University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center, Oklahoma City, OK, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">33264</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Croff</LastName><ForeName>Julie M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Rural Health, Oklahoma State University Center for Health Sciences, Tulsa, OK, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">33264</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K23 DA042898</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P20 GM109097</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01 DA055349</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Tob Use Insights</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101608659</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1179-173X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID severity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">combustible cigarette use</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electronic nicotine delivery system use</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smoking</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared the following potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: Dr. Hartwell receives research support through the National Institutes for Justice and the Health Resources Services Administration unrelated to the current work. Dr. Croff receives funding from the National Institutes for Health, Health Resources Services Administration, and the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration. Dr. Oliver receives funding from the National Institutes for Health and the Brain &amp; Behavior Research Foundation.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37324057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10262671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1179173X231179675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_1179173X231179675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bhatta DN, Glantz SA. Association of e-cigarette use with respiratory disease among adults: A longitudinal analysis. Am J Prev Med. 2020;58(2):182-190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6981012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31859175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goniewicz ML, Smith DM, Edwards KC, et al.Comparison of nicotine and toxicant exposure in users of electronic cigarettes and combustible cigarettes. JAMA Netw Open. 2018;1(8):e185937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6324349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30646298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osei AD, Mirbolouk M, Orimoloye OA, et al.Association between e-cigarette use and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease by smoking status: Behavioral risk factor surveillance system 2016 and 2017. Am J Prev Med. 2020;58(3):336-342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9843649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31902685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brake SJ, Barnsley K, Lu W, McAlinden KD, Eapen MS, Sohal SS. Smoking upregulates angiotensin-converting enzyme-2 receptor: A potential adhesion site for novel coronavirus SARS-CoV-2 (Covid-19). Journal of clinical medicine 2020;9(3):841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7141517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32244852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denholm JT, Gordon CL, Johnson PD, et al.Hospitalised adult patients with pandemic (H1N1) 2009 influenza in Melbourne, Australia. Med J Aust. 2010;192(2):84-86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20078408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arcavi L, Benowitz NL. Cigarette smoking and infection. Arch Intern Med. 2004;164(20):2206-2216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15534156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jindal S, Aggarwal A, Chaudhry K, et al.A multicentric study on epidemiology of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and its relationship with tobacco smoking and environmental tobacco smoke exposure. Indian J Chest Dis Allied Sci. 2006;48(1):23-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16482948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubin JH, Blot WJ, Berrino F, et al.Modifying risk of developing lung cancer by changing habits of cigarette smoking. Br Med J. 1984;288(6435):1953-1956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1442246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6428618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callahan-Lyon P. Electronic cigarettes: Human health effects. Tob Control. 2014;23 Suppl 2(suppl 2):ii36-ii40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3995250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24732161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schober W, Szendrei K, Matzen W, et al.Use of electronic cigarettes (e-cigarettes) impairs indoor air quality and increases FeNO levels of e-cigarette consumers. Int J Hyg Environ Health. 2014;217(6):628-637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24373737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pushalkar S, Paul B, Li Q, et al.Electronic cigarette aerosol modulates the oral microbiome and increases risk of infection. Iscience. 2020;23(3):100884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7113564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32105635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynos C, Bibli S-I, Katsaounou P, et al.Comparison of the effects of e-cigarette vapor with cigarette smoke on lung function and inflammation in mice. Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol. 2018;315(5):L662-L672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30091379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JB, Olgin JE, Nah G, et al.Cigarette and e-cigarette dual use and risk of cardiopulmonary symptoms in the health eHeart study. PloS one. 2018;13(7):e0198681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6059385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30044773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills TA, Pagano I, Williams RJ, Tam EK. E-cigarette use and respiratory disorder in an adult sample. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2019;194:363-370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6312492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30472577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan W-j, Liang W-h, He JX, Zhong NS. Comorbidity and its impact on 1590 patients with COVID-19 in China: A nationwide analysis. Eur Respir J. 2020;55(5):2001227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7098485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lusignan S, Dorward J, Correa A, et al.Risk factors for SARS-CoV-2 among patients in the Oxford royal college of general practitioners research and surveillance centre primary care network: A cross-sectional study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20(9):1034-1042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emami A, Javanmardi F, Pirbonyeh N, Akbari A. Prevalence of underlying diseases in hospitalized patients with COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Acad Emerg Med. 2020;8(1):e35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7096724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32232218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy RK, Charles WN, Sklavounos A, Dutt A, Seed PT, Khajuria A. The effect of smoking on COVID&#x2010;19 severity: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Med Virol. 2021;93(2):1045-1056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7436545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32749705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonica Singhal B, Celina Degano B, Sue K-O. Does vaping increase the risk of COVID-19 transmission and make individuals who vape susceptible to infection and prone to severe Illness? A review. J Can Dent Assoc. 2022;88(m1):1488-2159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35881057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Croft DP, Ossip DJ, Xie Z. The association between statewide vaping prevalence and COVID-19. Prev Med Rep. 2020;20:101254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7687362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaiha SM, Cheng J, Halpern-Felsher B. Association between youth smoking, electronic cigarette use, and COVID-19. J Adolesc Health. 2020;67(4):519-523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7417895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32798097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen DT-H, Kyriakos CN. Cigarette and E-cigarettes dual users, exclusive users and COVID-19: Findings from four UK birth cohort studies. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(8):3935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8069910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33918098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi G, Sanchis-Gomar F, Henry BM. Active smoking and COVID-19: A double-edged sword. Eur J Intern Med. 2020;77:123-124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7252038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32439289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Tao ZW, Wang L, et al.Analysis of factors associated with disease outcomes in hospitalized patients with 2019 novel coronavirus disease. Chin Med J. 2020;133:1032-1038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7147279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32118640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Q, Meng M, Kumar R, et al.The impact of COPD and smoking history on the severity of COVID&#x2010;19: A systemic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Med Virol. 2020;92(10):1915-1921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32293753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Z, Peng F, Xu B, et al.Risk factors of critical &amp; mortal COVID-19 cases: A systematic literature review and meta-analysis. J Infect. 2020;81(2):e16-e25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7177098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32335169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong R, Chen L, Zhang Q, et al.Which factors, smoking, drinking alcohol, betel quid chewing, or underlying diseases, are more likely to influence the severity of COVID-19? Front Physiol. 2021;11:1836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7849623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33536941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi G, Wong J, Henry BM. Hypertension in patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): A pooled analysis. Pol Arch Intern Med. 2020;130(4):304-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32231171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappuccio FP, Siani A. Covid-19 and cardiovascular risk: Susceptibility to infection to SARS-CoV-2, severity and prognosis of Covid-19 and blockade of the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system. An evidence-based viewpoint. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2020;30(8):1227-1235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7256508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32595085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Arora A, Sharma P, et al.Is diabetes mellitus associated with mortality and severity of COVID-19? A meta-analysis. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2020;14(4):535-545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7200339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32408118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olloquequi J. COVID&#x2010;19 Susceptibility in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Eur J Clin Invest. 2020;50(10):e13382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7435530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32780415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pranata R, Soeroto A, Huang I, et al.Effect of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and smoking on the outcome of COVID-19. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2020;24(8):838-843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32912389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freuer D, Linseisen J, Meisinger C. Impact of body composition on COVID-19 susceptibility and severity: A two-sample multivariable Mendelian randomization study. Metabolism. 2021;118:154732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7900753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33631142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong A, Cole JB, Brenner LN, Meigs JB, Florez JC, Mercader JM. Cardiometabolic risk factors for COVID-19 susceptibility and severity: A Mendelian randomization analysis. PLoS Med. 2021;18(3):e1003553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7971850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33661905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim L, Garg S, O&#x2019;Halloran Aet al.. Risk factors for intensive care unit admission and in-hospital mortality among hospitalized adults identified through the US coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19)-associated hospitalization surveillance network (COVID-NET). Clinical infectious diseases 2021;72(9):e206-e214. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciaa1012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciaa1012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32674114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patanavanich R, Glantz SA. Smoking is associated with worse outcomes of COVID-19 particularly among younger adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Public Health. 2021;21(1):1554-1559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8366155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34399729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai H. Sex difference and smoking predisposition in patients with COVID-19. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8(4):e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7103991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32171067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter LA, McGregor AJ. Sex-and gender-specific observations and implications for COVID-19. West J Emerg Med. 2020;21(3):507-509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7234726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32302282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcendor DJ. Racial disparities-associated COVID-19 mortality among minority populations in the US. J Clin Med. 2020;9(8):2442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7466083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32751633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anaele BI, Doran C, McIntire R. Visualizing COVID-19 mortality rates and African-American populations in the USA and Pennsylvania. J Racial Ethn Health Disparities. 2021;8(6):1356-1363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7872308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33565050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Kumar P, Kodidela S, et al.Racial health disparity and COVID-19. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2021;16:729-742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8426163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34499313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rentsch CT, Kidwai-Khan F, Tate JP, et al.Covid-19 testing, hospital admission, and intensive care among 2,026,227 United States veterans aged 54&#x2013;75 years. MedRxiv. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson SE, Brown J, Shahab L, Steptoe A, Fancourt D. COVID-19, smoking and inequalities: A study of 53 002 adults in the UK. Tob Control. 2021;30(e2):e111-e121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakhani HV, Pillai SS, Zehra M, Sharma I, Sodhi K. Systematic review of clinical insights into novel coronavirus (CoVID-19) pandemic: Persisting challenges in US rural population. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(12):4279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7345039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32549334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul R, Arif AA, Adeyemi O, Ghosh S, Han D. Progression of COVID&#x2010;19 from urban to rural areas in the United States: A spatiotemporal analysis of prevalence rates. J Rural Health. 2020;36(4):591-601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32602983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souch JM, Cossman JS. A commentary on rural&#x2010;urban disparities in COVID&#x2010;19 testing rates per 100,000 and risk factors. J Rural Health. 2021;37:188-190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32282964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Disease Control and Prevention . National Health Interview Survey 2020. Published online September 28 AF, 2022https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/nhis/2020nhis.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Rio C, Malani PN, Omer SB. Confronting the delta variant of SARS-CoV-2, summer 2021. Jama. 2021;326(11):1001-1002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34406361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisman DN, Tuite AR. Progressive increase in virulence of novel SARS-CoV-2 variants in Ontario, Canada. MedRxiv. 2021;2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8562985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34610919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheikh A, McMenamin J, Taylor B, Robertson C. SARS-CoV-2 delta VOC in Scotland: Demographics, risk of hospital admission, and vaccine effectiveness. Lancet. 2021;397(10293):2461-2462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8201647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34139198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krebs NM, D&#x2019;Souza G, Bordner C, et al.COVID-19 vaccination uptake and hesitancy among current tobacco users. Tob Use Insights. 2021;14:1179173X211068027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8721404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34987300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becerra MB, Becerra BJ. COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy among behavioral risk takers. Vaccines. 2022;10(5):767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9144473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35632523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao S, Singh M. The newly detected B. 1.1. 529 (Omicron) variant of SARS-CoV-2 with multiple mutations: Implications for transmission, diagnostics, therapeutics, and immune evasion. DHR proceedings. 2021;1(S5):7-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simons D, Shahab L, Brown J, Perski O. The association of smoking status with SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection, hospitalization and mortality from COVID&#x2010;19: A living rapid evidence review with Bayesian meta&#x2010;analyses (version 7). Addiction. 2021;116(6):1319-1368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7590402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33007104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abadom TR, Smith AD, Tempia S, Madhi SA, Cohen C, Cohen AL. Risk factors associated with hospitalisation for influenza-associated severe acute respiratory illness in South Africa: A case-population study. Vaccine. 2016;34(46):5649-5655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5714809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27720448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dye JA, Adler KB. Effects of cigarette smoke on epithelial cells of the respiratory tract. Thorax. 1994;49(8):825-834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC475133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8091331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Junqueira C, Crespo &#xc2;, Ranjbar S, et al.Fc&#x3b3;R-mediated SARS-CoV-2 infection of monocytes activates inflammation. Nature. 2022;606:576-584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10071495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35385861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beamer PI, Plotkin KR, Gerba CP, Sifuentes LY, Koenig DW, Reynolds KA. Modeling of human viruses on hands and risk of infection in an office workplace using micro-activity data. J Occup Environ Hyg. 2015;12(4):266-275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4455933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25436665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An LC, Berg CJ, Klatt CM, et al.Symptoms of cough and shortness of breath among occasional young adult smokers. Nicotine Tob Res. 2009;11(2):126-133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2658904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19264863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office on Smoking and Health NCfCDPaHP, https://www.cdc.gov/statesystem/factsheets/ecigarette/EcigSFIA.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz CM, Staley ME, Kearley J, et al.E-cigarette sharing behavior among college students: An exploratory study. J Am Coll Health. 2020;70:1297-1300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32877620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;lsen A, Yigitbas BA, Uslu B, Dr&#xf6;mann D, Kilinc O. The effect of smoking on COVID-19 symptom severity: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Pulm Med. 2020;2020:7590207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7499286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32963831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis SJ, Cherry NM, MclNiven R, Barber PV, Wilde K, Povey AC. Cotinine levels and self-reported smoking status in patients attending a bronchoscopy clinic. Biomarkers. 2003;8(3-4):218-228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12944174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Yu Y, Zhao Y, He D. Reduction in the infection fatality rate of Omicron variant compared with previous variants in South Africa. Int J Infect Dis. 2022;120:146-149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9022446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35462038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. . Clinical management of COVID-19: Interim guidance. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization. https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/332196 (2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>