<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39034480</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1467-9450</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scandinavian journal of psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of the symptom networks of long-COVID and chronic fatigue syndrome: From modularity to connectionism.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sjop.13060</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The objective was to compare the symptom networks of long-COVID and chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS) in conjunction with other theoretically relevant diagnoses in order to provide insight into the etiology of medically unexplained symptoms (MUS). This was a cross-sectional comparison of questionnaire items between six groups identified by clinical diagnosis. All participants completed a 65-item psychological and somatic symptom questionnaire (GSQ065). Diagnostically labelled groups were long-COVID (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;107), CFS (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;254), irritable bowel syndrome (IBS, N&#x2009;=&#x2009;369), fibromyalgia (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;1,127), severe asthma (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;100) and healthy group (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;207). The 22 symptoms that best discriminated between the six groups were selected for network analysis. Connectivity, fragmentation and number of symptom clusters (statistically related symptoms) were assessed. Compared to long-COVID, the symptom networks of CFS, IBS and fibromyalgia had significantly lower connectivity, greater fragmentation and more symptom clusters. The number of clusters varied between 9 for CFS and 3 for severe asthma, and the content of clusters varied across all groups. Of the 33 symptom clusters identified over the six groups 30 clusters were unique. Although the symptom networks of long-COVID and CFS differ, the variation of cluster content across the six groups is inconsistent with a modular causal structure but consistent with a connectionist (network, parallel distributed processing) biological basis of MUS. A connectionist structure would explain why symptoms overlap and merge between different functional somatic syndromes, the failure to discover a biological diagnostic test and how psychological and behavioral interventions are therapeutic.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Scandinavian Journal of Psychology published by Scandinavian Psychological Associations and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hyland</LastName><ForeName>Michael E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3879-0469</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Plymouth, Plymouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Antonacci</LastName><ForeName>Yuri</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bacon</LastName><ForeName>Alison M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Plymouth, Plymouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Scand J Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0404510</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0036-5564</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">asthma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic fatigue syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fibromyalgia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long&#x2010;COVID</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39034480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sjop.13060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Antonacci, Y., Astolfi, L., Nollo, G. &amp; Faes, L. (2020). Information transfer in linear multivariate processes assessed through penalized regression techniques: Validation and application to physiological networks. Entropy, 22, 732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astin, R., Banerjee, A., Baker, M.R., Dani, M., Ford, E., Hull, J.H. et&#xa0;al. (2023). Long COVID: Mechanisms, risk factors and recovery. Experimental Physiology, 108, 12&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barsky, A.J. &amp; Borus, J.F. (1999). Functional somatic syndromes. Annals of Internal Medicine, 130, 910&#x2013;921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedetti, F., Carlino, E. &amp; Pollo, A. (2011). How placebos change the patient's brain. Neuropsychopharmacology, 36, 339&#x2013;354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boomershine, C. (2015). Fibromyalgia: The prototypical central sensitivity syndrome. Current Rheumatology Reviews, 11, 131&#x2013;145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsboom, D. &amp; Cramer, A.O. (2013). Network analysis: An integrative approach to the structure of psychopathology. Annual Review of Clinical Psychology, 9, 91&#x2013;121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne, E.A. (2022). Understanding long covid: Nosology, social attitudes and stigma. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 99, 17&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban, F., Ling, S., Lui, L.M., Lee, Y., Gill, H., Teopiz, K.M. et&#xa0;al. (2022). Fatigue and cognitive impairment in post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 101, 93&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis, R. &amp; Humphreys, G.W. (1999). Connectionist psychology: A text with readings. London: Taylor &amp; Francis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epskamp, S., Borsboom, D. &amp; Fried, E.I. (2018). Estimating psychological networks and their accuracy: A tutorial paper. Behavior Research Methods, 50, 195&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faes, L., Porta, A. &amp; Nollo, G. (2015). Information decomposition in bivariate systems: Theory and application to cardiorespiratory dynamics. Entropy, 17, 277&#x2013;303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontesse, S., Fournier, V., G&#xe9;rain, P., Dassonneville, C., Lelorain, S., Duprez, C. et&#xa0;al. (2023). Happy thus survivor? A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis on the association between cancer survival and positive states, emotions, and traits. Psycho&#x2010;Oncology, 32, 1631&#x2013;1643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giral, C.R.M., Diaz&#x2010;Manchay, R. &amp; Leon&#x2010;Jimenez, F. (2021). Fibromyalgia: The underdiagnosed disease of pain. Reumatologia/Rheumatology, 59, 64&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golino, H.F. &amp; Epskamp, S. (2017). Exploratory graph analysis: A new approach for estimating the number of dimensions in psychological research. PLoS One, 12(6), e0174035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Hermosillo, J.A., Mart&#xed;nez&#x2010;L&#xf3;pez, J.P., Carrillo&#x2010;Lamp&#xf3;n, S.A., Ruiz&#x2010;Ojeda, D., Herrera&#x2010;Ram&#xed;rez, S., Amezcua&#x2010;Guerra, L.M. et&#xa0;al. (2021). Post&#x2010;acute COVID&#x2010;19 symptoms, a potential link with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: A 6&#x2010;month survey in a Mexican cohort. Brain Sciences, 11, 760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gy&#xf6;ngy&#xf6;si, M., Alcaide, P., Asselbergs, F.W., Brundel, B.J., Camici, G.G., Martins, P.D.C. et&#xa0;al. (2023). Long COVID and the cardiovascular system &#x2013; elucidating causes and cellular mechanisms in order to develop targeted diagnostic and therapeutic strategies: A joint scientific statement of the ESC Working Groups on Cellular Biology Of The Heart and Myocardial and Pericardial Diseases. Cardiovascular Research, 119, 336&#x2013;356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson, M.R. (2023). The viral origin of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. PLoS Pathogens, 19, e1011523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haslbeck, J.M.B. &amp; Waldorp, L.J. (2020). mgm: Estimating time&#x2010;varying mixed graphical models in high&#x2010;dimensional data. Journal of Statistical Software, 93, 1&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyland, M. E. (2011). The origins of health and disease. Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyland, M.E., Bacon, A.M., Lanario, J.W. &amp; Davies, A.F. (2019). Symptom frequency and development of a generic functional disorder symptom scale suitable for use in studies of patients with irritable bowel syndrome, fibromyalgia syndrome or chronic fatigue syndrome. Chronic Diseases and Translational Medicine, 5, 129&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyland, M.E., Lanario, J.W., Wei, Y., Jones, R.C. &amp; Masoli, M. (2019). Evidence for similarity in symptoms and mechanism: The extra&#x2010;pulmonary symptoms of severe asthma and the polysymptomatic presentation of fibromyalgia. Immunity, Inflammation and Disease, 7, 239&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivanov, P.C. (2021). The new field of network physiology: Building the human physiolome. Frontiers in Network Physiology, 1, 711778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanbara, K., Fukunaga, M., Mutsuura, H., Takeuchi, H., Kitamura, K. &amp; Nakai, Y. (2007). An exploratory study of subgrouping of patients with functional somatic syndrome based on the psychophysiological stress response: Its relationship with moods and subjective variables. Psychosomatic Medicine, 69, 158&#x2013;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kersten, J., Baumhardt, M., Hartveg, P., Hoyo, L., H&#xfc;ll, E., Imhof, A. et&#xa0;al. (2021). Long COVID: Distinction between organ damage and deconditioning. Journal of Clinical Medicine, 10, 3782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirsch, I. (2010). The emperor's new drugs: Exploding the antidepressant myth. New York: Basic Books.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraskov, A., St&#xf6;gbauer, H. &amp; Grassberger, P. (2004). Estimating mutual information. Physical Review. E, Statistical, Nonlinear, and Soft Matter Physics, 69, 066138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kujawski, S., S&#x142;omko, J., Newton, J.L., Eaton&#x2010;Fitch, N., Staines, D.R., Marshall&#x2010;Gradisnik, S. et&#xa0;al. (2021). Network analysis of symptoms co&#x2010;occurrence in chronic fatigue syndrome. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 18, 10736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, C.H. &amp; Giuliani, F. (2019). The role of inflammation in depression and fatigue. Frontiers in Immunology, 10, 463031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, D., Epskamp, S., Isvoranu, A.M., Chen, C., Liu, W. &amp; Hong, X. (2021). Network analysis of physical and psychiatric symptoms of hospital discharged patients infected with COVID&#x2010;19. Journal of Affective Disorders, 294, 707&#x2013;713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malkova, A.M. &amp; Shoenfeld, Y. (2023). Autoimmune autonomic nervous system imbalance and conditions: Chronic fatigue syndrome, fibromyalgia, silicone breast implants, COVID and post&#x2010;COVID syndrome, sick building syndrome, post&#x2010;orthostatic tachycardia syndrome, autoimmune diseases and autoimmune/inflammatory syndrome induced by adjuvants. Autoimmunity Reviews, 22, 103230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez&#x2010;Moragon, E., Plaza, V., Torres, I., Rosado, A., Urrutia, I., Casas, X. et&#xa0;al. (2017). Fibromyalgia as a cause of uncontrolled asthma: A case&#x2013;control multicenter study. Current Medical Research and Opinion, 33, 2181&#x2013;2186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKechnie, F. (2023). Mindfulness&#x2010;based therapy for managing fatigue: Supporting people with ME/CFS, fibromyalgia and long Covid. London, UK: Jessica Kingsley Publishers.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melidis, C., Denham, S.L. &amp; Hyland, M.E. (2018). A test of the adaptive network explanation of functional disorders using a machine learning analysis of symptoms. Biosystems, 165, 22&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi, B., Sudry, T., Flaks&#x2010;Manov, N., Yehezkelli, Y., Kalkstein, N., Akiva, P. et&#xa0;al. (2023). Long covid outcomes at one year after mild SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection: Nationwide cohort study. BMJ, 380, e072529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nacul, L., O'Boyle, S., Palla, L., Nacul, F.E., Mudie, K., Kingdon, C.C. et&#xa0;al. (2020). How myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) progresses: The natural history of ME/CFS. Frontiers in Neurology, 11, 826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimnuan, C., Hotopf, M. &amp; Wessely, S. (2001). Medically unexplained symptoms: An epidemiological study in seven specialities. Journal of Psychosomatic Research, 51, 361&#x2013;367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura, K., Nakayasu, K., Mori, M., Sanda, R., Shibayama, A. &amp; Kusunose, M. (2021). Are fatigue and pain overlooked in subjects with stable chronic obstructive pulmonary disease? Diagnostics, 11, 2029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okayama, T., Suzuki, K., Morishita, S., Inoue, J., Tanaka, T., Nakano, J. et&#xa0;al. (2024). Pretreatment quality of life and survival in patients with lung cancer: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. BMC Cancer, 24, 495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios, N., Fitzgerald, K.C., Komaroff, A.L. &amp; Ascherio, A. (2017). Incidence of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome in a large prospective cohort of US nurses. Fatigue: Biomedicine, Health &amp; Behavior, 5, 159&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennebaker, J.W. (2012). The psychology of physical symptoms. New York: Springer Science &amp; Business Media.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penninx, B.W., Kritchevsky, S.B., Yaffe, K., Newman, A.B., Simonsick, E.M., Rubin, S. et&#xa0;al. (2003). Inflammatory markers and depressed mood in older persons: Results from the health, aging and body composition study. Biological Psychiatry, 54, 566&#x2013;572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pompili, M., Magistri, C., Maddalena, S., Mellini, C., Persechino, S. &amp; Baldessarini, R.J. (2021). Risk of depression associated with finasteride treatment. Journal of Clinical Psychopharmacology, 41, 304&#x2013;309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pons, P. &amp; Latapy, M. (2005). Computing communities in large networks using random walks. In P. Yolum, T. G&#xfc;ng&#xf6;r, F. G&#xfc;rgen &amp; C. &#xd6;zturan (Eds.), Computer and information sciences &#x2013; ISCIS 2005. ISCIS 2005. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (Vol. 3733). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/11569596_31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche, K.N., Cooper, D., Armstrong, T.S. &amp; King, A.L. (2023). The link between psychological distress and survival in solid tumor patients: A systematic review. Cancer Medicine, 12, 3343&#x2013;3364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenkranz, M.A., Esnault, S., Christian, B.T., Crisafi, G., Gresham, L.K., Higgins, A.T. et&#xa0;al. (2016). Mind&#x2010;body interactions in the regulation of airway inflammation in asthma: A PET study of acute and chronic stress. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 58, 18&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosvall, M. &amp; Bergstrom, C.T. (2008). Maps of random walks on complex networks reveal community structure. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 105, 1118&#x2013;1123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sansing&#x2010;Foster, V., Haug, N., Mosholder, A., Cocoros, N.M., Bradley, M., Ma, Y. et&#xa0;al. (2021). Risk of psychiatric adverse events among montelukast users. The Journal of Allergy and Clinical Immunology. In Practice, 9, 385&#x2013;393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel, J.S., Shulman, G.L. &amp; Corbetta, M. (2022). Mapping correlated neurological deficits after stroke to distributed brain networks. Brain Structure and Function, 227, 3173&#x2013;3187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinden, N.J. &amp; Stockley, R.A. (2010). Systemic inflammation and comorbidity in COPD: A result of &#x201c;overspill&#x201d; of inflammatory mediators from the lungs? Review of the evidence. Thorax, 65, 930&#x2013;936.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone, J., Wojcik, W., Durrance, D., Carson, A., Lewis, S., MacKenzie, L. et&#xa0;al. (2002). What should we say to patients with symptoms unexplained by disease? The &#x201c;number needed to offend.&#x201d;. BMJ, 325, 1449&#x2013;1450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone, M.B., Yaseen, Z.S., Miller, B.J., Richardville, K., Kalaria, S.N. &amp; Kirsch, I. (2022). Response to acute monotherapy for major depressive disorder in randomized, placebo controlled trials submitted to the US Food and Drug Administration: Individual participant data analysis. BMJ, 378, e067606. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj&#x2010;2021&#x2010;067606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tate, W., Walker, M., Peppercorn, K. &amp; Chatterjee, A. (2022). Molecular mechanisms of neuroinflammation in ME/CFS and long COVID to sustain disease and promote relapses. Frontiers in Neurology, 13, 877772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uhde, M., Indart, A.C., Green, P.H., Yolken, R.H., Cook, D.B., Shukla, S.K. et&#xa0;al. (2023). Suppressed immune and metabolic responses to intestinal damage&#x2010;associated microbial translocation in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Brain, Behavior &amp; Immunity&#x2010;Health, 30, 100627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaes, A.W., Go&#xeb;rtz, Y.M., Van Herck, M., Machado, F.V., Meys, R., Delbressine, J.M. et&#xa0;al. (2021). Recovery from COVID&#x2010;19: A sprint or marathon? 6&#x2010;month follow&#x2010;up data from online long COVID&#x2010;19 support group members. ERJ Open Research, 7, 00141&#x2010;2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Meulen, M.L., Bos, M., Bakker, S.J., Gans, R.O. &amp; Rosmalen, J.G. (2024). Validity and diagnostic overlap of functional somatic syndrome diagnoses. Journal of Psychosomatic Research, 181, 111673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wessely, S., Nimnuan, C. &amp; Sharpe, M. (1999). Functional somatic syndromes: One or many? The Lancet, 354, 936&#x2013;939.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White, P.D. (2010). Chronic fatigue syndrome: Is it one discrete syndrome or many? Implications for the &#x201c;one vs. many&#x201d; functional somatic syndromes debate. Journal of Psychosomatic Research, 68, 455&#x2013;459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, T.L. &amp; Weitzer, D.J. (2021). Long COVID and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) &#x2013; a systemic review and comparison of clinical presentation and symptomatology. Medicina, 57, 418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright, P., Parker, M. C. &amp; Lord, A. (2013). Simulation results of Shannon entropy based flexgrid routing and spectrum assignment on a real network topology. In 39th European conference and exhibition on optical communication (ECOC 2013) (pp. 1&#x2013;3). IET. https://doi.org/10.1049/cp.2013.1428</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, C.P., Chang, C.M., Yang, C.C., Pariante, C.M. &amp; Su, K.P. (2022). Long COVID and long chain fatty acids (LCFAs): Psychoneuroimmunity implication of omega&#x2010;3 LCFAs in delayed consequences of COVID&#x2010;19. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 103, 19&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, E., Baker, Y., Ravikumar, P., Allen, G. &amp; Liu, Z. (2014). Mixed graphical models via exponential families. Proceedings of the Seventeenth International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics, in Proceedings of Machine Learning Research, 33, 1042&#x2013;1050. Available from https://proceedings.mlr.press/v33/yang14a.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yunus, M.B. (2007). Fibromyalgia and overlapping disorders: The unifying concept of central sensitivity syndromes. Seminars in Arthritis and Rheumatism, 36, 339&#x2013;356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zachar, P. &amp; Kendler, K.S. (2017). The philosophy of nosology. Annual Review of Clinical Psychology, 13, 49&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>