<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36631024</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1598-6357</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>46</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of Korean medical science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Korean Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID-19 and Health-Related Quality of Life of Mild Cases in Korea: 3-Months Follow-up of a Single Community Treatment Center.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e326</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e326</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e326</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3346/jkms.2022.37.e326</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (coronavirus disease 2019 [COVID-19]) survivors mount as the pandemic continues. To date, studies on persistent symptoms and their effects on health-related quality of life (HRQoL) in mild COVID-19 cases have been limited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A prospective online survey was conducted in COVID-19 patients who were admitted to Seongnam Community Treatment Center, an isolation center in South Korea, from November 23rd 2021 to January 2nd 2022. Patients above the age of 19 with no or mild symptoms were included in the study. Total of 147 patients returned to the follow-up survey 3 months after discharge. Baseline demographics, clinical characteristics, symptoms, and EuroQol-5 dimensions-5 levels (EQ-5D-5L) measures were investigated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The median (interquartile range [IQR]) interval period between the initial and follow-up survey was 96.0 (93.0-98.0) days. The median (IQR) age of participants was 51.0 (43.0-61.0). During isolation, 131 (89.1%) patients manifested symptoms. On follow-up, 82 (55.8%) participants remained symptomatic. Common symptoms were constitutional (fatigue, myalgia), neurological (memory impairment, hyposmia, hypogeusia, dizziness), and neuropsychiatric (anxiety) symptoms. Participants with remaining neuropsychiatric symptoms reported the lowest EQ-5D-5L index values. Factors associated with persistent symptoms and diminished HRQoL were identified as female sex, metabolic disease, and anxiety during acute COVID-19 phase.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Cardiopulmonary symptoms improved over time but constitutional, neurological, neuropsychiatric symptoms remained. Patients with neuropsychiatric symptoms (anxiety and insomnia) reported the worst HRQoL. Female sex, metabolic disease, and anxiety during the acute COVID-19 phase were associated with long COVID. Observations of long-term symptoms of COVID-19 with decline in HRQoL and integrated research in COVID-19 survivors are warranted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Korean Academy of Medical Sciences.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soh</LastName><ForeName>Hi Sun</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4192-300X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cho</LastName><ForeName>BeLong</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9558-689X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute on Aging, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea. belong@snu.ac.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Korean Med Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8703518</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1011-8934</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality of Life</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056910" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Republic of Korea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HRQoL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health-Related Quality of Life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Persistent Symptoms</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no potential conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36631024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9705205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3346/jkms.2022.37.e326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">37.e326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dong E, Du H, Gardner L. An interactive web-based dashboard to track COVID-19 in real time. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20(5):533&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32087114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Our World in Data. Daily new confirmed COVID-19 deaths per million people.  [Updated 2022].  [Accessed May 5, 2022].  
 https://ourworldindata.org/explorers/coronavirus-data-explorer
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Hu B, Hu C, Zhu F, Liu X, Zhang J, et al. Clinical characteristics of 138 hospitalized patients with 2019 novel coronavirus-infected pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA. 2020;323(11):1061&#x2013;1069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MK, Lee B, Choi YY, Um J, Lee KS, Sung HK, et al. Clinical characteristics of 40 patients infected with the SARS-CoV-2 omicron variant in Korea. J Korean Med Sci. 2022;37(3):e31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8763884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35040299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M. Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nat Immunol. 2022;23(2):194&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594(7862):259&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salamanna F, Veronesi F, Martini L, Landini MP, Fini M. Post-COVID-19 syndrome: the persistent symptoms at the post-viral stage of the disease. A systematic review of the current data. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021;8:653516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8129035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34017846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KG, Brokstad KA, Zhou F, Linchausen DW, Hansen BA, et al. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med. 2021;27(9):1607&#x2013;1613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns Hopkins Coronavirus Resource Center. COVID-19 dashboard.  [Updated 2022].  [Accessed May 2, 2022].  
 https://coronavirus.jhu.edu/map.html
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herdman M, Gudex C, Lloyd A, Janssen M, Kind P, Parkin D, et al. Development and preliminary testing of the new five-level version of EQ-5D (EQ-5D-5L) Qual Life Res. 2011;20(10):1727&#x2013;1736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3220807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21479777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finch AP, Brazier JE, Mukuria C. What is the evidence for the performance of generic preference-based measures? A systematic overview of reviews. Eur J Health Econ. 2018;19(4):557&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5913394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28560520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SH, Ahn J, Ock M, Shin S, Park J, Luo N, et al. The EQ-5D-5L valuation study in Korea. Qual Life Res. 2016;25(7):1845&#x2013;1852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26961008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding H, Yin S, Cheng Y, Cai Y, Huang W, Deng W. Neurologic manifestations of nonhospitalized patients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China. MedComm (2020) 2020;1(2):253&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7362024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34172986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xe9;nat JM, Blais-Rochette C, Kokou-Kpolou CK, Noorishad PG, Mukunzi JN, McIntee SE, et al. Prevalence of symptoms of depression, anxiety, insomnia, posttraumatic stress disorder, and psychological distress among populations affected by the COVID-19 pandemic: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res. 2021;295:113599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7689353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33285346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E, Kweon Y, Hwang Y, An M. Health-related quality of life and its related factors among cancer survivors and general adults: focusing on lifestyle behaviors and mental health. Korean J Adult Nurs. 2020;32(4):385&#x2013;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):626&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Self WH, Adams K, Gaglani M, Ginde AA, McNeal T, et al. Association between mRNA vaccination and COVID-19 hospitalization and disease severity. JAMA. 2021;326(20):2043&#x2013;2054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8569602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34734975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Self WH, Tenforde MW, Rhoads JP, Gaglani M, Ginde AA, Douin DJ, et al. Comparative effectiveness of Moderna, Pfizer-BioNTech, and Janssen (Johnson &amp; Johnson) vaccines in preventing COVID-19 hospitalizations among adults without immunocompromising conditions - United States, March-August 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2021;70(38):1337&#x2013;1343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34555004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker HA, Safavynia SA, Evered LA. The &#x2018;third wave&#x2019;: impending cognitive and functional decline in COVID-19 survivors. Br J Anaesth. 2021;126(1):44&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7577658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33187638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad I, Rathore FA. Neurological manifestations and complications of COVID-19: a literature review. J Clin Neurosci. 2020;77:8&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7200361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32409215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rybak LP. Metabolic disorders of the vestibular system. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 1995;112(1):128&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7816447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh P, Jain A, Kaur G. Impact of hypoglycemia and diabetes on CNS: correlation of mitochondrial oxidative stress with DNA damage. Mol Cell Biochem. 2004;260(1-2):153&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15228097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauro C, De Rosa V, Marelli-Berg F, Solito E. Metabolic syndrome and the immunological affair with the blood-brain barrier. Front Immunol. 2015;5:677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4283608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25601869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh MV, Chapleau MW, Harwani SC, Abboud FM. The immune system and hypertension. Immunol Res. 2014;59(1-3):243&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4313884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24847766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerges Harb J, Noureldine HA, Chedid G, Eldine MN, Abdallah DA, Chedid NF, et al. SARS, MERS and COVID-19: clinical manifestations and organ-system complications: a mini review. Pathog Dis. 2020;78(4):ftaa033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32633327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HC, Yoo SY, Lee BH, Lee SH, Shin HS. Psychiatric findings in suspected and confirmed Middle East respiratory syndrome patients quarantined in hospital: a retrospective chart analysis. Psychiatry Investig. 2018;15(4):355&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5912494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29593206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam MH, Wing YK, Yu MW, Leung CM, Ma RC, Kong AP, et al. Mental morbidities and chronic fatigue in severe acute respiratory syndrome survivors: long-term follow-up. Arch Intern Med. 2009;169(22):2142&#x2013;2147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20008700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed H, Patel K, Greenwood DC, Halpin S, Lewthwaite P, Salawu A, et al. Long-term clinical outcomes in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus outbreaks after hospitalisation or ICU admission: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Rehabil Med. 2020;52(5):jrm00063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32449782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J, Kremer S, Merdji H, Clere-Jehl R, Schenck M, Kummerlen C, et al. Neurologic features in severe SARS-CoV-2 infection. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(23):2268&#x2013;2270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7179967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32294339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Middle East Respiratory Syndrome. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Summary of probable SARS cases with onset of illness from 1 November 2002 to 31 July 2003.  [Updated 2015].  [Accessed April 29, 2022].  
 https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/summary-of-probable-sars-cases-with-onset-of-illness-from-1-november-2002-to-31-july-2003
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues E, Janvier P, Kherabi Y, Le Bot A, Hamon A, Gouze H, et al. Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. J Infect. 2020;81(6):e4&#x2013;e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arab-Zozani M, Hashemi F, Safari H, Yousefi M, Ameri H. Health-related quality of life and its associated factors in COVID-19 patients. Osong Public Health Res Perspect. 2020;11(5):296&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7577388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33117634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez O, Merino E, Leon-Ramirez JM, Andres M, Ramos JM, Arenas-Jim&#xe9;nez J, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: a Mediterranean cohort study. J Infect. 2021;82(3):378&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7802523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson KB, Rao M, Bonilla H, Subramanian A, Hack I, Madrigal M, et al. Patients with uncomplicated coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) have long-term persistent symptoms and functional impairment similar to patients with severe COVID-19: a cautionary tale during a global pandemic. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73(3):e826&#x2013;e829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33624010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez R, Balanz&#xe1;-Mart&#xed;nez V, Luperdi SC, Estrada I, Latorre A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Jim&#xe9;nez P, et al. Short-term neuropsychiatric outcomes and quality of life in COVID-19 survivors. J Intern Med. 2021;290(3):621&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33533521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Florencio LL, Cuadrado ML, Plaza-Manzano G, et al. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Intern Med. 2021;92:55&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34167876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go&#xeb;rtz YMJ, Van Herck M, Delbressine JM, Vaes AW, Meys R, Machado FVC, et al. Persistent symptoms 3 months after a SARS-CoV-2 infection: the post-COVID-19 syndrome? ERJ Open Res. 2020;6(4):00542-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik P, Patel K, Pinto C, Jaiswal R, Tirupathi R, Pillai S, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PCS) and health-related quality of life (HRQoL)-a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2022;94(1):253&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34463956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>