<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37805875</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1512-0112</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Issue>340-341</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Season>Jul-Aug</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Georgian medical news</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Georgian Med News</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>SARS-COV-2 INFECTION AND INVOLVEMENT OF PERIPHERAL NERVOUS SYSTEM: A CASE SERIES OF CARPAL TUNNEL SYNDROME AGGRAVATION OR NEW ONSET WITH COVID-19 DISEASE AND A REVIEW OF LITERATURE.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>61</StartPage><EndPage>66</EndPage><MedlinePgn>61-66</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>COVID-19 may be asymptomatic or have a typical presentation with fever, cough, anosmia, lymphocytopenia. In some cases, it occurs with a "chimeric" presentation, with more subtle and ambiguous symptoms which may be initially misdiagnosed and are referred to in long covid condition. A possible central and peripheral nervous system involvement has been recognized. We present our experience and review the literature about association between carpal tunnel syndrome (CTS) and hand's arthritis presenting a case series of patients who firmly state that their condition of CTS arised or got worse during a typical presentation of COVID-19. The outbreak of COVID-19 has resulted in significant global healthcare implications. While the respiratory manifestations of COVID-19 have been widely studied, there is emerging evidence suggesting potential associations between COVID-19 and various other health conditions. This review of the literature aims to investigate the potential relationship between COVID-19 and the development or exacerbation of CTS. By synthesizing the available literature on this topic, we aim to provide a comprehensive overview of the current knowledge and enhance our understanding of the potential implications of COVID-19 on CTS. Case series: In this article we report 13 cases of typical presentations of COVID-19 with fever, myalgia, and respiratory system involvement, with a simultaneous aggravation of the median nerve pre-existing neuralgia and some cases that developed a median nerve neuralgia during COVID-19, which came to the attention of the hand surgeon. Some cases had stable symptomatic CTS and were on waiting list for surgical carpal tunnel release, some cases were previously asymptomatic and developed a median nerve neuralgia during COVID-19. All patients referred to a rapid worsening of acral paraesthesia and neuralgic pain of the same quality of CTS and in the median nerve topography. Some patients developed typical COVID-19 symptoms and died; the others were surgically treated. CTS could be an atypical presentations of COVID-19 or a condition of long-covid disease and clinical and epidemiological significance needs to be fully studied. We presented cases of worsening of the median nerve neuralgia which presented among other symptoms of COVID infection. We conclude a causal relation may exist and needs to be further investigated.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Vitis</LastName><ForeName>R</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>1Fondazione Policlinico Universitario A. Gemelli IRCCS, Roma, Italia. Universit&#xe0; Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Istituto di Clinica Ortopedica, Roma, Italia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Passiatore</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>2ASST Spedali Civili, Brescia, Italia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cilli</LastName><ForeName>V</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>3Chirurgie de la main, CHIREC site Delta, Bruxelles, Belgique.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Apicella</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>4Fondazione Policlinico Universitario A. Gemelli IRCCS, Dipartimento Scienze della Salute della donna, del bambino e di Sanit&#xe0; Pubblica. Unit&#xe0; di Neuropsichiatria infantile, Roma, Italia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taccardo</LastName><ForeName>G</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>1Fondazione Policlinico Universitario A. Gemelli IRCCS, Roma, Italia. Universit&#xe0; Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Istituto di Clinica Ortopedica, Roma, Italia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Georgia (Republic)</Country><MedlineTA>Georgian Med News</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101218222</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1512-0112</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002349" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carpal Tunnel Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008475" MajorTopicYN="N">Median Nerve</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020423" MajorTopicYN="Y">Median Neuropathy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37805875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>