<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35350258</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2532-8689</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Le infezioni in medicina</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Infez Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID-19 syndrome as a fourth phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>22</StartPage><EndPage>29</EndPage><MedlinePgn>22-29</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.53854/liim-3001-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The SARS-CoV-2 pandemic has affected in the last two years a large number of subjects, with a high cost in terms of morbidity and mortality. The scientific community made progress in understanding risk factors, pathophysiology, clinical manifestations, diagnosis and treatment of acute SARS-CoV-2 infection. In the last months, another condition has become evident and caught the attention of the scientific community: the so-called long COVID syndrome. The pathophysiology of this condition is not known, even if some hypothesis have been made but not demonstrated yet. Long COVID is characterized by a very heterogeneous group of subacute and/or chronic symptoms and signs that follow the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection and have a very variable duration. The presence of this syndrome in an individual is not dependent from the severity of the acute SARS-CoV-2 infection. Because of the extreme clinical heterogeneity, and also due to the lack of a shared and specific definition of the disease, it is very difficult to know the real prevalence and incidence of this condition. Some risk factors for the development of the disease have been identified: advanced age, elevated body mass index, comorbidities, specific symptoms of acute COVID-19 (in particular dyspnea), number of symptoms in the acute phase and female sex. The number of individuals affected by long COVID is high, even if it occurs only in a part of the subjects who had COVID-19. Therefore, long COVID constitutes now a major health issue and has to be managed in order to ensure an adequate access to care for all the people that need it. "Post COVID" clinics have been created in various countries, especially in Europe, for the management of people affected by long COVID syndrome. Guidelines have been written to help clinicians. An important role in the management of long COVID patients is played by the general practitioner, directly or indirectly linked to post COVID hospital clinics. The extreme heterogeneity of clinical presentation needs a patient-tailored, multidisciplinary approach. As NHS guidelines say, the three principal of care for long COVID patients are personalized care, multidisciplinary support and rehabilitation. More studies are needed in order to know better the pathophysiology of the disease. It is also necessary to create standardized and shared definitions of the disease, in order to better understand the epidemiology, the diagnostic criteria and to offer the right treatment to all the individuals who need it, without social or economic diffeences.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 InfezMed.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Staffolani</LastName><ForeName>Silvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterological and Transplant Department, S.O.D. Malattie Infettive Emergenti e degli Immunodepressi, University Hospital "Ospedali Riuniti", Ancona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iencinella</LastName><ForeName>Valentina</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterological and Transplant Department, S.O.D. Malattie Infettive Emergenti e degli Immunodepressi, University Hospital "Ospedali Riuniti", Ancona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cimatti</LastName><ForeName>Matteo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterological and Transplant Department, S.O.D. Malattie Infettive Emergenti e degli Immunodepressi, University Hospital "Ospedali Riuniti", Ancona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tavio</LastName><ForeName>Marcello</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterological and Transplant Department, S.O.D. Malattie Infettive Emergenti e degli Immunodepressi, University Hospital "Ospedali Riuniti", Ancona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Infez Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9613961</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1124-9390</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">follow up</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post COVID</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest None of the authors have conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35350258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8929740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.53854/liim-3001-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1124-9390_30_1_2022_22-29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A&#x2019;Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. Management of post-acute COVID-19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020;370:m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE), Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN), Royal College of General Practitioners (RCGP) COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. NICE. 2022;1:13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Observatory on Health Systems and Policies. Rajan S, Khunti K, et al. In the wake of the pandemic: preparing for Long COVID. World Health Organization Regional Office for Europe. 2021:1997&#x2013;8073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33877759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. Updated estimates of the prevalence of long COVID symptoms. Office for National Statistics; 2021. p. 12788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, et al. Attributes and predictors of Long-COVID: analysis of COVID cases and their symptoms collected by the COVID Symptoms Study App. medRxiv. 2020:20214494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, et al. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network - United States, March&#x2013;June 2020. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69(30):993&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV, Jayadevan R, Sashidharan S. Long COVID: An overview. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15(3):869&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, et al. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One. 2020;15(11):e0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra V, Flanders SA, O&#x2019;Malley M, Malani AN, Prescott HC. Sixty-day outcomes among patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174(4):576&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7707210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):601&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf A, Bernabei R, Landi F Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Pittet LF, Curtis N. How common is long COVID in children and adolescent? Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40(12):e482&#x2013;e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34870392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, et al. More than 50 Long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):16144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colafrancesco S, Alessandri C, Conti F, Priori R. COVID-19 gone bad: A new character in the spectrum of the hyperferritinemic syndrome? Autoimmun Rev. 2020;19(7):102573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7199723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tay MZ, Poh CM, R&#xe9;nia L, MacAry PA, Ng LFP. The trinity of COVID-19: immunity, inflammation and intervention. Nat Rev Immunol. 2020;20:363&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32346093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan L, Xu D, Ye G, et al. Positive RT-PCR test results in patients recovered from COVID-19. JAMA</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7047852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32105304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biehl M, Sese D. Post-intensive care syndrome and COVID-19 implications post pandemic. Cleve Clin J Med. 2020 doi: 10.3949/ccjm.87a.ccc055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3949/ccjm.87a.ccc055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Post-COVID-19 global health strategies: the need for an interdisciplinary approach. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2020;32(8):1613&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7287410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32529595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G, Favieri F, Tambelli R, Casagrande M. COVID-19 pandemic in the Italian population: validation of a post-traumatic stress disorder questionnaire and prevalence of PTSD symptomatology. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(11):4151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7312976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32532077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang H, Nan J, Lv Z, Yang J. Psychological impacts of the COVID-19 epidemic on Chinese people: exposure, post-traumatic stress symptom, and emotion regulation. Asian Pac J Trop Med. 2020;13:252&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Committee for the COMEBAC Study Group. Morin L, Savale L, et al. Four-month clinical status of cohort of patients after hospitalization for COVID-19. JAMA. 2021;325(15):1525&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7970386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33729425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weerahandi H, Hochman KA, Simon E, et al. Post-discharge health status and symptoms in patients with severe COVID-19. J Gen Intern Med. 2021;36(3):738&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33443703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel JA, Nielsen FBH, Badiani AA, et al. Poverty, inequality and COVID-19: the forgotten vulnerable. Public Health. 2020;183:110&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7221360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32502699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbarialiabad H, Taghrir MH, Abdollahi A, et al. Long COVID, a comprehensive systematic scoping review. Infection. 2021;49(6):1163&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8317481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34319569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin JY, Shiliang L. Proposed sybtypes of post-COVID-19 syndrome (or long-COVID) and their respective potential therapies. Rev Med Virol. 2021:e2315..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34888989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Health Service. Guidelines for supporting our NHS people affected by Long COVID. NHS. 2022 Version 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurek M, Rayner C, Freyer A, et al. Recommendations for the recognition, diagnosis, and management of long COVID: a Delphi study. Br J Gen Pract. 2021;71(712):e815&#x2013;e25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8510689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34607799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Royal Australian College of General Practitioners. Caring for patients with post-COVID-19 conditions. East Melbourne, Vic: RACGP; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long COVID-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Istituto Superiore di Sanit&#xe0;. Indicazioni ad interim sui principi di gestione del Long-COVID. Rapporto ISS COVID-19. 20212021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Health Service. National guidance for post-COVID syndrome assessment clinics. NHS; 2021. Version 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salman D, Vishnubala D, Le Feuvre P, et al. Returning to physical activity after COVID-19. BMJ. 2021;372:m4721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33419740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinagra G, Anzini M, Pereira NL, et al. Myocarditis in clinical practice. Mayo Clin Proc. 2016;91(9):1256&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27489051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Society of Cardiology. ESC guidance for the diagnosis and management of CV disease during the COVID-19 pandemic. ESC; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onishi A, Ange KSt, Dordick JS, Linhardt RJ. Heparin and anticoagulation. Front Biosci (Landmark Ed) 2016;21:1372&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27100512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamson J, Ali S, Santhouse A, Wessely S, Chalder T. Cognitive behavioural therapy for chronic fatigue and chronic fatigue syndrome: outcomes from a specialist clinic in the UK. J R Soc Med. 2020;113(10):394&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7583448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32930040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torjesen I. NICE cautions using graded exercise therapy for patients recovering from COVID-19. BMJ. 2020;370:m2912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32694164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>