<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35833897</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2037-7452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of translational myology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Transl Myol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Can aquatic exercises contribute to the improvement of the gait stereotype function in patients with Long COVID outcomes?</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10698</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4081/ejtm.2022.10698</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A variety of rehabilitation programmes can be offered to Long COVID patients, specifically physical training. Indeed 90% of these patients reports impairments of verticalization, stability and spatial orientation, making difficult exercise in the gym. The aim of our study was to assess the effectiveness and safety of aquatic exercise techniques as part of a comprehensive rehabilitation program for patients with Long COVID. The first of a two-stage program involved development of aquatic exercises technique, which was evaluated in 12 patients with impaired upright posture control before and after exercising by "Habilect" video gait analysis system. During the second phase, effectiveness and safety of aqua exercises were tested in water pool as part of a comprehensive rehabilitation programme conducted in 23 patients with Long COVID outcomes. Physical examination, 6-minute step test, Euro-QL-5D questionnaire, Borg scale, laser Doppler flowmetry, cardiointervalography, and spirometry were performed before and after the aquatic exercises program. After the training with aquatic exercises, indices of deviations of the main body axes of the head and the body mass centre ameliorated, as well as direction of body movement vector decreased (p&lt;0.05). This study demonstrated a statistically significant improvement in exercise tolerance in both groups, as measured by the 6-minute step test after rehabilitation. The comparison group averaged 236.7 metres [126; 380] (T=8, p=0.047) after the rehabilitation course and the intervention group averaged 233.71 metres [150; 320] (T=8.0, p=0.047). When tested with the Euro-QL-5D questionnaire, a post-treatment improvement was noted in the comparison group on the anxiety/depression subscale (3 [3;3] (T=0, p=0.043)). In the intervention group, laser Doppler flowmetry revealed a statistically significant increase in microcirculation (6.36 standard units after rehabilitation) [5.54; 8.17] (T=7.0, p=0.004), and a decrease of oxidative metabolism index of 6.89 standard units. [4.76; 6.96] (T=4.0, p=0.03). No serious adverse events were reported. In conclusion, the developed aquatic exercises technique seems to contribute to recovery of impaired upright posture and motor function, normalizing the walking pattern.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lobanov</LastName><ForeName>Andrey A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Research Center, National Research Medical Center, Moscow. alobanov89@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Irina A Grishechkina</LastName><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Research Center, National Research Medical Center, Moscow. grishechkinaIA@nmicrk.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andronov</LastName><ForeName>Sergei V</ForeName><Initials>SV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Research Center, National Research Medical Center, Moscow. sergius198010@mail.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gleb N Barashkov</LastName><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>. BarashkovGN@nmicrk.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andrey I Popov</LastName><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Research Center, National Research Medical Center, Moscow. PopovAI@nmicrk.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anatoliy D Fesyun</LastName><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Research Center, National Research Medical Center, Moscow. fad68@yandex.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elena P Ivanova</LastName><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Research Center, National Research Medical Center, Moscow. IvanovaEP@nmicrk.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maccarone</LastName><ForeName>Maria Chiara</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation School, University of Padova, Padua. mariachiara.maccarone@studenti.unipd.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stefano Masiero</LastName><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation School, University of Padova, Padua, Italy; Rehabilitation Unit, Department of Neuroscience, University of Padova, Padua. stef.masiero@unipd.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Transl Myol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2037-7452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>We confirm that we have read the Journal&#x2019;s position on issues involved in ethical publication and affirm that this report is consistent with those guidelines. <b>S</b>o far, the New Coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic has affected more than 534 million people and caused more than 6 million deaths. A large proportion of patients infected with SARS-COV-2 do not fully recover and continue to experience a large number of symptoms even in the absence of a diagnosable viral infection. This condition of persistence of signs and symptoms that continue or develop after acute SARS CoV-2 infection has been called Long COVID syndrome. The prevalence of Long COVID seems to be high, both in outpatient (from 68.7% to 77.1%) and inpatient subjects, as long-term manifestations occur not only in patients with severe infection but also in those who have had asymptomatic or paucisymptomatic COVID-19 forms. The spectrum of Long COVID symptoms is varied, but a few key symptoms can be identified and targeted in rehabilitation interventions. These include persistent fatigue, breathlessness, coughing, muscle weakness, cognitive impairment and stress/anxiety.<sup>,</sup> All these symptoms can contribute to impaired mobility, self-care and independent functioning. Di Caudo et al. (2021) studying the evolution of patients with Long COVID syndrome and the effects of rehabilitative interventions 3 and 6 months after the acute phase of infection, found that respiratory and mobility complications were partially reversible after 3 months of rehabilitation treatment. Capin et al. (2022) demonstrated on patients hospitalized for COVID-19 an improvement in functional scores from 2-6 weeks to 18 weeks. While the need for rehabilitation of patients with Long COVID and the use of a multidisciplinary approach in rehabilitation interventions is generally accepted, there is no unified content of rehabilitation programmes. An important number of rehabilitation strategies involves general strengthening of patients, normalization of respiratory function and mobilization. Other rehabilitation programs focus predominantly on correcting severe respiratory failure, also by employing classical pulmonary rehabilitation methods. Nevertheless, regardless of the aim of the rehabilitation program, physical exercise is always included. However, as it was noted in our previous work Fesyun et al.(2020) and by other researchers,<sup>,</sup> 90% of patients who have had a COVID-19 infection present among other conditions impairments related to verticality, stability, spatial orientation, making difficult gym physical exercises. Therefore, we have developed an aquatic walking-recovery technique to be applied in the initial stages of medical rehabilitation, exploiting immersion up to mid-thorax and shoulder level. The aquatic environment provides a reduction of gravitational load up to 70-80%. This reduces the risk of falling, provides a soft resistance and a light massage effect on the musculoskeletal system thanks to the hydrodynamic properties. Moreover, the use of mineralized waters (sea, ocean, diluted brine, brine of limans and lakes), increases the gravitational effect and, due to the mineral composition, provides additional impact on metabolism. Considering the current available data on the natural course of Long COVID and the effectiveness of rehabilitation interventions, the National Medical Research Center in 2020 developed a comprehensive method for rehabilitate patients with novel coronavirus infection and pneumonia long-term outcomes. The program include initial examination by a multidisciplinary team, evaluation of functional impairment degree, and development of a personalized rehabilitation program, consisting of balneotherapy, physiotherapy and physical exercises. Thus, the aim of our study is to assess the effectiveness and safety of aquatic exercises in restoring functional state of patients with Long COVID as the initial part of a comprehensive rehabilitation program.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35833897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/ejtm.2022.10698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Data Repository by the Center for Systems Science and Engineering (CSSE) at Johns Hopkins University. Available at: https://github.com/CSSEGISandData/COVID-19 Published-online May 18, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cenko E, Badimon L, Bugiardini R, Claeys MJ, De Luca G, de Wit C, Derumeaux G, Dorobantu M, Duncker DJ, Eringa EC, Gorog DA, Hassager C, Heinzel FR, Huber K, Manfrini O, Milicic D, Oikonomou E, Padro T, Trifunovic-Zamaklar D, Vasiljevic-Pokrajcic Z, Vavlukis M, Vilahur G, Tousoulis D. Cardiovascular disease and COVID-19: a consensus paper from the ESC Working Group on Coronary Pathophysiology &amp; Microcirculation, ESC Working Group on Thrombosis and the Association for Acute CardioVascular Care (ACVC), in collaboration with the European Heart Rhythm Association (EHRA). Cardiovasc Res. 2021. Dec 17;117(14):2705-2729. doi: 10.1093/cvr/cvab298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34528075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell ML, Catalfamo CJ, Farland LV, Ernst KC, Jacobs ET, Klimentidis YC, Jehn M, Pogreba-Brown K. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 in a non-hospitalized cohort: Results from the Arizona CoVHORT. PLoS One. 2021. Aug 4;16(8):e0254347. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0254347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8336814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34347785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, Kang L, Guo L, Liu M, Zhou X, Luo J, Huang Z, Tu S, Zhao Y, Chen L, Xu D, Li Y, Li C, Peng L, Li Y, Xie W, Cui D, Shang L, Fan G, Xu J, Wang G, Wang Y, Zhong J, Wang C, Wang J, Zhang D, Cao B. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021. Jan 16;397(10270):220-232. doi: 10. 1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8. Epub 2021 Jan 8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT, Hamilton FW, Milne A, Morley AJ, Viner J, Attwood M, Noel A, Gunning S, Hatrick J, Hamilton S, Elvers KT, Hyams C, Bibby A, Moran E, Adamali HI, Dodd JW, Maskell NA, Barratt SL. Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up: results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax. 2021. Apr;76(4):399-401. doi: 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216086. Epub 2020 Dec 3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilazi M, Duffy EY, Thakkar A, Michos ED. COVID and Cardiovascular Disease: What We Know in 2021. Curr Atheroscler Rep. 2021; 23(7); 37. doi: 10.1007/s11883-021-00935-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8117457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33983522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramoff BA, Dillingham TR, Caldera FE, Ritchie MD, Pezzin LE. Inpatient Rehabilitation Outcomes After Severe COVID-19 Infections: A Retrospective Cohort Study. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2021. Dec 1;100(12):1109-1114. doi: 10.1097/PHM.0000000000001885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8594383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34657085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Caudo CG, Rivas Garc&#xed;a M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Rodr&#xed;guez I, G&#xf3;mez-Jurado G, Romero Garrido M, Membrilla-Mesa M. Tratamiento rehabilitador de la infecci&#xf3;n por COVID: caracterizaci&#xf3;n y seguimiento de pacientes hospitalizados en Granada, Espa&#xf1;a [Rehabilitation and COVID disease: characterization and follow-up of hospitalized patients in Granada, Spain]. Rehabilitacion (Madr). 2021. Oct 6:S0048-7120(21)00095-5. Spanish. doi: 10.1016/j.rh.2021. 09.001. Epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8495052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34627613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capin JJ, Wilson MP, Hare K, Vempati S, Little CE, McGregor D, Castillo-Mancilla J, Stevens-Lapsley JE, Jolley SE, Erlandson KM. Prospective telehealth analysis of functional performance, frailty, quality of life, and mental health after COVID-19 hospitalization. BMC Geriatr. 2022. Mar 26;22(1):251. doi: 10.1186/s12877-022-02854-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8956362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35337276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puchner B, Sahanic S, Kirchmair R, Pizzini A, Sonnweber B, W&#xf6;ll E, M&#xfc;hlbacher A, Garimorth K, Dareb B, Ehling R, Wenter J, Schneider S, Brenneis C, Weiss G, Tancevski I, Sonnweber T, L&#xf6;ffler-Ragg J. Beneficial effects of multi-disciplinary rehabilitation in postacute COVID-19: an observational cohort study. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2021. Apr;57(2):189-198. doi: 10.23736/ S1973-9087.21.06549-7. Epub 2021 Jan 15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33448756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutsch M, Frommhold J, Buhr-Schinner H, Djeiranachvili L, Gross T, Sch&#xfc;ller PO, Katalinic A, Deck R. Study protocol medical rehabilitation after COVID-19 disease: an observational study with a comparison group with obstructive airway disease / Re_Co. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021. Apr 22;21(1):373. doi: 10.1186/s12913-021-06378-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8061875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33888104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meshcheryakova NN, Belevskij AS, Kuleshov AV. [Guidelines pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with new coronavirus infection (covid-19) community-acquired bilateral pneumonia]. 2020. Moscow, Russia; 22 p. Available at: https://www.spulmo.ru/upload/metodichka_po_reabilitacii_covid.pdf (Accessed Mar 3, 2022). Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fesyun AD, Lobanov AA, Rachin AP, Yakovlev MY, Andronov SV, Konchugova TV, Gilmutdinova IR, Barashkov GN, Mitroshkina EE, Bogdanova EN, Lebedev YO, Nikitina AM. [Challenges and approaches to medical rehabilitation of patients with Covid-19 complications]. Bulletin of rehabilitation medicine. 2020; 97(3): 3-13. Russian. doi: 10.38025/ 2078-1962-2020-97-3-3-13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivanova GE, Bogolepova AN, Levin OS, Shamalov NA, Khasanova DR, Yanishevsky SN, Zakharov VV, Khatkova SE, Stakhovskya LV. Osnovnye napravleniya lecheniya i reabilitatsii nevrologicheskikh proyavlenii COVID-19. Rezolyutsiya soveta ekspertov [Current issues of treatment and rehabilitation of patients with neurological disorders and the consequences of COVID-19. Resolution of Advisory Board]. Zh Nevrol Psikhiatr Im S S Korsakova. 2021;121(6):145-151. Russian. doi: 10.17116/jnevro2021121061145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34283545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, Walshaw C, Kemp S, Corrado J, Singh R, Collins T, O'Connor RJ, Sivan M. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021. Feb;93(2):1013-1022. doi: 10.1002/jmv.26368. Epub 2020 Aug 17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2021). A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021. World Health Organization. Available at: https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/345824 (Accessed Mar 31, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittenberg E, Thompson J, Nam CS, Franz JR. Neuroimaging of Human Balance Control: A Systematic Review. Front Hum Neurosci. 2017. Apr 10;11:170. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2017.00170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5385364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28443007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dijkstra BW, Bekkers EMJ, Gilat M, de Rond V, Hardwick RM, Nieuwboer A. Functional neuroimaging of human postural control: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2020. Aug;115:351-362. doi: 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2020.04.028. Epub 2020 May 11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32407735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maccarone MC, Masiero S. Spa therapy interventions for post respiratory rehabilitation in COVID-19 subjects: does the review of recent evidence suggest a role? Environ Sci Pollut Res Int. 2021. Sep;28(33):46063-46066. doi: 10.1007/s11356-021-15443-8. Epub 2021 Jul 17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8286038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maccarone MC, Masiero S. Spa therapy interventions for post respiratory rehabilitation in COVID-19 subjects: does the review of recent evidence suggest a role? Environ Sci Pollut Res Int. 2021. Sep;28(33):46063-46066. doi: 10.1007/s11356-021-15443-8. Epub 2021 Jul 17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8286038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maccarone MC, Masiero S. Spa therapy interventions for post respiratory rehabilitation in COVID-19 subjects: does the review of recent evidence suggest a role? Environ Sci Pollut Res Int. 2021. Sep;28(33):46063-46066. doi: 10.1007/s11356-021-15443-8. Epub 2021 Jul 17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8286038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maccarone MC, Kamioka H, Cheleschi S, Tenti S, Masiero S, Karde&#x15f; S. Italian and Japanese public attention toward balneotherapy in the COVID-19 era. Environ Sci Pollut Res Int. 2021. Nov;28(43):61781-61789. doi: 10.1007/s11356-021-15058-z. Epub 2021 Jun 29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34185269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Donelli D. Respiratory rehabilitation for post-COVID19 patients in spa centers: first steps from theory to practice. Int J Biometeorol. 2020. Oct;64(10):1811-1813. doi: 10.1007/s00484-020-01962-5. Epub 2020 Jul 24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7380660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32710297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dondoladze K, Nikolaishvili M, Zurabashvili D. The effect of balneotherapy on the oxidative system and changes in anxiety behavior, enhanced by low doses of radon. Int J Radiat Biol. 2021;97(10):1461-1469. doi: 10.1080/09553002.2021.1956009. Epub 2021 Jul 29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34323641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dondoladze K, Nikolaishvili M, Zurabashvili D. The effect of balneotherapy on the oxidative system and changes in anxiety behavior, enhanced by low doses of radon. Int J Radiat Biol. 2021;97(10):1461-1469. doi: 10.1080/09553002.2021.1956009. Epub 2021 Jul 29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34323641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ergin G, Karadibak D, Sener HO, Gurpinar B. Effects of Aqua-Lymphatic Therapy on Lower Extremity Lymphedema: A Randomized Controlled Study. Lymphat Res Biol. 2017. Sep;15(3):284-291. doi: 10.1089/lrb.2017.0017. Epub 2017 Sep 7. Erratum in: Lymphat Res Biol. 2018. Feb;16(1): 132. PMID: 28880750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28880750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masiero S, Maccarone MC, Agostini F. Health resort medicine can be a suitable setting to recover disabilities in patients tested negative for COVID-19 discharged from hospital? A challenge for the future. Int J Biometeorol. 2020. Oct;64(10):1807-1809. doi: 10.1007/s00484-020-01947-4. Epub 2020 Jun 5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32504142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>