<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36381920</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Avascular Necrosis of the Hip: A Post COVID-19 Sequela.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e29976</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e29976</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e29976</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.29976</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A 60-year-old African American male presented to the hospital with seven months of progressively worsening left anterior hip pain with no known trauma. Two months after the pain onset, he underwent an x-ray of the pelvis with the lateral left hip, revealing dystrophic soft tissue calcification adjacent to the superolateral left acetabulum. Pain at this time was attributed to presumed sciatica vs arthritis. The patient underwent multimodal treatment for his pain without relief. In the month prior to the presentation, the patient also developed right hip pain. He then underwent a bilateral hip x-ray, revealing left femoral neck lucency suspicious for a nondisplaced fracture. CT pelvis was ordered at this time for further evaluation and demonstrated bilateral subcapital hip fractures. He was subsequently discharged from the emergency department with pending laboratory work and plans for close outpatient orthopedic surgery follow-up. The following day, the patient was instructed to return to the hospital due to an elevated erythrocyte sedimentation rate of 39 mm/hr and C-reactive protein of 41.6 mg/L. Subsequent MRI pelvis revealed bilateral subcapital femoral neck fractures with avascular necrosis (AVN) requiring surgical intervention with bilateral hip arthroplasty. Our patient underwent an extensive workup with no evidence of traditional risk factors for osteonecrosis, osteopenia, or other bone diseases. A pertinent finding in the patient's history was an admission for severe SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19) infection 10 months prior. 'Long COVID' is a complex illness that has been shown to affect intravascular blood flow, and likely contributed to the development of bilateral hip AVN in our patient. Given this novel presentation, it is crucial that AVN be considered early in evaluating anterior hip pain for patients with a history of COVID-19 infection in order to avoid severe consequences such as femoral neck fractures.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022, Kingma et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kingma</LastName><ForeName>Tyler J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Edward Via College of Osteopathic Medicine, Spartanburg, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoch</LastName><ForeName>Virginia</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine-Pediatrics, Christiana Care Health System, Newark, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Chelsey</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine-Pediatrics, Christiana Care Health System, Newark, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaudhry</LastName><ForeName>Bilal</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Christiana Care Health System, Newark, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">avascular femoral head necrosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">avascular necrosis (avn)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bilateral femoral neck fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hip joint pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">osteomyelitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sars-cov-2 (severe acute respiratory syndrome corona virus 2)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36381920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9636587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.29976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Type II collagen gene variants and inherited osteonecrosis of the femoral head. Liu YF, Chen WM, Lin YF, et al. N Engl J Med. 2005;352:2294&#x2013;2301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15930420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osteonecrosis of the femoral head: pathophysiology and current concepts of treatment. Petek D, Hannouche D, Suva D. EFORT Open Rev. 2019;4:85&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6440301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30993010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High-dose corticosteroid use and risk of hip osteonecrosis: meta-analysis and systematic literature review. Mont MA, Pivec R, Banerjee S, Issa K, Elmallah RK, Jones LC. J Arthroplasty. 2015;30:1506&#x2013;1512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7127809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25900167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcohol intake and the risk of osteonecrosis of the femoral head in Japanese populations: a dose-response meta-analysis of case-control studies. Yoon BH, Kim TY, Shin IS, Lee HY, Lee YJ, Koo KH. Clin Rheumatol. 2017;36:2517&#x2013;2524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28685377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 infection: viral macro- and micro-vascular coagulopathy and thromboembolism/prophylactic and therapeutic management. Manolis AS, Manolis TA, Manolis AA, Papatheou D, Melita H. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol Ther. 2021;26:12&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7492826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32924567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avascular necrosis bone complication after active covid-19 infection: preliminary results. Sulewski A, Siero&#x144; D, Szyluk K, D&#x105;browski M, Kubaszewski &#x141;, Lukoszek D, Christe A. Medicina (Kaunas) 2021;57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8709043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34946256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avascular necrosis as a part of 'long COVID-19'. Agarwala SR, Vijayvargiya M, Pandey P. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8256728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34215639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>