<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37675861</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the mechanisms of long COVID: Insights from computational analysis of SARS-CoV-2 gene expression and symptom associations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e29077</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e29077</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.29077</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long coronavirus disease&#xa0;(COVID) has emerged as a global health issue, affecting a substantial number of people worldwide. However, the underlying mechanisms that contribute to the persistence of symptoms in long COVID remain obscure, impeding the development of effective diagnostic and therapeutic interventions. In this study, we utilized computational methods to examine the gene expression profiles of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2&#xa0;(SARS-CoV-2) infection and their associations with the wide range of symptoms observed in long COVID patients. Using a comprehensive data set comprising over 255 symptoms affecting multiple organ systems, we identified differentially expressed genes&#xa0;and investigated their functional similarity, leading to the identification of key genes with the potential to serve as biomarkers for long COVID. We identified the participation of hub genes associated with G-protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs), which are essential regulators of T-cell immunity and viral infection responses. Among the identified common genes were CTLA4, PTPN22, KIT, KRAS, NF1, RET, and CTNNB1, which play a crucial role in modulating T-cell immunity via GPCR and contribute to a variety of symptoms, including autoimmunity, cardiovascular disorders, dermatological manifestations, gastrointestinal complications, pulmonary impairments, reproductive and genitourinary dysfunctions, and endocrine abnormalities. GPCRs and associated genes are pivotal in immune regulation and cellular functions, and their dysregulation may contribute to the persistent immune responses, chronic inflammation, and tissue abnormalities observed in long COVID. Targeting GPCRs and their associated pathways could offer promising therapeutic strategies to manage symptoms and improve outcomes for those experiencing long COVID. However, the complex mechanisms underlying the condition require continued study to develop effective treatments. Our study has significant implications for understanding the molecular mechanisms underlying long COVID and for identifying potential therapeutic targets. In addition, we have developed a comprehensive website (https://longcovid.omicstutorials.com/) that provides a curated list of biomarker-identified genes and treatment recommendations for each specific disease, thereby facilitating informed clinical decision-making and improved patient management. Our study contributes to the understanding of this debilitating disease, paving the way for improved diagnostic precision, and individualized therapeutic interventions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Das</LastName><ForeName>Sanisha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic &amp; Allied Health Science, Faculty of Health and Life Sciences, Management and Science University, Shah Alam, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Suresh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5682-0938</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic &amp; Allied Health Science, Faculty of Health and Life Sciences, Management and Science University, Shah Alam, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D043562">Receptors, G-Protein-Coupled</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020869" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gene Expression Profiling</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057285" MajorTopicYN="N">Precision Medicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043562" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, G-Protein-Coupled</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">T-cell immunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">repurposed drugs</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37675861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.29077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Del Rio C, Collins LF, Malani P. Long-term health consequences of COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(17):1723-1724. doi:10.1001/JAMA.2020.19719</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648. doi:10.1136/BMJ.N1648</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deer RR, Rock MA, Vasilevsky N, et al. Characterizing long COVID: deep phenotype of a complex condition. EBioMedicine. 2021;74:103722. doi:10.1016/j.ebiom.2021.103722</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): an overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front Microbiol. 2021;12:698169. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2021.698169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson HW, Amo-Addae M, Kenu E, Ilesanmi OS, Ameme DK, Sackey SO. Post-ebola syndrome among ebola virus disease survivors in montserrado county, Liberia 2016. BioMed Res Int. 2018;2018(2016):1-8. doi:10.1155/2018/1909410</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown K, Yahyouche A, Haroon S, Camaradou J, Turner G. Long COVID and self-management. Lancet. 2022;399(10322):355. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02798-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin CH, Chen SH, Wu HH, Ho CW, Ko MT, Lin CY. cytoHubba: identifying hub objects and sub-networks from complex interactome. BMC Syst Biol. 2014;8(4):S11. doi:10.1186/1752-0509-8-S4-S11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CI, Postema PG, Arbelo E, et al. SARS-CoV-2, COVID-19, and inherited arrhythmia syndromes. Heart Rhythm. 2020;17(9):1456-1462. doi:10.1016/j.hrthm.2020.03.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thuangtong R, Angkasekwinai N, Leeyaphan C, et al. Patient recovery from COVID-19 infections: follow-up of hair, nail, and cutaneous manifestations. BioMed Res Int. 2021;2021:1-6. doi:10.1155/2021/5595016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kariyawasam JC, Jayarajah U, Riza R, Abeysuriya V, Seneviratne SL. Gastrointestinal manifestations in COVID-19. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 2021;115(12):1362-1388. doi:10.1093/TRSTMH/TRAB042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE, et al. Short-term and long-term rates of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a systematic review. JAMA Network Open. 2021;4(10):e2128568. doi:10.1001/JAMANETWORKOPEN.2021.28568</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong TL, Weitzer DJ. Long COVID and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS)-a systemic review and comparison of clinical presentation and symptomatology. Medicina. 2021;57(5):418. doi:10.3390/MEDICINA57050418</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Anwar MW, Eesa M, Mansour W, Zake LG, Hendawy E. Analysis of ear, nose and throat manifestations in COVID-19 patients. Int Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2021;25(3):e343-e348. doi:10.1055/s-0041-1730456</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafari Z, Kolb BE, Mohajerani MH. Hearing loss, tinnitus, and dizziness in COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Canadian J&#xa0;Neurol&#xa0;Sc/Journal Canadien des Sciences Neurologiques. 2022;49(2):184-195. doi:10.1017/CJN.2021.63</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fajgenbaum DC, June CH. Cytokine storm. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(23):2255-2273. doi:10.1056/NEJMra2026131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Q, Huang D, Yu H, et al. COVID-19: abnormal liver function tests. J Hepatol. 2020;73(3):566-574. doi:10.1016/J.JHEP.2020.04.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik P, Patel U, Mehta D, et al. Biomarkers and outcomes of COVID-19 hospitalisations: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Evidence-Based Med. 2021;26(3):107-108. doi:10.1136/BMJEBM-2020-111536</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight JS, Caricchio R, Casanova JL, et al. The intersection of COVID-19 and autoimmunity. J Clin Invest. 2021;131(24):1-9. doi:10.1172/JCI154886</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185(5):881-895. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2022.01.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236&#x2009;379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatr. 2021;8(5):416-427. doi:10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00084-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang BZ, Chu H, Han S, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infects human neural progenitor cells and brain organoids. Cell Res. 2020;30(10):928-931. doi:10.1038/s41422-020-0390-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fotuhi M, Hachinski V, Whitehouse PJ. Changing perspectives regarding late-life dementia. Nat Rev Neurol. 2009;5(12):649-658. doi:10.1038/nrneurol.2009.175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini N, Nadjafi S, Ashtary B. Overview of COVID-19 and neurological complications. Rev Neurosci. 2021;32(6):671-691. doi:10.1515/revneuro-2020-0116</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeloye D, Elneima O, Daines L, et al. The long-term sequelae of COVID-19: an international consensus on research priorities for patients with pre-existing and new-onset airways disease. Lancet Respir&#xa0;Med. 2021;9(12):1467-1478. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00286-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Xu E, Al-Aly Z. Kidney outcomes in long COVID. JASN. 2021;32(11):2851-2862. doi:10.1681/ASN.2021060734</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Mu C, Zhang Q, Yang X, Yan H, Jiao H. Effects of infection with SARS-CoV-2 on the male and female reproductive systems: a review. Med Sci Monit. 2021;27:27. doi:10.12659/MSM.930168</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legler DF, Thelen M. New insights in chemokine signaling. F1000Research. 2018;7:95. doi:10.12688/F1000RESEARCH.13130.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riemekasten G, Petersen F, Heidecke H. What makes antibodies against G protein-coupled receptors so special? A novel concept to understand chronic diseases. Front Immunol. 2020;11:11. doi:10.3389/FIMMU.2020.564526</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Oliveira PG, Ramos MLS, Amaro AJ, Dias RA, Vieira SI. Gi/O-protein coupled receptors in the aging brain. Front Aging Neurosci. 2019;11(April):89. doi:10.3389/fnagi.2019.00089</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talla A, Vasaikar SV, Szeto GL, et al. Persistent serum protein signatures define an inflammatory subcategory of long COVID. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):3417.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>