<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39268246</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2667-0364</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of medicine open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-Acute Sequelae of Covid-19: A System-wise Approach on the Effects of Long-Covid-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100071</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100071</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100071</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ajmo.2024.100071</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The SARS-CoV-2 virus responsible for the COVID-19 pandemic has profoundly impacted global health, economics, and society. This review seeks to encompass an overview of current knowledge on COVID-19, including its transmission, pathogenesis, and clinical presentation related to various systems within the human body. COVID-19 is a highly contagious illness that has rapidly spread worldwide. As of August 4, 2023, the WHO reported over 570 million confirmed cases of COVID-19 and over 6.3 million deaths. Although the virus is most common in adults, children can also be infected. Respiratory droplets that are produced when an infected person coughs or sneezes are the primary transmission mode for COVID-19. Additionally, the virus can be disseminated via contact with contaminated surfaces or objects, as it can remain viable for several hours or days. SARS-CoV-2 is a respiratory virus that enters cells by bonding with the angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) receptor. Once inside the cell, the virus replicates and produces new particles that can infect other cells. Interestingly, the effects of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) encompass more than just respiratory system. The findings presented in the data suggest that PASC significantly impacts multiple organs and their respective physiological processes. In light of these observations, we aim to provide a detailed discussion of the relevant findings in this paper. Through our review, we hope to provide healthcare professionals with a deeper understanding of the effects of PASC on the human body, which could ultimately lead to improved patient outcomes and treatment strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Umakanthan</LastName><ForeName>Srikanth</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paraclinical Sciences, Faculty of Medical Sciences, The University of the West Indies, St. Augustine, Trinidad and Tobago.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katwaroo</LastName><ForeName>Arun Rabindra</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trinidad Institute of Medical Technology, Department of Medicine, St. Augustine, Trinidad and Tobago.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bukelo</LastName><ForeName>Maryann</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomical Pathology, Laboratory Services, North Central Regional Health Authority, Champ Fleurs, Trinidad and Tobago.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bg</LastName><ForeName>Shashidhar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical care Medicine, Manipal Hospital, Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boralingaiah</LastName><ForeName>Prashanth</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Early Psychosis Prevention and Intervention Center (EPPIC), Orygen Youth Health, Sunshine, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ranade</LastName><ForeName>Anu V</ForeName><Initials>AV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Basic Medical Sciences, College of Medicine, University of Sharjah, Sharjah, United Arab Emirates.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rangan</LastName><ForeName>Pallavi</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>New Jersey, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shashidhar</LastName><ForeName>Shabnam</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Sparsh Hospital, Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kini</LastName><ForeName>Jyoti Ramanath</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Kasturba Medical College, Mangalore, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kini</LastName><ForeName>Gayathri</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Kasturba Medical College, Mangalore, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918316788906676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2667-0364</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic effects</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thrombosis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>We acknowledge that we have read the journal's policy statement and agree to the same. We declare that we do not have an conflicts of interest and declare that this manuscript is not submitted elsewhere nor considered for publication in any other journals. Hence, we submit the manuscript entitled &#x201c;Post-Acute Sequelae of Covid-19: A System-wise Approach on the Effects of Long-Covid-19&#x201d; for full consideration in your esteemed journal.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39268246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11387218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajmo.2024.100071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2667-0364(24)00008-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Horberg M.A., et al. Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 with clinical condition definitions and comparison in a matched cohort. Nature communications. 2022;13(1):5822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9556630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36224218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seecheran R., et al. Atrial arrhythmias in a patient presenting with coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19) infection. Journal of Investigative Medicine High Impact Case Reports. 2020;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7218462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32370558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronavirus, W., Dashboard. WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard with vaccination data; 2021. Internet Available from: https://covid19.who.int/[cited 2021 Dec 13], 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y., et al. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nature medicine. 2022;28(3):583&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35132265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization, W.H. World Health Organization; 2021. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tereshchenko L.G., et al. Risk of cardiovascular events after COVID-19. The American Journal of Cardiology. 2022;179:102&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9282909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35843735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tereshchenko L.G., et al. Risk of Cardiovascular Events After COVID-19. Am J Cardiol. 2022;179:102&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9282909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35843735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho J.S., et al. Coronavirus-induced myocarditis: a meta-summary of cases. Heart &amp; Lung. 2020;49(6):681&#x2013;685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7440036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32861884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blagova O., et al. Chronic biopsy proven post-COVID myoendocarditis with SARS-Cov-2 persistence and high level of antiheart antibodies. Clinical Cardiology. 2022;45(9):952&#x2013;959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9349976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35855554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe5;hlberg M., et al. Post-COVID-19 tachycardia syndrome: a distinct phenotype of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. The American journal of medicine. 2021;134(12):1451&#x2013;1456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8356730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34390682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N., et al. Acute myocardial infarction in COVID-19 patients. A review of cases in the literature. Archives of Medical Science-Atherosclerotic Diseases. 2021;6(1):169&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8525248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34703946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou-Ismail M.Y., et al. The hypercoagulable state in COVID-19: Incidence, pathophysiology, and management. Thrombosis research. 2020;194:101&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7305763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akkaya F., et al. Long term effects of mild severity COVID&#x2011;19 on right ventricular functions. The International Journal of Cardiovascular Imaging. 2021;37(12):3451&#x2013;3457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8274467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34251551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szeghy R.E., et al. Long-Term Recovery from SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19): Six-month longitudinal tracking of arterial stiffness and blood pressure in young adults following SARS-CoV-2 infection. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2022;132(5):1297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9126215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35439042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lip S., et al. Protocol: Rationale and Design for the LOnger-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 INfection on blood Vessels And blood pRessure (LOCHINVAR): an observational phenotyping study. Open Heart. 2022;9(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9234432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35750422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z., Xie Y., Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594(7862):259&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L., et al. Gastrointestinal symptoms of 95 cases with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Gut. 2020;69(6):997&#x2013;1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32241899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipriano M., Ruberti E., Giacalone A. Gastrointestinal infection could be new focus for coronavirus diagnosis. Cureus. 2020;12(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7186097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32351807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norouzi Masir M., Shirvaliloo M. Symptomatology and microbiology of the gastrointestinal tract in post-COVID conditions. JGH Open. 2022;6(10):667&#x2013;676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36247234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan L., et al. Clinical characteristics of COVID-19 patients with digestive symptoms in Hubei, China: a descriptive, cross-sectional, multicenter study. The American journal of gastroenterology. 2020;115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32287140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redd W., et al. Prevalence and characteristics of gastrointestinal symptoms in patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection in the United States: a multicenter cohort study. Gastroenterology. 2020;159(2):765&#x2013;767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32333911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tullie L., et al. Gastrointestinal features in children with COVID-19: an observation of varied presentation in eight children. The Lancet Child &amp; Adolescent Health. 2020;4(7):e19&#x2013;e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7237361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang L., et al. Three-month follow-up study of survivors of coronavirus disease 2019 after discharge. Journal of Korean medical science. 2020;35(47)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7721559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33289374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen M.S., et al. Long COVID in the Faroe Islands: a longitudinal study among nonhospitalized patients. Clinical Infectious Diseases. 2021;73(11):e4058&#x2013;e4063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7799340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33252665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wypych T.P., Wickramasinghe L.C., Marsland B.J. The influence of the microbiome on respiratory health. Nature immunology. 2019;20(10):1279&#x2013;1290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31501577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keely S., Talley N.J., Hansbro P.M. Pulmonary-intestinal cross-talk in mucosal inflammatory disease. Mucosal immunology. 2012;5(1):7&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3243663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22089028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai H.-C., et al. Irritable bowel syndrome increases the risk of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a retrospective cohort study. Scientific Reports. 2020;10(1):10008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7305148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32561774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barcik W., et al. The role of lung and gut microbiota in the pathology of asthma. Immunity. 2020;52(2):241&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32075727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingula R., et al. Desired turbulence? Gut-lung axis, immunity, and lung cancer. Journal of oncology. 2017;2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5623803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29075294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamming I., et al. Tissue distribution of ACE2 protein, the functional receptor for SARS coronavirus. A first step in understanding SARS pathogenesis. The Journal of Pathology: A Journal of the Pathological Society of Great Britain and Ireland. 2004;203(2):631&#x2013;637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7167720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15141377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salomao R., et al. Sepsis of Patients Infected by SARS-CoV-2: Real-World Experience From the International. Sepsis and COVID-19: Cross-Talk in Signalling Pathways and in Therapeutic Perspectives. 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig A.M., et al. Evidence of the COVID-19 virus targeting the CNS: tissue distribution, host&#x2013;virus interaction, and proposed neurotropic mechanisms. ACS chemical neuroscience. 2020;11(7):995&#x2013;998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32167747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han H., et al. Profiling serum cytokines in COVID-19 patients reveals IL-6 and IL-10 are disease severity predictors. Emerging microbes &amp; infections. 2020;9(1):1123&#x2013;1130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7473317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32475230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effenberger M., et al. Faecal calprotectin indicates intestinal inflammation in COVID-19. Gut. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32312790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto T., et al. ACE2 links amino acid malnutrition to microbial ecology and intestinal inflammation. Nature. 2012;487(7408):477&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22837003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng S.C., Tilg H. COVID-19 and the gastrointestinal tract: more than meets the eye Gut: first published as 10.1136/gutjnl-2020-321195 on 9 April 2020. Gut Month. 2020:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32273292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., et al. Digestive system is a potential route of COVID-19: an analysis of single-cell coexpression pattern of key proteins in viral entry process. Gut. 2020;69(6):1010&#x2013;1018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J., et al. Infection of bat and human intestinal organoids by SARS-CoV-2. Nature medicine. 2020;26(7):1077&#x2013;1083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32405028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Q., et al. The mechanism and treatment of gastrointestinal symptoms in patients with COVID-19. American Journal of Physiology-Gastrointestinal and Liver Physiology. 2020;319(2):G245&#x2013;G252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7414235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32639848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belkaid Y., Hand T.W. Role of the microbiota in immunity and inflammation. Cell. 2014;157(1):121&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4056765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24679531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ, T T., Chew J, Lim WL. Antidepressive mechanisms of probiotics and their therapeutic potential. Frontiers in neuroscience. 2020;14(13):1361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6971226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32009871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng J., et al. Gastrointestinal sequelae 90 days after discharge for COVID-19. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;6(5):344&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7943402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33711290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vodnar D.C., et al. Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) Caused by (SARS-CoV-2) Infections: A Real Challenge for Human Gut Microbiota. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2020;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7756003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33363049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo T., et al. Alterations in gut microbiota of patients with COVID-19 during time of hospitalization. Gastroenterology. 2020;159(3):944&#x2013;955. e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7237927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowak J.K., et al. Age, inflammation, and disease location are critical determinants of intestinal expression of SARS-CoV-2 receptor ACE2 and TMPRSS2 in inflammatory bowel disease. Gastroenterology. 2020;159(3):1151&#x2013;1154. e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7217073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32413354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangma A., Voskuil M.D., Weersma R.K. TNF&#x3b1;-antagonist use and mucosal inflammation are associated with increased intestinal expression of SARS-CoV-2 host protease TMPRSS2 in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Gastroenterology. 2021;160(7):2621&#x2013;2622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32553760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambrose P.A., Goodman W.A. Impact of COVID-19 on patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Journal of exploratory research in pharmacology. 2022;7(1):37&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9373928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35966234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi B., Vesal A., Edalatifard M. Coronavirus and Its effect on the respiratory system: Is there any association between pneumonia and immune cells. Journal of Family Medicine and Primary Care. 2020;9(9):4729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33209791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kariyawasam J.C., et al. Gastrointestinal manifestations in COVID-19. Transactions of The Royal Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene. 2021;115(12):1362&#x2013;1388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7989191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33728439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke S.A., Abbara A., Dhillo W.S. Impact of COVID-19 on the Endocrine System: A Mini-review. Endocrinology. 2022;163(1):bqab203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34543404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anonymous, How COVID-19 Can Lead to Diabetes. 2021. June 8, .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ormiston C.K., &#x15a;wi&#x105;tkiewicz I., Taub P.R. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome as a sequela of COVID-19. Heart Rhythm. 2022;19(11):1880&#x2013;1889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9287587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35853576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallak J., et al. SARS-CoV-2 and its relationship with the genitourinary tract: Implications for male reproductive health in the context of COVID-19 pandemic. Andrology. 2021;9(1):73&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32869939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan L.K., et al. Effects of COVID-19 on the musculoskeletal system: Clinician's guide. Orthopedic Research and Reviews. 2021:141&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8464590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34584465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M., et al. Bidirectional associations between COVID-19 and psychiatric disorder: retrospective cohort studies of 62 354 COVID-19 cases in the USA. The Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8(2):130&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ettman C.K., et al. Prevalence of depression symptoms in US adults before and during the COVID-19 pandemic. JAMA network open. 2020;3(9) -e2019686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7489837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32876685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A., et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nature medicine. 2021;27(4):601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cellini N., et al. Changes in sleep pattern, sense of time and digital media use during COVID-19 lockdown in Italy. Journal of sleep research. 2020;29(4):e13074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7235482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32410272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkow N.D. American College of Physicians; 2020. Collision of the COVID-19 and addiction epidemics; pp. 61&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7138334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32240293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shear M. Complicated Grief New England Journal of Medicine. Mass Med Soc. 2015;372:153&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25564898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stangl A.L., et al. The Health Stigma and Discrimination Framework: a global, crosscutting framework to inform research, intervention development, and policy on health-related stigmas. BMC medicine. 2019;17:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6376797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30764826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tedeschi R.G., Calhoun L.G. Posttraumatic growth: conceptual foundations and empirical evidence. Psychological inquiry. 2004;15(1):1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torous J., et al. Digital mental health and COVID-19: using technology today to accelerate the curve on access and quality tomorrow. JMIR mental health. 2020;7(3):e18848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7101061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32213476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>