<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34888989</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1654</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Reviews in medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rev Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proposed subtypes of post-COVID-19 syndrome (or long-COVID) and their respective potential therapies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2315</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2315</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/rmv.2315</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The effects of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), a highly transmissible infectious respiratory disease that has initiated an ongoing pandemic since early 2020, do not always end in the acute phase. Depending on the study referred, about 10%-30% (or more) of COVID-19 survivors may develop long-COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome (PCS), characterised by persistent symptoms (most commonly fatigue, dyspnoea, and cognitive impairments) lasting for 3 months or more after acute COVID-19. While the pathophysiological mechanisms of PCS have been extensively described elsewhere, the subtypes of PCS have not. Owing to its highly multifaceted nature, this review proposes and characterises six subtypes of PCS based on the existing literature. The subtypes are non-severe COVID-19 multi-organ sequelae (NSC-MOS), pulmonary fibrosis sequelae (PFS), myalgic encephalomyelitis or chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS), postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS), post-intensive care syndrome (PICS) and medical or clinical sequelae (MCS). Original studies supporting each of these subtypes are documented in this review, as well as their respective symptoms and potential interventions. Ultimately, the subtyping proposed herein aims to provide better clarity on the current understanding of PCS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. Reviews in Medical Virology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yong</LastName><ForeName>Shin Jie</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9752-8386</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, School of Medical and Life Sciences, Sunway University, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Shiliang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Surveillance and Applied Research, Public Health Agency of Canada, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Epidemiology and Public Health, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Rev Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1052-9276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015673" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fatigue Syndrome, Chronic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054972" MajorTopicYN="Y">Postural Orthostatic Tachycardia Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sequelae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">subtype</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34888989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rmv.2315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Hu B, Guo H, Zhou P, Shi ZL. Characteristics of SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2020;19:141-154. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41579-020-00459-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malek RJ, Bill CA, Vines CM. Clinical drug therapies and biologicals currently used or in clinical trial to treat COVID-19. Biomed Pharmacother. 2021;144.112276. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2021.112276</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, Hishmeh L. Managing the long term effects of covid-19: summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ. 2021;372:n136. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n136</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A'Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020;370:m3026. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m3026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cevik M, Kuppalli K, Kindrachuk J, Peiris M. Virology, transmission, and pathogenesis of SARS-CoV-2. BMJ. 2020;371:m3862. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m3862</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oran DP, Topol EJ. Prevalence of asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection: a narrative review. Ann Intern Med. 2020;173(5):362-367. https://doi.org/10.7326/M20-3012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syangtan G, Bista S, Dawadi P, et&#xa0;al. Asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 carriers: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Public Health. 2020;8:587374. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2020.587374</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et&#xa0;al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601-615. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallett S, Allen AJ, Graziadio S, et&#xa0;al. At what times during infection is SARS-CoV-2 detectable and no longer detectable using RT-PCR-based tests? A systematic review of individual participant data. BMC Med. 2020;418(1):346. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12916-020-01810-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T, Hittle M, Goodman SN. Assessment of the frequency and variety of persistent symptoms among patients with COVID-19: a systematic review. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(5).e2111417. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.11417</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, et&#xa0;al. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6(9):e005427. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgh-2021-005427</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahriani M, Ilmawan M, Fajar JK, et&#xa0;al. Persistence of long COVID symptoms in COVID-19 survivors worldwide and its potential pathogenesis - a systematic review and meta-analysis. Narra J. 2021;1(2). https://doi.org/10.52225/narraj.v1i2.36</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusuf F, Fahriani M, Mamada SS, et&#xa0;al. Global prevalence of prolonged gastrointestinal symptoms in COVID-19 survivors and potential pathogenesis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. F1000Res. 2021;10:301.301. https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.52216.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullard A. Long COVID's long R&amp;D agenda. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2021;20:329-331. https://doi.org/10.1038/d41573-021-00069-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondratiuk AL, Pillay TD, Kon OM, Lalvani A. A conceptual framework to accelerate the clinical impact of evolving research into long COVID. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21:756-757. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1473-3099(21)00136-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo F, Karras BT, Phillips R, Kimball AM, Wolf F. Diagnoses, syndromes, and diseases: a knowledge representation problem. AMIA Annu Symp Proc. 2003:802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis. 2021;53:1-754. https://doi.org/10.1080/23744235.2021.1924397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera Martimbianco AL, Pacheco RL, Bagattini AM, Riera R. Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID-19: a systematic review. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75.e14357. https://doi.org/10.1111/ijcp.14357</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, et&#xa0;al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1).16144. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et&#xa0;al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n71</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et&#xa0;al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. medRxiv. 2021;2020. 12.24.20248802. https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.12.24.20248802</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et&#xa0;al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen MS, Kristiansen MF, Hanusson KD, et&#xa0;al. Long COVID in the Faroe Islands - a longitudinal study among non-hospitalized patients. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;30. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciaa1792</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin M, Schommers P, Stecher M, et&#xa0;al. Post-COVID syndrome in non-hospitalised patients with COVID-19: a longitudinal prospective cohort study. Lancet Reg Health Eur. 2021;6:100122. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Alberts J, et&#xa0;al. Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open. 2021;11(3).e048391. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2020-048391</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KG, Brokstad KA, et&#xa0;al. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med. 2021;27:1607-1613. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-021-01433-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardo MDM, Foppiani A, Peretti GM, et&#xa0;al. Long-term coronavirus disease 2019 complications in inpatients and outpatients: a one-year follow-up cohort study. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8(8).ofab384. https://doi.org/10.1093/ofid/ofab384</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seessle J, Waterboer T, Hippchen T, et&#xa0;al. Persistent symptoms in adult patients one year after COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Clin Infect Dis. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciab611</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Espuny Pujol F, Munblit D, McFarland S, Simpson F. Clinical characteristics, activity levels and mental health problems in children with Long COVID: a survey of 510 children. Preprints. 2021. https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202103.0271.v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Munblit D, De Rose C, et&#xa0;al. Preliminary evidence on long COVID in children. Acta Paediatr 2021;110:2208-2211. https://doi.org/10.1111/apa.15870</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osmanov IM, Spiridonova E, Bobkova P, et&#xa0;al. Risk factors for long covid in previously hospitalised children using the ISARIC Global follow-up protocol: a prospective cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2021:2101341. https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.01341-2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Cassar MP, Tunnicliffe EM, et&#xa0;al. Medium-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on multiple vital organs, exercise capacity, cognition, quality of life and mental health, post-hospital discharge. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;31.100683. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100683</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin L, Savale L, Pham T, et&#xa0;al. Four-month clinical status of a cohort of patients after hospitalization for COVID-19. JAMA. 2021;325:1525. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2021.3331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frija-Masson J, Debray MP, Boussouar S, et&#xa0;al. Residual ground glass opacities three months after Covid-19 pneumonia correlate to alteration of respiratory function: the post Covid M3 study. Respir Med. 2021;184.106435. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rmed.2021.106435</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Froidure A, Mahsouli A, Liistro G, et&#xa0;al. Integrative respiratory follow-up of severe COVID-19 reveals common functional and lung imaging sequelae. Respir Med. 2021;181.106383. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rmed.2021.106383</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mumoli N, Bonaventura A, Colombo A, et&#xa0;al. Lung function and symptoms in post-COVID-19 patients: a single-center experience. Mayo Clin Proc Innov Qual Outcomes. 2021;5(5):907-915. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mayocpiqo.2021.08.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robey RC, Kemp K, Hayton P, et&#xa0;al. Pulmonary sequelae at 4 mnths after COVID-19 infection: a single-centre experience of a COVID follow-up service. Adv Ther. 2021;38(8):4505-4519. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12325-021-01833-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Fan Y, Alwalid O, et&#xa0;al. Six-month follow-up chest CT findings after severe COVID-19 pneumonia. Radiology. 2021;299:E177-E186. https://doi.org/10.1148/radiol.2021203153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Shen C, Wang L, et&#xa0;al. Pulmonary fibrosis and its related factors in discharged patients with new corona virus pneumonia: a cohort study. Respir Res. 2021;22(1).203. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12931-021-01798-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Lv F, Huang Y, Xiao K. Follow-up study of the chest CT characteristics of COVID-19 survivors seven months after recovery. Front Med (Lausanne). 2021;8.636298. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2021.636298</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGroder CF, Zhang D, Choudhury MA, et&#xa0;al. Pulmonary fibrosis 4 months after COVID-19 is associated with severity of illness and blood leucocyte telomere length. Thorax. 2021;76:1242-1245. https://doi.org/10.1136/thoraxjnl-2021-217031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simani L, Ramezani M, Darazam IA, et&#xa0;al. Prevalence and correlates of chronic fatigue syndrome and post-traumatic stress disorder after the outbreak of the COVID-19. J Neurovirol. 2021;27:154-159. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13365-021-00949-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedor C, Freitag H, Meyer-Arndt L, et&#xa0;al. Chronic COVID-19 Syndrome and Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS) following the first pandemic wave in Germany - a first analysis of a prospective observational study. medRxiv. 2021. 2021.02.06.21249256. https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.02.06.21249256</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Hermosillo JA, Martinez-Lopez JP, Carrillo-Lampon SA, et&#xa0;al. Post-acute COVID-19 symptoms, a potential Link with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a 6-month survey in a Mexican cohort. Brain Sci 2021;11(6). https://doi.org/10.3390/brainsci11060760</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantovani E, Mariotto S, Gabbiani D, et&#xa0;al. Chronic fatigue syndrome: an emerging sequela in COVID-19 survivors? J Neurovirol. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13365-021-01002-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estiri H, Strasser ZH, Brat GA, Semenov YR, Patel CJ, Murphy SN. Evolving phenotypes of non-hospitalized patients that indicate long covid. medRxiv. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.04.25.21255923</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elanwar R, Hussein M, Magdy R, et&#xa0;al. Physical and mental fatigue in subjects recovered from COVID-19 infection: a case-control study. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2021;17:2063-2071. https://doi.org/10.2147/NDT.S317027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S, Whitelaw S. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) and other autonomic disorders after COVID-19 infection: a case series of 20 patients. Immunol Res. 2021;69:205-211. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12026-021-09185-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shouman K, Vanichkachorn G, Cheshire WP, et&#xa0;al. Autonomic dysfunction following COVID-19 infection: an early experience. Clin Auton Res. 2021;31:385-394. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10286-021-00803-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Moloney D, Finucane C, et&#xa0;al. Fatigue following COVID-19 infection is not associated with autonomic dysfunction. PLoS One. 2021;16(2):e0247280. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0247280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor RR, Trivedi B, Patel N, et&#xa0;al. Post-COVID symptoms reported at asynchronous virtual review and stratified follow-up after COVID-19 pneumonia. Clin Med (Lond). 2021;21:e384-e391. https://doi.org/10.7861/clinmed.2021-0037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valent A, Dudoignon E, Ressaire Q, Depret F, Plaud B. Three-month quality of life in survivors of ARDS due to COVID-19: a preliminary report from a French academic centre. Anaesth Crit Care Pain Med. 2020;39(6):740-741. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.accpm.2020.10.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daste C, Ficarra S, Dumitrache A, et&#xa0;al. Post-intensive care syndrome in patients surviving COVID-19. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2021;64:101549. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rehab.2021.101549</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rousseau AF, Minguet P, Colson C, et&#xa0;al. Post-intensive care syndrome after a critical COVID-19: cohort study from a Belgian follow-up clinic. Ann Intensive Care. 2021;11(1):118. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13613-021-00910-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Veenendaal N, van der Meulen IC, Onrust M, Paans W, Dieperink W, van der Voort PHJ. Six-month outcomes in COVID-19 ICU patients and their family members: a prospective cohort study. Healthcare (Basel). 2021;9(7):865. https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare9070865</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Khunti K, Nafilyan V, et&#xa0;al. Post-covid syndrome in individuals admitted to hospital with covid-19: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;372:n693. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n693</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594:259-264. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-021-03553-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416-427. https://doi.org/10.1016/s2215-0366(21)00084-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty SE, Guo Y, Heath K, et&#xa0;al. Risk of clinical sequelae after the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;373:n1098. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n1098</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chevinsky JR, Tao G, Lavery AM, et&#xa0;al. Late conditions diagnosed 1-4 months following an initial coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) encounter: a matched-cohort study using inpatient and outpatient Administrative data-United States, 1 March-30 June 2020. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73(Suppl 1):S5-S16. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciab338</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Romieu AC, Leung S, Mbanya A, et&#xa0;al. Health care utilization and clinical characteristics of nonhospitalized adults in an integrated health care system 28-180 days after COVID-19 diagnosis - Georgia, may 2020-March 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2021;70(17):644-650. https://doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm7017e3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund LC, Hallas J, Nielsen H, et&#xa0;al. Post-acute effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection in individuals not requiring hospital admission: a Danish population-based cohort study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21:1373-1382. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1473-3099(21)00211-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestre-Muniz MM, Arias A, Mata-Vazquez E, et&#xa0;al. Long-term outcomes of patients with coronavirus disease 2019 at one year after hospital discharge. J Clin Med. 2021;10(13):2945. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10132945</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Madhavan MV, Sehgal K, et&#xa0;al. Extrapulmonary manifestations of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2020;26(7):1017-1032. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-020-0968-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): an overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front Microbiol. 2021;12.698169. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2021.698169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021:n1648. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n1648</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B, Peters JB, Brink M, et&#xa0;al. Comprehensive health assessment three months after recovery from acute COVID-19. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;73:e1089-e1098. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciaa1750</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, et&#xa0;al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220-232. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(20)32656-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stylemans D, Smet J, Hanon S, et&#xa0;al. Evolution of lung function and chest CT 6 months after COVID-19 pneumonia: real-life data from a Belgian University Hospital. Respir Med. 2021;182:106421.106421. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rmed.2021.106421</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X, Huang H, Wang C, et&#xa0;al. Follow-up study of pulmonary function among COVID-19 survivors 1 year after recovery. J Infect. 2021;83:381-412. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2021.05.034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li X, Geng D, et&#xa0;al. Cerebral micro-structural changes in COVID-19 patients - an MRI-based 3-month follow-up study. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25.100484. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100484</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazhenets G, Schroter N, Bormann T, et&#xa0;al. Slow but evident recovery from neocortical dysfunction and cognitive impairment in a series of chronic COVID-19 patients. J Nucl Med. 2021. https://doi.org/10.2967/jnumed.121.262128</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Campion JY, Dudouet P, et&#xa0;al. (18)F-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in patients with long COVID. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48:2823-2833. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00259-021-05215-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntmann VO, Carerj ML, Wieters I, et&#xa0;al. Outcomes of cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in patients recently recovered from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiol 2020;5(11):1265-1273. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2020.3557</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan C, Zhang Z, Luo L, et&#xa0;al. Cardiac T1 and T2 mapping showed myocardial involvement in recovered COVID-19 patients initially considered devoid of cardiac damage. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2021;54:421-428. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmri.27534</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajpal S, Tong MS, Borchers J, et&#xa0;al. Cardiovascular magnetic resonance findings in competitive athletes recovering from COVID-19 infection. JAMA Cardiol 2020. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2020.4916</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malek LA, Marczak M, Milosz-Wieczorek B, et&#xa0;al. Cardiac involvement in consecutive elite athletes recovered from Covid-19: a magnetic resonance study. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2021;53:1723-1729. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmri.27513</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraro F, Calafiore D, Dambruoso F, Guidarini S, de Sire A. COVID-19 related fatigue: which role for rehabilitation in post-COVID-19 patients? A case series. J Med Virol. 2020;93:1896-1899. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.26717</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puchner B, Sahanic S, Kirchmair R, et&#xa0;al. Beneficial effects of multi-disciplinary rehabilitation in post-acute COVID-19 - an observational cohort study. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2021;57. https://doi.org/10.23736/S1973-9087.21.06549-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piquet V, Luczak C, Seiler F, et&#xa0;al. Do patients with COVID-19 benefit from rehabilitation? Functional outcomes of the first 100 patients in a COVID-19 rehabilitation unit. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;102:1067-1074. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmr.2021.01.069</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker-Davies RM, O'Sullivan O, Senaratne KPP, et&#xa0;al. The Stanford Hall consensus statement for post-COVID-19 rehabilitation. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(16):949-959. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2020-102596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z, McGoogan JM. Characteristics of and important lessons from the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) outbreak in China: summary of a report of 72314 cases from the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention. JAMA. 2020;323(13):1239-1242. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.2648</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>John AE, Joseph C, Jenkins G, Tatler AL. COVID-19 and pulmonary fibrosis: a potential role for lung epithelial cells and fibroblasts. Immunol Rev. 2021;302:228-240. https://doi.org/10.1111/imr.12977</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai DK, Sharma P, Kumar R. Post covid 19 pulmonary fibrosis. Is it real threat? Indian J Tuberc. 2021;68(3):330-333. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijtb.2020.11.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Anjum F. Ventilator-Induced Lung Injury (VILI). StatPearls. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates JHT, Smith BJ. Ventilator-induced lung injury and lung mechanics. Ann Transl Med. 2018;6(19):378. https://doi.org/10.21037/atm.2018.06.29</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechowicz K, Drozdzal S, Machaj F, et&#xa0;al. COVID-19: the potential treatment of pulmonary fibrosis associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Clin Med. 2020;9(6):1917. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm9061917</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambardar SR, Hightower SL, Huprikar NA, Chung KK, Singhal A, Collen JF. Post-COVID-19 pulmonary fibrosis: novel sequelae of the current pandemic. J Clin Med. 2021;10(11):2452. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10112452</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Wu Z, Li JW, et&#xa0;al. Discharge may not be the end of treatment: pay attention to pulmonary fibrosis caused by severe COVID-19. J Med Virol. 2021;93(3):1378-1386. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.26634</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umemura Y, Mitsuyama Y, Minami K, et&#xa0;al. Efficacy and safety of nintedanib for pulmonary fibrosis in severe pneumonia induced by Coronavirus disease 2019: an interventional study. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;108:454-460. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2021.05.055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiq MAB, Rathore FA, Clegg D, Rasker JJ. Pulmonary Rehabilitation in COVID-19 patients: a scoping review of current practice and its application during the pandemic. Turk J Phys Med Rehabil. 2020;66(4):480-494. https://doi.org/10.5606/tftrd.2020.6889</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurtais Aytur Y, Koseoglu BF, Ozyemisci Taskiran O, et&#xa0;al. Pulmonary rehabilitation principles in SARS-COV-2 infection (COVID-19): a guideline for the acute and subacute rehabilitation. Turk J Phys Med&#xa0;Rehabil. 2020;66(2):104-120. https://doi.org/10.5606/tftrd.2020.6444</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funke-Chambour M, Bridevaux PO, Clarenbach CF, Soccal PM, Nicod LP, von&#xa0;Garnier C. Swiss recommendations for the follow-up and treatment of pulmonary long COVID. Respiration. 2021;100(8):826-841. https://doi.org/10.1159/000517255</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang LL, Yang T. Pulmonary rehabilitation for patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Chronic Dis Transl Med. 2020;6(2):79-86. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cdtm.2020.05.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zampogna E, Paneroni M, Belli S, et&#xa0;al. Pulmonary rehabilitation in patients recovering from COVID-19. Respiration. 2021;100:1-422. https://doi.org/10.1159/000514387</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daynes E, Gerlis C, Chaplin E, Gardiner N, Singh SJ. Early experiences of rehabilitation for individuals post-COVID to improve fatigue, breathlessness exercise capacity and cognition - a cohort study. Chron Respir Dis. 2021;18. https://doi.org/10.1177/14799731211015691</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gloeckl R, Leitl D, Jarosch I, et&#xa0;al. Benefits of pulmonary rehabilitation in COVID-19: a prospective observational cohort study. ERJ Open Res. 2021;7(2). https://doi.org/10.1183/23120541.00108-2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curci C, Negrini F, Ferrillo M, et&#xa0;al. Functional outcome after inpatient rehabilitation in post-intensive care unit COVID-19 patients: findings and clinical implications from a real-practice retrospective study. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2021;57. https://doi.org/10.23736/S1973-9087.20.06660-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spielmanns M, Pekacka-Egli AM, Schoendorf S, Windisch W, Hermann M. Effects of a comprehensive pulmonary rehabilitation in severe post-COVID-19 patients. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(5):2695. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18052695</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Zhang W, Yang Y, Zhang J, Li Y, Chen Y. Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: a randomized controlled study. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2020;39.101166. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101166</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K, Straus SE, Hickie I, Sharpe MC, Dobbins JG, Komaroff A. The chronic fatigue syndrome: a comprehensive approach to its definition and study. International Chronic Fatigue Syndrome Study Group. Ann Intern Med. 1994;121(12):953-959. https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-121-12-199412150-00009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carruthers BM, Jain AK, De Meirleir KL, et&#xa0;al. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. J Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. 2003;11(1):7-115. https://doi.org/10.1300/J092v11n01_02</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clayton EW. Beyond myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: an IOM report on redefining an illness. JAMA. 2015;313(11):1101-1102. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2015.1346</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim EJ, Ahn YC, Jang ES, Lee SW, Lee SH, Son CG. Systematic review and meta-analysis of the prevalence of chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME). J Transl Med. 2020;18(1):100. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967-020-02269-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cairns R, Hotopf M. A systematic review describing the prognosis of chronic fatigue syndrome. Occup Med (Lond). 2005;55(1):20-31. https://doi.org/10.1093/occmed/kqi013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nacul L, O'Boyle S, Palla L, et&#xa0;al. How myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) progresses: the natural history of ME/CFS. Front Neurol. 2020;11:826. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2020.00826</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL. Advances in understanding the pathophysiology of chronic fatigue syndrome. J Am Med Assoc. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2019.8312</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu L, Valencia IJ, Garvert DW, Montoya JG. Onset patterns and course of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Front Pediatr. 2019;7. https://doi.org/10.3389/fped.2019.00012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg J, Gottfries CG, Elfaitouri A, Rizwan M, Rosen A. Infection elicited autoimmunity and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: an explanatory model. Front Immunol. 2018;9:229. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2018.00229</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL, Bateman L. Will COVID-19 lead to myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome? Front Med. 2021;7. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2020.606824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong TL, Weitzer DJ. Long COVID and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS)-A systemic review and comparison of clinical presentation and symptomatology. Medicina (Kaunas). 2021;57(5):418. https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina57050418</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghimi N, Di Napoli M, Biller J, et&#xa0;al. The neurological manifestations of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2021;21(9):44. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11910-021-01130-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DY, Lee JS, Park SY, Kim SJ, Son CG. Systematic review of randomized controlled trials for chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME). J Transl Med. Jan 6 2020;18(1):7. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967-019-02196-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bested AC, Marshall LM. Review of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: an evidence-based approach to diagnosis and management by clinicians. Rev Environ Health. 2015;30(4):223-249. https://doi.org/10.1515/reveh-2015-0026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes Rivera M, Mastronardi C, Silva-Aldana CT, Arcos-Burgos M, Lidbury BA. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a comprehensive review. Diagn. 2019;9(3). https://doi.org/10.3390/diagnostics9030091</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kindlon T. Do graded activity therapies cause harm in chronic fatigue syndrome? J Health Psychol. 2017;22(9):1146-1154. https://doi.org/10.1177/1359105317697323</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twisk FN, Maes M. A review on cognitive behavorial therapy (CBT) and graded exercise therapy (GET) in myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME)/chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS): CBT/GET is not only ineffective and not evidence-based, but also potentially harmful for many patients with ME/CFS. Neuroendocrinol Lett. 2009;30(3):284-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman M. Chronic fatigue syndrome and long covid: moving beyond the controversy. BMJ. Jun 23 2021;373:n1559. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n1559</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torjesen I. NICE backtracks on graded exercise therapy and CBT in draft revision to CFS guidance. BMJ. 2020;371:m4356. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m4356</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryarly M, Phillips LT, Fu Q, Vernino S, Levine BD. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome: JACC focus seminar. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;73(10):1207-1228. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2018.11.059</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheldon RS, Grubb BP, 2nd, Olshansky B, et&#xa0;al. Heart rhythm society expert consensus statement on the diagnosis and treatment of postural tachycardia syndrome, inappropriate sinus tachycardia, and vasovagal syncope. Heart Rhythm. 2015;12(6):e41-e63. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hrthm.2015.03.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedorowski A. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome: clinical presentation, aetiology and management. J Intern Med. 2019;285(4):352-366. https://doi.org/10.1111/joim.12852</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P, et&#xa0;al. Autonomic dysfunction in &#x2018;long COVID&#x2019;: rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin Med (Lond). 2020;21:e63-e67. https://doi.org/10.7861/clinmed.2020-0896</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman BP, Khoury JA, Blair JE, Grill MF. COVID-19 dysautonomia. Front Neurol. 2021;12.624968. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2021.624968</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallukat G, Hohberger B, Wenzel K, et&#xa0;al. Functional autoantibodies against G-protein coupled receptors in patients with persistent long-COVID-19 symptoms. J Transl Autoimmun. 2021;4.100100. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtauto.2021.100100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadhav K, Jariwala P. &#x2018;Ivabradin&#x2019; versus &#x2018;Carvedilol&#x2019; in the management of Post-COVID-19 palpitation with sinus tachycardia. Indian Heart J. 2020;72:S33. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ihj.2020.11.092</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue S, Hatakeyama J, Kondo Y, et&#xa0;al. Post-intensive care syndrome: its pathophysiology, prevention, and future directions. Acute Med Surg. 2019;6(3):233-246. https://doi.org/10.1002/ams2.415</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawal G, Yadav S, Kumar R. Post-intensive care syndrome: an overview. J Transl Int Med. 2017;5(2):90-92. https://doi.org/10.1515/jtim-2016-0016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peach BC, Valenti M, Sole ML. A call for the World Health Organization to create international classification of disease diagnostic codes for post-intensive care syndrome in the age of COVID-19. World Med Health Policy. 2021;13:373-382. https://doi.org/10.1002/wmh3.401</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangash MN, Owen A, Alderman JE, Chotalia M, Patel JM, Parekh D. COVID-19 recovery: potential treatments for post-intensive care syndrome. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8(11):1071-1073. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30457-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith EMT, Lee ACW, Smith JM, Thiele A, Zeleznik H, Ohtake PJ. COVID-19 and post-intensive care syndrome: community-based care for ICU survivors. Home Health Care Manag Pract. 2020;33:117-124. https://doi.org/10.1177/1084822320974956</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hariyanto TI, Kurniawan A. Metformin use is associated with reduced mortality rate from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) infection. Obes Med. 2020;19:100290. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.obmed.2020.100290</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hariyanto TI, Intan D, Hananto JE, Putri C, Kurniawan A. Pre-admission glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonist (GLP-1RA) and mortality from coronavirus disease 2019 (Covid-19): a systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2021;179:109031. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2021.109031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halacli B, Topeli Iskit A. Implementation of post-intensive care outpatient clinic (I-POINT) for critically-ill COVID-19 survivors. Turk J Med Sci. 2021. https://doi.org/10.3906/sag-2106-306</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt K, Gensichen J, Gehrke-Beck S, et&#xa0;al. Management of COVID-19 ICU-survivors in primary care:-a narrative review. BMC Fam Pract. 2021;22(1).160. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12875-021-01464-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taito S, Yamauchi K, Tsujimoto Y, Banno M, Tsujimoto H, Kataoka Y. Does enhanced physical rehabilitation following intensive care unit discharge improve outcomes in patients who received mechanical ventilation? A systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open.&#xa0;2019;9(6).e026075. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2018-026075</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minetto MA, Fior SD, Busso C, et&#xa0;al. Effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation therapy on physical function in patients with COVID-19 associated pneumonia: study protocol of a randomized controlled trial. Contemp Clin Trials Commun. 2021;21.100742. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conctc.2021.100742</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho AC, Moreira J, Cubelo P, Cantista P, Branco CA, Guimaraes B. Therapeutic respiratory and functional rehabilitation protocol for intensive care unit patients affected by COVID-19: a structured summary of a study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials. 2021;22(1).268. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13063-021-05210-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlake JH, Van Bommel J, Wils EJ, et&#xa0;al. Effect of intensive care unit-specific virtual reality (ICU-VR) to improve psychological well-being and quality of life in COVID-19 ICU survivors: a study protocol for a multicentre, randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2021;22(1):328. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13063-021-05271-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turan Z, Topaloglu M, Ozyemisci Taskiran O. Is tele-rehabilitation superior to home exercise program in COVID-19 survivors following discharge from intensive care unit? - a study protocol of a randomized controlled trial. Physiother Res Int. 2021;26.e1920. https://doi.org/10.1002/pri.1920</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojeda A, Calvo A, Cunat T, et&#xa0;al. Rationale and study design of an early care, therapeutic education, and psychological intervention program for the management of post-intensive care syndrome and chronic pain after COVID-19 infection (PAIN-COVID): study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2021;22(1):486. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13063-021-05463-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath A. Long-haul COVID. Neurology. 2020;95(13):559-560. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000010640</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hacker KA, Briss PA, Richardson L, Wright J, Petersen R. COVID-19 and chronic disease: the impact now and in the future. Prev Chronic Dis. 2021;18.E62. https://doi.org/10.5888/pcd18.210086</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callard F, Perego E. How and why patients made Long Covid. Soc Sci Med. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113426</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rando HM, Bennett TD, Byrd JB, et&#xa0;al. Challenges in defining long COVID: striking differences across literature, electronic health records, and patient-reported information. medRxiv. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.03.20.21253896</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan NA, Johnson L. Defining long COVID: going back to the start. Med (N Y). 2021;2:501-504. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.medj.2021.03.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-de-Las-Penas C, Palacios-Cena D, Gomez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Florencio LL. Defining post-COVID symptoms (post-acute COVID, long COVID, persistent post-COVID): an integrative classification. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(5):2621. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18052621</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran VT, Riveros C, Clepier B, et&#xa0;al. Development and validation of the long covid symptom and impact tools, a set of patient-reported instruments constructed from patients' lived experience. Clin Infect Dis. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciab352</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeMerle K, Angus DC, Seymour CW. Precision medicine for COVID-19: phenotype anarchy or promise realized? J Am Med Assoc. 2021;325:2041. https://d5oi.org/10.1001/jama.2021.5248</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>