<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36648876</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2079-9721</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Diseases (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Diseases</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Draft Report by the Institute for Quality and Efficiency in Healthcare Does Not Provide Any Evidence That Graded Exercise Therapy and Cognitive Behavioral Therapy Are Safe and Effective Treatments for Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/diseases11010011</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The German Institute for Quality and Efficiency in Healthcare (IQWiG) recently published its draft report to the government about myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). The IQWiG concluded that graded exercise therapy (GET) and cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) should be recommended in the treatment for mild and moderate ME/CFS based on two CBT and two GET studies. In this article, we reviewed the evidence used by IQWiG to support their claims, because their conclusion is diametrically opposed to the conclusion by the British National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) in its recently updated ME/CFS guidelines. Our analysis shows that the trials IQWiG used in support suffered from serious flaws, which included badly designed control groups; relying on subjective primary outcomes in non-blinded studies; alliance and response shift bias, including patients in their trials who did not have the disease under investigation, selective reporting, making extensive endpoint changes and low to very low adherence of treatments. Our analysis also shows that the report itself used one CBT and one GET study that both examined a different treatment. The report also used a definition of CBT that does not reflect the way it is being used in ME/CFS or was tested in the studies. The report noted that one study used a wrong definition of post-exertional malaise (PEM), the main characteristic of the disease, according to the report. Yet, it ignored the consequence of this, that less than the required minimum percentage of patients had the disease under investigation in that study. It also ignored the absence of improvement on most of the subjective outcomes, as well as the fact that the IQWiG methods handbook states that one should use objective outcomes and not rely on subjective outcomes in non-blinded studies. The report concluded that both treatments did not lead to objective improvement in the six-minute walk test but then ignored that. The report did not analyze the other objective outcomes of the studies (step test and occupational and benefits status), which showed a null effect. Finally, the report states that the studies do not report on safety yet assumes that the treatments are safe based on a tendency towards small subjective improvements in fatigue and physical functioning, even though the adherence to the treatments was (very) low and the studies included many patients who did not have the disease under investigation and, consequently, did not suffer from exertion intolerance contrary to ME/CFS patients. At the same time, it ignored and downplayed all the evidence that both treatments are not safe, even when the evidence was produced by a British university. In conclusion, the studies used by the report do not provide any evidence that CBT and GET are safe and effective. Consequently, the report and the studies do not provide any support for the recommendation to use CBT and GET for ME/CFS or long COVID, which, in many cases, is the same or resembles ME/CFS, after an infection with SARS-CoV-2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vink</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1079-5647</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Independent Researcher, 1096 HZ Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vink-Niese</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Independent Researcher, 30159 Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Diseases</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101636232</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2079-9721</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic fatigue syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive behavioral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myalgic encephalomyelitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-infectious disorders</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36648876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9844345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diseases11010011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">diseases11010011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>IQWiG Myalgische Enzephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS): Aktueller Kenntnisstand Vorbericht Auftrag: Version: Stand: N21 1.001 06.10.2022.  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/iqwig-report-n21-01_me-cfs-aktueller-kenntnisstand_vorbericht_v1-0.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute of Medicine (IOM) Beyond Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: Redefining an Illness. National Academies Press; Washington, DC, USA: 2015. Committee on the Diagnostic Criteria for Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome; Board on the Health of Select Populations.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutch Health Council  To the President of the Lower House of the States-General No. 2018, The Hague 19 March Health Council No.  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2021/01/gezondheidsraad-kernadvies_me_cvs.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE  Myalgic Encephalomyelitis (or Encephalopathy)/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: Diagnosis and Management. NICE Guideline [NG206] Oct 29, 2021.  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)].  Available online:  https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink M., Vink-Niese A. The draft updated NICE guidance for ME/CFS highlights the unreliability of subjective outcome measures in non-blinded trials. J. Health Psychol. 2022;27:9&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1177/1359105321990810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1359105321990810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33506707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilshire C.E., Kindlon T., Courtney R., Matthees A., Tuller D., Geraghty K., Levin B. Rethinking the treatment of chronic fatigue syndrome&#x2014;A reanalysis and evaluation of findings from a recent major trial of graded exercise and CBT. BMC Psychol. 2018;22:66. doi: 10.1186/s40359-018-0218-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-018-0218-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5863477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29562932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink M., Vink-Niese A. Cognitive behavioural therapy for myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome is not effective. Re-analysis of a Cochrane review. Health Psychol. Open. 2019;6:2055102919840614. doi: 10.1177/2055102919840614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2055102919840614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6498783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31080632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink M., Vink-Niese F. Work Rehabilitation and Medical Retirement for Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome Patients. A Rev. Apprais. Diagn. Strategies. Diagn. 2019;9:124. doi: 10.3390/diagnostics9040124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics9040124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6963831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31547009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal A., Marshall T. Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome in the Era of the Human Microbiome: Persistent Pathogens Drive Chronic Symptoms by Interfering With Host Metabolism, Gene Expression, and Immunity. Front. Pediatr. 2018;6:373. doi: 10.3389/fped.2018.00373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2018.00373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6288442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30564562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H.E., Assaf G.S., McCorkell L., Wei H., Low R.J., Re&#x2019;em Y., Redfield S., Austin J.P., Akrami A. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savovi&#x107; J., Jones H., Altman D., Harris R., J&#x171;ni P., Pildal J., Als-Nielsen B., Balk E., Gluud C., Gluud L., et al. Influence of reported study design characteristics on intervention effect estimates from randomised controlled trials: Combined analysis of meta-epidemiological studies. Health Technol. Assess. 2012;16:1&#x2013;82. doi: 10.3310/hta16350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3310/hta16350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22989478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheeres K., Knoop H., Meer V.D.J., Bleijenberg G. Clinical assessment of the physical activity pattern of chronic fatigue syndrome patients: A validation of three methods. Health Qual. Life Outcomes. 2009;7:29. doi: 10.1186/1477-7525-7-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1477-7525-7-29</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2674446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19338668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Berg-Emons R.J., L&#x2019;Ortye A.A., Buffart L.M., Nieuwenhuijsen C., Nooijen C.F., Bergen M.P., Stam H.J., Bussmann J.B. Validation of the Physical Activity Scale for individuals with physical disabilities. Arch. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 2011;92:923928. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2010.12.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2010.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21507382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercoulen J.H., Bazelmans E., Swanink C.M., Fennis J.F., Galama J.M., Jongen P.J., Hommes O., Van der Meer J.W., Bleijenberg G. Physical activity in chronic fatigue syndrome: Assessment and its role in fatigue. J. Psychiatr. Res. 1997;31:661673. doi: 10.1016/S0022-3956(97)00039-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-3956(97)00039-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9447571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink M., Vink-Niese F. Graded exercise therapy does not restore the ability to work in ME/CFS&#x2014;Rethinking of a Cochrane review. Work. 2020;66:283&#x2013;308. doi: 10.3233/WOR-203174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/WOR-203174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32568149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason L., Torres-Harding S., Friedberg F., Corradi K., Njoku M.G., Donalek J., Reynolds N., Brown M., Weitner B.B., Rademaker A., et al. Nonpharmacologic interventions for CFS: A randomized trial. J. Clin. Psychol. Med. Settings. 2007;172:485&#x2013;490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss-Morris R., Sharon C., Tobin R., Baldi J.C. A randomized controlled graded exercise trial for chronic fatigue syndrome: Outcomes and mechanisms of change. J. Health Psychol. 2005;10:245&#x2013;259. doi: 10.1177/1359105305049774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1359105305049774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15723894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FOIA Request to QMUL. Dataset File. FOIA Request 2014/F73a. 2016.  [(accessed on 13 January 2023)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2022/03/pace-ipd_foia-qmul-2014-f731.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FOIA Request to QMUL. A Selection of Individual Participant Data from the PACE Trial for Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Readme File. FOIA Request 2014/F73b. 2016.  [(accessed on 13 January 2023)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2022/03/pace-ipd-readme.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White P.D., Goldsmith K.A., Johnson A.L., Potts L., Walwyn R., DeCesare J.C., Baber H.L., Burgess M., Clark L.V., Cox D.L., et al. Comparison of adaptive pacing therapy, cognitive behaviour therapy, graded exercise therapy, and specialist medical care for chronic fatigue syndrome (PACE): A randomised trial. Lancet. 2011;377:823&#x2013;836. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(11)60096-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(11)60096-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3065633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21334061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IQWiG Methods Guidance Handbook (Allgemeine Methoden Version 6. 1 vom 24.01.2022)  [(accessed on 30 December 2022)].  Available online:  https://www.iqwig.de/methoden/allgemeine-methoden-v6-1.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An M.W., Duong Q., Le-Rademacher J., Mandrekar S.J. Principles of Good Clinical Trial Design. J. Thorac. Oncol. 2020;15:1277&#x2013;1280. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2020.05.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2020.05.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7390662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32417343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr D.C., Spring B., Freedland K.E., Beckner V., Arean P., Hollon S.D., Ockene J., Kaplan R. The Selection and Design of Control Conditions for Randomized Controlled Trials of Psychological Interventions. Psychother. Psychosom. 2009;78:275&#x2013;284. doi: 10.1159/000228248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000228248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19602916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janse A., Worm-Smeitink M., Bleijenberg G., Donders R., Knoop H. Efficacy of web-based cognitive-behavioural therapy for chronic fatigue syndrome: Randomised controlled trial. Br. J. Psychiatry. 2018;212:112&#x2013;118. doi: 10.1192/bjp.2017.22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.2017.22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29436329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dessel N., Den Boeft M., van der Wouden J.C., Kleinst&#xe4;uber M., Leone S., Terluin B., Numans M., van der Horst H., van Marwijk H. Non-pharmacological interventions for somatoform disorders and medically unexplained physical symptoms (MUPS) in adults. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2014;10:CD011142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10984143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25362239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunning D.L., Griffiths K., Kuyken W., Crane C., Foulkes L., Parker J., Dalgleish T. Research Review: The effects of mindfulness-based interventions on cognition and mental health in children and adolescents&#x2014;A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J. Child Psychol. Psychiatry. 2018;60:244&#x2013;258. doi: 10.1111/jcpp.12980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcpp.12980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6546608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30345511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haywood K.L., Staniszewska S., Chapman S. Quality and acceptability of patient-reported outcome measures used in chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis (CFS/ ME): A systematic review. Qual. Life Res. 2011;21:35&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1007/s11136-011-9921-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-011-9921-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21590511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiting P., Bagnall A.M., Sowden A.J., Cornell J.E., Mulrow C.D., Ram&#xed;rez G. Interventions for the Treatment and Management of Chronic Fatigue Syndrome&#x2014;A Systematic Review. JAMA. 2001;286:1360&#x2013;1368. doi: 10.1001/jama.286.11.1360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.286.11.1360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11560542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lilienfeld S.O., Ritschel L.A., Lynn S.J., Cautin R., Latzman R. Why ineffective psychotherapies appear to work: A taxonomy of causes of spurious therapeutic effectiveness. Perspect. Psychol. Sci. 2014;9:355&#x2013;387. doi: 10.1177/1745691614535216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1745691614535216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26173271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark L.V., Pesola F., Thomas J.M., Vergara-Williamson M., Beynon M., White P.D. Guided graded exercise self-help plus specialist medical care versus specialist medical care alone for chronic fatigue syndrome (GETSET): A pragmatic randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2017;390:363&#x2013;373. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(16)32589-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(16)32589-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5522576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28648402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess M., Chalder T. PACE Manual for Participants, Cognitive Behaviour Therapy for CFS/ME MREC Version 2 ISRCTN54285094 November 2004.  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/burgess-cbt-participant-manual.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark L.V., Tims E., White P.D. Getset Study Guided Graded Exercise Self-Help (GES) for CFS/ME Therapist Manual. Therapist Manual of the GETSET Trial. 2016.  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/getset-therapists-manual-with-appendices.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghatineh S., Vink M. FITNET&#x2019;s Internet-Based Cognitive Behavioural Therapy Is Ineffective and May Impede Natural Recovery in Adolescents with Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. A review. Behav. Sci. 2017;7:52. doi: 10.3390/bs7030052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bs7030052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5618060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28800089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surawy C., Hackmann A., Hawton K., Sharpe M. Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: A cognitive approach. Behav. Res. Ther. 1995;33:535&#x2013;544. doi: 10.1016/0005-7967(94)00077-W.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0005-7967(94)00077-W</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7598674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P., Cristea I.A. How to prove that your therapy is effective, even when it is not: A guideline. Epidemiol Psychiatr Sci. 2016;25:428&#x2013;435. doi: 10.1017/S2045796015000864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S2045796015000864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7137591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26411384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dragioti E., Dimoliatis I., Fountoulakis K.N., Evangelou E. Asystematic appraisal of allegiance effect in randomized controlled trials of psychotherapy. Ann Gen Psychiatry. 2015;14:25. doi: 10.1186/s12991-015-0063-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12991-015-0063-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4570291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26379758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luborsky L., Diguer L., Seligman D.A., Rosenthal R., Krause E.D., Johnson S., Halperin G., Bishop M., Berman J.S., Schweizer E. The Researcher&#x2019;s own therapy allegiances: A &#x2018;wild card&#x2019; in comparisons of treatment efficacy. Clin. Psychol. Sci. Pract. 1999;6:95&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luborsky L., Rosenthal R., Diguer L., Andrusyna T.P., Berman J.S., Levitt J.T., Seligman D.A., Krause E.D. The Dodo bird verdict is alive and well&#x2013;Mostly. Clin. Psychol. Sci. Pract. 2002;9:2&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munder T., Fl&#xfc;ckiger C., Gerger H., Wampold B.E., Barth J. Is the allegiance effect an epiphenomenon of true efficacy differences between treatments? A meta analysis. J. Couns. Psychol. J. Couns. Psychol. 2012;59:631&#x2013;637. doi: 10.1037/a0029571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0029571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22946981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilshire C. The problem of bias in behavioural intervention studies: Lessons from the PACE trial. J. Health Psychol. 2017;22:1128&#x2013;1133. doi: 10.1177/1359105317700885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1359105317700885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28805526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munder T., Br&#xfc;tsch O., Leonhart R. Researcher allegiance in psychotherapy outcome research: An overview of reviews. Clin. Psychol. Rev. 2013;33:501&#x2013;511. doi: 10.1016/j.cpr.2013.02.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpr.2013.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23500154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubet S. Investigator bias and the PACE trial. J. Health Psychol. 2017;22:1123&#x2013;1127. doi: 10.1177/1359105317697324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1359105317697324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28805514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PACE Trial Participants Newsletter. December 2008 Issue 3.  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2019/11/participantsnewsletter3.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharpe M.C., Archard L.C., Banatvala J.E., Borysiewicz L.K., Clare A.W., David A., Edwards R.H., Hawton K.E., Lambert H.P., Lane R.J., et al. A report--chronic fatigue syndrome: Guidelines for research. J. R. Soc. Med. 1991;84:118&#x2013;121. doi: 10.1177/014107689108400224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/014107689108400224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1293107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1999813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PACE Trial Protocol: Final Protocol Version 5.0. Feb 1, 2006.  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)].  ISRCTN54285094. Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/pace-finalprotocolversion5.0-01february2006.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K., Straus S.E., Hickie I., Sharpe M.C., Dobbins J.G., Komaroff A. The chronic fatigue syndrome: Acomprehensive approach to its definition and study. Ann. Intern. Med. 1994;121:953&#x2013;959. doi: 10.7326/0003-4819-121-12-199412150-00009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-121-12-199412150-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7978722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wearden A.J., Dowrick C., Chew-Graham C., Bentall R.P., Morriss R.K., Peters S., Riste L., Richardson G., Lovell K., Dunn G., et al. Nurse led, home based self help treatment for patients in primary care with chronic fatigue syndrome: Randomised controlled trial. BMJ. 2010;340:c1777. doi: 10.1136/bmj.c1777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.c1777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2859122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20418251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wearden A.J., Emsley R. Mediators of the effects on fatigue of pragmatic rehabilitation for chronic fatigue syndrome. J. Consult. Clin. Psychol. 2013;81:831&#x2013;838. doi: 10.1037/a0033561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0033561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23796316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tench C.M., McCarthy J., McCurdie I., White P.D., D&#x2019;Cruz D.P. Fatigue in systemic lupus erythematosus: A randomized controlled trial of exercise. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2003;42:1050&#x2013;1054. doi: 10.1093/rheumatology/keg289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/keg289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12730519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White P.D., Sharpe M., Chalder T., DeCesare J.C., Walwyn R. Pre-publication history Protocol for the PACE trial: A randomised controlled trial of adaptive pacing, cognitive behaviour therapy, and graded exercise as supplements to standardised specialist medical care versus standardised specialist medical care alone for patients with the chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis or encephalopathy. BMC Neurol. 2017;7:6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2147058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17397525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink M. The PACE trial authors continue to ignore their own null effect. J. Health Psychol. 2017;7:1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1177/1359105317703785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1359105317703785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28805519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans S. When and How Can Endpoints Be Changed after Initiation of a Randomized Clinical Trial? PLoS Clin. Trials. 2007;2:e18. doi: 10.1371/journal.pctr.0020018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pctr.0020018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1852589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17443237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepherd C.B. PACE trial claims for recovery in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome&#x2014;True or false? It&#x2019;s time for an independent review of the methodology and results. J. Health Psychol. 2017;22:1187&#x2013;1191. doi: 10.1177/1359105317703786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1359105317703786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28805522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicherts J.M., Bakker M., Molenaar D. Willingness to Share Research Data Is Related to the Strength of the Evidence and the Quality of Reporting of Statistical Results. PLoS ONE. 2011;6:e26828. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0026828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0026828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3206853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22073203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedom of Information Matthees 2015 Queen Mary University of London EA-2015-0269 (12-8-16)  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/freedom-of-information-matthees-2015-queen-mary-university-of-london-ea-2015-0269-12-8-16.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink M. Assessment of Individual the PACE trial Data: In Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/ Chronic Fatigue Syndrome, Cognitive Behavioral and Graded Exercise Therapy are Ineffective, Do Not Lead to Actual Recovery and Negative Outcomes may be Higher than Reported. J. Neurol Neurobiol. 2017;3:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrone P., Sharpe M., Chalder T., Knapp M., Johnson A.L., Goldsmith K.A., White P.D. Adaptive pacing, cognitive behaviour therapy, graded exercise, and specialist medical care for chronic fatigue syndrome: A cost-effectiveness analysis. PLoS ONE. 2012;7:e40808. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0040808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0040808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3411573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22870204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves W.C., Wagner D., Nisenbaum R., Jones J.F., Gurbaxani B., Solomon L., Papanicolaou D.A., Unger E.R., Vernon S.D., Heim C. Chronic fatigue syndrome--a clinically empirical approach to its definition and study. BMC Med. 2005;3:19. doi: 10.1186/1741-7015-3-19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1741-7015-3-19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1334212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16356178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White P.D., Goldsmith K., Johnson A.L., Chalder T., Sharpe M. Recovery from chronic fatigue syndrome after treatments given in the PACE trial. Psychol. Med. 2013;43:2227&#x2013;2235. doi: 10.1017/S0033291713000020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291713000020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3776285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23363640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stulemeijer M., de Jong L.W., Fiselier T.J., Hoogveld S.W., Bleijenberg G. Cognitive behaviour therapy for adolescents with chronic fatigue syndrome: Randomised controlled trial. BMJ. 2005;330:14. doi: 10.1136/bmj.38301.587106.63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.38301.587106.63</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC539840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15585538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson C. The Chalder Fatigue Scale (CFQ 11) Occup. Med. 2014;65:86. doi: 10.1093/occmed/kqu168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/occmed/kqu168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25559796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves W.C., Lloyd A., Vernon S.D., Klimas N., Jason L.A., Bleijenberg G., Evengard B., White P.D., Nisenbaum R., Unger E.R. International Chronic Fatigue Syndrome Study Group. Identification of ambiguities in the 1994 chronic fatigue syndrome research case definition and recommendations for resolution. BMC Health Serv. Res. 2003;3:25. doi: 10.1186/1472-6963-3-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6963-3-25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC317472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14702202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hvidberg M.F., Brinth L.S., Olesen A.V., Petersen K., Ehlers L. The healthrelated quality of life for patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) PLoS ONE. 2015;10:e0132421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4492975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26147503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olesen A.V., Oddershede L., Petersen K.D. Health-related quality of life in Denmark on a relative scale: Mini-catalogue of mean EQ-5D-3L index scores for 17 common chronic conditions. Nord. J. Health Econ. 2016;4:44&#x2013;56. doi: 10.5617/njhe.2413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5617/njhe.2413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas E.T., Heneghan C. Catalogue of bias: Selective outcome reporting bias. BMJ Evid. Based Med. 2022;27:370&#x2013;372. doi: 10.1136/bmjebm-2021-111845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjebm-2021-111845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35177482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink M., Vink-Niese F. Is It Useful to Question the Recovery Behaviour of Patients with ME/CFS or Long COVID? Healthcare. 2022;10:392. doi: 10.3390/healthcare10020392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare10020392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8872229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35207003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smakowski A., Adamson J., Turner T., Chalder T. Graded exercise therapy for patients with chronic fatigue syndrome in secondary care&#x2014;A benchmarking study. Disabil Rehabil. 2022;44:5878&#x2013;5886. doi: 10.1080/09638288.2021.1949049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638288.2021.1949049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34498994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heneghan C., Goldacre B., Mahtani K.R. Why clinical trial outcomes fail to translate into benefits for patients. Trials. 2017;18:122. doi: 10.1186/s13063-017-1870-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-017-1870-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5348914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28288676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink M., Vink-Niese A., Tyson S.F. Patients with CFS remain severely disabled after treatment with graded exercise therapy in a specialist clinic in the UK Response to Smakowski. Disabil Rehabil. 2022;20:1&#x2013;2. doi: 10.1080/09638288.2022.2048911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638288.2022.2048911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35306926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collin S.M., Crawley E. Specialist treatment of chronic fatigue syndrome/ME: A cohort study among adult patients in England. BMC Health Serv. Res. 2017;17:488. doi: 10.1186/s12913-017-2437-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-017-2437-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5513420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28709432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Berkel S., Brandon T., van Enst G.C. Reactivering van pati&#xeb;nten met chronische vermoeidheid middels &#x2018;graded exercise therapy&#x2019; met minimale directe begeleiding (2005&#x2013;2010) Sport Geneeskd. 2012;3:6&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>General Medical Council  First Do No Harm: Enhancing Patient Safety Teaching in Undergraduate Medical Education. 2021.  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)].  Available online:  https://www.gmc-uk.org/-/media/documents/First_do_no_harm_patient_safety_in_undergrad_education_FINAL.pdf_62483215.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downing N.S., Shah N.D., Aminawung J.A., Pease A.M., Zeitoun J.D., Krumholz H.M., Ross J.S. Postmarket Safety Events Among Novel Therapeutics Approved by the US Food and Drug Administration Between 2001 and 2010. JAMA. 2017;317:1854&#x2013;1863. doi: 10.1001/jama.2017.5150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2017.5150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5815036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28492899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bavinton J., Dyer N., White P.D. PACE Manual for Participants: Graded Exercise Therapy. 2004.  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/6-get-participant-manual.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FINE Trial Patient Booklet Version 9, 29/04/05.  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2019/11/fine-trial-patientpr-manual-ver9-apr05.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IQWiG Pressemitteilung Myalgische Enzephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: Vorbericht Ver&#xf6;ffentlicht 13.10.2022.  [(accessed on 30 December 2022)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2022/12/iqwig-myalgische-enzephalomyelitischronic-fatigue-syndrome-vorbericht-veroffentlicht.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kindlon T. Reporting of Harms Associated with Graded Exercise Therapy and Cognitive Behavioural Therapy in Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome.  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)];Bull. IACFS/ME. 2011 19:59&#x2013;111. Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/kindlon-reporting-of-harms-associated-with-get-and-cbt-in-me-cfs.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geraghty K., Hann M., Kurtev S. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients&#x2019; reports of symptom changes following cognitive behavioural therapy, graded exercise therapy and pacing treatments: Analysis of a primary survey compared with secondary surveys. J. Health Psychol. 2019;24:1318&#x2013;1333. doi: 10.1177/1359105317726152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1359105317726152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28847166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxford Clinical Allied Technology and Trials Services Unit (OxCATTS), Oxford Brookes University  Evaluation of a Survey Exploring the Experiences of Adults and Children with ME/CFS Who have Participated in CBT and GET Interventional Programmes FINAL REPORT. Feb 27, 2019.  [(accessed on 23 November 2022)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2019/11/nice-patient-survey-outcomes-cbt-and-get-oxford-brookes-full-report-03.04.19.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black C.D., McCully K.K. Time course of exercise induced alterations in daily activity in chronic fatigue syndrome. Dyn Med. 2005;4:10. doi: 10.1186/1476-5918-4-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1476-5918-4-10</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1280928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16255779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lien K., Johansen B., Veier&#xf8;d M.B., Haslestad A.S., B&#xf8;hn S.K., Melsom M.N., Kardel K.R., Iversen P.O. Abnormal blood lactate accumulation during repeated exercise testing in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Physiol. Rep. 2019;7:e14138. doi: 10.14814/phy2.14138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.14138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6546966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31161646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kujawski S., Cossington J., S&#x142;omko J., Zawadka-Kunikowska M., Tafil-Klawe M., Klawe J.J., Buszko K., Jakovljevic D.G., Kozakiewicz M., Morten K.J., et al. On Behalf Of The European Network On Me/Cfs Euromene. Relationship between Cardiopulmonary, Mitochondrial and Autonomic Nervous System Function Improvement after an Individualised Activity Programme upon Chronic Fatigue Syndrome Patients. J. Clin. Med. 2021;10:1542. doi: 10.3390/jcm10071542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm10071542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8038762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul L., Wood L., Behan W.M., Maclaren W.M. Demonstration of delayed recovery from fatiguing exercise in chronic fatigue syndrome. Eur. J. Neurol. 1999;6:63&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1046/j.1468-1331.1999.610063.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1468-1331.1999.610063.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10209352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;kel B., Kedor C., Grabowski P., Wittke K., Thiel S., Scherbakov N., Doehner W., Scheibenbogen C., Freitag H. Hand grip strength and fatigability: Correlation with clinical parameters and diagnostic suitability in ME/CFS. J. Transl. Med. 2021;19:159. doi: 10.1186/s12967-021-02774-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-021-02774-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33874961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens S., Snell C., Stevens J., Keller B., VanNess J.M. Cardiopulmonary Exercise Test Methodology for Assessing Exertion Intolerance in Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Front. Pediatr. 2018;6:242. doi: 10.3389/fped.2018.00242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2018.00242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6131594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30234078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanNess J.M., Stevens S.R., Bateman L., Stiles T.L., Snell C.R. Postexertional malaise in women with chronic fatigue syndrome. J. Womens Health. 2010;19:239&#x2013;244. doi: 10.1089/jwh.2009.1507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jwh.2009.1507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20095909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Light A.R., White A.T., Hughen R.W., Light K.C. Moderate Exercise Increases Expression for Sensory, Adrenergic, and Immune Genes in Chronic Fatigue Syndrome Patients but Not in Normal Subjects. J. Pain. 2009;10:1099&#x2013;1112. doi: 10.1016/j.jpain.2009.06.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpain.2009.06.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2757484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19647494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Light A.R., Bateman L., Jo D., Hughen R.W., VanHaitsma T.A., White A.T., Light K.C. Gene expression alterations at baseline and following moderate exercise in patients with Chronic Fatigue Syndrome and Fibromyalgia Syndrome. J. Intern. Med. 2011;271:64&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2796.2011.02405.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2796.2011.02405.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3175315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21615807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snell C.R., Stevens S.R., Davenport T.E., Van Ness J.M. Discriminative validity of metabolic and workload measurements for identifying people with chronic fatigue syndrome. Phys. Ther. 2013;93:14841492. doi: 10.2522/ptj.20110368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20110368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23813081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeulen R.C., Vermeulen van Eck I.W. Decreased oxygen extraction during cardiopulmonary exercise test in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. J. Transl. Med. 2014;12:46. doi: 10.1186/1479-5876-12-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1479-5876-12-20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3903040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24456560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White A.T., Light A.R., Hughen R.W., Bateman L., Martins T.B., Hill H.R., Light K.C. Severity of symptom flare after moderate exercise is linked to cytokine activity in chronic fatigue syndrome. Psychophysiology. 2010;47:615&#x2013;624. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-8986.2010.00978.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8986.2010.00978.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4378647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20230500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenport T.E., Stevens S.R., Baroni K., Van Ness J.M., Snell C.R. Diagnostic accuracy of symptoms characterising chronic fatigue syndrome. Disabil. Rehabil. 2011;33:1768&#x2013;1775. doi: 10.3109/09638288.2010.546936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/09638288.2010.546936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21208154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez M., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Sol&#xe0; J., Nu&#xf1;ez E., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Huerta J.M., God&#xe1;s-Sieso T., Gomez-Gil E. Health-related quality of life in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome: Group cognitive behavioural therapy and graded exercise versus usual treatment. A randomised controlled trial with 1 year of follow-up. Clin. Rheumatol. 2011;30:381&#x2013;389. doi: 10.1007/s10067-010-1677-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10067-010-1677-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21234629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohl M. Stellungnahme zum Vorbericht Berichtnr: N21-01 Titel: Aktueller Wissenschaftlicher Erkenntnisstand zu Myalgischer Enzephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrom (ME/CFS) Nov, 2022.  [(accessed on 30 December 2022)].  Available online:  https://huisartsvink.files.wordpress.com/2022/12/stellungnahme-prof.-kohl.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M., Smith G.D., Sterne J.A. Uses and abuses of meta-analysis. Clin. Med. 2001;1:478&#x2013;484. doi: 10.7861/clinmedicine.1-6-478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7861/clinmedicine.1-6-478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4953876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11792089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>