<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36352492</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1477-1128</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Primary health care research &amp; development</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Prim Health Care Res Dev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19 disease severity to predict persistent symptoms: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e69</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e69</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e69</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1017/S1463423622000585</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">It is unclear, whether the initial disease severity may help to predict which COVID-19 patients at risk of developing persistent symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM">The aim of this study was to examine whether the initial disease severity affects the risk of persistent symptoms in post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A systematic search was conducted using PUBMED, Google Scholar, EMBASE, and ProQuest databases to identify eligible articles published after January 2020 up to and including 30 August 2021. Pooled odds ratio (OR) and confidence intervals (CIs) were calculated using random effects meta-analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS">After searching a total of 7733 articles, 20 relevant observational studies with a total of 7840 patients were selected for meta-analysis. The pooled OR for persistent dyspnea in COVID-19 survivors with a severe versus nonsevere initial disease was 2.17 [95%CI 1.62 to 2.90], and it was 1.33 [95%CI 0.75 to 2.33] for persistent cough, 1.30 [95%CI 1.06 to 1.58] for persistent fatigue, 1.02 [95%CI 0.73 to 1.40] for persistent anosmia, 1.22 [95%CI 0.69 to 2.16] for persistent chest pain, and 1.30 [95%CI 0.93 to 1.81] for persistent palpitation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Contrary to expectations, we did not observe an association between the initial COVID-19 disease severity and common persistent symptoms except for dyspnea and fatigue. In addition, it was found that being in the acute or prolonged post-COVID phase did not affect the risk of symptoms. Primary care providers should be alert to potential most prevalent persistent symptoms in all COVID-19 survivors, which are not limited to patients with critical-severe initial disease.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dirican</LastName><ForeName>Emre</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3550-1326</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Department of Biostatistics, Hatay Mustafa Kemal University, Hatay, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bal</LastName><ForeName>Tayibe</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5315-122X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Department of Infectious Diseases and Clinical Microbiology, Hatay Mustafa Kemal University, Hatay, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Prim Health Care Res Dev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100897390</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1463-4236</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004417" MajorTopicYN="N">Dyspnea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disease severity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">persistent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">symptoms</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36352492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9706304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1463423622000585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1463423622000585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahmed H, Patel K, Greenwood DC, Halpin S, Lewthwaite P, Salawu A, Eyre L, Breen A, O&#x2019;connor R, Jones A and Sivan M (2020) Long-term clinical outcomes in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus outbreaks after hospitalisation or ICU admission: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Rehabilitation Medicine 52, jrm00063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32449782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera Martimbianco AL, Pacheco RL, Bagattini &#xc2; M and Riera R (2021) Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID-19: a systematic review. International Journal of Clinical Practice 75, e14357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8236920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33977626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cares-Marambio K, Montenegro-Jim&#xe9;nez Y, Torres-Castro R, Vera-Uribe R, Torralba Y, Alsina-Restoy X, Vasconcello-Castillo L and Vilar&#xf3; J (2021) Prevalence of potential respiratory symptoms in survivors of hospital admission after coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Chronic Respiratory Disease 18. doi: 10.1177/14799731211002240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/14799731211002240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7975482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33729021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Graaf MA, Antoni ML, Ter Kuile MM, Arbous MS, Duinisveld AJF, Feltkamp MCW, Groeneveld GH, Hinnen SCH, Janssen VR, Lijfering WM, Omara S, Postmus PE, Ramai SRS, Rius-Ottenheim N, Schalij MJ, Schiemanck SK, Smid L, St&#xf6;ger JL, Visser LG, De Vries JJC, Wijngaarden MA, Geelhoed JJM and Roukens AHE (2021) Short-term outpatient follow-up of COVID-19 patients: a multidisciplinary approach. EClinicalMedicine 32, 100731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7843037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33532720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lorenzo R, Conte C, Lanzani C, Benedetti F, Roveri L, Mazza MG, Brioni E, Giacalone G, Canti V, Sofia V, D&#x2019;amico M, Di Napoli D, Ambrosio A, Scarpellini P, Castagna A, Landoni G, Zangrillo A, Bosi E, Tresoldi M, Ciceri F and Rovere-Querini P (2020) Residual clinical damage after COVID-19: a retrospective and prospective observational cohort study. PLoS One 15, e0239570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7556454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33052920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Valle DM, Kim-Schulze S, Huang HH, Beckmann ND, Nirenberg S, Wang B, Lavin Y, Swartz TH, Madduri D, Stock A, Marron TU, Xie H, Patel M, Tuballes K, Van Oekelen O, Rahman A, Kovatch P, Aberg JA, Schadt E, Jagannath S, Mazumdar M, Charney AW, Firpo-Betancourt A, Mendu DR, Jhang J, Reich D, Sigel K, Cordon-Cardo C, Feldmann M, Parekh S, Merad M and Gnjatic S (2020) An inflammatory cytokine signature predicts COVID-19 severity and survival. Nature Medicine 26, 1636&#x2013;1643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7869028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32839624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-De-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Guijarro C, Plaza-Canteli S, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Barrera V and Torres-Macho J (2021) Prevalence of post-COVID-19 cough one year after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a multicenter study. Lung 199, 249&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8124095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33993321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ga Wells BS, O&#x2019;connell D, Peterson J, Welch V, Losos M and Tugwell P (2021) The Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) for assessing the quality of nonrandomised studies in meta-analyses [Online]. Retrieved 17 September 2021 from http://www.ohri.ca/programs/clinical_epidemiology/oxford.asp
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues E, Janvier P, Kherabi Y, Le Bot A, Hamon A, Gouze H, Doucet L, Berkani S, Oliosi E, Mallart E, Corre F, Zarrouk V, Moyer JD, Galy A, Honsel V, Fantin B and Nguyen Y (2020) Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. Journal of Infection 81, e4&#x2013;e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, Mcivor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, Mclean L, Walshaw C, Kemp S, Corrado J, Singh R, Collins T, O&#x2019;connor RJ and Sivan M (2021) Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. Journal of Medical Virology 93, 1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoy D, Brooks P, Woolf A, Blyth F, March L, Bain C, Baker P, Smith E and Buchbinder R (2012) Assessing risk of bias in prevalence studies: modification of an existing tool and evidence of interrater agreement. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology 65, 934&#x2013;939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22742910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, Kang L, Guo L, Liu M, Zhou X, Luo J, Huang Z, Tu S, Zhao Y, Chen L, Xu D, Li Y, Li C, Peng L, Li Y, Xie W, Cui D, Shang L, Fan G, Xu J, Wang G, Wang Y, Zhong J, Wang C, Wang J, Zhang D and Cao B (2021. a) 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet 397, 220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, Wang Q, Ren L, Wang Y, Hu P, Guo L, Liu M, Xu J, Zhang X, Qu Y, Fan Y, Li X, Li C, Yu T, Xia J, Wei M, Chen L, Li Y, Xiao F, Liu D, Wang J, Wang X and Cao B (2021. b) 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet 398, 747&#x2013;758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal A, Iqbal K, Arshad Ali S, Azim D, Farid E, Baig MD, Bin Arif T and Raza M (2021) The COVID-19 sequelae: a cross-sectional evaluation of post-recovery symptoms and the need for rehabilitation of COVID-19 survivors. Cureus 13, e13080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7932827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33680620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson KB, Rao M, Bonilla H, Subramanian A, Hack I, Madrigal M, Singh U, Jagannathan P and Grant P (2021) Patients with uncomplicated Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) have long-term persistent symptoms and functional impairment similar to patients with severe COVID-19: a cautionary tale during a global pandemic. Clinical Infectious Diseases 73, e826&#x2013;e829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33624010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal M, Abo Omirah M, Hussein A and Saeed H (2021) Assessment and characterisation of post-COVID-19 manifestations. International Journal of Clinical Practice 75, e13746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JY, Bae JY, Bae S, Cha HH, Kwon JS, Suh MH, Lee HJ, Jung J, Kim MJ, Cui C, Park H, Lee J, Park MS and Kim SH (2021) Diagnostic usefulness of subgenomic RNA detection of viable SARS-CoV-2 in patients with COVID-19. Clinical Microbiology and Infection 28, 101&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8360988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34400343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechien JR, Chiesa-Estomba CM, Beckers E, Mustin V, Ducarme M, Journe F, Marchant A, Jouffe L, Barillari MR, Cammaroto G, Circiu MP, Hans S and Saussez S (2021) Prevalence and 6-month recovery of olfactory dysfunction: a multicentre study of 1363 COVID-19 patients. Journal of Internal Medicine 290, 451&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33403772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerum TV, Aal&#xf8;kken TM, Br&#xf8;nstad E, Aarli B, Ikdahl E, Lund KMA, Durheim MT, Rodriguez JR, Meltzer C, Tonby K, Stavem K, Skj&#xf8;nsberg OH, Ashraf H and Einvik G (2021) Dyspnoea, lung function and CT findings 3-months after hospital admission for COVID-19. European Respiratory Journal 57, 1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardo MDM, Foppiani A, Peretti GM, Mangiavini L, Battezzati A, Bertoli S, Martinelli Boneschi F and Zuccotti GV (2021) Long-term Coronavirus disease 2019 complications in inpatients and outpatients: a one-year follow-up cohort study. Open Forum Infectious Diseases 8, ofab384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8344801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34386546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestre-Mu&#xf1;iz MM, Arias &#xc1;, Mata-V&#xe1;zquez E, Mart&#xed;n-Toledano M, L&#xf3;pez-Larramona G, Ruiz-Chicote AM, Nieto-Sandoval B and Lucendo AJ (2021) Long-term outcomes of patients with Coronavirus disease 2019 at one year after hospital discharge. Journal of Clinical Medicine 10, 1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8269002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34209085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltezou HC, Pavli A and Tsakris A (2021) Post-COVID syndrome: an insight on its pathogenesis. Vaccines (Basel) 9, 1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8151752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34066007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meije Y, Duarte-Borges A, Sanz X, Clemente M, Ribera A, Ortega L, Gonz&#xe1;lez-P&#xe9;rez R, Cid R, Pareja J, Cantero I, Ari&#xf1;o M, Sagu&#xe9;s T, LLaberia J, Ayestar&#xe1;n A, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Hidalgo N and Cand&#xe1;s-Est&#xe9;banez B (2021) Long-term outcomes of patients following hospitalization for coronavirus disease 2019: a prospective observational study. Clinical Microbiology and Infection 27, 1151&#x2013;1157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8062910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33901667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menges D, Ballouz T, Anagnostopoulos A, Aschmann HE, Domenghino A, Fehr JS and Puhan MA (2021) Burden of post-COVID-19 syndrome and implications for healthcare service planning: a population-based cohort study. PLoS One 16, e0254523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8274847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34252157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J and Altman DG (2009) Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Med 6, e1000097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin L, Savale L, Pham T, Colle R, Figueiredo S, Harrois A, Gasnier M, Lecoq AL, Meyrignac O, Noel N, Baudry E, Bellin MF, Beurnier A, Choucha W, Corruble E, Dortet L, Hardy-Leger I, Radiguer F, Sportouch S, Verny C, Wyplosz B, Zaidan M, Becquemont L, Montani D and Monnet X (2021) Four-month clinical status of a cohort of patients after hospitalization for COVID-19. JAMA 325, 1525&#x2013;1534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7970386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33729425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, Mcgroder C, Stevens JS, Cook JR, Nordvig AS, Shalev D, Sehrawat TS, Ahluwalia N, Bikdeli B, Dietz D, Der-Nigoghossian C, Liyanage-Don N, Rosner GF, Bernstein EJ, Mohan S, Beckley AA, Seres DS, Choueiri TK, Uriel N, Ausiello JC, Accili D, Freedberg DE, Baldwin M, Schwartz A, Brodie D, Garcia CK, Elkind MSV, Connors JM, Bilezikian JP, Landry DW and Wan EY (2021) Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nature Medicine 27, 601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortelli P, Ferrazzoli D, Sebastianelli L, Engl M, Romanello R, Nardone R, Bonini I, Koch G, Saltuari L, Quartarone A, Oliviero A, Kofler M and Versace V (2021) Neuropsychological and neurophysiological correlates of fatigue in post-acute patients with neurological manifestations of COVID-19: insights into a challenging symptom. Journal of the Neurological Sciences 420, 117271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntmann VO, Carerj ML, Wieters I, Fahim M, Arendt C, Hoffmann J, Shchendrygina A, Escher F, Vasa-Nicotera M, Zeiher AM, Vehreschild M and Nagel E (2020) Outcomes of cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in patients recently recovered from Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiology 5, 1265&#x2013;1273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin W, Chen S, Zhang Y, Dong F, Zhang Z, Hu B, Zhu Z, Li F, Wang X, Wang Y, Zhen K, Wang J, Wan Y, Li H, Elalamy I, Li C, Zhai Z and Wang C (2021) Diffusion capacity abnormalities for carbon monoxide in patients with COVID-19 at 3-month follow-up. European Respiratory Journal 58, 1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7877322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33574077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossman H, Shilo S, Meir T, Gorfine M, Shalit U and Segal E (2021) COVID-19 dynamics after a national immunization program in Israel. Nature Medicine 27, 1055&#x2013;1061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33875890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saccheri C, Morawiec E, Delemazure J, Mayaux J, Dub&#xe9; BP, Similowski T, Demoule A and Dres M (2020) ICU-acquired weakness, diaphragm dysfunction and long-term outcomes of critically ill patients. Annals of Intensive Care 10, 1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6942110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31900667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Ramirez DC, Normand K, Zhaoyun Y and Torres-Castro R (2021) Long-term impact of COVID-19: a systematic review of the literature and meta-analysis. Biomedicines 9, 1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34440104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shendy W, Ezzat MM, Elaidy DA and Abdelaziz A (2021) Prevalence of fatigue in patients post Covid. European Journal of Molecular &amp; Clinical Medicine 8, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song WJ, Hui CKM, Hull JH, Birring SS, Mcgarvey L, Mazzone SB and Chung KF (2021) Confronting COVID-19-associated cough and the post-COVID syndrome: role of viral neurotropism, neuroinflammation, and neuroimmune responses. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine 9, 533&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8041436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33857435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH and Crooks MG (2021) Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung 199, 113&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dowds J, O&#x2019;brien K, Sheill G, Dyer AH, O&#x2019;kelly B, Hynes JP, Mooney A, Dunne J, Ni Cheallaigh C, O&#x2019;farrelly C, Bourke NM, Conlon N, Martin-Loeches I, Bergin C, Nadarajan P and Bannan C (2021) Persistent poor health after COVID-19 is not associated with respiratory complications or initial disease severity. Annals of the American Thoracic Society 18, 997&#x2013;1003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8456724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanhorebeek I, Latronico N and Van Den Berghe G (2020) ICU-acquired weakness. Intensive Care Medicine 46, 637&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7224132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32076765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voruz P, Allali G, Benzakour L, Nuber-Champier A, Thomasson M, Jacot I, Pierce J, Lalive P, Lovblad K-O and Brallaird O (2021) Long COVID neuropsychological deficits after severe, moderate or mild infection. Clinical and Translational Neuroscience 6, 1&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Xu H, Jiang H, Wang L, Lu C, Wei X, Liu J and Xu S (2020) Clinical features and outcomes of discharged coronavirus disease 2019 patients: a prospective cohort study. QJM 113, 657&#x2013;665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7313792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
WHO (2020) Clinical management of COVID-19: interim guidance, 27 May 2020: World Health Organization. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-clinical-2021-2
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
WHO (2021) Coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard. Retrieved September 2021 from https://covid19.who.int/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie F, You Y, Huang J, Guan C, Chen Z, Fang M, Yao F and Han J (2021) Association between physical activity and digestive-system cancer: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Sport and Health Science 10, 4&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7856558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33010525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zayet S, Zahra H, Royer PY, Tipirdamaz C, Mercier J, Gendrin V, Lepiller Q, Marty-Quinternet S, Osman M, Belfeki N, Toko L, Garnier P, Pierron A, Plantin J, Messin L, Villemain M, Bouiller K and Klopfenstein T (2021) Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: nine months after SARS-CoV-2 infection in a cohort of 354 patients: data from the First Wave of COVID-19 in Nord Franche-Comt&#xe9; Hospital, France. Microorganisms 9, 1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8401026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34442798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>