<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37199425</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1534-7796</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>85</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2023 Jul-Aug 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Psychosomatic medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Psychosom Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Psychological Resilience to Trauma and Risk of COVID-19 Infection and Somatic Symptoms Across 2 Years.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>488</StartPage><EndPage>497</EndPage><MedlinePgn>488-497</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PSY.0000000000001215</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Exposure to trauma increases the risk of somatic symptoms, as well as acute and chronic physical diseases. However, many individuals display psychological resilience, showing positive psychological adaptation despite trauma exposure. Resilience to prior trauma may be a protective factor for physical health during subsequent stressors, including the COVID-19 pandemic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Using data from 528 US adults in a longitudinal cohort study, we examined psychological resilience to lifetime potentially traumatic events early in the pandemic and the risk of COVID-19 infection and somatic symptoms across 2 years of follow-up. Resilience was defined as level of psychological functioning relative to lifetime trauma burden, assessed in August 2020. Outcomes included COVID-19 infection and symptom severity, long COVID, and somatic symptoms assessed every 6 months for 24 months. Using regression models, we examined associations between resilience and each outcome adjusting for covariates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Higher psychological resilience to trauma was associated with a lower likelihood of COVID-19 infection over time, with one standard deviation higher resilience score associated with a 31% lower likelihood of COVID-19 infection, adjusting for sociodemographics and vaccination status. Furthermore, higher resilience was associated with lower levels of somatic symptoms during the pandemic, adjusting for COVID-19 infection and long COVID status. In contrast, resilience was not associated with COVID-19 disease severity or long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Psychological resilience to prior trauma is associated with lower risk of COVID-19 infection and lower somatic symptoms during the pandemic. Promoting psychological resilience to trauma may benefit not only mental but also physical health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by the American Psychosomatic Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishimi</LastName><ForeName>Kristen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6189-830</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Mental Health Service (Nishimi, Tan, Kelley, Neylan, O'Donovan), San Francisco Veterans Affairs Health Care System; Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences (Nishimi, Tan, Kelley, Neylan, O'Donovan), University of California San Francisco, San Francisco, California; Department of Natural and Applied Sciences (Scoglio), Bentley University, Waltham; Department of Epidemiology (Scoglio), Harvard TH Chan School of Public Health, Boston, Massashusetts; and Center for Precision Psychiatry, Department of Psychiatry (Choi) and Psychiatric and Neurodevelopment Genetics Unit (Choi), Center for Genomic Medicine, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massashusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Jeri</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scoglio</LastName><ForeName>Arielle</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3680-9405</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Karmel W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kelley</LastName><ForeName>Dennis Parker</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8492-2704</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neylan</LastName><ForeName>Thomas C</ForeName><Initials>TC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1572-2626</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Donovan</LastName><ForeName>Aoife</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2353-7217</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>IK2 CX002627</GrantID><Acronym>CX</Acronym><Agency>CSRD VA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K01 MH109871</GrantID><Acronym>MH</Acronym><Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Psychosom Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0376505</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0033-3174</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055500" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resilience, Psychological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071896" MajorTopicYN="Y">Medically Unexplained Symptoms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37199425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1894931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10524129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PSY.0000000000001215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006842-990000000-00125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Breslau N Epidemiologic studies of trauma, posttraumatic stress disorder, and other psychiatric disorders. Can J Psychiatry. 2002. Dec 1;47(10):923&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12553127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afari N, Ahumada SM, Wright LJ, Mostoufi S, Golnari G, Reis V, et al. Psychological trauma and functional somatic syndromes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychosom Med. 2014. Jan;76(1):2&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3894419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24336429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnurr PP, Green BL. Understanding relationships among trauma, posttraumatic stress disorder, and health outcomes. Adv Mind Body Med. 2004;20(1):18&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15068106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEwen BS, Gray J, Nasca C. Recognizing Resilience: Learning from the Effects of Stress on the Brain. Neurobiol Stress. 2015. Jan 1;1:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4260341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25506601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galatzer-Levy IR, Huang SH, Bonanno GA. Trajectories of resilience and dysfunction following potential trauma: A review and statistical evaluation. Clin Psychol Rev. 2018. Jul;63:41&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29902711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimi K, Neylan TC, Bertenthal D, Seal KH, O&#x2019;Donovan A. Association of Psychiatric Disorders With Incidence of SARS-CoV-2 Breakthrough Infection Among Vaccinated Adults. JAMA Netw Open. 2022. Apr 14;5(4):e227287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9011123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35420660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donovan A, Cohen BE, Seal KH, Bertenthal D, Margaretten M, Nishimi K, et al. Elevated risk for autoimmune disorders in iraq and afghanistan veterans with posttraumatic stress disorder. Biol Psychiatry. 2015. Feb 15;77(4):365&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4277929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25104173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumner JA, Kubzansky LD, Elkind MS, Roberts AL, Agnew-Blais J, Chen Q, et al. Trauma Exposure and Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Symptoms Predict Onset of Cardiovascular Events in Women. Circulation. 2015. Jul 28;132(4):251&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4519406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26124186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luthar SS, Cicchetti D, Becker B. The construct of resilience: a critical evaluation and guidelines for future work. Child Dev. 2000. Jun;71(3):543&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1885202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10953923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimi K, Koenen KC, Coull BA, Chen R, Kubzansky LD. Psychological resilience predicting cardiometabolic conditions in adulthood in the Midlife in the United States Study. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2021. Aug 10;118(32):e2102619118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8364125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34341103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Janicki-Deverts D, Doyle WJ, Miller GE, Frank E, Rabin BS, et al. Chronic stress, glucocorticoid receptor resistance, inflammation, and disease risk. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2012;109(16):5995&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3341031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22474371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozlowska K Stress, Distress, and Bodytalk: Co-constructing Formulations with Patients Who Present with Somatic Symptoms. Harv Rev Psychiatry. 2013. Dec;21(6):314&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24201822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi KW, Stein MB, Dunn EC, Koenen KC, Smoller JW. Genomics and psychological resilience: a research agenda. Mol Psychiatry. 2019. Dec;24(12):1770&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6874722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31341239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher D, Sarkar M. Psychological resilience: a review and critique of definitions, concepts, and theory. Eur Psychol. 2013;18(1):12&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimi K, Choi KW, Cerutti J, Powers A, Bradley B, Dunn EC. Measures of adult psychological resilience following early-life adversity: how congruent are different measures? Psychol Med. 2021. Nov 1;51(15):2637&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7863576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32406816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheerin CM, Stratton KJ, Amstadter AB, Education Clinical Center Mirecc Workgroup T, McDonald SD. Exploring resilience models in a sample of combat-exposed military service members and veterans: a comparison and commentary. Eur J Psychotraumatol. 2018;9(1):1486121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6032017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29988781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonanno GA, Romero SA, Klein SI. The temporal elements of psychological resilience: An integrative framework for the study of individuals, families, and communities. Psychol Inq. 2015;26(2):139&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantzer R, Cohen S, Russo SJ, Dinan TG. Resilience and immunity. Brain Behav Immun. 2018. Nov;74:28&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6545920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30102966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiecolt-Glaser JK, Bennett JM, Derry HM, Gillie BL, Fagundes CP. Resilience and Immune Function in Older Adults. Annu Rev Gerontol Geriatr. 2012. Feb 1;32(1):29&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Tyrrell DAJ, Smith AP. Psychological Stress and Susceptibility to the Common Cold. N Engl J Med. 1991. Aug 29;325(9):606&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1713648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang T, Farkas DK, Ahern TP, Lash TL, S&#xf8;rensen HT, Gradus JL. Posttraumatic stress disorder and incident infections: a nationwide cohort study. Epidemiology. 2019;30(6):911&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6779341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31584893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Quan L, Chavarro JE, Slopen N, Kubzansky LD, Koenen KC, et al. Associations of Depression, Anxiety, Worry, Perceived Stress, and Loneliness Prior to Infection With Risk of Post&#x2013;COVID-19 Conditions. JAMA Psychiatry. 2022. Sep 7;79(11):1081&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9453634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36069885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimi K, Neylan TC, Bertenthal D, Dolsen EA, Seal KH, O&#x2019;Donovan A. Post-traumatic stress disorder and risk for hospitalization and death following COVID-19 infection. Transl Psychiatry. 2022. Nov 22;12(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9678873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36411283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Pressman SD. Positive Affect and Health. Curr Dir Psychol Sci. 2016. Jun 22;15(3):122&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiecolt-Glaser JK, Glaser R, Gravenstein S, Malarkey WB, Sheridan J. Chronic stress alters the immune response to influenza virus vaccine in older adults. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 1996. Apr 2;93(7):3043&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC39758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8610165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Janicki-Deverts D, Turner RB, Doyle WJ. Does Hugging Provide Stress-Buffering Social Support? A Study of Susceptibility to Upper Respiratory Infection and Illness. Psychol Sci. 2015. Feb 1;26(2):135&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4323947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25526910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambr&#xe9;e O, Ruland C, Scheu S, Arolt V, Alferink J. Alterations of the Innate Immune System in Susceptibility and Resilience After Social Defeat Stress. Front Behav Neurosci. 2018;12:141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6053497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30057531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gururajan A, van de Wouw M, Boehme M, Becker T, O&#x2019;Connor R, Bastiaanssen TFS, et al. Resilience to chronic stress is associated with specific neurobiological, neuroendocrine and immune responses. Brain Behav Immun. 2019. Aug 1;80:583&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31059807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimi K, Koenen KC, Coull BA, Kubzansky LD. Association of psychological resilience with healthy lifestyle and body weight in young adulthood. J Adolesc Health Off Publ Soc Adolesc Med. 2022. Feb;70(2):258&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8792157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34521575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervera-Torres S, Ruiz-Fern&#xe1;ndez S, Godbersen H, Mass&#xf3; L, Mart&#xed;nez-Rubio D, Pintado-Cucarella S, et al. Influence of Resilience and Optimism on Distress and Intention to Self-Isolate: Contrasting Lower and Higher COVID-19 Illness Risk Samples From an Extended Health Belief Model. Front Psychol. 2021;12:662395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8180876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34108919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Schrojenstein Lantman M, Mackus M, Otten LS, de Kruijff D, van de Loo AJ, Kraneveld AD, et al. Mental resilience, perceived immune functioning, and health. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2017. Mar 21;10:107&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5367578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28356753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta MA. Review of somatic symptoms in post-traumatic stress disorder. Int Rev Psychiatry. 2013. Feb 1;25(1):86&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23383670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beutel ME, Tibubos AN, Klein EM, Schmutzer G, Reiner I, Kocalevent RD, et al. Childhood adversities and distress - The role of resilience in a representative sample. PloS One. 2017;12(3):e0173826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5351992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28296938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullerton DJ, Zhang LM, Kleitman S. An integrative process model of resilience in an academic context: Resilience resources, coping strategies, and positive adaptation. PLOS ONE. 2021. Feb 2;16(2):e0246000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7853478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33529232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feder A, Nestler EJ, Charney DS. Psychobiology and molecular genetics of resilience. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2009. Jun;10(6):446&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2833107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19455174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osofsky HJ, Weems CF, Graham RA, Osofsky JD, Hansel TC, King LS. Perceptions of resilience and physical health symptom improvement following post disaster integrated health services. Disaster Med Public Health Prep. 2019. Apr;13(2):223&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29916794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith B, Shatt&#xe9; A, Perlman A, Siers M, Lynch WD. Improvements in resilience, stress, and somatic symptoms following online resilience training: A dose&#x2013;response effect. J Occup Environ Med. 2018. Jan;60(1):1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5770111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28820863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye B, Zhou X, Im H, Liu M, Wang XQ, Yang Q. Epidemic rumination and resilience on college students&#x2019; depressive symptoms during the COVID-19 pandemic: The mediating role of fatigue. Front Public Health. 2020;8:560983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33363075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Santo T, Sun Y, Wu Y, He C, Wang Y, Jiang X, et al. Systematic review of mental health symptom changes by sex or gender in early-COVID-19 compared to pre-pandemic. Sci Rep. 2022. Jul 6;12(1):11417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9258011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35794116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi KW, Nishimi K, Jha SC, Sampson L, Hahn J, Kang JH, et al. Pre-pandemic resilience to trauma and mental health outcomes during COVID-19. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2022. Sep 28;1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9514982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36169684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niles AN, Woolley JD, Tripp P, Pesquita A, Vinogradov S, Neylan TC, et al. Randomized controlled trial testing mobile-based attention-bias modification for posttraumatic stress using personalized word stimuli. Clin Psychol Sci. 2020;8(4):756&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8373050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34414018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimi K, Borsari B, Marx BP, Tripp P, Woodward E, Rosen RC, et al. Posttraumatic stress disorder symptoms associated with protective and risky behaviors for coronavirus disease 2019. Health Psychol. 2022. Feb;41(2):104&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8932400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35238581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolsen EA, Nishimi K, LeWinn KZ, Byers AL, Tripp P, Woodward E, et al. Identifying correlates of suicide ideation during the COVID-19 pandemic: A cross-sectional analysis of 148 sociodemographic and pandemic-specific factors. J Psychiatr Res. 2022. Dec 1;156:186&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9553642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36252348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson EB, Smith SR, Palmieri PA, Dalenberg C, Ruzek JI, Kimerling R, et al. Development and validation of a brief self-report measure of trauma exposure: the Trauma History Screen. Psychol Assess. 2011. Jun;23(2):463&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3115408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21517189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weathers FW, Litz BT, Keane TM, Palmieri PA, Marx BP, Schnurr PP. The PTSD Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5). Scale Available Natl Cent PTSD Wwwptsdvagov. 2013;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antony MM, Bieling PJ, Cox BJ, Enns MW, Swinson RP. Psychometric properties of the 42-item and 21-item versions of the Depression Anxiety Stress Scales in clinical groups and a community sample. Psychol Assess. 1998;10(2):176&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaishnavi S, Connor K, Davidson JR. An abbreviated version of the Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC), the CD-RISC2: psychometric properties and applications in psychopharmacological trials. Psychiatry Res. 2007. Aug 30;152(2&#x2013;3):293&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2041449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17459488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connor KM, Davidson JR. Development of a new resilience scale: the Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC). Depress Anxiety. 2003;18(2):76&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12964174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pimple P, Lima BB, Hammadah M, Wilmot K, Ramadan R, Levantsevych O, et al. Psychological distress and subsequent cardiovascular events in individuals with coronary artery disease. J Am Heart Assoc. 2019;8(9):e011866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6512132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31055991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amstadter AB, Maes HH, Sheerin CM, Myers JM, Kendler KS. The relationship between genetic and environmental influences on resilience and on common internalizing and externalizing psychiatric disorders. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2016. May;51(5):669&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5137200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26687369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheerin CM, Lind MJ, Brown EA, Gardner CO, Kendler KS, Amstadter AB. The impact of resilience and subsequent stressful life events on MDD and GAD. Depress Anxiety. 2018. Feb;35(2):140&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5794521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29172241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC. COVID Data Tracker [Internet]. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2020.  [cited
2021 May 11]. Available from: https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid&#x2014;mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021. Jul 26;374:n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JBW. The PHQ-15: validity of a new measure for evaluating the severity of somatic symptoms. Psychosom Med. 2002. Apr;64(2):258&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11914441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witth&#xf6;ft M, Hiller W, Loch N, Jasper F. The latent structure of medically unexplained symptoms and its relation to functional somatic syndromes. Int J Behav Med. 2013. Jun;20(2):172&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22618306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howe CJ, Cole SR, Lau B, Napravnik S, Eron JJ. Selection bias due to loss to follow up in cohort studies. Epidemiology. 2016. Jan;27(1):91&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5008911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26484424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M Generalized estimating equations in longitudinal data analysis: a review and recent developments. Adv Stat. 2014;2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sylvester SV, Rusu R, Chan B, Bellows M, O&#x2019;Keefe C, Nicholson S. Sex differences in sequelae from COVID-19 infection and in long COVID syndrome: a review. Curr Med Res Opin. 2022. Aug 3;38(8):1391&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35726132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverstein B Gender Differences in the Prevalence of Somatic Versus Pure Depression: A Replication. Am J Psychiatry. 2002. Jun;159(6):1051&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12042198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vannini P, Gagliardi GP, Kuppe M, Dossett ML, Donovan NJ, Gatchel JR, et al. Stress, resilience, and coping strategies in a sample of community-dwelling older adults during COVID-19. J Psychiatr Res. 2021. Jun 1;138:176&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8369528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33862301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimi K, Borsari B, Marx BP, Rosen RC, Cohen BE, Woodward E, et al. Clusters of COVID-19 Protective and Risky Behaviors and their Associations with Pandemic, Socio-demographic, and Mental Health Factors in the United States. Prev Med Rep. 2022;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8669937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34926133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>To QG, Vandelanotte C, Cope K, Khalesi S, Williams SL, Alley SJ, et al. The association of resilience with depression, anxiety, stress and physical activity during the COVID-19 pandemic. BMC Public Health. 2022. Mar 12;22(1):491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8917786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35279118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du C, Zan MCH, Cho MJ, Fenton JI, Hsiao PY, Hsiao R, et al. The effects of sleep quality and resilience on perceived stress, dietary sleep quality and resilience on perceived stress, dietary behaviors, and alcohol misuse: A mediation-moderation analysis of higher education students from Asia, Europe, and North America during the COVID-19 pandemic. Nutrients. 2021. Feb;13(2):442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7911351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33572863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chastin SFM, Abaraogu U, Bourgois JG, Dall PM, Darnborough J, Duncan E, et al. Effects of regular physical activity on the immune system, vaccination and risk of community acquired infectious disease in the general population: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med Auckl NZ. 2021. Aug;51(8):1673&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33877614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett FC, Molofsky AV. The immune system and psychiatric disease: a basic science perspective. Clin Exp Immunol. 2019;197(3):294&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6693968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31125426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao K, Gillissie ES, Lui LMW, Ceban F, Teopiz KM, Gill H, et al. Immune response to vaccination in adults with mental disorders: A systematic review. J Affect Disord. 2022. May 1;304:66&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8837484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35167926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huppert FA. Psychological well-being: Evidence regarding its causes and consequences. Appl Psychol Health Well-Being. 2009;1(2):137&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostev K, Smith L, Koyanagi A, Jacob L. Prevalence of and factors associated with post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition in the 12 months after the diagnosis of COVID-19 in adults followed in general practices in Germany. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2022. Jul 1;9(7):ofac333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9278235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35891693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S, Wang R, Zhao Y, Ma X, Wu M, Yan X, et al. The relationship between self-rated health and objective health status: a population-based study. BMC Public Health. 2013. Apr 9;13(1):320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3637052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23570559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozenkrantz L How beliefs about coronavirus disease (COVID) influence COVID-like symptoms? &#x2013; A longitudinal study. Health Psychol. 20220718;41(8):519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35849379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews PW, Thomson JA. The bright side of being blue: Depression as an adaptation for analyzing complex problems. Psychol Rev. 2009. Jul;116(3):620&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2734449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19618990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson E, Sutin AR, Daly M, Jones A. A systematic review and meta-analysis of longitudinal cohort studies comparing mental health before versus during the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020. J Affect Disord. 2022. Jan 1;296:567&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8578001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34600966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez CA, Choi KW, Marshall BD, Vicente B, Saldivia S, Kohn R, et al. Assessing the relationship between psychosocial stressors and psychiatric resilience among Chilean disaster survivors. Br J Psychiatry. 2020;217(5):630&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8268117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32522300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke KEN. Seroprevalence of infection-induced SARS-CoV-2 antibodies &#x2014; United States, September 2021&#x2013;February 2022. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71(17):606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9098232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35482574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS. Psychological stress and immunoprotection versus immunopathology in the skin. Clin Dermatol. 2013. Jan 1;31(1):18&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23245970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>