<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35576613</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1868-1891</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Hormone molecular biology and clinical investigation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Horm Mol Biol Clin Investig</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Oxytocin, the panacea for long-COVID? a review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>363</StartPage><EndPage>371</EndPage><MedlinePgn>363-371</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/hmbci-2021-0034</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">In this hypothesis paper we explore the underlying mechanisms for long-COVID and how the oxytocinergic neurones could be infected by SARS-CoV-2 leading to a reduction in plasma oxytocin (OXT). Furthermore, we aim to review the relevance of OXT and hypothalamic function in recovery from long-COVID symptoms and pathology, through exploring the pro-health effects of the OXT neuropeptide.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A review of published literature was surveyed using Google Scholar and PubMed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Numerous experimental data can be shown to correlate with OXT and long-COVID symptoms and conditions, thus providing strong circumstantial evidence to support our hypothesis. It is postulated that the reduction in plasma OXT due to acute and post-viral damage to the hypothalamus and oxytocinergic neurones contributes to the variable multi-system, remitting and relapsing nature of long-COVID. The intranasal route of OXT application was determined to be most appropriate and clinically relevant for the restoration of oxytocinergic function post COVID-19 infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We believe it is imperative to further investigate whether OXT alleviates the prolonged suffering of patients with long-COVID. Succinctly, OXT may be the much-needed post-pandemic panacea.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Walter de Gruyter GmbH, Berlin/Boston.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diep</LastName><ForeName>Phuoc-Tan</ForeName><Initials>PT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, NHS Foundation Trust - University Hospitals of Morecambe Bay, Kendal, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaudry</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, NHS Foundation Trust - University Hospitals of Morecambe Bay, Kendal, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dixon</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp; Neuroscience, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaudry</LastName><ForeName>Faisal</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SKD pharmaceuticals, Blackburn, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kasabri</LastName><ForeName>Violet</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1927-0193</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Pharmacy, University of Jordan, Amman, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Horm Mol Biol Clin Investig</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101538885</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1868-1883</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009479">Neuropeptides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>50-56-6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010121">Oxytocin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009479" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuropeptides</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010121" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxytocin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">action mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypothalamus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxytocin</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35576613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/hmbci-2021-0034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">hmbci-2021-0034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Bryant, A, Lawrie, TA, Dowswell, T, Fordham, EJ, Mitchell, S, Hill, SR, et al.. Ivermectin for prevention and treatment of COVID-19 infection: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and trial sequential analysis to inform clinical guidelines. Am J Therapeut 2021;28:e434&#x2013;e460, https://doi.org/10.1097/mjt.0000000000001442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caly, L, Druce, JD, Catton, MG, Jans, DA, Wagstaff, KM. The FDA-approved drug ivermectin inhibits the replication of SARS-CoV-2 in vitro. Antivir Res 2020;178:104787, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.antiviral.2020.104787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajter, JC, Sherman, MS, Fatteh, N, Vogel, F, Sack, J, Rajter, JJ. Use of ivermectin is associated with lower mortality in hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019: the ivermectin in COVID nineteen study. Chest 2021;159:85&#x2013;92, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chest.2020.10.009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautret, P, Lagier, JC, Parola, P, Hoang, VT, Meddeb, L, Mailhe, M, et al.. Hydroxychloroquine and azithromycin as a treatment of COVID-19: results of an open-label non-randomized clinical trial. Int J Antimicrob Agents 2020;56:105949, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2020.105949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calegari, J, Beverina, A, Tiraboschi, S, Gruppo di Autoformazione Metodologica (GrAM). Hydroxychloroquine and azithromycin as a treatment of COVID-19. Intern Emerg Med 2020;15:841&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqui, AJ, Jahan, S, Ashraf, SA, Alreshidi, M, Ashraf, MS, Patel, M, et al.. Current status and strategic possibilities on potential use of combinational drug therapy against COVID-19 caused by SARS-CoV-2. J Biomol Struct Dyn 2021;39:6828&#x2013;41, https://doi.org/10.1080/07391102.2020.1802345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary, R, Shama, AK. Potential use of hydroxychloroquine, ivermectin and azithromycin drugs in fighting COVID-19: trends, scope and relevance. New Microbes New Infect 2020;35:100684, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nmni.2020.100684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadegiani, FA, Goren, A, Wambier, CG, McCoy, J. Early COVID-19 therapy with azithromycin plus nitazoxanide, ivermectin or hydroxychloroquine in outpatient settings significantly improved COVID-19 outcomes compared to known outcomes in untreated patients. New Microbes New Infect 2021;43:100915, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nmni.2021.100915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vimaleswaran, KS, Forouhi, NG, Khunti, K. Vitamin D and COVID-19. BMJ 2021;372:n544, https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, R, Wang, X, Ni, L, Di, X, Ma, B, Niu, S, et al.. COVID-19: melatonin as a potential adjuvant treatment. Life Sci 2020;250:117583, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lfs.2020.117583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buemann, B, Marazziti, D, Uvn&#xe4;s-Moberg, K. Can intravenous oxytocin infusion counteract hyperinflammation in COVID-19 infected patients? World J Biol Psychiatr 2020;11:1&#x2013;12, https://doi.org/10.1080/15622975.2020.1814408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imami, AS, O&#x2019;Donovan, SM, Creeden, JF, Wu, X, Eby, H, McCullumsmith, CB, et al.. Oxytocin&#x2019;s anti-inflammatory and proimmune functions in COVID-19: a transcriptomic signature-based approach. Physiol Genom 2020;52:401&#x2013;7, https://doi.org/10.1152/physiolgenomics.00095.2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson, KR. Considerations for active labor management with oxytocin: more may not be better. MCN Am J Matern/Child Nurs 2020;45:248, https://doi.org/10.1097/NMC.0000000000000639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breuil, V, Trojani, M-C, Ez-Zoubir, A. Oxytocin and bone: review and perspectives. Int J Mol Sci 2021;22:8551, https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms22168551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Z, Lian, X, Su, X, Wu, W, Marraro, GA, Zeng, Y. From SARS and MERS to COVID-19: a brief summary and comparison of severe acute respiratory infections caused by three highly pathogenic human coronaviruses. Respir Res 2020;21:224, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12931-020-01479-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chlamydas, S, Papavassiliou, AG, Piperi, C. Epigenetic mechanisms regulating COVID-19 infection. Epigenetics 2021;16:263&#x2013;70, https://doi.org/10.1080/15592294.2020.1796896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marazziti, D, Cianconi, P, Mucci, F, Foresi, L, Chiarantini, I, Della Vecchia, A. Climate change, environment pollution, COVID-19 pandemic and mental health. Sci Total Environ 2021;773:145182, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.145182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T, Song, J, Liu, H, Zheng, H, Chen, C. Positive Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus detection in coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) patients. Sci Rep 2021;11:10902, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-90351-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss, P. The ancient and the new: is there an interaction between cytomegalovirus and SARS-CoV-2 infection? Immun Ageing 2020;17:14, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12979-020-00185-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodd, LE, Freidlin, B, Korn, EL. Platform trials&#x2014;beware the noncomparable Control group. N Engl J Med 2021;384:1572&#x2013;3, https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmc2102446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, J, Gong, E, Zhang, B, Zheng, J, Gao, Z, Zhong, Y, et al.. Multiple organ infection and the pathogenesis of SARS. J Exp Med 2005;202:415&#x2013;24, https://doi.org/10.1084/jem.20050828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moses, AM, Thomas, DG, Canfield, MC, Collins, GH. Central diabetes insipidus due to cytomegalovirus infection of the hypothalamus in a patient with acquired immunodeficiency syndrome: a clinical, pathological, and immunohistochemical case study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2003;88:51&#x2013;4, https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2002-020879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrousos, GP, Zapanti, ED. Hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis in HIV infection and disease. Endocrinol Metab Clin N Am 2014;43:791&#x2013;806, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecl.2014.06.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y, Conboy, I. Unexpected evolutionarily conserved rapid effects of viral infection on oxytocin receptor and TGF-&#x3b2;/pSmad3. Skeletal Muscle 2017;7:7, https://doi.org/10.1186/s13395-017-0125-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter, C, Kenkel, W, Maclean, E, Wilson, S, Perkeybile, A, Yee, J, et al.. Is oxytocin &#x201c;nature&#x2019;s medicine&#x201d;. Pharm Rev 2020;72:829&#x2013;61, https://doi.org/10.1124/pr.120.019398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdman, S, Poutahidis, T. Probiotic &#x2018;glow of health&#x2019;: it&#x2019;s more than skin deep. Benef Microbes 2014;5:109&#x2013;19, https://doi.org/10.3920/bm2013.0042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imami, AS, O&#x2019;Donovan, SM, Creeden, JF, Wu, X, Eby, H, McCullumsmith, CB, et al.. Oxytocin&#x2019;s anti-inflammatory and proimmune functions in COVID-19: a transcriptomic signature-based approach. Physiol Genom 2020;52:401&#x2013;7, https://doi.org/10.1152/physiolgenomics.00095.2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diep, P-T, Talash, K, Kasabri, V. Hypothesis: oxytocin is a direct COVID-19 antiviral. Med Hypotheses 2020;145:110329, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mehy.2020.110329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsegay, KB, Adeyemi, CM, Gniffke, EP, Sather, DN, Walker, JK, Smith, SEP. A repurposed drug screen identifies compounds that inhibit the binding of the COVID-19 spike protein to ACE2. Front Pharmacol 2021;12:685308, https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2021.685308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bechter, K. Virus infection as a cause of inflammation in psychiatric disorders. Modern Trends Pharmacopsych 2013;28:49&#x2013;60, https://doi.org/10.1159/000343967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martimbianco, ALC, Pacheco, RL, Bagattini, &#xc2;M, Riera, R. Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID-19: a systematic review. Int J Clin Pract 2021;75: e14357, https://doi.org/10.1111/ijcp.14357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon, S, Wegman-Ostrosky, T, Perelman, C, Sepulveda, R, Rebolledo, PA, Cuapio, A, et al.. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep 2021;11:16144, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Institute of Medicine (IOM). 2015 Diagnostic criteria. CDC (Center of Disease Control) Control and Prevention, National Center for Emerging and oonotic Infectious Diseases; 2021: 1&#x2013;2 pp. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/me-cfs/healthcare-providers/diagnosis/iom-2015-diagnostic-criteria.html [Accessed 12 Sep 2021].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatziagelaki, E, Adamaki, M, Tsilioni, I, Dimitriadis, G, Theoharides, TC. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome-metabolic disease or disturbed homeostasis due to focal inflammation in the hypothalamus? J Pharmacol Exp Therapeut 2018;367:155&#x2013;67, https://doi.org/10.1124/jpet.118.250845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanElzakker, MB. Chronic fatigue syndrome from vagus nerve infection: a psychoneuroimmunological hypothesis. Med. Hypotheses 2013;81:414&#x2013;23, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mehy.2013.05.034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong, L, Li, J, Tang, Y, Han, T, Wei, C, Yu, X, et al.. The antinociception of oxytocin on colonic hypersensitivity in rats was mediated by inhibition of mast cell degranulation via Ca2+ NOS pathway. Sci Rep 2016;6:31452, https://doi.org/10.1038/srep31452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves, VE, Tilelli, CQ, Brito, NA, Brito, MN. Role of oxytocin in energy metabolism. Peptides 2013;45:9&#x2013;14, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.peptides.2013.04.010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordt, EA, Smith, CJ, Demarest, TG, Bilbo, SD, Kingsbury, MA. Mitochondria, oxytocin, and vasopressin: unfolding the inflammatory protein response. Neurotox Res 2019;36:239&#x2013;56, https://doi.org/10.1007/s12640-018-9962-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehdipour, M, Etienne, J, Chen, C-C, Gathwala, R, Rehman, M, Kato, C, et al.. Rejuvenation of brain, liver and muscle by simultaneous pharmacological modulation of two signaling determinants, that change in opposite directions with age. Aging [Albany NY] 2019;11:5628&#x2013;45, https://doi.org/10.18632/aging.102148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elabd, C, Cousin, W, Upadhyayula, P, Chen, RY, Chooljian, MS, Li, J, et al.. Oxytocin is an age-specific circulating hormone that is necessary for muscle maintenance and regeneration. Nat Commun 2014;5:4082, https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms5082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonneaux, V, Ouichou, A, Burbach, JPH, P&#xe9;vet, P. Vasopressin and oxytocin modulation of melatonin secretion from rat pineal glands. Peptides 1990;11:1075&#x2013;9, https://doi.org/10.1016/0196-9781(90)90133-p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandyk, R. MIF-induced augmentation of melatonin functions: possible relevance to mechanisms of action of MIF-1 in movement disorders. Int J Neurosci 1990;52:59&#x2013;65, https://doi.org/10.3109/00207459008994244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y-T, Chen, C-C, Huang, C-C, Nishimori, K, Hsu, K-S. Oxytocin stimulates hippocampal neurogenesis via oxytocin receptor expressed in CA3 pyramidal neurons. Nat Commun 2017;8:537, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-017-00675-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafarzadeh, N, Javeri, A, Khaleghi, M, Taha, MF. Oxytocin improves proliferation and neural differentiation of adipose tissue-derived stem cells. Neurosci Lett 2014;564:105&#x2013;10, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2014.02.012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erbas, O, Ta&#x15f;k&#x131;ran, D, Oltulu, F, Yava&#x15f;o&#x11f;lu, A, Bora, S, Bilge, O, et al.. Oxytocin provides protection against diabetic polyneuropathy in rats. Neurol Res 2017;39:45&#x2013;53, https://doi.org/10.1080/01616412.2016.1249630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;m&#xfc;s, B, Kuyucu, E, Erbas, O, Kazimoglu, C, Oltulu, F, Bora, OA. Effect of oxytocin administration on nerve recovery in the rat sciatic nerve damage model. J Orthop Surg Res 2015;10:161, https://doi.org/10.1186/s13018-015-0301-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leng, G, Sabatier, N. Oxytocin &#x2013; the sweet hormone? Trends Endocrinol Metabol 2017;28:365&#x2013;76, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tem.2017.02.007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, G-Z, Kaba, H, Okutani, F, Takahashi, S, Higuchi, T. The olfactory bulb: a critical site of action for oxytocin in the induction of maternal behavior in the rat. Neuroscience 1996;72:1083&#x2013;8, https://doi.org/10.1016/0306-4522(95)00600-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, MR, Wehring, HJ, McMahon, RP, Linthicum, J, Cascella, N, Liu, F, et al.. Effects of adjunctive intranasal oxytocin on olfactory identification and clinical symptoms in schizophrenia: results from a randomized double blind placebo controlled pilot study. Schizophr Res 2013;145:110&#x2013;5, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.schres.2013.01.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leuner, B, Caponiti, JM, Gould, E. Oxytocin stimulates adult neurogenesis even under conditions of stress and elevated glucocorticoids. Hippocampus 2012;22:861&#x2013;8, https://doi.org/10.1002/hipo.20947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marazziti, D, Catena Dell&#x2019;osso, M. The role of oxytocin in neuropsychiatric disorders. Curr Med Chem 2008;15:698&#x2013;704, https://doi.org/10.2174/092986708783885291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsushita, H, Latt, HM, Koga, Y, Nishiki, T, Matsui, H. Oxytocin and stress: neural mechanisms, stress-related disorders, and therapeutic approaches. Neuroscience 2019;417:1&#x2013;10, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2019.07.046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grinevich, V, Neumann, ID. Brain oxytocin: how puzzle stones from animal studies translate into psychiatry. Mol Psychiatr 2021;26:265&#x2013;79, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41380-020-0802-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L, Nabi, G, Zhang, T, Wu, Y, Li, D. Potential neurochemical and neuroendocrine effects of social distancing amidst the COVID-19 pandemic. Front Endocrinol 2020;11:582288, https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2020.582288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soumier, A, Sirigu, A. Oxytocin as a potential defense against Covid-19? Med Hypotheses 2020;140:109785, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mehy.2020.109785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur, P, Shrivastava, R, Shrivastava, VK. Oxytocin as a potential adjuvant against COVID-19 infection. Endocr Metab Immune Disord &#x2013; Drug Targets 2021;21:1155&#x2013;62, https://doi.org/10.2174/1871530320666200910114259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderberg, UM, Uvn&#xe4;s-Moberg, K. Plasma oxytocin levels in female fibromyalgia syndrome patients. Z Rheumatol 2000;59:373&#x2013;9, https://doi.org/10.1007/s003930070045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzabazis, A, Mechanic, J, Miller, J, Klukinov, M, Pascual, C, Manering, N, et al.. Oxytocin receptor: expression in the trigeminal nociceptive system and potential role in the treatment of headache disorders. Cephalalgia 2016;36:943&#x2013;50, https://doi.org/10.1177/0333102415618615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y-L, Yuan, Y, Yang, J, Wang, C-H, Pan, Y-J, Lu, L, et al.. The interaction between the oxytocin and pain modulation in headache patients. Neuropeptides 2013;47:93&#x2013;7, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.npep.2012.12.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodin, BR, Ness, TJ, Robbins, MT. Oxytocin &#x2013; a multifunctional analgesic for chronic deep tissue pain. Curr Pharmaceut Des 2015;21:906&#x2013;13, https://doi.org/10.2174/1381612820666141027111843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eliava, M, Melchior, M, Knobloch-Bollmann, HS, Wahis, J, da Silva Gouveia, M, Tang, Y, et al.. A new population of parvocellular oxytocin neurons controlling magnocellular neuron activity and inflammatory pain processing. Neuron 2016;89:1291&#x2013;304, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2016.01.041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lussier, D, Cruz-Almeida, Y, Ebner, NC. Musculoskeletal pain and brain morphology: oxytocin&#x2019;s potential as a treatment for chronic pain in aging. Front Aging Neurosci 2019;11:338, https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2019.00338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo, R, D&#x2019;Agostino, G, Mattace Raso, G, Avagliano, C, Cristiano, C, Meli, R, et al.. Central administration of oxytocin reduces hyperalgesia in mice: implication for cannabinoid and opioid systems. Peptides 2012;38:81&#x2013;8, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.peptides.2012.08.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meguro, Y, Miyano, K, Hirayama, S, Yoshida, Y, Ishibashi, N, Ogino, T, et al.. Neuropeptide oxytocin enhances &#x3bc; opioid receptor signaling as a positive allosteric modulator. J. Pharm.Sci. 2018;137:67&#x2013;75, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphs.2018.04.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nersesyan, Y, Demirkhanyan, L, Cabezas-Bratesco, D, Oakes, V, Kusuda, R, Dawson, T, et al.. Oxytocin modulates nociception as an agonist of pain-sensing TRPV1. Cell Rep 2017;21:1681&#x2013;91, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2017.10.063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An, X, Sun, X, Hou, Y, Yang, X, Chen, H, Zhang, P, et al.. Protective effect of oxytocin on LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice. Sci Rep 2019;9:2836, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-39349-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, C-H, Tsai, C-C, Chen, T-H, Chang, C-P, Yang, H-H. Oxytocin maintains lung histological and functional integrity to confer protection in heat stroke. Sci Rep 2019;9:18390, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-54739-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danalache, BA, Paquin, J, Donghao, W, Grygorczyk, R, Moore, JC, Mummery, CL, et al.. Nitric oxide signaling in oxytocin-mediated cardiomyogenesis. Stem Cell 2007;25:679&#x2013;88, https://doi.org/10.1634/stemcells.2005-0610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melis, MR, Succu, S, Iannucci, U, Argiolas, A. Oxytocin increases nitric oxide production in the paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus of male rats: correlation with penile erection and yawning. Regul Pept 1997;69:105&#x2013;11, https://doi.org/10.1016/s0167-0115(97)00002-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricciardolo, FLM. Multiple roles of nitric oxide in the airways. Thorax 2003;58:175&#x2013;82, https://doi.org/10.1136/thorax.58.2.175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longobardo, A, Montanari, C, Shulman, R, Benhalim, S, Singer, M, Arulkumaran, N. Inhaled nitric oxide minimally improves oxygenation in COVID-19 related acute respiratory distress syndrome. Br J Anaesth 2021;126:e44&#x2013;6, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2020.10.011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, J, Chen, AF. Nitric oxide: a newly discovered function on wound healing. Acta Pharm Sin 2005;26:259&#x2013;64, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1745-7254.2005.00058.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc5;kerstr&#xf6;m, S, Mousavi-Jazi, M, Klingstr&#xf6;m, J, Leijon, M, Lundkvist, &#xc5;, Mirazimi, A. Nitric oxide inhibits the replication cycle of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus. J Virol 2005;79:1966&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutkowska, J, Jankowski, M. Oxytocin revisited: it is also a cardiovascular hormone. J Am Soc. Hypert. 2008;2:318&#x2013;25, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jash.2008.04.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jankowski, M, Broderick, TL, Gutkowska, J. Oxytocin and cardioprotection in diabetes and obesity. BMC Endocr Disord 2016;16:34, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12902-016-0110-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, P, Wang, SC, Yang, H, Lv, C, Jia, S, Liu, X, et al.. Therapeutic potential of oxytocin in atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease: mechanisms and signaling pathways. Front Neurosci 2019;13:454, https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2019.00454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habecker, BA. Oxytocin: a new therapeutic for heart failure? JACC (J Am Coll Cardiol): Basic Trans. Sci. 2020;5:498&#x2013;500, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacbts.2020.03.011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, SC, Wang, Y-F. Cardiovascular protective properties of oxytocin against COVID-19. Life Sci 2021;270:119130, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lfs.2021.119130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfv&#xe9;n, G. Plasma oxytocin in children with recurrent abdominal pain. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr 2004;38:513&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavril, R, Hritcu, L, Padurariu, M, Ciobica, A, Horhogea, C, Stefanescu, G, et al.. Preliminary study on the correlations between oxytocin levels and irritable bowel syndrome in patients with depression. Rev Chim (Bucharest) 2019;70:2204&#x2013;6, https://doi.org/10.37358/rc.19.6.7305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hritcu, L, Dumitru, IO, Padurariu, M, Ciobica, A, Spataru, MC, Spataru, C, et al.. The modulation of oxytocin and cortisol levels in major depression disorder and irritable bowel syndrome. Rev Chim (Bucharest) 2020;71:150&#x2013;4, https://doi.org/10.37358/rc.20.1.7826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x130;&#x15f;eri, S&#xd6;, &#x15e;ener, G, Sa&#x11f;lam, B, Gedik, N, Ercan, F, Ye&#x11f;en, B&#xc7;. Oxytocin ameliorates oxidative colonic inflammation by a neutrophil-dependent mechanism. Peptides 2005;26:483&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, Y, Shi, Y, Gao, Y, Xu, X, Han, T, Li, J, et al.. Oxytocin system alleviates intestinal inflammation by regulating macrophages polarization in experimental colitis. Clin Sci [Lond] 2019;133:1977&#x2013;92, https://doi.org/10.1042/cs20190756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cetinel, S, Hancio&#x11f;lu, S, Sener, E, Uner, C, Kili&#xe7;, M, Sener, G, et al.. Oxytocin treatment alleviates stress-aggravated colitis by a receptor-dependent mechanism. Regul Pept 2010;160:146&#x2013;52, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.regpep.2009.11.011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erbas, O, Anil Korkmaz, H, Oltulu, F, Aktug, H, Yavasoglu, A, Akman, L, et al.. Oxytocin alleviates cisplatin-induced renal damage in rats. Iran J Basic Med Sci 2014;17:747&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deing, V, Roggenkamp, D, K&#xfc;hnl, J, Gruschka, A, St&#xe4;b, F, Wenck, H, et al.. Oxytocin modulates proliferation and stress responses of human skin cells: implications for atopic dermatitis. Exp Dermatol 2013;22:399&#x2013;405, https://doi.org/10.1111/exd.12155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersson, M, Lundeberg, T, Sohlstr&#xf6;m, A, Wiberg, U, Uvn&#xe4;s-Moberg, K. Oxytocin increases the survival of musculocutaneous flaps. Naunyn-Schmiedeberg&#x2019;s Arch Pharmacol 1998;357:701&#x2013;4, https://doi.org/10.1007/pl00005227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, P-F, Fang, M-J, Jin, Y-Z, Wang, L-S, Lin, D-S. Effect of oxytocin on the survival of random skin flaps. Oncotarget 2017;8:92955&#x2013;65, https://doi.org/10.18632/oncotarget.21696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, YS, Kwon, JS, Hong, MH, Kang, WS, Jeong, H, Kang, H, et al.. Restoration of angiogenic capacity of diabetes-insulted mesenchymal stem cells by oxytocin. BMC Cell Biol 2013;14:38, https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2121-14-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, J, Yu, Y, Zheng, L, Zhang, C, Tu, Y, Liu, Y, et al.. Hypothalamus-pituitary-adrenal axis involves in anti-viral ability through regulation of immune response in piglets infected by highly pathogenic porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus. BMC Vet Res 2018;14:92, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12917-018-1414-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y-H, Cui, X-Y, Yang, W, Fan, D-Y, Liu, D, Wang, P-G, et al.. Zika virus infection in hypothalamus causes hormone deficiencies and leads to irreversible growth delay and memory impairment in mice. Cell Rep 2018;25:1537&#x2013;47, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2018.10.025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn, HJ, Chung, J-H, Kim, D-M, Yoon, N-R, Kim, C-M. Hemorrhagic fever with renal syndrome accompanied by panhypopituitarism and central diabetes insipidus: a case report. J Neurovirol 2018;24:382&#x2013;7, https://doi.org/10.1007/s13365-018-0624-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stojanovic, M, Pekic, S, Cvijovic, G, Miljic, D, Doknic, M, Nikolic-Djurovic, M, et al.. High risk of hypopituitarism in patients who recovered from hemorrhagic fever with renal syndrome. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2008;93:2722&#x2013;8, https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2008-0311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leow, MK, Kwek, DS, Ng, AW, Ong, K, Kaw, GJ, Lee, LS. Hypocortisolism in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS). Clin Endocrinol 2005;63:197&#x2013;202, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2265.2005.02325.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stock, S, Uvn&#xe4;s&#x2010;Moberg, K. Increased plasma levels of oxytocin in response to afferent electrical stimulation of the sciatic and vagal nerves and in response to touch and pinch in anaesthetized rats. Acta Physiol Scand 1988;132:29&#x2013;34, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1748-1716.1988.tb08294.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin, MR, Koufman, JA. Vagal neuropathy after upper respiratory infection: a viral etiology? Am J Otolaryngol 2001;22:251&#x2013;6, https://doi.org/10.1053/ajot.2001.24823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachor, E, Bonkowsky, V, Hacki, T. Herpes simplex virus type I reactivation as a cause of a unilateral temporary paralysis of the vagus nerve. Eur Arch Oto-Rhino-Laryngol 1996;253:297&#x2013;300, https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00171147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rangon, C-M, Krantic, S, Moyse, E, Foug&#xe8;re, B. The vagal autonomic pathway of COVID-19 at the crossroad of alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and aging: a review of knowledge. J Alzheim. Dis Rep. 2020;4:537&#x2013;51, https://doi.org/10.3233/adr-200273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diep, P-T. Is there an underlying link between COVID-19, ACE2, oxytocin and vitamin D? Med Hypotheses 2021;146:110360, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mehy.2020.110360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLean, EL, Wilson, SR, Martin, WL, Davis, JM, Nazarloo, HP, Carter, CS. Challenges for measuring oxytocin: the blind men and the elephant? Psychoneuroendocrinology 2019;107:225&#x2013;31, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psyneuen.2019.05.018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskaran, C, Plessow, F, Silva, L, Asanza, E, Marengi, D, Eddy, KT, et al.. Oxytocin secretion is pulsatile in men and is related to social-emotional functioning. Psychoneuroendocrinology 2017;85:28&#x2013;34, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psyneuen.2017.07.486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter, CS. The oxytocin&#x2013;vasopressin pathway in the context of love and fear. Front Endocrinol 2017;8:356, https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2017.00356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis, BJ, Horn, AJ, Carter, CS, van IJzendoorn, MH, Bakermans-Kranenburg, MJ. Developmental programming of oxytocin through variation in early-life stress: four meta-analyses and a theoretical reinterpretation. Clin Psychol Rev 2021;86:101985, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpr.2021.101985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamo, S, Pigna, E, Lugar&#xe0;, R, Moresi, V, Coletti, D, Bouch&#xe9;, M. Skeletal muscle: a significant novel neurohypophyseal hormone-secreting organ. Front Physiol 2019;9:1885, https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2018.01885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J, Liu, S, Zhang, Z, Lee, X, Wu, W, Huang, Z, et al.. Association between the nasopharyngeal microbiome and metabolome in patients with COVID-19. Synth Syst Biotech 2021;6:135&#x2013;43, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.synbio.2021.06.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer, P, Bressan, P. Infection threat shapes our social instincts. Behav Ecol Sociobiol 2021;75:4, https://doi.org/10.1007/s00265-021-02975-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amro, M, Mohamed, A, Alawna, M. Effects of increasing aerobic capacity on improving psychological problems seen in patients with COVID-19: a review. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci 2021;25:2808&#x2013;21, https://doi.org/10.26355/eurrev_202103_25443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg, DM, Decety, J, Gordon, I. The social neuroscience of music: understanding the social brain through human song. Am Psychol 2021;76:1172&#x2013;85 https://doi.org/10.1037/amp0000819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meijer, LL, Hasenack, B, Kamps, JCC, Mahon, A, Titone, G, Dijkerman, HC, et al.. Affective touch perception and longing for touch during the COVID-19 pandemic. Sci Rep 2022;12:3887&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ionio, C, Ciuffo, G, Landoni, M. Parent&#x2013;infant skin-to-skin contact and stress regulation: a systematic review of the literature. Int J Environ Res Publ Health 2021;18:4695, https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18094695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, H-J, Macbeth, AH, Pagani, J, Young, WS. Oxytocin: the great facilitator of life. Prog Neurobiol 2009;88:127&#x2013;51, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pneurobio.2009.04.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patrick, RP, Ames, BN. Vitamin D hormone regulates serotonin synthesis. Part 1: relevance for autism. Faseb J 2014;28:2398&#x2013;413, https://doi.org/10.1096/fj.13-246546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsling, ML, Wheeler, MJ, Williams, AJ. The effect of melatonin administration on pituitary hormone secretion in man. Clin Endocrinol 1999;51:637&#x2013;42, https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365-2265.1999.00820.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, JS, Koh, SH, Cooper, GM. Haemodynamic effects of oxytocin given as i.v. bolus or infusion on women undergoing Caesarean section. Br J Anaesth 2007;98:116&#x2013;9, https://doi.org/10.1093/bja/ael302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phaneuf, S, Rodr&#xed;guez Li&#xf1;ares, B, TambyRaja, RL, MacKenzie, IZ, L&#xf3;pez Bernal, A. Loss of myometrial oxytocin receptors during oxytocin-induced and oxytocin-augmented labor. J Reprod Fertil 2000;120:91&#x2013;7, https://doi.org/10.1530/jrf.0.1200091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabak, BA, McCullough, ME, Szeto, A, Mendez, AJ, McCabe, PM. Oxytocin indexes relational distress following interpersonal harms in women. Psychoneuroendocrinology 2011;36:115&#x2013;22, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psyneuen.2010.07.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winter, J, Meyer, M, Berger, I, Peters, S, Royer, M, Bianchi, M, et al.. Chronic oxytocin-driven alternative splicing of CRFR2&#x3b1; induces anxiety. Mol Psychiatr 2021, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41380-021-01141-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto, Y, Higashida, H. RAGE regulates oxytocin transport into the brain. Commun Biol 2020;3:1&#x2013;4, https://doi.org/10.1038/s42003-020-0799-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintana, DS, Smerud, KT, Andreassen, OA, Djupesland, PG. Evidence for intranasal oxytocin delivery to the brain: recent advances and future perspectives. Ther Deliv 2018;9:515&#x2013;25, https://doi.org/10.4155/tde-2018-0002.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>