<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39016279</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5948</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of occupational and environmental medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Occup Environ Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Psychological General Well-being, Cognitive Failure, and Inflammation Biomarkers Among Workers 4 Months After a Mild/Asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 Infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>793</StartPage><EndPage>802</EndPage><MedlinePgn>793-802</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JOM.0000000000003174</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the relationship between cognitive complaints, systemic inflammatory biomarkers, and psychological general well-being (PGWB) after mild/asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection, according to the presence of long COVID and work tasks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">University employees and metal workers were recruited in a cross-sectional study 4 months after SARS-CoV-2 infection to assess cognitive impairment, individual PGWB index, inflammatory biomarkers, namely platelet-lymphocyte, neutrophil-lymphocyte, and lymphocyte-monocyte ratios, and the presence of long COVID symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A significant increase in the levels of inflammatory biomarkers was observed in subjects with long COVID. Furthermore, the PGWB index was influenced by long COVID symptoms and subjective cognitive and depressive symptoms, but not by work activity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In occupational settings, it is crucial to detect the presence of long COVID symptoms and systemic inflammation early, as they may be associated with lower PGWB.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of the American College of Occupational and Environmental Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stufano</LastName><ForeName>Angela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9101-7742</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Interdisciplinary Department of Medicine, University of Bari Aldo Moro, Bari, Italy(A.S., V.S., L.d.M., L.V., P.L.); Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany(G.L., A.F.); Department of Medicine, Surgery and Neuroscience, University of Siena, Siena, Italy (D.P.); and Department of Public Health, University of Naples Federico II, Naples, Italy (I.I.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lucchese</LastName><ForeName>Guglielmo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schino</LastName><ForeName>Valentina</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plantone</LastName><ForeName>Domenico</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Maria</LastName><ForeName>Luigi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vimercati</LastName><ForeName>Luigi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Floel</LastName><ForeName>Agnes</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iavicoli</LastName><ForeName>Ivo</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lovreglio</LastName><ForeName>Piero</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Occup Environ Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9504688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1076-2752</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="Y">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="Y">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Stufano, Lucchese, Schino, Plantone, Maria, Vimercati, Floel, Iavicoli, and Lovreglio have no relationships/conditions/circumstances that present potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39016279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JOM.0000000000003174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00043764-990000000-00602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. The Ottawa Charter for Health Promotion . Geneva, Switzerland: WHO. 1986. Available at: http://www.who.int/healthpromotion/conferences/previous/ottawa/en/index.html . Accessed December 12, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adisasmito WB, Almuhairi S, Behravesh CB, et alOne Health High-Level Expert Panel (OHHLEP). One Health: a new definition for a sustainable and healthy future. PLoS Pathog 2022;18:e1010537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. The Geneva Charter for Well-being . Geneva: World Health Organization; 2021; Available at: https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/the-genevacharter-for-well-being . Accessed December 22, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang YY, Tang R, Gross JJ. Promoting psychological well-being through an evidence-based mindfulness training program. Front Hum Neurosci 2019;13:237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundgren-Nilsson &#xc5;, Jonsdottir IH, Ahlborg G Jr., Tennant A. Construct validity of the psychological general well being index (PGWBI) in a sample of patients undergoing treatment for stress-related exhaustion: a Rasch analysis. Health Qual Life Outcomes 2013;11:2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggeri K, Garcia-Garzon E, Maguire &#xc1;, Matz S, Huppert FA. Well-being is more than happiness and life satisfaction: a multidimensional analysis of 21 countries. Health Qual Life Outcomes 2020;18:192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovreglio P, Leso V, Riccardi E, et al. Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) pandemic: the psychological well-being in a cohort of Workers of a Multinational Company. Saf Health Work 2022;13:66&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj L, Kannapadi NV, Briggs J, et al. Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: a meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci 2022;434:120162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Descatha A, Evanoff BA, Fadel M. Post-COVID condition or &#x201c;long COVID&#x201d;, return-to work, and occupational health research. Scand J Work Environ Health 2023;49:165&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Bae S, Chang HH, et al. Long COVID prevalence and impact on quality of life 2 years after acute COVID-19. Sci Rep 2023;13:11207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anka AU, Tahir MI, Abubakar SD, et al. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): an overview of the immunopathology, serological diagnosis and management. Scand J Immunol 2021;93:e12998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misiewicz A, Dymicka-Piekarska V. Fashionable, but what is their real clinical usefulness? NLR, LMR, and PLR as a promising Indicator in colorectal cancer prognosis: a systematic review. J Inflamm Res 2023;16:69&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eissa M, Shaarawy S, Abdellateif MS. The role of different inflammatory indices in the diagnosis of COVID-19. Int J Gen Med 2021;14:7843&#x2013;7853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosid&#x142;o JW, Wolszczak-Biedrzycka B, Matowicka-Karna J, Dymicka-Piekarska V, Dorf J. Clinical significance and diagnostic utility of NLR, LMR, PLR and SII in the course of COVID-19: a literature review. J Inflamm Res 2023;16:539&#x2013;562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong P, Liu Y, Gong Y, et al. The association of neutrophil to lymphocyte ratio, platelet to lymphocyte ratio, and lymphocyte to monocyte ratio with post-thrombolysis early neurological outcomes in patients with acute ischemic stroke. J Neuroinflammation 2021;18:51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Tan L, Xue B, et al. Platelet-to-lymphocyte, neutrophil-to-lymphocyte and lymphocyte-to-monocyte ratios are related to cancer-related fatigue and quality of life in patients with cancer: a cross-sectional study. BMJ Open 2023;13:e075398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurner C, Stengel A. Long-COVID syndrome: physical-mental interplay in the spotlight. Inflammopharmacology 2023;31:559&#x2013;564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena SK, Kumar S, Ansari S, et al. Characterization of the novel SARS-CoV-2 omicron (B.1.1.529) variant of concern and its global perspective. J Med Virol 2022;94:1738&#x2013;1744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP; STROBE iInitiative. The strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Lancet 2007 Oct 20;370:1453&#x2013;1457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stufano A, Lucchese G, Stahl B, et al. Impact of COVID-19 emergency on the psychological well-being of susceptible individuals. Sci Rep 2022;12:11152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, et al. Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat Med 2022;28:1706&#x2013;1714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV; WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis 2022; 22:e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broadbent DE, Cooper PF, FitzGerald P, Parkes KR. The Cognitive Failures Questionnaire (CFQ) and its correlates. Br J Clin Psychol 1982;21:1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stratta P, Rinaldi O, Daneluzzo E, Rossi A. Utilizzo della versione italiana del Cognitive Failures Questionnaire (CFQ) in un campione di studenti: uno studio di validazione. Riv Psichiatr 2006;41:260&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rast P, Zimprich D, Van Boxtel M, Jolles J. Factor structure and measurement invariance of the cognitive failures questionnaire across the adult life span. Assessment 2009;16:145&#x2013;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corsi G, Nava S, Barco S. A novel tool to monitor the individual functional status after COVID-19: the Post-COVID-19 Functional Status (PCFS) scale. G Ital Cardiol (Rome) 2020;21:757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzotti E, Fassone G, Picardi A, et al. II Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ) per lo screening dei disturbi psichiatrici: Uno studio di validazione nei confronti della Intervista Clinica Strutturata per il DSM-IV asse I (SCID-I). Ital J Psychopathol 2003;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB. The PHQ-9: validity of a brief depression severity measure. J Gen Intern Med 2001;16:606&#x2013;613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuy HJ. The Psychological General Well-being (PGWBI) Index. In: Wenger NK, Mattson ME, Furburg CD, Elinson J, eds. Assessment of Quality of Life in Clinical Trials of Cardiovascular Therapies . New York: Le Jacq Publishing; 1984:170&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossi E, Mosconi P, Groth N, Niero M, Apolone G. Questionario Psychological General Well-Being Index. Versione Italiana . Milano, Italy: Istituto di Ricerche Farmacologiche &#x201c;Mario Negri&#x201d; Milano; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossi E, Compare A. Psychological General Well-Being Index (PGWB). In: Michalos AC, ed. Encyclopedia of Quality of Life and Well-Being Research . Dordrecht: Springer; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linting M, van der Kooij A. Nonlinear principal components analysis with CATPCA: a tutorial. J Pers Assess 2012;94:12&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meulman JJ, Van der Kooij AJ, Heiser WJ. In: Kaplan D, ed. Principal Components Analysis with Nonlinear Optimal Scaling Transformations for Ordinal and Nominal Data in The Sage Handbook of Quantitative methodology for the Social Sciences . California: Sage publications; 2004:49&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemalbay G, Korkmazo&#x11f;lu &#xd6;B. Categorical principal component logistic regression: a case study for housing loan approval. Procedia Soc Behav Sci 2014;109:730&#x2013;736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wulf Hanson S, Abbafati C, Aerts JG, et alGlobal Burden of Disease Long COVID Collaborators. Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA 2022;328:1604&#x2013;1615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE, et al. Short-term and long-term rates of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a systematic review. JAMA Netw Open 2021;4:e2128568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godeau D, Petit A, Richard I, Roquelaure Y, Descatha A. Return-to-work, disabilities and occupational health in the age of COVID-19. Scand J Work Environ Health 2021;47:408&#x2013;409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dymicka-Piekarska V, Dorf J, Milewska A, et al. Neutrophil/lymphocyte ratio (NLR) and lymphocyte/monocyte ratio (LMR)&#x2014;risk of death inflammatory biomarkers in patients With COVID-19. J Inflamm Res 2023;16:2209&#x2013;2222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akkaya F, Yener&#xe7;a&#x11f; FNT, Kaya A, &#x15e;ener YZ, Ba&#x11f;c&#x131; A. Long term effects of mild severity COVID-19 on right ventricular functions. Int J Cardiovasc Imaging 2021;37:3451&#x2013;3457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente I, Sinatti G, Cirella A, Santini SJ, Balsano C. Alteration of inflammatory parameters and psychological post-traumatic syndrome in long-COVID patients. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022;19:7103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riccardi E, Fontana L, Pacella D, et al. Impact of Covid-19 pandemic on psychological well-being of firefighters. Saf Health Work 2023;14:317&#x2013;324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'&#xc1;vila KG, Monaiar LR, Dantas LDP, et al. Decrease in health-related quality of life and post-COVID-19 syndrome in health care workers After SARS-CoV-2 infection: a cohort study. J Occup Environ Med 2023;65:e1&#x2013;e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Ling S, Lui LMW, et al. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in post-COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun 2022;101:93&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard. November 5, 2023. Available at: https://covid19.who.int/?mapFilter=cases . Accessed November 9, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE. COVID-19 Rapid Guideline: Managing the Long-Term Effects of COVID-19 . London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh D, Tan A. Return to work for workers with post-COVID conditions. Saf Health Work 2022;13:377&#x2013;378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik A, Ayuso-Mateos JL, Baranyi G, et al. Mental health at work: WHO guidelines. World Psychiatry 2023;22:331&#x2013;332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi M, Zakerian A, Mehri A, et al. Investigation into effects of work-related quality of life and some related factors on cognitive failures Among nurses. Int J Occup Saf Ergon 2017;23:386&#x2013;392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez J, Perez-Rojo G, Noriega C, Martinez-Huertas JA, Velasco C. Emotional distress among older adults during the COVID-19 outbreak: understanding the longitudinal psychological impact of the COVID-19 pandemic. Psychogeriatrics 2022;22:77&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bridger RS, Brasher K, Dew A, Sparshott K, Kilminster S. Job strain related to cognitive failure in naval personnel. Ergonomics 2010;53:739&#x2013;747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Raaij BFM, St&#xf6;ger JL, Hinnen C, et al. Fibrotic-like abnormalities notably prevalent one year after hospitalization with COVID-19. Respir Med Res 2022;82:100973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braga J, Lepra M, Kish SJ, et al. Neuroinflammation after COVID-19 with persistent depressive and cognitive symptoms. JAMA Psychiatry 2023;80:787&#x2013;795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zawilska JB, Kuczy&#x144;ska K. Psychiatric and neurological complications of long COVID. J Psychiatr Res 2022;156:349&#x2013;360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolsen MR, Soehner AM, Harvey AG. Proinflammatory cytokines, mood, and sleep in interepisode bipolar disorder and insomnia: a pilot study with implications for psychosocial interventions. Psychosom Med 2018;80:87&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santoft F, Hedman-Lagerl&#xf6;f E, Salomonsson S, et al. Inflammatory cytokines in patients with common mental disorders treated with cognitive behavior therapy. Brain Behav Immun Health 2020;3:100045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenblat JD, Cha DS, Mansur RB, McIntyre RS. Inflamed moods: a review of the interactions between inflammation and mood disorders. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry 2014;53:23&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedetti F, Palladini M, Paolini M, et al. Brain correlates of depression, post-traumatic distress, and inflammatory biomarkers in COVID-19 survivors: a multimodal magnetic resonance imaging study. Brain Behav Immun Health 2021;18:100387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han WJ, Hart J. Job precarity and economic prospects during the COVID-19 public health crisis. Soc Sci Q 2021;102:2394&#x2013;2411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, et al. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Health 2021;6:e005427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo D, Mei B, Wang P, et al. Prevalence and risk factors for persistent symptoms after COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect 2024;30:328&#x2013;335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F, Tomasoni D, Falcinella C, et al. Female gender is associated with long COVID syndrome: a prospective cohort study. Clin Microbiol Infect 2022;28:611.e9&#x2013;611.e16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellan M, Baricich A, Patrucco F, et al. Long-term sequelae are highly prevalent one year after hospitalization for severe COVID-19. Sci Rep 2021;11:22666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med 2021;27:626&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond) 2021;53:737&#x2013;754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker JH, Vannorsdall TD, Weisenbach SL. Evaluation of post-COVID-19 cognitive dysfunction: recommendations for researchers. JAMA Psychiatry 2023;80:1085&#x2013;1086.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns KE, Duffett M, Kho ME, et al. A guide for the design and conduct of self-administered surveys of clinicians. CMAJ 2008;179:245&#x2013;252.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>