<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37698148</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2702</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Emotional, mental health and physical symptom experience of patients hospitalized with COVID-19 up to 3 months post-hospitalization: A longitudinal study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>591</StartPage><EndPage>605</EndPage><MedlinePgn>591-605</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocn.16880</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To explore emotional, mental health and physical symptoms up to 3 months after discharge for adults hospitalized with COVID-19.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">10%-30% of adults with COVID-19 experience physical and psychological symptoms 3&#x2009;months or more following infection. Knowing symptoms can help direct early intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">A longitudinal descriptive design to study COVID-related symptoms 2&#x2009;weeks, 6&#x2009;weeks and 3 months after hospitalization.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Sixty-six patients were recruited from a hospital system in Midwestern US (October 2020-May 2021). Participants self-reported demographics, hospital and post discharge symptoms, PROMIS measures (depression, anxiety, fatigue, cognitive function, satisfaction social roles, sleep disturbance) and Impact of Event Scale-Revised (IES-R). Hospital length of stay, comorbidities, lowest oxygen saturation, respiratory support and resources used were collected. Descriptive and nonparametric statistics described the sample and identified correlations between variables. The STROBE checklist was used.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Data from 1 (T1) and 3 months (T2) post discharge were analysed (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;52). A majority were female, white and married; 96% experienced &#x2265;1 COVID-related symptoms at T1; 85% at T2. Fatigue was most prevalent, followed by shortness of breath, muscle weakness and foggy thinking. More physical symptoms during hospitalization correlated positively with number of symptoms at T1 and T2; a majority stated these impacted their normal routine 'somewhat' or 'a lot'. T1 depression highly correlated with all T2 PROMIS and IES-R scores and number of physical symptoms. More symptoms at T1 were associated with worse fatigue, lower cognitive function and lower satisfaction with social roles at T2.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study adds to the growing knowledge of mental, physical and emotional symptoms and relationships between these early after hospitalization with COVID-19.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RELEVANCE TO CLINICAL PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Findings can help identify holistic nursing interventions to improve health and mitigate symptoms for people with long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENT OR PUBLIC CONTRIBUTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patients contributed via study participation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Journal of Clinical Nursing published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tracy</LastName><ForeName>Mary Fran</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9186-2332</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Minnesota School of Nursing, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hagstrom</LastName><ForeName>Sandy</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>M Health Fairview, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathiason</LastName><ForeName>Michelle</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Minnesota School of Nursing, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wente</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>M Health Fairview, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lindquist</LastName><ForeName>Ruth</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Minnesota School of Nursing, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>UL1TR002494</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1TR002494</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9207302</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0962-1067</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008603" MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000359" MajorTopicYN="N">Aftercare</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010351" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Discharge</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006760" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitalization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emotions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">longitudinal studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">symptoms</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37698148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.16880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Albu, S., Zozaya, N. R., Murillo, N., Garc&#xed;a-Molina, A., Chac&#xf3;n, C. A. F., &amp; Kumru, H. (2021). What's going on following acute COVID-19? Clinical characteristics of patients in an out-patient rehabilitation program. NeuroRehabilitation, 48(4), 469-480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asukai, N., Kato, H., Kawamura, N., Kim, Y., Yamamoto, K., Kishimoto, J., Miyake, Y., &amp; Nishizono-Maher, A. (2002). Reliability and validity of the Japanese-language version of the impact of event scale-revised (IES-R-J). Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease, 190(3), 175-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach, K. (2022). New data shows long Covid is keeping as many as 4 million people out of work. Brookings. https://www.brookings.edu/research/new-data-shows-long-covid-is-keeping-as-many-as-4-million-people-out-of-work/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey, E. K., Steward, K. A., VandenBussche Jantz, A. B., Kamper, J. E., Mahoney, E. J., &amp; Duchnick, J. J. (2021). Neuropsychology of COVID-19: Anticipated cognitive and mental health outcomes. Neuropsychology, 35(4), 335-351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellan, M., Baricich, A., Patrucco, F., Zeppegno, P., Gramaglia, C., Balbo, P. E., Carriero, A., Amico, C. S., Avanzi, G. C., Barini, M., Battaglia, M., Bor, S., Cantaluppi, V., Cappellano, G., Ceruti, F., Chiocchetti, A., Clivati, E., Giordano, M., Cuneo, D., &#x2026; Pirisi, M. (2021). Long-term sequelae are highly prevalent one year after hospitalization for severe COVID-19. Scientific Reports, 11(1), 1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergman, J., Ballin, M., Nordstr&#xf6;m, A., &amp; Nordstr&#xf6;m, P. (2021). Risk factors for COVID-19 diagnosis, hospitalization, and subsequent all-cause mortality in Sweden: A nationwide study. European Journal of Epidemiology, 36(3), 287-298. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10654-021-00732-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bienvenu, O. J., Williams, J. B., Yang, B. S., Hopkins, R. O., &amp; Needham, D. M. (2013). Posttraumatic stress disorder in survivors of acute lung injury: Evaluating the impact of event scale-revised. Chest, 144(1), 24-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, S. M., Bose, S., Banner- Goodspeed, V., Beesley, S. J., Dinglas, V. D., Hopkins, R. O., Jackson, J. C., Mir-Kasimov, M., Needham, D. M., &amp; Sevin, C. M. (2019). Approaches to addressing post intensive care syndrome among intensive care unit survivors. Annals of the American Thoracic Society, 16(8), 947-956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull-Otterson, L., Baca, S., Saydah, S., Boehmer, T. K., Adjei, S., Gray, S., &amp; Harris, A. M. (2022). Post-COVID conditions among adult COVID-19 survivors aged 18-64 and &#x2265;65&#x2009;years-United States, March 2020-November 2021. Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report, 71(21), 713-717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. (2021). COVID-19 interim guidance on evaluating and caring for patients with post-COVID conditions. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-index.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, C., Haupert, S. R., Zimmermann, L., Shi, X., Fritsche, L. G., &amp; Mukherjee, B. (2022). Global prevalence of post COVID-19 condition or long COVID: A meta-analysis and systematic review. The Journal of Infectious Diseases, 226(9), 1593-1607. https://doi.org/10.1093/infdis/jiac136</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creamer, M., Bell, R., &amp; Failla, S. (2003). Psychometric properties of the impact of event scale-revised. Behaviour Research and Therapy, 41(12), 1489-1496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dziadzko, V., Dziadzko, M. A., Johnson, M. M., Gajic, O., &amp; Karnatovskaia, L. V. (2017). Acute psychological trauma in the critically ill: Patient and family perspectives. General Hospital Psychiatry, 47, 68-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff, D., Sun, A., Ssentongo, A. E., Ba, D. M., Parsons, N., Poudel, G. R., Lekoubou, A., Oh, J. S., Ericson, J. E., Ssentongo, P., &amp; Chinchilli, V. M. (2021). Short-term and long-term rates of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: A systematic review. JAMA Network Open, 4(10), e2128568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamdan, M., Badrasawi, M., Zidan, S., Sayarah, A., Zahra, L. A., Dana, S., &amp; Almasry, T. (2021). Risk factors associated with hospitalization owing to COVID-19: A cross-sectional study in Palestine. Journal of International Medical Research, 49(12), 3000605211064405. https://doi.org/10.1177/03000605211064405</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanmer, J., Jensen, R. E., &amp; Rothrock, N. (2020). A reporting checklist for HealthMeasures' patient-reported outcomes: ASCQ-me, neuro-QoL, NIH toolbox, and PROMIS. Journal of Patient-Reported Outcomes, 4(1), 1-7. https://doi.org/10.1186/s41687-020-0176-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, P. A., Taylor, R., Thielke, R., Payne, J., Gonzalez, N., &amp; Conde, J. G. (2009). Research electronic data capture (REDCap): A metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. Journal of Biomedical Informatics, 42(2), 377-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HealthMeasures. (2020). PROMIS measure development and research. http://www.healthmeasures.net/explore-measurement-systems/promis/measure-development-research</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heydon, E., Wibrow, B., Jacques, A., Sonawane, R., &amp; Anstey, M. (2020). The needs of patients with post-intensive care syndrome: A prospective, observational study. Australian Critical Care, 33, 116-122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamura, N., Yoshiharu, K., &amp; Nozomu, A. (2001). Suppression of cellular immunity in men with a past history of post traumatic stress disorder. American Journal of Psychiatry, 158, 484-486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon, S., Wegman-Ostrosky, T., Perelman, C., Sepulveda, R., Rebolledo, P. A., Cuapio, A., &amp; Villapol, S. (2021). More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Scientific Reports, 11(1), 16144. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McSpedon, C. (2022). Long COVID: What we know now. American Journal of Nursing, 122(7), 20-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering and Medicine. (2022a). Caring for people with serious illnesses: Lessons learned from the COVID-19 pandemic: Proceedings of a workshop. The National Academies Press. https://doi.org/10.17226/26596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering and Medicine. (2022b). Long COVID: Examining long-term health effects of COVID-19 and implications for the Social Security Administration: Proceedings of a workshop. The National Academies Press. https://doi.org/10.17226/26619</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker, A. M., Brigham, E., Connolly, B., McPeake, J., Agranovich, A. V., Kenes, M. T., Casey, K., Reynolds, C., Schmidt, K. F. R., Kim, S. Y., Kaplin, A., Sevin, C. M., Brodsky, M. B., &amp; Turnbull, A. E. (2021). Addressing the post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: A multidisciplinary model of care. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine, 9(11), 1328-1341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto, M. D., Owens, C. A., Lamber, N., &amp; Burton, C. W. (2021). How an effective response to post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) relies on nursing research. Research in Nursing &amp; Health, 44, 743-745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stam, H. J., Stucki, G., Bickenbach, J. (2020). COVID-19 and post intensive care syndrome: A call for action. Journal of Rehabilitation Medicine, 52, jrm00044. https://doi.org/10.2340/16501977-2677</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Survivor Corps. (2021). Post-COVID care: Guidelines for multidisciplinary care centers. https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5e8b5f63562c031c16e36a93/t/605a8a3262f0191b99584df0/1616546355297/PCCC+Standard+of+Practice+3_23.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Survivor Corps. (2022). Post-COVID care centers (PCCC). https://www.survivorcorps.com/pccc</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasilewski, M. B., Cimino, S. R., Kokorelias, K. M., Simpson, R., Hitzig, S. L., &amp; Robinson, L. (2022). Providing rehabilitation to patients recovering from COVID-19: A scoping review. PM&amp;R, 14, 239-258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weerahandi, H., Hochman, K. A., Simon, E., Blaum, C., Chodosh, J., Duan, E., Garry, K., Kahan, T., Karmen-Tuohy, S. L., Karpel, H. C., Mendoza, F., Prete, A. M., Quintana, L., Rutishauser, J., Martinez, L. S., Shah, K., Sharma, S., Simon, E., Stimiman, A. Z., &amp; Horwitz, L. I. (2021). Post-discharge health status and symptoms in patients with severe COVID-19. Journal of General Internal Medicine, 36(3), 738-745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss, D. S., &amp; Marmar, C. D. (1997). The impact of event scale-revised. In J. P. Wilson &amp; T. M. Keane (Eds.), Assessing psychological trauma and PTSD: A practitioner's handbook (pp. 399-411). Guilford Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (n.d.). WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard. https://covid19.who.int/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (WHO). (2021). A clinical definition of post COVID-19 conditions by Delphi consensus. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo, S. M., Liu, T. C., Motwani, Y., Sim, M. S., Viswanathan, N., Samras, N., Hsu, F., &amp; Wenger, N. S. (2022). Factors associated with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (PASC) after diagnosis of symptomatic COVID-19 in the inpatient and outpatient setting in a diverse cohort. Journal of General Internal Medicine, 37, 1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, F., Yu, T., Du, R., Fan, G., Liu, Y., Liu, Z., Xiang, J., Wang, Y., Song, B., Gu, X., Guan, L., Wei, Y., Li, H., Wu, X., Xu, J., Tu, S., Zhang, Y., Chen, H., &amp; Cao, B. (2020). Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: A retrospective cohort study. The Lancet, 395(10229), 1054-1062. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30566-3</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>