<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38394160</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2767-3375</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PLOS global public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLOS Glob Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long-term psychological impact of the pandemic COVID-19: Identification of high-risk groups and assessment of precautionary measures five months after the first wave of restrictions was lifted.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0002847</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0002847</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0002847</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pgph.0002847</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Critical facets of our lives have been disrupted by the COVID-19 outbreak for almost three years. During this time, there has been a lot of clinical and research interest in issues related to mental health. However, few have examined the pandemic's long-term psychological effects. The aims of the present study were to assess the long-term psychological impact of the pandemic COVID -19, five months after the first wave restriction measures were lifted, to identify high-risk groups and to address the use of precautionary measures (PM). Information about sociodemographic characteristics, mental health, coping mechanisms, and compliance with precautionary measures (PM) were all gathered in Cyprus through an anonymous online survey. The poll was completed by 1128 people (73% of whom were female). For the purposes of the present study, descriptive statistics and structural equation modeling were used. 32.3% of participants experienced moderate-to-severe anxiety symptoms, where 16.4% and 23% reported moderate-to-severe depression and post-traumatic stress symptoms respectively. Lower levels of anxiety, depression, and post-traumatic stress symptoms as well as greater compliance to PM were linked to higher levels of resilience. Additionally, subgroups of participants, at a higher risk for negative psychological effects were identified, such as women and young adults. Our findings demonstrate the long-lasting effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on mental health and provide guidance on how to deal with similar situations. It also raises questions about the concurrent effects on people with the long COVID syndrome.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2024 Solomou et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solomou</LastName><ForeName>Ioulia</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Cyprus, Nicosia, Cyprus.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Applied Neuroscience, University of Cyprus, Nicosia, Cyprus.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nikolaou</LastName><ForeName>Flora</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Cyprus, Nicosia, Cyprus.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Applied Neuroscience, University of Cyprus, Nicosia, Cyprus.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michaelides</LastName><ForeName>Michalis P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6314-3680</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Cyprus, Nicosia, Cyprus.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Constantinidou</LastName><ForeName>Fofi</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7928-8363</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Cyprus, Nicosia, Cyprus.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Applied Neuroscience, University of Cyprus, Nicosia, Cyprus.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLOS Glob Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918283779606676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2767-3375</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>We, the authors, declare that there are no competing interests related to this research.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38394160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10889631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0002847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PGPH-D-23-00723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abayomi A, Odukoya O, Osibogun A, Wright O, Adebayo B, Balogun M, et al.. Presenting symptoms and predictors of poor outcomes among 2,184 patients with COVID-19 in Lagos State, Nigeria. International Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2021. Jan 1;102:226&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2020.10.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2020.10.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7566672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33075534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri L, Vanacore N, Donfrancesco C, Lo Noce C, Canevelli M, Punzo O, et al.. Clinical characteristics of hospitalized individuals dying with COVID-19 by age group in Italy. The Journals of Gerontology: Series A. 2020. Sep;75(9):1796&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7314182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32506122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin D, Friedman DB, Qiao S, Tam CC, Li X, Li X. Information uncertainty: a correlate for acute stress disorder during the COVID-19 outbreak in China. BMC Public Health. 2020. Dec;20:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33287780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomou I, Constantinidou F. Prevalence and predictors of anxiety and depression symptoms during the COVID-19 pandemic and compliance with precautionary measures: age and sex matter. International journal of environmental research and public health. 2020. Jul;17(14):4924. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17144924</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17144924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7400373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32650522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolakowsky-Hayner SA, Goldin Y, Kingsley K, Alzueta E, Arango-Lasprilla JC, Perrin PB, et al.. Psychosocial impacts of the COVID-19 quarantine: A study of gender differences in 59 countries. Medicina. 2021. Jul 31;57(8):789. doi: 10.3390/medicina57080789</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina57080789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8400641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34440995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolakowsky-Hayner SA, Shen J, Goldin Y, Kingsley K, Alzueta E, Arango-Lasprilla JC, et al.. The COVID-19 pandemic: Age differences in sleep quality and mental health across 59 Countries. Age. 2021;18(29):22&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shreffler J, Petrey J, Huecker M. The impact of COVID-19 on healthcare worker wellness: a scoping review. Western Journal of Emergency Medicine. 2020. Sep;21(5):1059. doi: 10.5811/westjem.2020.7.48684</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5811/westjem.2020.7.48684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7514392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32970555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan BY, Chew NW, Lee GK, Jing M, Goh Y, Yeo LL, et al.. Psychological impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on health care workers in Singapore. Annals of internal medicine. 2020. Aug 18;173(4):317&#x2013;20. doi: 10.7326/M20-1083</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M20-1083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7143149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saurabh K, Ranjan S. Compliance and psychological impact of quarantine in children and adolescents due to Covid-19 pandemic. The Indian Journal of Pediatrics. 2020. Jul;87:532&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1007/s12098-020-03347-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12098-020-03347-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7257353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32472347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browning MH, Larson LR, Sharaievska I, Rigolon A, McAnirlin O, Mullenbach L, et al.. Psychological impacts from COVID-19 among university students: Risk factors across seven states in the United States. PloS one. 2021. Jan 7;16(1):e0245327. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0245327</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0245327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7790395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33411812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao W, Fang Z, Hou G, Han M, Xu X, Dong J, et al.. The psychological impact of the COVID-19 epidemic on college students in China. Psychiatry research. 2020. May 1;287:112934. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2020.112934</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2020.112934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32229390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Hegde S, Son C, Keller B, Smith A, Sasangohar F. Investigating mental health of US college students during the COVID-19 pandemic: Cross-sectional survey study. Journal of medical Internet research. 2020. Sep 17;22(9):e22817. doi: 10.2196/22817</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/22817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7505693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32897868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serafini G, Parmigiani B, Amerio A, Aguglia A, Sher L, Amore M. The psychological impact of COVID-19 on the mental health in the general population.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7337855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32569360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aus&#xed;n B, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Sanguino C, Castellanos M&#xc1;, Mu&#xf1;oz M. Gender-related differences in the psychological impact of confinement as a consequence of COVID-19 in Spain. Journal of Gender Studies. 2021. Jan 2;30(1):29&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Sanguino C, Aus&#xed;n B, Castellanos M&#xc1;, Saiz J, L&#xf3;pez-G&#xf3;mez A, Ugidos C, et al.. Mental health consequences during the initial stage of the 2020 Coronavirus pandemic (COVID-19) in Spain. Brain, behavior, and immunity. 2020. Jul 1;87:172&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2020.05.040</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2020.05.040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7219372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32405150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Pan R, Wan X, Tan Y, Xu L, Ho CS, et al.. Immediate psychological responses and associated factors during the initial stage of the 2019 coronavirus disease (COVID-19) epidemic among the general population in China. International journal of environmental research and public health. 2020. Mar;17(5):1729. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17051729</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17051729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7084952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32155789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Losada-Baltar A, Jim&#xe9;nez-Gonzalo L, Gallego-Alberto L, Pedroso-Chaparro MD, Fernandes-Pires J, M&#xe1;rquez-Gonz&#xe1;lez M. &#x201c;We are staying at home.&#x201d; Association of self-perceptions of aging, personal and family resources, and loneliness with psychological distress during the lock-down period of COVID-19. The Journals of Gerontology: Series B. 2021. Feb;76(2):e10&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1093/geronb/gbaa048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/geronb/gbaa048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32282920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otu A, Charles CH, Yaya S. Mental health and psychosocial well-being during the COVID-19 pandemic: The invisible elephant in the room. International journal of mental health systems. 2020. Dec;14:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7257210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32514302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao H, Chen JH, Xu YF. Patients with mental health disorders in the COVID-19 epidemic.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7269717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32199510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar N, Kar B, Kar S. Stress and coping during COVID-19 pandemic: Result of an online survey. Psychiatry research. 2021. Jan 1;295:113598. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113598</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7688436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33264677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margeti&#x107; B, Peraica T, Stojanovi&#x107; K, Ivanec D. Predictors of emotional distress during the COVID-19 pandemic; a Croatian study. Personality and individual differences. 2021. Jun 1;175:110691. doi: 10.1016/j.paid.2021.110691</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.paid.2021.110691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33518867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prowse R, Sherratt F, Abizaid A, Gabrys RL, Hellemans KG, Patterson ZR, et al.. Coping with the COVID-19 pandemic: examining gender differences in stress and mental health among university students. Frontiers in psychiatry. 2021. Apr 7;12:650759. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2021.650759</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2021.650759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8058407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33897499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shechter A, Diaz F, Moise N, Anstey DE, Ye S, Agarwal S, et al.. Psychological distress, coping behaviors, and preferences for support among New York healthcare workers during the COVID-19 pandemic. General hospital psychiatry. 2020. Sep 1;66:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2020.06.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2020.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7297159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32590254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volk AA, Brazil KJ, Franklin-Luther P, Dane AV, Vaillancourt T. The influence of demographics and personality on COVID-19 coping in young adults. Personality and individual differences. 2021. Jan 1;168:110398. doi: 10.1016/j.paid.2020.110398</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.paid.2020.110398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7492069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32952250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou F. Fengying Bi, Rong Jiao, Dan Luo, and Kangxing Song. 2020. Gender differences of depression and anxiety among social media users during the COVID-19 outbreak in China: a cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health.;20(1):1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7609822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33148202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman LR, Kwok KO, Redd RE, Yi YY, Ward H, Wei WI, et al.. Public perceptions and preventive behaviours during the early phase of the COVID-19 pandemic: a comparative study between Hong Kong and the United Kingdom. MedRxiv. 2020. Aug 7:2020&#x2013;08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7942393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33539309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodas M, Peleg K. Self-isolation compliance in the covid-19 era influenced by compensation: Findings from a recent survey in israel: Public attitudes toward the covid-19 outbreak and self-isolation: a cross sectional study of the adult population of israel. Health Affairs. 2020. Jun 1;39(6):936&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32271627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. WHO COVID-19 Dashboard [Internet]. World Health Organisation.
2022. Available from: https://covid19.who.int</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourmistrova NW, Solomon T, Braude P, Strawbridge R, Carter B. Long-term effects of COVID-19 on mental health: A systematic review. Journal of affective disorders. 2022. Feb 15;299:118&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2021.11.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2021.11.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8758130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34798148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patridge EF, Bardyn TP. Research electronic data capture (REDCap). Journal of the Medical Library Association: JMLA. 2018. Jan;106(1):142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JB, L&#xf6;we B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Archives of internal medicine. 2006. May 22;166(10):1092&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16717171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;we B, Decker O, M&#xfc;ller S, Br&#xe4;hler E, Schellberg D, Herzog W, et al.. Validation and standardization of the Generalized Anxiety Disorder Screener (GAD-7) in the general population. Medical care. 2008. Mar 1:266&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1097/MLR.0b013e318160d093</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MLR.0b013e318160d093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18388841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;we B, Un&#xfc;tzer J, Callahan CM, Perkins AJ, Kroenke K. Monitoring depression treatment outcomes with the patient health questionnaire-9. Medical care. 2004. Dec 1:1194&#x2013;201. doi: 10.1097/00005650-200412000-00006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005650-200412000-00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15550799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocalevent RD, Hinz A, Br&#xe4;hler E. Standardization of the depression screener patient health questionnaire (PHQ-9) in the general population. General hospital psychiatry. 2013. Sep 1;35(5):551&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2013.04.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2013.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23664569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanaken L, Scheveneels S, Belmans E, Hermans D. Validation of the impact of event scale with modifications for COVID-19 (IES-COVID19). Frontiers in psychiatry. 2020. Jul 28;11:738. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2020.00738</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2020.00738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7399230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32848918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinclair VG, Wallston KA. The development and psychometric evaluation of the Brief Resilient Coping Scale. Assessment. 2004. Mar;11(1):94&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1177/1073191103258144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1073191103258144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14994958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahariadis N, Exadaktylos T, Sparf J, Petridou E, Kyriakidis A, Papadopoulos I. Assessing the effectiveness of public health interventions for Covid&#x2010;19 in Greece and Cyprus. European Policy Analysis. 2022. Sep;8(3):345&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1002/epa2.1153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/epa2.1153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9349912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35942067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomou I, Constantinidou F, Karekla M, Psaltis C, Chatzittofis A. The COVID-19 international student well-being study (C-19 ISWS). European Journal of Psychology Open. 2021. Oct 5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob L, Haro JM, Koyanagi A. Relationship between living alone and common mental disorders in the 1993, 2000 and 2007 National Psychiatric Morbidity Surveys. PloS one. 2019. May 1;14(5):e0215182. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0215182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0215182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6493731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31042720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xe4;nnlund A, Hammarstr&#xf6;m A. Higher education and psychological distress: a 27-year prospective cohort study in Sweden. Scandinavian journal of public health. 2014. Mar;42(2):155&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1177/1403494813511559</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1403494813511559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24265167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murasko JE. A lifecourse study on education and health: The relationship between childhood psychosocial resources and outcomes in adolescence and young adulthood. Social Science Research. 2007. Dec 1;36(4):1348&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konstantinou N, Nicolaou SA, Petrou C, Pieri M. Trust in authorities and demographic factors affect vaccine acceptance during the COVID-19 pandemic in Cyprus. European Journal of Psychology Open. 2021. Sep 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonovsky A, Danon R, Schiff M, Shelef L. Predicting mental burnout among Israeli Home Front Command soldiers during the COVID-19 pandemic. Health Promotion International. 2022. Apr;37(2):daab036. doi: 10.1093/heapro/daab036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapro/daab036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8344459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34279594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendau A, Petzold MB, Pyrkosch L, Mascarell Maricic L, Betzler F, Rogoll J, et al.. Associations between COVID-19 related media consumption and symptoms of anxiety, depression and COVID-19 related fear in the general population in Germany. European archives of psychiatry and clinical neuroscience. 2021. Mar;271:283&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1007/s00406-020-01171-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00406-020-01171-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7371788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32691135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao N, Zhou G. Social media use and mental health during the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic: Moderator role of disaster stressor and mediator role of negative affect. Applied Psychology: Health and Well&#x2010;Being. 2020. Dec;12(4):1019&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1111/aphw.12226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aphw.12226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32945123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu J, Shen B, Zhao M, Wang Z, Xie B, Xu Y. A nationwide survey of psychological distress among Chinese people in the COVID-19 epidemic: implications and policy recommendations. General psychiatry. 2020;33(2). doi: 10.1136/gpsych-2020-100213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gpsych-2020-100213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7061893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y, Qin W, Wang Z, Yang F. Factors influencing social distancing to prevent the community spread of COVID-19 among Chinese adults. Preventive Medicine. 2021. Feb 1;143:106385. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2020.106385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2020.106385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7774485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei X, Xiao YT, Wang J, Chen R, Zhang W, Yang Y, et al.. Sex differences in severity and mortality among patients with COVID-19: evidence from pooled literature analysis and insights from integrated bioinformatic analysis. arXiv preprint arXiv:2003.13547. 2020. Mar 30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong KK, Chen JH, Yu EW, Wu AM. Adherence to COVID&#x2010;19 precautionary measures: Applying the health belief model and generalised social beliefs to a probability community sample. Applied Psychology: Health and Well&#x2010;Being. 2020. Dec;12(4):1205&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1111/aphw.12230</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aphw.12230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33010119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan AK, Nickson CP, Rudolph JW, Lee A, Joynt GM. Social media for rapid knowledge dissemination: early experience from the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic. Anaesthesia. 2020. Dec;75(12):1579. doi: 10.1111/anae.15057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32227594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li LZ, Wang S. Prevalence and predictors of general psychiatric disorders and loneliness during COVID-19 in the United Kingdom. Psychiatry research. 2020. Sep 1;291:113267. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113267</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7326403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32623266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullana MA, Hidalgo-Mazzei D, Vieta E, Radua J. Coping behaviors associated with decreased anxiety and depressive symptoms during the COVID-19 pandemic and lockdown. Journal of Affective Disorders. 2020. Oct 1;275:80&#x2013;1. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2020.06.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2020.06.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7329680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32658829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barzilay R, Moore TM, Greenberg DM, DiDomenico GE, Brown LA, White LK, et al.. Resilience, COVID-19-related stress, anxiety and depression during the pandemic in a large population enriched for healthcare providers. Translational psychiatry. 2020. Aug 20;10(1):291. doi: 10.1038/s41398-020-00982-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-020-00982-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7439246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32820171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>