<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36120804</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-2165</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cosmetic dermatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cosmet Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Future perspective safe cosmetics: Focused on associated with ISO natural organic index.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6619</StartPage><EndPage>6627</EndPage><MedlinePgn>6619-6627</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocd.15398</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">As we enter the era of long COVID, recent studies on the relationship between coronavirus disease-19 (COVID-19) and skin are being conducted from various angles. Awareness of the safety of healthy skin is increasing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Therefore, in this study, we empirically analyzed safe cosmetics, natural cosmetics, and organic cosmetics, which have recently become a critical issue.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Keywords such as 'long COVID', 'COVID-19 Skin', 'ISO Natural Organic Index', 'edible', 'safe cosmetics', 'natural cosmetics', and 'organic cosmetics' were searched and created. This study was conducted using PubMed, Google Scholar, Riss, Scopus, and ResearchGate. Accordingly, a total of 689 papers were studied. This paper was successfully completed using a total of 41 references in this study using PRISMA flow diagram.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In the long COVID era, customers in the beauty and cosmetics market will have to apply ISO natural organic ingredients to the cosmetics and beauty industry, reflecting consumer demand for edible ingredients for safety issues. Therefore, it will be able to provide new strategy and implications for a safer cosmetic market that values health and beauty.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Therefore, in this literature review, interest in skin has increased due to the long corona, and it was determined that changes in the cosmetic market would be necessary by using the ISO natural organic index for the consumer's desire for healthy skin. Therefore, in this article, in the future development of eco-friendly organic cosmetics, in line with the natural and environment-friendly changes reminiscent of the efficacy or ingredients of products, it is necessary to develop cosmetics using the ISO natural organic index that meets the needs of consumers and a differentiated strategy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jinkyung</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Beauty Arts Care, Department of Beauty Arts Care, Graduate School, Dongguk University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Beauty and Health Care, Namseoul University, Cheonan, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwon</LastName><ForeName>Ki Han</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of General Education, Kookmin University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Cosmet Dermatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101130964</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1473-2130</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003358">Cosmetics</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003358" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cosmetics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012867" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ISO natural organic index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cosmetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">edible</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">safe</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36120804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocd.15398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, et al. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6(9):e005427. doi:10.1136/bmjgh-2021-005427 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH, Crooks MG. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;199(2):113-119. doi:10.1007/s00408-021-00423-z Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbarialiabad H, Taghrir MH, Abdollahi A, et al. Long COVID, a comprehensive systematic scoping review. Infection. 2021;49(6):1163-1186. doi:10.1007/s15010-021-01666-x Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M. Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nat Immunol. 2022;23(2):194-202. doi:10.1038/s41590-021-01104-y Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR, Arnold AC, Barboi A, et al. American autonomic society. Long-COVID postural tachycardia syndrome: an American autonomic society statement. Clin Auton Res. 2021;31(3):365-368. doi:10.1007/s10286-021-00798-2 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wollina U, Karada&#x11f; AS, Rowland-Payne C, Chiriac A, Lotti T. Cutaneous signs in COVID-19 patients: a review. Dermatol Ther. 2020;33(5):e13549. doi:10.1111/dth.13549 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VOAKorea. WHO confirms more than 200 cases of monkeypox in 20 countries. https://www.voakorea.com/a/6593342.html. Accessed 2022.5.28. [Dataset].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang J. A study on the ingredients and efficacy of natural cosmetics. J Korean Soc Beauty art. 2008;6(1):5-26. Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kwon KH. Sustainable changes in beauty market trends focused on the perspective of safety in the post-coronavirus disease-19 period. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2022;21(7):2700-2707. doi:10.1111/jocd.14493 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heo K. Quality Foundation, ISO 16128 (natural/Organic Cosmetic Ingredients &amp; Cosmetics) Conformity Confirmation. 2020. Cosmorning. https://www.cosmorning.com/news/article.html?no=36602. Accessed 2020.05.03. [Dataset].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S. Regulations of organic cosmetics in Europe. Korean J Aesthet Cosmet Soc. 2013;11(6):1023-1032. Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi E. A study on changes in cosmetic policy associated with the enactment and revision of cosmetics act. J Korean Soc Nail Beauty. 2019;7(1):47-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K. Revision of cosmetics labeling and advertisement management guidelines. EZCOS. http://www.ezcos.co.kr/sub/customer/notice.asp?mode=view&amp;bid=1&amp;s_type=&amp;s_keyword=&amp;s_cate=&amp;idx=20830&amp;page=1. Accessed 2022.01.03. [Dataset].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV, Jayadevan R, Sashidharan S. Long COVID: an overview. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15(3):869-875. doi:10.1016/j.dsx.2021.04.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648. doi:10.1136/bmj.n1648 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon DE, Gallman AE, Hruza GJ, et al. Long COVID in the skin: a registry analysis of COVID-19 dermatological duration. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21(3):313-314. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30986-5 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak N, Peng W, Naegeli MC, et al. SARS-CoV-2, COVID-19, skin and immunology - What do we know so far? Allergy. 2021;76(3):698-713. doi:10.1111/all.14498 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, Bunker CB, Ciurtin C, et al. Chilblain-like acral lesions in long COVID-19: management and implications for understanding microangiopathy. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21(7):912. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00133-X Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cazzato G, Mazzia G, Cimmino A, et al. SARS-CoV-2 and skin: the pathologist's point of view. Biomolecules. 2021;11(6):838. doi:10.3390/biom11060838 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tammaro A, Parisella FR, Adebanjo GAR. Cutaneous long COVID. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2021;20(8):2378-2379. doi:10.1111/jocd.14291 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim H, Shine J. Purchasing decision factors and logotype status of natural and organic cosmetics -focusing on the baby cosmetics. Treatise Plast Media. 2016;19(4):201-209. Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J. Accelerating the establishment of standards for organic cosmetics. Tech Standard. 2010;101:24-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi S, Son S. Analysis of COSMOS-standard AISBL and Korean organic cosmetics standards. Korea J Org Agricu. 2015;23(1):1-18. Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaliyadan F, Al Dhafiri M, Aatif M. Attitudes toward organic cosmetics: a cross-sectional population-based survey from the Middle East. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2021;20(8):2552-2555. doi:10.1111/jocd.13909 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias R, Oliveira H, Fernandes I, Simal-Gandara J, Perez-Gregorio R. Recent advances in extracting phenolic compounds from food and their use in disease prevention and as cosmetics. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2021;61(7):1130-1151. doi:10.1080/10408398.2020.1754162 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taribagil P, Creer D, Tahir H. Long COVID' syndrome. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14(4):e241485. doi:10.1136/bcr-2020-241485 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zag&#xf3;rska-Dziok M, Ziemlewska A, Bujak T, Nizio&#x142;-&#x141;ukaszewska Z, Hordyjewicz-Baran Z. Cosmetic and dermatological properties of selected ayurvedic plant extracts. Molecules. 2021;26(3):614. doi:10.3390/molecules26030614 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aburjai T, Natsheh FM. Plants used in cosmetics. Phytother Res. 2003;17(9):987-1000. doi:10.1002/ptr.1363 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kwon KH. Good ingredients from foods to vegan cosmetics after COVID-19 pandemic. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2022;21(8):3190-3199. doi:10.1111/jocd.15028 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jae S, Kim J. A study on consumer awareness and use of organic cosmetics. Korean Soc Cosmet Cosmetol. 2015;5(2):151-160. Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kwon KH. Changes in the use of cosmetics worldwide due to increased use of masks in the coronavirus disease-19 pandemic. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2022;21(7):2708-2712. doi:10.1111/jocd.14515 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Lim C. A study on package design and illustration for eco-friendly organic cosmetics. Illus Forum. 2012;13(32):15-26. Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim B. A study on purchasing factors for organic cosmetics and packaging design colors. Illus Forum. 2016;17(47):71-80. Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pi B, Choi D, Park S, Nam J, Kim Y, Han S. Development of oleanolic acid solubilization formulation using natural hydrogenated lecithin. J Korean Soc Cosmet. 2011;37(4):289-295. Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, et al. TLC study group. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med. 2021;114(9):428-442. doi:10.1177/01410768211032850 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai AD, Lavelle M, Boursiquot BC, Wan EY. Long-term complications of COVID-19. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2022;322(1):C1-C11. doi:10.1152/ajpcell.00375.2021 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galli E, Cipriani F, Ricci G, Maiello N. Cutaneous manifestation during COVID-19 pandemic. Pediatr Allergy Immunol. 2020;31 Suppl 26(Suppl 26):89-91. doi:10.1111/pai.13384 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gisondi P, Piaserico S, Bordin C, Alaibac M, Girolomoni G, Naldi L. Cutaneous manifestations of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a clinical update. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2020;34(11):2499-2504. doi:10.1111/jdv.16774 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VOAKorea. The spread of monkeypox&#x2026; Confirmed in 12 countries. https://www.voakorea.com/a/who-expects-more-cases-of-monkeypox-to-emerge-globally/6584415.html. Accessed 2022.5.28. [Dataset].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Camargo AC, Schwember AR, Parada R, et al. Opinion on the hurdles and potential health benefits in value-added use of plant food processing by-products as sources of phenolic compounds. Int J Mol Sci. 2018;19(11):3498. doi:10.3390/ijms19113498 Dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagbo IJ, Mbeng WO. Are plants used in the eastern cape province for cosmetics fully commercialized? Indian J Pharmacol. 2019;51(3):140-149. doi:10.4103/ijp.IJP_262_18 Dataset.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>