<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37726566</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1076</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>183</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of the COVID-19 pandemic on the pediatric infectious disease landscape.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1001</StartPage><EndPage>1009</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1001-1009</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00431-023-05210-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This narrative review aims to present an overview of the COVID-19 pandemic's effects on the landscape of pediatric infectious diseases. While COVID-19 generally results in mild symptoms and a favorable prognosis in children, the pandemic brought forth significant consequences. These included persistent symptoms among infected children ("long COVID"), a profound transformation in healthcare utilization (notably through the widespread adoption of telemedicine), and the implementation of optimization strategies within healthcare settings. Furthermore, the pandemic resulted in alterations in the circulation patterns of respiratory pathogens, including influenza, RSV, and Streptococcus pneumoniae. The possible reasons for those changes are discussed in this review. COVID-19 effect was not limited to respiratory infectious diseases, as other diseases, including urinary tract and gastrointestinal infections, have displayed decreased transmission rates, likely attributable to heightened hygiene measures and shifts in care-seeking behaviors. Finally, the disruption of routine childhood vaccination programs has resulted in reduced immunization coverage and an upsurge in vaccine hesitancy. In addition, the pandemic was associated with issues of antibiotic misuse and over-prescription.&#xa0; &#xa0; &#xa0;Conclusion: In conclusion, the COVID-19 pandemic has left a profound and multifaceted impact on the landscape of pediatric infectious diseases, ranging from the emergence of "long COVID" in children to significant changes in healthcare delivery, altered circulation patterns of various pathogens, and concerning disruptions in vaccination programs and antibiotic usage. What is Known: &#x2022;&#xa0;COVID-19 usually presents with mild symptoms in children, although severe and late manifestations are possible. &#x2022;&#xa0;The pandemic resulted in a dramatically increased use of health care services, as well as alterations in the circulation patterns of respiratory pathogens, decreased rates of other, non-respiratory, infections, disruption of routine childhood vaccination programs, and antibiotic misuse. What is New: &#x2022;&#xa0;Possible strategies to tackle future outbreaks are presented, including changes in health care services utilization, implementation of updated vaccine programs and antibiotic stewardship protocols. &#x2022;&#xa0;The decline in RSV and influenza circulation during COVID-19 was probably not primarily related to NPI measures, and rather related to other, non-NPI measures implementation, including specific pathogen-host interactions on the level of the biological niche (the nasopharynx).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shmueli</LastName><ForeName>Moshe</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Beer Sheva, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lendner</LastName><ForeName>Idan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Beer Sheva, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Department B, Soroka University Medical Center, Beer-Sheva, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ben-Shimol</LastName><ForeName>Shalom</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Beer Sheva, Israel. shalomb2@clalit.org.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Infectious Disease Unit, Soroka University Medical Center, Beer Sheva, Israel. shalomb2@clalit.org.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7603873</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0340-6199</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007252">Influenza Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007251" MajorTopicYN="Y">Influenza, Human</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073602" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antimicrobial Stewardship</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007252" MajorTopicYN="Y">Influenza Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antibiotic stewardship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthcare services</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pediatric infectious diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS&#x2011;CoV&#x2011;2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccines</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37726566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-023-05210-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00431-023-05210-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lenharo M (2023) WHO declares end to COVID-19&#x2019;s emergency phase. Nature. https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-023-01559-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/d41586-023-01559-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38102379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Bavel JJ, Baicker K, Boggio PS, Capraro V, Cichocka A, Cikara M, Crockett MJ et al (2020) Using social and behavioural science to support COVID-19 pandemic response. Nat Hum Behav 4:460&#x2013;471. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-020-0884-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41562-020-0884-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32355299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Y, Mo X, Hu Y, Qi X, Jiang F, Jiang Z, Tong S (2020) Epidemiology of COVID-19 among children in China. Pediatrics 145 https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2020-0702</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarovsky D, de Freitas FG, Zampol RM, de Oliveira TA, Farias CGA, da Silva D, Cavalcante DTG, Nery SB, de Moraes JC, de Oliveira FI, Almeida FJ, S&#xe1;fadi MAP (2023) Characteristics and clinical outcomes of COVID-19 in children: a hospital-based surveillance study in Latin America&#x2019;s hardest-hit city. IJID Reg 7:52&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijregi.2022.12.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijregi.2022.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36536932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolopoulou GB, Maltezou HC (2022) COVID-19 in children: where do we stand? Arch Med Res 53:1&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arcmed.2021.07.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arcmed.2021.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34311990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tagarro A, Epalza C, Santos M, Sanz-Santaeufemia FJ, Otheo E, Moraleda C, Calvo C (2020) Screening and severity of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in children in Madrid. JAMA Pediatr, Spain. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.1346</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.1346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zachariah P, Johnson CL, Halabi KC, Ahn D, Sen AI, Fischer A, Banker SL, Giordano M, Manice CS, Diamond R, Sewell TB, Schweickert AJ, Babineau JR, Carter RC, Fenster DB, Orange JS, McCann TA, Kernie SG, Saiman L, Columbia Pediatric C-MG (2020) Epidemiology, clinical features, and disease severity in patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in a children&#x2019;s hospital in New York City, New York. JAMA Pediatr 174:e202430. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.2430</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Curtis N (2020) Coronavirus infections in children including COVID-19: an overview of the epidemiology, clinical features, diagnosis, treatment and prevention options in children. Pediatr Infect Dis J 39:355&#x2013;368. https://doi.org/10.1097/INF.0000000000002660</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000002660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32310621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7158880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castagnoli R, Votto M, Licari A, Brambilla I, Bruno R, Perlini S, Rovida F, Baldanti F, Marseglia GL (2020) Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection in children and adolescents: a systematic review. JAMA Pediatr 174:882&#x2013;889. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.1467</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.1467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32320004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim L, Whitaker M, O'Halloran A, Kambhampati A, Chai SJ, Reingold A, Armistead I, et al. (2020) Hospitalization rates and characteristics of children aged &lt;18 years hospitalized with laboratory-confirmed COVID-19 - COVID-NET, 14 States, March 1-July 25, 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 69:1081&#x2013;1088. https://doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm6932e3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta NS, Mytton OT, Mullins EWS, Fowler TA, Falconer CL, Murphy OB, Langenberg C, Jayatunga WJP, Eddy DH, Nguyen-Van-Tam JS (2020) SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19): what do we know about children? A systematic review. Clin Infect Dis 71:2469&#x2013;2479. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciaa556</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciaa556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32392337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7239259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nachega JB, Sam-Agudu NA, Machekano RN, Rabie H, van der Zalm MM, Redfern A, Dramowski A et al (2022) Assessment of clinical outcomes among children and adolescents hospitalized with COVID-19 in 6 sub-Saharan African countries. JAMA Pediatr 176:e216436. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapediatrics.2021.6436</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Shimol S, Livni G, Megged O, Greenberg D, Danino D, Youngster I, Shachor-Meyouhas Y et al (2021) COVID-19 in a subset of hospitalized children in Israel. J Pediatric Infect Dis Soc 10:757&#x2013;765. https://doi.org/10.1093/jpids/piab035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jpids/piab035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34129032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow EJ, Englund JA (2022) Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infections in children. Infect Dis Clin North Am 36:435&#x2013;479. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.idc.2022.01.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.idc.2022.01.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35636909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8806161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarden Bilavski H, Balanson S, Damouni Shalabi R, Dabaja-Younis H, Grisaru-Soen G, Youngster I, Glikman D, Ben Shimol S, Somech E, Tasher D, Stein M, Gottesmanm G, Livni G, Megged O (2021) Benign course and clinical features of COVID-19 in hospitalised febrile infants up to 60 days old. Acta Paediatr 110:2790&#x2013;2795. https://doi.org/10.1111/apa.15993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apa.15993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34143508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8444866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua PEY, Shah SU, Gui H, Koh J, Somani J, Pang J (2021) Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of non-severe and severe pediatric and adult COVID-19 patients across different geographical regions in the early phase of pandemic: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. J Investig Med 69:1287&#x2013;1296. https://doi.org/10.1136/jim-2021-001858</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jim-2021-001858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34135068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8485127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Ayuzo Del Valle NC, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, Villapol S (2022) Long-COVID in children and adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Sci Rep 12:9950. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-13495-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-13495-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35739136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9226045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mafham MM, Spata E, Goldacre R, Gair D, Curnow P, Bray M, Hollings S, Roebuck C, Gale CP, Mamas MA, Deanfield JE, de Belder MA, Luescher TF, Denwood T, Landray MJ, Emberson JR, Collins R, Morris EJA, Casadei B, Baigent C (2020) COVID-19 pandemic and admission rates for and management of acute coronary syndromes in England. Lancet 396:381&#x2013;389. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31356-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31356-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32679111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7429983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moynihan R, Johansson M, Maybee A, Lang E, Legare F (2020) COVID-19: an opportunity to reduce unnecessary healthcare. BMJ 370:m2752. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m2752</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moynihan R, Sanders S, Michaleff ZA, Scott AM, Clark J, To EJ, Jones M, Kitchener E, Fox M, Johansson M, Lang E, Duggan A, Scott I, Albarqouni L (2021) Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on utilisation of healthcare services: a systematic review. BMJ Open 11:e045343. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2020-045343</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogharab V, Ostovar M, Ruszkowski J, Hussain SZM, Shrestha R, Yaqoob U, Aryanpoor P et al (2022) Global burden of the COVID-19 associated patient-related delay in emergency healthcare: a panel of systematic review and meta-analyses. Global Health 18:58. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12992-022-00836-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12992-022-00836-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35676714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9175527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil-Khan A, Khan MA (2023) The impact of COVID-19 on primary care: a scoping review. Cureus 15:e33241. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.33241</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandita KK, Noor T, Sahoo SK (2022) COVID-19 pandemic: hospital preparedness in a tertiary care hospital in North East India. J Family Med Prim Care 11:2877&#x2013;2883. https://doi.org/10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_1571_21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_1571_21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36119267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9480626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serlachius A, Badawy SM, Thabrew H (2020) Psychosocial challenges and opportunities for youth with chronic health conditions during the COVID-19 pandemic. JMIR Pediatr Parent 3:e23057. https://doi.org/10.2196/23057</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haldane V, De Foo C, Abdalla SM, Jung AS, Tan M, Wu S, Chua A, Verma M, Shrestha P, Singh S, Perez T, Tan SM, Bartos M, Mabuchi S, Bonk M, McNab C, Werner GK, Panjabi R, Nordstrom A, Legido-Quigley H (2021) Health systems resilience in managing the COVID-19 pandemic: lessons from 28 countries. Nat Med 27:964&#x2013;980. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-021-01381-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01381-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34002090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann DM, Chen J, Chunara R, Testa PA, Nov O (2020) COVID-19 transforms health care through telemedicine: evidence from the field. J Am Med Inform Assoc 27:1132&#x2013;1135. https://doi.org/10.1093/jamia/ocaa072</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jamia/ocaa072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32324855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7188161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arsenault C, Gage A, Kim MK, Kapoor NR, Akweongo P, Amponsah F, Aryal A et al (2022) COVID-19 and resilience of healthcare systems in ten countries. Nat Med 28:1314&#x2013;1324. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-01750-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01750-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35288697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9205770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komori A, Mori H, Naito T (2022) The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on other infections differs by their route of transmission: a retrospective, observational study in Japan. J Infect Chemother 28:1700&#x2013;1703. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiac.2022.08.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiac.2022.08.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36064143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9439856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toelen J, Ritz N, de Winter JP (2021) Changes in pediatric infections during the COVID-19 pandemic: &#x2018;a quarantrend for coronials&#x2019;? Eur J Pediatr 180:1965&#x2013;1967. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00431-021-03986-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-021-03986-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33649911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7920544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Brusselen D, De Troeyer K, Ter Haar E, Vander Auwera A, Poschet K, Van Nuijs S, Bael A, Stobbelaar K, Verhulst S, Van Herendael B, Willems P, Vermeulen M, De Man J, Bossuyt N, Vanden Driessche K (2021) Bronchiolitis in COVID-19 times: a nearly absent disease? Eur J Pediatr 180:1969&#x2013;1973. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00431-021-03968-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-021-03968-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33517482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7847293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broberg EK, Waris M, Johansen K, Snacken R, Penttinen P, European Influenza Surveillance N (2018) Seasonality and geographical spread of respiratory syncytial virus epidemics in 15 European countries, 2010 to 2016. Euro Surveill 23 https://doi.org/10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2018.23.5.17-00284</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenah E, Chao DL, Matrajt L, Halloran ME, Longini IM, Jr. (2011) The global transmission and control of influenza. PLoS One 6:e19515. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0019515</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen SJ, Winn AK, Budd AP, Prill MM, Steel J, Midgley CM, Kniss K, et al. (2021) Changes in influenza and other respiratory virus activity during the COVID-19 pandemic - United States, 2020&#x2013;2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 70:1013&#x2013;1019. https://doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm7029a1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danino D, Ben-Shimol S, van der Beek BA, Givon-Lavi N, Avni YS, Greenberg D, Weinberger DM, Dagan R (2022) Decline in pneumococcal disease in young children during the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic in israel associated with suppression of seasonal respiratory viruses, despite persistent pneumococcal carriage: a prospective cohort study. Clin Infect Dis 75:e1154&#x2013;e1164. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciab1014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab1014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34904635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinazzi M, Davis JT, Ajelli M, Gioannini C, Litvinova M, Merler S, Pastore YPA, Mu K, Rossi L, Sun K, Viboud C, Xiong X, Yu H, Halloran ME, Longini IM Jr, Vespignani A (2020) The effect of travel restrictions on the spread of the 2019 novel coronavirus (COVID-19) outbreak. Science 368:395&#x2013;400. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aba9757</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aba9757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32144116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7164386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymann DL, Shindo N, Scientific WHO, Technical advisory group for infectious H, (2020) COVID-19: what is next for public health? Lancet 395:542&#x2013;545. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30374-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30374-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32061313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7138015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai S, Ruktanonchai NW, Zhou L, Prosper O, Luo W, Floyd JR, Wesolowski A, Santillana M, Zhang C, Du X, Yu H, Tatem AJ (2020) Effect of non-pharmaceutical interventions to contain COVID-19 in China. Nature 585:410&#x2013;413. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2293-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-020-2293-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32365354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7116778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao J, Shiu EYC, Gao H, Wong JY, Fong MW, Ryu S, Cowling BJ (2020) Nonpharmaceutical measures for pandemic influenza in nonhealthcare settings-personal protective and environmental measures. Emerg Infect Dis 26:967&#x2013;975. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid2605.190994</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid2605.190994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32027586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7181938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dadras O, Alinaghi SAS, Karimi A, MohsseniPour M, Barzegary A, Vahedi F, Pashaei Z, Mirzapour P, Fakhfouri A, Zargari G, Saeidi S, Mojdeganlou H, Badri H, Qaderi K, Behnezhad F, Mehraeen E (2021) Effects of COVID-19 prevention procedures on other common infections: a systematic review. Eur J Med Res 26:67. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40001-021-00539-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40001-021-00539-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34217366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8253677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khataee H, Scheuring I, Czirok A, Neufeld Z (2021) Effects of social distancing on the spreading of COVID-19 inferred from mobile phone data. Sci Rep 11:1661. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-81308-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-81308-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33462369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7813880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Huang H, Ju J, Sun R, Zhang J (2022) Impact of vaccination on the COVID-19 pandemic in U.S. states. Sci Rep 12:1554. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-05498-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson OJ, Barnsley G, Toor J, Hogan AB, Winskill P, Ghani AC (2022) Global impact of the first year of COVID-19 vaccination: a mathematical modelling study. Lancet Infect Dis 22:1293&#x2013;1302. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(22)00320-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(22)00320-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35753318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9225255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow EJ, Uyeki TM, Chu HY (2023) The effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on community respiratory virus activity. Nat Rev Microbiol 21:195&#x2013;210. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41579-022-00807-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00807-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36253478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin R (2021) Influenza&#x2019;s unprecedented low profile during COVID-19 pandemic leaves experts wondering what this flu season has in store. JAMA 326:899&#x2013;900. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2021.14131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.14131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34431979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang ML, Xu YP, Wu H, Zhu RN, Sun Y, Chen DM, Wang F, Zhou YT, Guo Q, Wu A, Qian Y, Zhou HY, Zhao LQ (2023) Changes in endemic patterns of respiratory syncytial virus infection in pediatric patients under the pressure of nonpharmaceutical interventions for COVID-19 in Beijing, China. J Med Virol 95:e28411. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.28411</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosscrop LG, Williams TC, Tregoning JS (2022) Respiratory syncytial virus after the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic - what next? Nat Rev Immunol 22:589&#x2013;590. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41577-022-00764-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-022-00764-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35831610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9281204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozlowski PA, Mantis NJ, Frey A (2022) Editorial: mucosal vaccination: strategies to induce and evaluate mucosal immunity. Front Immunol 13:905150. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2022.905150</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell MW, Mestecky J (2022) Mucosal immunity: the missing link in comprehending SARS-CoV-2 infection and transmission. Front Immunol 13:957107. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2022.957107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell MW, Moldoveanu Z, Ogra PL, Mestecky J (2020) Mucosal immunity in COVID-19: a neglected but critical aspect of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Front Immunol 11:611337. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2020.611337</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamers MM, Haagmans BL (2022) SARS-CoV-2 pathogenesis. Nat Rev Microbiol 20:270&#x2013;284. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41579-022-00713-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00713-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35354968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HM, Lee EJ, Lee NJ, Woo SH, Kim JM, Rhee JE, Kim EJ (2021) Impact of coronavirus disease 2019 on respiratory surveillance and explanation of high detection rate of human rhinovirus during the pandemic in the Republic of Korea. Influenza Other Respir Viruses 15:721&#x2013;731. https://doi.org/10.1111/irv.12894</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/irv.12894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34405546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8446939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagan R, van der Beek BA, Ben-Shimol S, Greenberg D, Shemer-Avni Y, Weinberger DM, Danino D (2023) The COVID-19 pandemic as an opportunity for unravelling the causative association between respiratory viruses and pneumococcus-associated disease in young children: a prospective study. EBioMedicine 90:104493. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ebiom.2023.104493</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rybak A, Levy C, Angoulvant F, Auvrignon A, Gembara P, Danis K, Vaux S, Levy-Bruhl D, van der Werf S, Bechet S, Bonacorsi S, Assad Z, Lazzati A, Michel M, Kaguelidou F, Faye A, Cohen R, Varon E, Ouldali N (2022) Association of nonpharmaceutical interventions during the COVID-19 pandemic with invasive pneumococcal disease, pneumococcal carriage, and respiratory viral infections among children in France. JAMA Netw Open 5:e2218959. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.18959</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCullers JA (2006) Insights into the interaction between influenza virus and pneumococcus. Clin Microbiol Rev 19:571&#x2013;582. https://doi.org/10.1128/CMR.00058-05</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/CMR.00058-05</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16847087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1539103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandeel A, Fahim M, Deghedy O, Roshdy WH, Khalifa MK, Shesheny RE, Kandeil A, Naguib A, Afifi S, Mohsen A, Abdelghaffar K (2023) Resurgence of influenza and respiratory syncytial virus in Egypt following two years of decline during the COVID-19 pandemic: outpatient clinic survey of infants and children, October 2022. BMC Public Health 23:1067. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-023-15880-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-023-15880-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37277781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10240446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Raya B, Vineta Paramo M, Reicherz F, Lavoie PM (2023) Why has the epidemiology of RSV changed during the COVID-19 pandemic? EClinicalMedicine 61:102089. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2023.102089</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen R, Ashman M, Taha MK, Varon E, Angoulvant F, Levy C, Rybak A, Ouldali N, Guiso N, Grimprel E (2021) Pediatric Infectious Disease Group (GPIP) position paper on the immune debt of the COVID-19 pandemic in childhood, how can we fill the immunity gap? Infect Dis Now 51:418&#x2013;423. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.idnow.2021.05.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.idnow.2021.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33991720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8114587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treggiari D, Piubelli C, Formenti F, Silva R, Perandin F (2022) Resurgence of respiratory virus after relaxation of COVID-19 containment measures: a real-world data study from a regional hospital of Italy. Int J Microbiol 2022:4915678. https://doi.org/10.1155/2022/4915678</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/4915678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36466968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9718619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertran M, Amin-Chowdhury Z, Sheppard CL, Eletu S, Zamarreno DV, Ramsay ME, Litt D, Fry NK, Ladhani SN (2022) Increased incidence of invasive pneumococcal disease among children after COVID-19 pandemic, England. Emerg Infect Dis 28:1669&#x2013;1672. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid2808.220304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid2808.220304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35876698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9328924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farahat RA, Shaheen N, Kundu M, Shaheen A, Abdelaal A (2022) The resurfacing of hand, foot, and mouth disease: are we on the verge of another epidemic? Ann Med Surg (Lond) 81:104419. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amsu.2022.104419</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binns E, Koenraads M, Hristeva L, Flamant A, Baier-Grabner S, Loi M, Lempainen J, Osterheld E, Ramly B, Chakakala-Chaziya J, Enaganthi N, Simo Nebot S, Buonsenso D (2022) Influenza and respiratory syncytial virus during the COVID-19 pandemic: time for a new paradigm? Pediatr Pulmonol 57:38&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1002/ppul.25719</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ppul.25719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34644459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagan R, Danino D, Weinberger DM (2022) The pneumococcus-respiratory virus connection-unexpected lessons from the COVID-19 pandemic. JAMA Netw Open 5:e2218966. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.18966</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilligan P (2022) Impact of COVID-19 on infectious diseases and public health. American Society for Microbiology</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride DL (2021) Social Distancing for COVID-19 Decreased infectious diseases in children. J Pediatr Nurs 58:100&#x2013;101. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pedn.2021.02.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pedn.2021.02.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33640227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8815104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plantener E, Nanthan KR, Deding U, Damkj&#xe6;r M, Marmolin ES, Hansen LH, Petersen JJH, Pinilla R, Coia JE, Wolff DL, Song Z, Chen M (2023) Impact of COVID-19 restrictions on acute gastroenteritis in children: a regional, Danish, register-based study. Children 10:816</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/children10050816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37238364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10217309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuitunen I, Artama M, Haapanen M, Renko M (2022) Urinary tract infections decreased in Finnish children during the COVID-19 pandemic. Eur J Pediatr 181:1979&#x2013;1984. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00431-022-04389-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-022-04389-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35098402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8801286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cesca L, Conversano E, Vianello FA, Martelli L, Gualeni C, Bassani F, Brugnara M, Rubin G, Parolin M, Anselmi M, Marchiori M, Vergine G, Miorin E, Vidal E, Milocco C, Orsi C, Puccio G, Peruzzi L, Montini G, Dall&#x2019;Amico R, on the behalf of the Italian Society of Pediatric N (2022) How COVID-19 changed the epidemiology of febrile urinary tract infections in children in the emergency department during the first outbreak. BMC Pediatr 22:550. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12887-022-03516-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-022-03516-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatoun J, Correa ET, Donahue SMA, Vernacchio L (2020) Social distancing for COVID-19 and diagnoses of other infectious diseases in children. Pediatrics 146 https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2020-006460</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobo-Vazquez E, Aguilera-Alonso D, Carrasco-Colom J, Calvo C, Saavedra-Lozano J, Ped GASnWG (2023) Increasing incidence and severity of invasive group A streptococcal disease in Spanish children in 2019&#x2013;2022. Lancet Reg Health Eur 27:100597. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lanepe.2023.100597</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen PR, Rybak A, Werner A, Bechet S, Desandes R, Hassid F, Andre JM, Gelbert N, Thiebault G, Kochert F, Cahn-Sellem F, Vie Le Sage F, Angoulvant PF, Ouldali N, Frandji B, Levy C (2022) Trends in pediatric ambulatory community acquired infections before and during COVID-19 pandemic: a prospective multicentric surveillance study in France. Lancet Reg Health Eur 22:100497. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lanepe.2022.100497</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamagni T, Guy R, Chand M, Henderson KL, Chalker V, Lewis J, Saliba V, Elliot AJ, Smith GE, Rushton S, Sheridan EA, Ramsay M, Johnson AP (2018) Resurgence of scarlet fever in England, 2014&#x2013;16: a population-based surveillance study. Lancet Infect Dis 18:180&#x2013;187. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(17)30693-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(17)30693-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29191628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Allot A, Lu Z (2020) Keep up with the latest coronavirus research. Nature 579:193. https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-020-00694-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/d41586-020-00694-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32157233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subbiah V (2023) The next generation of evidence-based medicine. Nat Med 29:49&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-02160-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-02160-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36646803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira da Silva JA, Tsigaris P, Erfanmanesh M (2021) Publishing volumes in major databases related to COVID-19. Scientometrics 126:831&#x2013;842. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11192-020-03675-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11192-020-03675-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32904414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raynaud M, Goutaudier V, Louis K, Al-Awadhi S, Dubourg Q, Truchot A, Brousse R, Saleh N, Giarraputo A, Debiais C, Demir Z, Certain A, Tacafred F, Cortes-Garcia E, Yanes S, Dagobert J, Naser S, Robin B, Bailly E, Jouven X, Reese PP, Loupy A (2021) Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on publication dynamics and non-COVID-19 research production. BMC Med Res Methodol 21:255. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12874-021-01404-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-021-01404-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34809561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8607966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riccaboni M, Verginer L (2022) The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on scientific research in the life sciences. PLoS One 17:e0263001. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0263001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohrabi C, Mathew G, Franchi T, Kerwan A, Griffin M, Soleil CDMJ, Ali SA, Agha M, Agha R (2021) Impact of the coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic on scientific research and implications for clinical academic training - a review. Int J Surg 86:57&#x2013;63. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijsu.2020.12.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijsu.2020.12.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33444873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7833269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaton PM (2020) The COVID-19 vaccine-development multiverse. N Engl J Med 383:1986&#x2013;1988. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMe2025111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMe2025111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luxi N, Giovanazzi A, Capuano A, Crisafulli S, Cutroneo PM, Fantini MP, Ferrajolo C, Moretti U, Poluzzi E, Raschi E, Ravaldi C, Reno C, Tuccori M, Vannacci A, Zanoni G, Trifiro G, Ccg I (2021) COVID-19 Vaccination in pregnancy, paediatrics, immunocompromised patients, and persons with history of allergy or prior SARS-CoV-2 infection: overview of current recommendations and pre- and post-marketing evidence for vaccine efficacy and safety. Drug Saf 44:1247&#x2013;1269. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40264-021-01131-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40264-021-01131-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34739716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8569292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folegatti PM, Bittaye M, Flaxman A, Lopez FR, Bellamy D, Kupke A, Mair C et al (2020) Safety and immunogenicity of a candidate Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus viral-vectored vaccine: a dose-escalation, open-label, non-randomised, uncontrolled, phase 1 trial. Lancet Infect Dis 20:816&#x2013;826. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30160-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30160-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7172901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin JE, Louder MK, Holman LA, Gordon IJ, Enama ME, Larkin BD, Andrews CA, Vogel L, Koup RA, Roederer M, Bailer RT, Gomez PL, Nason M, Mascola JR, Nabel GJ, Graham BS, Team VRCS (2008) A SARS DNA vaccine induces neutralizing antibody and cellular immune responses in healthy adults in a Phase I clinical trial. Vaccine 26:6338&#x2013;6343. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vaccine.2008.09.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2008.09.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Blum J, Le Thanh T, Havelange N, Magini D, Yoon IK (2022) The mRNA vaccine development landscape for infectious diseases. Nat Rev Drug Discov 21:333&#x2013;334. https://doi.org/10.1038/d41573-022-00035-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/d41573-022-00035-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35149859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbier AJ, Jiang AY, Zhang P, Wooster R, Anderson DG (2022) The clinical progress of mRNA vaccines and immunotherapies. Nat Biotechnol 40:840&#x2013;854. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41587-022-01294-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41587-022-01294-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35534554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Z, Tian Y, Song J, An G, Yang P (2022) mRNA vaccines: the dawn of a new era of cancer immunotherapy. Front Immunol 13:887125. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2022.887125</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao L, Zhang Y, Huang L (2021) mRNA vaccine for cancer immunotherapy. Mol Cancer 20:41. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12943-021-01335-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12943-021-01335-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33632261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7905014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Summan A, Nandi A, Shet A, Laxminarayan R (2023) The effect of the COVID-19 pandemic on routine childhood immunization coverage and timeliness in India: retrospective analysis of the National Family Health Survey of 2019&#x2013;2021 data. Lancet Reg Health Southeast Asia 8:100099. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lansea.2022.100099</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavie M, Lavie I, Laskov I, Cohen A, Grisaru D, Grisaru-Soen G, Michaan N (2023) Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on human papillomavirus vaccine uptake in Israel. J Low Genit Tract Dis 27:168&#x2013;172. https://doi.org/10.1097/LGT.0000000000000729</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/LGT.0000000000000729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36815631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10026726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raut A, Huy NT (2022) Impediments to child education, health and development during the COVID-19 pandemic in India. Lancet Reg Health Southeast Asia 1:100005. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lansea.2022.04.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotez PJ (2021) Mounting antiscience aggression in the United States. PLoS Biol 19:e3001369. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.3001369</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karafillakis E, Van Damme P, Hendrickx G, Larson HJ (2022) COVID-19 in Europe: new challenges for addressing vaccine hesitancy. Lancet 399:699&#x2013;701. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(22)00150-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(22)00150-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35123665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8813064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson E (2022) Is anti-vaccine sentiment affecting routine childhood immunisations? BMJ 376:o360. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.o360</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel M, Lee AD, Redd SB, Clemmons NS, McNall RJ, Cohn AC, Gastanaduy PA (2019) Increase in measles cases - United States, January 1-April 26, 2019. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 68:402&#x2013;404. https://doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm6817e1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SeyedAlinaghi S, Karimi A, Mojdeganlou H, Alilou S, Mirghaderi SP, Noori T, Shamsabadi A, Dadras O, Vahedi F, Mohammadi P, Shojaei A, Mahdiabadi S, Janfaza N, Keshavarzpoor Lonbar A, Mehraeen E, Sabatier JM (2022) Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on routine vaccination coverage of children and adolescents: a systematic review. Health Sci Rep 5:e00516. https://doi.org/10.1002/hsr2.516</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neves FPG, Mestrovic T, Pinto TCA (2023) Editorial: drug resistance in maternal and paediatric bacterial and fungal infections: is COVID-19 changing the landscape. Front Microbiol 14:1177669. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2023.1177669</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2023.1177669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37007484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10050869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontana C, Favaro M, Minelli S, Bossa MC, Altieri A (2021) Co-infections observed in SARS-CoV-2 positive patients using a rapid diagnostic test. Sci Rep 11:16355. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-95772-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-95772-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34381118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8357960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutcher L, Li Y, Lee G, Grundmeier R, Hamilton KW, Gerber JS (2022) COVID-19 and antibiotic prescribing in pediatric primary care. Pediatrics 149 https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2021-053079</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kronman MP, Gerber JS, Grundmeier RW, Zhou C, Robinson JD, Heritage J, Stout J, Burges D, Hedrick B, Warren L, Shalowitz M, Shone LP, Steffes J, Wright M, Fiks AG, Mangione-Smith R (2020) Reducing antibiotic prescribing in primary care for respiratory illness. Pediatrics 146 https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2020-0038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittman SR, Martin JM, Mehrotra A, Ray KN (2023) Antibiotic receipt during outpatient visits for COVID-19 in the US, From 2020 to 2022. JAMA Health Forum 4:e225429. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamahealthforum.2022.5429</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik SS, Mundra S (2022) Increasing consumption of antibiotics during the COVID-19 pandemic: implications for patient health and emerging anti-microbial resistance. Antibiotics (Basel) 12. https://doi.org/10.3390/antibiotics12010045</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kariyawasam RM, Julien DA, Jelinski DC, Larose SL, Rennert-May E, Conly JM, Dingle TC, Chen JZ, Tyrrell GJ, Ronksley PE, Barkema HW (2022) Antimicrobial resistance (AMR) in COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis (November 2019-June 2021). Antimicrob Resist Infect Control 11:45. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13756-022-01085-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-022-01085-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8899460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>