<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38495273</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1948-5182</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of hepatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Hepatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on incidence and treatment strategies of hepatocellular carcinoma in people with chronic liver disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>211</StartPage><EndPage>228</EndPage><MedlinePgn>211-228</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4254/wjh.v16.i2.211</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Chronic liver disease (CLD) was associated with adverse clinical outcomes among people with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine the effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on the incidence and treatment strategy of hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) among patients with CLD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective, territory-wide cohort of CLD patients was identified from an electronic health database in Hong Kong. Patients with confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection [coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19)+CLD] between January 1, 2020 and October 25, 2022 were identified and matched 1:1 by propensity-score with those without (COVID-19-CLD). Each patient was followed up until death, outcome event, or November 15, 2022. Primary outcome was incidence of HCC. Secondary outcomes included all-cause mortality, adverse hepatic outcomes, and different treatment strategies to HCC (curative, non-curative treatment, and palliative care). Analyses were further stratified by acute (within 20 d) and post-acute (21 d or beyond) phases of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Incidence rate ratios (IRRs) were estimated by Poisson regression models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 193589 CLD patients (&gt; 95% non-cirrhotic) in the cohort, 55163 patients with COVID-19+CLD and 55163 patients with COVID-19-CLD were included after 1:1 propensity-score matching. Upon 249-d median follow-up, COVID-19+CLD was not associated with increased risk of incident HCC (IRR: 1.19, 95%CI: 0.99-1.42, <i>P</i> = 0.06), but higher risks of receiving palliative care for HCC (IRR: 1.60, 95%CI: 1.46-1.75, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.001), compared to COVID-19-CLD. In both acute and post-acute phases of infection, COVID-19+CLD were associated with increased risks of all-cause mortality (acute: IRR: 7.06, 95%CI: 5.78-8.63, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.001; post-acute: IRR: 1.24, 95%CI: 1.14-1.36, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.001) and adverse hepatic outcomes (acute: IRR: 1.98, 95%CI: 1.79-2.18, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.001; post-acute: IRR: 1.24, 95%CI: 1.13-1.35, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.001), compared to COVID-19-CLD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Although CLD patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection were not associated with increased risk of HCC, they were more likely to receive palliative treatment than those without. The detrimental effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection persisted in post-acute phase.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2024. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mak</LastName><ForeName>Lung-Yi</ForeName><Initials>LY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Liver Research, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chung</LastName><ForeName>Matthew Shing Hin</ForeName><Initials>MSH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmacy, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xue</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmacy, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Data Discovery for Health (D24H), Hong Kong Science and Technology Park, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Francisco Tsz Tsun</ForeName><Initials>FTT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmacy, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Data Discovery for Health (D24H), Hong Kong Science and Technology Park, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wan</LastName><ForeName>Eric Yuk Fai</ForeName><Initials>EYF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmacy, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Data Discovery for Health (D24H), Hong Kong Science and Technology Park, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine and Primary Care, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chui</LastName><ForeName>Celine Sze Ling</ForeName><Initials>CSL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Data Discovery for Health (D24H), Hong Kong Science and Technology Park, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Franco Wing Tak</ForeName><Initials>FWT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmacy, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Esther Wai Yin</ForeName><Initials>EWY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmacy, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Data Discovery for Health (D24H), Hong Kong Science and Technology Park, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheung</LastName><ForeName>Ching Lung</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmacy, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Data Discovery for Health (D24H), Hong Kong Science and Technology Park, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Au</LastName><ForeName>Ivan Chi Ho</ForeName><Initials>ICH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmacy, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Xi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmacy, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seto</LastName><ForeName>Wai-Kay</ForeName><Initials>WK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Liver Research, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuen</LastName><ForeName>Man-Fung</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Liver Research, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Carlos King Ho</ForeName><Initials>CKH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmacy, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Data Discovery for Health (D24H), Hong Kong Science and Technology Park, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine and Primary Care, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China. carlosho@hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Ian Chi Kei</ForeName><Initials>ICK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmacy, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Data Discovery for Health (D24H), Hong Kong Science and Technology Park, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Department of Practice and Policy, University College London, London WC1E 6BT, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aston School of Pharmacy, Aston University, Birmingham B4 7ET, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>WT_</Acronym><Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Hepatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101532469</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic liver disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cirrhosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatocellular carcinoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2 infection</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: Lung-Yi Mak is an advisory board member for Gilead Sciences. Xue Li has received research grants from the Health Bureau of the Government of the Hong Kong SAR, research and educational grants from Janssen and Pfizer; internal funding from the University of Hong Kong; consultancy fee from Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, unrelated to this work. Francisco Tsz Tsun Lai has been supported by the RGC Postdoctoral Fellowship under the Hong Kong Research Grants Council and has received research grants from the Health Bureau of the Government of the Hong Kong SAR, outside the submitted work. Eric Yuk Fai Wan has received research grants from the Health Bureau of the Government of the Hong Kong SAR, and the Hong Kong Research Grants Council, outside the submitted work. Celine Sze Ling Chui has received grants from the Health Bureau of the Hong Kong Government, Hong Kong Research Grant Council, Hong Kong Innovation and Technology Commission, Pfizer, IQVIA, and Amgen; personal fee from Primevigilance Ltd.; outside the submitted work. Esther Wai Yin Chan reports honorarium from the Hospital Authority, grants from the Research Grants Council (RGC, Hong Kong), Research Fund Secretariat of the Health Bureau, National Natural Science Fund of China, Wellcome Trust, Bayer, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Pfizer, Janssen, Amgen, Takeda, and Narcotics Division of the Security Bureau of the Hong Kong SAR, outside the submitted work. Ching Lung Cheung received research grants and honorarium from Amgen, research grant support from HMRF, and honorarium from Abbott. Wai Kay Seto received speaker's fees from AstraZeneca and Mylan, is an advisory board member of CSL Behring, is an advisory board member and received speaker's fees from AbbVie, and is an advisory board member, received speaker's fees, and researching funding from Gilead Sciences. Man-Fung Yuen serves as advisor/consultant for AbbVie, Assembly Biosciences, Aligos Therapeutics, Arbutus Biopharma, Bristol Myer Squibb, Clear B Therapeutics, Dicerna Pharmaceuticals, Finch Therapeutics, GlaxoSmithKline, Gilead Sciences, Immunocore, Janssen, Merck Sharp and Dohme, Hoffmann-La Roche, and Springbank Pharmaceuticals, Vir Biotechnology and receives grant/research support from Assembly Biosciences, Aligos Therapeutics, Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals, Bristol Myer Squibb, Fujirebio Incorporation, Gilead Sciences, Immunocore, Merck Sharp and Dohme, Hoffmann-La Roche, Springbank Pharmaceuticals, and Sysmex Corporation, outside the submitted work. Carlos King Ho Wong reports receipt of research funding from the EuroQoL Group Research Foundation, the Hong Kong Research Grants Council, the Hong Kong Health and Medical Research Fund, AstraZeneca and Boehringer Ingelheim, all outside of the submitted work. Ian Chi Kei Wong reports research funding outside the submitted work from Amgen, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Pfizer, Janssen, Bayer, GSK, Novartis, the Hong Kong RGC, and the Hong Kong Health and Medical Research Fund, National Institute for Health Research in England, European Commission, National Health and Medical Research Council in Australia. All other authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38495273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10941734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4254/wjh.v16.i2.211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ioannou GN, Liang PS, Locke E, Green P, Berry K, O'Hare AM, Shah JA, Crothers K, Eastment MC, Fan VS, Dominitz JA. Cirrhosis and Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 Infection in US Veterans: Risk of Infection, Hospitalization, Ventilation, and Mortality. Hepatology. 2021;74:322&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33219546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge J, Pletcher MJ, Lai JC N3C Consortium. Outcomes of SARS-CoV-2 Infection in Patients With Chronic Liver Disease and Cirrhosis: A National COVID Cohort Collaborative Study. Gastroenterology. 2021;161:1487&#x2013;1501.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8286237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34284037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marjot T, Moon AM, Cook JA, Abd-Elsalam S, Aloman C, Armstrong MJ, Pose E, Brenner EJ, Cargill T, Catana MA, Dhanasekaran R, Eshraghian A, Garc&#xed;a-Ju&#xe1;rez I, Gill US, Jones PD, Kennedy J, Marshall A, Matthews C, Mells G, Mercer C, Perumalswami PV, Avitabile E, Qi X, Su F, Ufere NN, Wong YJ, Zheng MH, Barnes E, Barritt AS 4th, Webb GJ. Outcomes following SARS-CoV-2 infection in patients with chronic liver disease: An international registry study. J Hepatol. 2021;74:567&#x2013;577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33035628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajaj JS, Garcia-Tsao G, Biggins SW, Kamath PS, Wong F, McGeorge S, Shaw J, Pearson M, Chew M, Fagan A, de la Rosa Rodriguez R, Worthington J, Olofson A, Weir V, Trisolini C, Dwyer S, Reddy KR. Comparison of mortality risk in patients with cirrhosis and COVID-19 compared with patients with cirrhosis alone and COVID-19 alone: multicentre matched cohort. Gut. 2021;70:531&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7371484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32660964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon AM, Singal AG, Tapper EB. Contemporary Epidemiology of Chronic Liver Disease and Cirrhosis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;18:2650&#x2013;2666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7007353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31401364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheemerla S, Balakrishnan M. Global Epidemiology of Chronic Liver Disease. Clin Liver Dis (Hoboken) 2021;17:365&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8177826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34136143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Association for the Study of the Liver. EASL Clinical Practice Guidelines: Management of hepatocellular carcinoma. J Hepatol. 2018;69:182&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29628281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Burdens of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 by severity of acute infection, demographics and health status. Nat Commun. 2021;12:6571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8589966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34772922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Acute and postacute sequelae associated with SARS-CoV-2 reinfection. Nat Med. 2022;28:2398&#x2013;2405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9671810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36357676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, Cook JR, Nordvig AS, Shalev D, Sehrawat TS, Ahluwalia N, Bikdeli B, Dietz D, Der-Nigoghossian C, Liyanage-Don N, Rosner GF, Bernstein EJ, Mohan S, Beckley AA, Seres DS, Choueiri TK, Uriel N, Ausiello JC, Accili D, Freedberg DE, Baldwin M, Schwartz A, Brodie D, Garcia CK, Elkind MSV, Connors JM, Bilezikian JP, Landry DW, Wan EY. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapper EB, Asrani SK. The COVID-19 pandemic will have a long-lasting impact on the quality of cirrhosis care. J Hepatol. 2020;73:441&#x2013;445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong CKH, Mak LY, Au ICH, Lai FTT, Li X, Wan EYF, Chui CSL, Chan EWY, Cheng WY, Cheng FWT, Yuen MF, Wong ICK. Risk of acute liver injury following the mRNA (BNT162b2) and inactivated (CoronaVac) COVID-19 vaccines. J Hepatol. 2022;77:1339&#x2013;1348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9376738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35817224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai FTT, Li X, Peng K, Huang L, Ip P, Tong X, Chui CSL, Wan EYF, Wong CKH, Chan EWY, Siu DCW, Wong ICK. Carditis After COVID-19 Vaccination With a Messenger RNA Vaccine and an Inactivated Virus Vaccine : A Case-Control Study. Ann Intern Med. 2022;175:362&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8814917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35073155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Tong X, Yeung WWY, Kuan P, Yum SHH, Chui CSL, Lai FTT, Wan EYF, Wong CKH, Chan EWY, Lau CS, Wong ICK. Two-dose COVID-19 vaccination and possible arthritis flare among patients with rheumatoid arthritis in Hong Kong. Ann Rheum Dis. 2022;81:564&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8550868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34686479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam ICH, Wong CKH, Zhang R, Chui CSL, Lai FTT, Li X, Chan EWY, Luo H, Zhang Q, Man KKC, Cheung BMY, Tang SCW, Lau CS, Wan EYF, Wong ICK. Long-term post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 infection: a retrospective, multi-database cohort study in Hong Kong and the UK. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;60:102000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10173760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37197226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne AW, McEvoy D, Collins AB, Hunt K, Casey M, Barber A, Butler F, Griffin J, Lane EA, McAloon C, O'Brien K, Wall P, Walsh KA, More SJ. Inferred duration of infectious period of SARS-CoV-2: rapid scoping review and analysis of available evidence for asymptomatic and symptomatic COVID-19 cases. BMJ Open. 2020;10:e039856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7409948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Samaniego L, Bighelli F, Us&#xf3;n C, Caravaca C, Fern&#xe1;ndez Carrillo C, Romero M, Barreales M, Perell&#xf3; C, Madej&#xf3;n A, Marcos AC, Albillos A, Fern&#xe1;ndez I, Garc&#xed;a-Samaniego J, Calleja JL, Ba&#xf1;ares R. Elevation of Liver Fibrosis Index FIB-4 Is Associated With Poor Clinical Outcomes in Patients With COVID-19. J Infect Dis. 2020;222:726&#x2013;733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7337860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32563190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen K, Ren S, Heath K, Dasmari&#xf1;as MC, Jubilo KG, Guo Y, Lipsitch M, Daugherty SE. Risk of persistent and new clinical sequelae among adults aged 65 years and older during the post-acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2022;376:e068414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8828141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35140117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMenamin ME, Nealon J, Lin Y, Wong JY, Cheung JK, Lau EHY, Wu P, Leung GM, Cowling BJ. Vaccine effectiveness of one, two, and three doses of BNT162b2 and CoronaVac against COVID-19 in Hong Kong: a population-based observational study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:1435&#x2013;1443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9286709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35850128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin PC. Some methods of propensity-score matching had superior performance to others: results of an empirical investigation and Monte Carlo simulations. Biom J. 2009;51:171&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19197955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao X, Lv F, He X, Zhao Y, Liu Y, Zu J, Henry L, Wang J, Yeo YH, Ji F, Nguyen MH. Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on liver disease-related mortality rates in the United States. J Hepatol. 2023;78:16&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9611810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35988691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montazersaheb S, Hosseiniyan Khatibi SM, Hejazi MS, Tarhriz V, Farjami A, Ghasemian Sorbeni F, Farahzadi R, Ghasemnejad T. COVID-19 infection: an overview on cytokine storm and related interventions. Virol J. 2022;19:92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9134144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35619180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taneva G, Dimitrov D, Velikova T. Liver dysfunction as a cytokine storm manifestation and prognostic factor for severe COVID-19. World J Hepatol. 2021;13:2005&#x2013;2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35070004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boettler T, Csernalabics B, Sali&#xe9; H, Luxenburger H, Wischer L, Salimi Alizei E, Zoldan K, Krimmel L, Bronsert P, Schwabenland M, Prinz M, Mogler C, Neumann-Haefelin C, Thimme R, Hofmann M, Bengsch B. SARS-CoV-2 vaccination can elicit a CD8 T-cell dominant hepatitis. J Hepatol. 2022;77:653&#x2013;659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9021033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35461912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mederacke I, Hsu CC, Troeger JS, Huebener P, Mu X, Dapito DH, Pradere JP, Schwabe RF. Fate tracing reveals hepatic stellate cells as dominant contributors to liver fibrosis independent of its aetiology. Nat Commun. 2013;4:2823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4059406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24264436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanner N, Andrieux G, Badia-I-Mompel P, Edler C, Pfefferle S, Lindenmeyer MT, Schmidt-Lauber C, Czogalla J, Wong MN, Okabayashi Y, Braun F, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Meister E, Lu S, Noriega MLM, G&#xfc;nther T, Grundhoff A, Fischer N, Br&#xe4;uninger H, Lindner D, Westermann D, Haas F, Roedl K, Kluge S, Addo MM, Huber S, Lohse AW, Reiser J, Ondruschka B, Sperhake JP, Saez-Rodriguez J, Boerries M, Hayek SS, Aepfelbacher M, Scaturro P, Puelles VG, Huber TB. Molecular consequences of SARS-CoV-2 Liver tropism. Nat Metab. 2022;4:310&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8964418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35347318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quarleri J, Delpino MV. Molecular mechanisms implicated in SARS-CoV-2 Liver tropism. World J Gastroenterol. 2022;28:6875&#x2013;6887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9827585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36632318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupberger J, Hildt E. Hepatitis B virus-induced oncogenesis. World J Gastroenterol. 2007;13:74&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4065878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17206756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivasudhan E, Blake N, Lu Z, Meng J, Rong R. Hepatitis B Viral Protein HBx and the Molecular Mechanisms Modulating the Hallmarks of Hepatocellular Carcinoma: A Comprehensive Review. Cells. 2022;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8870387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35203390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phipps MM, Barraza LH, LaSota ED, Sobieszczyk ME, Pereira MR, Zheng EX, Fox AN, Zucker J, Verna EC. Acute Liver Injury in COVID-19: Prevalence and Association with Clinical Outcomes in a Large U.S. Cohort. Hepatology. 2020;72:807&#x2013;817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7300739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32473607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hundt MA, Deng Y, Ciarleglio MM, Nathanson MH, Lim JK. Abnormal Liver Tests in COVID-19: A Retrospective Observational Cohort Study of 1,827 Patients in a Major U.S. Hospital Network. Hepatology. 2020;72:1169&#x2013;1176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9258788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Young CH, Lau SH, He ML. Outbreak control management: Lessons from SARS-CoV-2 infections in 2020-2022 in Hong Kong, an international municipality with high-frequency travelers. MedComm (2020) 2022;3:e158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9309738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35898696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oubaya N, Pombet T, Delestrain C, Remus N, Douvry B, Grenet D, Corvol H, Thouvenin G, Pruli&#xe8;re-Escabasse V, Mounir H, Argoud D, Fretigne C, Costes L, Mackiewicz MP, Jung C, Ahamada L, Lanone S, Maitre B, B&#xe9;got AC, Epaud R. Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic and associated lockdown measures on the management, health, and behavior of the cystic fibrosis population in France during 2020 (MUCONFIN) Front Public Health. 2022;10:978627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9703073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36452951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Association for the Study of the Liver. EASL 2017 Clinical Practice Guidelines on the management of hepatitis B virus infection. J Hepatol. 2017;67:370&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28427875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terrault NA, Lok ASF, McMahon BJ, Chang KM, Hwang JP, Jonas MM, Brown RS Jr, Bzowej NH, Wong JB. Update on prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of chronic hepatitis B: AASLD 2018 hepatitis B guidance. Hepatology. 2018;67:1560&#x2013;1599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5975958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29405329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toyoda H, Huang DQ, Le MH, Nguyen MH. Liver Care and Surveillance: The Global Impact of the COVID-19 Pandemic. Hepatol Commun. 2020;4:1751&#x2013;1757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7405084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Lancet. The COVID-19 pandemic in 2023: far from over. Lancet. 2023;401:79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36641201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenblum HG, Wallace M, Godfrey M, Roper LE, Hall E, Fleming-Dutra KE, Link-Gelles R, Pilishvili T, Williams J, Moulia DL, Brooks O, Talbot HK, Lee GM, Bell BP, Daley MF, Meyer S, Oliver SE, Twentyman E. Interim Recommendations from the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices for the Use of Bivalent Booster Doses of COVID-19 Vaccines - United States, October 2022. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71:1436&#x2013;1441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9707353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36355612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> Interim Clinical Considerations for COVID-19 Treatment in Outpatients. 2023. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/outpatient-treatment-overview.html .</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>