<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37201006</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2587-1250</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>69</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Turkish journal of physical medicine and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Turk J Phys Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Musculoskeletal involvement: COVID-19 and post COVID 19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>7</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-7</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5606/tftrd.2023.12521</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The worldwide pandemic of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) was known to predominantly affect the lungs, but it was realized that COVID-19 had a large variety of clinical involvement. Cardiovascular, gastrointestinal, neurological, and musculoskeletal systems are involved by direct or indirect mechanisms with various manifestations. The musculoskeletal involvement can manifest during COVID-19 infection, due to medications used for the treatment of COVID-19, and in the post/long COVID-19 syndrome. The major symptoms are fatigue, myalgia/arthralgia, back pain, low back pain, and chest pain. During the last two years, musculoskeletal involvement increased, but no clear consensus was obtained about the pathogenesis. However, there is valuable data that supports the hypothesis of angiotensinconverting enzyme 2, inflammation, hypoxia, and muscle catabolism. Additionally, medications that were used for treatment also have musculoskeletal adverse effects, such as corticosteroid-induced myopathy and osteoporosis. Therefore, while deciding the drugs, priorities and benefits should be taken into consideration. Symptoms that begin three months from the onset of the COVID-19 infection, continue for at least two months, and cannot be explained by another diagnosis is accepted as post/long COVID-19 syndrome. Prior symptoms may persist and fluctuate, or new symptoms may manifest. In addition, there must be at least one symptom of infection. Most common musculoskeletal symptoms are myalgia, arthralgia, fatigue, back pain, muscle weakness, sarcopenia, impaired exercise capacity, and physical performance. In addition, the female sex, obesity, elderly patients, hospitalization, prolonged immobility, having mechanical ventilation, not having vaccination, and comorbid disorders can be accepted as clinical predictors for post/long COVID-19 syndrome. Musculoskeletal pain is also a major problem and tends to be in chronic form. There is no consensus on the mechanism, but inflammation and angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 seem to play an important role. Localized and generalized pain may occur after COVID-19, and general pain is at least as common as localized pain. An accurate diagnosis allows physicians to initiate pain management and proper rehabilitation programs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023, Turkish Society of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Evcik</LastName><ForeName>Deniz</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1731-3463</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Ankara Private G&#xfc;ven Hospital, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Turkey</Country><MedlineTA>Turk J Phys Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101719024</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2587-1250</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post/long COVID-19.</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest: The authors declared no conflicts of interest with respect to the authorship and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37201006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10186015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5606/tftrd.2023.12521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Berger JR. COVID-19 and the nervous system. J Neurovirol. 2020;26:143&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32447630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> Available at: https://covid19.saglik.gov.tr/TR-66935/genelkoronavirus-tablosu.html .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falasca L, Nardacci R, Colombo D, Lalle E, Di Caro A, Nicastri E, et al. Postmortem findings in Italian patients with COVID-19: A descriptive full autopsy study of cases with and without comorbidities. J Infect Dis. 2020;222:1807&#x2013;1815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32914853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng KI, Feng G, Liu WY, Targher G, Byrne CD, Zheng MH. Extrapulmonary complications of COVID-19: A multisystem disease. J Med Virol. 2021;93:323&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7405144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32648973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechien JR, Chiesa-Estomba CM, Place S, Van Laethem Y, Cabaraux P, Mat Q, et al. Clinical and epidemiological characteristics of 1420 European patients with mildto-moderate coronavirus disease 2019. J Intern Med. 2020;288:335&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32352202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan LK, Deadwiler B, Haratian A, Bolia IK, Weber AE, Petrigliano FA. Effects of COVID-19 on the musculoskeletal system: Clinician&#x2019;s guide. Orthop Res Rev. 2021;13:141&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8464590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34584465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullahi A, Candan SA, Abba MA, Bello AH, Alshehri MA, Afamefuna Victor E, et al. Neurological and musculoskeletal features of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Neurol. 2020;11:687&#x2013;687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7333777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32676052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collantes MEV, Espiritu AI, Sy MCC, Anlacan VMM, Jamora RDG. Neurological manifestations in COVID-19 infection: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Can J Neurol Sci. 2021;48:66&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7492583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32665054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murat S, Dogruoz Karatekin B, Icagasioglu A, Ulasoglu C, &#x130;&#xe7;ten S, Incealtin O. Clinical presentations of pain in patients with COVID-19 infection. Ir J Med Sci. 2021;190:913&#x2013;917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7666574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33188626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuzun S, Keles A, Okutan D, Yildiran T, Palamar D. Assessment of musculoskeletal pain, fatigue and grip strength in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2021;57:653&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33393277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapra L, Saini C, Garg B, Gupta R, Verma B, Mishra PK, et al. Long-term implications of COVID-19 on bone health: Pathophysiology and therapeutics. Inflamm Res. 2022;71:1025&#x2013;1040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9330992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35900380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mi B, Xiong Y, Zhang C, Zhou W, Chen L, Cao F, et al. SARSCoV-2-induced overexpression of miR-4485 suppresses osteogenic differentiation and impairs fracture healing. Int J Biol Sci. 2021;17:1277&#x2013;1288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8040480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33867845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disser NP, De Micheli AJ, Schonk MM, Konnaris MA, Piacentini AN, Edon DL, et al. Musculoskeletal &#x441;onsequences of COVID-19. J Bone Joint Surg [Am] 2020;102:1197&#x2013;1204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32675661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meacci E, Pierucci F, Garcia-Gil M. Skeletal muscle and COVID-19: The potential involvement of bioactive sphingolipids. Biomedicines. 2022;10:1068&#x2013;1068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9138286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35625805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos PK, Sigoli E, Bragan&#xe7;a LJG, Cornachione AS. The musculoskeletal involvement after mild to moderate COVID-19 infection. Front Physiol. 2022;13:813924&#x2013;813924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9040683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35492595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrandi PJ, Alway SE, Mohamed JS. The interaction between SARS-CoV-2 and ACE2 may have consequences for skeletal muscle viral susceptibility and myopathies. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2020;129:864&#x2013;867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32673162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares MN, Eggelbusch M, Naddaf E, Gerrits KHL, van der Schaaf M, van den Borst B, et al. Skeletal muscle alterations in patients with acute Covid-19 and post-acute sequelae of Covid-19. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022;13:11&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8818659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34997689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali AM, Kunugi H. Skeletal muscle damage in COVID19: A call for action. Medicina (Kaunas) 2021;57:372&#x2013;372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8069858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33921429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trinity JD, Craig JC, Fermoyle CC, McKenzie AI, Lewis MT, Park SH, et al. Impact of presymptomatic COVID-19 on vascular and skeletal muscle function: A case study. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2021;130:1961&#x2013;1970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8213510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34002634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang X, Luo Y, Song Y, Fan H, Dong S, Liu P, et al. Neurological manifestations in COVID-19 and its possible mechanism. Aging (Albany NY) 2020;12:18754&#x2013;18764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7585068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32986016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Girolamo FG, Fiotti N, Sisto UG, Nunnari A, Colla S, Mearelli F, et al. Skeletal muscle in hypoxia and inflammation: Insights on the COVID-19 pandemic. Front Nutr. 2022;9:865402&#x2013;865402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9072827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35529457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awosanya OD, Dadwal UC, Imel EA, Yu Q, Kacena MA. The impacts of COVID-19 on musculoskeletal health. Curr Osteoporos Rep. 2022;20:213&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9207429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35723777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piotrowicz K, G&#x105;sowski J, Michel JP, Veronese N. PostCOVID-19 acute sarcopenia: Physiopathology and management. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2021;33:2887&#x2013;2898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8323089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34328636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welch C, Greig C, Masud T, Wilson D, Jackson TA. COVID-19 and acute sarcopenia. Welch C, Greig C, Masud T, Wilson D, Jackson TA. COVID-19 and acute sarcopenia. Aging Dis 2020;11:1345- 51. doi: 10.14336/AD.2020.1014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7673845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33269092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Andrade-Junior MC, de Salles ICD, de Brito CMM, Pastore-Junior L, Righetti RF, Yamaguti WP. Skeletal muscle wasting and function impairment in intensive care patients with severe COVID-19. Front Physiol. 2021;12:640973&#x2013;640973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7991788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33776796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paneroni M, Simonelli C, Saleri M, Bertacchini L, Venturelli M, Troosters T, et al. Muscle strength and physical performance in patients without previous disabilities recovering from COVID-19 pneumonia. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;100:105&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannah JR, Ali SS, Nagra D, Adas MA, Buazon AD, Galloway JB, et al. Skeletal muscles and Covid-19: A systematic review of rhabdomyolysis and myositis in SARSCoV-2 infection. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2022;40:329&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35225218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokhale Y, Patankar A, Holla U, Shilke M, Kalekar L, Karnik ND, et al. Dermatomyositis during COVID-19 pandemic (a case series): Is there a cause effect relationship. J Assoc Physicians India. 2020;68:20&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33187031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiersinga WJ, Rhodes A, Cheng AC, Peacock SJ, Prescott HC. Pathophysiology, transmission, diagnosis, and treatment of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): A review. JAMA. 2020;324:782&#x2013;793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32648899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anker MS, Landmesser U, von Haehling S, Butler J, Coats AJS, Anker SD. Weight loss, malnutrition, and cachexia in COVID-19: Facts and numbers. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2021;12:9&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7890265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33382211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wierdsma NJ, Kruizenga HM, Konings LA, Krebbers D, Jorissen JR, Joosten MI, et al. Poor nutritional status, risk of sarcopenia and nutrition related complaints are prevalent in COVID-19 patients during and after hospital admission. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2021;43:369&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Giorgio MR, Di Noia S, Morciano C, Conte D. The impact of SARS-CoV-2 on skeletal muscles. Acta Myol. 2020;39:307&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7783438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33458586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen L, Allard NAE, Saris CGJ, Keijer J, Hopman MTE, Timmers S. Muscle toxicity of drugs: When drugs turn physiology into pathophysiology. Physiol Rev. 2020;100:633&#x2013;672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31751166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izcovich A, Siemieniuk RA, Bartoszko JJ, Ge L, Zeraatkar D, Kum E, et al. Adverse effects of remdesivir, hydroxychloroquine and lopinavir/ritonavir when used for COVID-19: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised trials. e048502BMJ Open. 2022;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8895418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35236729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minetto MA, Lanfranco F, Motta G, Allasia S, Arvat E, D'Antona G. Steroid myopathy: Some unresolved issues. J Endocrinol Invest. 2011;34:370&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21677507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021. World Health Organization.  Available at: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_ case_definition-2021.1/ </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sis&#xf3;-Almirall A, Brito-Zer&#xf3;n P, Conangla Ferr&#xed;n L, Kostov B, Moragas Moreno A, Mestres J, et al. Long Covid-19: Proposed primary care clinical guidelines for diagnosis and disease management. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:4350&#x2013;4350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33923972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi G, Sanchis-Gomar F, Henry BM. COVID-19 and its long-term sequelae: What do we know in 2023. 16402Pol Arch Intern Med. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36626183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbarialiabad H, Taghrir MH, Abdollahi A, Ghahramani N, Kumar M, Paydar S, et al. Long COVID, a comprehensive systematic scoping review. Infection. 2021;49:1163&#x2013;1186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8317481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34319569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pires RE, Reis IGN, Waldolato GS, Pires DD, Bidolegui F, Giordano V. What do we need to know about musculoskeletal manifestations of COVID-19. : A systematic review. e22JBJS Rev. 2022;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35658089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter RS, Nieters A, Kr&#xe4;usslich HG, Brockmann SO, G&#xf6;pel S, Kindle G, et al. Post-acute sequelae of covid-19 six to 12 months after infection: Population based study. e071050BMJ. 2022;379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9557001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36229057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montes-Ibarra M, Oliveira CLP, Orsso CE, Landi F, Marzetti E, Prado CM. The impact of Long COVID-19 on muscle health. Clin Geriatr Med. 2022;38:545&#x2013;557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8934728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35868672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiala K, Martens J, Abd-Elsayed A. Post-COVID pain syndromes. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 2022;26:379&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8907389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35267156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet. 2022;399:2263&#x2013;2264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35717982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Cancela-Cilleruelo I, MoroL&#xf3;pez-Menchero P, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, G&#xf3;mezMayordomo V, Torres-Macho J, et al. Prevalence of musculoskeletal post-COVID pain in hospitalized COVID19 survivors depending on infection with the historical, alpha or delta SARS-CoV-2 variant. Biomedicines. 2022;10:1951&#x2013;1951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9406216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36009498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karaarslan F, G&#xfc;neri FD, Karde&#x15f; S. Long COVID: Rheumatologic/musculoskeletal symptoms in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors at 3 and 6 months. Clin Rheumatol. 2022;41:289&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8553494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34713356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bak&#x131;lan F, G&#xf6;kmen &#x130;G, Ortanca B, U&#xe7;an A, Eker G&#xfc;ven&#xe7; &#x15e;, &#x15e;ahin Mutlu F, et al. Musculoskeletal symptoms and related factors in postacute COVID-19 patients. e14734Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8420386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34387911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anaya JM, Rojas M, Salinas ML, Rodr&#xed;guez Y, Roa G, Lozano M, et al. Post-COVID syndrome. A case series and comprehensive review. Autoimmun Rev. 2021;20:102947&#x2013;102947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8428988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34509649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarantino U, Visconti VV, Bonanni R, Gatti A, Marcozzi M, Calabr&#xf2; D, et al. Osteosarcopenia and Long-COVID: A dangerous combination. 1759720X221130485Ther Adv Musculoskelet Dis. 2022;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9614591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36317068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Gassel RJJ, Bels J, Remij L, van Bussel BCT, Posthuma R, Gietema HA, et al. Functional outcomes and their association with physical performance in mechanically ventilated coronavirus disease 2019 survivors at 3 months following hospital discharge: A cohort study. Crit Care Med. 2021;49:1726&#x2013;1738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8439632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33967204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aschman T, Schneider J, Greuel S, Meinhardt J, Streit S, Goebel HH, et al. Association between SARS-CoV-2 infection and immune-mediated myopathy in patients who have died. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78:948&#x2013;960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34115106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoja O, Silva Passadouro B, Mulvey M, Delis I, Astill S, Tan AL, et al. Clinical characteristics and mechanisms of musculoskeletal pain in Long COVID. J Pain Res. 2022;15:1729&#x2013;1748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35747600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maamar M, Artime A, Pariente E, Fierro P, Ruiz Y, Guti&#xe9;rrez S, et al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome, low-grade inflammation and inflammatory markers: A crosssectional study. Curr Med Res Opin. 2022;38:901&#x2013;909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8935459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35166141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiala K, Martens J, Abd-Elsayed A. Post-COVID pain syndromes. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 2022;26:379&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8907389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35267156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Nijs J, Neblett R, Polli A, Moens M, Goudman L, et al. Phenotyping post-COVID pain as a nociceptive, neuropathic, or nociplastic pain condition. Biomedicines. 2022;10:2562&#x2013;2562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9599440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36289827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>