<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36426658</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2702</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Persistent symptoms among post-COVID-19 survivors: A&#xa0;systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>29</StartPage><EndPage>39</EndPage><MedlinePgn>29-39</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocn.16471</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Single studies support the presence of several post-COVID-19 symptoms; however, there is no evidence for the synthesis of symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We attempt to provide an overview of the persistent symptoms that post-COVID-19 patients encounter, as well as the duration of these symptoms to help them plan their rehabilitation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Systematic review and meta-analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 16 studies involving 8756 patients post-COVID-19 were included.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The CINAHL, PubMed, EMBASE, Scopus, and Web of Science databases were searched from 2019 to August 2021. Observational studies that reported data on post-COVID-19 symptoms were included. The methodological quality of the studies was assessed using the Joanna Briggs Institute Critical Appraisal for Observational Studies. We included medium- to high-quality studies. We used a random-effects model for the meta-analytical pooled prevalence of each post-COVID-19 symptom, and I<sup>2</sup> statistics for heterogeneity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">From the 2481 studies identified, 16 met the inclusion criteria. The sample included 7623 hospitalised and 1133 non-hospitalised patients. We found the most prevalent symptoms were fatigue and dyspnea with a pooled prevalence ranging from 42% (27%-58%). Other post-COVID-19 symptoms included sleep disturbance 28% (14%-45%), cough 25% (10%-44%), anosmia/ageusia 24% (7%-47%), fever 21% (4%-47%), myalgia 17% (2%-41%), chest pain 11% (5%-20%), and headache 9% (2%-20%). In addition to physical symptoms, anxiety/depression was also prevalent 27% (8%-53%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Fatigue and dyspnea were the most prevalent post-COVID-19 symptoms and experienced up to 12&#x2009;months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RELEVANCE TO CLINICAL PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Multiple persistent symptoms are still experienced until 12&#x2009;months of post-Covid 19. This meta-analysis should provide some awareness to nurses to highlights the unmet healthcare needs of post-COVID-19 patients. Long-term monitoring for the evaluation and treatment of symptoms and conditions and rehabilitation programs should be conducted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rochmawati</LastName><ForeName>Erna</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2193-6812</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Master in Nursing, Universitas Muhammadiyah Yogyakarta, Yogyakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iskandar</LastName><ForeName>Ayuk Cucuk</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5828-1990</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Universitas Borneo Tarakan, Tarakan, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamilah</LastName><ForeName>Farhah</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1427-6609</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Master in Nursing, Universitas Muhammadiyah Yogyakarta, Yogyakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9207302</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0962-1067</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002637" MajorTopicYN="N">Chest Pain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003371" MajorTopicYN="N">Cough</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004417" MajorTopicYN="N">Dyspnea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dyspnea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long hauler COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">persistent COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sequalae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survivor</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36426658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.16471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Afrin, L. B., Weinstock, L. B., &amp; Molderings, G. J. (2020). Covid-19 hyperinflammation and post-Covid-19 illness may be rooted in mast cell activation syndrome. International Journal of Infectious Diseases, 100, 327-332. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2020.09.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi, O. L., Hughes, S. E., Turner, G., Rivera, S. C., McMullan, C., Chandan, J. S., Haroon, S., Price, G., Davies, E. H., Nirantharakumar, K., Sapey, E., &amp; Calvert, M. J. (2021). Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: A review. Journal of the Royal Society of Medicine, 114(9), 428-442. https://doi.org/10.1177/01410768211032850</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkodaymi, M. S., Omrani, O. A., Fawzy, N. A., Shaar, B. A., Almamlouk, R., Riaz, M., Obeidat, M., Obeidat, Y., Gerberi, D., Taha, R. M., Kashour, Z., Kashour, T., Berbari, E. F., Alkattan, K., &amp; Tleyjeh, I. M. (2022). Prevalence of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome symptoms at different follow-up periods: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clinical Microbiology and Infection., 28, 657-666. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2022.01.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aromataris, E., &amp; Munn, Z., (Eds.), (2021). JBI Manual for Evidence Synthesis. JBI, 2020. ISBN: 978-0-6488488-0-6. https://synthesismanual.jbi.global. https://doi.org/10.46658/JBIMES-20-01</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin, M., Schommers, P., Stecher, M., Dewald, F., Gieselmann, L., Gruell, H., Horn, C., Vanshylla, K., Di Cristanziano, V., Osebold, L., Roventa, M., Riaz, T., Tschernoster, N., Altmueller, J., Rose, L., Salomon, S., Priesner, V., Luers, J. C., Alb, C., &#x2026; Lehmann, C. (2021). Post-COVID syndrome in non-hospitalised patients with COVID-19: A longitudinal prospective cohort study. The Lancet Regional Health - Europe, 6, 100122. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baradaran, A., Malek, A., Moazzen, N., &amp; Abbasi Shaye, Z. (2020). COVID-19 associated multisystem inflammatory syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Iranian Journal of Allergy, Asthma and Immunology, 19(6), 570-588. https://doi.org/10.18502/ijaai.v19i6.4927</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bardakci, M. I., Ozturk, E. N., Ozkarafakili, M. A., Ozkurt, H., Yanc, U., &amp; Yildiz Sevgi, D. (2021). Evaluation of long-term radiological findings, pulmonary functions, and health-related quality of life in survivors of severe COVID-19. Journal of Medical Virology, 93(9), 5574-5581. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.27101</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastola, A., Nepal, R., Shrestha, B., Maharjan, K., Shrestha, S., Chalise, B. S., &amp; Neupane, J. (2021). Persistent symptoms in post-COVID-19 patients attending follow-up OPD at Sukraraj tropical and infectious disease hospital (STIDH), Kathmandu, Nepal. Tropical Medicine and Infectious Disease, 6(3), 1-10. https://doi.org/10.3390/tropicalmed6030113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burki, T. K. (2021). Lifting of COVID-19 restrictions in the UKand the Delta variant. Lancet Respiratory Medicine, 9(8), e85. https://doi.org/10.1016/s2213-2600(21)00328-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cares-Marambio, K., Montenegro-Jim&#xe9;nez, Y., Torres-Castro, R., Vera-Uribe, R., Torralba, Y., Alsina-Restoy, X., Vasconcello-Castillo, L., &amp; Vilar&#xf3;, J. (2021). Prevalence of potential respiratory symptoms in survivors of hospital admission after coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): A systematic review and meta-analysis. Chronic Respiratory Disease, 18, 14799731211002240. https://doi.org/10.1177/14799731211002240</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caronna, E., Ballv&#xe9;, A., Llaurad&#xf3;, A., Gallardo, V. J., Ariton, D. M., Lallana, S., Maza, S. L., Gadea, M. O., Quibus, L., Restrepo, J. L., Rodrigo-Gisbert, M., Vilaseca, A., Gonzalez, M. H., Gallo, M. M., Alpuente, A., Torres-Ferrus, M., Borrell, R. P., Alvarez-Sabin, J., &amp; Pozo-Rosich, P. (2020). Headache: A striking prodromal and persistent symptom, predictive of COVID-19 clinical evolution. Cephalalgia, 40(13), 1410-1421. https://doi.org/10.1177/0333102420965157</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Schneider, C., Laurent, E., Lemaignen, A., Beaufils, E., Bourbao-Tournois, C., Laribi, S., Flament, T., Ferreira-Maldent, N., Bruy&#xe8;re, F., Stefic, K., Gaudy-Graffin, C., Grammatico-Guillon, L., &amp; Bernard, L. (2021). Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 27(2), 258-263. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2020.09.052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ejaz, H., Alsrhani, A., Zafar, A., Javed, H., Junaid, K., Abdalla, A. E., Abosalif, K. O., Ahmed, Z., &amp; Younas, S. (2020). COVID-19 and comorbidities: Deleterious impact on infected patients. Journal of Infection and Public Health, 13(12), 1833-1839. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiph.2020.07.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinholt, T., Doddapaneni, H., Qin, X., Menon, V., Meng, Q., Metcalf, G., Chao, H., Gingras, M.-C., Avadhanula, V., Farinholt, P., Agrawal, C., Muzny, D. M., Piedra, P. A., Gibbs, R. A., &amp; Petrosino, J. (2021). Transmission event of SARS-CoV-2 delta variant reveals multiple vaccine breakthrough infections. BMC Medicine, 19(1), 255. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12916-021-02103-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as, C., Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a, D., G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo, V., Florencio, L. L., Cuadrado, M. L., Plaza-Manzano, G., &amp; Navarro-Santana, M. (2021). Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: A systematic review and meta-analysis. European Journal of Internal Medicine, 92, 55-70. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejim.2021.06.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh, T., Knight, M., A'Court, C., Buxton, M., &amp; Husain, L. (2020). Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ, 370, m3026. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m3026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin, S. J., McIvor, C., Whyatt, G., Adams, A., Harvey, O., McLean, L., Walshaw, C., Kemp, S., Corrado, J., Singh, R., Collins, T., O'Connor, R. J., &amp; Sivan, M. (2021). Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. Journal of Medical Virology, 93(2), 1013-1022. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.26368</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, X., Hong, W., Pan, X., Lu, G., &amp; Wei, X. (2021). SARS-CoV-2 omicron variant: Characteristics and prevention. MedComm, 2(4), 838-845. https://doi.org/10.1002/mco2.110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C., Huang, L., Wang, Y., Li, X., Ren, L., Gu, X., Kang, L., Guo, L., Liu, M., Zhou, X., Luo, J., Huang, Z., Tu, S., Zhao, Y., Chen, L., Xu, D., Li, Y., Li, C., Peng, L., &#x2026; Cao, B. (2021). 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: A cohort study. The Lancet, 397(10270), 220-232. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal, A., Iqbal, K., Arshad Ali, S., Azim, D., Farid, E., Baig, M. D., Arif, T. B., &amp; Raza, M. (2021). The COVID-19 sequelae: A cross-sectional evaluation of post-recovery symptoms and the need for rehabilitation of COVID-19 survivors. Cureus, 13(2), e13080. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.13080</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal, M., Abo Omirah, M., Hussein, A., &amp; Saeed, H. (2021). Assessment and characterisation of post-COVID-19 manifestations. International Journal of Clinical Practice, 75(3), e13746. https://doi.org/10.1111/ijcp.13746</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandeel, M., Mohamed, M. E. M., Abd El-Lateef, H. M., Venugopala, K. N., &amp; El-Beltagi, H. S. (2022). Omicron variant genome evolution and phylogenetics. Journal of Medical Virology, 94(4), 1627-1632. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.27515</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayaaslan, B., Eser, F., Kalem, A. K., Kaya, G., Kaplan, B., Kacar, D., Hasanoglu, I., Coskun, B., &amp; Guner, R. (2021). Post-COVID syndrome: A single-center questionnaire study on 1007 participants recovered from COVID-19. Journal of Medical Virology, 93(12), 6566-6574. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.27198</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodeir, M. M., Shabana, H. A., Rasheed, Z., Alkhamiss, A. S., Khodeir, M., Alkhowailed, M. S., Alharbi, S., Alsoghair, M., Alsagaby, S. A., &amp; Al Abdulmonem, W. (2021). COVID-19: Post-recovery long-term symptoms among patients in Saudi Arabia. PLoS One, 16(12), e0260259. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0260259</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, M. K., Lee, B., Choi, Y. Y., Um, J., Lee, K. S., Sung, H. K., Kim, Y., Park, J.-S., Lee, M., Jang, H.-C., Bang, J. H., Chung, K.-H., &amp; Jeon, J. (2022). Clinical characteristics of 40 patients infected with the SARS-CoV-2 omicron variant in Korea. Journal of Korean Medical Science, 37(3), e31. https://doi.org/10.3346/jkms.2022.37.e31</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladds, E., Rushforth, A., Wieringa, S., Taylor, S., Rayner, C., Husain, L., &amp; Greenhalgh, T. (2020). Persistent symptoms after Covid-19: Qualitative study of 114 "long Covid" patients and draft quality principles for services. BMC Health Services Research, 20(1), 1144. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913-020-06001-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite, V. F., Rampim, D. B., Jorge, V. C., de Lima, M., Cezarino, L. G., da Rocha, C. N., &amp; Esper, R. B. (2021). Persistent symptoms and disability after COVID-19 hospitalization: Data from a comprehensive telerehabilitation program. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, 102(7), 1308-1316. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmr.2021.03.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Q., Guan, X., Wu, P., Wang, X., Zhou, L., Tong, Y., Ren, R., Leung, K. S. M., Lau, E. H. Y., Wong, J. Y., Xing, X., Xiang, N., Wu, Y., Li, C., Chen, Q., Li, D., Liu, T., Zhao, J., Liu, M., &#x2026; Feng, Z. (2020). Early transmission dynamics in Wuhan, China, of novel coronavirus-infected pneumonia. The New England Journal of Medicine, 382(13), 1199-1207. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2001316</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon, S., Wegman-Ostrosky, T., Perelman, C., Sepulveda, R., Rebolledo, P. A., Cuapio, A., &amp; Villapol, S. (2021). More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Scientific Reports, 11(1), 16144. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, R., Zhao, X., Li, J., Niu, P., Yang, B., Wu, H., Wang, W., Song, H., Huang, B., &amp; Zhu, N. (2020). Genomic characterisation and epidemiology of 2019 novel coronavirus: Implications for virus origins and receptor binding. The Lancet, 395(10224), 565-574. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30251-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik, P., Patel, K., Pinto, C., Jaiswal, R., Tirupathi, R., Pillai, S., &amp; Patel, U. (2022). Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PCS) and health-related quality of life (HRQoL)-A systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Medical Virology, 94(1), 253-262. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.27309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monti, G., Leggieri, C., Fominskiy, E., Scandroglio, A. M., Colombo, S., Tozzi, M., Moizo, E., Mucci, M., Crivellari, M., Pieri, M., Guzzo, F., Piemontese, S., De Lorenzo, R., Da Prat, V., Fedrizzi, M., Faustini, C., Di Piazza, M., Conte, F., Lembo, R., &#x2026; Zangrillo, A. (2021). Two-months quality of life of COVID-19 invasively ventilated survivors; an Italian single-center study. The Acta Anaesthesiologica Scandinavica Foundation, 65(7), 912-920. https://doi.org/10.1111/aas.13812</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin, L., Savale, L., Pham, T., Colle, R., Figueiredo, S., Harrois, A., Gasnier, M., Lecoq, A.-L., Meyrignac, O., Noel, N., Baudry, E., Bellin, M.-F., Beurnier, A., Choucha, W., Corruble, E., Dortet, L., Hardy-L&#xe9;ger, I., Radiguer, F., Sportouch, S., &#x2026; Monnet, X. (2021). Four-month clinical status of a cohort of patients after hospitalization for COVID-19. JAMA, 325(15), 1525-1534. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2021.3331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostafaei, H., Sadeghi-Bazargani, H., Hajebrahimi, S., Salehi-Pourmehr, H., Ghojazadeh, M., Onur, R., Al Mousa, R. T., &amp; Oelke, M. (2020). Prevalence of female urinary incontinence in the developing world: A systematic review and meta-analysis-A report from the developing world Committee of the International Continence Society and Iranian Research Center for evidence based medicine. Neurourology and Urodynamics, 39(4), 1063-1086.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onder, G., Rezza, G., &amp; Brusaferro, S. (2020). Case-fatality rate and characteristics of patients dying in relation to COVID-19 in Italy. JAMA, 323(18), 1775-1776. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.4683</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page, M. J., Moher, D., Bossuyt, P. M., Boutron, I., Hoffmann, T. C., Mulrow, C. D., Shamseer, L., Tetzlaff, J. M., Akl, E. A., Brennan, S. E., &amp; Chou, R. (2021). PRISMA 2020 explanation and elaboration: Updated guidance and exemplars for reporting systematic reviews. Bmj, 372, 1-36. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n160</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj, L., Kannapadi, N. V., Briggs, J., Seal, S. M., Battaglini, D., Fanning, J., Suen, J., Robba, C., Fraser, J., &amp; Cho, S. M. (2022). Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: A meta-analysis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 434, 120162. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2022.120162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran, A. V., Jayadevan, R., &amp; Sashidharan, S. (2021). Long COVID: An overview. Diabetes &amp; Metabolic Syndrome: Clinical Research &amp; Reviews, 15(3), 869-875. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dsx.2021.04.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salamanna, F., Veronesi, F., Martini, L., Landini, M. P., &amp; Fini, M. (2021). Post-COVID-19 syndrome: The persistent symptoms at the post-viral stage of the disease. A systematic review of the current data. Frontiers in Medicine, 8, 653516. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2021.653516</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schou, T. M., Joca, S., Wegener, G., &amp; Bay-Richter, C. (2021). Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19-A systematic review. Brain Behavior and Immunity, 97, 328-348. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2021.07.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoucri, S. M., Purpura, L., DeLaurentis, C., Adan, M. A., Theodore, D. A., Irace, A. L., Robbins-Juarez, S. Y., Khedagi, A. M., Letchford, D., Harb, A. A., Zerihun, L. M., Lee, K. E., Gambina, K., Lauring, M. C., Chen, N., Sperring, C. P., Mehta, S. S., Myers, E. L., Shih, H., &#x2026; Zucker, J. E. (2021). Characterising the long-term clinical outcomes of 1190 hospitalised patients with COVID-19 in New York City: A retrospective case series. BMJ Open, 11(6), 1-9. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2021-049488</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, W.-J., Hui, C. K. M., Hull, J. H., Birring, S. S., McGarvey, L., Mazzone, S. B., &amp; Chung, K. F. (2021). Confronting COVID-19-associated cough and the post-COVID syndrome: Role of viral neurotropism, neuroinflammation, and neuroimmune responses. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine, 9(5), 533-544. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00125-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem, K., Ghanima, W., Olsen, M. K., Gilboe, H. M., &amp; Einvik, G. (2021). Prevalence and determinants of fatigue after COVID-19 in non-hospitalized subjects: A population-based study. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 18(4), 1-11. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18042030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, R. R., Trivedi, B., Patel, N., Singh, R., Ricketts, W. M., Elliott, K., Yarwood, M., White, V., Hylton, H., Allen, R., Thomas, G., Kapil, V., McGuckin, R., &amp; Pfeffer, P. E. (2021). Post-COVID symptoms reported at asynchronous virtual review and stratified follow-up after COVID-19 pneumonia. Clinical Medicine, 21, e384-e391. https://doi.org/10.7861/clinmed.2021-0037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde, M. W., Kim, S. S., Lindsell, C. J., Billig Rose, E., Shapiro, N. I., Files, D. C., Gibbs, K. W., Erickson, H. L., Steingrub, J. S., Smithline, H. A., Gong, M. N., Aboodi, M. S., Exline, M. C., Henning, D. J., Wilson, J. G., Khan, A., Qadir, N., Brown, S. M., Peltan, I. D., &#x2026; Feldstein, L. R. (2020). Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network-United States, march-June 2020. Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report, 69(30), 993-998. https://doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm6930e1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend, L., Dowds, J., O'Brien, K., Sheill, G., Dyer, A. H., O'Kelly, B., Hynes, J. P., Mooney, A., Dunne, J., Cheallaigh, C. N., O'Farrelly, C., Bourke, N. M., Conlon, N., Martin-Loeches, I., Bergin, C., Nadarajan, P., &amp; Bannan, C. (2021). Persistent poor health after COVID-19 is not associated with respiratory complications or initial disease severity. Annals of the American Thoracic Society, 18(6), 997-1003. https://doi.org/10.1513/AnnalsATS.202009-1175OC</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend, L., Dyer, A. H., Jones, K., Dunne, J., Mooney, A., Gaffney, F., O'Connor, L., Leavy, D., O'Brien, K., Dowds, J., Sugrue, J. A., Hopkins, D., Martin-Loeches, I., Cheallaigh, C. N., Nadarajan, P., McLaughlin, A. M., Bourke, N. M., Bergin, C., O'Farrell, C., &#x2026; Conlon, N. (2020). Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One, 15(11), e0240784. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0240784</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trigo, J., Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n, D., Planchuelo-G&#xf3;mez, &#xc1;., Mart&#xed;nez-P&#xed;as, E., Talavera, B., Hern&#xe1;ndez-P&#xe9;rez, I., Valle-Pe&#xf1;acoba, G., Sim&#xf3;n-Campo, P., de Lera, M., Chavarr&#xed;a-Miranda, A., L&#xf3;pez-Sanz, C., Guti&#xe9;rrez-S&#xe1;nchez, M., Mart&#xed;nez-Velasco, E., Pedraza, M., Sierra, &#xc1;., G&#xf3;mez-Vicente, B., Arenillas, J. F., &amp; Guerrero, &#xc1;. L. (2020). Factors associated with the presence of headache in hospitalized COVID-19 patients and impact on prognosis: A retrospective cohort study. The Journal of Headache and Pain, 21(1), 94. https://doi.org/10.1186/s10194-020-01165-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venturelli, S., Benatti, S. V., Casati, M., Binda, F., Zuglian, G., Imeri, G., Conti, C., Biffi, A. M., Spada, M. S., Bondi, E., Camera, G., Severgnini, R., Giammarresi, A., Marinaro, C., Rossini, A., Bonaffini, P. A., Guerra, G., Bellasi, A., Cesa, S., &amp; Rizzi, M. (2021). Surviving COVID-19 in Bergamo Province: A post-acute outpatient re-evaluation. Epidemiology and Infection., 149, e32. https://doi.org/10.1017/s0950268821000145</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vindegaard, N., &amp; Benros, M. E. (2020). COVID-19 pandemic and mental health consequences: Systematic review of the current evidence. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 89, 531-542. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2020.05.048</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. (2020). Clinical management of severe acute respiratory infection (SARI) when COVID-19 disease is suspected: interim guidance, 13 March 2020. https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/331446</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willi, S., L&#xfc;thold, R., Hunt, A., H&#xe4;nggi, N. V., Sejdiu, D., Scaff, C., Bender, N., Staub, K., &amp; Schlagenhauf, P. (2021). COVID-19 sequelae in adults aged less than 50&#x2009;years: A systematic review. Travel Medicine and Infectious Disease, 40, 101995. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tmaid.2021.101995</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2022). WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard. https://covid19.who.int/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, X., Liu, X., Zhou, Y., Yu, H., Li, R., Zhan, Q., Ni, F., Fang, S., Lu, Y., Ding, X., Liu, H., Ewing, R. M., Jones, M. G., Hu, Y., Nie, H., &amp; Wang, Y. (2021). 3-Month, 6-month, 9-month, and 12-month respiratory outcomes in patients following COVID-19-related hospitalisation: A prospective study. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine, 9(7), 747-754. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00174-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong, Q., Xu, M., Li, J., Liu, Y., Zhang, J., Xu, Y., &amp; Dong, W. (2021). Clinical sequelae of COVID-19 survivors in Wuhan, China: A single-Centre longitudinal study. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 27(1), 89-95. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2020.09.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. J., Dong, X., Cao, Y. Y., Yuan, Y. D., Yang, Y. B., Yan, Y. Q., Akdis, C. A., &amp; Gao, Y. D. (2020). Clinical characteristics of 140 patients infected with SARS-CoV-2 in Wuhan, China. Allergy, 75(7), 1730-1741. https://doi.org/10.1111/all.14238</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X., Wang, F., Shen, Y., Zhang, X., Cen, Y., Wang, B., Zhao, S., Zhou, Y., Hu, B., Wang, M., Liu, Y., Miao, H., Jones, P., Ma, X., He, Y., Cao, G., Cheng, L., &amp; Li, L. (2021). Symptoms and health outcomes among survivors of COVID-19 infection 1 year after discharge from hospitals in Wuhan, China. JAMA Network Open, 4(9), e2127403. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.27403</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>