<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37859788</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2185-5323</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Japanese journal of comprehensive rehabilitation science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Jpn J Compr Rehabil Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Changes in respiratory, physical, and mental conditions in moderate and severe COVID-19 cases at our convalescent rehabilitation ward.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>10</StartPage><EndPage>15</EndPage><MedlinePgn>10-15</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.11336/jjcrs.14.10</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Akimoto K, Asano S, Satoh Y, Yokogushi K. Changes in respiratory, physical, and mental conditions in moderate and severe COVID-19 cases at our convalescent rehabilitation ward. Jpn J Compr Rehabil Sci 2023; 14: 10-15.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study clarified the changes in respiratory condition, and physical and mental functions pertaining to them, of patients with the coronavirus disease 2019 ("COVID-19") who were admitted to our convalescent rehabilitation ward. It also examined the conditions remaining after the disease (long-COVID).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We focused on 16 moderate and severe patients with COVID-19 who were transferred to our convalescent rehabilitation ward and discharged home between March and September 2021. We evaluated the patients' respiratory, physical, and mental conditions at the time of admission, four weeks after admission, and at the time of discharge.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We confirmed an improvement in the shortness of breath in those with respiratory conditions, and a significant improvement in the walking distance related to physical function before the time of discharge, but anxiety and depression remained.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patients with moderate to severe COVID-19 can be discharged home after convalescent rehabilitation. Despite improved dyspnea and walking distance, the patients tend to have incomplete recovery, including physical deconditioning, mood disorders, and other long-COVID conditions at discharge.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Kaifukuki Rehabilitation Ward Association 2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akimoto</LastName><ForeName>Kentaro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Education and Training, Sapporo Keijinkai Rehabilitation Hospital, Hokkaido, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asano</LastName><ForeName>Shinjiro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Education and Training, Sapporo Keijinkai Rehabilitation Hospital, Hokkaido, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Satoh</LastName><ForeName>Yoshifumi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Sapporo Keijinkai Rehabilitation Hospital, Hokkaido, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yokogushi</LastName><ForeName>Kazutoshi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Sapporo Keijinkai Rehabilitation Hospital, Hokkaido, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Jpn J Compr Rehabil Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918556585006676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2185-5323</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">convalescent rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">moderate to severe COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory symptom</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest: The authors declare that there was no corporate involvement in this study that could represent an actual or potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37859788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10585009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11336/jjcrs.14.10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Higgins V, Sohaei D, Diamandis EP, Prassas I.. COVID-19: from an acute to chronic disease? Potential long-term health consequences. Crit Rev Clin Lab Sci 2021; 58: 297-310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33347790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delbressine JM, Machado FVC, Go&#xeb;rtz YMJ, Van Herck M, Meys R, Houben-Wilke S, et al.. The Impact of Post-COVID-19 Syndrome on Self-Reported Physical Activity. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021; 18: 6017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8199934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34205086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng J, Zhou F, Hou W, Silver Z, Wong CY, Chang O, et al.. The prevalence of depression, anxiety, and sleep disturbances in COVID-19 patients: a meta-analysis. Ann N Y Acad Sci 2021; 1486: 90-111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33009668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministryof Health,
Labourand Welfare.. 
86th
COVID-19 Control Advisory Board: Sample References. Available
from: https://www.mhlw.go.jp/content/10900000/000945990.pdf
(cited 2022 July
23).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministryof Health,
Labourand Welfare.. 
COVID-19
Medical treatment guide. separate volume. management of post COVID-19
condition. 2022;
1-1. Available from: https://www.mhlw.go.jp/content/000952700.pdf
(cited 2022 July
23).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministryof Health,
Labourand Welfare.. 
COVID-19
Medical treatment guide. 2022;
7-2. Available from: https://www.mhlw.go.jp/content/000936623.pdf
(cited 2022 July
23).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Initiative for
Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease (GOLD) .
The Global Strategy for the Diagnosis, Management and
Prevention of COPD, 2022: Sample References.
Available from: http://www.goldcopd.org/.(cited
2022 July 23).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daynes E, Gerlis C, Briggs-Price S, Jones P, Singh SJ.. COPD assessment test for the evaluation of COVID-19 symptoms. Thorax 2021; 76: 185-187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33148809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraiva MD, Apolinario D, Avelino-Silva TJ, de Assis Moura Tavares C, Gatt&#xe1;s-Vernaglia IF, Marques Fernandes C, et al.. The Impact of Frailty on the Relationship between Life-Space Mobility and Quality of Life in Older Adults during the COVID-19 Pandemic. J Nutr Health Aging 2021; 25: 440-447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7678592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33786560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickton FM, Chisati E, Rylance J, Morton B.. An Improvised Pulmonary Telerehabilitation Program for Postacute COVID-19 Patients Would Be Feasible and Acceptable in a Low-Resource Setting. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 2021; 100: 209-212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7886367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33395048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guralnik JM, Simonsick EM, Ferrucci L, Glynn RJ, Berkman LF, Blazer DG, et al.. A short physical performance battery assessing lower extremity function: association with self-reported disability and prediction of mortality and nursing home admission. J Gerontol 1994; 49: 85-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8126356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Boon GJAM, Barco S, Endres M, Geelhoed JJM, Knauss S, et al.: The Post-COVID-19 Functional Status scale: a tool to measure functional status over time after COVID-19. Eur Respir J 2020; 56: 2001494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirwan R, McCullough D, Butler T, Perez de Heredia F, Davies IG, Stewart C.. Sarcopenia during COVID-19 lockdown restrictions: long-term health effects of short-term muscle loss. Geroscience 2020; 42: 1547-1578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7528158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33001410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Data management service of the Uniform Data System for Medical Rehabilitation and the Center for Functional Assessment Research.. Guide for use of the uniform data set for medical rehabilitation. State University of New York; at Buffalo. Version 3.0. March 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Sonoda S, Domen K.. Stroke Impairment Assessment Set (SIAS) and Functional Independence Measure (FIM) and their practical use. In: Chino N, ed. Functional Assessment of Stroke Patients: Practical Aspects of SIAS and FIM. Tokyo: SplingerVerlag; 1997: 17-139. Japanese.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuji T, Sonoda S, Domen K, Saitoh E, Liu M, Chino N.. ADL structure for stroke patients in Japan based on the functional independence measure. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 1995; 74: 432-438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8534387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada S, Liu M, Hase K, Tanaka N, Fujiwara T, Tsuji T, et al.. Development of a short version of the motor FIM for use in long-term care settings. J Rehabil Med 2006; 38: 50-56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16548088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones PW, Adamek L, Nadeau G, Banik N.. Comparisons of health status scores with MRC grades in COPD: implications for the GOLD 2011 classification. Eur Respir J 2013; 42: 647-654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23258783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Zhang W, Yang Y, Zhang J, Li Y, Chen Y.. Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: A randomized controlled study. Complement Ther Clin Pract 2020; 39: 101166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellan M, Soddu D, Balbo PE, Baricich A, Zeppegno P, Avanzi GC, et al.. Respiratory and Psychophysical Sequelae Among Patients With COVID-19 Four Months After Hospital Discharge. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4: 2036142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7841464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33502487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a M, de-la-Llave-Rinc&#xf3;n AI, Fuensalida-Novo S, Florencio LL, et al.. Psychometric Properties of the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS) in Previously Hospitalized COVID-19 Patients. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022; 19: 9273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9367824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35954630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang LL, Yang T.. Pulmonary rehabilitation for patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Chronic Dis Transl Med 2020; 6: 79-86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7221406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32411496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>