<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38975933</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3724</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical journal of sport medicine : official journal of the Canadian Academy of Sport Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin J Sport Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19 Infection in Ultramarathon Runners: Findings of the Ultrarunners Longitudinal TRAcking Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>597</StartPage><EndPage>602</EndPage><MedlinePgn>597-602</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001252</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Ultramarathon runners are a unique patient population who have been shown to have a lower rate of severe chronic medical conditions. This study aimed to determine the effect that COVID-19 infection has had on this population and their running behavior.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">The Ultrarunners Longitudinal TRAcking (ULTRA) Study is a large longitudinal study of ultramarathon runners. Questions on health status, running behavior, and COVID-19 infection were included in the most recent survey.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">Community survey.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Seven hundred thirty-four ultramarathon runners participated in the study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS" NlmCategory="METHODS">None.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Personal, exercise, and COVID-19 infection history.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">52.7% of study participants reported having been symptomatic from a COVID-19 infection, with 6.7% testing positive multiple times. Participants required a total of 4 days of hospitalization. The most common symptoms included fever (73.6%), fatigue (68.5%), sore throat (68.2%), runny nose (67.7%), and cough (67.4%). Cardiovascular symptoms, which are of particular interest in the running population, included shortness of breath (46.3%), tachycardia (44.7%), chest pain (36.2%), and wheezing (33.3%). A total of 50 subjects (6.8%) reported long COVID (symptoms lasting more than 12 weeks).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Severe COVID-19 infection has been rare in this population of ultramarathon runners, although symptomatic infection that affects running is common. To support the well-being of this group of highly active athletes, clinicians should appreciate that cardiovascular symptoms are common and the long-term significance of these symptoms in runners is unknown.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level 2 prospective study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jastifer</LastName><ForeName>James R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9559-2736</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Ascension Borgess Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Western Michigan University Homer Stryker MD School of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jastifer</LastName><ForeName>Ethan J</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Ascension Borgess Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Western Michigan University Homer Stryker MD School of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffman</LastName><ForeName>Martin D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Ascension Borgess Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Western Michigan University Homer Stryker MD School of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin J Sport Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9103300</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1050-642X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000081642" MajorTopicYN="Y">Marathon Running</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="N">Running</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006760" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitalization</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38975933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042752-990000000-00208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Basics of COVID-19: Center for Disease Control and Prevention; 2021. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/your-health/about-covid-19/basics-covid-19.html . Accessed March 1, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal M. Cardiovascular disease and COVID-19. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2020;14:247&#x2013;250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Chen L, Krishnan E. Body mass index and its correlates in 1,212 ultramarathon runners: baseline findings from the ULTRA study. J Phys Act Health. 2014;11:1549&#x2013;1555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Krishnan E. Health and exercise-related medical issues among 1,212 ultramarathon runners: baseline findings from the Ultrarunners Longitudinal TRAcking (ULTRA) Study. PloS one. 2014;9:e83867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Krishnan E. Exercise behavior of ultramarathon runners: baseline findings from the ULTRA study. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27:2939&#x2013;2945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Krouse R. Ultra-obligatory running among ultramarathon runners. Res Sports Med. 2018;26:211&#x2013;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. World Health Organization A Clinical Case Definition of Post COVID-19 Condition by a Delphi Consensus; 2021. Available at: https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/345824 . Accessed February 21, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. World Health Organization Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19): Post COVID-19 Condition; 2021. Available at: https://www.who.int/news-room/questions-and-answers/item/coronavirus-disease-(covid-19)-post-covid-19-condition . Accessed February 21, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajpal S, Tong MS, Borchers J, et al. Cardiovascular magnetic resonance findings in competitive athletes recovering from COVID-19 infection. JAMA Cardiol. 2021;6:116&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, Brito GM, Pinto AJ, et al. High SARS-CoV-2 infection rate after resuming professional football in S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil. Br J Sports Med. 2021;56:1004&#x2013;1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumacher YO, Tabben M, Hassoun K, et al. Resuming professional football (soccer) during the COVID-19 pandemic in a country with high infection rates: a prospective cohort study. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55:1092&#x2013;1098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemes IR, Smaira FI, Ribeiro WJD, et al. Acute and post-acute COVID-19 presentations in athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56:941&#x2013;947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulson N, Petek BJ, Drezner JA, et al. SARS-CoV-2 cardiac involvement in young competitive athletes. Circulation. 2021; 144:256&#x2013;266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma&#x142;ek &#x141;A, Marczak M, Mi&#x142;osz-Wieczorek B, et al. Cardiac involvement in consecutive elite athletes recovered from Covid-19: a magnetic resonance study. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2021;53:1723&#x2013;1729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntmann VO, Carerj ML, Wieters I, et al. Outcomes of cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in patients recently recovered from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:1265&#x2013;1273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leidman E, Duca LM, Omura JD, et al. COVID-19 trends among persons aged 0-24 Years: United States, March 1-December 12, 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2021;70:88&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logue JK, Franko NM, McCulloch DJ, et al. Sequelae in adults at 6 Months after COVID-19 infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e210830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Scientific Rep. 2021;11:16144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, et al. Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis. 2022;226:1593&#x2013;1607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>JonathanKim HM, Baggish AL, et al. COVID-19 and the athletic heart: key updates from the American college of cardiology sports &amp; exercise leadership council: American college of cardiology; 2022. Available at: https://www.acc.org/Membership/Sections-and-Councils/Sports-and-Exercise-Cardiology-Section/Section-Updates/2022/01/24/19/52/COVID-19-and-the-Athletic-Heart . Accessed 16, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Levine BD, Phelan D, et al. Coronavirus disease 2019 and the athletic heart: emerging perspectives on pathology, risks, and return to play. JAMA Cardiol. 2021;6:219&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez MW, Tucker AM, Bloom OJ, et al. Prevalence of inflammatory heart disease among professional athletes with prior COVID-19 infection who received systematic return-to-play cardiac screening. JAMA Cardiol. 2021;6:745&#x2013;752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels CJ, Rajpal S, Greenshields JT, et al. Prevalence of clinical and subclinical myocarditis in competitive athletes with recent SARS-CoV-2 infection: results from the big ten COVID-19 cardiac registry. JAMA Cardiol. 2021;6:1078&#x2013;1087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson RJ, Campbell JP, Gleeson M, et al. Can exercise affect immune function to increase susceptibility to infection?. Exerc Immunol Rev. 2020;26:8&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebhard C, Regitz-Zagrosek V, Neuhauser HK, et al. Impact of sex and gender on COVID-19 outcomes in Europe. Biol Sex Differences. 2020;11:29&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scully EP, Haverfield J, Ursin RL, et al. Considering how biological sex impacts immune responses and COVID-19 outcomes. Nat Rev Immunol. 2020;20:442&#x2013;447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabeer N, Razavi S, van der Meulen Rodgers Y. Feminist economic perspectives on the COVID-19 pandemic. Fem Econ. 2021;27:1&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viveiros A, Rasmuson J, Vu J, et al. Sex differences in COVID-19: candidate pathways, genetics of ACE2, and sex hormones. Am J Physiol-Heart Circ Physiol. 2021;320:H296&#x2013;H304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin J-M, Bai P, He W, et al. Gender differences in patients with COVID-19: focus on severity and mortality. Front Public Health. 2020;8:152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee S, Pahan K. Is COVID-19 gender-sensitive? J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2021;16:38&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pijls BG, Jolani S, Atherley A, et al. Demographic risk factors for COVID-19 infection, severity, ICU admission and death: a meta-analysis of 59 studies. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e044640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma G, Volgman AS, Michos ED. Sex differences in mortality from COVID-19 pandemic: are men vulnerable and women protected? JACC Case Reports. 2020;2:1407&#x2013;1410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenham C, Smith J, Morgan R, et al. COVID-19: the gendered impacts of the outbreak. Lancet (London, England). 2020;395:846&#x2013;848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Krishnan E. Health and exercise-related medical issues among 1,212 ultramarathon runners: baseline findings from the Ultrarunners Longitudinal TRAcking (ULTRA) Study. PloS One. 2014;9:e83867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma KC, Dorabawila V, Le&#xf3;n TM, et al. Trends in laboratory-confirmed SARS-CoV-2 reinfections and associated hospitalizations and deaths among adults aged &#x2265;18 Years: 18 U.S. Jurisdictions, september 2021&#x2013;december 2022. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2023;72:683&#x2013;689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD. Anthropometric characteristics of ultramarathoners. Int J Sports Med. 2008;29:808&#x2013;811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD. Ultramarathon trail running comparison of performance-matched men and women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:1681&#x2013;1686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD. Performance trends in 161-km ultramarathons. Int J Sports Med. 2010;31:31&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Fogard K. Factors related to successful completion of a 161-km ultramarathon. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2011;6:25&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Fogard K. Demographic characteristics of 161-km ultramarathon runners. Res Sports Med (Print). 2012;20:59&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Lebus DK, Ganong AC, et al. Body composition of 161-km ultramarathoners. Int J Sports Med. 2010;31:106&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Ong JC, Wang G. Historical analysis of participation in 161 km ultramarathons in North America. Int J Hist Sport. 2010;27:1877&#x2013;1891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Wegelin JA. The western States 100-mile endurance run: participation and performance trends. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:2191&#x2013;2198.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>