<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35012590</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1824-7288</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Italian journal of pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ital J Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reasons in favour of universal vaccination campaign against COVID-19 in the pediatric population.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4</StartPage><MedlinePgn>4</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13052-021-01192-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Despite the growing evidence of the extreme efficacy of COVID-19 vaccines in adults and the elderly, the administration of the same prophylactic measures to pediatric subjects is debated by some parents and by a number of researchers. The aim of this manuscript is to explain the reasons for overcoming hesitancy towards COVID-19 vaccination in children and adolescents and to highlight the importance of universal COVID-19 vaccination in the pediatric population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Recent epidemiological data suggest that the risk that a child with COVID-19 is hospitalized or admitted to the pediatric intensive care unit is greater than initially thought. Children may also suffer from long COVID and school closure because of COVID-19 can cause relevant mental health problems in the pediatric population. Placebo-controlled, observer-blinded, clinical trials showed appropriate efficacy, safety and tolerability of authorized mRNA COVID-19 vaccines in children and adolescents 12-17&#x2009;years old. Vaccination in children younger than 12&#x2009;years of age will allow further benefits .</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">COVID-19 vaccine administration seems mandatory in all the children and adolescents because of COVID-19 related complications as well as the efficacy, safety and tolerability of COVID-19 vaccines in this population. Due to the recent approval of COVID-9 vaccines for children 5-10&#x2009;years old, it is desirable that vaccine opponents can understand how important is the universal immunization against COVID-19 for the pediatric subjects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Principi</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esposito</LastName><ForeName>Susanna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4103-2837</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pietro Barilla Children's Hospital, Department of Medicine and Surgery, University of Parma, Via Gramsci 14, 43126, Parma, Italy. susanna.esposito@unimi.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Ital J Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101510759</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1720-8424</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000086663">COVID-19 Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000367" MajorTopicYN="N">Age Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086663" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19 Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006760" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitalization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017589" MajorTopicYN="Y">Immunization Programs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D037141" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mandatory Programs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018570" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Assessment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 vaccine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pediatric infectious disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35012590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8743738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13052-021-01192-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13052-021-01192-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Self WH, Tenforde MW, Rhoads JP, Gaglani M, Ginde AA, Douin DJ, Olson SM, Talbot HK, Casey JD, Mohr NM, Zepeski A, McNeal T, Ghamande S, Gibbs KW, Files DC, Hager DN, Shehu A, Prekker ME, Erickson HL, Gong MN, Mohamed A, Henning DJ, Steingrub JS, Peltan ID, Brown SM, Martin ET, Monto AS, Khan A, Hough CL, Busse LW, ten Lohuis CC, Duggal A, Wilson JG, Gordon AJ, Qadir N, Chang SY, Mallow C, Rivas C, Babcock HM, Kwon JH, Exline MC, Halasa N, Chappell JD, Lauring AS, Grijalva CG, Rice TW, Jones ID, Stubblefield WB, Baughman A, Womack KN, Lindsell CJ, Hart KW, Zhu Y, Mills L, Lester SN, Stumpf MM, Naioti EA, Kobayashi M, Verani JR, Thornburg NJ, Patel MM, IVY Network. IVY Network. Calhoun N, Murthy K, Herrick J, McKillop A, Hoffman E, Zayed M, Smith M, Seattle N, Ettlinger J, Priest E, Thomas J, Arroliga A, Beeram M, Kindle R, Kozikowski LA, de Souza L, Ouellette S, Thornton-Thompson S, Mehkri O, Ashok K, Gole S, King A, Poynter B, Stanley N, Hendrickson A, Maruggi E, Scharber T, Jorgensen J, Bowers R, King J, Aston V, Armbruster B, Rothman RE, Nair R, Chen JTT, Karow S, Robart E, Maldonado PN, Khan M, So P, Levitt J, Perez C, Visweswaran A, Roque J, Rivera A, Angeles L, Frankel T, Angeles L, Goff J, Huynh D, Howell M, Friedel J, Tozier M, Driver C, Carricato M, Foster A, Nassar P, Stout L, Sibenaller Z, Walter A, Mares J, Olson L, Clinansmith B, Rivas C, Gershengorn H, McSpadden E, Truscon R, Kaniclides A, Thomas L, Bielak R, Valvano WD, Fong R, Fitzsimmons WJ, Blair C, Valesano AL, Gilbert J, Crider CD, Steinbock KA, Paulson TC, Anderson LA, Kampe C, Johnson J, McHenry R, Blair M, Conway D, LaRose M, Landreth L, Hicks M, Parks L, Bongu J, McDonald D, Cass C, Seiler S, Park D, Hink T, Wallace M, Burnham CA, Arter OG. Comparative effectiveness of Moderna, Pfizer-BioNTech, and Janssen (Johnson &amp; Johnson) vaccines in preventing COVID-19 hospitalizations among adults without immunocompromising conditions - United States, march-august 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2021;70(38):1337&#x2013;1343. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm7038e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm7038e1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34555004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Washington Post. For many families, the countdown has begun to coronavirus vaccines for younger children By Lindsey Bever. Available at: https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2021/09/27/kids-covid-vaccine/. Accessed 26 Sept 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannidis JPA. COVID-19 vaccination in children and university students. Eur J Clin Investig. 2021;Epub Sep 16:e13678. doi: 10.1111/eci.13678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/eci.13678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8646734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34529274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberhardt CS, Siegrist CA. Is there a role for childhood vaccination against COVID-19? Pediatr Allergy Immunol. 2021;32(1):9&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1111/pai.13401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pai.13401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33113210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. CDC director statement on Pfizer&#x2019;s use of COVID-19 vaccine in adolescents age 12 and older. Available at: https://www-cdc-gov.pros.lib.unimi.it/media/releases/2021/s0512-advisory-committee-signing.html. Accessed 26 Sept 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GOV. UK. JCVI issues advice on COVID- 19 vaccination of children and young people. Available at: https://www.gov.uk/government/news/jcvi-issues-advice-on-covid-19-vaccination-of-children-and-young-people. Accessed 26 Sept 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sverigesradio. Children aged 12 to 15 to be offered Covid vaccine, government says Available at: https://sverigesradio.se/artikel/children-aged-12-to-15-to-be-offered-covid-vaccine-government-says. Accessed on 26 Sept 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Drug Administration. FDA authorizes Pfizer-BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine for emergency use in children 5 through 11 years of age. Available at: https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-authorizes-pfizer-biontech-covid-19-vaccine-emergency-use-children-5-through-11-years-age. Accessed 29 Nov 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency. Comirnaty COVID-19 vaccine: EMA recommends approval for children aged 5 to 11. Available at: https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/news/comirnaty-covid-19-vaccine-ema-recommends-approval-children-aged-5-11. Accessed 29 Nov 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza TH, Nadal JA, Nogueira RJN, Pereira RM, Brand&#xe3;o MB. Clinical manifestations of children with COVID-19: a systematic review. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2020;55(8):1892&#x2013;1899. doi: 10.1002/ppul.24885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ppul.24885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7300659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32492251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Academy of Pediatrics and the Children&#x2019;s Hospital Association. Children and COVID-19: state data report. Version: 9/16/21. Available at: https://downloads.aap.org/AAP/PDF/AAP%20and%20CHA%20-%20Children%20and%20COVID-19%20State%20Data%20Report%209.16%20FINAL.pdf. Accessed 27 Sept 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Raya B, Migliori GB, O'Ryan M, Edwards K, Torres A, Alffenaar JW, et al. Coronavirus disease-19: an interim evidence synthesis of the world association for infectious diseases and immunological disorders (Waidid) Front Med (Lausanne) 2020;7:572485. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2020.572485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2020.572485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7662576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33195319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAX Plank Institute COVerAGE-DB: a database of age structured COVID-19 cases and deaths. Available at: https://www.demogr.mpg.de/papers/working/wp-2020-032.pdf. Accessed 27 Sept 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garazzino S, Lo Vecchio A, Pierantoni L, Cal&#xf2; Carducci FI, Marchetti F, Meini A, Castagnola E, Vergine G, Don&#xe0; D, Bosis S, Dodi I, Venturini E, Felici E, Giacchero R, Denina M, Pierri L, Nicolini G, Montagnani C, Krzysztofiak A, Bianchini S, Marabotto C, Tovo PA, Pruccoli G, Lanari M, Villani A, Castelli Gattinara G, The Italian SITIP-SIP Pediatric Infection Study Group Epidemiology, clinical features and prognostic factors of pediatric SARS-CoV-2 infection: results from an Italian multicenter study. Front Pediatr. 2021;9:649358. doi: 10.3389/fped.2021.649358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2021.649358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8007917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33796491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 INED. The demography of COVID-19 deaths. An unprecedented context of health crisis. Available at: https://dc-covid.site.ined.fr/en/. Accessed 26 Sept 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito S, Marchetti F, Lanari M, Caramelli F, De Fanti A, Vergine G, et al. COVID-19 management in the pediatric age: consensus document of the COVID-19 working group in paediatrics of the Emilia-Romagna Region (RE-CO-Ped), Italy. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(8):3919. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18083919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18083919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8068343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preston LE, Chevinsky JR, Kompaniyets L, Lavery AM, Kimball A, Boehmer TK, Goodman AB. Characteristics and disease severity of US children and adolescents diagnosed with COVID-19. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(4):e215298. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.5298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.5298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8035649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33835179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito S, Principi N. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children related to SARS-CoV-2. Paediatr Drugs. 2021;23(2):119&#x2013;129. doi: 10.1007/s40272-020-00435-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40272-020-00435-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7819738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33479801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Principi N, Esposito S. Are we sure that the neurological impact of COVID 19 in childhood has not been underestimated? Ital J Pediatr. 2021;47(1):191. doi: 10.1186/s13052-021-01144-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13052-021-01144-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8449691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34537061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603&#x2013;605. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.12603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.12603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, Kang L, Guo L, Liu M, Zhou X, Luo J, Huang Z, Tu S, Zhao Y, Chen L, Xu D, Li Y, Li C, Peng L, Li Y, Xie W, Cui D, Shang L, Fan G, Xu J, Wang G, Wang Y, Zhong J, Wang C, Wang J, Zhang D, Cao B. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220&#x2013;232. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Pittet L, Nigel C. How common is long COVID in children and adolescents? [published online ahead of print September 28, 2021]. Pediatr Infect Dis J. Available from: Journals@Ovid Full Text at http://ovidsp.ovid.com/ovidweb.cgi?T=JS&amp;PAGE=reference&amp;D=ovftw&amp;NEWS=N&amp;AN=00006454-900000000-95677. Accessed 04 Oct 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34870392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito S, Zona S, Vergine G, Fantini M, Marchetti F, Stella M, Valletta E, Biasucci G, Lanari M, Dodi I, Bigi M, Magista AM, Vaienti F, Cella A, Affanni P, Re MC, Sambri V, Principi N, on behalf of the Regione Emilia-Romagna COVID How to manage children if a second wave of COVID-19 occurs. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2020;24(10):1116&#x2013;1118. doi: 10.5588/ijtld.20.0543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5588/ijtld.20.0543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33126950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meuris C, Kremer C, Geerinck A, Locquet M, Bruy&#xe8;re O, Def&#xea;che J, Meex C, Hayette MP, Duchene L, Dellot P, Azarzar S, Mar&#xe9;chal N, Sauvage AS, Frippiat F, Giot JB, L&#xe9;onard P, Fombellida K, Moutschen M, Durkin K, Artesi M, Bours V, Faes C, Hens N, Darcis G. Transmission of SARS-CoV-2 after COVID-19 screening and mitigation measures for primary school children attending School in Li&#xe8;ge, Belgium. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(10):e2128757. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.28757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.28757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8511974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34636913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiri T, Evans M, Talarico CA, Morgan AR, Mussad M, Buck PO, et al. Vaccinating adolescents and children significantly reduces COVID-19 morbidity and mortality across all ages: a population-based modeling study using the UK as an example. Vaccines (Basel) 2021;9:1180. doi: 10.3390/vaccines9101180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vaccines9101180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8537561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34696288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito S, Giannitto N, Squarcia A, Neglia C, Argentiero A, Minichetti P, Cotugno N, Principi N. Development of psychological problems among adolescents during school closures because of the COVID-19 lockdown phase in Italy: a cross-sectional survey. Front Pediatr. 2021;8:628072. doi: 10.3389/fped.2020.628072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2020.628072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7862750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33553079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito S, Caramelli F, Principi N. What are the risk factors for admission to the pediatric intensive unit among pediatric patients with COVID-19? Ital J Pediatr. 2021;47(1):103. doi: 10.1186/s13052-021-01057-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13052-021-01057-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8090919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33941228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia J, Torres C, Barbieri M, Camarda C, Cambois E, Caporali A, etal Differences in COVID-19 mortality: implications of imperfect and diverse data collection systems. Population. 2021;76(1):35&#x2013;72. doi: 10.3917/popu.2101.0037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3917/popu.2101.0037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumenthal KG, Robinson LB, Camargo CA, Jr, Shenoy ES, Banerji A, Landman AB, Wickner P. Acute allergic reactions to mRNA COVID-19 vaccines. JAMA. 2021;325(15):1562&#x2013;1565. doi: 10.1001/jama.2021.3976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.3976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7941251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33683290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf8;eg TB, Krug A, Stevenson J, Mandrola J. SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccination-associated myocarditis in children ages 12&#x2013;17: a stratified national database analysis. MedRxiv. 2021:2021.08.30.21262866 10.1101/2021.08.30.21262866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanveer S, Rowhani-Farid A, Hong K, Jefferson T, Doshi P. Transparency of COVID-19 vaccine trials: decisions without data. BMJ Evid Based Med. 2021;Epub Aug 9:bmjebm-2021-111735. doi: 10.1136/bmjebm-2021-111735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjebm-2021-111735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frenck RW, Jr, Klein NP, Kitchin N, Gurtman A, Absalon J, Lockhart S, et al. Safety, immunogenicity, and efficacy of the BNT162b2 Covid-19 vaccine in adolescents. N Engl J Med. 2021;385(3):239&#x2013;250. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2107456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2107456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8174030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34043894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali K, Berman G, Zhou H, Deng W, Faughnan V, Coronado-Voges M, et al. Evaluation of mRNA-1273 SARS-CoV-2 vaccine in adolescents. N Engl J Med. 2021;Epub Aug 11:NEJMoa2109522. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2109522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2109522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8385554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34379915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettoello-Mantovani M, Carrasco-Sanz A, Huss G, Mestrovic J, Vural M, Pop TL, et al. Viewpoint of the European Pediatric Societies over Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) vaccination in children younger than age 12 years amid return to school and the surging virus variants. J Pediatr. 2021;Epub Sep 15:S0022-3476(21)00886-6. doi: 10.1016/j.jpeds.2021.09.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2021.09.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8442301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34536493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calcaterra G, Mehta JL, de Gregorio C, Butera G, Neroni P, Fanos V, Bassareo PP. COVID 19 vaccine for adolescents. Concern about myocarditis and pericarditis. Pediatr Rep. 2021;13(3):530&#x2013;533. doi: 10.3390/pediatric13030061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pediatric13030061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34564344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gargano JW, Wallace M, Hadler SC, Langley G, Su JR, Oster M, et al. Use of mRNA COVID-19 vaccine after reports of myocarditis among vaccine recipients: update from the advisory committee on immunization practices - United States, June 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2021;70:977&#x2013;982. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm7027e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm7027e2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8312754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34237049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>