<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35227568</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-3618</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>59</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Seminars in immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Semin Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>E-series resolvin metabolome, biosynthesis and critical role of stereochemistry of specialized pro-resolving mediators (SPMs) in inflammation-resolution: Preparing SPMs for long COVID-19, human clinical trials, and targeted precision nutrition.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101597</StartPage><MedlinePgn>101597</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.smim.2022.101597</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1044-5323(22)00014-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The COVID-19 pandemic has raised international awareness of the importance of rigorous scientific evidence and the havoc caused by uncontrolled excessive inflammation. Here we consider the evidence on whether the specialized pro-resolving mediators (SPMs) are ready to meet this challenge as well as targeted metabololipidomics of the resolution-inflammation metabolomes. Specific stereochemical mechanisms in the biosynthesis of SPMs from omega-3 essential fatty acids give rise to unique local-acting lipid mediators. SPMs possess stereochemically defined potent bioactive structures that are high-affinity ligands for cognate G protein-coupled surface receptors that evoke the cellular responses required for efficient resolution of acute inflammation. The SPMs biosynthesized from the major omega-3 fatty acids eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA) and docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) are coined Resolvins (resolution phase interaction products; E series and D-series), Protectins and Maresins (macrophage mediators in resolving inflammation). Their biosynthesis and stereochemical assignments are established and confirmed (&gt;1,441 resolvin publications in PubMed.gov) as well as their functional roles on innate immune cells and adaptive immune cells (both lymphocyte T-cell subsets and B-cells). The resolution of a protective acute inflammatory response is governed mainly by phagocytes that actively clear apoptotic cells, debris, blood clots and pathogens. These resolution phase functions of the acute inflammatory response are enhanced by SPMs, which together prepare the inflammatory loci for homeostasis and stimulate tissue regeneration via activating stem cells and the biosynthesis of novel cys-SPMs (e.g. MCTRs, PCTRs and RCTRs). These cys-SPMs also activate regeneration, are organ protective and stimulate resolution of local inflammation. Herein, we review the biosynthesis and functions of the E-series resolvins, namely resolvin E1 (the first n-3 resolvin identified), resolvin E2, resolvin E3 and resolvin E4 biosynthesized from their precursor eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA), and the critical role of total organic synthesis in confirming SPM complete stereochemistry, establishing their potent functions in resolution of inflammation, and novel structures. The physical properties of each biologically derived SPM, i.e., ultra-violet (UV) absorbance, chromatographic behavior, and tandem mass spectrometry (MS<sup>2</sup>) fragmentation, were matched to SPMs biosynthesized and prepared by stereospecific total organic synthesis. We briefly review this approach, also used with the endogenous D-series resolvins, protectins and maresins confirming their potent functions in resolution of inflammation, that paves the way for their rigorous evaluation in human tissues and clinical trials. The assignment of complete stereochemistry for each of the E and D series Resolvins, Protectins and Maresins was a critical and required step that enabled human clinical studies as in SPM profiling in COVID-19 infections and experimental animal disease models that also opened the promise of resolution physiology, resolution pharmacology and targeted precision nutrition as new areas for monitoring health and disease mechanisms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Serhan</LastName><ForeName>Charles N</ForeName><Initials>CN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Experimental Therapeutics and Reperfusion Injury, Department of Anesthesiology, Perioperative and Pain Medicine, Brigham and Women's Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA 02115, USA. Electronic address: cserhan@bwh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Libreros</LastName><ForeName>Stephania</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Experimental Therapeutics and Reperfusion Injury, Department of Anesthesiology, Perioperative and Pain Medicine, Brigham and Women's Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA 02115, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nshimiyimana</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Experimental Therapeutics and Reperfusion Injury, Department of Anesthesiology, Perioperative and Pain Medicine, Brigham and Women's Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA 02115, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K99 HL153673</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Semin Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9009458</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1044-5323</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>25167-62-8</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004281">Docosahexaenoic Acids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>AAN7QOV9EA</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015118">Eicosapentaenoic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018836">Inflammation Mediators</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004281" MajorTopicYN="N">Docosahexaenoic Acids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015118" MajorTopicYN="Y">Eicosapentaenoic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018836" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation Mediators</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055442" MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002986" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Docosahexaenoic acid (DHA)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human phagocytes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">M2 macrophages</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neutrophils</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35227568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8847098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smim.2022.101597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1044-5323(22)00014-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hu B., Huang S., Yin L. The cytokine storm and COVID-19. J. Med. Virol. 2021;93(1):250&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32592501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stasi C., Fallani S., Voller F., Silvestri C. Treatment for COVID-19: an overview. Eur. J. Pharmacol. 2020;889</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7548059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33053381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Netea M.G., Balkwill F., Chonchol M., Cominelli F., Donath M.Y., Giamarellos-Bourboulis E.J., Golenbock D., Gresnigt M.S., Heneka M.T., Hoffman H.M., Hotchkiss R., Joosten L.A.B., Kastner D.L., Korte M., Latz E., Libby P., Mandrup-Poulsen T., Mantovani A., Mills K.H.G., Nowak K.L., O&#x2019;Neill L.A., Pickkers P., van der Poll T., Ridker P.M., Schalkwijk J., Schwartz D.A., Siegmund B., Steer C.J., Tilg H., van der Meer J.W.M., van de Veerdonk F.L., Dinarello C.A. A guiding map for inflammation. Nat. Immunol. 2017;18(8):826&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5939996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28722720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N., Ward P.A., Gilroy D.W. Cambridge University Press; New York: 2010. Fundamentals of Inflammation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haeggstrom J.Z. Leukotriene biosynthetic enzymes as therapeutic targets. J. Clin. Invest. 2018;128(7):2680&#x2013;2690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6026001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30108195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuelsson B. Leukotrienes: mediators of immediate hypersensitivity reactions and inflammation. Science. 1983;220:568&#x2013;575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6301011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N. Pro-resolving lipid mediators are leads for resolution physiology. Nature. 2014;510(7503):92&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4263681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24899309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N., Hong S., Gronert K., Colgan S.P., Devchand P.R., Mirick G., Moussignac R.-L. Resolvins: a family of bioactive products of omega-3 fatty acid transformation circuits initiated by aspirin treatment that counter pro-inflammation signals. J. Exp. Med. 2002;196:1025&#x2013;1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2194036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12391014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N., Chiang N., Van Dyke T.E. Resolving inflammation: dual anti-inflammatory and pro-resolution lipid mediators. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2008;8:349&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2744593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18437155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindbom L. Regulation of vascular permeability by neutrophils in acute inflammation. Chem. Immunol. Allergy. 2003;83:146&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12947983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang N., Fredman G., B&#xe4;ckhed F., Oh S.F., Vickery T.W., Schmidt B.A., Serhan C.N. Infection regulates pro-resolving mediators that lower antibiotic requirements. Nature. 2012;484:524&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3340015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22538616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannenberg G.L., Chiang N., Ariel A., Arita M., Tjonahen E., Gotlinger K.H., Hong S., Serhan C.N. Molecular circuits of resolution: formation and actions of resolvins and protectins. J. Immunol. 2005;174:4345&#x2013;4355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15778399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy B.D., Clish C.B., Schmidt B., Gronert K., Serhan C.N. Lipid mediator class switching during acute inflammation: signals in resolution. Nat. Immunol. 2001;2:612&#x2013;619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11429545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong S., Gronert K., Devchand P., Moussignac R.-L., Serhan C.N. Novel docosatrienes and 17S-resolvins generated from docosahexaenoic acid in murine brain, human blood and glial cells: autacoids in anti-inflammation. J. Biol. Chem. 2003;278:14677&#x2013;14687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12590139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N., Yang R., Martinod K., Kasuga K., Pillai P.S., Porter T.F., Oh S.F., Spite M. Maresins: novel macrophage mediators with potent anti-inflammatory and pro-resolving actions. J. Exp. Med. 2009;206:15&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2626672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19103881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arienti S., Barth N.D., Dorward D.A., Rossi A.G., Dransfield I. Regulation of apoptotic cell clearance during resolution of inflammation. Front. Pharmacol. 2019;10:891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6701246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31456686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalli J., Serhan C.N. Specific lipid mediator signatures of human phagocytes: microparticles stimulate macrophage efferocytosis and pro-resolving mediators. Blood. 2012;120:e60&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3471524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22904297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werz O., Gerstmeier J., Libreros S., De la Rosa X., Werner M., Norris P.C., Chiang N., Serhan C.N. Human macrophages differentially produce specific resolvin or leukotriene signals that depend on bacterial pathogenicity. Nat. Commun. 2018;9(1):59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5754355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29302056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan P.M., Gerstmeier J., Pace S., Bilancia R., Rao Z., Borner F., Miek L., Gutierrez-Gutierrez O., Arakandy V., Rossi A., Ialenti A., Gonzalez-Estevez C., Loffler B., Tuchscherr L., Serhan C.N., Werz O. Staphylococcus aureus-derived alpha-hemolysin evokes generation of specialized pro-resolving mediators promoting inflammation resolution. Cell Rep. 2020;33(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7729929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33053344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T., Xiang A., Peng T., Doran A.C., Tracey K.J., Barnes B.J., Tabas I., Son M., Diamond B. HMGB1-C1q complexes regulate macrophage function by switching between leukotriene and specialized proresolving mediator biosynthesis. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2019;116(46):23254&#x2013;23263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6859319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31570601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N., Clish C.B., Brannon J., Colgan S.P., Chiang N., Gronert K. Novel functional sets of lipid-derived mediators with antiinflammatory actions generated from omega-3 fatty acids via cyclooxygenase 2-nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs and transcellular processing. J. Exp. Med. 2000;192:1197&#x2013;1204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2195872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11034610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang N., Serhan C.N. Cell-cell interaction in the transcellular biosynthesis of novel omega-3-derived lipid mediators. Methods Mol. Biol. 2006;341:227&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16799203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archambault A.S., Zaid Y., Rakotoarivelo V., Turcotte C., Dor&#xe9; &#xc9;., Dubuc I., Martin C., Flamand O., Amar Y., Cheikh A., Fares H., El Hassani A., Tijani Y., C&#xf4;t&#xe9; A., Laviolette M., Boilard &#xc9;., Flamand L., Flamand N. High levels of eicosanoids and docosanoids in the lungs of intubated COVID-19 patients. FASEB J. 2021;35(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz B., Sharma L., Roberts L., Peng X., Bermejo S., Leighton I., Massana A.C., Farhadian S., Ko A., DelaCruz C., Bosio C.M. Severe SARS-CoV-2 infection in humans is defined by a shift in the serum lipidome resulting in dysregulation of eicosanoid immune mediators. medRxiv. 2020 doi: 10.1101/2020.07.09.20149849. Preprint, July 13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.07.09.20149849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7962598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33277388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koenis D., Beegun I., Jouvene C., Aguirre G.A., Souza P.R., Gonzalez-Nunez M., Ly L., Pistorius K., Kocher H.M., Ricketts W., Thomas G., Perretti M., Alusi G., Pfeffer P., Dalli J. Disrupted resolution mechanisms favor altered phagocyte responses in Covid-19. Circ. Res. 2021;129:e54&#x2013;e71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8336787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34238021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turnbull J., Jha R., Ortori C.A., Lunt E., Tighe P.J., Irving W.L., Gohir S.A., Kim D.H., Valdes A.M., Tarr A.W., Barrett D.A., Chapman V. Serum levels of pro-inflammatory lipid mediators and specialised pro-resolving molecules are increased in SARS-CoV-2 patients and correlate with markers of the adaptive immune response. J. Infect. Dis. 2022 doi: 10.1093/infdis/jiab632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiab632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8755389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34979019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang R., Chiang N., Oh S.F., Serhan C.N. Metabolomics-lipidomics of eicosanoids and docosanoids generated by phagocytes. Curr. Protoc. Immunol. Suppl. 2011;95:14.26.1&#x2013;14.26.26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3321370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22048801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N., Lu Y., Hong S., Yang R. Mediator lipidomics: search algorithms for eicosanoids, resolvins and protectins. Meth. Enzymol. 2007;432:275&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17954222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y., Hong S., Yang R., Uddin J., Gotlinger K.H., Petasis N.A., Serhan C.N. Identification of endogenous resolvin E1 and other lipid mediators derived from eicosapentaenoic acid via electrospray low energy tandem mass spectrometry: spectra and fragmentation mechanisms. Rapid Commun. Mass Spectrom. 2007;21:7&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17131464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong S., Lu Y., Yang R., Gotlinger K.H., Petasis N.A., Serhan C.N. Resolvin D1, protectin D1, and related docosahexaenoic acid-derived products: analysis via electrospray/low energy tandem mass spectrometry based on spectra and fragmentation mechanisms. J. Am. Soc. Mass Spectrom. 2007;18:128&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2763184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17055291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz B., Sharma L., Roberts L., Peng X., Bermejo S., Leighton I., Casanovas-Massana A., Minasyan M., Farhadian S., Ko A.I., Dela Cruz C.S., Bosio C.M. Cutting edge: severe SARS-CoV-2 infection in humans is defined by a shift in the serum lipidome, resulting in dysregulation of eicosanoid immune mediators. J. Immunol. 2021;206(2):329&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7962598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33277388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreakos E., Papadaki M., Serhan C.N. Dexamethasone, pro-resolving lipid mediators and resolution of inflammation in COVID-19. Allergy. 2021;76(3):626&#x2013;628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32956495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panigrahy D., Gilligan M.M., Huang S., Gartung A., Cort&#xe9;s-Puch I., Sime P.J., Phipps R.P., Serhan C.N., Hammock B.D. Inflammation resolution: a dual-pronged approach to averting cytokine storms in COVID-19? Cancer Metastasis Rev. 2020;39:337&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7207990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32385712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recchiuti A., Patruno S., Mattoscio D., Isopi E., Pomilio A., Lamolinara A., Iezzi M., Pecce R., Romano M. Resolvin D1 and D2 reduce SARS-CoV-2-induced inflammatory responses in cystic fibrosis macrophages. FASEB J. 2021;35(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33749902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barden A.E., Mas E., Croft K.D., Phillips M., Mori T.A. Specialized proresolving lipid mediators in humans with the metabolic syndrome after n-3 fatty acids and aspirin. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 2015;102(6):1357&#x2013;1364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26561623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazan H.A., Lu Y., Jun B., Fang Z., Woods T.C., Hong S. Circulating inflammation-resolving lipid mediators RvD1 and DHA are decreased in patients with acutely symptomatic carotid disease. Prostaglandins Leukot. Essent. Fatty Acids. 2017;125:43&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5909403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28987721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barden A.E., Shinde S., Burke V., Puddey I.B., Beilin L.J., Irish A.B., Watts G.F., Mori T.A. The effect of n-3 fatty acids and coenzyme Q10 supplementation on neutrophil leukotrienes, mediators of inflammation resolution and myeloperoxidase in chronic kidney disease. Prostaglandins Other Lipid Mediat. 2018;136:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29577973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartling I., Cremonesi A., Osuna E., Lou P.H., Lucchinetti E., Zaugg M., Hersberger M. Quantitative profiling of inflammatory and pro-resolving lipid mediators in human adolescents and mouse plasma using UHPLC-MS/MS. Clin. Chem. Lab. Med. 2021;59:1811&#x2013;1823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34243224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mas E., Barden A., Burke V., Beilin L.J., Watts G.F., Huang R.C., Puddey I.B., Irish A.B., Mori T.A. A randomized controlled trial of the effects of n-3 fatty acids on resolvins in chronic kidney disease. Clin. Nutr. (Edinburgh, Scotland) 2016;35(2):331&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25908532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mas E., Croft K.D., Zahra P., Barden A., Mori T.A. Resolvins D.1, D2, and other mediators of self-limited resolution of inflammation in human blood following n-3 fatty acid supplementation. Clin. Chem. 2012;58:1476&#x2013;1484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22912397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polinski K.J., Armstrong M., Manke J., Seifert J., Crume T., Yang F., Clare-Salzler M., Holers V.M., Reisdorph N., Norris J.M. Collection and storage of human plasma for measurement of oxylipins. Metabolites. 2021;11(3):137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7996814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33652624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulte F., Asbeutah A.A., Benotti P.N., Wood G.C., Still C., Bistrian B.R., Hardt M., Welty F.K. The relationship between specialized pro-resolving lipid mediators, morbid obesity and weight loss after bariatric surgery. Sci. Rep. 2020;10(1):20128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7674470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33208757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barden A., Mas E., Croft K.D., Phillips M., Mori T.A. Short-term n-3 fatty acid supplementation but not aspirin increases plasma proresolving mediators of inflammation. J. Lipid Res. 2014;55:2401&#x2013;2407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4617141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25187667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss G.A., Troxler H., Klinke G., Rogler D., Braegger C., Hersberger M. High levels of anti-inflammatory and pro-resolving lipid mediators lipoxins and resolvins and declining docosahexaenoic acid levels in human milk during the first month of lactation. Lipids Health Dis. 2013;12:89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3698171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23767972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barden A., Shinde S., Tsai I.J., Croft K.D., Beilin L.J., Puddey I.B., Mori T.A. Effect of weight loss on neutrophil resolvins in the metabolic syndrome. Prostaglandins Leukot. Essent. Fatty Acids. 2019;148:25&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31492430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barden A.E., Moghaddami M., Mas E., Phillips M., Cleland L.G., Mori T.A. Specialised pro-resolving mediators of inflammation in inflammatory arthritis. Prostaglandins Leukot. Essent. Fatty Acids. 2016;107:24&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27033423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keelan J.A., Mas E., D&#x2019;Vaz N., Dunstan J.A., Li S., Barden A.E., Mark P.J., Waddell B.J., Prescott S.L., Mori T.A. Effects of maternal n-3 fatty acid supplementation on placental cytokines, pro-resolving lipid mediators and their precursors. Reproduction. 2015;149(2):171&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25504868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markworth J.F., Brown L.A., Lim E., Castor-Macias J.A., Larouche J., Macpherson P.C.D., Davis C., Aguilar C.A., Maddipati K.R., Brooks S.V. Metabolipidomic profiling reveals an age-related deficiency of skeletal muscle pro-resolving mediators that contributes to maladaptive tissue remodeling. Aging Cell. 2021;20(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8208786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34075679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markworth J.F., Sugg K.B., Sarver D.C., Maddipati K.R., Brooks S.V. Local shifts in inflammatory and resolving lipid mediators in response to tendon overuse. FASEB J. 2021;35(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9527947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34042218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamon-Fava S., So J., Mischoulon D., Ziegler T.R., Dunlop B.W., Kinkead B., Schettler P.J., Nierenberg A.A., Felger J.C., Maddipati K.R., Fava M., Rapaport M.H. Dose- and time-dependent increase in circulating anti-inflammatory and pro-resolving lipid mediators following eicosapentaenoic acid supplementation in patients with major depressive disorder and chronic inflammation. Prostaglandins Leukot. Essent. Fatty Acids. 2021;164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7855824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33316626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markworth J.F., Vella L.D., Lingard B.S., Tull D.L., Rupasinghe T.W., Sinclair A.J., Maddipati K.R., Cameron-Smith D. Human inflammatory and resolving lipid mediator responses to resistance exercise and ibuprofen treatment. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Compar. Physiol. 2013;305:R1281&#x2013;R1296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3882565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24089379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terrando N., Park J.J., Devinney M., Chan C., Cooter M., Avasarala P., Mathew J.P., Quinones Q.J., Maddipati K.R., Berger M. Immunomodulatory lipid mediator profiling of cerebrospinal fluid following surgery in older adults. Sci. Rep. 2021;11(1):3047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7862598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33542362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eickmeier O., Fussbroich D., Mueller K., Serve F., Smaczny C., Zielen S., Schubert R. Pro-resolving lipid mediator Resolvin D1 serves as a marker of lung disease in cystic fibrosis. PLoS One. 2017;12(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5291435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28158236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barden A., Shinde S., Phillips M., Beilin L., Mas E., Hodgson J.M., Puddey I., Mori T.A. The effects of alcohol on plasma lipid mediators of inflammation resolution in patients with Type 2 diabetes mellitus. Prostaglandins Leukot. Essent. Fatty Acids. 2018;133:29&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29789130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>See V.H.L., Mas E., Prescott S.L., Beilin L.J., Burrows S., Barden A.E., Huang R.C., Mori T.A. Effects of prenatal n-3 fatty acid supplementation on offspring resolvins at birth and 12 years of age: a double-blind, randomised controlled clinical trial. Br. J. Nutr. 2017;118:971&#x2013;980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29173199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen T.V., Vik A., Serhan C.N. The protectin family of specialized pro-resolving mediators: potent immunoresolvents enabling innovative approaches to target obesity and diabetes. Front. Pharmacol. 2019;9:1582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6344435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30705632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez A.R., Spur B.W. First total syntheses of the pro-resolving lipid mediators 7(S),13(R),20(S)-Resolvin T1 and 7(S),13(R)-Resolvin T4. Tetrahedron Lett. 2020;61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7169962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32313313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez A.R., Spur B.W. First total synthesis of the pro-resolving lipid mediator 7(S),12(R),13(S)-Resolvin T2 and its 13(R)-epimer. Tetrahedron Lett. 2020;61(20)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32863450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang N., Sakuma M., Rodriguez A.R., Spur B.W., Irimia D., Serhan C.N. Resolvin T-series reduce neutrophil extracellular traps. Blood. 2021 doi: 10.1182/blood.2021013422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.2021013422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8612755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34814186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr S.K., Colas R.A., Dalli J., Chiang N., Serhan C.N. Proresolving actions of a new resolvin D1 analog mimetic qualifies as an immunoresolvent. Am. J. Physiol. Lung Cell Mol. Physiol. 2015;308(9):L904&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4421783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25770181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libreros S., Shay A.E., Nshimiyimana R., Fichtner D., Martin M.J., Wourms N., Serhan C.N. A new E-series resolvin: RvE4 stereochemistry and function in efferocytosis of inflammation-resolution. Front. Immunol. 2020;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7902526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33643307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edin M.L., Zeldin D.C. Commercial scale production of RvD4 opens the resolving door to new research. J. Leukoc. Biol. 2018 doi: 10.1002/jlb.3ce0118-032r.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jlb.3ce0118-032r</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6165702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29603390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasturk H., Schulte F., Martins M., Sherzai H., Floros C., Cugini M., Chiu C.J., Hardt M., Van Dyke T. Safety and preliminary efficacy of a novel host-modulatory therapy for reducing gingival inflammation. Front. Immunol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8475270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34589083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan E., Kantharidis P., Cooper M.E., Godson C. Pro-resolving lipid mediators: regulators of inflammation, metabolism and kidney function. Nat. Rev. Nephrol. 2021;17(11):725&#x2013;739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8287849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34282342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vartak T., Godson C., Brennan E. Therapeutic potential of pro-resolving mediators in diabetic kidney disease. Adv. Drug Deliv. Rev. 2021;178</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34508793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickery T.W., Armstrong M., Kofonow J.M., Robertson C.E., Kroehl M.E., Reisdorph N.A., Ramakrishnan V.R., Frank D.N. Altered tissue specialized pro-resolving mediators in chronic rhinosinusitis. Prostaglandins Leukot. Essent. Fatty Acids. 2021;164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7855833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33338738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Novo C.A., Watelet J.B., Claeys C., Van Cauwenberge P., Bachert C. Prostaglandin, leukotriene, and lipoxin balance in chronic rhinosinusitis with and without nasal polyposis. J. Allergy Clin. Immunol. 2005;115(6):1189&#x2013;1196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15940133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Caterina R. n-3 fatty acids in cardiovascular disease. N. Engl. J. Med. 2011;364(25):2439&#x2013;2450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21696310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris W.S., Calder P.C., Mozaffarian D., Serhan C.N. Bang and Dyerberg&#x2019;s omega-3 discovery turns fifty. Nat. Food. 2021;2:303&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37117719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt D.L., Steg P.G., Miller M., Brinton E.A., Jacobson T.A., Ketchum S.B., Doyle R.T., Jr., Juliano R.A., Jiao L., Granowitz C., Tardif J.C., Ballantyne C.M., Investigators R.-I. Cardiovascular risk reduction with icosapent ethyl for hypertriglyceridemia. N. Engl. J. Med. 2019;380(1):11&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30415628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darwesh A.M., Bassiouni W., Sosnowski D.K., Seubert J.M. Can N-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids be considered a potential adjuvant therapy for COVID-19-associated cardiovascular complications? Pharmacol. Ther. 2021;219</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M., Bianchini F., Aliberti J., Sher A., Chiang N., Hong S., Yang R., Petasis N.A., Serhan C.N. Stereochemical assignment, anti-inflammatory properties, and receptor for the omega-3 lipid mediator resolvin E1. J. Exp. Med. 2005;201:713&#x2013;722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2212834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15753205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotran R.S., Kumar V., Collins T. W.B. Saunders Co.; Philadelphia: 1999. Robbins Pathologic Basis of Disease.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colgan S.P. In: Methods in Molecular Biology. Walker J.M., editor. Humana Press; Totowa, NJ: 2006. Cell-cell interactions: methods and protocols.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dona M., Fredman G., Schwab J.M., Chiang N., Arita M., Goodarzi A., Cheng G., von Andrian U.H., Serhan C.N. Resolvin E1, an EPA-derived mediator in whole blood, selectively counterregulates leukocytes and platelets. Blood. 2008;112:848&#x2013;855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2481548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18480426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M., Clish C.B., Serhan C.N. The contributions of aspirin and microbial oxygenase to the biosynthesis of anti-inflammatory resolvins: novel oxygenase products from omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 2005;338(1):149&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16112645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh S.F., Pillai P.S., Recchiuti A., Yang R., Serhan C.N. Pro-resolving actions and stereoselective biosynthesis of 18S E-series resolvins in human leukocytes and murine inflammation. J. Clin. Invest. 2011;121:569&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3026718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21206090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tjonahen E., Oh S.F., Siegelman J., Elangovan S., Percarpio K.B., Hong S., Arita M., Serhan C.N. Resolvin E2: Identification and anti-inflammatory actions: pivotal role of human 5-lipoxygenase in resolvin E series biosynthesis. Chem. Biol. 2006;13:1193&#x2013;1202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17114001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trilleaud C., Gauttier V., Biteau K., Girault I., Belarif L., Mary C., Pengam S., Teppaz G., Thepenier V., Danger R., Robert-Siegwald G., N&#xe9;el M., Bruneau S., Gl&#xe9;main A., N&#xe9;el A., Poupon A., Mosnier J.F., Ch&#xea;ne G., Dubourdeau M., Blancho G., Vanhove B., Poirier N. Agonist anti-ChemR23 mAb reduces tissue neutrophil accumulation and triggers chronic inflammation resolution. Sci. Adv. 2021;7(14)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11057782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33811066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab J.M., Chiang N., Arita M., Serhan C.N. Resolvin E1 and protectin D1 activate inflammation-resolution programmes. Nature. 2007;447:869&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2757086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17568749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasturk H., Kantarci A., Ohira T., Arita M., Ebrahimi N., Chiang N., Petasis N.A., Levy B.D., Serhan C.N., Van Dyke T.E. RvE1 protects from local inflammation and osteoclast mediated bone destruction in periodontitis. FASEB J. 2006;20:401&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16373400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M., Oh S., Chonan T., Hong S., Elangovan S., Sun Y.-P., Uddin J., Petasis N.A., Serhan C.N. Metabolic inactivation of resolvin E1 and stabilization of its anti-inflammatory actions. J. Biol. Chem. 2006;281:22847&#x2013;22854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16757471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isobe Y., Arita M., Matsueda S., Iwamoto R., Fujihara T., Nakanishi H., Taguchi R., Masuda K., Sasaki K., Urabe D., Inoue M., Arai H. Identification and structure determination of novel anti-inflammatory mediator resolvin E3, 17,18-dihydroxyeicosapentaenoic acid. J. Biol. Chem. 2012;287(13):10525&#x2013;10534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3322993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22275352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo J., Sano M., Isobe Y., Fukuda K., Kang J.X., Arai H., Arita M. 18-HEPE, an n-3 fatty acid metabolite released by macrophages, prevents pressure overload-induced maladaptive cardiac remodeling. J. Exp. Med. 2014;211(8):1673&#x2013;1687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4113943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25049337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norris P.C., Libreros S., Serhan C.N. Resolution metabolomes activated by hypoxic environment. Sci. Adv. 2019;5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6810174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31681846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutzner L., Goloshchapova K., Rund K.M., Jubermann M., Blum M., Rothe M., Kirsch S.F., Schunck W.H., Kuhn H., Schebb N.H. Human lipoxygenase isoforms form complex patterns of double and triple oxygenated compounds from eicosapentaenoic acid. Biochim. Biophys. Acta Mol. Cell Biol. Lipids. 2020;1865(12)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32841762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinertsen A.F., Primdahl K.G., Shay A.E., Serhan C.N., Hansen T.V., Aursnes M. Stereoselective synthesis and structural confirmation of the specialized pro-resolving mediator resolvin E4. J. Org. Chem. 2021;86(4):3535&#x2013;3545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7901022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33534565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassatella M.A. 2003. The Neutrophil an Emergenging Regulator of Inflammatory and Immune Response.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nauseef W.M., Borregaard N. Neutrophils at work. Nat. Immunol. 2014;15(7):602&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24940954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Do K.V., Hjorth E., Wang Y., Jun B., Kautzmann M.A., Eriksdotter M., Schultzberg M., Bazan N.G. Cerebrospinal fluid profile of lipid mediators in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Res. Sq. 2021 doi: 10.21203/rs.3.rs-1029034/v1. [Preprint]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.3.rs-1029034/v1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9957874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35362880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okabe Y., Medzhitov R. Tissue biology perspective on macrophages. Nat. Immunol. 2016;17(1):9&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26681457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J., An J.U., Kim T.H., Ko Y.J., Park J.B., Oh D.K. Discovery and engineering of a microbial double-oxygenating lipoxygenase for synthesis of dihydroxy fatty acids as specialized proresolving mediators. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2020;8:16172&#x2013;16183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cl&#xe0;ria J., Serhan C.N. Aspirin triggers previously undescribed bioactive eicosanoids by human endothelial cell-leukocyte interactions. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 1995;92:9475&#x2013;9479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC40824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7568157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J.Y., Han S.H., Park M.H., Song I.S., Choi M.K., Yu E., Park C.M., Kim H.J., Kim S.H., Schuchman E.H., Jin H.K., Bae J.S. N-AS-triggered SPMs are direct regulators of microglia in a model of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Nat. Commun. 2020;11(1):2358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7217877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalli J., Chiang N., Serhan C.N. Elucidation of novel 13-series resolvins that increase with atorvastatin and clear infections. Nat. Med. 2015;21(9):1071&#x2013;1075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4560998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26236990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radmark O., Werz O., Steinhilber D., Samuelsson B. 5-Lipoxygenase, a key enzyme for leukotriene biosynthesis in health and disease. Biochim. Biophys. Acta. 2015;1851(4):331&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25152163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Z., Tao D., Xiong J., Lou F., Zhang J., Chen J., Dai W., Sun J., Wang Y. Phosphorylation of 5-LOX: the potential set-point of inflammation. Neurochem. Res. 2020;45(10):2245&#x2013;2257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32671628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Y., Lin Y., Perez-Polo J.R., Uretsky B.F., Ye Z., Tieu B.C., Birnbaum Y. Phosphorylation of 5-lipoxygenase at ser523 by protein kinase A determines whether pioglitazone and atorvastatin induce proinflammatory leukotriene B4 or anti-inflammatory 15-epi-lipoxin a4 production. J. Immunol. 2008;181(5):3515&#x2013;3523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M., Yoshida M., Hong S., Tjonahen E., Glickman J.N., Petasis N.A., Blumberg R.S., Serhan C.N. Resolvin E1, an endogenous lipid mediator derived from omega-3 eicosapentaenoic acid, protects against 2,4,6-trinitrobenzene sulfonic acid-induced colitis. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2005;102(21):7671&#x2013;7676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1103706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15890784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawada Y., Honda T., Hanakawa S., Nakamizo S., Murata T., Ueharaguchi-Tanada Y., Ono S., Amano W., Nakajima S., Egawa G., Tanizaki H., Otsuka A., Kitoh A., Dainichi T., Ogawa N., Kobayashi Y., Yokomizo T., Arita M., Nakamura M., Miyachi Y., Kabashima K. Resolvin E1 inhibits dendritic cell migration in the skin and attenuates contact hypersensitivity responses. J. Exp. Med. 2015;212(11):1921&#x2013;1930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4612099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26438363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C.T., Teles R., Kantarci A., Chen T., McCafferty J., Starr J.R., Brito L.C., Paster B.J., Van Dyke T.E. Resolvin E1 reverses experimental periodontitis and dysbiosis. J. Immunol. 2016;197(7):2796&#x2013;2806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5026932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27543615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park C.K., Xu Z.Z., Liu T., Lu N., Serhan C.N., Ji R.R. Resolvin D2 is a potent endogenous inhibitor for transient receptor potential subtype V1/A1, inflammatory pain, and spinal cord synaptic plasticity in mice: distinct roles of resolvin D1, D2, and E1. J. Neurosci. 2011;31(50):18433&#x2013;18438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3242808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22171045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albuquerque-Souza E., Schulte F., Chen T., Hardt M., Hasturk H., Van Dyke T.E., Holzhausen M., Kantarci A. Maresin-1 and resolvin E1 promote regenerative properties of periodontal ligament stem cells under inflammatory conditions. Front. Immunol. 2020;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7546375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33101318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddoch-Cardenas K.M., Sharma U., Salgado C.L., Cantu C., Darlington D.N., Pidcoke H.F., Bynum J.A., Cap A.P. Use of specialized pro-resolving mediators to alleviate cold platelet storage lesion. Transfusion. 2020;60(Suppl. 3):S112&#x2013;s118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32478925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton J.M., Yin K. Role of specialized pro-resolving mediators in modifying host defense and decreasing bacterial virulence. Molecules. 2021;26(22):6970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8618792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34834062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Purvis G.S.D., Collotta D., Al Zoubi S., Sugimoto M.A., Cacace A., Martin L., Colas R.A., Collino M., Dalli J., Thiemermann C. RvE1 attenuates polymicrobial sepsis-induced cardiac dysfunction and enhances bacterial clearance. Front. Immunol. 2020;11:2080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7492649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32983159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keyes K.T., Ye Y., Lin Y., Zhang C., Perez-Polo J.R., Gjorstrup P., Birnbaum Y. Resolvin E1 protects the rat heart against reperfusion injury. Am. J. Physiol. Heart Circ. Physiol. 2010;299(1):H153&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20435846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freire M.O., Dalli J., Serhan C.N., Van Dyke T.E. Neutrophil resolvin E1 receptor expression and function in type 2 diabetes. J. Immunol. 2017;198(2):718&#x2013;728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5224973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27994073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell E.L., MacManus C.F., Kominsky D.J., Keely S., Glover L.E., Bowers B.E., Scully M., Bruyninckx W.J., Colgan S.P. Resolvin E1-induced intestinal alkaline phosphatase promotes resolution of inflammation through LPS detoxification. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2010;107(32):14298&#x2013;14303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2922533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20660763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quiros M., Feier D., Birkl D., Agarwal R., Zhou D.W., Garcia A.J., Parkos C.A., Nusrat A. Resolvin E1 is a pro-repair molecule that promotes intestinal epithelial wound healing. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2020;117(17):9477&#x2013;9482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7197018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32300016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haworth O., Cernadas M., Levy B.D. NK cells are effectors for resolvin E1 in the timely resolution of allergic airway inflammation. J. Immunol. 2011;186(11):6129&#x2013;6135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3823382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21515793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Periz A., Horrillo R., Ferre N., Gronert K., Dong B., Moran-Salvador E., Titos E., Martinez-Clemente M., Lopez-Parra M., Arroyo V., Claria J. Obesity-induced insulin resistance and hepatic steatosis are alleviated by omega-3 fatty acids: a role for resolvins and protectins. FASEB J. 2009;23(6):1946&#x2013;1957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2698663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19211925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho K.J., Spite M., Owens C.D., Lancero H., Kroemer A.H., Pande R., Creager M.A., Serhan C.N., Conte M.S. Aspirin-triggered lipoxin and resolvin E1 modulate vascular smooth muscle phenotype and correlate with peripheral atherosclerosis. Am. J. Pathol. 2010;177(4):2116&#x2013;2123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2947304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20709806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulciner M.L., Serhan C.N., Gilligan M.M., Mudge D.K., Chang J., Gartung A., Lehner K.A., Bielenberg D.R., Schmidt B., Dalli J., Greene E.R., Gus-Brautbar Y., Piwowarski J., Mammoto T., Zurakowski D., Perretti M., Sukhatme V.P., Kaipainen A., Kieran M.W., Huang S., Panigrahy D. Resolvins suppress tumor growth and enhance cancer therapy. J. Exp. Med. 2018;215(1):115&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5748851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29191914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawada Y., Honda T., Nakamizo S., Otsuka A., Ogawa N., Kobayashi Y., Nakamura M., Kabashima K. Resolvin E1 attenuates murine psoriatic dermatitis. Sci. Rep. 2018;8(1):11873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6082864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30089836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas-Stapleton E.J., Lu Y., Hong S., Arita M., Favoreto S., Nigam S., Serhan C.N., Agabian N. Candida albicans modulates host defense by biosynthesizing the pro-resolving mediator resolvin E1. PLoS One. 2007;2(12):e1316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2134765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18091990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajasagi N.K., Reddy P.B., Suryawanshi A., Mulik S., Gjorstrup P., Rouse B.T. Controlling herpes simplex virus-induced ocular inflammatory lesions with the lipid-derived mediator resolvin E1. J. Immunol. 2011;186(3):1735&#x2013;1746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3888773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21187448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z.Z., Zhang L., Liu T., Park J.Y., Berta T., Yang R., Serhan C.N., Ji R.R. Resolvins RvE1 and RvD1 attenuate inflammatory pain via central and peripheral actions. Nat. Med. 2010;16(5):592&#x2013;597. 1p following 597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2866054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20383154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colas R.A., Souza P.R., Walker M.E., Burton M., Zaslona Z., Curtis A.M., Marques R.M., Dalli J. Impaired production and diurnal regulation of vascular RvDn-3 DPA increase systemic inflammation and cardiovascular disease. Circ. Res. 2018;122(6):855&#x2013;863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5924694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29437834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez J.L., Gasper W.J., Khetani S.A., Zahner G.J., Hills N.K., Mitchell P.T., Sansbury B.E., Conte M.S., Spite M., Grenon S.M. Fish oil increases specialized pro-resolving lipid mediators in PAD (The OMEGA-PAD II trial) J. Surg. Res. 2019;238:164&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6462350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30771686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnardottir H., Orr S.K., Dalli J., Serhan C.N. Human milk proresolving mediators stimulate resolution of acute inflammation. Mucosal Immunol. 2016;9(3):757&#x2013;766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4833718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26462421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motwani M.P., Colas R.A., George M.J., Flint J.D., Dalli J., Richard-Loendt A., Dee Maeyer R.P., Serhan C.N., Gilroy D.W. Pro-resolving mediators promote resolution in a human skin model of UV-killed Escherichia coli-driven acute inflammation. JCI Insight. 2018;3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5926908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29563331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deyama S., Shimoda K., Suzuki H., Ishikawa Y., Ishimura K., Fukuda H., Hitora-Imamura N., Ide S., Satoh M., Kaneda K., Shuto S., Minami M. Resolvin E1/E2 ameliorate lipopolysaccharide-induced depression-like behaviors via ChemR23. Psychopharmacology (Berl.) 2018;235(1):329&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29090333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murakami Y., Fukuda H., Muromoto R., Hirashima K., Ishimura K., Fujiwara K., Ishihara J., Matsuda T., Watanabe M., Shuto S. Design and synthesis of benzene congeners of resolvin E2, a proresolving lipid mediator, as its stable equivalents. ACS Med. Chem. Lett. 2020;11(4):479&#x2013;484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7153029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32292553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato M., Aoki-Saito H., Fukuda H., Ikeda H., Koga Y., Yatomi M., Tsurumaki H., Maeno T., Saito T., Nakakura T., Mori T., Yanagawa M., Abe M., Sako Y., Dobashi K., Ishizuka T., Yamada M., Shuto S., Hisada T. Resolvin E3 attenuates allergic airway inflammation via the interleukin-23-interleukin-17A pathway. FASEB J. 2019;33(11):12750&#x2013;12759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6902733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31469599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deyama S., Shimoda K., Ikeda H., Fukuda H., Shuto S., Minami M. Resolvin E3 attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced depression-like behavior in mice. J. Pharmacol. Sci. 2018;138(1):86&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30293959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita A., Kawana K., Tomio K., Taguchi A., Isobe Y., Iwamoto R., Masuda K., Furuya H., Nagamatsu T., Nagasaka K., Arimoto T., Oda K., Wada-Hiraike O., Yamashita T., Taketani Y., Kang J.X., Kozuma S., Arai H., Arita M., Osuga Y., Fujii T. Increased tissue levels of omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids prevents pathological preterm birth. Sci. Rep. 2013;3:3113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3814804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24177907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda H., Ikeda H., Muromoto R., Hirashima K., Ishimura K., Fujiwara K., Aoki-Saito H., Hisada T., Watanabe M., Ishihara J., Matsuda T., Shuto S. Synthesis of resolvin E3, a proresolving lipid mediator, and its deoxy derivatives: identification of 18-deoxy-resolvin E3 as a potent anti-inflammatory agent. J. Org. Chem. 2020;85(21):14190&#x2013;14200. doi: 10.1021/acs.joc.0c01701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.joc.0c01701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32942849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deyama S. Resolvins as novel targets for rapid-acting antidepressants. Folia Pharmacol. Jpn. 2020;155(6):381&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33132254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt D.L., Steg P.G., Miller M. Cardiovascular risk reduction with icosapent ethyl. reply. N. Engl. J. Med. 2019;380(17):1678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31018077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan A., Sullenbarger B., Prakash R., McDaniel J.C. Supplementation with eicosapentaenoic acid and docosahexaenoic acid reduces high levels of circulating proinflammatory cytokines in aging adults: a randomized, controlled study. Prostaglandins Leukot. Essent. Fatty Acids. 2018;132:23&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5941937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29735019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza P.R., Marques R.M., Gomez E.A., Colas R.A., De Matteis R., Zak A., Patel M., Collier D.J., Dalli J. Enriched marine oil supplements increase peripheral blood specialized pro-resolving mediators concentrations and reprogram host immune responses: a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled study. Circ. Res. 2020;126(1):75&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31829100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welty F.K., Schulte F., Alfaddagh A., Elajami T.K., Bistrian B.R., Hardt M. Regression of human coronary artery plaque is associated with a high ratio of (18-hydroxy-eicosapentaenoic acid + resolvin E1) to leukotriene B(4) FASEB J. 2021;35(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8037777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33749913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeley E.C., Li H.J., Cogle C.R., Handberg E.M., Merz C.N.B., Pepine C.J. Specialized proresolving mediators in symptomatic women with coronary microvascular dysfunction (from the women&#x2019;s ischemia trial to reduce events in nonobstructive CAD [WARRIOR] trial) Am. J. Cardiol. 2022;162:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8754056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34728061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y.-P., Oh S.F., Uddin J., Yang R., Gotlinger K., Campbell E., Colgan S.P., Petasis N.A., Serhan C.N. Resolvin D1 and its aspirin-triggered 17R epimer: stereochemical assignments, anti-inflammatory properties and enzymatic inactivation. J. Biol. Chem. 2007;282:9323&#x2013;9334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17244615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spite M., Norling L.V., Summers L., Yang R., Cooper D., Petasis N.A., Flower R.J., Perretti M., Serhan C.N. Resolvin D2 is a potent regulator of leukocytes and controls microbial sepsis. Nature. 2009;461:1287&#x2013;1291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2779525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19865173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalli J., Winkler J.W., Colas R.A., Arnardottir H., Cheng C.Y.C., Chiang N., Petasis N.A., Serhan C.N. Resolvin D3 and aspirin-triggered resolvin D3 are potent immunoresolvents. Chem. Biol. 2013;20:188&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3583372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23438748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norris P.C., Arnardottir H., Sanger J.M., Fichtner D., Keyes G.S., Serhan C.N. Resolvin D3 multi-level proresolving actions are host protective during infection. Prostaglandins Leukot. Essent. Fatty Acids. 2018;138:81&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4958045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26858146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler J.W., Uddin J., Serhan C.N., Petasis N.A. Stereocontrolled total synthesis of the potent anti-inflammatory and pro-resolving lipid mediator resolvin D3 and its aspirin-triggered 17R-epimer. Org. Lett. 2013;15(7):1424&#x2013;1427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3696528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23510485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler J.W., Libreros S., De La Rosa X., Sansbury B.E., Norris P.C., Chiang N., Fichtner D., Keyes G.S., Wourms N., Spite M., Serhan C.N. Structural insights into Resolvin D4 actions and further metabolites via a new total organic synthesis and validation. J. Leukoc. Biol. 2018;103:995&#x2013;1010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6136982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29377345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler J.W., Orr S.K., Dalli J., Cheng C.Y., Sanger J.M., Chiang N., Petasis N.A., Serhan C.N. Resolvin D4 stereoassignment and its novel actions in host protection and bacterial clearance. Sci. Rep. 2016;6:18972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4705531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26743932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shay A.E., Nshimiyimana R., Samuelsson B., Petasis N.A., Haeggstrom J.Z., Serhan C.N. Human leukocytes selectively convert 4S,5S-epoxy-resolvin to resolvin D3, resolvin D4, and a cys-resolvin isomer. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2021;118(51)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8713978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34911767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherpokova D., Jouvene C.C., Libreros S., DeRoo E., Chu L., de la Rosa X., Norris P., Wagner D.D., Serhan C.N. Resolvin D4 attenuates the severity of pathological thrombosis in mice. Blood. 2019;134:1458&#x2013;1468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6839959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31300403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holinstat M. Resolvin the clot: DVT resolution through RvD4. Blood. 2019;134:1370&#x2013;1371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6839958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31698428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh K. Resolution of thrombus burden by targeting inflammatory mediators to treat DVT. Nat. Rev. Cardiol. 2019;16(10):577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31435029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morita M., Kobayashi Y. Stereocontrolled synthesis of resolvin D4. J. Org. Chem. 2018;83(7):3906&#x2013;3914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29547275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz L.A., Altman N.H., Khan W.N., Serhan C.N., Adkins B. Specialized proresolving mediators rescue infant mice from lethal Citrobacter rodentium infection and promote immunity against reinfection. Infect. Immun. 2017;85(10):e00464&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5607424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28694292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez A.R., Spur B.W. First total synthesis of 7(S),17(S)-resolvin D5, a potent anti-inflammatory docosanoid. Tetrahedron Lett. 2005;46:3623&#x2013;3627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa N., Sugiyama T., Morita M., Suganuma Y., Kobayashi Y. Total synthesis of resolvin D5. J. Org. Chem. 2017;82(4):2032&#x2013;2039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28098462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry S.C., Kalyanaraman C., Tourdot B.E., Conrad W.S., Akinkugbe O., Freedman J.C., Holinstat M., Jacobson M.P., Holman T.R. 15-Lipoxygenase-1 biosynthesis of 7S,14S-diHDHA implicates 15-lipoxygenase-2 in biosynthesis of resolvin D5. J. Lipid Res. 2020;61(7):1087&#x2013;1103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7328043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32404334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorokin A.V., Norris P., English J., Dey A.K., Chaturvedi A., Baumer Y., Silverman J., Playford M.P., Serhan C.N., Mehta N.N. Identification of pro-resolving and inflammatory lipid mediators in human psoriasis. J. Clin. Lipidol. 2018;12(4):1047&#x2013;1060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6112609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29730187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rich&#xe9; F., Chousterman B.G., Valleur P., Mebazaa A., Launay J.M., Gayat E. Protracted immune disorders at one year after ICU discharge in patients with septic shock. Crit. Care. 2018;22:42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5822646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29467023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo X., Gu Y., Tao X., Serhan C.N., Ji R.R. Resolvin D5 inhibits neuropathic and inflammatory pain in male but not female mice: distinct actions of D-series resolvins in chemotherapy-induced peripheral neuropathy. Front. Pharmacol. 2019;10:745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6624779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31333464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ariel A., Li P.-L., Wang W., Tang W.-X., Fredman G., Hong S., Gotlinger K.H., Serhan C.N. The docosatriene protectin D1 is produced by TH2 skewing and promotes human T cell apoptosis via lipid raft clustering. J. Biol. Chem. 2005;280:43079&#x2013;43086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16216871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiurchiu V., Leuti A., Dalli J., Jacobsson A., Battistini L., Maccarrone M., Serhan C.N. Proresolving lipid mediators resolvin D1, resolvin D2, and maresin 1 are critical in modulating T cell responses. Sci. Transl. Med. 2016;8(353)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5149396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27559094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramon S., Bancos S., Thatcher T.H., Murant T.I., Moshkani S., Sahler J.M., Bottaro A., Sime P.J., Phipps R.P. Peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor gamma B cell-specific-deficient mice have an impaired antibody response. J. Immunol. 2012;189(10):4740&#x2013;4747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3490033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23041568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada H., Saegusa J., Sendo S., Ueda Y., Okano T., Shinohara M., Morinobu A. Effect of resolvin D5 on T cell differentiation and osteoclastogenesis analyzed by lipid mediator profiling in the experimental arthritis. Sci. Rep. 2021;11(1):17312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8397777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34453072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham T.L., He J., Kakazu A.H., Calandria J., Do K.V., Nshimiyimana R., Petasis N.A., Bazan H.E.P., Bazan N.G. Elovanoid-N32 or RvD6-isomer decrease ACE2 and binding of S protein RBD after injury or INF&#x3b3; in the eye. Res. Sq. 2020 doi: 10.21203/rs.3.rs-55764/v1. [Preprint]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.3.rs-55764/v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham T.L., He J., Kakazu A.H., Calandria J., Do K.V., Nshimiyimana R., Lam T.F., Petasis N.A., Bazan H.E.P., Bazan N.G. ELV-N32 and RvD6 isomer decrease pro-inflammatory cytokines, senescence programming, ACE2 and SARS-CoV-2-spike protein RBD binding in injured cornea. Sci. Rep. 2021;11(1):12787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8211643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34140611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham T.L., Bazan H.E.P. Docosanoid signaling modulates corneal nerve regeneration: effect on tear secretion, wound healing, and neuropathic pain. J. Lipid Res. 2021;62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7933495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cianci E., Recchiuti A., Trubiani O., Diomede F., Marchisio M., Miscia S., Colas R.A., Dalli J., Serhan C.N., Romano M. Human periodontal stem cells release specialized proresolving mediators and carry immunomodulatory and prohealing properties regulated by lipoxins. Stem Cells Transl. Med. 2016;5(1):20&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4704879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26607175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham T.L., Kakazu A.H., He J., Nshimiyimana R., Petasis N.A., Jun B., Bazan N.G., Bazan H.E.P. Elucidating the structure and functions of Resolvin D6 isomers on nerve regeneration with a distinctive trigeminal transcriptome. FASEB J. 2021;35(8)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8362171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34245621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong S., Tjonahen E., Morgan E.L., Yu L., Serhan C.N., Rowley A.F. Rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss) brain cells biosynthesize novel docosahexaenoic acid-derived resolvins and protectins &#x2013; mediator lipidomic analysis. Prostaglandins Other Lipid Mediat. 2005;78:107&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16303609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calder P.C. Eicosapentaenoic and docosahexaenoic acid derived specialised pro-resolving mediators: concentrations in humans and the effects of age, sex, disease and increased omega-3 fatty acid intake. Biochimie. 2020;178:105&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raatz S.K., Golovko M.Y., Brose S.A., Rosenberger T.A., Burr G.S., Wolters W.R., Picklo M.J., Sr. Baking reduces prostaglandin, resolvin, and hydroxy-fatty acid content of farm-raised Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar) J. Agric. Food Chem. 2011;59:11278&#x2013;11286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3222145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21919483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee P.K., Marcheselli V.L., Serhan C.N., Bazan N.G. Neuroprotectin D1: a docosahexaenoic acid-derived docosatriene protects human retinal pigment epithelial cells from oxidative stress. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2004;101:8491&#x2013;8496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC420421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15152078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcheselli V.L., Hong S., Lukiw W.J., Hua Tian X., Gronert K., Musto A., Hardy M., Gimenez J.M., Chiang N., Serhan C.N., Bazan N.G. Novel docosanoids inhibit brain ischemia-reperfusion-mediated leukocyte infiltration and pro-inflammatory gene expression. J. Biol. Chem. 2003;278:43807&#x2013;43817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12923200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gronert K., Maheshwari N., Khan N., Hassan I.R., Dunn M., Schwartzman M.L. A role for the mouse 12/15-lipoxygenase pathway in promoting epithelial wound healing and host defense. J. Biol. Chem. 2005;280:15267&#x2013;15278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15708862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy B.D., Kohli P., Gotlinger K., Haworth O., Hong S., Kazani S., Israel E., Haley K.J., Serhan C.N. Protectin D1 is generated in asthma and dampens airway inflammation and hyper-responsiveness. J. Immunol. 2007;178:496&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3005704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17182589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffield J.S., Hong S., Vaidya V., Lu Y., Fredman G., Serhan C.N., Bonventre J.V. Resolvin D series and protectin D1 mitigate acute kidney injury. J. Immunol. 2006;177:5902&#x2013;5911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17056514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukiw W.J., Cui J.G., Marcheselli V.L., Bodker M., Botkjaer A., Gotlinger K., Serhan C.N., Bazan N.G. A role for docosahexaenoic acid-derived neuroprotectin D1 in neural cell survival and Alzheimer disease. J. Clin. Invest. 2005;115:2774&#x2013;2783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1199531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16151530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N., Gotlinger K., Hong S., Lu Y., Siegelman J., Baer T., Yang R., Colgan S.P., Petasis N.A. Anti-inflammatory actions of neuroprotectin D1/protectin D1 and its natural stereoisomers: assignments of dihydroxy-containing docosatrienes. J. Immunol. 2006;176:1848&#x2013;1859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16424216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N., Fredman G., Yang R., Karamnov S., Belayev L.S., Bazan N.G., Zhu M., Winkler J.W., Petasis N.A. Novel proresolving aspirin-triggered DHA pathway. Chem. Biol. 2011;18:976&#x2013;987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3164791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21867913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N., Dalli J., Colas R.A., Winkler J.W., Chiang N. Protectins and maresins: new pro-resolving families of mediators in acute inflammation and resolution bioactive metabolome. Biochim. Biophys. Acta. 2015;1851:397&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4324013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25139562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N., Dalli J., Karamnov S., Choi A., Park C.K., Xu Z.Z., Ji R.R., Zhu M., Petasis N.A. Macrophage pro-resolving mediator maresin 1 stimulates tissue regeneration and controls pain. FASEB J. 2012;26:1755&#x2013;1765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3316905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22253477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalli J., Zhu M., Vlasenko N.A., Deng B., Haeggstrom J.Z., Petasis N.A., Serhan C.N. The novel 13S,14S-epoxy-maresin is converted by human macrophages to maresin1 (MaR1), inhibits leukotriene A4 hydrolase (LTA4H), and shifts macrophage phenotype. FASEB J. 2013;27:2573&#x2013;2583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3688739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23504711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng B., Wang C.W., Arnardottir H.H., Li Y., Cheng C.Y., Dalli J., Serhan C.N. Maresin biosynthesis and identification of maresin 2, a new anti-inflammatory and pro-resolving mediator from human macrophages. PLoS One. 2014;9(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4103848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25036362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramon S., Dalli J., Sanger J.M., Winkler J.W., Aursnes M., Tungen J.E., Hansen T.V., Serhan C.N. The Protectin PCTR1 is produced by human M2 macrophages and enhances resolution of infectious inflammation. Am. J. Pathol. 2016;186:962&#x2013;973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4822332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26878209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalli J., Chiang N., Serhan C.N. Identification of sulfido-conjugated mediators that promote resolution of infection and organ protection. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2014;111:E4753&#x2013;4761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4226123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25324525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de la Rosa X., Norris P.C., Chiang N., Rodriguez A.R., Spur B.W., Serhan C.N. Identification and complete stereochemical assignments of the new Resolvin Conjugates in Tissue Regeneration (RCTR) in human tissues that stimulate proresolving phagocyte functions and tissue regeneration. Am. J. Pathol. 2018;188:950&#x2013;966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5866152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29571326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalli J., Ramon S., Norris P.C., Colas R.A., Serhan C.N. Novel proresolving and tissue regenerative resolvin and protectin sulfido-conjugated pathways. FASEB J. 2015;29:2120&#x2013;2136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4415017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25713027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalli J., Vlasakov I., Riley I.R., Rodriguez A.R., Spur B., Petasis N.A., Chiang N., Serhan C.N. Maresin conjugates in tissue regeneration biosynthesis enzymes in human macrophages. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2016;113:12232&#x2013;12237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5087052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27791009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jouvene C.C., Shay A.E., Soens M.A., Norris P.C., Haeggstrom J.Z., Serhan C.N. Biosynthetic metabolomes of cysteinyl-containing immunoresolvents. FASEB J. 2019;33:13794&#x2013;13807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6894058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31589826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang N., Serhan C.N. Specialized pro-resolving mediator network: an update on production and actions. Essays Biochem. 2020;64:443&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7682745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32885825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddipati K.R. Non-inflammatory physiology of &#x201c;Inflammatory&#x201d; mediators - unalamation, a new paradigm. Front. Immunol. 2020;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33117385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>So J., Wu D., Lichtenstein A.H., Tai A.K., Matthan N.R., Maddipati K.R., Lamon-Fava S. EPA and DHA differentially modulate monocyte inflammatory response in subjects with chronic inflammation in part via plasma specialized pro-resolving lipid mediators: a randomized, double-blind, crossover study. Atherosclerosis. 2021;316:90&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai W.C., Kalyanaraman C., Yamaguchi A., Holinstat M., Jacobson M.P., Holman T.R. In vitro biosynthetic pathway investigations of neuroprotectin D1 (NPD1) and protectin DX (PDX) by human 12-lipoxygenase, 15-lipoxygenase-1, and 15-lipoxygenase-2. Biochemistry. 2021;60(22):1741&#x2013;1754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9007043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34029049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C.R., Zeldin D.C. Resolvin infectious inflammation by targeting the host response. N. Engl. J. Med. 2015;373(22):2183&#x2013;2185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5512422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26605933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N., Chiang N., Dalli J., Levy B.D. Lipid mediators in the resolution of inflammation. Cold Spring Harb. Perspect. Biol. 2014;7(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4315926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25359497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simopoulos A.P., Serhan C.N., Bazinet R.P. The need for precision nutrition, genetic variation and resolution in Covid-19 patients. Mol. Aspects Med. 2021;77</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7843119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33551236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norling L.V., Spite M., Yang R., Flower R.J., Perretti M., Serhan C.N. Cutting edge: humanized nano-proresolving medicines mimic inflammation-resolution and enhance wound healing. J. Immunol. 2011;186:5543&#x2013;5547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3145138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21460209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sok M.C.P., Tria M.C., Olingy C.E., San Emeterio C.L., Botchwey E.A. Aspirin-Triggered Resolvin D1-modified materials promote the accumulation of pro-regenerative immune cell subsets and enhance vascular remodeling. Acta Biomater. 2017;53:109&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5512001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28213094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon R., Krzyszczyk P., Berthiaume F. Pro-resolution potency of resolvins D1, D2 and E1 on neutrophil migration and in dermal wound healing. Nano Life. 2017;7(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5851488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29552232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norris P.C., Libreros S., Chiang N., Serhan C.N. A cluster of immunoresolvents links coagulation to innate host defense in human blood. Sci. Signal. 2017;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5683850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28765512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnardottir H., Pawelzik S.C., &#xd6;hlund Wistbacka U., Artiach G., Hofmann R., Reinholdsson I., Braunschweig F., Tornvall P., Religa D., B&#xe4;ck M. Stimulating the resolution of inflammation through Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids in COVID-19: rationale for the COVID-Omega-F trial. Front. Physiol. 2020;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7830247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33505321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilroy D.W., Lawrence T., Perretti M., Rossi A.G. Inflammatory resolution: new opportunities for drug discovery. Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 2004;3:401&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15136788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan C.N., Savill J. Resolution of inflammation: the beginning programs the end. Nat. Immunol. 2005;6:1191&#x2013;1197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16369558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredman G., Van Dyke T.E., Serhan C.N. Resolvin E1 regulates adenosine diphosphate activation of human platelets. Arterioscler. Thromb. Vasc. Biol. 2010;30(10):2005&#x2013;2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2982748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20702811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy B.D., Zhang Q.Y., Bonnans C., Primo V., Reilly J.J., Perkins D.L., Liang Y., Amin Arnaout M., Nikolic B., Serhan C.N. The endogenous pro-resolving mediators lipoxin A4 and resolvin E1 preserve organ function in allograft rejection. Prostaglandins Leukot. Essent. Fatty Acids. 2011;84(1&#x2013;2):43&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3019284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20869861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantarci A., Aytan N., Palaska I., Stephens D., Crabtree L., Benincasa C., Jenkins B.G., Carreras I., Dedeoglu A. Combined administration of resolvin E1 and lipoxin A4 resolves inflammation in a murine model of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Exp. Neurol. 2018;300:111&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29126887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laguna-Fernandez A., Checa A., Carracedo M., Artiach G., Petri M.H., Baumgartner R., Forteza M.J., Jiang X., Andonova T., Walker M.E., Dalli J., Arnardottir H., Gistera A., Thul S., Wheelock C.E., Paulsson-Berne G., Ketelhuth D.F.J., Hansson G.K., Back M. ERV1/ChemR23 signaling protects against atherosclerosis by modifying oxidized low-density lipoprotein uptake and phagocytosis in macrophages. Circulation. 2018;138(16):1693&#x2013;1705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6200387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29739755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colgan S.P. Resolvins resolve to heal mucosal wounds. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2020;117(20):10621&#x2013;10622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32371481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isobe Y., Arita M., Iwamoto R., Urabe D., Todoroki H., Masuda K., Inoue M., Arai H. Stereochemical assignment and anti-inflammatory properties of the omega-3 lipid mediator resolvin E3. J. Biochem. 2013;153(4):355&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23293324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Chen C.Y., Arita M., Kim K., Li X., Zhang H., Kang J.X. An omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acid derivative, 18-HEPE, protects against CXCR4-associated melanoma metastasis. Carcinogenesis. 2018;39(11):1380&#x2013;1388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7191087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30184109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiore S., Serhan C.N. Formation of lipoxins and leukotrienes during receptor-mediated interactions of human platelets and recombinant human granulocyte/macrophage colony-stimulating factor-primed neutrophils. J. Exp. Med. 1990;172(5):1451&#x2013;1457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2188683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2172436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowley A.F., Lloyd-Evans P., Barrow S.E., Serhan C.N. Lipoxin biosynthesis by trout macrophages involves the formation of epoxide intermediates. Biochemistry. 1994;33(4):856&#x2013;863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8305432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koltsida O., Karamnov S., Pyrillou K., Vickery T., Chairakaki A.D., Tamvakopoulos C., Sideras P., Serhan C.N., Andreakos E. Toll-like receptor 7 stimulates production of specialized pro-resolving lipid mediators and promotes resolution of airway inflammation. EMBO Mol. Med. 2013;5(5):762&#x2013;775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3662318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23584892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukic A., Larssen P., Fauland A., Samuelsson B., Wheelock C.E., Gabrielsson S., Radmark O. GM-CSF- and M-CSF-primed macrophages present similar resolving but distinct inflammatory lipid mediator signatures. FASEB J. 2017;31(10):4370&#x2013;4381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28637652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada T., Tani Y., Nakanishi H., Taguchi R., Arita M., Arai H. Eosinophils promote resolution of acute periotonitis by producing proresolving mediators in mice. FASEB J. 2011;25:561&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20959515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang N., Shinohara M., Dalli J., Mirakaj V., Kibi M., Choi A.M., Serhan C.N. Inhaled carbon monoxide accelerates resolution of inflammation via unique proresolving mediator-heme oxygenase-1 circuits. J. Immunol. 2013;190(12):6378&#x2013;6388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3679316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23650615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahl&#xe9;n S.-E., Serhan C.N. In: Lipoxygenases and Their Products. Wong A., Crooke S.T., editors. Academic Press; San Diego: 1991. Lipoxins: bioactive lipoxygenase interaction products; pp. 235&#x2013;276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa M., Ishihara T., Isobe Y., Kato T., Kuba K., Imai Y., Uchino Y., Tsubota K., Arita M. Eosinophils promote corneal wound healing via the 12/15-lipoxygenase pathway. FASEB J. 2020;34(9):12492&#x2013;12501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32721046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M., Ohira T., Sun Y.P., Elangovan S., Chiang N., Serhan C.N. Resolvin E1 selectively interacts with leukotriene B4 receptor BLT1 and ChemR23 to regulate inflammation. J. Immunol. 2007;178:3912&#x2013;3917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17339491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong S., Porter T.F., Lu Y., Oh S.F., Pillai P.S., Serhan C.N. Resolvin E1 metabolome in local inactivation during inflammation-resolution. J. Immunol. 2008;180:3512&#x2013;3519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18292578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>