<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38028346</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2059-8661</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical and translational science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Transl Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring team dynamics during the development of a multi-institutional cross-disciplinary translational team: Implications for potential best practices.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e220</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e220</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e220</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1017/cts.2023.640</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A recent literature review revealed no studies that explored teams that used an explicit theoretical framework for multiteam systems in academic settings, such as the increasingly important multi-institutional cross-disciplinary translational team (MCTT) form. We conducted an exploratory 30-interview grounded theory study over two rounds to analyze participants' experiences from three universities who assembled an MCTT in order to pursue a complex grant proposal related to research on post-acute sequelae of COVID-19, also called "long COVID." This article considers activities beginning with preliminary discussions among principal investigators through grant writing and submission, and completion of reviews by the National Center for Advancing Translational Sciences, which resulted in the proposal not being scored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There were two stages to this interview study with MCTT members: pre-submission, and post-decision. Round one focused on the process of developing structures to collaborate on proposal writing and assembly, whereas round two focused on evaluation of the complete process. A total of 15 participants agreed to be interviewed in each round.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The first round of interviews was conducted prior to submission and explored issues during proposal writing, including (1) importance of the topic; (2) meaning and perception of "team" within the MCTT context; and (3) leadership at different levels of the team. The second round explored best practices-related issues including (1) leadership and design; (2) specific proposal assembly tasks; (3) communication; and (4) critical events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We conclude with suggestions for developing best practices for assembling MCTTs involving multi-institutional teams.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kotarba</LastName><ForeName>Joseph A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5345-8152</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Translational Sciences, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sociology, Texas State University, San Marcos, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Molldrem</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1907-8081</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Translational Sciences, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Bioethics and Health Humanities, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Elise</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4615-8204</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Translational Sciences, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Bioethics and Health Humanities, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spratt</LastName><ForeName>Heidi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9420-5028</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Translational Sciences, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics and Data Science, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhavnani</LastName><ForeName>Suresh K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9282-8838</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Translational Sciences, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics and Data Science, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farroni</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Translational Sciences, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Bioethics and Health Humanities, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wooten</LastName><ForeName>Kevin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Translational Sciences, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Houston Clear Lake, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR001439</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Transl Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101689953</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2059-8661</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">leadership</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multi-institutional</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">team science</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">translational science</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38028346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10643934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/cts.2023.640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2059866123006404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ameredes BT, Hellmich MR, Cestone CM, et al. The multidisciplinary translational team (MTT) model for training and development of translational research investigators: MTT model for training and development of translational investigators. Clin Transl Sci. 2015;8(5):533&#x2013;541. doi: 10.1111/cts.12281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cts.12281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4626313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26010046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotarba JA. Symbolic interaction and applied social research: a focus on translational science research. Symb Interact. 2014;37(3):412&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4159952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25221375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones B, Wuchy S, Uzzi B. Multi-university research teams: shifting impact, geography, and stratification in science. Science. 2008;21(5905):1259&#x2013;1262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18845711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disis ML, Slattery JT. The road we must take: multidisciplinary team science. Sci Transl Med. 2010;2:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20374998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wuchty S, Jones BF, Uzzi B. The increasing dominance of teams in production of knowledge. Science. 2007;316(5827):1036&#x2013;1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17431139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calhoun W, Wooten K, Bhavnani S, Anderson K, Freeman J. Brasier AR the CTSA as an exemplar framework for developing multidisciplinary translational teams. Clin Transl Sci. 2012;6(1):60&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3786412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23399092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wooten KC, Calhoun WJ, Bhavnani S, Rose RM, Ameredes B, Brasier AR. Evolution of multidisciplinary translational teams (MTTs): insights for accelerating translational innovations. Clin Transl Sci. 2015;5:542&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4575623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25801998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerner D, Palm ME, Concannon TW. Broadly Engaged Team Science in Clinical and Translational Research. Cham, Switzerland: Springer International Publishing; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall KL, Vogel AL, Stipleman BA, Stokols D, Morgan G, Gehlert S. A four phase model of translational team-based research: goals, team processes, and strategies. Transl Behav Med. 2012;2(4):415&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3589144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23483588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaccaro SJ, Marks MA, DeChurch LA. Multiteam systems: An organization form for dynamic and complex environments. London: Routledge/Taylor &amp; Francis Group; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter DR, Asencio R, Trainer HM, DeChurch LA, Kanfer R, Zaccaro SJ. Best practices for researchers working in multiteam systems. In: Hall KL, Vogel AL, Croyle RT, eds. Strategies for Team Science Success. Berlin: Springer International Publishing; 2019: 391&#x2013;400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings JN, Kiesler S. Collaborative research across disciplinary and organizational boundaries. Soc Stud Sci. 2005;35(5):703&#x2013;722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wooten KC, Rose RM, Oster GV, Calhoun WJ, Ameredes BT, Brasier AR. Assessing and evaluating multidisciplinary translational teams: a mixed methods approach. Eval Health Prof. 2014;37(1):33&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4180502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24064432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhavnani SK, Zhang W, Hatch S, Urban R, Tignanelli C. Identification of symptom-based phenotypes in PASC patients through bipartite network analysis: implications for patient triage and precision treatment strategies. J Clin Transl Sci. 2022;6(s1):68&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeChurch LA, Zaccaro SJ. Perspectives: Teams won't solve this problem. Hum Factors. 2010;52(2):329&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20942260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charmaz K. Constructing Grounded Theory: A Practical Guide Through Qualitative Analysis. 2nd ed. London: Sage; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser K. Protecting respondent confidentiality in qualitative research. Qual Health Res. 2009;19(11):1632&#x2013;1641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2805454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19843971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullen MR, Baiocchi M, Chamberlain L, et al. Population health science as a unifying foundation for translational clinical and public health research. SSM - Population Health. 2022;18:101047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8885441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35252530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman M, Hamm ME, Schenker Y, et al. 200 benefits and challenges of human-centered design: perspectives from research teams. JCTS. 2022;6(1):29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Montoya L, Mahoney J. The logic of critical event analysis. Trajectories. 2019;30:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peralta CF, Lopes PN, Gilson LL, et al. Innovation processes and team effectiveness: the role of goal clarity and commitment, and team affective tone. J Occup Organ Psychol. 2015;88(1):80&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West MA, Borrill CS, Dawson JF, Brodbeck F, Shapiro DA, Haward B. Leadership clarity and team innovation in health care. Leadership Q. 2003;14(4-5):393&#x2013;410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout RJ, Cannon-Bowers JA, Salas E, Milanovich DM. Planning, shared mental models, and coordinated performance: An empirical link is. Hum Factors. 1999; 41(1): 61&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovacic I, Filzmoser M, Denk F. Interdisciplinary design: Influence of team structure on project. Procedia Soc. 2014; 119: 549&#x2013;556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang HL, Tang JH. Team structure and team performance in IS development: a social network perspective. Info Manage. 2004;41(3):335&#x2013;349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel MM, Moseley TW, Nia ES, Perez F, Kapoor MM, Whitman GJ. Team science: a practical approach to starting collaborative projects. J Breast Imaging. 2021; 3(6):721&#x2013;726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8599160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34805982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callaert J, Landoni P, Van Looy B, Verganti R. Scientific yield from collaboration with industry: the relevance of researchers&#x2019; strategic approaches. Res Pol. 2015;44(4):990&#x2013;998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellers TA, Caporaso N, Lapidus S, Petersen GM, Trent J. Opportunities and barriers in the age of team science: Strategies for success. Cancer Cause Control. 2006; 17: 229&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16489530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgs M, Plewnia U, Ploch J. Influence of team composition and task complexity on team performance. Team Perform Manag. 2005; 7(8):227&#x2013;250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chae S, Seo Y, Lee KC. Effects of task complexity on individual creativity through knowledge interaction: A comparison of temporary and permanent teams. Comput Hum Behav. 2015; 42: 138&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitney KM, Daniels CB. The root cause of failure in complex IT projects: Complexity itself. Procedia Comp Sci. 2013; 20: 325&#x2013;330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa AC, Roe RA, Taillieu T. Trust within teams: the relation with performance effectiveness. Eur J Work Org. 2001; 10(3):225&#x2013;244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiore SM, Carter DR, Asencio R. Conflict, trust, and cohesion: examining affective and attitudinal factors in science teams. In: Team Cohesion: Advances in Psychological Theory, Methods and Practice. Bingley UK: Emerald Group Publishing Limited; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarvenpaa SL, Leidner DE. Communication and trust in global virtual teams. Organ Sci. 1999;10(6):791&#x2013;815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilkien&#x117; M, Alonderien&#x117; R, Chmieliauskas A, &#x160;imkonis S, M&#xfc;ller R. The governance of horizontal leadership in projects. Int. J Proj Manag. 2018; 36(7):913&#x2013;924.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J, Liao Z, Yam KC, Johnson RE. Shared leadership: a state-of-the-art review and future research agenda. J Organ Behav. 2018;39(7):834&#x2013;852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Vogel, Stipelman BA, Hall KL, Nebeling L, Stokols D, Spruijt-Metz D. Pioneering the transdisciplinary team science approach: lessons learned from national cancer institute grantees. J Transl Med. 2014;2(2):1027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4280018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25554748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin Y, Kim M, Choi JN, Lee SH. Does team culture matter? roles of team culture and collective regulatory focus in team task and creative performance. Group Organ Manag. 2016;41(2):232&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz RM, Bennett LM. Team effectiveness model for science (TEMS): using a mutual learning shared mindset to design, develop, and sustain science teams. J Clin Transl Sci. 2021;5(1):e157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8427543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34527296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endsley MR, Jones W. 5 Situation Awareness. London: The Oxford Handbook of Cognitive Engineering; 2013:88&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saner LD, Bolstad CS, Gonzalez C, Cuevas HM. Measuring and predicting shared situation awareness in teams. J Cogn Eng Decis Mak. 2009;3(3):280&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Undre S, Koutantji M, Sevdalis N, et al. Multidisciplinary crisis simulations: The way forward for training surgical teams. World J Surg. 2007;31:1843&#x2013;1853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17610109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salas E, Prince C, Baker DP, Shrestha L. Situation awareness in team performance: implications for measurement and training. Hum Factors. 1995;37(1):123&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Love H, Fosdick BK, Cross JE, et al. Towards understanding the characteristics of successful and unsuccessful collaborations: a case based team science study. Humanit Soc Sci. 2022; 9(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salas E, DiazGranados D, Klein C, et al. Does team training improve team performance? A meta-analysis. Hum Factors. 2008;50(6):903&#x2013;933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19292013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delise LA, Allen Gorman C, Brooks AM, Rentsch JR, Steele-Johnson D. The effects of team training on team outcomes: a meta-analysis. Perform Improv Q. 2010;22(4):53&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begerowski S, Traylor A, Shuffler M, Salas E. An integrative review and practical guide to team development interventions for translational science teams: one size does not fit all. J Clin Transl Sci. 2021;5(1):E198. doi: 10.1017/cts.2021.832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/cts.2021.832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8634301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34888067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan S, Mosser A, Ahn S, et al. Developing and evaluating a team development intervention to support interdisciplinary teams. J Clin Transl Sci. 2021;5(1):E166. doi: 10.1017/cts.2021.831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/cts.2021.831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8532188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34733543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacerenza CN, Marlow SL, Tannenbaum SI, Salas E. Team development interventions: evidence-based approaches for improving teamwork. Am Psychol. 2018;73(4):517&#x2013;531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29792465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuffler ML, DiazGranados D, Salas E. There&#x2019;s a science for that: team development interventions in organizations. Curr Dir Psychol Sci. 2011;20(6):365&#x2013;372.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>