<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39159783</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2352-3840</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Canadian journal of diabetes</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Can J Diabetes</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence of Long COVID and the Impact on Diabetes Management and Physical Activity Participation in Adults With Type 2 Diabetes: An Australia-wide Cross-sectional Online Survey.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1499-2671(24)00147-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jcjd.2024.08.004</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this research was to understand the prevalence and impact of long COVID on adults with type 2 diabetes (T2D). Specifically, we sought to identify the proportion of adults with T2D who have had COVID-19 and experienced long COVID symptoms. We also explored how these ongoing symptoms impact diabetes management and physical activity participation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Our study was carried out using an online survey of adults in Australia with T2D who had confirmed COVID-19 &#x2265;12 weeks before participation. Respondents were asked to report the presence (and severity) of long COVID-19 symptoms, and, for those with long COVID, the impact of their symptoms on diabetes management (blood glucose, body weight) and physical activity participation (activities of daily living, work/study, exercise).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Survey responses were provided by 1,046 adults with T2D (median age 61.0 [interquartile range 49.8 to 70.0] years; 56.0% men, 42.1% women, and 1% nonbinary/transgender; median T2D duration 10.0 [5.0 to 18.0] years and median time since COVID-19 infection 33.0 [20.3 to 36.1] weeks). Almost one third (30%) of respondents reported long COVID symptoms (present &#x2265;12 weeks after most recent infection); 40% of respondents with long COVID symptoms reported a worsening of their diabetes management since their COVID-19 infection, with 29% reporting trouble controlling their blood glucose and 43% reporting a higher body weight. Two thirds of respondents with ongoing symptoms reported that these symptoms moderately to severely impacted their ability to perform activities of daily living, work, and/or exercise. The majority of those with long COVID reported reducing the frequency, duration, and/or intensity of exercise since their COVID-19 infection, with 36.1% not yet returning to their preinfection exercise levels; 66% cited ongoing symptoms as the primary reason for these limitations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Physical activity is a crucial component of diabetes management. However, the high prevalence of long COVID is hindering participation in this population, as well as deleteriously impacting diabetes management. Developing strategies to support adults with T2D and long COVID to recommence safe levels of physical activity is of critical importance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cox</LastName><ForeName>Emily R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Active Living and Learning, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia; Active Living and Learning Research Program, Hunter Medical Research Institute, New Lambton, New South Wales, Australia; School of Biomedical Sciences and Pharmacy, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia. Electronic address: emily.cox10@newcastle.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plotnikoff</LastName><ForeName>Ronald C</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Active Living and Learning, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia; Active Living and Learning Research Program, Hunter Medical Research Institute, New Lambton, New South Wales, Australia; School of Education, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gibson</LastName><ForeName>Peter G</ForeName><Initials>PG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Treatable Traits Centre for Research Excellence, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia; Asthma and Breathing Research Program, Hunter Medical Research Institute, New Lambton, New South Wales, Australia; School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia; John Hunter Hospital, New Lambton, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keating</LastName><ForeName>Shelley E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research on Exercise, Physical Activity and Health, School of Human Movement and Nutrition Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Acharya</LastName><ForeName>Shamasunder</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia; John Hunter Hospital, New Lambton, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lewthwaite</LastName><ForeName>Hayley</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Treatable Traits Centre for Research Excellence, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia; Asthma and Breathing Research Program, Hunter Medical Research Institute, New Lambton, New South Wales, Australia; School of Nursing and Midwifery, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>Can J Diabetes</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101148810</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1499-2671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glyc&#xe9;mie</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood glucose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body weight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetes mellitus type 2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diab&#xe8;te sucr&#xe9; de type 2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercice physique</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">poids corporel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postacute COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">syndrome post-COVID-19</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39159783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcjd.2024.08.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1499-2671(24)00147-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>