<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37881468</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2633-4402</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NIHR open research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>NIHR Open Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of an online intervention for the Rehabilitation Exercise and psycholoGical support After covid-19 InfectioN (REGAIN) trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>10</StartPage><MedlinePgn>10</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3310/nihropenres.13371.2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Up to half of people hospitalised with COVID-19 report diverse and persistent symptoms affecting quality of life for months and sometimes years after discharge (long-COVID). We describe the development of an online group exercise and behavioural support intervention for people who continue to experience such physical and/or emotional health problems more than three months after hospital discharge.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Intervention development was informed by the Medical Research Council framework for complex interventions. Our multidisciplinary team of academics, clinicians, and people with long-COVID, had collective expertise in the development and testing of complex interventions. We integrated a bio-psycho-social model of care drawing on rehabilitation literature for long-term health conditions and experiences from our pre-pilot study. Multiple stakeholder meetings were held to refine the intervention which was designed to be deliverable within the UK National Health Service. We adhere to TIDieR guidance for transparent and explicit reporting of telehealth interventions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The final REGAIN online exercise and behavioural support intervention consisted of an initial 1:1 consultation with a trained practitioner, followed by eight online group exercise, and six group support, sessions delivered over eight weeks. Participants could also access an online library of on-demand exercise and support videos.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The final REGAIN intervention, combining exercise and behavioural support, is fully manualised with clear pathways to delivery and implementation. It is currently being tested in a randomised controlled trial. The intervention, developed with extensive patient and stakeholder engagement, could be incorporated into existing NHS rehabilitation programmes, should it prove to be clinically and cost-effective for people with long-COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">International Standard Randomised Controlled Trial Number (ISRCTN) 11466448: Rehabilitation exercise and psychological support after COVID-19 infection: REGAIN.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2023 Ennis S et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ennis</LastName><ForeName>Stuart</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Trials Unit, University of Warwick, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiopulmonary Rehabilitation, University Hospitals Coventry &amp; Warwickshire NHS Trust, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heine</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Trials Unit, University of Warwick, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiopulmonary Rehabilitation, University Hospitals Coventry &amp; Warwickshire NHS Trust, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sandhu</LastName><ForeName>Harbinder</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Trials Unit, University of Warwick, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheehan</LastName><ForeName>Bart</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Oxford Psychological Medicine Centre, Oxford University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yeung</LastName><ForeName>Joyce</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2950-4758</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Trials Unit, University of Warwick, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McWilliams</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9086-2557</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Care Excellence, Coventry University, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Christina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICUsteps Peer Support Charity, ICUsteps Peer Support Charity, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abraham</LastName><ForeName>Charles</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, Deakin University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Underwood</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Trials Unit, University of Warwick, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bruce</LastName><ForeName>Julie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8462-7999</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Trials Unit, University of Warwick, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seers</LastName><ForeName>Kate</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7921-552X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Sciences, University of Warwick, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGregor</LastName><ForeName>Gordon</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8963-9107</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Trials Unit, University of Warwick, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiopulmonary Rehabilitation, University Hospitals Coventry &amp; Warwickshire NHS Trust, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Sport, Exercise and Life Sciences, Coventry University, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>Dryad</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>10.5061/dryad.n8pk0p30r</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>NIHR Open Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918333281906676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2633-4402</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Long-COVID has many debilitating symptoms, such as breathlessness, muscle weakness and fatigue, which significantly affect peoples&#x2019; physical and mental health and quality of life. Rehabilitation programmes can help people improve their quality of life in other medical conditions with similar symptoms. We developed a programme of physical and mental health rehabilitation, delivered online, specifically to support people with ongoing long-COVID symptoms more than three months after hospital discharge. The programme was developed by people with long-COVID along with clinicians and researchers. The programme described in this article is now being tested in a large research trial to see if it can help people with long-COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2023 Ennis S et al.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intervention development</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">online support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: JB, MU, GM, HS, BS, JY, DW are chief or co-investigators on multiple research grants funded by NIHR and other funding bodies. KS previously sat on the NIHR HS&amp;RD funding board for 8 years. SE and GM are directors of Atrium Health Ltd, a provider of rehabilitation services for the National Health Service. HS is director of Health Psychology Services Ltd, providing psychological services for a range of health-related conditions. MU is chief investigator or co-investigator grants from Arthritis Research UK and is a co-investigator on grants funded by the Australian NHMRC and Norwegian MRC. He was an NIHR Senior Investigator until March 2021. He has received travel expenses for speaking at conferences from the professional organisations hosting the conferences. He is a director and shareholder of Clinvivo Ltd that provides electronic data collection for health services research. He is part of an academic partnership with Serco Ltd, funded by the European Social Fund, related to return to work initiatives. MU and JB receive some salary support from University Hospitals Coventry and Warwickshire NHS Trust. MU is a co-investigator on two current and one completed NIHR funded studies that are, of have had, additional support from Stryker Ltd. Until March 2020 he was an editor of the NIHR journal series, and a member of the NIHR Journal Editors Group, for which he received a fee. JB is a co-investigator on one NIHR funded study that receives support from Stryker Ltd.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37881468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10593321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3310/nihropenres.13371.2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>
Office for National Statistics:
Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK 5.
2023.
Reference Source
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins V, Sohaei D, Diamandis EP, et al. : COVID-19: from an acute to chronic disease? Potential long-term health consequences. Crit Rev Clin Lab Sci. 2021;58(5):297&#x2013;310. 10.1080/10408363.2020.1860895</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408363.2020.1860895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33347790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladds E, Rushforth A, Wieringa S, et al. : Persistent symptoms after Covid-19: qualitative study of 114 "long Covid" patients and draft quality principles for services. BMC Health Serv Res. 2020;20(1): 1144. 10.1186/s12913-020-06001-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-020-06001-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7750006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33342437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahase E: Covid-19: What do we know about "long covid"? BMJ. 2020;370: m2815. 10.1136/bmj.m2815</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m2815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32665317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, McAuley H, Harrison EM, et al. : Physical, cognitive, and mental health impacts of COVID-19 after hospitalisation (PHOSP-COVID): a UK multicentre, prospective cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9(11):1275&#x2013;1287. 10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00383-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00383-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34627560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
NIHR:
Themed Review: Living with Covid19 - Second review.NIHR;2021.
Reference Source
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) SIGNS, Royal College of General Practitioners (RCGP): COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
NHS England:
Your COVID Recovery.
Reference Source
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fugazzaro S, Contri A, Esseroukh O, et al. : Rehabilitation Interventions for Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome: A Systematic Review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(9): 5185. 10.3390/ijerph19095185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19095185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9104923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35564579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy B, Casey D, Devane D, et al. : Pulmonary rehabilitation for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;2015(2): CD003793. 10.1002/14651858.CD003793.pub3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD003793.pub3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10008021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25705944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau HMC, Ng GYF, Jones AYM, et al. : A randomised controlled trial of the effectiveness of an exercise training program in patients recovering from severe acute respiratory syndrome. Aust J Physiother. 2005;51(4):213&#x2013;9. 10.1016/s0004-9514(05)70002-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0004-9514(05)70002-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7130114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16321128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGregor G, Sandhu H, Bruce J, et al. : Rehabilitation Exercise and psycholoGical support After covid-19 InfectioN' (REGAIN): a structured summary of a study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials. 2021;22(1):8. 10.1186/s13063-020-04978-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-020-04978-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7785779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33407804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skivington K, Matthews L, Simpson SA, et al. : A new framework for developing and evaluating complex interventions: update of Medical Research Council guidance. BMJ. 2021;374: n2061. 10.1136/bmj.n2061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n2061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34593508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhon DI, Fritz JM, Kerns RD, et al. : TIDieR-telehealth: precision in reporting of telehealth interventions used in clinical trials - unique considerations for the Template for the Intervention Description and Replication (TIDieR) checklist. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2022;22(1):161. 10.1186/s12874-022-01640-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-022-01640-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9161193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35655144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Zhang W, Yang Y, et al. : Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: A randomized controlled study. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2020;39: 101166. 10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101166</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larun L, Brurberg KG, Odgaard-Jensen J, et al. : Exercise therapy for chronic fatigue syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;4(4): CD003200. 10.1002/14651858.CD003200.pub7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD003200.pub7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6419524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28444695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngai JC, Ko FW, Ng SS, et al. : The long-term impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome on pulmonary function, exercise capacity and health status. Respirology. 2010;15(3):543&#x2013;50. 10.1111/j.1440-1843.2010.01720.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1843.2010.01720.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7192220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20337995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stussman B, Williams A, Snow J, et al. : Characterization of Post-exertional Malaise in Patients With Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Front Neurol. 2020;11: 1025. 10.3389/fneur.2020.01025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2020.01025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7530890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33071931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kop WJ: Biopsychosocial Processes of Health and Disease During the COVID-19 Pandemic. Psychosom Med. 2021;83(4):304&#x2013;308. 10.1097/PSY.0000000000000954</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PSY.0000000000000954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33938503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakrawarty A, Ranjan P, Klanidhi KB, et al. : Psycho-social and behavioral impact of COVID-19 on middle-aged and elderly individuals: A qualitative study. J Educ Health Promot. 2021;10:269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8395993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34485566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, van Stralen MM, West R: The behaviour change wheel: a new method for characterising and designing behaviour change interventions. Implement Sci. 2011;6:42. 10.1186/1748-5908-6-42</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-6-42</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21513547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A: Self-efficacy: toward a unifying theory of behavioral change. Psychol Rev. 1977;84(2):191&#x2013;215. 10.1037//0033-295x.84.2.191</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037//0033-295x.84.2.191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">847061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copeland L, McNamara R, Kelson M, et al. : Mechanisms of change within motivational interviewing in relation to health behaviors outcomes: A systematic review. Patient Educ Couns. 2015;98(4):401&#x2013;11. 10.1016/j.pec.2014.11.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pec.2014.11.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25535015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borek AJ, Abraham C: How do Small Groups Promote Behaviour Change? An Integrative Conceptual Review of Explanatory Mechanisms. Appl Psychol Health Well Being. 2018;10(1):30&#x2013;61. 10.1111/aphw.12120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aphw.12120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29446250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Psychological Society: Guidance for the public on the mental health and wellbeing aspects of coronavirus (COVID-19).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGregor G: REGAIN trial intervention development process evaluation data. Dryad. [Dataset],2023. 10.5061/dryad.n8pk0p30r</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5061/dryad.n8pk0p30r</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>