<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37351054</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2008-7802</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of preventive medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Prev Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-COVID-19 Syndrome Mechanisms, Prevention and Management.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>59</StartPage><MedlinePgn>59</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">59</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/ijpvm.ijpvm_508_21</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As the population of patients recovering from COVID-19 grows, post COVID-19 challenges are recognizing by ongoing evidences at once. Long COVID is defined as a syndrome with a range of persistent symptoms that remain long after (beyond 12 weeks) the acute SARS-CoV-2 infection. Studies have shown that long COVID can cause multi-organ damages with a wide spectrum of manifestations. Many systems, but not limited to, including respiratory, cardiovascular, nervous, gastrointestinal, and musculoskeletal systems, are involved in long COVID. Fatigue and dyspnea are the most common symptoms of long COVID. Long COVID-19 may be driven by tissue damage caused by virus-specific pathophysiologic changes or secondary to pathological long-lasting inflammatory response because of viral persistence, immune dysregulation, and autoimmune reactions. Some risk factors like sex and age, more than five early symptoms, and specific biomarkers have been revealed as a probable long COVID predicator discussed in this review. It seems that vaccination is the only way for prevention of long COVID and it can also help patients who had already long COVID. Managing long COVID survivors recommended being in a multidisciplinary approach, and a framework for identifying those at high risk for post-acute COVID-19 must be proposed. Possible therapeutic options and useful investigation tools for follow-up are suggested in this review. In sum, as evidence and researches are regularly updated, we provide the current understanding of the epidemiology, clinical manifestation, suspected pathophysiology, associated risk factors, and treatment options of long COVID in this review.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2023 International Journal of Preventive Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Najafi</LastName><ForeName>Majed B</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology Research Center, Isfahan Cardiovascular Research Institute, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Javanmard</LastName><ForeName>Shaghayegh H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology Research Center, Isfahan Cardiovascular Research Institute, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Prev Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101535380</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2008-7802</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic COVID syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long haul COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long hauler COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute COVID syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37351054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijpvm.ijpvm_508_21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJPVM-14-59</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baud D, Qi X, Nielsen-Saines K, Musso D, Pomar L, Favre G. Real estimates of mortality following COVID-19 infection. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20:773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32171390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oronsky B, Larson C, Hammond TC, Oronsky A, Kesari S, Lybeck M, et al. A review of persistent post-COVID syndrome (PPCS) Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2021:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1007/s12016.021.08848.3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33609255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg M, Maralakunte M, Garg S, Dhooria S, Sehgal I, Bhalla AS, et al. The conundrum of &#x2018;long-COVID-19&#x2032;: A narrative review. Int J Gen Med. 2021;14:2491&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8214209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll E, Neumann H, Aguero-Rosenfeld ME, Lighter J, Czeisler BM, Melmed K, et al. Post&#x2013;COVID-19 inflammatory syndrome manifesting as refractory status epilepticus. Epilepsia. 2020;61:e135&#x2013;e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32944946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, Rose EB, Shapiro NI, Files DC, et al. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network&#x2014;United States, March&#x2013;June 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly. 2020;69:993&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: A cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, Buxton M, Husain L. Management of post-acute COVID-19 in primary care? BMJ. 2020;370:m3026. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi N. Long COVID: How to define it and how to manage it. BMJ. 2020;370:m3489. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m3489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32895219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg P, Arora U, Kumar A, Wig N. The &#x201c;post-COVID&#x201d; syndrome: How deep is the damage? J Med Virol. 2021;93:673&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32852801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, Hishmeh L. Managing the long term effects of COVID-19: Summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline? BMJ. 2021;372:n136. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, et al.  More than 50 Long-term effects of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. SSRN J. 2021.  Available from: https://ssrn.com/abstract=3769978. 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Shin H-S, Park HY, Kim JL, Lee JJ, Lee H, et al. Depression as a mediator of chronic fatigue and post-traumatic stress symptoms in Middle East respiratory syndrome survivors. Psychiatry investig. 2019;16:59&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6354037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30605995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam MH-B, Wing Y-K, Yu MW-M, Leung C-M, Ma RC, Kong AP, et al. Mental morbidities and chronic fatigue in severe acute respiratory syndrome survivors: Long-term follow-up. Arch Intern Med. 2009;169:2142&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20008700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cellai M, O&#x2019;Keefe JB, editors. Open Forum Infectious Diseases. Oxford University Press US; 2020. Characterization of prolonged COVID-19 symptoms in an outpatient telemedicine clinic.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33117851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27:626&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirulli E, Barrett KMS, Riffle S, Bolze A, Neveux I, Dabe S, et al. Long-term COVID-19 symptoms in a large unselected population? medrxiv. 2020 doi: 10.1101/2020.10.07.20208702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bliddal S, Banasik K, Pedersen OB, Nissen J, Cantwell L, Schwinn M, et al. Acute and persistent symptoms in non-hospitalized PCR-confirmed COVID-19 patients? Sci Rep. 2021;11:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-92045-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8222239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34162913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havervall S, Rosell A, Phillipson M, Mangsbo SM, Nilsson P, Hober S, et al. Symptoms and functional impairment assessed 8 months after mild COVID-19 among health care workers. JAMA. 2021;325:2015&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8027932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33825846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehme M, Braillard O, Alcoba G, Aebischer Perone S, Courvoisier D, Chappuis F, et al. COVID-19 symptoms: Longitudinal evolution and persistence in outpatient settings. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174:723&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7741180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33284676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez O, Merino E, Leon-Ramirez J-M, Andres M, Ramos JM, Arenas-Jim&#xe9;nez J, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome.Incidence and risk factors: A Mediterranean cohort study. J Infect. 2021;82:378&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7802523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venturelli S, Benatti SV, Casati M, Binda F, Zuglian G, Imeri G, et al. Surviving COVID-19 in Bergamo province: A post-acute outpatient re-evaluation? Epidemiol Infect. 2021;149:e32. doi: 10.1017/S0950268821000145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiesa-Estomba CM, Lechien JR, Radulesco T, Michel J, Sowerby LJ, Hopkins C, et al. Patterns of smell recovery in 751 patients affected by the COVID-19 outbreak. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27:2318&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7405216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32677329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D. Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK: 1 April 2021. Off Natl Stat. 2021:1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin L, Savale L, Pham T, Colle R, Figueiredo S, Harrois A, et al. Four-month clinical status of a cohort of patients after hospitalization for COVID-19. JAMA. 2021;325:1525&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7970386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33729425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosn J, Piroth L, Epaulard O, Le Turnier P, Mentr&#xe9; F, Bachelet D, et al. Persistent COVID-19 symptoms are highly prevalent 6 months after hospitalization: Results from a large prospective cohort. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021:1041.e1&#x2013;1041.e4. doi: 10.1016/j.cmi. 2021.03.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8107834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34125067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin M, Schommers P, Stecher M, Dewald F, Gieselmann L, Gruell H, et al. Post-COVID syndrome in non-hospitalised patients with COVID-19: A longitudinal prospective cohort study? Lancet Reg Health Eur. 2021;6:100122. doi: 10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8129613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34027514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitaker M, Elliott J, Chadeau-Hyam M, Riley S, Darzi A, Cooke G, et al. Persistent symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection in a random community sample of 508,707 people. medRxiv. 2021 doi: 10.1101/2021.06.28.21259452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson EJ, Williams DM, Walker AJ, Mitchell RE, Niedzwiedz CL, Yang TC, et al. Risk factors for long COVID: Analyses of 10 longitudinal studies and electronic health records in the UK? medRxiv. 2021 doi: 10.1101/2021.06.24.21259277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue S, Hatakeyama J, Kondo Y, Hifumi T, Sakuramoto H, Kawasaki T, et al. Post-intensive care syndrome: Its pathophysiology, prevention, and future directions. Acute Med Surg. 2019;6:233&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6603316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31304024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrenfeld M, Tincani A, Andreoli L, Cattalini M, Greenbaum A, Kanduc D, et al. COVID-19 and autoimmunity? Autoimmun Rev. 2020;19:102597. doi: 10.1016/j.autrev. 2020.102597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7289100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32535093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye G, Pan Z, Pan Y, Deng Q, Chen L, Li J, et al. Clinical characteristics of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 reactivation. J Infect. 2020;80:e14&#x2013;e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32171867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Diseases Control and Prevention. Investigative criteria for suspected cases of SARS-CoV-2 reinfection (ICR) 2020.  Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/php/invest-criteria.html. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stratton CW, Tang YW, Lu H. Pathogenesis-directed therapy of 2019 novel coronavirus disease. J Med Virol. 2021;93:1320&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33073355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni W, Yang X, Yang D, Bao J, Li R, Xiao Y, et al. Role of angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) in COVID-19? Crit Care. 2020;24:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1186/s13054.020.03120.0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7356137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32660650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afrin LB, Weinstock LB, Molderings GJ. COVID-19 hyperinflammation and post-COVID-19 illness may be rooted in mast cell activation syndrome. Int J Infect Dis. 2020;100:327&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7529115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32920235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Cheng V, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, Dagens D, Hastie C, et al. Characterising long term COVID-19: A living systematic review. MedRxiv. 2021 doi: 10.1101/2020.12.08.20246025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, Rivera SC, McMullan C, Chandan JS, et al. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: A review. J R Soc Med. 2021;114:428&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardo MDM, Foppiani A, Peretti GM, Mangiavini L, Battezzati A, Bertoli S, et al. Long-term coronavirus disease 2019 complications in inpatients and outpatients: A one-year follow-up cohort study? Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8:ofab384. doi: 10.1093/ofid/ofab384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8344801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34386546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngai JC, Ko FW, Ng SS, TO KW, Tong M, Hui DS. The long-term impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome on pulmonary function, exercise capacity and health status. Respirology. 2010;15:543&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7192220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20337995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re&#x2019;em Y, et al.  Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. SSRN J. 2021.  Available from: https://ssrn.com/abstract=3820561. 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simani L, Ramezani M, Darazam IA, Sagharichi M, Aalipour MA, Ghorbani F, et al. Prevalence and correlates of chronic fatigue syndrome and post-traumatic stress disorder after the outbreak of the COVID-19. J Neurovirol. 2021;27:154&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7852482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33528827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg M, Prabhakar N, Bhalla AS, Irodi A, Sehgal I, Debi U, et al. Computed tomography chest in COVID-19: When &amp; why? Indian J Med Res. 2021;153:86&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8184074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33402610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Froidure A, Mahsouli A, Liistro G, De Greef J, Belkhir L, Gerard L, et al. Integrative respiratory follow-up of severe COVID-19 reveals common functional and lung imaging sequelae? Respir Med. 2021;181:106383. doi: 10.1016/j.rmed.2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8019490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33839588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues E, Janvier P, Kherabi Y, Le Bot A, Hamon A, Gouze H, et al. Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. J Infect. 2020;81:e4&#x2013;e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Q, Xu M, Li J, Liu Y, Zhang J, Xu Y, et al. Clinical sequelae of COVID-19 survivors in Wuhan, China: A single-centre longitudinal study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:89&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7510771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32979574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frija-Masson J, Debray MP, Gilbert M, Lescure FX, Travert F, Borie R, et al. Functional characteristics of patients with SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia at 30 days post-infection? Eur Respir J. 2020;56:2001754. doi: 10.1183/13993003.01754-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32554533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra V, Flanders SA, O&#x2019;Malley M, Malani AN, Prescott HC. Sixty-day outcomes among patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174:576&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7707210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93:1013&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund LC, Hallas J, Nielsen H, Koch A, Mogensen SH, Brun NC, et al. Post-acute effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection in individuals not requiring hospital admission: A Danish population-based cohort study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21:1373&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8110209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33984263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darcis G, Bouquegneau A, Maes N, Thys M, Henket M, Labye F, et al. Long-term clinical follow-up of patients suffering from moderate-to-severe COVID-19 infection: A monocentric prospective observational cohort study. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;109:209&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8278829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Fan Y, Alwalid O, Li N, Jia X, Yuan M, et al. Six-month follow-up chest CT findings after severe COVID-19 pneumonia. Radiology. 2021;299:E177&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7841877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnweber T, Sahanic S, Pizzini A, Luger A, Schwabl C, Sonnweber B, et al. Cardiopulmonary recovery after COVID-19: An observational prospective multicentre trial? Eur Respir J. 2021;57:2003481. doi: 10.1183/13993003.03481.2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alharthy A, Abuhamdah M, Balhamar A, Faqihi F, Nasim N, Ahmad S, et al. Residual lung injury in patients recovering from COVID-19 critical illness: A prospective longitudinal point-of-care lung ultrasound study. J Ultrasound Med. 2021;40:1823&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33185316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao YM, Shang YM, Song WB, Li QQ, Xie H, Xu QF, et al. Follow-up study of the pulmonary function and related physiological characteristics of COVID-19 survivors three months after recovery? EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100463. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabatabaei SMH, Rajebi H, Moghaddas F, Ghasemiadl M, Talari H. Chest CT in COVID-19 pneumonia: What are the findings in mid-term follow-up? Emerg Radiol. 2020;27:711&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7649573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33165674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo X, Jian W, Su Z, Chen M, Peng H, Peng P, et al. Abnormal pulmonary function in COVID-19 patients at time of hospital discharge? Eur Respir J. 2020;55:2001217. doi: 10.1183/13993003.01217-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32381497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huppert LA, Matthay MA, Ware LB, editors. Thieme Medical Publishers; 2019. Pathogenesis of acute respiratory distress syndrome. Seminars in Respiratory and Critical Ccare Medicine.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7060969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31060086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidarta-Oliveira D, Jara CP, Ferruzzi AJ, Skaf MS, Velander WH, Araujo EP, et al. SARS-CoV-2 receptor is co-expressed with elements of the kinin&#x2013;kallikrein, renin&#x2013;angiotensin and coagulation systems in alveolar cells? Sci Rep. 2020;10:1&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-76488-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7658217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33177594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carsana L, Sonzogni A, Nasr A, Rossi RS, Pellegrinelli A, Zerbi P, et al. Pulmonary post-mortem findings in a series of COVID-19 cases from northern Italy: A two-centre descriptive study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20:1135&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7279758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32526193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaller T, Hirschb&#xfc;hl K, Burkhardt K, Braun G, Trepel M, M&#xe4;rkl B, et al. Postmortem examination of patients with COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;323:2518&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Michele S, Sun Y, Yilmaz MM, Katsyv I, Salvatore M, Dzierba AL, et al. Forty postmortem examinations in COVID-19 patients: Two distinct pathologic phenotypes and correlation with clinical and radiologic findings. Am J Clin Pathol. 2020;154:748&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7499554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32876680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Wu D, Guo W, Cao Y, Huang D, Wang H, et al. Clinical and immunological features of severe and moderate coronavirus disease 2019. J Clin Invest. 2020;130:2620&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7190990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharat A, Querrey M, Markov NS, Kim S, Kurihara C, Garza-Castillon R, et al. Lung transplantation for patients with severe COVID-19. Sci Transl Med. 2020:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8050952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramadan MS, Bertolino L, Zampino R, Durante-Mangoni E Monaldi Hospital Cardiovascular Infection Study Group. Cardiac sequelae after coronavirus disease 2019 recovery: A systematic review. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:1250&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8220864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34171458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulson N, Petek BJ, Drezner JA, Harmon KG, Kliethermes SA, Patel MR, et al. SARS-CoV-2 cardiac involvement in young competitive athletes. Circulation. 2021;144:256&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8300154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33866822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson M, St&#xe5;hlberg M, Runold M, Nygren-Bonnier M, Nilsson J, Olshansky B, et al. Long-haul post&#x2013;COVID-19 symptoms presenting as a variant of postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome: The Swedish experience. JACC Case Rep. 2021;3:573&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7946344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33723532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miglis MG, Prieto T, Shaik R, Muppidi S, Sinn D-I, Jaradeh S. A case report of postural tachycardia syndrome after COVID-19. Clin Auton Res. 2020;30:449&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7471493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32880754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe5;hlberg M, Reistam U, Fedorowski A, Villacorta H, Horiuchi Y, Bax J, et al. Post-COVID-19 Tachycardia syndrome: A distinct phenotype of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Am J Med. 2021;134:1451&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8356730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34390682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez MW, Tucker AM, Bloom OJ, Green G, DiFiori JP, Solomon G, et al. Prevalence of inflammatory heart disease among professional athletes with prior COVID-19 infection who received systematic return-to-play cardiac screening. JAMA Cardiol. 2021;6:745&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7934073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33662103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotecha T, Knight DS, Razvi Y, Kumar K, Vimalesvaran K, Thornton G, et al. Patterns of myocardial injury in recovered troponin-positive COVID-19 patients assessed by cardiovascular magnetic resonance. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:1866&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7928984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33596594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594:259&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Khunti K, Nafilyan V, Maddox T, Humberstone B, Diamond I, et al. Post-COVID syndrome in individuals admitted to hospital with COVID-19: Retrospective cohort study? BMJ. 2021;372:n693. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8010267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindner D, Fitzek A, Br&#xe4;uninger H, Aleshcheva G, Edler C, Meissner K, et al. Association of cardiac infection with SARS-CoV-2 in confirmed COVID-19 autopsy cases. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:1281&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siripanthong B, Nazarian S, Muser D, Deo R, Santangeli P, Khanji MY, et al. Recognizing COVID-19&#x2013;related myocarditis: The possible pathophysiology and proposed guideline for diagnosis and management. Heart Rhythm. 2020;17:1463&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7199677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Zhou L, Sun X, Yan Z, Hu C, Wu J, et al. Altered lipid metabolism in recovered SARS patients twelve years after infection. Sci Rep. 2017;7:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-09536-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5567209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28831119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazzerini PE, Laghi-Pasini F, Boutjdir M, Capecchi PL. Cardioimmunology of arrhythmias: The role of autoimmune and inflammatory cardiac channelopathies. Nat Rev Immunol. 2019;19:63&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30552387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts LN, Whyte MB, Georgiou L, Giron G, Czuprynska J, Rea C, et al. Postdischarge venous thromboembolism following hospital admission with COVID-19. Blood. 2020;136:1347&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32746455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patell R, Bogue T, Koshy A, Bindal P, Merrill M, Aird WC, et al. Postdischarge thrombosis and hemorrhage in patients with COVID-19. Blood. 2020;136:1342&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32766883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salisbury R, Iotchkova V, Jaafar S, Morton J, Sangha G, Shah A, et al. Incidence of symptomatic, image-confirmed venous thromboembolism following hospitalization for COVID-19 with 90-day follow-up. Blood Adv. 2020;4:6230&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7757009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33351117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannis D, Allen SL, Tsang J, Flint S, Pinhasov T, Williams S, et al. Postdischarge thromboembolic outcomes and mortality of hospitalized patients with COVID-19: The CORE-19 registry. Blood. 2021;137:2838&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8032474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33824972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolai L, Leunig A, Brambs S, Kaiser R, Weinberger T, Weigand M, et al. Immunothrombotic dysregulation in COVID-19 pneumonia is associated with respiratory failure and coagulopathy. Circulation. 2020;142:1176&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7497892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32755393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pons S, Fodil S, Azoulay E, Zafrani L. The vascular endothelium: The cornerstone of organ dysfunction in severe SARS-CoV-2 infection? Crit Care. 2020;24:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1186/s13054-020-03062-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7296907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32546188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghebrehiwet B, Peerschke EI. Complement and coagulation: Key triggers of COVID-19&#x2013;induced multiorgan pathology. J Clin Invest. 2020;130:5674&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7598033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32925166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hottz ED, Azevedo-Quintanilha IG, Palhinha L, Teixeira L, Barreto EA, P&#xe3;o CR, et al. Platelet activation and platelet-monocyte aggregate formation trigger tissue factor expression in patients with severe COVID-19. Blood. 2020;136:1330&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32678428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szturmowicz M, Demkow U. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) in severe SARS-CoV-2 lung disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:8854. doi: 10.3390/ijms22168854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8396177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34445556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song W-C, FitzGerald GA. COVID-19, microangiopathy, hemostatic activation, and complement. J Clin Invest. 2020;130:3950&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7410042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32459663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Xu E, Al-Aly Z. Kidney outcomes in long COVID. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;32:2851&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8806085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34470828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins-Juarez SY, Qian L, King KL, Stevens JS, Husain SA, Radhakrishnan J, et al. Outcomes for patients with COVID-19 and acute kidney injury: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Kidney Int Rep. 2020;5:1149&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7314696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32775814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings MJ, Baldwin MR, Abrams D, Jacobson SD, Meyer BJ, Balough EM, et al. Epidemiology, clinical course, and outcomes of critically ill adults with COVID-19 in New York City: A prospective cohort study. Lancet. 2020;395:1763&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7237188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens JS, King KL, Robbins-Juarez SY, Khairallah P, Toma K, Alvarado Verduzco H, et al. High rate of renal recovery in survivors of COVID-19 associated acute renal failure requiring renal replacement therapy. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0244131. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone. 0244131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7769434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33370368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch JS, Ng JH, Ross DW, Sharma P, Shah HH, Barnett RL, et al. Acute kidney injury in patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Kidney Int. 2020;98:209&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7229463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32416116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei G, Zhang Z, Peng J, Liu L, Zhang C, Yu C, et al. Renal involvement and early prognosis in patients with COVID-19 pneumonia. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020;31:1157&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7269350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32345702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stockmann H, Hardenberg J-HB, Aigner A, Hinze C, Gotthardt I, Stier B, et al. High rates of long-term renal recovery in survivors of coronavirus disease 2019&#x2013;associated acute kidney injury requiring kidney replacement therapy. Kidney Int. 2021;99:1021&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7839389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33515574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su H, Yang M, Wan C, Yi L-X, Tang F, Zhu H-Y, et al. Renal histopathological analysis of 26 postmortem findings of patients with COVID-19 in China. Kidney Int. 2020;98:219&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32327202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kudose S, Batal I, Santoriello D, Xu K, Barasch J, Peleg Y, et al. Kidney biopsy findings in patients with COVID-19. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020;31:1959&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32680910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma P, Uppal NN, Wanchoo R, Shah HH, Yang Y, Parikh R, et al. COVID-19&#x2013;associated kidney injury: A case series of kidney biopsy findings. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020;31:1948&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32660970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golmai P, Larsen CP, DeVita MV, Wahl SJ, Weins A, Rennke HG, et al. Histopathologic and ultrastructural findings in postmortem kidney biopsy material in 12 patients with AKI and COVID-19. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020;31:1944&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32675304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santoriello D, Khairallah P, Bomback AS, Xu K, Kudose S, Batal I, et al. Postmortem kidney pathology findings in patients with COVID-19. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020;31:2158&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32727719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velez JCQ, Caza T, Larsen CP. COVAN is the new HIVAN: The re-emergence of collapsing glomerulopathy with COVID-19. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2020;16:565&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7400750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peleg Y, Kudose S, D&#x2019;Agati V, Siddall E, Ahmad S, Nickolas T, et al. Acute kidney injury due to collapsing glomerulopathy following COVID-19 infection. Kidney Int Rep. 2020;5:940&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7186120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32346659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jhaveri KD, Meir LR, Chang BSF, Parikh R, Wanchoo R, Barilla-LaBarca ML, et al. Thrombotic microangiopathy in a patient with COVID-19. Kidney Int. 2020;98:509&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7276225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32525010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathish T, Cao Y, Kapoor N. Newly diagnosed diabetes in COVID-19 patients. Prim Care Diabetes. 2020;15:194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7451214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32900656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akter F, Mannan A, Mehedi HH, Rob MA, Ahmed S, Salauddin A, et al. Clinical characteristics and short term outcomes after recovery from COVID-19 in patients with and without diabetes in Bangladesh. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2020;14:2031&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33113469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal M, Abo Omirah M, Hussein A, Saeed H. Assessment and characterisation of post-COVID-19 manifestations? Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:e13746. doi: 10.1111/ijcp. 13746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh A, Anjana RM, Rani CSS, Rani SJ, Gupta R, Jha A, et al. Glycemic parameters in patients with new-onset diabetes during COVID-19 pandemic are more severe than in patients with new-onset diabetes before the pandemic: NOD COVID India Study. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15:215&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7771314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan K, Gong Y-M, Liu L, Sun Y-K, Tian S-S, Wang Y-J, et al. Prevalence of posttraumatic stress disorder after infectious disease pandemics in the twenty- first century, including COVID-19: A meta-analysis and systematic review. Mol Psychiatry. 2021;26:4982&#x2013;4998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7861006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33542468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggeri RM, Campenn&#xec; A, Siracusa M, Frazzetto G, Gullo D. Subacute thyroiditis in a patient infected with SARS-COV-2: An endocrine complication linked to the COVID-19 pandemic. Hormones. 2021;20:219&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7365600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32676935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brancatella A, Ricci D, Viola N, Sgr&#xf2; D, Santini F, Latrofa F. Subacute thyroiditis after Sars-COV-2 infection. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2020;105:2367&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7314004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32436948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Perez O, Merino E, Alfayate R, Torregrosa ME, Andres M, Leon-Ramirez JM, et al. Male pituitary-gonadal axis dysfunction in post-acute COVID-19 syndrome.Prevalence and associated factors: A Mediterranean case series. Clin Endocrinol. 2021 doi: 10.1111/cen.14537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34160836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mondal S, DasGupta R, Lodh M, Gorai R, Choudhury B, Hazra AK, et al. Predictors of new-onset diabetic ketoacidosis in patients with moderate to severe COVID-19 receiving parenteral glucocorticoids: A prospective single-centre study among Indian type 2 diabetes patients. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15:795&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8004476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33839639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentile S, Strollo F, Mambro A, Ceriello A. COVID-19, ketoacidosis and new-onset diabetes: Are there possible cause and effect relationships among them? Diabetes Obes Metab. 2020;22:2507&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7436911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J-K, Lin S-S, Ji X-J, Guo L-M. Binding of SARS coronavirus to its receptor damages islets and causes acute diabetes. Acta Diabetol. 2010;47:193&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7088164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19333547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farag AA, Hassanin HM, Soliman HH, Sallam A, Sediq AM, Elbanna K. Newly diagnosed diabetes in patients with COVID-19: Different types and short-term outcomes? Trop Med Infect Dis. 2021;6:142. doi: 10.3390/tropicalmed6030142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8396224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34449740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM. Deleterious outcomes in long-hauler COVID-19: The effects of SARS-CoV-2 on the CNS in chronic COVID syndrome. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2020;11:4017&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33275404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijeratne T, Crewther S. Post-COVID 19 Neurological Syndrome (PCNS); a novel syndrome with challenges for the global neurology community. J Neurol Sci. 2020:419. doi: 10.1016/j.jns. 2020.117179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7550857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33070003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boscolo-Rizzo P, Borsetto D, Fabbris C, Spinato G, Frezza D, Menegaldo A, et al. Evolution of altered sense of smell or taste in patients with mildly symptomatic COVID-19. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2020;146:729&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7333173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32614442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li X, Geng D, Mei N, Wu P-Y, Huang C-C, et al. Cerebral micro-structural changes in COVID-19 patients&#x2013;an MRI-based 3-month follow-up study. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siow I, Lee KS, Zhang JJ, Saffari SE, Ng A, Young B. Stroke as a neurological complication of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis of incidence, outcomes and predictors? J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;30:105549. doi: 10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis. 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33341565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Fern&#xe1;ndez F, Sandoval Valencia H, Barbella-Aponte RA, Collado-Jim&#xe9;nez R, Ayo-Mart&#xed;n &#xd3;, Barrena C, et al. Cerebrovascular disease in patients with COVID-19: Neuroimaging, histological and clinical description. Brain. 2020;143:3089&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32645151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Harrison PJ. Bidirectional associations between COVID-19 and psychiatric disorder: Retrospective cohort studies of 62 354 COVID-19 cases in the USA. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:130&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Rio C, Collins LF, Malani P. Long-term health consequences of COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:1723&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8019677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, De Lorenzo R, Conte C, Poletti S, Vai B, Bollettini I, et al. Anxiety and depression in COVID-19 survivors: Role of inflammatory and clinical predictors. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;89:594&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7390748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubair AS, McAlpine LS, Gardin T, Farhadian S, Kuruvilla DE, Spudich S. Neuropathogenesis and neurologic manifestations of the coronaviruses in the age of coronavirus disease 2019: A review. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:1018&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7484225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendelson M, Nel J, Blumberg L, Madhi S, Dryden M, Stevens W, et al. Long-COVID: An evolving problem with an extensive impact. S Afr Med J. 2021;111:10&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33403997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Campion J, Dudouet P, Kaphan E, Bregeon F, Tissot-Dupont H, et al. 18 F-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in patients with long COVID. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48:2823&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33501506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: A retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heneka MT, Golenbock D, Latz E, Morgan D, Brown R. Immediate and long-term consequences of COVID-19 infections for the development of neurological disease? Alzheimer's Res Ther. 2020;12:1&#x2013;3. doi: 10.1186/s13195-020-00640-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32498691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muccioli L, Pensato U, Cani I, Guarino M, Cortelli P, Bisulli F. COVID-19-associated encephalopathy and cytokine-mediated neuroinflammation. Ann Neurol. 2020;88:860&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilotto A, Padovani A. Reply to the letter&#x201d; COVID-19-associated encephalopathy and cytokine-mediated neuroinflammation&#x201d;. Ann Neurol. 2020;88:861&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7436670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32737995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>South K, McCulloch L, McColl BW, Elkind MS, Allan SM, Smith CJ. Preceding infection and risk of stroke: An old concept revived by the COVID-19 pandemic. Int J Stroke. 2020;15:722&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32618498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichard RR, Kashani KB, Boire NA, Constantopoulos E, Guo Y, Lucchinetti CF. Neuropathology of COVID-19: A spectrum of vascular and acute disseminated encephalomyelitis (ADEM)-like pathology. Acta Neuropathol. 2020;140:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32449057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameres M, Brandstetter S, Toncheva AA, Kabesch M, Leppert D, Kuhle J, et al. Association of neuronal injury blood marker neurofilament light chain with mild-to-moderate COVID-19. J Neurol. 2020;267:3476&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7345451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32647900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortolato B, F Carvalho A, K Soczynska J, I Perini G, S McIntyre R. The involvement of TNF-&#x3b1; in cognitive dysfunction associated with major depressive disorder: An opportunity for domain specific treatments. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2015;13:558&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4761629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26467407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrin R, Riste L, Hann M, Walther A, Mukherjee A, Heald A. Into the looking glass: Post-viral syndrome post COVID-19? Med Hypotheses. 2020;144:110055. doi: 10.1016/j.mehy. 2020.110055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7320866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32758891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaseda ET, Levine AJ. Post-traumatic stress disorder: A differential diagnostic consideration for COVID-19 survivors. Clin Neuropsychol. 2020;34:1498&#x2013;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32847484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miglis MG, Goodman BP, Chemali KR, Stiles L. Re: &#x2018;Post-COVID-19 chronic symptoms&#x2019; by Davido et al . Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7470728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32891765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Y, Rong L, Nian W, He Y. gastrointestinal features in COVID-19 and the possibility of faecal transmission. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2020;51:843&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7161803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32222988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmulson M, D&#xe1;valos M, Berumen J. Beware: Gastrointestinal symptoms can be a manifestation of COVID-19. Rev Gastroenterol M&#xe9;x (Engl Ed) 2020;85:282&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32376072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizvi A, Patel Z, Liu Y, Satapathy SK, Sultan K, Trindade AJ, et al. Gastrointestinal sequelae 3 and 6 months after hospitalization for coronavirus disease 2019. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021:271&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8245666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34217880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng J, Li Y, Li J, Shen L, Zhu L, Liang Y, et al. Gastrointestinal sequelae 90 days after discharge for COVID-19. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;6:344&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7943402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33711290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Guo C, Tang L, Hong Z, Zhou J, Dong X, et al. Prolonged presence of SARS-CoV-2 viral RNA in faecal samples. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;5:434&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32199469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effenberger M, Grabherr F, Mayr L, Schwaerzler J, Nairz M, Seifert M, et al. Faecal calprotectin indicates intestinal inflammation in COVID-19. Gut. 2020;69:1543&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32312790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang MK, Yue HY, Cai J, Zhai YJ, Peng JH, Hui JF, et al. COVID-19 and the digestive system: A comprehensive review. World J Clin Cases. 2021;9:3796&#x2013;813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8180220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34141737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung KS, Hung IFN, Chan PPY, Lung KC, Tso E, Liu R, et al. Gastrointestinal manifestations of SARS-CoV-2 infection and virus load in fecal samples from a Hong Kong cohort: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Gastroenterology. 2020;159:81&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao F, Tang M, Zheng X, Liu Y, Li X, Shan H. Evidence for Gastrointestinal Infection of SARS-CoV-2. Gastroenterology. 2020;158:1831&#x2013;3.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7130181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donati Zeppa S, Agostini D, Piccoli G, Stocchi V, Sestili P. Gut microbiota status in COVID-19: An unrecognized player?? Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2020;10:576551. doi: 10.3389/fcimb.2020.576551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7725702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33324572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley KC, Finsterbusch K, Schnepf D, Crotta S, Llorian M, Davidson S, et al. Microbiota-driven tonic interferon signals in lung stromal cells protect from influenza virus infection. Cell Rep. 2019;28:245&#x2013;56 e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31269444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon DE, Gallman AE, Hruza GJ, Rosenbach M, Lipoff JB, Desai SR, et al. Long COVID in the skin: A registry analysis of COVID-19 dermatological duration. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21:313&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33460566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tammaro A, Parisella FR, Adebanjo GAR. Cutaneous long COVID. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2021;20:2378&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8447311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34129734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Arrones O, Lobato-Berezo A, Gomez-Zubiaur A, Arias-Santiago S, Saceda-Corralo D, Bernardez-Guerra C, et al. SARS-CoV-2-induced telogen effluvium: A multicentric study. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2021;35:e181&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrantes TF, Artounian KA, Falsey R, Sim&#xe3;o JCL, Va&#xf1;&#xf3;-Galv&#xe1;n S, Ferreira SB, et al. Time of onset and duration of post-COVID-19 acute telogen effluvium. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2021;85:975&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8294706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34302903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, Bunker CB, Ciurtin C, Porter JC, Chambers RC, Papdopoulou C, et al. Chilblain-like acral lesions in long COVID-19: Management and implications for understanding microangiopathy? Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21:912. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00133-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33705725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH, Crooks MG. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: What is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;199:113&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, Dunne J, Mooney A, Gaffney F, et al. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. Plos One. 2020;15:e0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. UK Office for National Statistics. Prevalence of long COVID symptoms and COVID-19 complications.  Available from: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/healthandlifeexpectancies/datasets/prevalenceoflongCOVIDsymptomsandCOVID19complications. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazato Y, Morioka S, Tsuzuki S, Akashi M, Osanai Y, Tanaka K, et al., editors. Oxford University Press US; 2020. Prolonged and late-onset symptoms of coronavirus disease 2019. Open Forum Infectious Diseases.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33230486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B, Peters JB, Brink M, Schoon Y, Bleeker-Rovers CP, Schers H, et al. Comprehensive health assessment 3 months after recovery from acute coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e1089&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poyraz B&#xc7;, Poyraz CA, Olgun Y, G&#xfc;rel &#xd6;, Alkan S, &#xd6;zdemir YE, et al. Psychiatric morbidity and protracted symptoms after COVID-19? Psychiatry Res. 2021;295:113604. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres. 2020.113604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7695976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33296818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, et al. Attributes and predictors of Long-COVID: Analysis of COVID cases and their symptoms collected by the COVID symptoms study app. medRxiv. 2020 doi: 10.1101/2020.10.19.20214494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, Ghanima W, Olsen MK, Gilboe HM, Einvik G. Persistent symptoms 1.5&#x2013;6 months after COVID-19 in non-hospitalised subjects: A population-based cohort study. Thorax. 2021;76:405&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taboada M, Cari&#xf1;ena A, Moreno E, Rodr&#xed;guez N, Dom&#xed;nguez MJ, Casal A, et al. Post-COVID-19 functional status six-months after hospitalization. J Infect. 2021;82:e31&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33373650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Cassar MP, Tunnicliffe EM, Filippini N, Griffanti L, Alfaro-Almagro F, et al. Medium-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on multiple vital organs, exercise capacity, cognition, quality of life and mental health, post-hospital discharge? EClinicalMedicine. 2021;31:100683. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33490928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewitt J, Carter B, Vilches-Moraga A, Quinn T, Braude P, Verduri A. Th e effect of frailty on survival in patients with COVID-19 (COPE): A multicentre, European, observational cohort study. Lancet Public Health. 2020;5:e444&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7326416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32619408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, Brown JS, Denneny EK, Hare SS, et al. &#x2019;Long-COVID&#x2019;: A cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Penfold RS, Merino J, Sudre CH, Molteni E, Berry S, et al. Risk factors and disease profile of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection in UK users of the COVID Symptom Study app: A prospective, community-based, nested, case-control study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;22:43&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34480857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledford H. Do vaccines protect against long COVID.What the data say? Nature. 2021;599:546&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34815580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. Coronavirus (COVID-19) vaccination and self-reported long COVID in the UK: 25 October 2021. 2021.  Available from: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/articles/coronavirus COVID19vaccinationandselfreportedlongCOVIDintheuk/25october2021. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akrami A, Assaf G, Davis H, Harris K, Iwasaki A, Krumholz H, et al. Change in symptoms and immune response in people with post-acute sequelae of SARS-Cov-2 infection (PASC) after SARS-Cov-2 vaccination. medRxiv. 2021 doi: 10.1101/2021.07.21.21260391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guideline N. NICE Guideline; COVID-19 rapid guideline: Managing the long-term effects of COVID-19.  Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>George PM, Barratt SL, Condliffe R, Desai SR, Devaraj A, Forrest I, et al. Respiratory follow-up of patients with COVID-19 pneumonia. Thorax. 2020;75:1009&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32839287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Taylor S. NICE guideline on long COVID? BMJ. 2020;371:m4938. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m4938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33361141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker-Davies RM, O&#x2019;Sullivan O, Senaratne KPP, Baker P, Cranley M, Dharm-Datta S, et al. The Stanford Hall consensus statement for post-COVID-19 rehabilitation. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:949&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7418628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32475821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang TJ, Chau B, Lui M, Lam G-T, Lin N, Humbert S. PM&amp;R and pulmonary rehabilitation for COVID-19. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2020 doi: 10.1097/PHM.0000000000001505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7315835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32541352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grigoletto I, Cavalheri V, de Lima FF, Ramos EMC. Recovery after COVID-19: The potential role of pulmonary rehabilitation. Braz J Phys Ther. 2020;24:463&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7368839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32723665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Zhang W, Yang Y, Zhang J, Li Y, Chen Y. Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: A randomized controlled study? Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2020;39:101166. doi: 10.1016/j.ctcp. 2020.101166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demeco A, Marotta N, Barletta M, Pino I, Marinaro C, Petraroli A, et al. Rehabilitation of patients post-COVID-19 infection: A literature review. J Int Med Res. 2020;48:0300060520948382. doi: 10.1177/0300060520948382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7450453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32840156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Q, Levine BD. Exercise and non-pharmacological treatment of POTS. Auton Neurosci. 2018;215:20&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6289756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30001836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larun L, Brurberg KG, Odgaard-Jensen J, Price JR. Exercise therapy for chronic fatigue syndrome? Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;10:CD003200. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD003200.pub8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6953363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31577366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twisk F, Maes M. A review on cognitive behavorial therapy (CBT) and graded exercise therapy (GET) in myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME)/chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS): CBT/GET is not only ineffective and not evidence-based, but also potentially harmful for many patients with ME/CFS. Neuro Endocrinol Lett. 2009;30:284&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19855350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torrisi SE, Kahn N, Vancheri C, Kreuter M. Evolution and treatment of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Presse M&#xe9;d. 2020;49:104025. doi: 10.1016/j.lpm. 2020.104025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghu G, Wilson KC. COVID-19 interstitial pneumonia: Monitoring the clinical course in survivors. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8:839&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7398671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32758440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai AD, Boursiquot BC, Melki L, Wan EY. Management of arrhythmias associated with COVID-19? Curr Cardiol Rep. 2021;23:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1007/s11886-020-01434-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7685181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33231782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendren NS, Drazner MH, Bozkurt B, Cooper LT., Jr Description and proposed management of the acute COVID-19 cardiovascular syndrome. Circulation. 2020;141:1903&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7314493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32297796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>