<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37070369</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2060</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An update of the reported effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on person with intellectual disability and their carers: a scoping review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2196437</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2196437</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2196437</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/07853890.2023.2196437</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The effects of the COVID-19 pandemic has been felt by all groups in society and people with intellectual disability are especially vulnerable due to underlying conditions/health problems, multi-morbidity, limitations in understanding, frailty and social circumstances. This places people with intellectual disability, their families and carers at increased risk of stress and in need of support.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To update and chart the evidence of the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on people with intellectual disability, their families and carers reported within the research in 2021.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A scoping review of research published in 2021 across 7 databases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">84 studies met the inclusion criteria, and the findings highlight people with intellectual disability are at a greater risk to COVID-19 health outcomes due to underlying health concerns and access issues. The effects of COVID-19 can be seen from a personal, social and health perspective for people with intellectual disability, their carers and families. However, COVID-19 did have some unanticipated benefits such as: less demand on time, greater opportunity to engage with people of value and building resilience.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">COVID-19 presents many challenges but for people with intellectual disability compounding existing obstacles encountered in access issues, service provision and supports available. There is a need to identify and describe the experiences of people with intellectual disability, their families and carers in the medium-long term during COVID-19. Greater supports and evidence of effective interventions to promote health, deliver services and support individual with intellectual disability is needed as there is little evidence of clinical care for people with intellectual disability during COVID-19.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keenan</LastName><ForeName>Paul Michael</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2015-1482</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing and Midwifery, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Doody</LastName><ForeName>Owen</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3708-1647</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing and Midwifery, Health Research Institute, University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8906388</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0785-3890</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008607" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intellectual Disability</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="N">Caregivers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006293" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Promotion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>During pandemics the perspectives of people with intellectual disability, their carers and service providers are central to addressing systemic health care inequalities and poor-quality person-centred care.Greater collaboration is needed to learn from pandemics in terms of health and social care policy improvements.There remains a need for large scale studies that are representative of the broad spectrum of the intellectual disability population and examine Long-COVID in this group of people.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intellectual disability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pandemic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scoping review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The contents of this manuscript, including figures and tables, are those of the authors. Views expressed do not necessarily represent the viewpoints of the Universities they work for. No potential conflict of interest was reported by the author(s).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37070369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10120563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2023.2196437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rommel A. Covid-19&#x2013;an unexpected journey. Argumentum. 2022;18:1&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation . 2022. Who coronavirus disease (COVID-19) pandemic. Geneva: world Health Organization. https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019?adgroupsurvey={adgroupsurvey}&amp;gclid=EAIaIQobChMIjc-Pk9Da-QIVwu7tCh01EQfiEAAYASAAEgJ5VPD_BwE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke S, Parker S, Fleming P, et al. . Building health system resilience through policy development in response to COVID-19 in Ireland: from shock to reform. Lancet Regional Health-Europe. 2021;9:100223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8495249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34642676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu DK, Akl EA, Duda S, et al. . Physical distancing, face masks, and eye protection to prevent person-to-person transmission of SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet. 2020;395(10242):1973&#x2013;1987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7263814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32497510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desroches ML, Ailey S, Fisher K, et al. . Impact of COVID-19: nursing challenges to meeting the care needs of people with developmental disabilities. Disabil Health J. 2021;14(1):101015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7640896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33184022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher B, Van Noorden R.. How the COVID pandemic is changing global science collaborations. Nature. 2021;594(7863):316&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34135528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doody O, Keenan PM.. The reported effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on people with intellectual disability and their carers: a scoping review. Ann Med. 2021;53(1):786&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8205046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34110258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schalock RL, Luckasson R, Tasse MJ.. 2021. Intellectual disability: definition, classification, and systems of supports. 12th ed. Silver Spring (MD): American Association on Intellectual and Developmental Disabilities.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34700345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H, O&#x2019;Malley L.. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2005;8(1):19&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn Z, Peters MD, Stern C, et al. . Systematic review or scoping review? Guidance for authors when choosing between a systematic or scoping review approach. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2018;18(1):143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6245623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30453902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradbury-Jones C, Aveyard H, Herber OR, et al. . Scoping reviews: the PAGER framework for improving the quality of reporting. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2022;25(4):457&#x2013;470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levac D, Colquhoun H, O&#x2019;Brien KK.. Scoping studies: advancing the methodology. Implementation Sci. 2010;5(1):69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2954944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20854677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock D, Davies EL, Peters MD, et al. . Undertaking a scoping review: a practical guide for nursing and midwifery students, clinicians, researchers, and academics. J Adv Nurs. 2021;77(4):2102&#x2013;2113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8049063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33543511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, et al. . PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169(7):467&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. . The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Syst Rev. 2021;10(1):1&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daudt HM, van Mossel C, Scott SJ.. Enhancing the scoping study methodology: a large, inter-professional team&#x2019;s experience with Arksey and O&#x2019;Malley&#x2019;s framework. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2013;13(1):48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3614526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23522333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abuzaid SMO, Taibah University, Special Education, Saudi Arabia . Consequences of coronavirus as a predictor of emotional security among mothers of children with intellectual disabilities. J Intellect Disabl Diagn Treat. 2021;9(4):390&#x2013;396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amor AM, Navas P, Verdugo M&#xc1;, et al. . Perceptions of people with intellectual and developmental disabilities about COVID&#x2010;19 in Spain: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. J Intell Disabil Res. 2021;65(5):381&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araten-Bergman T, Shpigelman CN.. Staying connected during COVID-19: family engagement with adults with developmental disabilities in supported accommodation. Res Dev Disabil. 2021;108:103812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33202349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashworth M, Palikara O, Burchell E, et al. . Online and face-to-face performance on two cognitive tasks in children with Williams syndrome. Front Psychol. 2021;11:594465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7889503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33613354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athbah SY. Covid-19 impact on children with autism spectrum disorder and intellectual disability: study in Saudi Arabia. JESR. 2021;11(6):78&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey T, Hastings RP, Totsika V.. COVID&#x2010;19 impact on psychological outcomes of parents, siblings and children with intellectual disability: longitudinal before and during lockdown design. J Intell Disabil Res. 2021;65(5):397&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33634520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baksh RA, Pape SE, Smith J, et al. . Understanding inequalities in COVID-19 outcomes following hospital admission for people with intellectual disability compared to the general population: a matched cohort study in the UK. BMJ Open. 2021;11(10):e052482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8491000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34607870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bente BE, Van &#x2018;t Klooster JWJR, Schreijer MA, et al. . The Dutch COVID-19 contact tracing app (the CoronaMelder): usability study. JMIR Form Res. 2021;5(3):e27882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33724198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond C, Stacey G, Gordon E, et al. . COVID-19: experiences and contributions of learning disability nurses during the first wave of the pandemic. Learn Disabil Pr. 2021;24(4):17&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullard L, Harvey D, Abbeduto L.. Exploring the feasibility of collecting multimodal multiperson assessment data via distance in families affected by fragile X syndrome. J Telemed Telecare. 2021;Online paper identifier - 1357633X211003810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8505575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33840279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carey IM, Cook DG, Harris T, et al. . Risk factors for excess all-cause mortality during the first wave of the COVID-19 pandemic in England: a retrospective cohort study of primary care data. PLOS One. 2021;16(12):e0260381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8659693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34882700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chemerynska N, Marczak M, Kucharska J.. What are the experiences of clinical psychologists working with people with intellectual disabilities during the COVID-19 pandemic. Res Intellect Disabil. 2022;35(2):587&#x2013;595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34913546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKenna B, Curtis HJ, Walker AJ, et al. ; All OpenSAFELY study authors . Trends and clinical characteristics of 57.9 million COVID-19 vaccine recipients: a federated analysis of patients&#x2019; primary care records in situ using OpenSAFELY. Br J Gen Pract. 2022;72(714):e51&#x2013;e62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8589463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34750106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das-Munshi J, Chang CK, Bakolis I, et al. . All-cause and cause-specific mortality in people with mental disorders and intellectual disabilities, before and during the COVID-19 pandemic: cohort study. Lancet Reg Health Eur. 2021;11:100228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8639185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34877563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domaga&#x142;a-Zy&#x15b;k E. Attitudes of different age groups toward people with intellectual disability during the COVID-19 pandemic. Front Psychiatry. 2021;12:591707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8310948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34322039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Embregts P, Heerkens L, Frielink N, et al. . Experiences of mothers caring for a child with an intellectual disability during the COVID-19 pandemic in The Netherlands. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2021;65(8):760&#x2013;771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34076326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Embregts PJCM, Tournier T, Frielink N.. The experiences of psychologists working with people with intellectual disabilities during the COVID-19 crisis. Res Intellect Disabil. 2022;35(1):295&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8420360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34197019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Festen DAM, Schoufour JD, Hilgenkamp TIM, et al. . Determining frailty in people with intellectual disabilities in the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic. J Policy Practic Intellect Disabil. 2021;18(3):203&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33821163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher MH, Sung C, Kammes RR, et al. . Social support as a mediator of stress and life satisfaction for people with intellectual or developmental disabilities during the COVID-19 pandemic. J Appl Res Intellect Disabil. 2022;35(1):243&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8646736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34633129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flynn S, Caton S, Gillooly A, et al. . The experiences of adults with learning disabilities in the UK during the COVID-19 pandemic: qualitative results from wave 1 of the coronavirus and people with learning disabilities study. TLDR. 2021;26(4):224&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flynn S, Hatton C.. Health and social care access for adults with learning disabilities across the UK during the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020. TLDR. 2021;26(3):174&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman C. The COVID-19 pandemic and quality of life outcomes of people with intellectual and developmental disabilities. Disabil Health J. 2021;14(4):101117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8436150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34144897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gacek M, Krzywoszanski L.. Symptoms of anxiety and depression in students with developmental disabilities during COVID-19 lockdown in Poland. Front Psychiatry. 2021;12:576867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8012510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33815160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gale TM, Boland B.. COVID-19 deaths in a secondary mental health service. Comph Psychiat. 2021;111:152277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8461000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34592645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geuijen PM, Vromans L, Embregts PJCM.. A qualitative investigation of support workers&#x2019; experiences of the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on Dutch migrant families who have children with intellectual disabilities. J Intellect Dev Disabil. 2021;46(4):300&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil-Llario MD, D&#xed;az-Rodr&#xed;guez I, Morell-Mengual V, et al. . Sexual health in Spanish people with intellectual disability: the impact of the lockdown due to COVID-19. Sex Res Soc Policy. 2021;19(3):1217&#x2013;1227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8308064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34335991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatton C, Bailey T, Bradshaw J, et al. . The willingness of UK adults with intellectual disabilities to take COVID-19 vaccines. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2021;65(11):949&#x2013;961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8657332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34529314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heslop P, Byrne V, Calkin R, et al. . Deaths of people with intellectual disabilities: analysis of deaths in England from COVID-19 and other causes. J Appl Res Intellect Disabil. 2021;34(6):1630&#x2013;1640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8420486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34272793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honingh AK, Koelewijn A, Veneberg B, et al. . Implications of COVID-19 regulations for people with visual and intellectual disabilities: lessons to learn from visiting restrictions. Policy Practice Intel Disabi. 2022;19(1):64&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34909049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xfc;ls A, Costa ACS, Dierssen M, et al. . Medical vulnerability of individuals with down syndrome to severe COVID-19-data from the trisomy 21 research society and the UK ISARIC4C survey. EClinicalMed. 2021;33:100769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7897934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33644721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iadarola S, Siegel JF, Gao Q, et al. . COVID-19 vaccine perceptions in New York state&#x2019;s intellectual and developmental disabilities community. Disabil Health J. 2022;15(1):101178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8325377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34362712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya A, Sahin CH.. I did not even receive even a phone call from any institution: experiences and recommendations related to disability during COVID-19. Int J Dev Disabil. 2021;Online paper identifier - 20473869.2021.1978268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10402854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37547553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MA, Yi J, Sung J, et al. . Changes in life experiences of adults with intellectual disabilities in the COVID-19 pandemics in South Korea. Disabil Health J. 2021;14(4):101120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9761012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34074618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MA, Yi J, Jung SM, et al. . A qualitative study on parents&#x2019; concerns about adult children with intellectual disabilities amid the COVID-19 pandemic in South Korea. J Appl Res Intellect Disabil. 2021;34(4):1145&#x2013;1155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8237012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33694235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lake JK, Jachyra P, Volpe T, et al. . The wellbeing and mental health care experiences of adults with intellectual and developmental disabilities during COVID-19. J Ment Health Res Intellect Disabil. 2021;14(3):285&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landes SD, Turk MA, Damiani MR, et al. . Risk factors associated with covid-19 outcomes among people with intellectual and developmental disabilities receiving residential services. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(6):e2112862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8188265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34100935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landes SD, Turk MA, Wong AWWA.. COVID-19 outcomes among people with intellectual and developmental disability in California: the importance of type of residence and skilled nursing care needs. Disabil Health J. 2021;14(2):101051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33309535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landes SD, Turk MA, Ervin DA.. COVID-19 case-fatality disparities among people with intellectual and developmental disabilities: evidence from 12&#x2009;US jurisdictions. Disabil Health J. 2021;14(4):101116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8436051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34039516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langdon PE, Marczak M, Clifford C, et al. . Occupational stress, coping and wellbeing among registered psychologists working with people with intellectual disabilities during the COVID-19 pandemic in the United Kingdom. J Intellect Dev Disabil. 2022;47(3):195&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee RLT, West S, Tang ACY, et al. . A qualitative exploration of the experiences of school nurses during COVID-19 pandemic as the frontline primary health care professionals. Nurs Outlook. 2021;69(3):399&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33541726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LoPorto J, Spina K.. Risk perception and coping strategies among direct support professionals in the age of COVID-19. J Soc Behav Health Sci. 2021;15(1):201&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunsky Y, Durbin A, Balogh R, et al. . Covid-19 positivity rates, hospitalizations and mortality of adults with and without intellectual and developmental disabilities in Ontario, Canada. Disabil Health J. 2022;15(1):101174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8312045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34340949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunsky Y, Bobbette N, Chacra MA, et al. . Predictors of worker mental health in intellectual disability services during COVID&#x2010;19. J Appl Res Intellect Disabil. 2021;34(6):1655&#x2013;1660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33998117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunsky Y, Kithulegoda N, Thai K, et al. . Beliefs regarding COVID-19 vaccines among Canadian workers in the intellectual disability sector prior to vaccine implementation. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2021;65(7):617&#x2013;625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33788310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunsky Y, Bobbette N, Selick A, et al. . The doctor will see you now: direct support professionals&#x2019; perspectives on supporting adults with intellectual and developmental disabilities accessing health care during COVID-19. Disabil Health J. 2021;14(3):101066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9760310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33531290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maggio MG, Cuzzola F, Calatozzo M, et al. . Improving cognitive functions in adolescents with learning difficulties: a feasibility study on the potential use of telerehabilitation during covid-19 pandemic in Italy. J Adol. 2021;89(1):194&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8631547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34022448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCausland D, Luus R, McCallion P, et al. . The impact of COVID&#x2010;19 on the social inclusion of older adults with an intellectual disability during the first wave of the pandemic in Ireland. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2021;65(10):879&#x2013;889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8447302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34165228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie K, Murray GC, Martin R.. It&#x2019;s been adapted rather than impacted: a qualitative evaluation of the impact of covid-19 restrictions on the positive behavioural support of people with an intellectual disability and/or autism. J Appl Res Intellect Disabil. 2021;34(4):1089&#x2013;1097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33484052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNally Keehn R, Enneking B, James C, et al. . Telehealth evaluation of pediatric neurodevelopmental disabilities during the COVID-19 pandemic: clinician and caregiver perspectives. J Dev Behav Pediatr. 2022;43(5):262&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34954761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosbah H, Coupaye M, Jacques F, et al. . Effects of the COVID-19 pandemic and lockdown on the mental and physical health of adults with Prader-Willi syndrome. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2021;16(1):202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8097667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33952330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munir MM, Rubaca U, Munir MH, et al. . An analysis of families&#x2019; experiences with young children with intellectual and developmental disabilities (IDDs) during COVID-19 lockdown in Pakistan. Int Multidiscip J Soc Sci. 2021;10(1):81&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mupaku WM, van Breda AD, Kelly B.. Transitioning to adulthood from residential childcare during COVID&#x2010;19: experiences of young people with intellectual disabilities and/or autism spectrum disorder in South Africa. Br J Learn Disabil. 2021;49(3):341&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34548837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray GC, McKenzie K, Martin R, et al. . The impact of COVID-19 restrictions in the United Kingdom on the positive behavioural support of people with an intellectual disability. Br J Learn Disabil. 2021;49(2):138&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33821134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naqvi D, Perera B, Mitchell S, et al. . COVID-19 pandemic impact on psychotropic prescribing for adults with intellectual disability: an observational study in English specialist community services. BJPsych Open. 2021;8(1):e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8649353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34865678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navas P, Verdugo M&#xc1;, Mart&#xed;nez S, et al. . Impact of COVID-19 on the burden of care of families of people with intellectual and developmental disabilities. Res Intellect Disabil. 2022;35(2):577&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34888996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navas P, Amor AM, Crespo M, et al. . Supports for people with intellectual and developmental disabilities during the COVID-19 pandemic from their own perspective. Res Dev Disabil. 2021;108:103813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7651232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33271448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oudshoorn CEM, Frielink N, Riper H, et al. . Experiences of therapists conducting psychological assessments and video conferencing therapy sessions with people with mild intellectual disabilities during the COVID-19 pandemic. Int J Dev Disabil. 2021;Online paper identifier - 20473869.2021.1967078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10071960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37025338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parchomiuk M. Care and rehabilitation institutions for people with intellectual disabilities during the COVID-19 pandemic: polish experiences. Int Soc Work. 2021;Online paper identifier - 00208728211060471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10336334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37457859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel V, Perez&#x2010;Olivas G, Kroese BS, et al. . The experiences of carers of adults with intellectual disabilities during the first COVID&#x2010;19 lockdown period. Policy Practice Intel Disabi. 2021;18(4):254&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34226830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulauskaite L, Farris O, Spencer HM, et al. . My son can&#x2019;t socially distance or wear a mask: how families of preschool children with severe developmental delays and challenging behavior experienced the COVID-19 pandemic. J Ment Health Res Intellect Disabil. 2021;14(2):225&#x2013;236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peacock-Brennan S, Stewart K, Angier RJ, et al. . The experience of COVID-19 &#x201c;lockdown&#x201d; for people with a learning disability: results from surveys in Jersey and Guernsey. TLDR. 2021;26(3):121&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Power N, Dolby R, Thorne D.. Reflecting or frozen: the impact of covid-19 on art therapists working with people with a learning disability. Int J Art Ther. 2021;26(3):84&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purrington J, Nye A, Beail N.. Exploring maintaining gains following therapy during the coronavirus pandemic with adults with an intellectual disability. AMHID. 2021;15(6):253&#x2013;268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauf B, Sheikh H, Majid H, et al. . COVID-19-related prescribing challenge in intellectual disability. BJPsych Open. 2021;7(2):E66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8058854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33736746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawlings GH, Wright KP, Rolling K, et al. . Telephone-delivered compassion-focused therapy for adults with intellectual disabilities: a case series. AMHID. 2021;15(2/3):89&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawlings GH, Gaskell C, Rolling K, et al. . Exploring how to deliver videoconference-mediated psychological therapy to adults with an intellectual disability during the coronavirus pandemic. AMHID. 2021;15(1):20&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redquest BK, Tint A, Ries H, et al. . Exploring the experiences of siblings of adults with intellectual/developmental disabilities during the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2021;65(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33124773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers K, McAliskey S, McKinney P, et al. . Managing an outbreak of COVID-19 in a learning disability setting. Learn Disabil Pract. 2021;25(3):ldp.2021.e2116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosencrans M, Arango P, Sabat C, et al. . The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the health, wellbeing, and access to services of people with intellectual and developmental disabilities. Res Dev Disabil. 2021;114:103985&#x2013;103985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9758885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34049229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rousseau MC, Hully M, Milh M, et al. . Clinical characteristics of COVID-19 infection in polyhandicapped persons in France. Arch Pediatrie. 2021;28(5):374&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8064873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33994267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryzhikov K. Virtual therapeutic horticulture: a social wellness program for adults with intellectual and developmental disabilities. Acta Hortic. 2021;1330:55&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salzner J, Dall M, Weber C, et al. . Deaf residents with intellectual disabilities during the first covid-19 associated lockdown. J Deaf Stud Deaf Edu. 2021;26(4):556&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8344832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34185050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Larsen A, Conde-Blanco E, Viloria-Alebesque A, et al. . COVID-19 prevalence and mortality in people with epilepsy: a nation-wide multicenter study. Epilepsy Behav. 2021;125:108379&#x2013;108379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9759834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34731719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheffers F, Moonen X, van Vugt E.. Assessing the quality of support and discovering sources of resilience during COVID-19 measures in people with intellectual disabilities by professional carers. Res Dev Disabil. 2021;111:103889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9758889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33578230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schott W, Tao S, Shea L.. COVID-19 risk: adult medicaid beneficiaries with autism, intellectual disability, and mental health conditions. Autism. 2022;26(4):975&#x2013;987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8859009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34420427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehan R, Dalton-Locke C, Ali A, et al. . Effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on mental healthcare and services: results of a UK survey of front-line staff working with people with intellectual disability and/or autism. BJPsych Bull. 2021;44(4):201&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9768507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33977886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suarez-Balcazar Y, Mirza M, Errisuriz VL, et al. . Impact of covid-19 on the mental health and well-being of Latinx caregivers of children with intellectual and developmental disabilities. IJERPH. 2021;18(15):7971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8345447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34360263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vereijken FR, Giesbers SAH, Jahoda A, et al. . Homeward bound: exploring the motives of mothers who brought their offspring with intellectual disabilities home from residential settings during the COVID-19 pandemic. Res Intellect Disabil. 2022;35(1):150&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8420307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34213037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wieting J, Eberlein C, Bleich S, et al. . Behavioural change in Prader&#x2013;Willi syndrome during COVID-19 pandemic. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2021;65(7):609&#x2013;616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33754414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson EJ, McDonald HI, Bhaskaran K, et al. . Risks of covid-19 hospital admission and death for people with learning disability: population based cohort study using the OpenSAFELY platform. BMJ. 2021;374:n1592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8278652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34261639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolstencroft J, Hull L, Warner L, IMAGINE-ID consortium, et al.. We have been in lockdown since he was born&#x2019;: a mixed methods exploration of the experiences of families caring for children with intellectual disability during the COVID-19 pandemic in the UK. BMJ Open. 2021;11(9):e049386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8487017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34593495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wos K, Kamecka-Antczak C, Szafra&#x144;ski M.. Remote support for adults with intellectual disability during COVID-19: from a caregiver&#x2019;s perspective. Policy Practice Intel Disabi. 2021;18(4):279&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8447416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34548876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan YQ, Ding JN, Bi N, et al. . Physical activity and sedentary behaviour among children and adolescents with intellectual disabilities during the COVID-19 lockdown in China. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2021;66(12):913&#x2013;923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8657159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34730262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nation . Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities (CRPD); 2006. Available from: www.un.org/development/desa/disabilities/convention-on-the-rights-of-persons-with-disabilities.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Xu X, Han Q, et al. . Factors associated with public attitudes towards persons with disabilities: a systematic review. BMC Public Health. 2021;21(1):1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8173851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34082734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JJ, Co L.. Attitudes and experiences of general practitioners who provided health care for people with intellectual disabilities: a South Australian perspective. Res Pract Intellect Dev Disabil. 2021;8(1):25&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breau G, Baumbusch J, Thorne S, et al. . Primary care providers&#x2019; attitudes towards individuals with intellectual disability: associations with experience and demographics. J Intellect Disabil. 2021;25(1):65&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31272273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Health Service . The Oliver McGowan mandatory training on learning disability and autism. National Health Service Health Education England; 2022. https://www.hee.nhs.uk/our-work/learning-disability/current-projects/oliver-mcgowan-mandatory-training-learning-disability-autism</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirvikoski T, Boman M, Tideman M, et al. . Association of intellectual disability with all-cause and cause-specific mortality in Sweden. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(6):e2113014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8220491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34156453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle A, O&#x2019;Sullivan M, Craig S, et al. . People with intellectual disability in Ireland are still dying young. J Appl Res Intellect Disabil. 2021;34(4):1057&#x2013;1065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8359186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33377272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeste S, Hyde C, Distefano C, et al. . Changes in access to educational and healthcare services for individuals with intellectual and developmental disabilities during COVID&#x2010;19 restrictions. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2020;64(11):825&#x2013;833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32939917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaagsma M, Volkers KM, Swart EA, et al. . The use of online support by people with intellectual disabilities living independently during COVID&#x2010;19. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2020;64(10):750&#x2013;756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32830390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander R, Ravi A, Barclay H, et al. . Guidance for the treatment and management of COVID&#x2010;19 among people with intellectual disabilities. J Policy Practic Intellect Disabil. 2020;17(3):256&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7307021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32837529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations . 2020. Policy brief: education during COVID-19 and beyond. New York: United Nations.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taddio A, Ipp M, Thivakaran S, et al. . Survey of the prevalence of immunization non-compliance due to needle fears in children and adults. Vaccine. 2012;30(32):4807&#x2013;4812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22617633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLenon J, Rogers MA.. The fear of needles: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Adv Nurs. 2019;75(1):30&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30109720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldsmith L, Woodward V, Jackson L, et al. . Informed consent for blood tests in people with a learning disability. J Adv Nurs. 2013;69(9):1966&#x2013;1976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23215815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleason J, Ross W, Fossi A, et al. . The devastating impact of covid-19 on individuals with intellectual disabilities in the United States. NEJM Catalyst. 2021. 5;2(2):1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baghdadli A, Picot MC, Miot S, et al. . A call to action to implement effective COVID-19 prevention and screening of individuals with severe intellectual developmental and autism spectrum disorders. J Autism Dev Disord. 2021;51(7):2566&#x2013;2568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7526962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33000394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley VJ. How COVID-19 may change the world of services to people with intellectual and developmental disabilities. Intellect Dev Disabil. 2020;58(5):355&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33032314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavanagh A, Dickinson H, Carey G, et al. . Improving health care for disabled people in COVID-19 and beyond: lessons from Australia and England. Disabil Health J. 2021;14(2):101050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7969381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33341397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes N, Anderson G.. The experience of the COVID-19 pandemic in a UK learning disability service: lost in a sea of ever changing variables&#x2013;a perspective. Int J Dev Disabil. 2022;68(3):374&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9122349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35603005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onwumere J, Creswell C, Livingston G, et al. . H. COVID-19 and UK family carers: policy implications. The Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8(10):929&#x2013;936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8445736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34537103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock A, Campbell P, Struthers C, et al. . Development of the ACTIVE framework to describe stakeholder involvement in systematic reviews. J Health Serv Res Policy. 2019;24(4):245&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30997859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>