<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39310121</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2164-7712</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of clinical and experimental immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Clin Exp Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Advance in the mechanism and clinical research of myalgia in long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>142</StartPage><EndPage>164</EndPage><MedlinePgn>142-164</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.62347/TXVO6284</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) continues to evolve, mortality rates of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) have significantly decreased. However, a variable proportion of patients exhibit persistent prolonged symptoms of COVID-19 infection (long COVID). This virus primarily attacks respiratory system, but numerous individuals complain persistent skeletal muscle pain or worsening pre-existing muscle pain post COVID-19, which severely affects the quality of life and recovery. Currently, there is limited research on the skeletal muscle pain in long COVID. In this brief review, we review potential pathological mechanisms of skeletal muscle pain in long COVID, and summarize the various auxiliary examinations and treatments for skeletal muscle pain in long COVID. We consider abnormal activation of inflammatory response, myopathy, and neurological damages as pivotal pathological mechanisms of skeletal muscle pain in long COVID. A comprehensive examination is significantly important in order to work out effective treatment plans and relieve skeletal muscle pain. So far, rehabilitation interventions for myalgia in long COVID contain but are not limited to drug, nutraceutical therapy, gut microbiome-targeted therapy, interventional therapy and strength training. Our study provides a potential mechanism reference for clinical researches, highlighting the importance of comprehensive approach and management of skeletal muscle pain in long COVID. The relief of skeletal muscle pain will accelerate rehabilitation process, improve activities of daily living and enhance the quality of life, promoting individuals return to society with profound significance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJCEI Copyright &#xa9; 2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhai</LastName><ForeName>Xiuyun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Shanghai General Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University No. 100, Haining Road, Shanghai 200080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Weijun</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Shanghai General Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University No. 100, Haining Road, Shanghai 200080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Siliang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Therapy, School of Health, Shanghai Normal University Tianhua College No. 1661, North Shengxin Road, Shanghai 201815, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miao</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Shanghai General Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University No. 100, Haining Road, Shanghai 200080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, School of International Medical Technology, Shanghai Sanda University No. 2727, Jinhai Road, Shanghai 201209, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Clin Exp Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101587157</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myalgia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skeletal muscle pain</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39310121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11411160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62347/TXVO6284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Varatharaj A, Thomas N, Ellul MA, Davies NWS, Pollak TA, Tenorio EL, Sultan M, Easton A, Breen G, Zandi M, Coles JP, Manji H, Al-Shahi Salman R, Menon DK, Nicholson TR, Benjamin LA, Carson A, Smith C, Turner MR, Solomon T, Kneen R, Pett SL, Galea I, Thomas RH, Michael BD CoroNerve Study Group. Neurological and neuropsychiatric complications of COVID-19 in 153 patients: a UK-wide surveillance study. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;7:875&#x2013;882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7316461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32593341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanou MI, Palaiodimou L, Bakola E, Smyrnis N, Papadopoulou M, Paraskevas GP, Rizos E, Boutati E, Grigoriadis N, Krogias C, Giannopoulos S, Tsiodras S, Gaga M, Tsivgoulis G. Neurological manifestations of long-COVID syndrome: a narrative review. Ther Adv Chronic Dis. 2022;13:20406223221076890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8859684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35198136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aschman T, Schneider J, Greuel S, Meinhardt J, Streit S, Goebel HH, B&#xfc;ttnerova I, Elezkurtaj S, Scheibe F, Radke J, Meisel C, Drosten C, Radbruch H, Heppner FL, Corman VM, Stenzel W. Association between SARS-CoV-2 infection and immune-mediated myopathy in patients who have died. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78:948&#x2013;960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34115106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte-Neto AN, Monteiro RAA, da Silva LFF, Malheiros DMAC, de Oliveira EP, Theodoro-Filho J, Pinho JRR, Gomes-Gouv&#xea;a MS, Salles APM, de Oliveira IRS, Mauad T, Saldiva PHN, Dolhnikoff M. Pulmonary and systemic involvement in COVID-19 patients assessed with ultrasound-guided minimally invasive autopsy. Histopathology. 2020;77:186&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7280721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32443177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CC, Ko WC, Lee PI, Jean SS, Hsueh PR. Extra-respiratory manifestations of COVID-19. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2020;56:106024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32450197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, Ghanima W, Olsen MK, Gilboe HM, Einvik G. Persistent symptoms 1.5-6 months after COVID-19 in non-hospitalised subjects: a population-based cohort study. Thorax. 2021;76:405&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan WJ, Ni ZY, Hu Y, Liang WH, Ou CQ, He JX, Liu L, Shan H, Lei CL, Hui DSC, Du B, Li LJ, Zeng G, Yuen KY, Chen RC, Tang CL, Wang T, Chen PY, Xiang J, Li SY, Wang JL, Liang ZJ, Peng YX, Wei L, Liu Y, Hu YH, Peng P, Wang JM, Liu JY, Chen Z, Li G, Zheng ZJ, Qiu SQ, Luo J, Ye CJ, Zhu SY, Zhong NS China Medical Treatment Expert Group for Covid-19. Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:1708&#x2013;1720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32109013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y, Zhang L, Fan G, Xu J, Gu X, Cheng Z, Yu T, Xia J, Wei Y, Wu W, Xie X, Yin W, Li H, Liu M, Xiao Y, Gao H, Guo L, Xie J, Wang G, Jiang R, Gao Z, Jin Q, Wang J, Cao B. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020;395:497&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechien JR, Chiesa-Estomba CM, Place S, Van Laethem Y, Cabaraux P, Mat Q, Huet K, Plzak J, Horoi M, Hans S, Rosaria Barillari M, Cammaroto G, Fakhry N, Martiny D, Ayad T, Jouffe L, Hopkins C, Saussez S COVID-19 Task Force of YO-IFOS. Clinical and epidemiological characteristics of 1420 European patients with mild-to-moderate coronavirus disease 2019. J Intern Med. 2020;288:335&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32352202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Hu B, Hu C, Zhu F, Liu X, Zhang J, Wang B, Xiang H, Cheng Z, Xiong Y, Zhao Y, Li Y, Wang X, Peng Z. Clinical characteristics of 138 hospitalized patients with 2019 novel coronavirus-infected pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA. 2020;323:1061&#x2013;1069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paliwal VK, Garg RK, Gupta A, Tejan N. Neuromuscular presentations in patients with COVID-19. Neurol Sci. 2020;41:3039&#x2013;3056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32935156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batur EB, Korez MK, Gezer IA, Levendoglu F, Ural O. Musculoskeletal symptoms and relationship with laboratory findings in patients with COVID-19. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:e14135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33686741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFarland AJ, Yousuf MS, Shiers S, Price TJ. Neurobiology of SARS-CoV-2 interactions with the peripheral nervous system: implications for COVID-19 and pain. Pain Rep. 2021;6:e885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7803673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33458558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickie I, Davenport T, Wakefield D, Vollmer-Conna U, Cameron B, Vernon SD, Reeves WC, Lloyd A Dubbo Infection Outcomes Study Group. Post-infective and chronic fatigue syndromes precipitated by viral and non-viral pathogens: prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2006;333:575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1569956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16950834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amenta EM, Spallone A, Rodriguez-Barradas MC, El Sahly HM, Atmar RL, Kulkarni PA. Postacute COVID-19: an overview and approach to classification. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2020;7:ofaa509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33403218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra N, Chowdhury M, Singh AK, Ma K, Kumar A, Ranjan P, Desai D, Wig N. Clinical predictors of long COVID-19 and phenotypes of mild COVID-19 at a tertiary care centre in India. Drug Discov Ther. 2021;15:156&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34234065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Florencio LL. Defining post-COVID symptoms (post-acute COVID, long COVID, persistent post-COVID): an integrative classification. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:2621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos PK, Sigoli E, Bragan&#xe7;a LJG, Cornachione AS. The musculoskeletal involvement after mild to moderate COVID-19 infection. Front Physiol. 2022;13:813924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9040683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35492595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, Kang L, Guo L, Liu M, Zhou X, Luo J, Huang Z, Tu S, Zhao Y, Chen L, Xu D, Li Y, Li C, Peng L, Li Y, Xie W, Cui D, Shang L, Fan G, Xu J, Wang G, Wang Y, Zhong J, Wang C, Wang J, Zhang D, Cao B. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Husain M, Harrison PJ. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 2021;18:e1003773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martone AM, Tosato M, Ciciarello F, Galluzzo V, Zazzara MB, Pais C, Savera G, Calvani R, Marzetti E, Robles MC, Ramirez M, Landi F Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Team. Sarcopenia as potential biological substrate of long COVID-19 syndrome: prevalence, clinical features, and risk factors. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022;13:1974&#x2013;1982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9349974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35698920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gransee HM, Mantilla CB, Sieck GC. Respiratory muscle plasticity. Compr Physiol. 2012;2:1441&#x2013;1462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3962767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23798306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naddaf E, Milone M. Hereditary myopathies with early respiratory insufficiency in adults. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56:881&#x2013;886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28181274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leth S, Gunst JD, Mathiasen V, Hansen K, S&#xf8;gaard O, &#xd8;stergaard L, Jensen-Fangel S, Storgaard M, Agergaard J. Persistent symptoms in patients recovering from COVID-19 in Denmark. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8:ofab042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7928683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33875970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher A, Balfanz P, Cornelissen C, M&#xfc;ller A, Bergs I, Marx N, M&#xfc;ller-Wieland D, Hartmann B, Dreher M, M&#xfc;ller T. Follow up of patients with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): pulmonary and extrapulmonary disease sequelae. Respir Med. 2020;174:106197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33120193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go&#xeb;rtz YMJ, Van Herck M, Delbressine JM, Vaes AW, Meys R, Machado FVC, Houben-Wilke S, Burtin C, Posthuma R, Franssen FME, van Loon N, Hajian B, Spies Y, Vijlbrief H, van&#x2019;t Hul AJ, Janssen DJA, Spruit MA. Persistent symptoms 3 months after a SARS-CoV-2 infection: the post-COVID-19 syndrome? ERJ Open Res. 2020;6:00542-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH, Crooks MG. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;199:113&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs LG, Gourna Paleoudis E, Lesky-Di Bari D, Nyirenda T, Friedman T, Gupta A, Rasouli L, Zetkulic M, Balani B, Ogedegbe C, Bawa H, Berrol L, Qureshi N, Aschner JL. Persistence of symptoms and quality of life at 35 days after hospitalization for COVID-19 infection. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0243882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7732078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li X, Geng D, Mei N, Wu PY, Huang CC, Jia T, Zhao Y, Wang D, Xiao A, Yin B. Cerebral micro-structural changes in COVID-19 patients - an MRI-based 3-month follow-up study. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanbehzadeh S, Tavahomi M, Zanjari N, Ebrahimi-Takamjani I, Amiri-Arimi S. Physical and mental health complications post-COVID-19: scoping review. J Psychosom Res. 2021;147:110525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8133797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34051516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karaarslan F, G&#xfc;neri FD, Karde&#x15f; S. Long COVID: rheumatologic/musculoskeletal symptoms in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors at 3 and 6 months. Clin Rheumatol. 2022;41:289&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8553494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34713356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj L, Kannapadi NV, Briggs J, Seal SM, Battaglini D, Fanning J, Suen J, Robba C, Fraser J, Cho SM. Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: a meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci. 2022;434:120162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8798975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taboada M, Moreno E, Cari&#xf1;ena A, Rey T, Pita-Romero R, Leal S, Sanduende Y, Rodr&#xed;guez A, Nieto C, Vilas E, Ochoa M, Cid M, Seoane-Pillado T. Quality of life, functional status, and persistent symptoms after intensive care of COVID-19 patients. Br J Anaesth. 2021;126:e110&#x2013;e113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosn J, Piroth L, Epaulard O, Le Turnier P, Mentr&#xe9; F, Bachelet D, Laou&#xe9;nan C French COVID cohort study and investigators groups. Persistent COVID-19 symptoms are highly prevalent 6 months after hospitalization: results from a large prospective cohort. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:1041.e1041&#x2013;1041.e1044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8107834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34125067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauwers M, Au M, Yuan S, Wen C. COVID-19 in joint ageing and osteoarthritis: current status and perspectives. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8775477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35054906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Cancela-Cilleruelo I, Moro-L&#xf3;pez-Menchero P, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Pellicer-Valero OJ, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Arendt-Nielsen L. Exploring the trajectory curve of long-term musculoskeletal post-COVID pain symptoms in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: a multicenter study. Pain. 2023;164:413&#x2013;420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35930390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Wang F, Shen Y, Zhang X, Cen Y, Wang B, Zhao S, Zhou Y, Hu B, Wang M, Liu Y, Miao H, Jones P, Ma X, He Y, Cao G, Cheng L, Li L. Symptoms and health outcomes among survivors of COVID-19 infection 1 year after discharge from hospitals in Wuhan, China. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2127403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34586367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shivani F, Kumari N, Bai P, Rakesh F, Haseeb M, Kumar S, Jamil A, Zaidi M, Shaukat F, Rizwan A. Long-term symptoms of COVID-19: one-year follow-up study. Cureus. 2022;14:e25937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9282616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35844318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkodaymi MS, Omrani OA, Fawzy NA, Shaar BA, Almamlouk R, Riaz M, Obeidat M, Obeidat Y, Gerberi D, Taha RM, Kashour Z, Kashour T, Berbari EF, Alkattan K, Tleyjeh IM. Prevalence of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome symptoms at different follow-up periods: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28:657&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8812092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rass V, Beer R, Schiefecker AJ, Lindner A, Kofler M, Ianosi BA, Mahlknecht P, Heim B, Peball M, Carbone F, Limmert V, Kindl P, Putnina L, Fava E, Sahanic S, Sonnweber T, L&#xf6;scher WN, Wanschitz JV, Zamarian L, Djamshidian A, Tancevski I, Weiss G, Bellmann-Weiler R, Kiechl S, Seppi K, Loeffler-Ragg J, Pfausler B, Helbok R. Neurological outcomes 1 year after COVID-19 diagnosis: a prospective longitudinal cohort study. Eur J Neurol. 2022;29:1685&#x2013;1696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9111823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35239247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, Plaza-Manzano G, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, Arendt-Nielsen L. Time course prevalence of post-COVID pain symptoms of musculoskeletal origin in patients who had survived severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pain. 2022;163:1220&#x2013;1231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34561390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham EL, Clark JR, Orban ZS, Lim PH, Szymanski AL, Taylor C, DiBiase RM, Jia DT, Balabanov R, Ho SU, Batra A, Liotta EM, Koralnik IJ. Persistent neurologic symptoms and cognitive dysfunction in non-hospitalized Covid-19 &#x201c;long haulers&#x201d;. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2021;8:1073&#x2013;1085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33755344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Fuensalida-Novo S, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a M, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Florencio LL, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Barrera V, Arendt-Nielsen L. Myalgia as a symptom at hospital admission by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection is associated with persistent musculoskeletal pain as long-term post-COVID sequelae: a case-control study. Pain. 2021;162:2832&#x2013;2840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33863864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, de-la-Llave-Rinc&#xf3;n AI, Ortega-Santiago R, Ambite-Quesada S, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Arias-Naval&#xf3;n JA, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Barrera V, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Pellicer-Valero OJ, Arendt-Nielsen L. Prevalence and risk factors of musculoskeletal pain symptoms as long-term post-COVID sequelae in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: a multicenter study. Pain. 2022;163:e989&#x2013;e996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34913880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva NS, de Ara&#xfa;jo NK, Dos Santos KA, de Souza KSC, de Ara&#xfa;jo JNG, Cruz MS, Parra EJ, Silbiger VN, Luchessi AD. Post-Covid condition and clinic characteristics associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection: a 2-year follow-up to Brazilian cases. Sci Rep. 2023;13:13973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10460396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37633999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pel&#xe0; G, Goldoni M, Solinas E, Cavalli C, Tagliaferri S, Ranzieri S, Frizzelli A, Marchi L, Mori PA, Majori M, Aiello M, Corradi M, Chetta A. Sex-related differences in long-COVID-19 syndrome. J Womens Health (Larchmt) 2022;31:620&#x2013;630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35333613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bak&#x131;lan F, G&#xf6;kmen &#x130;G, Ortanca B, U&#xe7;an A, Eker G&#xfc;ven&#xe7; &#x15e;, &#x15e;ahin Mutlu F, G&#xf6;kmen HM, Ekim A. Musculoskeletal symptoms and related factors in postacute COVID-19 patients. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:e14734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8420386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34387911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiers S, Ray PR, Wangzhou A, Sankaranarayanan I, Tatsui CE, Rhines LD, Li Y, Uhelski ML, Dougherty PM, Price TJ. ACE2 and SCARF expression in human dorsal root ganglion nociceptors: implications for SARS-CoV-2 virus neurological effects. Pain. 2020;161:2494&#x2013;2501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7572821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rom&#xe1;n-Montes CM, Flores-Soto Y, Guaracha-Basa&#xf1;ez GA, Tamez-Torres KM, Sifuentes-Osornio J, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Lara MF, de Le&#xf3;n AP. Post-COVID-19 syndrome and quality of life impairment in severe COVID-19 Mexican patients. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1155951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10225709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37255755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr&#xf9; G, Bertelloni D, Diolaiuti F, Mucci F, Di Giuseppe M, Biella M, Gemignani A, Ciacchini R, Conversano C. Long-COVID syndrome? A study on the persistence of neurological, psychological and physiological symptoms. Healthcare (Basel) 2021;9:575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8152255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34068009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soh HS, Cho B. Long COVID-19 and health-related quality of life of mild cases in Korea: 3-months follow-up of a single community treatment center. J Korean Med Sci. 2022;37:e326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9705205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36631024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erden E, Turk AC, Erden E, Dag Z. Musculoskeletal system symptoms in patients with COVID-19 and the impact of these symptoms on quality of life. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2023;36:1061&#x2013;1074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37458011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun W, Gao H, Luo Y, Zheng H, Liao X, Xiong D, Xiao L. Management of immunity alteration-induced chronic pain during the coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19) pandemic. Front Microbiol. 2020;11:572318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7541845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33072033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang J, Wan Y, Luo C, Ye G, Geng Q, Auerbach A, Li F. Cell entry mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2020;117:11727&#x2013;11734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7260975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32376634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrandi PJ, Alway SE, Mohamed JS. The interaction between SARS-CoV-2 and ACE2 may have consequences for skeletal muscle viral susceptibility and myopathies. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2020;129:864&#x2013;867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32673162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohn MK, Hall A, Sepiashvili L, Jung B, Steele S, Adeli K. Pathophysiology of COVID-19: mechanisms underlying disease severity and progression. Physiology (Bethesda) 2020;35:288&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7426542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32783610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez A, Orozco-Aguilar J, Achiardi O, Simon F, Cabello-Verrugio C. SARS-CoV-2/Renin-angiotensin system: deciphering the clues for a couple with potentially harmful effects on skeletal muscle. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:7904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7663203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33114359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M, Kleine-Weber H, Schroeder S, Kr&#xfc;ger N, Herrler T, Erichsen S, Schiergens TS, Herrler G, Wu NH, Nitsche A, M&#xfc;ller MA, Drosten C, P&#xf6;hlmann S. SARS-CoV-2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and is blocked by a clinically proven protease inhibitor. Cell. 2020;181:271&#x2013;280. e278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Valera M, Martinez-Canton M, Gallego-Selles A, Galv&#xe1;n-Alvarez V, Gelabert-Rebato M, Morales-Alamo D, Santana A, Martin-Rodriguez S, Ponce-Gonzalez JG, Larsen S, Losa-Reyna J, Perez-Suarez I, Dorado C, Curtelin D, Gonzalez-Henriquez JJ, Boushel R, Hallen J, de Pablos Velasco P, Freixinet-Gilart J, Holmberg HC, Helge JW, Martin-Rincon M, Calbet JAL. Angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (SARS-CoV-2 receptor) expression in human skeletal muscle. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31:2249&#x2013;2258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34551157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hikmet F, M&#xe9;ar L, Edvinsson &#xc5;, Micke P, Uhl&#xe9;n M, Lindskog C. The protein expression profile of ACE2 in human tissues. Mol Syst Biol. 2020;16:e9610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Z, de Vries HJ, Vlaar APJ, van der Hoeven J, Boon RA, Heunks LMA, Ottenheijm CAC Dutch COVID-19 Diaphragm Investigators. Diaphragm pathology in critically ill patients with COVID-19 and postmortem findings from 3 medical centers. JAMA Intern Med. 2021;181:122&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7670391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33196760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suh J, Mukerji SS, Collens SI, Padera RF Jr, Pinkus GS, Amato AA, Solomon IH. Skeletal muscle and peripheral nerve histopathology in COVID-19. Neurology. 2021;97:e849&#x2013;e858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34099523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzano GS, Woods JK, Amato AA. Covid-19-associated myopathy caused by type I interferonopathy. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:2389&#x2013;2390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7722689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33216474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrag&#xe1;n-Iglesias P, Franco-Enz&#xe1;stiga &#xda;, Jeevakumar V, Shiers S, Wangzhou A, Granados-Soto V, Campbell ZT, Dussor G, Price TJ. Type I interferons act directly on nociceptors to produce pain sensitization: implications for viral infection-induced pain. J Neurosci. 2020;40:3517&#x2013;3532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7189756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32245829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doykov I, H&#xe4;llqvist J, Gilmour KC, Grandjean L, Mills K, Heywood WE. &#x2018;The long tail of Covid-19&#x2019; - The detection of a prolonged inflammatory response after a SARS-CoV-2 infection in asymptomatic and mildly affected patients. F1000Res. 2020;9:1349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7745182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33391730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colosio M, Brocca L, Gatti MF, Neri M, Crea E, Cadile F, Canepari M, Pellegrino MA, Polla B, Porcelli S, Bottinelli R. Structural and functional impairments of skeletal muscle in patients with postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2023;135:902&#x2013;917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37675472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finsterer J, Scorza FA. Exercise intolerance in post-COVID syndrome cannot only be due to skeletal muscle impairment. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2023;135:1384&#x2013;1385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38051269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polese J, Ramos AD, Moulaz IR, Sant&#x2019;Ana L, Lacerda BSP, Soares CES, Lan&#xe7;a KEM, Thompson BP, J&#xfa;nior GPB, Polese Pinto II, Mill JG. Pulmonary function and exercise capacity six months after hospital discharge of patients with severe COVID-19. Braz J Infect Dis. 2023;27:102789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10403708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37442195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh I, Joseph P, Heerdt PM, Cullinan M, Lutchmansingh DD, Gulati M, Possick JD, Systrom DM, Waxman AB. Persistent exertional intolerance after COVID-19: insights from invasive cardiopulmonary exercise testing. Chest. 2022;161:54&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8354807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34389297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baratto C, Caravita S, Faini A, Perego GB, Senni M, Badano LP, Parati G. Impact of COVID-19 on exercise pathophysiology: a combined cardiopulmonary and echocardiographic exercise study. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2021;130:1470&#x2013;1478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8143785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33764166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boengler K, Kosiol M, Mayr M, Schulz R, Rohrbach S. Mitochondria and ageing: role in heart, skeletal muscle and adipose tissue. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2017;8:349&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5476857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28432755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE, Mohamed JS, Myers MJ. Mitochondria initiate and regulate sarcopenia. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2017;45:58&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5357179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28098577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Ot&#xed;n C, Blasco MA, Partridge L, Serrano M, Kroemer G. The hallmarks of aging. Cell. 2013;153:1194&#x2013;1217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3836174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23746838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB, Howe A, Munier CML, Patel SK, Juno JA, Burrell LM, Kent SJ, Dore GJ, Kelleher AD, Matthews GV. Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Immunol. 2022;23:210&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maamar M, Artime A, Pariente E, Fierro P, Ruiz Y, Guti&#xe9;rrez S, Tobalina M, D&#xed;az-Salazar S, Ramos C, Olmos JM, Hern&#xe1;ndez JL. Post-COVID-19 syndrome, low-grade inflammation and inflammatory markers: a cross-sectional study. Curr Med Res Opin. 2022;38:901&#x2013;909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8935459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35166141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cicco S, Cicco G, Racanelli V, Vacca A. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) and damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs): two potential targets for COVID-19 treatment. Mediators Inflamm. 2020;2020:7527953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7366221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32724296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coperchini F, Chiovato L, Croce L, Magri F, Rotondi M. The cytokine storm in COVID-19: an overview of the involvement of the chemokine/chemokine-receptor system. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2020;53:25&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32446778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens EM, Koretzky GA. Review: cytokine storm syndrome: looking toward the precision medicine era. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2017;69:1135&#x2013;1143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28217930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azkur AK, Akdis M, Azkur D, Sokolowska M, van de Veen W, Br&#xfc;ggen MC, O&#x2019;Mahony L, Gao Y, Nadeau K, Akdis CA. Immune response to SARS-CoV-2 and mechanisms of immunopathological changes in COVID-19. Allergy. 2020;75:1564&#x2013;1581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32396996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soy M, Keser G, Atag&#xfc;nd&#xfc;z P, Tabak F, Atag&#xfc;nd&#xfc;z I, Kayhan S. Cytokine storm in COVID-19: pathogenesis and overview of anti-inflammatory agents used in treatment. Clin Rheumatol. 2020;39:2085&#x2013;2094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7260446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32474885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Zhao Y, Zhang F, Wang Q, Li T, Liu Z, Wang J, Qin Y, Zhang X, Yan X, Zeng X, Zhang S. The use of anti-inflammatory drugs in the treatment of people with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): the perspectives of clinical immunologists from China. Clin Immunol. 2020;214:108393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32222466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Authier FJ, Chazaud B, Plonquet A, Eliezer-Vanerot MC, Poron F, Belec L, Barlovatz-Meimon G, Gherardi RK. Differential expression of the IL-1 system components during in vitro myogenesis: implication of IL-1beta in induction of myogenic cell apoptosis. Cell Death Differ. 1999;6:1012&#x2013;1021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10556979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forcina L, Miano C, Scicchitano BM, Rizzuto E, Berardinelli MG, De Benedetti F, Pelosi L, Musar&#xf2; A. Increased circulating levels of interleukin-6 affect the redox balance in skeletal muscle. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2019;2019:3018584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6881749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31827671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang H, Pang S, Wang M, Xiao X, Rong Y, Wang H, Zang YQ. TLR4 activation is required for IL-17-induced multiple tissue inflammation and wasting in mice. J Immunol. 2010;185:2563&#x2013;2569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20631308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid MB, Li YP. Tumor necrosis factor-alpha and muscle wasting: a cellular perspective. Respir Res. 2001;2:269&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC59514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11686894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanderVeen BN, Fix DK, Montalvo RN, Counts BR, Smuder AJ, Murphy EA, Koh HJ, Carson JA. The regulation of skeletal muscle fatigability and mitochondrial function by chronically elevated interleukin-6. Exp Physiol. 2019;104:385&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6750733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30576589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swarnakar R, Jenifa S, Wadhwa S. Musculoskeletal complications in long COVID-19: a systematic review. World J Virol. 2022;11:485&#x2013;495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9724204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36483107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran EM, Mastaglia FL. Cytokines in immune-mediated inflammatory myopathies: cellular sources, multiple actions and therapeutic implications. Clin Exp Immunol. 2014;178:405&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4238868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25171057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hund E. Neurological complications of sepsis: critical illness polyneuropathy and myopathy. J Neurol. 2001;248:929&#x2013;934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11757954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batiha GE, Al-Kuraishy HM, Al-Gareeb AI, Welson NN. Pathophysiology of post-COVID syndromes: a new perspective. Virol J. 2022;19:158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9548310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36210445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akin C, Valent P, Metcalfe DD. Mast cell activation syndrome: proposed diagnostic criteria. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2010;126:1099&#x2013;1104. e1094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3753019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21035176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akin C. Mast cell activation syndromes. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2017;140:349&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28780942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komi DEA, Khomtchouk K, Santa Maria PL. A review of the contribution of mast cells in wound healing: involved molecular and cellular mechanisms. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2020;58:298&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30729428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dina OA, Green PG, Levine JD. Role of interleukin-6 in chronic muscle hyperalgesic priming. Neuroscience. 2008;152:521&#x2013;525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2336107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18280048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manjavachi MN, Motta EM, Marotta DM, Leite DFP, Calixto JB. Mechanisms involved in IL-6-induced muscular mechanical hyperalgesia in mice. Pain. 2010;151:345&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20709454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Wu Z, Li JW, Zhao H, Wang GQ. Cytokine release syndrome in severe COVID-19: interleukin-6 receptor antagonist tocilizumab may be the key to reduce mortality. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2020;55:105954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32234467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes-Long S, Cort&#xe9;s-Altamirano JL, Bandala C, Avenda&#xf1;o-Ortiz K, Bonilla-Jaime H, Bueno-Nava A, &#xc1;vila-Luna A, S&#xe1;nchez-Aparicio P, Clavijo-Cornejo D, Dotor-LLerena AL, Cabrera-Ruiz E, Alfaro-Rodr&#xed;guez A. Role of the microRNAs in the pathogenic mechanism of painful symptoms in long COVID: systematic review. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24:3574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9963913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36834984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva CC, Bichara CNC, Carneiro FRO, Palacios VRDCM, Berg AVSVD, Quaresma JAS, Magno Falc&#xe3;o LF. Muscle dysfunction in the long coronavirus disease 2019 syndrome: pathogenesis and clinical approach. Rev Med Virol. 2022;32:e2355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9111061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35416359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, Boirie Y, Bruy&#xe8;re O, Cederholm T, Cooper C, Landi F, Rolland Y, Sayer AA, Schneider SM, Sieber CC, Topinkova E, Vandewoude M, Visser M, Zamboni M Writing Group for the European Working Group on Sarcopenia in Older People 2 (EWGSOP2), and the Extended Group for EWGSOP2. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48:601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6593317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31081853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landi F, Calvani R, Martone AM, Salini S, Zazzara MB, Candeloro M, Coelho-Junior HJ, Tosato M, Picca A, Marzetti E. Normative values of muscle strength across ages in a &#x2018;real world&#x2019; population: results from the longevity check-up 7+ project. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2020;11:1562&#x2013;1569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7749608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33147374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil S, de Oliveira J&#xfa;nior GN, Sarti FM, Filho WJ, Longobardi I, Turri JAO, Shinjo SK, Ferriolli E, Avelino-Silva TJ, Busse AL, Gualano B, Roschel H. Acute muscle mass loss predicts long-term fatigue, myalgia, and health care costs in COVID-19 survivors. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2023;24:10&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9682050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36493804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agergaard J, Leth S, Pedersen TH, Harbo T, Blicher JU, Karlsson P, &#xd8;stergaard L, Andersen H, Tankisi H. Myopathic changes in patients with long-term fatigue after COVID-19. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132:1974&#x2013;1981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8102077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34020890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannah JR, Ali SS, Nagra D, Adas MA, Buazon AD, Galloway JB, Gordon PA. Skeletal muscles and Covid-19: a systematic review of rhabdomyolysis and myositis in SARS-CoV-2 infection. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2022;40:329&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35225218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony S, Phrathep DD, El-Husari A, Ismaili A, Healey KD, Scott R. Post-COVID-19 polymyositis: a case report. Cureus. 2022;14:e30991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9715395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36475159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin S, Rahim F, Noor M, Bangash A, Ghani F. Polymyositis: the comet tail after COVID-19. Cureus. 2022;14:e26453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9338774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35915688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saif DS, Ibrahem RA, Eltabl MA. Prevalence of peripheral neuropathy and myopathy in patients post-COVID-19 infection. Int J Rheum Dis. 2022;25:1246&#x2013;1253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35915515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megremis S, Walker TDJ, He X, Ollier WER, Chinoy H, Hampson L, Hampson I, Lamb JA. Antibodies against immunogenic epitopes with high sequence identity to SARS-CoV-2 in patients with autoimmune dermatomyositis. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79:1383&#x2013;1386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7509518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32444414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lokineni S, Mortezavi M. Delayed-onset necrotizing myositis following COVID-19 infection. Eur J Case Rep Intern Med. 2021;8:002461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8112084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33987125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hejb&#xf8;l EK, Harbo T, Agergaard J, Madsen LB, Pedersen TH, &#xd8;stergaard LJ, Andersen H, Schr&#xf8;der HD, Tankisi H. Myopathy as a cause of fatigue in long-term post-COVID-19 symptoms: evidence of skeletal muscle histopathology. Eur J Neurol. 2022;29:2832&#x2013;2841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9348124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35661354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerma LA, Chaudhary A, Bryan A, Morishima C, Wener MH, Fink SL. Prevalence of autoantibody responses in acute coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) J Transl Autoimmun. 2020;3:100073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7691817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33263103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapkota HR, Nune A. Long COVID from rheumatology perspective - a narrative review. Clin Rheumatol. 2022;41:337&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8629735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34845562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng Y, Ma Q, Du YS, Peng N, Yang T, Zhang SY, Wu FF, Lin HL, Su L. Rhabdomyolysis is associated with in-hospital mortality in patients with COVID-19. Shock. 2021;56:360&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8354485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33443364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He YC, Chen F. Rhabdomyolysis as potential late complication associated with COVID-19. Emerg Infect Dis. 2020;26:2297&#x2013;2298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32818421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Shan KS, Minalyan A, O&#x2019;Sullivan C, Nace T. A rare presentation of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) induced viral myositis with subsequent rhabdomyolysis. Cureus. 2020;12:e8074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7290109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32542129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merbouh M, El Aidouni G, Serbource J, Couprie LM, Bernardoni C, Housni B, Monchi M. Isolated severe rhabdomyolisis revealing COVID-19: case report. Oxf Med Case Reports. 2022;2022:omac039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35619684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suh J, Amato AA. Neuromuscular complications of coronavirus disease-19. Curr Opin Neurol. 2021;34:669&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8452251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34155186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam B, Ahmed M, Islam Z, Begum SM. Severe acute myopathy following SARS-CoV-2 infection: a case report and review of recent literature. Skelet Muscle. 2021;11:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8058144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33883014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finsterer J, Scorza F. SARS-CoV-2 associated rhabdomyolysis in 32 patients. Turk J Med Sci. 2021;51:1598&#x2013;1601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8283436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33576584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan A, Stepien KM, Narayana STK. Carnitine palmitoyltransferase II deficiency and post-COVID vaccination rhabdomyolysis. QJM. 2021;114:596&#x2013;597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8083200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33871650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wongkittichote P, Watson JR, Leonard JM, Toolan ER, Dickson PI, Grange DK. Fatal COVID-19 infection in a patient with long-chain 3-hydroxyacyl-CoA dehydrogenase deficiency: a case report. JIMD Rep. 2020;56:40&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7653242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33204595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ftiha F, Shalom M, Jradeh H. Neurological symptoms due to Coronavirus disease 2019. Neurol Int. 2020;12:8639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32874447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M, Hu Y, Chen S, He Q, Chang J, Hong C, Zhou Y, Wang D, Miao X, Li Y, Hu B. Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:683&#x2013;690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7149362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuberb&#xfc;hler P, Conti ME, Le&#xf3;n-Cejas L, Maximiliano-Gonz&#xe1;lez F, Bonardo P, Miquelini A, Halfon J, Mart&#xed;nez J, Guti&#xe9;rrez MV, Reisin R. Guillain-Barre syndrome associated to COVID-19 infection: a review of published case reports. Rev Neurol. 2021;72:203&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33710610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond KB, Weisberg MD, Ng MK, Erez O, Edelstein D. COVID-19 peripheral neuropathy: a report of three cases. Cureus. 2021;13:e18132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8525663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34692341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bureau BL, Obeidat A, Dhariwal MS, Jha P. Peripheral neuropathy as a complication of SARS-Cov-2. Cureus. 2020;12:e11452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7673277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33214969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andalib S, Biller J, Di Napoli M, Moghimi N, McCullough LD, Rubinos CA, O&#x2019;Hana Nobleza C, Azarpazhooh MR, Catanese L, Elicer I, Jafari M, Liberati F, Camejo C, Torbey M, Divani AA. Peripheral nervous system manifestations associated with COVID-19. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2021;21:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7882462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33586020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JJ, Zhang QF, Liu D, Du Q, Xu C, Wu QX, Tang Y, Jin WS. Self-reported neurological symptoms two years after hospital discharge among COVID-19 survivors. J Alzheimers Dis Rep. 2023;7:1127&#x2013;1132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10657710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38025798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel UK, Mehta N, Patel A, Patel N, Ortiz JF, Khurana M, Urhoghide E, Parulekar A, Bhriguvanshi A, Patel N, Mistry AM, Patel R, Arumaithurai K, Shah S. Long-term neurological sequelae among severe COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cureus. 2022;14:e29694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9616013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36321004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon IH, Normandin E, Bhattacharyya S, Mukerji SS, Keller K, Ali AS, Adams G, Hornick JL, Padera RF Jr, Sabeti P. Neuropathological features of Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:989&#x2013;992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7304421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brann DH, Tsukahara T, Weinreb C, Lipovsek M, Van den Berge K, Gong B, Chance R, Macaulay IC, Chou HJ, Fletcher RB, Das D, Street K, de Bezieux HR, Choi YG, Risso D, Dudoit S, Purdom E, Mill J, Hachem RA, Matsunami H, Logan DW, Goldstein BJ, Grubb MS, Ngai J, Datta SR. Non-neuronal expression of SARS-CoV-2 entry genes in the olfactory system suggests mechanisms underlying COVID-19-associated anosmia. Sci Adv. 2020;6:eabc5801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10715684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32937591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke J, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Hagel C, Sperhake JP, Schr&#xf6;der AS, Edler C, Mushumba H, Fitzek A, Allweiss L, Dandri M, Dottermusch M, Heinemann A, Pfefferle S, Schwabenland M, Sumner Magruder D, Bonn S, Prinz M, Gerloff C, P&#xfc;schel K, Krasemann S, Aepfelbacher M, Glatzel M. Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19:919&#x2013;929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7535629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang YH, Jiang D, Huang JT. SARS-CoV-2 detected in cerebrospinal fluid by PCR in a case of COVID-19 encephalitis. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7202824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriguchi T, Harii N, Goto J, Harada D, Sugawara H, Takamino J, Ueno M, Sakata H, Kondo K, Myose N, Nakao A, Takeda M, Haro H, Inoue O, Suzuki-Inoue K, Kubokawa K, Ogihara S, Sasaki T, Kinouchi H, Kojin H, Ito M, Onishi H, Shimizu T, Sasaki Y, Enomoto N, Ishihara H, Furuya S, Yamamoto T, Shimada S. A first case of meningitis/encephalitis associated with SARS-Coronavirus-2. Int J Infect Dis. 2020;94:55&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paniz-Mondolfi A, Bryce C, Grimes Z, Gordon RE, Reidy J, Lednicky J, Sordillo EM, Fowkes M. Central nervous system involvement by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) J Med Virol. 2020;92:699&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32314810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J, Radke J, Dittmayer C, Franz J, Thomas C, Mothes R, Laue M, Schneider J, Br&#xfc;nink S, Greuel S, Lehmann M, Hassan O, Aschman T, Schumann E, Chua RL, Conrad C, Eils R, Stenzel W, Windgassen M, R&#xf6;&#xdf;ler L, Goebel HH, Gelderblom HR, Martin H, Nitsche A, Schulz-Schaeffer WJ, Hakroush S, Winkler MS, Tampe B, Scheibe F, K&#xf6;rtv&#xe9;lyessy P, Reinhold D, Siegmund B, K&#xfc;hl AA, Elezkurtaj S, Horst D, Oesterhelweg L, Tsokos M, Ingold-Heppner B, Stadelmann C, Drosten C, Corman VM, Radbruch H, Heppner FL. Olfactory transmucosal SARS-CoV-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with COVID-19. Nat Neurosci. 2021;24:168&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolebeyan AS, Zhang N, Cooper V, Kuruvilla DE. Headache in patients with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection: a narrative review. Headache. 2020;60:2131&#x2013;2138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33017479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerkman JN, Daffertshofer A, Gollo LL, Breakspear M, Boonstra TW. Network structure of the human musculoskeletal system shapes neural interactions on multiple time scales. Sci Adv. 2018;4:eaat0497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6021138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29963631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mense S. The pathogenesis of muscle pain. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 2003;7:419&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14604500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moy JK, Khoutorsky A, Asiedu MN, Black BJ, Kuhn JL, Barrag&#xe1;n-Iglesias P, Megat S, Burton MD, Burgos-Vega CC, Melemedjian OK, Boitano S, Vagner J, Gkogkas CG, Pancrazio JJ, Mogil JS, Dussor G, Sonenberg N, Price TJ. The MNK-eIF4E signaling axis contributes to injury-induced nociceptive plasticity and the development of chronic pain. J Neurosci. 2017;37:7481&#x2013;7499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5546114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28674170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mody PH, Dos Santos NL, Barron LR, Price TJ, Burton MD. eIF4E phosphorylation modulates pain and neuroinflammation in the aged. Geroscience. 2020;42:1663&#x2013;1674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7732936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moy JK, Khoutorsky A, Asiedu MN, Dussor G, Price TJ. eIF4E phosphorylation influences Bdnf mRNA translation in mouse dorsal root ganglion neurons. Front Cell Neurosci. 2018;12:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5808250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29467623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bocci T, Bertini A, Campiglio L, Botta S, Libelli G, Guidetti M, Priori A. Not myopathic, but autonomic changes in patients with long-COVID syndrome: a case series. Neurol Sci. 2023;44:1147&#x2013;1153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9896447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36735149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams RMC, Simpson DM, Navis A, Jette N, Zhou L, Shin SC. Small fiber neuropathy associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Muscle Nerve. 2022;65:440&#x2013;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34766365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieco T, Gomes V, Rossi A, Cantisani C, Greco ME, Rossi G, Sernicola A, Pellacani G. The pathological culprit of neuropathic skin pain in long COVID-19 patients: a case series. J Clin Med. 2022;11:4474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9369885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35956094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott MG, Allawi Z, Hofer M, Ansorge O, Brady S, Fadic R, Torres G, Knight R, Calvo M, Bennett DLH, Themistocleous AC. Acute small fiber neuropathy after Oxford-AstraZeneca ChAdOx1-S vaccination: a report of three cases and review of the literature. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2022;27:325&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35962630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinyes D, Mu&#xf1;oz-Sellart M, Caballero TG. Local anesthetics as a therapeutic tool for post COVID-19 patients: a case report. Medicine (Baltimore) 2022;101:e29358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11132361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35839020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravi B, Li Z, Lang CN, Schmid B, Lang FK, Grad S, Alini M, Richards RG, Schmal H, S&#xfc;dkamp N, Lang GM. The tissue renin-angiotensin system and its role in the pathogenesis of major human diseases: quo vadis? Cells. 2021;10:650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7999456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33804069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khazaal S, Harb J, Rima M, Annweiler C, Wu Y, Cao Z, Abi Khattar Z, Legros C, Kovacic H, Fajloun Z, Sabatier JM. The pathophysiology of long COVID throughout the renin-angiotensin system. Molecules. 2022;27:2903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9101946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35566253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twisk FN, Maes M. A review on cognitive behavorial therapy (CBT) and graded exercise therapy (GET) in myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME)/chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS): CBT/GET is not only ineffective and not evidence-based, but also potentially harmful for many patients with ME/CFS. Neuro Endocrinol Lett. 2009;30:284&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19855350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aul DR, Gates DJ, Draper DA, Dunleavy DA, Ruickbie DS, Meredith DH, Walters DN, van Zeller DC, Taylor DV, Bridgett DM, Dunwoody DR, Grubnic DS, Jacob DT, Ean Ong DY. Complications after discharge with COVID-19 infection and risk factors associated with development of post-COVID pulmonary fibrosis. Respir Med. 2021;188:106602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8425673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34536697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Husinat L, Nusir M, Al-Gharaibeh H, Alomari AA, Smadi MM, Battaglini D, Pelosi P. Post-COVID-19 syndrome symptoms after mild and moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022;9:1017257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9573938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36262270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xe8;nech-Montoliu S, Puig-Barber&#xe0; J, Pac-Sa MR, Vidal-Utrillas P, Latorre-Poveda M, Rio-Gonz&#xe1;lez AD, Ferrando-Rubert S, Ferrer-Abad G, S&#xe1;nchez-Urbano M, Aparisi-Esteve L, Badenes-Marques G, Cervera-Ferrer B, Clerig-Arnau U, Dols-Bernad C, Fontal-Carcel M, Gomez-Lanas L, Jovani-Sales D, Le&#xf3;n-Domingo MC, Llopico-Vilanova MD, Moros-Blasco M, Notari-Rodr&#xed;guez C, Ru&#xed;z-Puig R, Valls-L&#xf3;pez S, Arnedo-Pena A. ABO Blood Groups and the incidence of complications in COVID-19 patients: a population-based prospective cohort study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:10039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8507737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34639344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayaaslan B, Eser F, Kalem AK, Kaya G, Kaplan B, Kacar D, Hasanoglu I, Coskun B, Guner R. Post-COVID syndrome: a single-center questionnaire study on 1007 participants recovered from COVID-19. J Med Virol. 2021;93:6566&#x2013;6574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8426910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34255355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Choi T, Al-Aly Z. Association of treatment with Nirmatrelvir and the risk of post-COVID-19 condition. JAMA Intern Med. 2023;183:554&#x2013;564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10037200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Choi T, Al-Aly Z. Molnupiravir and risk of post-acute sequelae of covid-19: cohort study. BMJ. 2023;381:e074572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10126525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37161995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Q, Lau RI, Liu Q, Chan FKL, Ng SC. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and gut dysbiosis linger beyond 1 year after SARS-CoV-2 clearance. Gut. 2023;72:1230&#x2013;1232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35940857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor RJ, Preston N, Parkin A, Makower S, Ross D, Gee J, Halpin SJ, Horton M, Sivan M. The COVID-19 Yorkshire Rehabilitation Scale (C19-YRS): application and psychometric analysis in a post-COVID-19 syndrome cohort. J Med Virol. 2022;94:1027&#x2013;1034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34676578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz Gokmen G, Durmaz D, Demir C, Yilmaz FN. Determining post-COVID-19 symptoms and rehabilitation needs in hospitalized and nonhospitalized COVID-19 survivors with tele-assessment methods. Telemed J E Health. 2023;29:1312&#x2013;1323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36757300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Boon GJAM, Barco S, Endres M, Geelhoed JJM, Knauss S, Rezek SA, Spruit MA, Vehreschild J, Siegerink B. The Post-COVID-19 Functional Status scale: a tool to measure functional status over time after COVID-19. Eur Respir J. 2020;56:2001494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith P, De Pauw R, Van Cauteren D, Demarest S, Drieskens S, Cornelissen L, Devleesschauwer B, De Ridder K, Charafeddine R. Post COVID-19 condition and health-related quality of life: a longitudinal cohort study in the Belgian adult population. BMC Public Health. 2023;23:1433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10373376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37495947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Abell&#xe1;n J, Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Padilla S, Garc&#xed;a JA, Agull&#xf3; V, Lozano V, Ena N, Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;nchez L, Guti&#xe9;rrez F, Masi&#xe1; M. Immunologic phenotype of patients with long-COVID syndrome of 1-year duration. Front Immunol. 2022;13:920627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9451924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36090973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Zhou Y, Ma Y, Chen P, Tang J, Yang B, Li H, Liang M, Xue Y, Liu Y, Zhang J, Wang X. Gut microbiota dysbiosis correlates with long COVID-19 at one-year after discharge. J Korean Med Sci. 2023;38:e120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10111044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37069814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterbury S. Post-COVID conditions-What practitioners need to know. Nurse Pract. 2021;46:44&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34695052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sar&#x131;o&#x11f;lu N, Aksu GD, &#xc7;oban H, B&#xfc;lb&#xfc;l E, Demirpolat G, Arslan AT, Erel F. Clinical and radiological outcomes of longCOVID: is the post-COVID fibrosis common? Tuberk Toraks. 2023;71:48&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10795271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36912409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gameil MA, Marzouk RE, Elsebaie AH, Rozaik SE. Long-term clinical and biochemical residue after COVID-19 recovery. Egypt Liver J. 2021;11:74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8435147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34777873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, Villapol S. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021;11:16144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, Brown JS, Denneny EK, Hare SS, Heightman M, Hillman TE, Jacob J, Jarvis HC, Lipman MCI, Naidu SB, Nair A, Porter JC, Tomlinson GS, Hurst JR ARC Study Group. &#x2018;Long-COVID&#x2019;: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#xe5;hl&#xe9;n K, Ernberg M, Kosek E, Mannerkorpi K, Gerdle B, Ghafouri B. Significant correlation between plasma proteome profile and pain intensity, sensitivity, and psychological distress in women with fibromyalgia. Sci Rep. 2020;10:12508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32719459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luyendyk JP, Schoenecker JG, Flick MJ. The multifaceted role of fibrinogen in tissue injury and inflammation. Blood. 2019;133:511&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6367649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30523120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanobashvili J, Neumayer C, F&#xfc;gl A, Punz A, Blumer R, Prager M, Mittlb&#xf6;ck M, Gruber H, Polterauer P, Roth E, Malinski T, Huk I. Ischemia/reperfusion injury of skeletal muscle: plasma taurine as a measure of tissue damage. Surgery. 2003;133:91&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12563243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Amato A. Electrodiagnostic evaluation of myopathies. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am. 2013;24:193&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4435557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23177039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versace V, Sebastianelli L, Ferrazzoli D, Saltuari L, Kofler M, L&#xf6;scher W, Uncini A. Case report: myopathy in critically ill COVID-19 patients: a consequence of hyperinflammation? Front Neurol. 2021;12:625144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7878532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33584530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittaker A, Anson M, Harky A. Neurological Manifestations of COVID-19: a systematic review and current update. Acta Neurol Scand. 2020;142:14&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7273036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32412088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kissel JT. Muscle biopsy in patients with myalgia: still a painful decision. Neurology. 2007;68:170&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17224566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramani SL, Samet J, Franz CK, Hsieh C, Nguyen CV, Horbinski C, Deshmukh S. Musculoskeletal involvement of COVID-19: review of imaging. Skeletal Radiol. 2021;50:1763&#x2013;1773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7889306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33598718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revzin MV, Raza S, Srivastava NC, Warshawsky R, D&#x2019;Agostino C, Malhotra A, Bader AS, Patel RD, Chen K, Kyriakakos C, Pellerito JS. Multisystem imaging manifestations of COVID-19, part 2: from cardiac complications to pediatric manifestations. Radiographics. 2020;40:1866&#x2013;1892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7646410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33136488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smitaman E, Flores DV, Mej&#xed;a G&#xf3;mez C, Pathria MN. MR imaging of atraumatic muscle disorders. Radiographics. 2018;38:500&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29451848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty ND, Dhande RP, Nagendra V, Unadkat BS, Shelar SS. Post-COVID-19 myositis based on magnetic resonance imaging: a case report. Cureus. 2022;14:e30293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9657587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36407178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehan WA, Yoon BC, Lang M, Li MD, Rincon S, Buch K. Paraspinal myositis in patients with COVID-19 infection. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2020;41:1949&#x2013;1952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7661075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32763902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippetti L, Pace N, Louis JS, Mandry D, Goehringer F, Rocher MS, Jay N, Selton-Suty C, Hossu G, Huttin O, Marie PY. Long-lasting myocardial and skeletal muscle damage evidenced by serial CMR during the first year in COVID-19 patients from the first wave. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9:831580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8959613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35355964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ercegovac M, Asanin M, Savic-Radojevic A, Ranin J, Matic M, Djukic T, Coric V, Jerotic D, Todorovic N, Milosevic I, Stevanovic G, Simic T, Bukumiric Z, Pljesa-Ercegovac M. Antioxidant genetic profile modifies probability of developing neurological sequelae in Long-COVID. Antioxidants (Basel) 2022;11:954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9138155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35624818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathore FA, Khalil MT, Khan OJ. Rehabilitation perspectives in long COVID-19. J Pak Med Assoc. 2023;73:1553&#x2013;1555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37469084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galluzzo V, Zazzara MB, Ciciarello F, Tosato M, Bizzarro A, Paglionico A, Varriano V, Gremese E, Calvani R, Landi F Gemelli against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Team. Use of first-line oral analgesics during and after COVID-19: results from a survey on a sample of Italian 696 COVID-19 survivors with post-acute symptoms. J Clin Med. 2023;12:2992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10142362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37109328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ripani U, Bisaccia M, Meccariello L. Dexamethasone and nutraceutical therapy can reduce the myalgia due to COVID-19 - a systemic review of the active substances that can reduce the expression of interlukin-6. Med Arch. 2022;76:66&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8976893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35422571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarzi-Puttini P, Giorgi V, Marotto D, Atzeni F. Fibromyalgia: an update on clinical characteristics, aetiopathogenesis and treatment. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2020;16:645&#x2013;660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pektas S, Gursoy C, Demirbilek SG. The use of pregabalin in intensive care unit in the treatment of Covid-19-related pain and cough. J Coll Physicians Surg Pak. 2021;31:143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34271819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slee A, Nazareth I, Bondaronek P, Liu Y, Cheng Z, Freemantle N. Pharmacological treatments for generalised anxiety disorder: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Lancet. 2019;393:768&#x2013;777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30712879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vertigan AE, Kapela SL, Ryan NM, Birring SS, McElduff P, Gibson PG. Pregabalin and speech pathology combination therapy for refractory chronic cough: a randomized controlled trial. Chest. 2016;149:639&#x2013;648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26447687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aksan F, Nelson EA, Swedish KA. A COVID-19 patient with intense burning pain. J Neurovirol. 2020;26:800&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7416991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32779108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravagnan G, De Filippis A, Carten&#xec; M, De Maria S, Cozza V, Petrazzuolo M, Tufano MA, Donnarumma G. Polydatin, a natural precursor of resveratrol, induces &#x3b2;-defensin production and reduces inflammatory response. Inflammation. 2013;36:26&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22956122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardinali DP, Brown GM, Pandi-Perumal SR. Possible application of melatonin in long COVID. Biomolecules. 2022;12:1646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9687267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36358996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galano A, Tan DX, Reiter RJ. Melatonin as a natural ally against oxidative stress: a physicochemical examination. J Pineal Res. 2011;51:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21752095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boonstra A, Barrat FJ, Crain C, Heath VL, Savelkoul HF, O&#x2019;Garra A. 1alpha,25-Dihydroxyvitamin d3 has a direct effect on naive CD4(+) T cells to enhance the development of Th2 cells. J Immunol. 2001;167:4974&#x2013;4980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11673504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fawaz L, Mrad MF, Kazan JM, Sayegh S, Akika R, Khoury SJ. Comparative effect of 25(OH)D3 and 1,25(OH)2D3 on Th17 cell differentiation. Clin Immunol. 2016;166-167:59&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27041081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranisavljev M, Todorovic N, Ostojic J, Ostojic SM. Reduced tissue creatine levels in patients with long COVID-19: a cross-sectional study. J Postgrad Med. 2023;69:162&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10394531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37171415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Mak JWY, Su Q, Yeoh YK, Lui GC, Ng SSS, Zhang F, Li AYL, Lu W, Hui DS, Chan PK, Chan FKL, Ng SC. Gut microbiota dynamics in a prospective cohort of patients with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Gut. 2022;71:544&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Xu Z, Mak JWY, Chow KM, Lui G, Li TCM, Wong CK, Chan PKS, Ching JYL, Fujiwara Y, Chan FKL, Ng SC. Gut microbiota-derived synbiotic formula (SIM01) as a novel adjuvant therapy for COVID-19: an open-label pilot study. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;37:823&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35170078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau RI, Su Q, Lau ISF, Ching JYL, Wong MCS, Lau LHS, Tun HM, Mok CKP, Chau SWH, Tse YK, Cheung CP, Li MKT, Yeung GTY, Cheong PK, Chan FKL, Ng SC. A synbiotic preparation (SIM01) for post-acute COVID-19 syndrome in Hong Kong (RECOVERY): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Infect Dis. 2024;24:256&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38071990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zha M, Chaffee K, Alsarraj J. Trigger point injections and dry needling can be effective in treating long COVID syndrome-related myalgia: a case report. J Med Case Rep. 2022;16:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8763132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35039086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galluzzo V, Zazzara MB, Ciciarello F, Tosato M, Martone AM, Pais C, Savera G, Calvani R, Picca A, Marzetti E, Landi F On Behalf Of Gemelli Against Covid-Post-Acute Care Team. Inadequate physical activity is associated with worse physical function in a sample of COVID-19 survivors with post-acute symptoms. J Clin Med. 2023;12:2517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10095156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37048602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouzigon R, Dupuy O, Tiemessen I, De Nardi M, Bernard JP, Mihailovic T, Theurot D, Miller ED, Lombardi G, Dugu&#xe9; BM. Cryostimulation for post-exercise recovery in athletes: a consensus and position paper. Front Sports Act Living. 2021;3:688828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8652002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34901847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobbi M, Trotti G, Tanzi M, Kasap F, Piter&#xe0; P, Capodaglio P. Post-COVID symptoms and whole-body cryotheraphy: a case report. J Rehabil Med Clin Commun. 2022;5:1000075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8771767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35154582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis J, Theurot D, Filliard JR, Volondat M, Dugu&#xe9; B, Dupuy O. The use of whole-body cryotherapy: time- and dose-response investigation on circulating blood catecholamines and heart rate variability. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020;120:1733&#x2013;1743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7340648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32474683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capodaglio P, Cremascoli R, Piter&#xe0; P, Fontana JM. Whole-body cryostimulation: a rehabilitation booster. J Rehabil Med Clin Commun. 2022;5:2810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9495643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36189129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras-Brice&#xf1;o F, Espinosa-Ram&#xed;rez M, Rozenberg D, Reid WD. Eccentric training in pulmonary rehabilitation of post-COVID-19 patients: an alternative for improving the functional capacity, inflammation, and oxidative stress. Biology (Basel) 2022;11:1446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9598133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36290350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>