<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36605094</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1841-0413</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Europe's journal of psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Network Perspective on Neuropsychiatric and Cognitive Symptoms of the Post-COVID Syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>350</StartPage><EndPage>356</EndPage><MedlinePgn>350-356</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5964/ejop.10097</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Many patients that were infected with SARS-CoV-2 experience cognitive and affective symptoms weeks and months after their acute COVID-19 disease, even when acute symptoms were mild to moderate. For these patients, purely neurological explanations are struggling to explain the development and maintenance of the great variety of neuropsychiatric and cognitive symptoms occurring after COVID-19. We provide a psychological perspective based on the network theory of mental disorders as an added explanation that does not displace neurological mechanism but rather complements them. We suggest viewing the SARS-CoV-2 infection as a trigger that first activates nodes in a causally connected network of neuropsychiatric and cognitive symptoms. In the following, activation will spread throughout the network that will get in a self-sustaining stable and dysfunctional state manifesting in ongoing symptoms known as post-COVID-19 syndrome. The network perspective allows to generalize explanations for persistent neuropsychiatric and cognitive symptoms to patients that experienced mild or moderate acute courses of COVID-19, but also to similar phenomena following other viral infections. In addition, it could explain why some symptoms did not occur during acute COVID-19, but develop weeks or months after it. This network perspective shifts the focus from viewing persistent symptoms as a continuation of COVID-19 to acknowledging it as a complex syndrome that indeed originates from the disease but fully unfolds after it (post-COVID). To test the presented network perspective, we will need extensive cross-sectional as well as longitudinal data on cognitive and neuropsychiatric symptoms in post-COVID patients.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scharfenberg</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology &amp; Gender Studies, Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostic and Intervention (CeNDI), Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schild</LastName><ForeName>Ann-Katrin</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Warnke</LastName><ForeName>Clemens</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maier</LastName><ForeName>Franziska</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101638700</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1841-0413</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain fog</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive deficits</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-vac syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>CW received personal compensation from BioNTech for participating in an educational discussion. DS, AKS and FM have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36605094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9780734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5964/ejop.10097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ejop.10097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alkodaymi, M. S., Omrani, O. A., Fawzy, N. A., Shaar, B. A., Almamlouk, R., Riaz, M., Obeidat, M., Obeidat, Y., Gerberi, D., Taha, R. M., Kashour, Z., Kashour, T., Berbari, E. F., Alkattan, K., &amp; Tleyjeh, I. M. (2022). Prevalence of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome symptoms at different follow-up periods: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 28(5), 657&#x2013;666. 10.1016/j.cmi.2022.01.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmi.2022.01.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8812092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anapa, G., Roheger, M., Seven, &#xdc;. S., Liebermann-Jordanidis, H., Onur, O. A., Kessler, J., &amp; Kalbe, E. (2021). Effects of sociodemographic variables and depressive symptoms on MoCA test performance in native Germans and Turkish migrants in Germany. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 18(12). Advance online publication. 10.3390/ijerph18126335</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18126335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8296159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34208085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin, M., Schommers, P., Stecher, M., Dewald, F., Gieselmann, L., Gruell, H., Horn, C., Vanshylla, K., Di Cristanziano, V., Osebold, L., Roventa, M., Riaz, T., Tschernoster, N., Altmueller, J., Rose, L., Salomon, S., Priesner, V., Luers, J. C., Albus, C., et al. Lehmann, C. (2021). Post-COVID syndrome in non-hospitalised patients with COVID-19: A longitudinal prospective cohort study. Lancet Regional Health. Europe, 6, e100122. 10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8129613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34027514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beard, C., Millner, A. J., Forgeard, M. J. C., Fried, E. I., Hsu, K. J., Treadway, M. T., Leonard, C. V., Kertz, S. J., &amp; Bj&#xf6;rgvinsson, T. (2016). Network analysis of depression and anxiety symptom relationships in a psychiatric sample. Psychological Medicine, 46(16), 3359&#x2013;3369. 10.1017/S0033291716002300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291716002300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5430082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27623748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker, N. B., Jesus, S. N., Jo&#xe3;o, K. A. D. R., Viseu, J. N., &amp; Martins, R. I. S. (2017). Depression and sleep quality in older adults: A meta-analysis. Psychology, Health and Medicine, 22(8), 889&#x2013;895. 10.1080/13548506.2016.1274042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13548506.2016.1274042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28013552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellan, M., Baricich, A., Patrucco, F., Zeppegno, P., Gramaglia, C., Balbo, P. E., Carriero, A., Amico, C. S., Avanzi, G. C., Barini, M., Battaglia, M., Bor, S., Cantaluppi, V., Cappellano, G., Ceruti, F., Chiocchetti, A., Clivati, E., Giordano, M., Cuneo, D., et al. Pirisi, M. (2021). Long-term sequelae are highly prevalent one year after hospitalization for severe COVID-19. Scientific Reports, 11(1), e22666. 10.1038/s41598-021-01215-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-01215-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8608998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34811387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertuccelli, M., Ciringione, L., Rubega, M., Bisiacchi, P., Masiero, S., &amp; Del Felice, A. (2022). Cognitive impairment in people with previous COVID-19 infection: A scoping review. Cortex, 154, 212&#x2013;230. 10.1016/j.cortex.2022.06.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cortex.2022.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9187867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35780756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsboom, D. (2017). A network theory of mental disorders. World Psychiatry; Official Journal of the World Psychiatric Association, 16(1), 5&#x2013;13. 10.1002/wps.20375</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5269502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28127906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsboom, D., &amp; Cramer, A. O. J. (2013). Network analysis: An integrative approach to the structure of psychopathology. Annual Review of Clinical Psychology, 9, 91&#x2013;121. 10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-050212-185608</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-050212-185608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23537483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsboom, D., Deserno, M. K., Rhemtulla, M., Epskamp, S., Fried, E. I., McNally, R. J., Robinaugh, D. J., Perugini, M., Dalege, J., Costantini, G., Isvoranu, A.-M., Wysocki, A. C., van Borkulo, C. D., van Bork, R., &amp; Waldorp, L. J. (2021). Network analysis of multivariate data in psychological science. Nature Reviews Methods Primers, 1(1). Advance online publication. 10.1038/s43586-021-00055-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43586-021-00055-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, C., Haupert, S. R., Zimmermann, L., Shi, X., Fritsche, L. G., &amp; Mukherjee, B. (2022). Global prevalence of post COVID-19 condition or Long COVID: A meta-analysis and systematic review. Journal of Infectious Diseases. Advance online publication. 10.1093/infdis/jiac136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiac136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couzin-Frankel, J., &amp; Vogel, G. (2022). Vaccines may cause rare, Long Covid-like symptoms. Science, 375(6579), 364&#x2013;366. 10.1126/science.ada0536</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.ada0536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35084966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox, R. C., &amp; Olatunji, B. O. (2020). Sleep in the anxiety-related disorders: A meta-analysis of subjective and objective research. Sleep Medicine Reviews, 51, e101282. 10.1016/j.smrv.2020.101282</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2020.101282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32109832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damiano, R. F., Guedes, B. F., de Rocca, C. C., de P&#xe1;dua Serafim, A., Castro, L. H. M., Munhoz, C. D., Nitrini, R., Filho, G. B., Miguel, E. C., Lucchetti, G., &amp; Forlenza, O. (2022). Cognitive decline following acute viral infections: Literature review and projections for post-COVID-19. European Archives of Psychiatry and Clinical Neuroscience, 272(1), 139&#x2013;154. 10.1007/s00406-021-01286-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00406-021-01286-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8231753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34173049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daroische, R., Hemminghyth, M. S., Eilertsen, T. H., Breitve, M. H., &amp; Chwiszczuk, L. J. (2021). Cognitive impairment after COVID-19: A review on objective test data. Frontiers in Neurology, 12, e699582. 10.3389/fneur.2021.699582</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2021.699582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8357992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34393978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortier-Brochu, E., Beaulieu-Bonneau, S., Ivers, H., &amp; Morin, C. M. (2012). Insomnia and daytime cognitive performance: A meta-analysis. Sleep Medicine Reviews, 16(1), 83&#x2013;94. 10.1016/j.smrv.2011.03.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2011.03.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21636297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulpers, B., Ramakers, I., Hamel, R., K&#xf6;hler, S., Oude Voshaar, R., &amp; Verhey, F. (2016). Anxiety as a predictor for cognitive decline and dementia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. American Journal of Geriatric Psychiatry, 24(10), 823&#x2013;842. 10.1016/j.jagp.2016.05.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jagp.2016.05.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27591161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashioka, S., Inoue, K., Miyaoka, T., Hayashida, M., Wake, R., Oh-Nishi, A., &amp; Inagaki, M. (2019). The possible causal link of periodontitis to neuropsychiatric disorders: More than psychosocial mechanisms. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 20(15), e3723. 10.3390/ijms20153723</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms20153723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6695849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31366073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser, T., Herzog, P., Voderholzer, U., &amp; Brakemeier, E.-L. (2021). Unraveling the comorbidity of depression and anxiety in a large inpatient sample: Network analysis to examine bridge symptoms. Depression and Anxiety, 38(3), 307&#x2013;317. 10.1002/da.23136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.23136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33465284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, D., Epskamp, S., Isvoranu, A.-M., Chen, C., Liu, W., &amp; Hong, X. (2021). Network analysis of physical and psychiatric symptoms of hospital discharged patients infected with COVID-19. Journal of Affective Disorders, 294, 707&#x2013;713. 10.1016/j.jad.2021.07.043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2021.07.043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8284061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34343929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin, E., &amp; Velayudhan, L. (2020). Neuropsychiatric symptoms in mild cognitive impairment: A literature review. Dementia and Geriatric Cognitive Disorders, 49(2), 146&#x2013;155. 10.1159/000507078</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000507078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32289790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru, S., &amp; Merad, M. (2022). Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nature Immunology, 23(2), 194&#x2013;202. 10.1038/s41590-021-01104-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-021-01104-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyata, S., Noda, A., Iwamoto, K., Kawano, N., Okuda, M., &amp; Ozaki, N. (2013). Poor sleep quality impairs cognitive performance in older adults. Journal of Sleep Research, 22(5), 535&#x2013;541. 10.1111/jsr.12054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jsr.12054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23560612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monaco, S., Mariotto, S., Ferrari, S., Calabrese, M., Zanusso, G., Gajofatto, A., Sansonno, D., &amp; Dammacco, F. (2015). Hepatitis C virus-associated neurocognitive and neuropsychiatric disorders: Advances in 2015. World Journal of Gastroenterology, 21(42), 11974&#x2013;11983. 10.3748/wjg.v21.i42.11974</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v21.i42.11974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4641119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26576086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian, A., Sehgal, K., Gupta, A., Madhavan, M. V., McGroder, C., Stevens, J. S., Cook, J. R., Nordvig, A. S., Shalev, D., Sehrawat, T. S., Ahluwalia, N., Bikdeli, B., Dietz, D., Der-Nigoghossian, C., Liyanage-Don, N., Rosner, G. F., Bernstein, E. J., Mohan, S., Beckley, A. A., et al. Wan, E. Y. (2021). Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nature Medicine, 27(4), 601&#x2013;615. 10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. (2020). COVID-19 rapid guideline: Managing the long-term effects of COVID-19 (National Institute for Health and Care Excellence: Clinical guidelines). National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rock, P. L., Roiser, J. P., Riedel, W. J., &amp; Blackwell, A. D. (2014). Cognitive impairment in depression: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychological Medicine, 44(10), 2029&#x2013;2040. 10.1017/S0033291713002535</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291713002535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24168753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers, J. P., Chesney, E., Oliver, D., Pollak, T. A., McGuire, P., Fusar-Poli, P., Zandi, M. S., Lewis, G., &amp; David, A. S. (2020). Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: A systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet. Psychiatry, 7(7), 611&#x2013;627. 10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30203-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30203-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7234781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schild, A.-K., Goereci, Y., Scharfenberg, D., Klein, K., L&#xfc;lling, J., Meiberth, D., Schweitzer, F., St&#xfc;rmer, S., Zeyen, P., Sahin, D., Fink, G. F., Jessen, F., Franke, C., Onur, O. A., Kessler, J., Warnke, C., &amp; Maier, F. (2022). Multidomain cognitive impairment in non-hospitalized patients with the post-COVID-19 syndrome: results from a prospective monocentric cohort. Journal of Neurology. Advance online publication. 10.1007/s00415-022-11444-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-022-11444-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9686246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36422669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schweitzer, F., Goereci, Y., Franke, C., Silling, S., B&#xf6;sl, F., Maier, F., Heger, E., Deiman, B., Pr&#xfc;ss, H., Onur, O. A., Klein, F., Fink, G. R., Di Cristanziano, V., &amp; Warnke, C. (2022). Cerebrospinal fluid analysis post-COVID-19 is not suggestive of persistent central nervous system infection. Annals of Neurology, 91(1), 150&#x2013;157. 10.1002/ana.26262</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.26262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8653324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34724243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet, M., Dercon, Q., Luciano, S., Geddes, J. R., Husain, M., &amp; Harrison, P. J. (2021). Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: A 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Medicine, 18(9), e1003773. 10.1371/journal.pmed.1003773</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1003773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troyer, E. A., Kohn, J. N., &amp; Hong, S. (2020). Are we facing a crashing wave of neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19? Neuropsychiatric symptoms and potential immunologic mechanisms. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 87, 34&#x2013;39. 10.1016/j.bbi.2020.04.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2020.04.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7152874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>