<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37602544</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-7385</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>103</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of physical medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Phys Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association of Sleep Quality With Fatigue in Post-COVID-19 Patients in an Indian Population.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>188</StartPage><EndPage>193</EndPage><MedlinePgn>188-193</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PHM.0000000000002332</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The aims of the study are to assess the quality of sleep in recently recovered COVID-19 and long-COVID cases and to determine its associations with fatigue and pain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Post-COVID-19 cases ( n = 201) and controls ( n = 206) were assessed using the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index questionnaire for sleep quality, Fatigue Severity Scale for fatigue, and Numeric Pain Rating Scale for pain in this observational study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Global Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index score was higher ( P &#x2264; 0.001) among cases (5.7 &#xb1; 5.1; 95% confidence interval, 5.0-6.4) than controls (2.1 &#xb1; 2.0; 95% confidence interval, 1.8-2.4). Normal sleep latency was observed in 56 (27.9%) patients and 164 (79.6%) controls ( P &lt; 0.001). Fatigue Severity Scale score was higher ( P &#x2264; 0.001) among cases (16.8 &#xb1; 10.2; 95% confidence interval, 15.4, 18.2) against controls (10.9 &#xb1; 4.1; 95% confidence interval, 10.3-11.4). The Fatigue Severity Scale scores in mild, moderate, and severe COVID-19 were 14.3 &#xb1; 8.1, 22.1 &#xb1; 10.8, and 22.8 &#xb1; 13, respectively ( P &lt; 0.001) and higher in the older (20.7 &#xb1; 12.1) and middle-aged (19.6 &#xb1; 10.3) than in younger (13.9 &#xb1; 8.3) ( P &#x2264; 0.001) cases. The global Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index score was positively correlated with the Fatigue Severity Scale ( r = 0.755, P &lt; 0.001) and Numeric Pain Rating Scale scores ( r = 0.657, P &lt; 0.001). Numeric Pain Rating Scale score correlated with Fatigue Severity Scale score ( r = 0.710, P &lt; 0.001). Fatigue Severity Scale and global Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index scores were higher in the long-COVID group ( P &lt; 0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Significantly poor sleep quality was observed in post-COVID-19 individuals including long COVID being positively associated with fatigue and pain.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghosh</LastName><ForeName>Srutarshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1946-0536</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Patna, India (SG, AK, SKP); and ESIMCH, Bihta, Patna, India (SK).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Anjani</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandey</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay Kumar</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9013-4277</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Sanyal</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0218-2632</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Phys Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8803677</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0894-9115</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000089943" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep Quality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010146" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012893" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Wake Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Financial disclosure statements have been obtained, and no conflicts of interest have been reported by the authors or by any individuals in control of the content of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37602544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000002332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00002060-990000000-00305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, et al.; WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition: A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis 2022;22:e102&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarrott B, Head R, Pringle KG, et al.: &#x201c;LONG COVID&#x201d;&#x2014;a hypothesis for understanding the biological basis and pharmacological treatment strategy. Pharmacol Res Perspect 2022;10:e00911</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health and Family Welfare, Government of India. National comprehensive guidelines for management of post-COVID sequelae. Available at: http://www.mohfw.gov.in/pdf/nationalcomprehensiveguidelinesformanagementofpostcovidsequelae.pdf . Accessed March 3, 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wulf Hanson S, Abbafati C, et al.Global Burden of Disease Long COVID Collaborators: Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA 2022;328:1604&#x2013;15</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, et al.: Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med 2021;114:428&#x2013;42</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daynes E, Gerlis C, Chaplin E, et al.: Early experiences of rehabilitation for individuals post-COVID to improve fatigue, breathlessness exercise capacity and cognition&#x2014;a cohort study. Chron Respir Dis 2021;18:14799731211015691</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n A, Franco-L&#xf3;pez F, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, et al.: Rehabilitation for post-COVID-19 condition through a supervised exercise intervention: a randomized controlled trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports 2022;32:1791&#x2013;801</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doerr JM, Ditzen B, Strahler J, et al.: Reciprocal relationship between acute stress and acute fatigue in everyday life in a sample of university students. Biol Psychol 2015;110:42&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canori A, Amiri AM, Thapa-Chhetry B, et al.: Relationship between pain, fatigue, and physical activity levels during a technology-based physical activity intervention. J Spinal Cord Med 2021;44:549&#x2013;56</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et al.: Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine 2021;38:101019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chhajer R, Shukla SD: Sleep quality of COVID-19 recovered patients in India. Neurosci Insights 2022;17:26331055221109174</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahrami H, BaHammam AS, Bragazzi NL, et al.: Sleep problems during the COVID-19 pandemic by population: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Sleep Med 2021;17:299&#x2013;313</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Yang YQ, Liu Y, et al.: Effects of group psychological intervention combined with pulmonary rehabilitation exercises on anxiety and sleep disorders in patients with mild coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) infections in a Fangcang hospital. Psychol Health Med 2022;27:333&#x2013;42</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barros MBA, Lima MG, Ceolim MF, et al.: Quality of sleep, health and well-being in a population-based study. Rev Saude Publica 2019;53:82</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF 3rd, Monk TH, et al.: Quantification of subjective sleep quality in healthy elderly men and women using the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI). Sleep 1991;14:331&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen MP, McFarland CA: Increasing the reliability and validity of pain intensity measurement in chronic pain patients. Pain 1993;55:195&#x2013;203</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortelli P, Ferrazzoli D, Sebastianelli L, et al.: Neuropsychological and neurophysiological correlates of fatigue in post-acute patients with neurological manifestations of COVID-19: insights into a challenging symptom. J Neurol Sci 2021;420:117271</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul BS, Singh A, Jain D, et al.: Assessment of fatigue in Parkinson's disease: Indian perspective. Ann Indian Acad Neurol 2016;19:451&#x2013;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Treatment Guidelines Panel: Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Treatment Guidelines . National Institutes of Health. Available at: https://www.covid19treatmentguidelines.nih.gov/ . Accessed March 26, 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morjaria R, Alexander I, Purbrick RMJ, et al.: Impact of diabetic retinopathy on sleep, mood, and quality of life. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci 2019;60:2304&#x2013;10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Sayed S, Gomaa S, Shokry D, et al.: Sleep in post-COVID-19 recovery period and its impact on different domains of quality of life. Egypt J Neurol Psychiatr Neurosurg 2021;57:172</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadock VA, Ruiz PBJ: Kaplan and Sadock&#x2019;s Synopsis of Psychiatry , 11th ed. Philadelphia, PA, Wolters Kluwer, 2014:88&#x2013;92</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#x131;lmaz S, &#xd6;ner P: Melatonin levels are low in COVID-19 positive patients and these levels are associated with depression, death anxiety and insomnia. Scand J Clin Lab Invest 2023;83:86&#x2013;94</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su WL, Wu CC, Wu SV, et al.: A review of the potential effects of melatonin in compromised mitochondrial redox activities in elderly patients with COVID-19. Front Nutr 2022;9:865321</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Abreu-Gonzalez P, Marik PE, et al.: Therapeutic algorithm for use of melatonin in patients with COVID-19. Front Med (Lausanne) 2020;7:226</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowes DA, Almawash AM, Webster NR, et al.: Melatonin and structurally similar compounds have differing effects on inflammation and mitochondrial function in endothelial cells under conditions mimicking sepsis. Br J Anaesth 2011;107:193&#x2013;201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousavi SA, Heydari K, Mehravaran H, et al.: Melatonin effects on sleep quality and outcomes of COVID-19 patients: an open-label, randomized, controlled trial. J Med Virol 2022;94:263&#x2013;71</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul BD, Lemle MD, Komaroff AL, et al.: Redox imbalance links COVID-19 and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2021;118:e2024358118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Tan DX, Rosales-Corral S, et al.: Mitochondria: central organelles for melatonin's antioxidant and anti-aging actions. Molecules 2018;23:509</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>