<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38299237</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1791-244X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of molecular medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Mol Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A mid&#x2011;pandemic night's dream: Melatonin, from&#xa0;harbinger of anti&#x2011;inflammation to mitochondrial savior in acute and long COVID&#x2011;19 (Review).</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">28</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3892/ijmm.2024.5352</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID&#x2011;19), a systemic illness caused by severe acute respiratory distress syndrome&#xa0;2 (SARS&#x2011;CoV&#x2011;2), has triggered a worldwide pandemic with symptoms ranging from asymptomatic to chronic, affecting practically every organ. Melatonin, an ancient antioxidant found in all living organisms, has been suggested as a safe and effective therapeutic option for the treatment of SARS&#x2011;CoV&#x2011;2 infection due to its good safety characteristics and broad&#x2011;spectrum antiviral medication properties. Melatonin is essential in various metabolic pathways and governs physiological processes, such as the sleep&#x2011;wake cycle and circadian rhythms. It exhibits oncostatic, anti&#x2011;inflammatory, antioxidant and anti&#x2011;aging properties, exhibiting promise for use in the treatment of numerous disorders, including COVID&#x2011;19. The preventive and therapeutic effects of melatonin have been widely explored in a number of conditions and have been well&#x2011;established in experimental ischemia/reperfusion investigations, particularly in coronary heart disease and stroke. Clinical research evaluating the use of melatonin in COVID&#x2011;19 has shown various improved outcomes, including reduced hospitalization durations; however, the trials are small. Melatonin can alleviate mitochondrial dysfunction in COVID&#x2011;19, improve immune cell function and provide antioxidant properties. However, its therapeutic potential remains underexplored due to funding limitations and thus further investigations are required.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lempesis</LastName><ForeName>Ioannis G</ForeName><Initials>IG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathophysiology, Laiko General Hospital, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, 11527 Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Georgakopoulou</LastName><ForeName>Vasiliki Epameinondas</ForeName><Initials>VE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathophysiology, Laiko General Hospital, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, 11527 Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reiter</LastName><ForeName>Russel J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cellular and Structural Biology, UT Health Science Center, San Antonio, TX 78229, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spandidos</LastName><ForeName>Demetrios A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Clinical Virology, School of Medicine, University of Crete, 71003 Heraklion, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Greece</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Mol Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9810955</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1107-3756</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000975">Antioxidants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>JL5DK93RCL</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008550">Melatonin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000975" MajorTopicYN="N">Antioxidants</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Melatonin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID&#x2011;19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antioxidant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID&#x2011;19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">melatonin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mitochondrial dysfunction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>DAS is the Editor-in-Chief for the journal, but had no personal involvement in the reviewing process, or any influence in terms of adjudicating on the final decision, for this article. The other authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38299237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10852014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ijmm.2024.5352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">28</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Hu B, Hu C, Zhu F, Liu X, Zhang J, Wang B, Xiang H, Cheng Z, Xiong Y, et al. Clinical characteristics of 138 hospitalized patients with 2019 novel coronavirus-infected pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA. 2020;323:1061&#x2013;1069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgakopoulou VE, Makrodimitri S, Triantafyllou M, Samara S, Voutsinas PM, Anastasopoulou A, Papageorgiou CV, Spandidos DA, Gkoufa A, Papalexis P, et al. Immature granulocytes: Innovative biomarker for SARS-CoV-2 infection. Mol Med Rep. 2022;26:217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9175277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35551416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lempesis IG, Karlafti E, Papalexis P, Fotakopoulos G, Tarantinos K, Lekakis V, Papadakos SP, Cholongitas E, Georgakopoulou VE. COVID-19 and liver injury in individuals with obesity. World J Gastroenterol. 2023;29:908&#x2013;916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9950870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36844135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan WJ, Ni ZY, Hu Y, Liang WH, Ou CQ, He JX, Liu L, Shan H, Lei CL, Hui DSC, et al. Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:1708&#x2013;1720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32109013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gracia-Ramos AE, Jaquez-Quintana JO, Contreras-Omana R, Auron M. Liver dysfunction and SARS-CoV-2 infection. World J Gastroenterol. 2021;27:3951&#x2013;3970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8311530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34326607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gkoufa A, Maneta E, Ntoumas GN, Georgakopoulou VE, Mantelou A, Kokkoris S, Routsi C. Elderly adults with COVID-19 admitted to intensive care unit: A narrative review. World J Crit Care Med. 2021;10:278&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8462023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34616662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgakopoulou VE, Gkoufa A, Garmpis N, Makrodimitri S, Papageorgiou CV, Barlampa D, Garmpi A, Chiapoutakis S, Sklapani P, Trakas N, Damaskos C. COVID-19 and acute pancreatitis: A systematic review of case reports and case series. Ann Saudi Med. 2022;42:276&#x2013;287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9357298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35933608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgakopoulou VE, Lembessis P, Skarlis C, Gkoufa A, Sipsas NV, Mavragani CP. Hematological abnormalities in COVID-19 disease: Association with type I interferon pathway activation and disease outcomes. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022;9:850472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8968418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35372456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madjid M, Safavi-Naeini P, Solomon SD, Vardeny O. Potential effects of coronaviruses on the cardiovascular system: A review. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:831&#x2013;840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32219363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lempesis IG, Georgakopoulou VE. Implications of obesity and adiposopathy on respiratory infections; focus on emerging challenges. World J Clin Cases. 2023;11:2925&#x2013;2933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10198078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37215426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lempesis IG, Georgakopoulou VE. Physiopathological mechanisms related to inflammation in obesity and type 2 diabetes mellitus. World J Exp Med. 2023;13:7&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10308320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37396883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgakopoulou VE, Bali T, Adamantou M, Asimakopoulou S, Makrodimitri S, Samara S, Triantafyllou M, Voutsinas PM, Eliadi I, Karamanakos G, et al. Acute hepatitis and liver injury in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 infection. Exp Ther Med. 2022;24:691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9535623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36277149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathioudakis N, Zachiotis M, Papadakos S, Triantafyllou M, Karapanou A, Samara S, Karamanakos G, Spandidos DA, Papalexis P, Damaskos C, et al. Onodera's prognostic nutritional index: Comparison of its role in the severity and outcomes of patients with COVID-19 during the periods of alpha, delta and omicron variant predominance. Exp Ther Med. 2022;24:675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9501760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36177343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cholongitas E, Bali T, Georgakopoulou VE, Kamiliou A, Vergos I, Makrodimitri S, Samara S, Triantafylou M, Basoulis D, Eliadi I, et al. Comparison of liver function test- and inflammation-based prognostic scores for coronavirus disease 2019: A single center study. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;34:1165&#x2013;1171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36170686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgakopoulou VE, Gkoufa A, Damaskos C, Papalexis P, Pierrakou A, Makrodimitri S, Sypsa G, Apostolou A, Asimakopoulou S, Chlapoutakis S, et al. COVID-19-associated acute appendicitis in adults. A report of five cases and a review of the literature. Exp Ther Med. 2022;24:482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35761802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cholongitas E, Bali T, Georgakopoulou VE, Giannakodimos A, Gyftopoulos A, Georgilaki V, Gerogiannis D, Basoulis D, Eliadi I, Karamanakos G, et al. Prevalence of abnormal liver biochemistry and its impact on COVID-19 patients' outcomes: A single-center Greek study. Ann Gastroenterol. 2022;35:290&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9062840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35599935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loh D, Reiter RJ. Melatonin: Regulation of viral phase separation and epitranscriptomics in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:8122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9368024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35897696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: Major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M. Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nat Immunol. 2022;23:194&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vehar S, Boushra M, Ntiamoah P, Biehl M. Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: Caring for the 'long-haulers'. Cleve Clin J Med. 2021;88:267&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33941600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bali T, Georgakopoulou VE, Kamiliou A, Vergos I, Adamantou M, Vlachos S, Ermidis G, Sipsas NV, Samarkos M, Cholongitas E. Abnormal liver function tests and coronavirus disease 2019: A close relationship. J Viral Hepat. 2023;30:79&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9878169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36369662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guarnieri JW, Dybas JM, Fazelinia H, Kim MS, Frere J, Zhang Y, Soto Albrecht Y, Murdock DG, Angelin A, Singh LN, et al. Core mitochondrial genes are down-regulated during SARS-CoV-2 infection of rodent and human hosts. Sci Transl Med. 2023;15:eabq1533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37556555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Tan DX, Galano A. Melatonin: Exceeding expectations. Physiology (Bethesda) 2014;29:325&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25180262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Sharma R, Rosales-Corral S, de Campos Zuccari DAP, de Almeida Chuffa LG. Melatonin: A mitochondrial resident with a diverse skill set. Life Sci. 2022;301:120612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35523285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Sharma R, Tan DX, Neel RL, Simko F, Manucha W, Rosales-Corral S, Cardinali DP. Melatonin use for SARS-CoV-2 infection: Time to diversify the treatment portfolio. J Med Virol. 2022;94:2928&#x2013;2930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9088493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35338491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero A, Ramos E, L&#xf3;pez-Mu&#xf1;oz F, Gil-Mart&#xed;n E, Escames G, Reiter RJ. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) and its neuroinvasive capacity: Is it time for melatonin? Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2022;42:489&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7415199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32772307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Sharma R, Simko F, Dominguez-Rodriguez A, Tesarik J, Neel RL, Slominski AT, Kleszczynski K, Martin-Gimenez VM, Manucha W, Cardinali DP. Melatonin: Highlighting its use as a potential treatment for SARS-CoV-2 infection. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2022;79:143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8858600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35187603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouffak S, Shubbar Q, Saleh E, El-Awady R. Recent advances in management of COVID-19: A review. Biomed Pharmacother. 2021;143:112107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8390390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34488083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wichniak A, Kania A, Siemi&#x144;ski M, Cuba&#x142;a WJ. Melatonin as a potential adjuvant treatment for COVID-19 beyond sleep disorders. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:8623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8395320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34445329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos E, L&#xf3;pez-Mu&#xf1;oz F, Gil-Mart&#xed;n E, Egea J, &#xc1;lvarez-Merz I, Painuli S, Semwal P, Martins N, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Guijo JM, Romero A. The coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): key emphasis on melatonin safety and therapeutic efficacy. Antioxidants (Basel) 2021;10:1152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8301107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34356384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boga JA, Coto-Montes A, Rosales-Corral SA, Tan DX, Reiter RJ. Beneficial actions of melatonin in the management of viral infections: A new use for this 'molecular handyman'? Rev Med Virol. 2012;22:323&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7169144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22511571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juybari KB, Pourhanifeh MH, Hosseinzadeh A, Hemati K, Mehrzadi S. Melatonin potentials against viral infections including COVID-19: Current evidence and new findings. Virus Res. 2020;287:198108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7405774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32768490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgakopoulou VE, Gkoufa A, Makrodimitri S, Basoulis D, Tsakanikas A, Karamanakos G, Mastrogianni E, Voutsinas PM, Spandidos DA, Papageorgiou CV, et al. Early 3-day course of remdesivir for the prevention of the progression to severe COVID-19 in the elderly: A single-centre, real-life cohort study. Exp Ther Med. 2023;26:462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10469144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37664680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basoulis D, Tsakanikas A, Gkoufa A, Bitsani A, Karamanakos G, Mastrogianni E, Georgakopoulou VE, Makrodimitri S, Voutsinas PM, Lamprou P, et al. Effectiveness of oral nirmatrelvir/ritonavir vs intravenous three-day remdesivir in preventing progression to severe COVID-19: A single-center, prospective, comparative, real-life study. Viruses. 2023;15:1515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10383489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37515201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulou A, Karavalakis G, Papadopoulou E, Xochelli A, Bousiou Z, Vogiatzoglou A, Papayanni PG, Georgakopoulou A, Giannaki M, Stavridou F, et al. SARS-CoV-2-specific T cell therapy for severe COVID-19: a randomized phase 1/2 trial. Nat Med. 2023;29:2019&#x2013;2029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37460756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlafti E, Paramythiotis D, Pantazi K, Georgakopoulou VE, Kaiafa G, Papalexis P, Protopapas AA, Ztriva E, Fyntanidou V, Savopoulos C. Drug-induced liver injury in hospitalized patients during SARS-CoV-2 infection. Medicina (Kaunas) 2022;58:1848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9782075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36557050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgakopoulou VE, Basoulis D, Voutsinas PM, Makrodimitri S, Samara S, Triantafyllou M, Eliadi I, Karamanakos G, Papageorgiou CV, Anastasopoulou A, et al. Factors predicting poor outcomes of patients treated with tocilizumab for COVID-19-associated pneumonia: A retrospective study. Exp Ther Med. 2022;24:724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9627569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36340609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gkoufa A, Saridaki M, Georgakopoulou VE, Spandidos DA, Cholongitas E. COVID-19 vaccination in liver transplant recipients (Review) Exp Ther Med. 2023;25:291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10189597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37206557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elrashdy F, Tambuwala MM, Hassan SS, Adadi P, Seyran M, Abd El-Aziz TM, Rezaei N, Lal A, Aljabali AAA, Kandimalla R, et al. Autoimmunity roots of the thrombotic events after COVID-19 vaccination. Autoimmun Rev. 2021;20:102941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8426137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34508917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taskou C, Sarantaki A, Beloukas A, Georgakopoulou VE, Daskalakis G, Papalexis P, Lykeridou A. Knowledge and attitudes of healthcare professionals regarding perinatal influenza vaccination during the COVID-19 pandemic. Vaccines (Basel) 2023;11:168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9863632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36680013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goeser S, Ruble J, Chandler L. Melatonin: Historical and clinical perspectives. J Pharmaceut Care Pain Symptom Contr. 1997;5:37&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer CE, Steketee JD, Saphier D. Antioxidant properties of melatonin-an emerging mystery. Biochem Pharmacol. 1998;56:1265&#x2013;1272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9825724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad SB, Ali A, Bilal M, Rashid SM, Wani AB, Bhat RR, Rehman MU. Melatonin and health: Insights of melatonin action, biological functions, and associated disorders. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2023;43:2437&#x2013;2458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9907215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36752886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardeland R, Balzer I, Poeggeler B, Fuhrberg B, Ur&#xed;a H, Behrmann G, Wolf R, Meyer TJ, Reiter RJ. On the primary functions of melatonin in evolution: Mediation of photoperiodic signals in a unicell, photooxidation, and scavenging of free radicals. J Pineal Res. 1995;18:104&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7629689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipolla-Neto J, Amaral FGD. Melatonin as a hormone: New physiological and clinical insights. Endocr Rev. 2018;39:990&#x2013;1028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30215696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manchester LC, Coto-Montes A, Boga JA, Andersen LP, Zhou Z, Galano A, Vriend J, Tan DX, Reiter RJ. Melatonin: An ancient molecule that makes oxygen metabolically tolerable. J Pineal Res. 2015;59:403&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26272235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardeland R, Reiter R, Poeggeler B, Tan DX. The significance of the metabolism of the neurohormone melatonin: Antioxidative protection and formation of bioactive substances. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 1993;17:347&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8272286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ. Pineal melatonin: Cell biology of its synthesis and of its physiological interactions. Endocr Rev. 1991;12:151&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1649044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseinzadeh A, Bagherifard A, Koosha F, Amiri S, Karimi-Behnagh A, Reiter RJ, Mehrzadi S. Melatonin effect on platelets and coagulation: Implications for a prophylactic indication in COVID-19. Life Sci. 2022;307:120866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9356576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35944663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan DX, Hardeland R, Manchester LC, Paredes SD, Korkmaz A, Sainz RM, Mayo JC, Fuentes-Broto L, Reiter RJ. The changing biological roles of melatonin during evolution: From an antioxidant to signals of darkness, sexual selection and fitness. Biol Rev Camb Philos Soc. 2010;85:607&#x2013;623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20039865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen LPH, G&#xf6;genur I, Rosenberg J, Reiter RJ. Pharmacokinetics of melatonin: The missing link in clinical efficacy? Clin Pharmacokinet. 2016;55:1027&#x2013;1030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27000757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Tan DX, Korkmaz A. The circadian melatonin rhythm and its modulation: Possible impact on hypertension. J Hypertens Suppl. 2009;27:S17&#x2013;S20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19633446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vriend J, Reiter RJ. Melatonin feedback on clock genes: A theory involving the proteasome. J Pineal Res. 2015;58:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25369242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erren TC, Reiter RJ. Melatonin: A universal time messenger. Neuro Endocrinol Lett. 2015;36:187&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26313381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrzadi S, Karimi MY, Fatemi A, Reiter RJ, Hosseinzadeh A. SARS-CoV-2 and other coronaviruses negatively influence mitochondrial quality control: Beneficial effects of melatonin. Pharmacol Ther. 2021;224:107825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7919585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33662449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauriz JL, Collado PS, Veneroso C, Reiter RJ, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Gallego J. A review of the molecular aspects of melatonin's anti-inflammatory actions: Recent insights and new perspectives. J Pineal Res. 2013;54:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22725668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slominski RM, Reiter RJ, Schlabritz-Loutsevitch N, Ostrom RS, Slominski AT. Melatonin membrane receptors in peripheral tissues: Distribution and functions. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2012;351:152&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3288509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22245784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurunathan S, Kang MH, Choi Y, Reiter RJ, Kim JH. Melatonin: A potential therapeutic agent against COVID-19. Melatonin Res. 2021;4:30&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naskar A, Prabhakar V, Singh R, Dutta D, Mohanakumar KP. Melatonin enhances L-DOPA therapeutic effects, helps to reduce its dose, and protects dopaminergic neurons in 1-methyl-4-phenyl-1,2,3,6-tetrahydropyridine-induced Parkinsonism in mice. J Pineal Res. 2015;58:262&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25626558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Mayo JC, Tan DX, Sainz RM, Alatorre-Jimenez M, Qin L. Melatonin as an antioxidant: Under promises but over delivers. J Pineal Res. 2016;61:253&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27500468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos E, Pati&#xf1;o P, Reiter RJ, Gil-Mart&#xed;n E, Marco-Contelles J, Parada E, de Los Rios C, Romero A, Egea J. Ischemic brain injury: New insights on the protective role of melatonin. Free Radic Biol Med. 2017;104:32&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28065781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Barcelo EJ, Rueda N, Mediavilla MD, Martinez-Cue C, Reiter RJ. Clinical uses of melatonin in neurological diseases and mental and behavioural disorders. Curr Med Chem. 2017;24:3851&#x2013;3878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28721826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali T, Rahman SU, Hao Q, Li W, Liu Z, Ali Shah F, Murtaza I, Zhang Z, Yang X, Liu G, Li S. Melatonin prevents neuroinflammation and relieves depression by attenuating autophagy impairment through FOXO3a regulation. J Pineal Res. 2020;69:e12667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32375205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vriend J, Reiter RJ. Melatonin as a proteasome inhibitor. Is there any clinical evidence? Life Sci. 2014;115:8&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25219883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo JC, Sainz RM, Gonz&#xe1;lez Men&#xe9;ndez P, Cepas V, Tan DX, Reiter RJ. Melatonin and sirtuins: A 'not-so unexpected' relationship. J Pineal Res. 2017;62:e12391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28109165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurunathan S, Qasim M, Kang MH, Kim JH. Role and therapeutic potential of melatonin in various type of cancers. Onco Targets Ther. 2021;14:2019&#x2013;2052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7987311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33776451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourhanifeh MH, Mehrzadi S, Kamali M, Hosseinzadeh A. Melatonin and gastrointestinal cancers: Current evidence based on underlying signaling pathways. Eur J Pharmacol. 2020;886:173471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32877658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Rosales-Corral SA, Tan DX, Acuna-Castroviejo D, Qin L, Yang SF, Xu K. Melatonin, a full service anti-cancer agent: inhibition of initiation, progression and metastasis. Int J Mol Sci. 2017;18:843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5412427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28420185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Tan DX, Paredes SD, Fuentes-Broto L. Beneficial effects of melatonin in cardiovascular disease. Ann Med. 2010;42:276&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20455793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galano A, Tan DX, Reiter RJ. Melatonin: A versatile protector against oxidative DNA damage. Molecules. 2018;23:530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6017920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29495460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simko F, Baka T, Paulis L, Reiter RJ. Elevated heart rate and nondipping heart rate as potential targets for melatonin: A review. J Pineal Res. 2016;61:127&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27264986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Tan DX, Kim SJ, Qi W. Melatonin as a pharmacological agent against oxidative damage to lipids and DNA. Proc West Pharmacol Soc. 1998;41:229&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9836298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Tan DX, Rosales-Corral S, Manchester LC. The universal nature, unequal distribution and antioxidant functions of melatonin and its derivatives. Mini Rev Med Chem. 2013;13:373&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23190034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a JJ, L&#xf3;pez-Pingarr&#xf3;n L, Almeida-Souza P, Tres A, Escudero P, Garc&#xed;a-Gil FA, Tan DX, Reiter RJ, Ram&#xed;rez JM, Bernal-P&#xe9;rez M. Protective effects of melatonin in reducing oxidative stress and in preserving the fluidity of biological membranes: A review. J Pineal Res. 2014;56:225&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan DX, Korkmaz A, Reiter RJ, Manchester LC. Ebola virus disease: Potential use of melatonin as a treatment. J Pineal Res. 2014;57:381&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25262626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Ma Q, Sharma R. Treatment of Ebola and other infectious diseases: Melatonin 'goes viral'. Melatonin Res. 2020;3:43&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Sharma R, Ma Q, Liu C, Manucha W, Gonz&#xe1;lez P, Dominguez-Rodriguez A. Metabolic plasticity of activated immune cells: Advantages for suppression of COVID-19 disease by melatonin. Melatonin Res. 2020;3:362&#x2013;379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Sharma R, Ma Q, Dominquez-Rodriguez A, Marik PE, Abreu-Gonzalez P. Melatonin inhibits COVID-19-induced cytokine storm by reversing aerobic glycolysis in immune cells: A mechanistic analysis. Med Drug Discov. 2020;6:100044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32395713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar S, Chattopadhyay A, Bandyopadhyay D. Multiple strategies of melatonin protecting against cardiovascular injury related to inflammation: A comprehensive overview. Melatonin Res. 2021;4:1&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito E, Cuzzocrea S. Antiinflammatory activity of melatonin in central nervous system. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2010;8:228&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3001216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21358973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardeland R, Cardinali DP, Brown GM, Pandi-Perumal SR. Melatonin and brain inflammaging. Prog Neurobiol. 2015;127-128:46&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25697044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farez MF, Mascanfroni ID, M&#xe9;ndez-Huergo SP, Yeste A, Murugaiyan G, Garo LP, Balbuena Aguirre ME, Patel B, Ysrraelit MC, Zhu C, et al. Melatonin contributes to the seasonality of multiple sclerosis relapses. Cell. 2015;162:1338&#x2013;1352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4570563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26359987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominguez-Rodriguez A, Abreu-Gonzalez P, Marik PE, Reiter RJ. Melatonin, cardiovascular disease and COVID-19: A potential therapeutic strategy? Melatonin Res. 2020;3:318&#x2013;321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozdemir G, Erg&#xfc;n Y, Bakari&#x15f; S, K&#x131;l&#x131;n&#xe7; M, Durdu H, Ganiyusufo&#x11f;lu E. Melatonin prevents retinal oxidative stress and vascular changes in diabetic rats. Eye (Lond) 2014;28:1020&#x2013;1027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4135253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24924441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gheban BA, Rosca IA, Crisan M. The morphological and functional characteristics of the pineal gland. Med Pharm Rep. 2019;92:226&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6709953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31460502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipolla-Neto J, Amaral F, Afeche SC, Tan DX, Reiter RJ. Melatonin, energy metabolism, and obesity: A review. J Pineal Res. 2014;56:371&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24654916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lempesis IG, Hoebers N, Essers Y, Jocken JWE, Dineen R, Blaak EE, Manolopoulos KN, Goossens GH. Distinct inflammatory signatures of upper and lower body adipose tissue and adipocytes in women with normal weight or obesity. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2023;14:1205799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10338223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37455922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lempesis IG, Varrias D, Sagris M, Attaran RR, Altin ES, Bakoyiannis C, Palaiodimos L, Dalamaga M, Kokkinidis DG. Obesity and peripheral artery disease: Current evidence and controversies. Curr Obes Rep. 2023;12:264&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10220347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37243875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lempesis IG, Apple SJ, Duarte G, Palaiodimos L, Kalaitzopoulos DR, Dalamaga M, Kokkinidis DG. Cardiometabolic effects of SGLT2 inhibitors on polycystic ovary syndrome. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2023;39:e3682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37392147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lempesis IG, Tsilingiris D, Liu J, Dalamaga M. Of mice and men: Considerations on adipose tissue physiology in animal models of obesity and human studies. Metabol Open. 2022;15:100208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9460138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36092796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simko F, Hrenak J, Dominguez-Rodriguez A, Reiter RJ. Melatonin as a putative protection against myocardial injury in COVID-19 infection. Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol. 2020;13:921&#x2013;924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32893686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirza-Aghazadeh-Attari M, Reiter RJ, Rikhtegar R, Jalili J, Hajalioghli P, Mihanfar A, Majidinia M, Yousefi B. Melatonin: An atypical hormone with major functions in the regulation of angiogenesis. IUBMB Life. 2020;72:1560&#x2013;1584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32329956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melhuish Beaupre LM, Brown GM, Gon&#xe7;alves VF, Kennedy JL. Melatonin's neuroprotective role in mitochondria and its potential as a biomarker in aging, cognition and psychiatric disorders. Transl Psychiatry. 2021;11:339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8172874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34078880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Rosales-Corral S, Tan DX, Jou MJ, Galano A, Xu B. Melatonin as a mitochondria-targeted antioxidant: One of evolution's best ideas. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2017;74:3863&#x2013;3881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11107735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28864909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Ma Q, Sharma R. Melatonin in mitochondria: Mitigating clear and present dangers. Physiology (Bethesda) 2020;35:86&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32024428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakatsuki A, Okatani Y, Shinohara K, Ikenoue N, Kaneda C, Fukaya T. Melatonin protects fetal rat brain against oxidative mitochondrial damage. J Pineal Res. 2001;30:22&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11168903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Tan DX, Rosales-Corral S, Galano A, Jou MJ, Acuna-Castroviejo D. Melatonin mitigates mitochondrial meltdown: Interactions with SIRT3. Int J Mol Sci. 2018;19:2439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6121285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30126181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han L, Wang H, Li L, Li X, Ge J, Reiter RJ, Wang Q. Melatonin protects against maternal obesity-associated oxidative stress and meiotic defects in oocytes via the SIRT3-SOD2-dependent pathway. J Pineal Res. 2017;63:e12431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28658527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mar t&#xed;n M, Mac&#xed;as M, Escames G, Le&#xf3;n J, Acu&#xf1;a-Castroviejo D. Melatonin but not vitamins C and E maintains glutathione homeostasis in t-butyl hydroperoxide-induced mitochondrial oxidative stress. FASEB J. 2000;14:1677&#x2013;1679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10973915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venegas C, Garc&#xed;a JA, Escames G, Ortiz F, L&#xf3;pez A, Doerrier C, Garc&#xed;a-Corzo L, L&#xf3;pez LC, Reiter RJ, Acu&#xf1;a-Castroviejo D. Extrapineal melatonin: Analysis of its subcellular distribution and daily fluctuations. J Pineal Res. 2012;52:217&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21884551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suofu Y, Li W, Jean-Alphonse FG, Jia J, Khattar NK, Li J, Baranov SV, Leronni D, Mihalik AC, He Y, et al. Dual role of mitochondria in producing melatonin and driving GPCR signaling to block cytochrome c release. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2017;114:E7997&#x2013;E8006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5617277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28874589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He C, Wang J, Zhang Z, Yang M, Li Y, Tian X, Ma T, Tao J, Zhu K, Song Y, et al. Mitochondria synthesize melatonin to ameliorate its function and improve mice oocyte's quality under in vitro conditions. Int J Mol Sci. 2016;17:939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4926472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27314334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan DX, Reiter RJ. Mitochondria: The birth place, battle ground and the site of melatonin metabolism in cells. Melatonin Res. 2019;2:44&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumboatong W, Thummayot S, Govitrapong P, Tocharus C, Jittiwat J, Tocharus J. Neuroprotection of agomelatine against cerebral ischemia/reperfusion injury through an antiapoptotic pathway in rat. Neurochem Int. 2017;102:114&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28012846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vries HE, Witte M, Hondius D, Rozemuller AJ, Drukarch B, Hoozemans J, van Horssen J. Nrf2-induced antioxidant protection: A promising target to counteract ROS-mediated damage in neurodegenerative disease? Free Radic Biol Med. 2008;45:1375&#x2013;1383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18824091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin M, Macias M, Escames G, Reiter RJ, Agapito MT, Ortiz GG, Acu&#xf1;a-Castroviejo D. Melatonin-induced increased activity of the respiratory chain complexes I and IV can prevent mitochondrial damage induced by ruthenium red in vivo. J Pineal Res. 2000;28:242&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10831160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheleme T, Bekele F, Ayela T. Clinical presentation of patients infected with coronavirus disease 19: A systematic review. Infect Dis (Auckl) 2020;13:1178633720952076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7495523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32973375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lempesis IG, Georgakopoulou VE, Papalexis P, Chrousos GP, Spandidos DA. Role of stress in the pathogenesis of cancer (Review) Int J Oncol. 2023;63:124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10552722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37711028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgakopoulou VE, Gkoufa A, Bougea A, Basoulis D, Tsakanikas A, Makrodimitri S, Karamanakos G, Spandidos DA, Angelopoulou E, Sipsas NV. Characteristics and outcomes of elderly patients with Parkinson's disease hospitalized due to COVID-19-associated pneumonia. Med Int (Lond) 2023;3:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10336924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37448768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourgonje AR, Abdulle AE, Timens W, Hillebrands JL, Navis GJ, Gordijn SJ, Bolling MC, Dijkstra G, Voors AA, Osterhaus AD, et al. Angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2), SARS-CoV-2 and the pathophysiology of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) J Pathol. 2020;251:228&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7276767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32418199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozkurt Z, &#xc7;&#x131;nar Tanr&#x131;verdi E. COVID-19: Gastrointestinal manifestations, liver injury and recommendations. World J Clin Cases. 2022;10:1140&#x2013;1163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8855202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35211548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Xiang R, Huo S, Zhou Y, Jiang S, Wang Q, Yu F. Molecular mechanism of interaction between SARS-CoV-2 and host cells and interventional therapy. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6:233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8193598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34117216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgakopoulou VE, Gkoufa A, Tsakanikas A, Makrodimitri S, Karamanakos G, Basoulis D, Voutsinas PM, Eliadi I, Bougea A, Spandidos DA, et al. Predictors of COVID-19-associated mortality among hospitalized elderly patients with dementia. Exp Ther Med. 2023;26:395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10347294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37456163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur V, Ratho RK, Kumar P, Bhatia SK, Bora I, Mohi GK, Saxena SK, Devi M, Yadav D, Mehariya S. Multi-organ involvement in COVID-19: Beyond pulmonary manifestations. J Clin Med. 2021;10:446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7866189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33498861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n Gim&#xe9;nez VM, de las Heras N, Ferder L, Lahera V, Reiter RJ, Manucha W. Potential Effects of melatonin and micronutrients on mitochondrial dysfunction during a cytokine storm typical of oxidative/inflammatory diseases. Diseases. 2021;9:30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8167770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bougea A, Georgakopoulou VE, Palkopoulou M, Efthymiopoulou E, Angelopoulou E, Spandidos DA, Zikos P. New-onset non-motor symptoms in patients with Parkinson's disease and post-COVID-19 syndrome: A prospective cross-sectional study. Med Int (Lond) 2023;3:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10192951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37214229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad I, Rathore FA. Neurological manifestations and complications of COVID-19: A literature review. J Clin Neurosci. 2020;77:8&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7200361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32409215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long B, Brady WJ, Koyfman A, Gottlieb M. Cardiovascular complications in COVID-19. Am J Emerg Med. 2020;38:1504&#x2013;1507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7165109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32317203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legrand M, Bell S, Forni L, Joannidis M, Koyner JL, Liu K, Cantaluppi V. Pathophysiology of COVID-19-associated acute kidney injury. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2021;17:751&#x2013;764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8256398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34226718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley SE, Karlson EW, Levitan EB, Levy B, McComsey GA, McCorkell L, Nadkarni GN, Parthasarathy S, Singh U, et al. Development of a definition of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA. 2023;329:1934&#x2013;1946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10214179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efstathiou V, Stefanou MI, Demetriou M, Siafakas N, Makris M, Tsivgoulis G, Zoumpourlis V, Kympouropoulos SP, Tsoporis JN, Spandidos DA, et al. Long COVID and neuropsychiatric manifestations (Review) Exp Ther Med. 2022;23:363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9019760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35493431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efstathiou V, Stefanou MI, Demetriou M, Siafakas N, Katsantoni E, Makris M, Tsivgoulis G, Zoumpourlis V, Kympouropoulos SP, Tsoporis JN, et al. New-onset neuropsychiatric sequelae and 'long-COVID'syndrome (Review) Exp Ther Med. 2022;24:705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9622976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36324612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty SE, Guo Y, Heath K, Dasmari&#xf1;as MC, Jubilo KG, Samranvedhya J, Lipsitch M, Cohen K. Risk of clinical sequelae after the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection: Retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;373:n1098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8132065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Li X, Gu X, Zhang H, Ren L, Guo L, Liu M, Wang Y, Cui D, Wang Y, et al. Health outcomes in people 2 years after surviving hospitalisation with COVID-19: A longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10:863&#x2013;876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9094732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35568052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, Kang L, Guo L, Liu M, Zhou X, et al. 6-Month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: A cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>E E, R F, &#xd6;i E, Im L, M L, S R, E W, C J, M H, A M. Impaired diffusing capacity for carbon monoxide is common in critically ill Covid-19 patients at four months post-discharge. Respir Med. 2021;182:106394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8047337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33901787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet. 2022;399:2263&#x2013;2264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35717982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaglia F, Salladini E, Carraro M, Minervini G, Tosatto SCE, Le Mercier P. SARS-CoV-2 variants preferentially emerge at intrinsically disordered protein sites helping immune evasion. FEBS J. 2022;289:4240&#x2013;4250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9542094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35108439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipsitch M, Krammer F, Regev-Yochay G, Lustig Y, Balicer RD. SARS-CoV-2 breakthrough infections in vaccinated individuals: Measurement, causes and impact. Nat Rev Immunol. 2022;22:57&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8649989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34876702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes LD, Ingram J, Sculthorpe NF. More than 100 persistent symptoms of SARS-CoV-2 (long COVID): A scoping review. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021;8:750378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8591053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34790680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re'em Y, Redfield S, Austin JP, Akrami A. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 Months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaebler C, Wang Z, Lorenzi JCC, Muecksch F, Finkin S, Tokuyama M, Cho A, Jankovic M, Schaefer-Babajew D, Oliveira TY, et al. Evolution of antibody immunity to SARS-CoV-2. Nature. 2021;591:639&#x2013;644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): An overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front Microbiol. 2021;12:698169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalkeri R, Goebel S, Sharma GD. SARS-CoV-2 shedding from asymptomatic patients: Contribution of potential extrapulmonary tissue reservoirs. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2020;103:18&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7356473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32406369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubchenko S, Kril I, Nadizhko O, Matsyura O, Chopyak V. Herpesvirus infections and post-COVID-19 manifestations: A pilot observational study. Rheumatol Int. 2022;42:1523&#x2013;1530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9159383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35650445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, Ng RH, Wang K, Choi J, Li S, Hong S, Zhang R, Xie J, et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185:881&#x2013;895.e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiner P, Harrer T, Scheibenbogen C, Lamer S, Schlosser A, Naviaux RK, Prusty BK. Human herpesvirus-6 reactivation, mitochondrial fragmentation, and the coordination of antiviral and metabolic phenotypes in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Immunohorizons. 2020;4:201&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32327453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deeks SG, Mustapic M, Kapogiannis D, Henrich TJ, Lu S, Goldberg SA, Hoh R, Chen JY, Martinez EO, et al. SARS-CoV-2 and mitochondrial proteins in neural-derived exosomes of COVID-19. Ann Neurol. 2022;91:772&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9082480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35285072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villaume WA. Marginal BH4 deficiencies, iNOS, and self-perpetuating oxidative stress in post-acute sequelae of Covid-19. Med Hypotheses. 2022;163:110842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9006446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35431403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleh J, Peyssonnaux C, Singh KK, Edeas M. Mitochondria and microbiota dysfunction in COVID-19 pathogenesis. Mitochondrion. 2020;54:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32574708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh KK, Chaubey G, Chen JY, Suravajhala P. Decoding SARS-CoV-2 hijacking of host mitochondria in COVID-19 pathogenesis. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2020;319:C258&#x2013;C267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7381712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32510973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchi S, Guilbaud E, Tait SWG, Yamazaki T, Galluzzi L. Mitochondrial control of inflammation. Nat Rev Immunol. 2023;23:159&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9310369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West AP, Shadel GS. Mitochondrial DNA in innate immune responses and inflammatory pathology. Nat Rev Immunol. 2017;17:363&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7289178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28393922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P, Luo R, Zhang M, Wang Y, Song T, Tao T, Li Z, Jin L, Zheng H, Chen W, et al. A cross-talk between epithelium and endothelium mediates human alveolar-capillary injury during SARS-CoV-2 infection. Cell Death Dis. 2020;11:1042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7721862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33293527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortese M, Lee JY, Cerikan B, Neufeldt CJ, Oorschot VMJ, K&#xf6;hrer S, Hennies J, Schieber NL, Ronchi P, Mizzon G, et al. Integrative imaging reveals SARS-CoV-2-induced reshaping of subcellular morphologies. Cell Host Microbe. 2020;28:853&#x2013;866.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7670925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33245857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui DS, I Azhar E, Madani TA, Ntoumi F, Kock R, Dar O, Ippolito G, Mchugh TD, Memish ZA, Drosten C, et al. The continuing 2019-nCoV epidemic threat of novel coronaviruses to global health-the latest 2019 novel coronavirus outbreak in Wuhan, China. Int J Infect Dis. 2020;91:264&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31953166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon DE, Hiatt J, Bouhaddou M, Rezelj VV, Ulferts S, Braberg H, Jureka AS, Obernier K, Guo JZ, Batra J, et al. Comparative host-coronavirus protein interaction networks reveal pan-viral disease mechanisms. Science. 2020;370:eabe9403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33060197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon DE, Jang GM, Bouhaddou M, Xu J, Obernier K, White KM, O'Meara MJ, Rezelj VV, Guo JZ, Swaney DL, et al. A SARS-CoV-2 protein interaction map reveals targets for drug repurposing. Nature. 2020;583:459&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7431030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32353859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stukalov A, Girault V, Grass V, Karayel O, Bergant V, Urban C, Haas DA, Huang Y, Oubraham L, Wang A, et al. Multilevel proteomics reveals host perturbations by SARS-CoV-2 and SARS-CoV. Nature. 2021;594:246&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33845483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Ma F, Yokota T, Garcia G, Jr, Palermo A, Wang Y, Farrell C, Wang YC, Wu R, Zhou Z, et al. Metabolic reprogramming and epigenetic changes of vital organs in SARS-CoV-2-induced systemic toxicity. JCI insight. 2021;6:e145027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7934846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33284134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bojkova D, Klann K, Koch B, Widera M, Krause D, Ciesek S, Cinatl J, M&#xfc;nch C. Proteomics of SARS-CoV-2-infected host cells reveals therapy targets. Nature. 2020;583:469&#x2013;472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32408336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller B, Silverstein A, Flores M, Cao K, Kumagai H, Mehta HH, Yen K, Kim SJ, Cohen P. Host mitochondrial transcriptome response to SARS-CoV-2 in multiple cell models and clinical samples. Sci Rep. 2021;11:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7794290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33420163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medini H, Zirman A, Mishmar D. Immune system cells from COVID-19 patients display compromised mitochondrial-nuclear expression co-regulation and rewiring toward glycolysis. iScience. 2021;24:103471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8599136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34812416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Codo AC, Davanzo GG, Monteiro LB, de Souza GF, Muraro SP, Virgilio-da-Silva JV, Prodonoff JS, Carregari VC, de Biagi Junior CAO, Crunfli F, et al. Elevated glucose levels favor SARS-CoV-2 infection and monocyte response through a HIF-1&#x3b1;/glycolysis-dependent axis. Cell Metab. 2020;32:437&#x2013;446.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7367032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32697943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian M, Liu W, Li X, Zhao P, Shereen MA, Zhu C, Huang S, Liu S, Yu X, Yue M, et al. HIF-1&#x3b1; promotes SARS-CoV-2 infection and aggravates inflammatory responses to COVID-19. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6:308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8371950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34408131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan DX, Reiter RJ. Mechanisms and clinical evidence to support melatonin's use in severe COVID-19 patients to lower mortality. Life Sci. 2022;294:120368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8800937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35108568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang PY, Wu JY, Liu TH, Tsai YW, Chen PT, Liao CT, Toh HS. The clinical efficacy of melatonin in the treatment of patients with COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Med (Lausanne) 2023;10:1171294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10166833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37181363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fara A, Mitrev Z, Rosalia RA, Assas BM. Cytokine storm and COVID-19: A chronicle of pro-inflammatory cytokines. Open Biol. 2020;10:200160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32961074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Abreu-Gonzalez P, Marik PE, Dominguez-Rodriguez A. Therapeutic algorithm for use of melatonin in patients with COVID-19. Front Med (Lausanne) 2020;7:226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7242729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32574327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan DX, Manchester LC, Terron MP, Flores LJ, Reiter RJ. One molecule, many derivatives: A never-ending interaction of melatonin with reactive oxygen and nitrogen species? J Pineal Res. 2007;42:28&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17198536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan DX, Hardeland R, Manchester LC, Poeggeler B, Lopez-Burillo S, Mayo JC, Sainz RM, Reiter RJ. Mechanistic and comparative studies of melatonin and classic antioxidants in terms of their interactions with the ABTS cation radical. J Pineal Res. 2003;34:249&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12662346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez C, Mayo JC, Sainz RM, Antol&#xed;n I, Herrera F, Mart&#xed;n V, Reiter RJ. Regulation of antioxidant enzymes: A significant role for melatonin. J Pineal Res. 2004;36:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14675124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuzzocrea S, Zingarelli B, Costantino G, Caputi AR. Protective effect of melatonin in a non-septic shock model induced by zymosan in the rat. J Pineal Res. 1998;25:24&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9694401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuzzocrea S, Zingarelli B, Gilad E, Hake P, Salzman AL, Szab&#xf3; C. Protective effect of melatonin in carrageenan-induced models of local inflammation: Relationship to its inhibitory effect on nitric oxide production and its peroxynitrite scavenging activity. J Pineal Res. 1997;23:106&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9392449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sokkary GH, Omar HM, Hassanein AFMM, Cuzzocrea S, Reiter RJ. Melatonin reduces oxidative damage and increases survival of mice infected with Schistosoma mansoni. Free Radic Biol Med. 2002;32:319&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11841922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costantino G, Cuzzocrea S, Mazzon E, Caputi AP. Protective effects of melatonin in zymosan-activated plasma-induced paw inflammation. Eur J Pharmacol. 1998;363:57&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9877082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong J, Zhang Y, Liu S, Li H, Liu S, Wang J, Qin X, Jiang X, Yang J, Zhang C, Zhang W. Melatonin attenuates angiotensin II-induced abdominal aortic aneurysm through the down-regulation of matrix metalloproteinases. Oncotarget. 2017;8:14283&#x2013;14293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5362405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28179581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Li X, Grailer JJ, Wang N, Wang M, Yao J, Zhong R, Gao GF, Ward PA, Tan DX, Li X. Melatonin alleviates acute lung injury through inhibiting the NLRP3 inflammasome. J Pineal Res. 2016;60:405&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26888116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaivola J, Nyman TA, Matikainen S. Inflammasomes and SARS-CoV-2 infection. Viruses. 2021;13:2513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8706865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34960782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kucia M, Ratajczak J, Bujko K, Adamiak M, Ciechanowicz A, Chumak V, Brzezniakiewicz-Janus K, Ratajczak MZ. An evidence that SARS-Cov-2/COVID-19 spike protein (SP) damages hematopoietic stem/progenitor cells in the mechanism of pyroptosis in Nlrp3 inflammasome-dependent manner. Leukemia. 2021;35:3026&#x2013;3029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8219510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies DA, Adlimoghaddam A, Albensi BC. The effect of COVID-19 on NF-&#x3ba;B and neurological manifestations of disease. Mol Neurobiol. 2021;58:4178&#x2013;4187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8169418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34075562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manik M, Singh RK. Role of toll-like receptors in modulation of cytokine storm signaling in SARS-CoV-2-induced COVID-19. J Med Virol. 2022;94:869&#x2013;877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li HW, Ying P, Cai QQ, Yang ZH, Wu XL. Exogenous melatonin alleviates hemorrhagic shock-induced hepatic ischemic injury in rats by inhibiting the NF-&#x3ba;B/I&#x3ba;B&#x3b1; signaling pathway. Mol Med Rep. 2021;23:341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7974417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33760198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin M, Liu Y, Sun M, Li X, Xu J, Zhang L, Jiang H. Protective effects of melatonin on the white matter damage of neonatal rats by regulating NLRP3 inflammasome activity. Neuroreport. 2021;32:739&#x2013;747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33994520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao S, Shrestha S, Li J, Yu X, Chen J, Yan F, Ying G, Gu C, Wang L, Chen G. Melatonin-mediated mitophagy protects against early brain injury after subarachnoid hemorrhage through inhibition of NLRP3 inflammasome activation. Sci Rep. 2017;7:2417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5445068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28546552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan DX, Hardeland R. Targeting host defense system and rescuing compromised mitochondria to increase tolerance against pathogens by melatonin may impact outcome of deadly virus infection pertinent to COVID-19. Molecules. 2020;25:4410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7582936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32992875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sygitowicz G, Sitkiewicz D. Molecular mechanisms of organ damage in sepsis: An overview. Braz J Infect Dis. 2020;24:552&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9392098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33169675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo J, Song J, Zhang H, Zhang F, Liu H, Li L, Zhang Z, Chen L, Zhang M, Lin D, et al. Melatonin mediated Foxp3-downregulation decreases cytokines production via the TLR2 and TLR4 pathways in H. pylori infected mice. Int Immunopharmacol. 2018;64:116&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30173051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Wang G, Ai L, Shi J, Zhang J, Chen YX. Melatonin suppresses TLR9-triggered proinflammatory cytokine production in macrophages by inhibiting ERK1/2 and AKT activation. Sci Rep. 2018;8:15579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6197220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30349079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng R, Adeniran SO, Huang F, Li Y, Ma M, Zheng P, Zhang G. The ameliorative effect of melatonin on LPS-induced Sertoli cells inflammatory and tight junctions damage via suppression of the TLR4/MyD88/NF-&#x3ba;B signaling pathway in newborn calf. Theriogenology. 2022;179:103&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34871925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan DX, Reiter RJ. Melatonin reduces the mortality of severely-infected COVID-19 patients. Melatonin Res. 2021;4:613&#x2013;616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren DL, Sun AA, Li YJ, Chen M, Ge SC, Hu B. Exogenous melatonin inhibits neutrophil migration through suppression of ERK activation. J Endocrinol. 2015;227:49&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26303298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maldonado MD, Mora-Santos M, Naji L, Carrascosa-Salmoral MP, Naranjo MC, Calvo JR. Evidence of melatonin synthesis and release by mast cells. Possible modulatory role on inflammation. Pharmacol Res. 2010;62:282&#x2013;287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19963060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muxel SM, Pires-Lapa MA, Monteiro AWA, Cecon E, Tamura EK, Floeter-Winter LM, Markus RP. NF-&#x3ba;B drives the synthesis of melatonin in RAW 264.7 macrophages by inducing the transcription of the arylalkylamine-N-acetyltransferase (AA-NAT) gene. PLoS One. 2012;7:e52010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3528721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23284853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maldonado MD, Garc&#xed;a-Moreno H, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Yanes C, Calvo JR. Possible involvement of the inhibition of NF-&#x3ba;B factor in anti-inflammatory actions that melatonin exerts on mast cells. J Cell Biochem. 2016;117:1926&#x2013;1933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26756719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan MZ, Islam S, Matsumoto K, Kawai T. Meta-analysis of single-cell RNA-seq data reveals phenotypic switching of immune cells in severe COVID-19 patients. Comput Biol Med. 2021;137:104792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8390121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34478921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardinali DP, Brown GM, Pandi-Perumal SR. An urgent proposal for the immediate use of melatonin as an adjuvant to anti-SARS-CoV-2 vaccination. Melatonin Res. 2021;4:206&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zipeto D, Palmeira JDF, Arga&#xf1;araz GA, Arga&#xf1;araz ER. ACE2/ADAM17/TMPRSS2 interplay may be the main risk factor for COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2020;11:576745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33117379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shukla M, Htoo HH, Wintachai P, Hernandez JF, Dubois C, Postina R, Xu H, Checler F, Smith DR, Govitrapong P, Vincent B. Melatonin stimulates the nonamyloidogenic processing of &#x3b2;APP through the positive transcriptional regulation of ADAM10 and ADAM17. J Pineal Res. 2015;58:151&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25491598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zlack&#xe1; J, Stebelov&#xe1; K, Zeman M, Herichov&#xe1; I. Interactions of renin-angiotensin system and COVID-19: The importance of daily rhythms in ACE2, ADAM17 and TMPRSS2 expression. Physiol Res. 2021;70(S2):S177&#x2013;S194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8884363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34913351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazra S, Chaudhuri AG, Tiwary BK, Chakrabarti N. Matrix metallopeptidase 9 as a host protein target of chloroquine and melatonin for immunoregulation in COVID-19: A network-based meta-analysis. Life Sci. 2020;257:118096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32679150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cecon E, Izabelle C, Poder SL, Real F, Zhu A, Tu L, Ghigna MR, Klonjkowski B, Bomsel M, Jockers R, Dam J. Therapeutic potential of melatonin and melatonergic drugs on K18-hACE2 mice infected with SARS-CoV-2. J Pineal Res. 2022;72:e12772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8646885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34586649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cecon E, Fernandois D, Renault N, Coelho CFF, Wenzel J, Bedart C, Izabelle C, Gallet S, Le Poder S, Klonjkowski B, et al. Melatonin drugs inhibit SARS-CoV-2 entry into the brain and virus-induced damage of cerebral small vessels. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2022;79:361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9191404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35697820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loh D. The potential of melatonin in the prevention and attenuation of oxidative hemolysis and myocardial injury from cd147 SARS-CoV-2 spike protein receptor binding. Melatonin Res. 2020;3:380&#x2013;416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morchang A, Malakar S, Poonudom K, Noisakran S, Yenchitsomanus PT, Limjindaporn T. Melatonin inhibits dengue virus infection via the sirtuin 1-mediated interferon pathway. Viruses. 2021;13:659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8070382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33920458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai X, Wang N, Jiao H, Zhang J, Li C, Ren W, Reiter RJ, Su S. Melatonin and other indoles show antiviral activities against swine coronaviruses in vitro at pharmacological concentrations. J Pineal Res. 2021;71:e12754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34139040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesarik J. Melatonin attenuates growth factor receptor signaling required for SARS-CoV-2 replication. Melatonin Res. 2020;3:534&#x2013;537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter RJ, Cardinali DP, Neel RL, Rodriguez AD, Brown GM, Tesarik J. Rationale for the continued use of melatonin to combat the delta variant of SARS-CoV-2. Melatonin Res. 2021;4:495&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klann K, Bojkova D, Tascher G, Ciesek S, M&#xfc;nch C, Cinatl J. Growth factor receptor signaling inhibition prevents SARS-CoV-2 replication. Mol Cell. 2020;80:164&#x2013;174 e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7418786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32877642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behl T, Kaur I, Aleya L, Sehgal A, Singh S, Sharma N, Bhatia S, Al-Harrasi A, Bungau S. CD147-spike protein interaction in COVID-19: Get the ball rolling with a novel receptor and therapeutic target. Sci Total Environ. 2022;808:152072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8634688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34863742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, Chen W, Zhang Z, Deng Y, Lian JQ, Du P, Wei D, Zhang Y, Sun XX, Gong L, et al. CD147-spike protein is a novel route for SARS-CoV-2 infection to host cells. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2020;5:283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7714896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33277466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed Taha A, Adel Abdelkader Saed S, Hossam-Eldin Moawad M, Abd El-Tawab Moawad W, Al-Hejazi T, Mousa Y, Sharma R, Reiter RJ. Safety and efficacy of melatonin as an adjuvant therapy in COVID-19 patients: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Adv Med Sci. 2023;68:341&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37742478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini A, Esmaeili Gouvarchin Ghaleh H, Aghamollaei H, Fasihi Ramandi M, Alishiri G, Shahriary A, Hassanpour K, Tat M, Farnoosh G. Evaluation of Th1 and Th2 mediated cellular and humoral immunity in patients with COVID-19 following the use of melatonin as an adjunctive treatment. Eur J Pharmacol. 2021;904:174193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8127523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34015316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh Z, Keyhanian N, Ghaderkhani S, Dashti-Khavidaki S, Shokouhi Shoormasti R, Pourpak Z. A Pilot study on controlling coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) inflammation using melatonin supplement. Iran J Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2021;20:494&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34418903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darban M, Malek F, Memarian M, Gohari A, Kiani A, Emadi A, Lavvaf S, Bagheri B. Efficacy of high dose vitamin C, melatonin and zinc in iranian patients with acute respiratory syndrome due to coronavirus infection: A pilot randomized trial. J Cell Mol Anesth. 2021;6:164&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farnoosh G, Akbariqomi M, Badri T, Bagheri M, Izadi M, Saeedi-Boroujeni A, Rezaie E, Ghaleh HEG, Aghamollaei H, Fasihi-Ramandi M, et al. Efficacy of a low dose of melatonin as an adjunctive therapy in hospitalized patients with COVID-19: A randomized, double-blind clinical trial. Arch Med Res. 2022;53:79&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8220995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34229896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousavi SA, Heydari K, Mehravaran H, Saeedi M, Alizadeh-Navaei R, Hedayatizadeh-Omran A, Shamshirian A. Melatonin effects on sleep quality and outcomes of COVID-19 patients: An open-label, randomized, controlled trial. J Med Virol. 2022;94:263&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34460132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavarr&#xed;a AP, V&#xe1;zquez RRV, Cherit JGD, Bello HH, Suastegui HC, Moreno-Casta&#xf1;eda L, Alan&#xed;s Estrada G, Hern&#xe1;ndez F, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Marcos O, Saucedo-Orozco H, et al. Antioxidants and pentoxifylline as coadjuvant measures to standard therapy to improve prognosis of patients with pneumonia by COVID-19. Comput Struct Biotechnol J. 2021;19:1379&#x2013;1390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7910139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33680348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaeili Gouvarchin Ghaleh H, Hosseini A, Aghamollaei H, Fasihi-Ramandi M, Alishiri G, Saeedi-Boroujeni A, Hassanpour K, Mahmoudian-Sani MR, Farnoosh G. NLRP3 inflammasome activation and oxidative stress status in the mild and moderate SARS-CoV-2 infected patients: Impact of melatonin as a medicinal supplement. Z Naturforsch C J Biosci. 2021;77:37&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34355546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bologna C, Madonna P, Pone E. Efficacy of prolonged-release melatonin 2 mg (PRM 2 mg) prescribed for insomnia in hospitalized patients for COVID-19: A retrospective observational study. J Clin Med. 2021;10:5857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8705392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34945156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>