<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34921381</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1305-7456</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of dentistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Dent</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID Oral Cavity Symptoms Based on Selected Clinical Cases.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>458</StartPage><EndPage>463</EndPage><MedlinePgn>458-463</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/s-0041-1739445</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) is characterized by variable clinical features, different durations, and several previously unheard-of late complications. Knowledge about this infection is constantly evolving.The aim of the study is to present selected cases of the most common symptoms of long COVID in the oral cavity.Among the 1,256 studied patients, 32% of them had discoloration, ulceration, and hemorrhagic changes on the oral mucosa, 29.69% had mycosis located on the tongue, 25.79% of patients had aphthous-like lesions on the hard palate, and in 12.5% atrophic cheilitis was observed. During the anamnesis, approximately 60% of patients reported salivary secretory disorders in the initial period of infection, which is 6.68% prolonged up to 4 months after systemic symptoms disappeared. In an extreme case, an aphthous-like lesion was located on the hard palate, which persisted for 6 months. Approximately 36% of patients did not agree to the proposed treatment. As a result, they only received recommendations on the use of oral hygiene products and received weekly check-ups. In this group of patients, most pathological changes spontaneously cleared after 3 weeks. The elderly with coexisting diseases, persons with a more severe SARS-CoV-2, and hospitalized patients had more extensive and severe lesions in the oral cavity that persisted for a long time after infection.In patients after the SARS-CoV-2 infection and suspected of this infection, a detailed intraoral examination should be performed, and the patient must be obligatorily monitored for a minimum period of 6 months. Depending on the patient's clinical condition, changes in the oral cavity require observation, basic or specialist treatment. In the case of changes in the cavity without pain symptoms, observation should be made for approximately 4 weeks and wait for the spontaneous regression of the changes. However, when pain occurs, a good solution is to use laser biostimulation. In the case of complex pathological changes occurring in the oral cavity, the patient should be directed for specialist treatment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>The Author(s). This is an open access article published by Thieme under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, permitting unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction so long as the original work is properly cited. (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rafa&#x142;owicz</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5509-4062</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dental Propaedeutics and Prophylaxis, Medical University of Warsaw, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wagner</LastName><ForeName>Leopold</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9769-4701</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dental Propaedeutics and Prophylaxis, Medical University of Warsaw, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rafa&#x142;owicz</LastName><ForeName>Juliusz</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stomatologia Rafa&#x142;owicz, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Dent</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101303672</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34921381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9339924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0041-1739445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>for the Zhongnan Hospital of Wuhan University Novel Coronavirus Management and Research Team, Evidence-Based Medicine Chapter of China International Exchange and Promotive Association for Medical and Health Care (CPAM) . Jin Y H, Cai L, Cheng Z S et al.A rapid advice guideline for the diagnosis and treatment of 2019 novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV) infected pneumonia (standard version) Mil Med Res. 2020;7(01):4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7003341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32029004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y R, Cao Q D, Hong Z S et al.The origin, transmission and clinical therapies on coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) outbreak - an update on the status. Mil Med Res. 2020;7(01):11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7068984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32169119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabino-Silva R, Jardim A CG, Siqueira W L. Coronavirus COVID-19 impacts to dentistry and potential salivary diagnosis. Clin Oral Investig. 2020;24(04):1619&#x2013;1621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7088419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32078048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daneshgaran G, Dubin D P, Gould D J. Cutaneous manifestations of COVID-19: an evidence-based review. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2020;21(05):627&#x2013;639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7456663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32865778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo Neto C LM, Bannwart L C, de Melo Moreno A L, Goiato M C. SARS-CoV-2 and dentistry-review. Eur J Dent. 2020;14 01:S130&#x2013;S139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7775231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32932534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradowska-Stolarz A M. Oral manifestations of COVID-19: brief review. Dent Med Probl. 2021;58(01):123&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33590976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iranmanesh B, Khalili M, Amiri R, Zartab H, Aflatoonian M. Oral manifestations of COVID-19 disease: a review article. Dermatol Ther (Heidelb) 2021;34(01):e14578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7744903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33236823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carod-Artal F J. Post-COVID-19 syndrome: epidemiology, diagnostic criteria and pathogenic mechanisms involved [in Spanish] Rev Neurol. 2021;72(11):384&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34042167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVERSCAN study investigators . Dennis A, Wamil M, Alberts J et al.Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open. 2021;11(03):e048391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanichkachorn G, Newcomb R, Cowl C T et al.Post-COVID-19 syndrome (Long Haul Syndrome): description of a multidisciplinary clinic at Mayo clinic and characteristics of the initial patient cohort. Mayo Clin Proc. 2021;96(07):1782&#x2013;1791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8112396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34218857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz Tapia R O, Peraza Labrador A J, Guimaraes D M, Matos Valdez L H. Oral mucosal lesions in patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Report of four cases. Are they a true sign of COVID-19 disease? Spec Care Dentist. 2020;40(06):555&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32882068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n Carreras-Presas C, Amaro S&#xe1;nchez J, L&#xf3;pez-S&#xe1;nchez A F, Jan&#xe9;-Salas E, Somacarrera P&#xe9;rez M L. Oral vesiculobullous lesions associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Oral Dis. 2021;27 03:710&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32369674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amorim Dos Santos J, Normando A GC, Carvalho da Silva R L et al.Oral mucosal lesions in a COVID-19 patient: new signs or secondary manifestations? Int J Infect Dis. 2020;97:326&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7280113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32526392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciccarese G, Drago F, Boatti M, Porro A, Muzic S I, Parodi A. Oral erosions and petechiae during SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Med Virol. 2021;93(01):129&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7362051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32579237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomo S, Miyahara G I, Simonato L E. Oral mucositis in a SARS-CoV-2-infected patient: secondary or truly associated condition? Oral Dis. 2020;00:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32726467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujayanto R, Indraswary R.Differential diagnosis of COVID-19 enanthema Eur J Dent 202014(S 01):S179&#x2013;S181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7775208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33242912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasseem I, Issa J, Badrah M, Klugar M. Angular cheilitis of COVID-19 patients: A case-series and literature review. Oral Dis. 2022 01:999&#x2013;1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33043573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharatha A, Kandamaran L, Krishnamurthy K. Commentary: &#x201c;Fungal infections of oral cavity: diagnosis, management, and association with COVID-19&#x201d;. SN Compr Clin Med. 2021;3:1&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8272443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34278228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riad A, Kassem I, Stanek J, Badrah M, Klugarova J, Klugar M. Aphthous stomatitis in COVID-19 patients: case-series and literature review. Dermatol Ther (Heidelb) 2021;34(01):e14735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7883083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33389769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riad A, Gomaa E, Hockova B, Klugar M. Oral candidiasis of COVID-19 patients: case report and review of evidence. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2021;20(06):1580&#x2013;1584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33713390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dziedzic A, Wojtyczka R. The impact of coronavirus infectious disease 19 (COVID-19) on oral health. Oral Dis. 2021;27 03:703&#x2013;706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32304276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezerra T M, Feitosa S G, Carneiro D TO, Costa F WG, Pires F R, Pereira K MA.Oral lesions in COVID-19 infection: Is long-term follow-up important in the affected patients? Oral Dis 2020(e-pub ahead of print)10.1111/odi.13705</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/odi.13705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33135278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xed;az Rodr&#xed;guez M, Jimenez Romera A, Villarroel M. Oral manifestations associated with COVID-19. Oral Dis. 2022 01:960&#x2013;962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7404436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32697005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paces J, Strizova Z, Smrz D, Cerny J. COVID-19 and the immune system. Physiol Res. 2020;69(03):379&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8648321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CARE Group . Gagnier J J, Kienle G, Altman D G, Moher D, Sox H, Riley D S. The CARE guidelines: consensus-based clinical case reporting guideline development. Glob Adv Health Med. 2013;2(05):38&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3833570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24416692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>