<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39415747</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2768-3613</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of integrative and complementary medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Integr Complement Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Use of Complementary and Integrative Health Approaches in Adults with Long COVID in the US, a Nationally Representative Survey.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1089/jicm.2024.0283</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b><i>Background:</i></b> Long COVID is a serious, complex condition that has affected the lives of millions of people globally. Complementary and integrative health (CIH) approaches offer a wide range of potential therapies for the management of long COVID symptoms. However, there is limited information available about the utilization of CIH among long COVID patients. <b><i>Methods:</i></b> Nationally representative cross-sectional data from the United States 2022 National Health Interview Survey (NHIS, response rate 47.7%, <i>n</i> = 27,651) were used to investigate prevalence and predictors of CIH use in the past 12 months among individuals who experienced long COVID. The 12-month prevalence of CIH use was descriptively analyzed for those with long COVID versus those without using chi-squared tests or unpaired <i>t</i>-tests. Independent predictors of CIH use among individuals with long COVID were analyzed using a stepwise multiple logistic regression analysis. <b><i>Results:</i></b> A weighted total of 17,610,801 US adults (19.7%) who had a confirmed case of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) developed long COVID symptoms. A slightly greater proportion of individuals with long COVID (44.4%) than those without (40.9%) used CIH approaches in the past 12 months. The most used approaches were meditation, yoga, and massage therapy. CIH use by those with long COVID was significantly associated with younger age, female sex, higher education level, having health insurance coverage, higher household income level, receiving three or more COVID-19 vaccination doses, ever having asthma, and ever having an anxiety or depression diagnosis. <b><i>Conclusions:</i></b> Long COVID represents a major challenge for patients, health care providers, health care systems, economies, and global public health. CIH approaches may play an important role in symptom management for some patients, and additional research is needed to identify which modalities are most effective. Patients and health care providers may benefit from better information about the available options for treatment.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grout</LastName><ForeName>Leah</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4427-7314</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Southern California University of Health Sciences, Whittier, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Integr Complement Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918283075806676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2768-3605</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complementary and alternative medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complementary and integrative health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post COVID-19 condition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39415747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jicm.2024.0283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>