<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38024037</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical Approach to Post-acute Sequelae After COVID-19 Infection and Vaccination.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e49204</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e49204</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e49204</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.49204</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The spike protein of SARS-CoV-2 has been found to exhibit pathogenic characteristics and be a possible cause of post-acute sequelae after SARS-CoV-2 infection or COVID-19 vaccination. COVID-19 vaccines utilize a modified, stabilized prefusion spike protein that may share similar toxic effects with its viral counterpart. The aim of this study is to investigate possible mechanisms of harm to biological systems from SARS-CoV-2 spike protein and vaccine-encoded spike protein and to propose possible mitigation strategies. We searched PubMed, Google Scholar, and 'grey literature' to find studies that (1) investigated the effects of the spike protein on biological systems, (2) helped differentiate between viral and vaccine-generated spike proteins, and (3) identified possible spike protein detoxification protocols and compounds that had signals of benefit and acceptable safety profiles.&#xa0;We found abundant evidence that SARS-CoV-2 spike protein may cause damage in the cardiovascular, hematological, neurological, respiratory, gastrointestinal, and immunological systems. Viral and vaccine-encoded spike proteins have been shown to&#xa0;play a direct role in cardiovascular and thrombotic injuries from both SARS-CoV-2 and vaccination. Detection of spike protein for at least 6-15 months after vaccination and infection in those with post-acute sequelae indicates&#xa0;spike protein as a possible primary contributing factor to long COVID. We rationalized that these findings give support to the potential benefit of spike protein detoxification protocols in those with long-term post-infection and/or vaccine-induced complications. We propose a base spike detoxification protocol, composed of oral nattokinase, bromelain, and curcumin. This approach holds immense promise as a base of clinical care, upon which additional therapeutic agents are applied with the goal of aiding in the resolution of post-acute sequelae after SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19 vaccination. Large-scale, prospective, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trials are warranted in order to determine the relative risks and benefits of the base spike detoxification protocol.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023, Hulscher et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hulscher</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epidemiology, Unversity of Michigan School of Public Health, Ann Arbor, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Procter</LastName><ForeName>Brian C</ForeName><Initials>BC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, McKinney Family Medicine, McKinney, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wynn</LastName><ForeName>Cade</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, McKinney Family Medicine, McKinney, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCullough</LastName><ForeName>Peter A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Cardiology, McKinney Family Medicine, McKinney, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, Epidemiology, and Public Health, McCullough Foundation, Dallas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19 treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19 vaccines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute sequelae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sars-cov-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sars-cov-2 spike protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spike glycoprotein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spike protein detoxification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment protocol</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>PM receives partial salary support and holds an equity position in The Wellness Company, Boca Raton, Florida, which had no role in this study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38024037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10663976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.49204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>An update on COVID-19: SARS-CoV-2 variants, antiviral drugs, and vaccines. Hillary VE, Ceasar SA. Heliyon. 2023;9:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9946785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36855648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard.  [
Nov;
2023 
]. 2023. https://covid19.who.int/ https://covid19.who.int/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comprehensive review of SARS-CoV-2 vaccines: Pfizer, Moderna &amp; Johnson &amp; Johnson. Patel R, Kaki M, Potluri VS, Kahar P, Khanna D. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2022;18:2002083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8862159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35130825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 spike protein: pathogenesis, vaccines, and potential therapies. Almehdi AM, Khoder G, Alchakee AS, Alsayyid AT, Sarg NH, Soliman SS. Infection. 2021;49:855&#x2013;876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8326314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A retrospective analysis of clinically confirmed long post-COVID vaccination syndrome. Finterer J, Scorza FA. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9706319/ J Clin Transl Res. 2022;8:506&#x2013;508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9706319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36452006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short-term and long-term rates of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a systematic review. Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE, et al. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34643720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The prevalence of post-COVID-19 vaccination syndrome and quality of life among COVID-19-vaccinated individuals [IN PRESS] Shrestha Y, Venkataraman R. Vacunas. 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The frequency and patterns of post-COVID-19 vaccination syndrome reveal initially mild and potentially Immunocytopenic signs in primarily young Saudi women. Said KB, Al-Otaibi A, Aljaloud L, Al-Anazi B, Alsolami A, Alreshidi FS. Vaccines (Basel) 2022;10:1015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9323608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35891179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Could SARS-CoV-2 spike protein be responsible for long-COVID syndrome? Theoharides TC. Mol Neurobiol. 2022;59:1850&#x2013;1861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8757925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35028901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: pathophysiological factors and abnormalities of coagulation. Turner S, Khan MA, Putrino D, Woodcock A, Kell DB, Pretorius E. Trends Endocrinol Metab. 2023;34:321&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10113134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37080828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2018;Spikeopathy&#x2019;: COVID-19 spike protein is pathogenic, from both virus and vaccine mRNA. Parry PI, Lefringhausen A, Turni C, Neil CJ, Cosford R, Hudson NJ, Gillespie J. Biomedicines. 2023;11:2287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10452662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37626783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The SARS-CoV-2 spike protein disrupts human cardiac pericytes function through CD147 receptor-mediated signalling: a potential non-infective mechanism of COVID-19 microvascular disease. Avolio E, Carrabba M, Milligan R, et al. Clin Sci (Lond) 2021;135:2667&#x2013;2689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8674568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34807265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spike protein impairs mitochondrial function in human cardiomyocytes: mechanisms underlying cardiac injury in COVID-19. Huynh TV, Rethi L, Lee TW, Higa S, Kao YH, Chen YJ. Cells. 2023;12:877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10046940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36980218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 spike protein-mediated cardiomyocyte fusion may contribute to increased arrhythmic risk in COVID-19. Clemens DJ, Ye D, Zhou W, et al. PLoS One. 2023;18:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9994677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36888581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Circulating spike protein detected in post-COVID-19 mRNA vaccine myocarditis. Yonker LM, Swank Z, Bartsch YC, et al. Circulation. 2023;147:867&#x2013;876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10010667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36597886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intramyocardial Inflammation after COVID-19 vaccination: an endomyocardial biopsy-proven case series. Baumeier C, Aleshcheva G, Harms D, et al. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:6940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9266869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35805941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The spike protein of SARS-CoV-2 induces endothelial inflammation through integrin &#x3b1;5&#x3b2;1 and NF-&#x3ba;B signaling. Robles JP, Zamora M, Adan-Castro E, Siqueiros-Marquez L, Martinez de la Escalera G, Clapp C. J Biol Chem. 2022;298:101695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8820157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 spike protein S1 induces fibrin(ogen) resistant to fibrinolysis: implications for microclot formation in COVID-19. Grobbelaar LM, Venter C, Vlok M, et al. Biosci Rep. 2021;41:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8380922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34328172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 spike protein causes blood coagulation and thrombosis by competitive binding to heparan sulfate. Zheng Y, Zhao J, Li J, et al. Int J Biol Macromol. 2021;193:1124&#x2013;1129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8553634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34743814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evidence of SARS-CoV-2 spike protein on retrieved thrombi from COVID-19 patients. De Michele M, d'Amati G, Leopizzi M, et al. J Hematol Oncol. 2022;15:108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9380658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35974404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 spike protein disrupts blood-brain barrier integrity via RhoA activation. DeOre BJ, Tran KA, Andrews AM, Ramirez SH, Galie PA. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2021;16:722&#x2013;728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8536479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34687399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 spike protein induces cognitive deficit and anxiety-like behavior in mouse via non-cell autonomous hippocampal neuronal death. Oh J, Cho WH, Barcelon E, Kim KH, Hong J, Lee SJ. Sci Rep. 2022;12:5496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8970073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35361832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spike proteins of SARS-CoV-2 induce pathological changes in molecular delivery and metabolic function in the brain endothelial cells. Kim ES, Jeon MT, Kim KS, Lee S, Kim S, Kim DG. Viruses. 2021;13:2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8538996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34696455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 Spike protein induces TLR4-mediated long-term cognitive dysfunction recapitulating post-COVID-19 syndrome in mice. Fontes-Dantas FL, Fernandes GG, Gutman EG, et al. Cell Rep. 2023;42:112189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9935273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36857178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The SARS-CoV-2 S1 spike protein promotes MAPK and NF-kB activation in human lung cells and inflammatory cytokine production in human lung and intestinal epithelial cells. Forsyth CB, Zhang L, Bhushan A, et al. Microorganisms. 2022;10:1996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9607240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36296272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 spike protein activates human lung macrophages. Palestra F, Poto R, Ciardi R, et al. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24:3036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9917796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36769357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 spike protein induces lung endothelial cell dysfunction and thrombo-inflammation depending on the C3a/C3a receptor signalling. Perico L, Morigi M, Pezzotta A, et al. Sci Rep. 2023;13:11392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10349115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37452090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 spike spurs intestinal inflammation via VEGF production in enterocytes. Zeng FM, Li YW, Deng ZH, et al. EMBO Mol Med. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9081906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35362189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 spike protein in intestinal cells of a patient with coronavirus disease 2019 multisystem inflammatory syndrome. Mayordomo-Colunga J, Vivanco-Allende A, L&#xf3;pez-Alonso I, L&#xf3;pez-Mart&#xed;nez C, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Vega I, Gil-Pe&#xf1;a H, Rey C. J Pediatr. 2022;243:214&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8626144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34843710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinoza VE, Emmady PD. StatPearls. Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; 2023. Histology, monocytes.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32491550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of different types of recombinant SARS-CoV-2 spike protein on circulating monocytes&#x2019; structure. Vettori M, Dima F, Henry BM, et al. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24:9373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10253607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37298324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The S1 subunit of the SARS-CoV-2 spike protein activates human monocytes to produce cytokines linked to COVID-19: relevance to galectin-3. Schroeder JT, Bieneman AP. Front Immunol. 2022;13:831763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8982143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35392091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 spike protein induces a differential monocyte activation that may contribute to age bias in COVID-19 severity. Ait-Belkacem I, Cartagena Garc&#xed;a C, Millet-Wallisky E, et al. Sci Rep. 2022;12:20824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9716544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36460710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistence of SARS CoV-2 S1 protein in CD16+ monocytes in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) up to 15 months post-infection. Patterson BK, Francisco EB, Yogendra R, et al. Front Immunol. 2021;12:746021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8784688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An evidence that SARS-CoV-2/COVID-19 spike protein (SP) damages hematopoietic stem/progenitor cells in the mechanism of pyroptosis in Nlrp3 inflammasome-dependent manner. Kucia M, Ratajczak J, Bujko K, et al. Leukemia. 2021;35:3026&#x2013;3029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8219510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccine design enabled by prototype pathogen preparedness. Corbett KS, Edwards DK, Leist SR, et al. Nature. 2020;586:567&#x2013;571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7581537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32756549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cryo-EM structure of the 2019-nCoV spike in the prefusion conformation. Wrapp D, Wang N, Corbett KS, et al. Science. 2020;367:1260&#x2013;1263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7164637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32075877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Detection of recombinant Spike protein in the blood of individuals vaccinated against SARS-CoV-2: possible molecular mechanisms. Brogna C, Cristoni S, Marino G, et al. Proteomics Clin Appl. 2023:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37650258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent circulation of soluble and extracellular vesicle-linked Spike protein in individuals with postacute sequelae of COVID-19. Craddock V, Mahajan A, Spikes L, et al. J Med Virol. 2023;95:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10048846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36756925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A systematic review of autopsy findings in deaths after COVID-19 vaccination [PREPRINT] Hulscher N, Alexander P, Amerling R, et al. Zenodo. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39120477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thrombotic complications of COVID-19. Avila J, Long B, Holladay D, Gottlieb M. Am J Emerg Med. 2021;39:213&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7528743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33036855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical rationale for SARS-CoV-2 base spike protein detoxification in post COVID-19 and vaccine injury syndromes. McCullough PA, Wynn C, Procter BC. https://jpands.org/vol28no3/mccullough.pdf J Am Physicians Surg. 2023;28:90&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Microbial nattokinase: from synthesis to potential application. Sheng Y, Yang J, Wang C, Sun X, Yan L. Food Funct. 2023;14:2568&#x2013;2585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36857725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nattokinase: production and application. Dabbagh F, Negahdaripour M, Berenjian A, et al. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol. 2014;98:9199&#x2013;9206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25348469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natto extract, a Japanese fermented soybean food, directly inhibits viral infections including SARS-CoV-2 in&#xa0;vitro. Oba M, Rongduo W, Saito A, et al. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2021;570:21&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8276596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34271432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degradative effect of nattokinase on spike protein of SARS-CoV-2. Tanikawa T, Kiba Y, Yu J, et al. Molecules. 2022;27:5405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9458005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36080170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A single-dose of oral nattokinase potentiates thrombolysis and anti-coagulation profiles. Kurosawa Y, Nirengi S, Homma T, Esaki K, Ohta M, Clark JF, Hamaoka T. Sci Rep. 2015;5:11601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4479826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26109079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The cysteine proteinases of the pineapple plant. Rowan AD, Buttle DJ, Barrett AJ. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1131219/ Biochem J. 1990;266:869&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1131219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2327970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>On the pharmacology of bromelain: an update with special regard to animal studies on dose-dependent effects. Lotz-Winter H. Planta Med. 1990;56:249&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2203073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The combination of bromelain and curcumin as an immune-boosting nutraceutical in the prevention of severe COVID-19. Kritis P, Karampela I, Kokoris S, Dalamaga M. Metabol Open. 2020;8:100066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7661945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33205039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The combination of bromelain and acetylcysteine (Bromac) synergistically inactivates SARS-CoV-2. Akhter J, Qu&#xe9;rom&#xe8;s G, Pillai K, et al. Viruses. 2021;13:425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7999995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33800932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromelain: biochemistry, pharmacology and medical use. Maurer HR. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2001;58:1234&#x2013;1245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11337410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11577981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromelain a potential bioactive compound: a comprehensive overview from a pharmacological perspective. Chakraborty AJ, Mitra S, Tallei TE, et al. Life (Basel) 2021;11:317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8067380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anti-infective properties of the golden spice curcumin. Praditya D, Kirchhoff L, Br&#xfc;ning J, Rachmawati H, Steinmann J, Steinmann E. Front Microbiol. 2019;10:912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6509173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31130924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curcumin, a traditional spice component, can hold the promise against COVID-19? Soni VK, Mehta A, Ratre YK, et al. Eur J Pharmacol. 2020;886:173551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32931783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curcumin inhibits spike protein of new SARS-CoV-2 variant of concern (VOC) Omicron, an in silico study. Nag A, Banerjee R, Paul S, Kundu R. Comput Biol Med. 2022;146:105552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9044632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35508082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Promising clinical outcomes of nano-curcumin treatment as an adjunct therapy in hospitalized COVID-19 patients: a randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial. Sadeghizadeh M, Asadollahi E, Jahangiri B, et al. Phytother Res. 2023;37:3631&#x2013;3644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37118944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A triple-blind, placebo-controlled, randomized clinical trial to evaluate the effect of curcumin-containing nanomicelles on cellular immune responses subtypes and clinical outcome in COVID-19 patients. Hassaniazad M, Eftekhar E, Inchehsablagh BR, et al. Phytother Res. 2021;35:6417&#x2013;6427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34541720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phase I clinical trial of curcumin, a chemopreventive agent, in patients with high-risk or pre-malignant lesions. Cheng AL, Hsu CH, Lin JK, et al.  https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11712783/ Anticancer Res. 2001;21:2895&#x2013;2900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11712783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curcumin formulations for better bioavailability: what we learned from clinical trials thus far? Hegde M, Girisa S, BharathwajChetty B, Vishwa R, Kunnumakkara AB. ACS Omega. 2023;8:10713&#x2013;10746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10061533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37008131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hydroxychloroquine blocks SARS-CoV-2 entry into the endocytic pathway in mammalian cell culture. Yuan Z, Pavel MA, Wang H, et al. Commun Biol. 2022;5:958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9472185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36104427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HCQ for COVID-19: real-time meta analysis of 413 studies.  [
Nov;
2023 
];https://c19hcq.org/meta.html c19hcq. 2023 2023:9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety and efficacy of hydroxychloroquine in 152 outpatients with confirmed COVID-19: a pilot observational study. Sogut O, Can MM, Guven R, et al. Am J Emerg Med. 2021;40:41&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33348222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colchicine for the treatment of COVID-19 patients: efficacy, safety, and model informed dosage regimens. Karatza E, Ismailos G, Karalis V. Xenobiotica. 2021;51:643&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8054498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33845715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of low-dose colchicine in patients with coronary disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized trials. Fiolet AT, Opstal TS, Mosterd A, et al. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:2765&#x2013;2775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33769515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colchicine for the treatment of myocardial injury in patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19)&#x2014;an old drug with new life? Rabbani AB, Parikh RV, Rafique AM. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32579190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A rare case of pleurodynia after the COVID-19 vaccine. Ajala O, Azhar A, Kalaji W, et al. Chest. 2022;162:0&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colchicine for community-treated patients with COVID-19 (COLCORONA): a phase 3, randomised, double-blinded, adaptive, placebo-controlled, multicentre trial. Tardif JC, Bouabdallaoui N, L'Allier PL, et al. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:924&#x2013;932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8159193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34051877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety and efficacy of colchicine in COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized control trials. Yasmin F, Najeeb H, Moeed A, et al. PLoS One. 2022;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8982874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35381033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conformational perturbation of SARS-CoV-2 spike protein using N-acetyl cysteine, a molecular scissor: a probable strategy to combat COVID-19 [PREPRINT] Debnath U, Dewaker V, Prabhakar YS, Bhattacharyya P, Mandal A. ChemRxiv. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37477247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The function of SARS-CoV-2 spike protein is impaired by disulfide-bond disruption with mutation at cysteine-488 and by thiol-reactive N-acetyl-cysteine and glutathione. Murae M, Shimizu Y, Yamamoto Y, et al. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2022;597:30&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8800159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35123263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potential therapeutic effects of ivermectin in COVID-19. Barati N, Motavallihaghi S, Nikfar B, Chaichian S, Momtazi-Borojeni AA. Exp Biol Med (Maywood) 2022;247:1388&#x2013;1396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9442455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35686662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molecular docking studies of apigenin, kaempferol, and quercetin as potential target against spike receptor protein of SARS CoV. Tuli H, Sood S, Pundir A, et al. J Exp Biol Agric Sci. 2022;10:144&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Two important controversial risk factors in SARS-CoV-2 infection: obesity and smoking. Engin AB, Engin ED, Engin A. Environ Toxicol Pharmacol. 2020;78:103411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7227557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicotinic receptors as SARS-CoV-2 spike co-receptors? Dormoy V, Perotin JM, Gosset P, Maskos U, Polette M, Desl&#xe9;e G. Med Hypotheses. 2022;158:110741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8669939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34924680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emodin blocks the SARS coronavirus spike protein and angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 interaction. Ho TY, Wu SL, Chen JC, Li CC, Hsiang CY. Antiviral Res. 2007;74:92&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7114332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16730806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Targeting SARS-CoV-2 spike protein of COVID-19 with naturally occurring phytochemicals: an in silico study for drug development. Pandey P, Rane JS, Chatterjee A, Kumar A, Khan R, Prakash A, Ray S. J Biomol Struct Dyn. 2021;39:6306&#x2013;6316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7441770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32698689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein as inhibitory target for Insilico screening of natural compounds. Omoboyowa DA, Balogun TA, Chukwudozie O, et al. Biointerface Res Appl Chem. 2021;11:14974&#x2013;14985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silibinin as potential tool against SARS-CoV-2: in silico spike receptor-binding domain and main protease molecular docking analysis, and in vitro endothelial protective effects. Speciale A, Muscar&#xe0; C, Molonia MS, Cimino F, Saija A, Giofr&#xe8; SV. Phytother Res. 2021;35:4616&#x2013;4625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33822421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N-acetylcysteine (NAC): impacts on human health. Ten&#xf3;rio MC, Graciliano NG, Moura FA, Oliveira AC, Goulart MO. Antioxidants (Basel) 2021;10:967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8234027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34208683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of micellized food supplements on health-related quality of life in patients with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome.  [
Nov;
2023 
]. 2022. https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT05150782?cond=Long%20COVID&amp;term=Post%20Acute%20Sequelae%20of%20COVID-19&amp;intr=Curcumin&amp;rank=1 https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT05150782?cond=Long%20COVID&amp;term=Post%20Acute%20Sequelae%20of%20COVID-19&amp;intr=Curcumin&amp;rank=1</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>