<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39261313</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-8491</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European archives of psychiatry and clinical neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-COVID syndrome - novel clinical findings.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00406-024-01908-7</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adorjan</LastName><ForeName>Kristina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Psychiatric Phenomics and Genomics (IPPG), LMU University Hospital, LMU Munich, Germany. kristina.adorjan@unibe.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, University of Bern, Bolligenstr. 111, Bern, 3000, Switzerland. kristina.adorjan@unibe.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martins-de-Souza</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroproteomics, Institute of Biology, University of Campinas, Campinas, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walter</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, University of Jena, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9103030</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0940-1334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post COVID</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39261313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00406-024-01908-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00406-024-01908-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Global Burden of Disease Long COVID Collaborators (2022) Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA 328(16):1604&#x2013;1615. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2022.18931 PMID: 36215063; PMCID: PMC9552043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.18931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9552043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antunes ASLM, Reis-de-Oliveira G, Martins-de-Souza D (2024) Molecular overlaps of neurological manifestations of COVID-19 and schizophrenia from a proteomic perspective. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. Jul 19. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00406-024-01842-8 . Epub ahead of print. PMID: 39028452</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruzicka M, Sachenbacher S, Heimkes F, Uebleis AO, Karch S, Grosse-Wentrup F, Ibarra Fonseca GJ, Wunderlich N, Bogner J, Mayerle J, von Bergwelt-Baildon M, Falkai P, Subklewe M, Ruzicka T, Benesch C, Valdinoci E, Pernpruner A, Thomas A, Heindl B, Stubbe HC, Adorjan K (2024) Characterization of cognitive symptoms in post COVID-19 patients. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. May 13. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00406-024-01821-z . Epub ahead of print. PMID: 38739263</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Yuan M, He D, Dang W, Zhang W (2024) Long-term follow-up of brain regional changes and the association with cognitive impairment in quarantined COVID-19 survivors. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. Feb 6. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00406-023-01741-4 . Epub ahead of print. PMID: 38319396</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shil RSK, Hughes TW, Sargent BF, Huang Y, Tamborska AA, Frank B, Ellul MA, Michael BD (2023) A clinical approach to the investigation and management of long COVID associated neuropathic pain. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. Dec 8. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00406-023-01721-8 . Epub ahead of print. PMID: 38063895</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rueb M, Ruzicka M, Fonseca GJI, Valdinoci E, Benesch C, Pernpruner A, von Baum M, Remi J, Jebrini T, Sch&#xf6;berl F, Straube A, Stubbe HC, Adorjan K (2024) Headache severity in patients with post COVID-19 condition: a case-control study. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. Jun 25. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00406-024-01850-8 . Epub ahead of print. PMID: 38914852</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruzicka M, Ibarra Fonseca GJ, Sachenbacher S, Heimkes F, Grosse-Wentrup F, Wunderlich N, Benesch C, Pernpruner A, Valdinoci E, Rueb M, Uebleis AO, Karch S, Bogner J, Mayerle J, von Bergwelt-Baildon M, Subklewe M, Heindl B, Stubbe HC, Adorjan K (2023 Nov) Substantial differences in perception of disease severity between post COVID-19 patients, internists, and psychiatrists or psychologists: the Health Perception Gap and its clinical implications. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci 13. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00406-023-01700-z Epub ahead of print. PMID: 37955681</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helbing DL, Dommaschk EM, Danyeli LV, Liepinsh E, Refisch A, Sen ZD, Zvejniece L, Rockt&#xe4;schel T, Stabenow LK, Schi&#xf6;th HB, Walter M, Dambrova M, Besteher B (2024) Conceptual foundations of acetylcarnitine supplementation in neuropsychiatric long COVID syndrome: a narrative review. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. Jan 3. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00406-023-01734-3 . Epub ahead of print. PMID: 38172332</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gloeckl R, Leitl D, Schneeberger T, Jarosch I, Koczulla AR (2023) Rehabilitative interventions in patients with persistent post COVID-19 symptoms-a review of recent advances and future perspectives. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. Jun 16. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00406-023-01631-9 . Epub ahead of print. PMID: 37326700</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmid S, Uecker C, Fr&#xf6;hlich A, Langhorst J (2024) Effects of an integrative multimodal inpatient program on fatigue and work ability in patients with Post-COVID Syndrome-a prospective observational study. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. Apr 5. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00406-024-01792-1 . Epub ahead of print. PMID: 38578435</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>