<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38506116</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1520-6777</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurourology and urodynamics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurourol Urodyn</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does COVID-19 cause or worsen LUT dysfunction, what are the mechanisms and possible treatments? ICI-RS 2023.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1458</StartPage><EndPage>1463</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1458-1463</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/nau.25441</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) causes coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) and produced a worldwide pandemic in 2020. There have been 770,875,433 confirmed cases and 6,959,316 attributed deaths worldwide until September 19, 2023. The virus can also affect the lower urinary tract (LUT) leading to bladder inflammation and producing lower urinary tract symptoms (LUTS) in both the acute and chronic phases of disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">At the 2023 meeting of the International Consultation on Incontinence-Research Society (ICI-RS), the literature relating to COVID-19 and bladder dysfunction was reviewed. The LUTS&#xa0;reported, as well as the pathophysiology of these bladder symptoms, were the subject of considerable discussion. A number of different topics were discussed including lower LUTS reported in COVID-19, how SARS-CoV-2 may infect and affect the urinary tract, and proposed mechanisms for how viral infection result in new, worsened, and in some persisting LUTS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The workshop discussed the interaction between the virus and the immune system, covering current evidence supporting theories underlying the causes of acute and chronic LUTS related to COVID-19 infection. Research questions for further investigation were suggested and identified.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors. Neurourology and Urodynamics published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khullar</LastName><ForeName>Vik</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4775-7495</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urogynaecology, St Mary's Hospital, Imperial College, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lemmon</LastName><ForeName>Berni</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7280-656X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urogynaecology, St Mary's Hospital, Imperial College, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Acar</LastName><ForeName>Omer</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6094-9264</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, University of Illinois, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abrams</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2776-2200</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bristol Urological Institute, Southmead Hospital Bristol, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vahabi</LastName><ForeName>Bahareh</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7186-0943</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Applied Sciences, University of the West of England, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neurourol Urodyn</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8303326</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0733-2467</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059411" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lower Urinary Tract Symptoms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID&#x2010;19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long&#x2010;COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lower urinary tract symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urinary frequency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urinary urgency</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38506116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nau.25441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Valderrama&#x2010;Beltran S, Cuervo&#x2010;Rojas J, Martinez&#x2010;Vernaza S, Alvarez&#x2010;Moreno CA, Rodriguez&#x2010;Morales AJ. SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 vaccination strategies: should the extended dosing interval strategy be implemented in future pandemics? Travel Med Infect Dis. 2023;56:102650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei P, Zhang L, Han P, et al. Liver injury in patients with COVID&#x2010;19: clinical profiles, CT findings, the correlation of the severity with liver injury. Hepatol Int. 2020;14(5):733&#x2010;742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishiga M, Wang DW, Han Y, Lewis DB, Wu JC. COVID&#x2010;19 and cardiovascular disease: from basic mechanisms to clinical perspectives. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2020;17(9):543&#x2010;558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E, Venter C, Laubscher GJ, et al. Prevalence of symptoms, comorbidities, fibrin amyloid microclots and platelet pathology in individuals with long COVID/post&#x2010;acute sequelae of COVID&#x2010;19 (PASC). Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballering AV, van Zon SKR, Olde Hartman TC, Rosmalen JGM. Persistence of somatic symptoms after COVID&#x2010;19 in the Netherlands: an observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022;400(10350):452&#x2010;461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID&#x2010;19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603&#x2010;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;fstr&#xf6;m E, Kunkel S, K&#xf6;tz A, Lingman M, Und&#xe9;n J, Nygren JM. Health&#x2010;related quality of life and long&#x2010;term symptoms among patients with non&#x2010;severe covid&#x2010;19&#x2014;a prospective cohort study. Infect Dis. 2023;55(4):272&#x2010;281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grabbert M, Mumm JN, Klehr B, et al. Extended follow&#x2010;up of the AdVance XP male sling in the treatment of male urinary stress incontinence after 48 months: results of a prospective and multicenter study. Neurourol Urodyn. 2019;38(7):1973&#x2010;1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhar N, Dhar S, Timar R, Lucas S, Lamb LE, Chancellor MB. De novo urinary symptoms associated with COVID&#x2010;19: COVID&#x2010;19&#x2010;associated cystitis. J Clin Med Res. 2020;12(10):681&#x2010;682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin D, Wirtheim E, Vetter P, et al. Long&#x2010;term consequences of COVID&#x2010;19: research needs. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20(10):1115&#x2010;1117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng YT, Chuang YC, Shu CC, Hung CC, Hsu CF, Wang JY. Empirical use of fluoroquinolones improves the survival of critically ill patients with tuberculosis mimicking severe pneumonia. Crit Care. 2012;16(5):R207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luciani LG, Gallo F, Malossini G. Re: Jan&#x2010;Niclas Mumm, Andreas Osterman, Michael Ruzicka, et al. Urinary Frequency as a Possible Overlooked Symptom in COVID&#x2010;19 Patients: Does SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 Cause Viral Cystitis? Eur Urol. In press. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.eururo.2020.05.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severe Involvement of the Urinary Tract During COVID&#x2010;19 Infection. Eur Urol. 2020;78(3):e129&#x2010;e130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can O, Otunctemur A. Impact of coronavirus disease on the management of lower urinary tract symptoms and voiding dysfunction. Curr Opin Urol. 2022;32(2):141&#x2010;145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daryanto B, Janardhana A, Purnomo A. The effect of Covid&#x2010;19 severity on lower urinary tract symptoms manifestations. Med Arch. 2022;76(2):127&#x2010;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mumm JN, Osterman A, Ruzicka M, et al. Urinary frequency as a possibly overlooked symptom in COVID&#x2010;19 patients: does SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 cause viral cystitis? Eur Urol. 2020;78(4):624&#x2010;628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya Y, Kaya C, Kartal T, Tahta T, Tokg&#xf6;z VY. Could LUTS be early symptoms of COVID&#x2010;19. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75(3):e13850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb LE, Timar R, Wills M, et al. Long COVID and COVID&#x2010;19&#x2010;associated cystitis (CAC). Int Urol Nephrol. 2022;54(1):17&#x2010;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welk B, Richard L, Braschi E, Averbeck MA. Is coronavirus disease 2019 associated with indicators of long&#x2010;term bladder dysfunction? Neurourol Urodyn. 2021;40(5):1200&#x2010;1206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marand AJB, Bach C, Janssen D, et al. Lower urinary tract signs and symptoms in patients with COVID&#x2010;19. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb LE, Dhar N, Timar R, Wills M, Dhar S, Chancellor MB. COVID&#x2010;19 inflammation results in urine cytokine elevation and causes COVID&#x2010;19 associated cystitis (CAC). Med Hypotheses. 2020;145:110375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou X, Chen K, Zou J, Han P, Hao J, Han Z. Single&#x2010;cell RNA&#x2010;seq data analysis on the receptor ACE2 expression reveals the potential risk of different human organs vulnerable to 2019&#x2010;nCoV infection. Front&#xa0;Med. 2020;14(2):185&#x2010;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szukiewicz D, Wojdasiewicz P, Watroba M, Szewczyk G. Mast cell activation syndrome in COVID&#x2010;19 and female reproductive function: theoretical background vs. accumulating clinical evidence. J Immunol Res. 2022;2022:9534163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haghpanah A, Masjedi F, Salehipour M, Hosseinpour A, Roozbeh J, Dehghani A. Is COVID&#x2010;19 a risk factor for progression of benign prostatic hyperplasia and exacerbation of its related symptoms?: a systematic review. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis. 2022;25(1):27&#x2010;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvi I, D&#xf6;nmez MI, Ziylan O, Oktar T. Urodynamically proven lower urinary tract dysfunction in children after COVID&#x2010;19: a case series. Low&#xa0;Urin&#xa0;Tract Symptoms. 2022;14(4):301&#x2010;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breyer BN, Van den Eeden SK, Horberg MA, et al. HIV status is an independent risk factor for reporting lower urinary tract symptoms. J Urol. 2011;185(5):1710&#x2010;1715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro NM, Freitas DM, Rodrigues Jr. W, Muniz Jr. A, Oliveira P, Carvalho EM. Urodynamic features of the voiding dysfunction in HTLV&#x2010;1 infected individuals. Int&#xa0;Braz J Urol. 2007;33(2):238&#x2010;244</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>discussion 244&#x2010;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro NM, Rodrigues W, Freitas Jr DM, Muniz A, Oliveira P, Carvalho EM. Urinary symptoms associated with human T&#x2010;cell lymphotropic virus type I infection: evidence of urinary manifestations in large group of HTLV&#x2010;I carriers. Urology. 2007;69(5):813&#x2010;818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson CB, Farzan M, Chen B, Choe H. Mechanisms of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 entry into cells. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2022;23(1):3&#x2010;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga Z, Flammer AJ, Steiger P, et al. Endothelial cell infection and endotheliitis in COVID&#x2010;19. Lancet. 2020;395(10234):1417&#x2010;1418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyagi P, Tyagi V, Qu X, Chuang YC, Kuo HC, Chancellor M. Elevated CXC chemokines in urine noninvasively discriminate OAB from UTI. Am&#xa0;J&#xa0;Physiol Renal Physiol. 2016;311(3):F548&#x2010;F554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcoran AT, Yoshimura N, Tyagi V, Jacobs B, Leng W, Tyagi P. Mapping the cytokine profile of painful bladder syndrome/interstitial cystitis in human bladder and urine specimens. World J Urol. 2013;31(1):241&#x2010;246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyagi P, Barclay D, Zamora R, et al. Urine cytokines suggest an inflammatory response in the overactive bladder: a pilot study. Int Urol Nephrol. 2010;42(3):629&#x2010;635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna C, Cristoni S, Petrillo M, Querci M, Piazza O, Van den Eede G. Toxin&#x2010;like peptides in plasma, urine and faecal samples from COVID&#x2010;19 patients. F1000Research. 2021;10:550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna C, Cristoni S, Brogna B, et al. Toxin&#x2010;like peptides from the bacterial cultures derived from gut microbiome infected by SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2&#x2010;new data for a possible role in the long COVID pattern. Biomedicines. 2022;11(1):87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx V. Scientists set out to connect the dots on long COVID. Nat&#xa0;Methods. 2021;18(5):449&#x2010;453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebman AW, Aucott JN. Post&#x2010;treatment lyme disease as a model for persistent symptoms in lyme disease. Front Med. 2020;7:57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrillo M, Brogna C, Cristoni S, Querci M, Piazza O, Van den Eede G. Increase of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 RNA load in faecal samples prompts for rethinking of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 biology and COVID&#x2010;19 epidemiology. F1000Research. 2021;10:370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna C, Brogna B, Bisaccia DR, et al. Could SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 have bacteriophage behavior or induce the activity of other bacteriophages?Vaccines (Basel). 2022;10(5):708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo T, Liu Q, Zhang F, et al. Depicting SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 faecal viral activity in association with gut microbiota composition in patients with COVID&#x2010;19. Gut. 2021;70(2):276&#x2010;284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ancona G, Alagna L, Alteri C, et al. Gut and airway microbiota dysbiosis and their role in COVID&#x2010;19 and long&#x2010;COVID. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1080043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panicker JN, Marcelissen T, von Gontard A, Vrijens D, Abrams P, Wyndaele M. Bladder&#x2010;bowel interactions: do we understand pelvic organ cross&#x2010;sensitization? International Consultation on Incontinence Research Society (ICI&#x2010;RS) 2018. Neurourol Urodyn. 2019;38(suppl 5):S25&#x2010;S34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez&#x2010;Carrasco V, Soriano&#x2010;Lerma A, Soriano M, Guti&#xe9;rrez&#x2010;Fern&#xe1;ndez J, Garcia&#x2010;Salcedo JA. Urinary microbiome: Yin and Yang of the urinary tract. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2021;11:617002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung J, Kim A, Yang SH. The innovative approach in functional bladder disorders: the communication between bladder and brain&#x2010;gut axis. Int Neurourol J. 2023;27(1):15&#x2010;22.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>