<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36420354</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2472-7245</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Season>Oct-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JB &amp; JS open access</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JB JS Open Access</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Bisphosphonates for Post-COVID Osteonecrosis of the Femoral Head: Medical Management of a Surgical Condition.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e22.00060</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2106/JBJS.OA.22.00060</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">COVID-19 infection can cause long-term effects, cumulatively known as long COVID syndrome. One such sequela is osteonecrosis of the femoral head (also called avascular necrosis of the femoral head, or AVNFH). On the basis of our 20-year experience in using bisphosphonate therapy in the successful management of osteonecrosis, we conducted the present study to evaluate the efficacy of the therapy in the management of post-COVID osteonecrosis of the femoral head. In addition, we aimed to evaluate the cumulative dosage of corticosteroids and the duration between the commencement of corticosteroids and the development of osteonecrosis in COVID-19 survivors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This was a retrospective evaluation of 48 patients (88 hips) diagnosed with osteonecrosis of the femoral head at a tertiary care center after COVID-19 infection between September 2020 and May 2021. Patients received intravenous zoledronic acid (5 mg) at the initiation of therapy and oral alendronate (35 mg) twice weekly, and were followed for a minimum of 6 months. Clinical evaluation was conducted using a visual analog scale (VAS) for pain and the Harris hip score (HHS). Radiographic evaluation was performed to assess the progression of the disease and collapse of the femoral head.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">At a mean follow-up of 10 months, 84 (95.5%) of the hips showed good clinical outcomes, and only 4 (4.5%) of the hips required surgical intervention. The mean VAS pain score and HHS improved at 6 weeks and steadily improved on subsequent follow-ups. In 16 (18%) of the 88 affected hips, radiographic progression was observed. The mean dose of corticosteroids administered to the patients to manage COVID-19 infection was 841.3 mg of prednisolone equivalents. The mean duration between the commencement of corticosteroid therapy and the development of osteonecrosis was 179 days.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Post-COVID osteonecrosis appears to be more aggressive, with COVID-19 itself contributing to its etiopathogenesis in addition to corticosteroids. However, it can be diagnosed by magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) in symptomatic patients and then effectively treated medically, especially if detected in the early stages.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Prognostic Level III. See Instructions for Authors for a complete description of levels of evidence.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Published by The Journal of Bone and Joint Surgery, Incorporated. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agarwala</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Orthopedics and Traumatology, P.D. Hinduja Hospital and Medical Research Centre, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vijayvargiya</LastName><ForeName>Mayank</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, P.D. Hinduja Hospital and Medical Research Centre, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sawant</LastName><ForeName>Tushar</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, P.D. Hinduja Hospital and Medical Research Centre, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kulkarni</LastName><ForeName>Siddhesh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, P.D. Hinduja Hospital and Medical Research Centre, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JB JS Open Access</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101726219</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2472-7245</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The Disclosure of Potential Conflicts of Interest forms are provided with the online version of the article (http://links.lww.com/JBJSOA/A437).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36420354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9678628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.OA.22.00060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JBJSOA-D-22-00060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. 2021. 
Nov
11. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annane D. Corticosteroids for COVID-19. Journal of Intensive Medicine. 2021 Jul;1(1):14-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7919540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36943816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwala SR, Vijayvargiya M, Pandey P. Avascular necrosis as a part of &#x2018;long COVID-19&#x2019;. BMJ Case Rep. 2021. Jul 2;14(7):e242101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8256728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34215639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris WH. Traumatic arthritis of the hip after dislocation and acetabular fractures: treatment by mold arthroplasty. An end-result study using a new method of result evaluation. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1969. Jun;51(4):737-55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5783851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arlet J, Ficat C. Ischemic necrosis of the femoral head. Treatment by core decompression. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1990. Jan;72(1):151-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2295665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwala S, Vijayvargiya M. A Paradigm Shift in Osteonecrosis Treatment with Bisphosphonates: A 20-Year Study. JB JS Open Access. 2021. Dec 17;6(4):e21.00042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8683207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34934885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re&#x2019;em Y, Redfield S, Austin JP, Akrami A. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021. Aug;38:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhanasekararaja P, Soundarrajan D, Kumar KS, Pushpa BT, Rajkumar N, Rajasekaran S. Aggressive Presentation and Rapid Progression of Osteonecrosis of the Femoral Head After COVID-19. Indian J Orthop. 2022. Apr 25;56(7):1259-67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9037053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35495964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell C, Chang C, Naguwa SM, Cheema G, Gershwin ME. Steroid induced osteonecrosis: An analysis of steroid dosing risk. Autoimmun Rev. 2010. Sep;9(11):721-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7105235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20621176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue S, Horii M, Asano T, Fujioka M, Ogura T, Shibatani M, Kim WC, Nakagawa M, Tanaka T, Hirota Y, Kubo T. Risk factors for nontraumatic osteonecrosis of the femoral head after renal transplantation. J Orthop Sci. 2003;8(6):751-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14648260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo KH, Kim R, Ko GH, Song HR, Jeong ST, Cho SH. Preventing collapse in early osteonecrosis of the femoral head. A randomised clinical trial of core decompression. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 1995. Nov;77(6):870-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7593097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffith JF, Antonio GE, Kumta SM, Hui DS, Wong JK, Joynt GM, Wu AK, Cheung AY, Chiu KH, Chan KM, Leung PC, Ahuja AT. Osteonecrosis of hip and knee in patients with severe acute respiratory syndrome treated with steroids. Radiology. 2005. Apr;235(1):168-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15703312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oinuma K, Harada Y, Nawata Y, Takabayashi K, Abe I, Kamikawa K, Moriya H. Osteonecrosis in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus develops very early after starting high dose corticosteroid treatment. Ann Rheum Dis. 2001. Dec;60(12):1145-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1753447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11709458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan KL, Mok CC. Glucocorticoid-induced avascular bone necrosis: diagnosis and management. Open Orthop J. 2012;6(1):449-57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3480825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23115605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kichloo A, Dettloff K, Aljadah M, Albosta M, Jamal S, Singh J, Wani F, Kumar A, Vallabhaneni S, Khan MZ. COVID-19 and Hypercoagulability: A Review. Clin Appl Thromb Hemost. 2020. Jan-Dec;26:1076029620962853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7592310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33074732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magro C, Mulvey JJ, Berlin D, Nuovo G, Salvatore S, Harp J, Baxter-Stoltzfus A, Laurence J. Complement associated microvascular injury and thrombosis in the pathogenesis of severe COVID-19 infection: A report of five cases. Transl Res. 2020. Jun;220:1-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32299776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afrin LB, Weinstock LB, Molderings GJ. Covid-19 hyperinflammation and post-Covid-19 illness may be rooted in mast cell activation syndrome. Int J Infect Dis. 2020. Nov;100:327-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7529115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32920235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lykissas MG, Gelalis ID, Kostas-Agnantis IP, Vozonelos G, Korompilias AV. The role of hypercoagulability in the development of osteonecrosis of the femoral head. Orthop Rev (Pavia). 2012. May 9;4(2):e17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3395986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22802985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulewski A, Siero&#x144; D, Szyluk K, D&#x105;browski M, Kubaszewski &#x141;, Lukoszek D, Christe A. Avascular Necrosis Bone Complication after Active COVID-19 Infection: Preliminary Results. Medicina (Kaunas). 2021. Nov 30;57(12):1311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8709043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34946256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwala SR, Vijayvargiya M, Sawant T. Secondary osteonecrosis of the knee as a part of long COVID-19 syndrome: a case series. BMJ Case Rep. 2022. Mar 29;15(3):e248583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10577750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35351759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwala S, Shah S, Joshi VR. The use of alendronate in the treatment of avascular necrosis of the femoral head: follow-up to eight years. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2009. Aug;91(8):1013-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19651826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwala S, Banavali SD, Vijayvargiya M. Bisphosphonate Combination Therapy in the Management of Postchemotherapy Avascular Necrosis of the Femoral Head in Adolescents and Young Adults: A Retrospective Study From India. J Glob Oncol. 2018. Sep;4:1-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6223416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30241233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>