<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36046290</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-COVID Syndrome and Severity of COVID-19: A Cross-Sectional Epidemiological Evaluation From North India.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e27345</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e27345</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e27345</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.27345</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background COVID-19 has now lasted for more than two years as a pandemic and has had enduring effects on the health of people as the post-COVID syndrome. Recent literature has&#xa0;shown the long-term effects of&#xa0;COVID-19 on various organ systems, including but not limited to respiratory, cardiovascular, neurological, musculoskeletal, and gastrointestinal systems. Methods and objectives We aimed&#xa0;to estimate the prevalence of post-acute COVID symptoms in a tertiary&#xa0;care center in northern India; observe the effects of the demographic profile of age, BMI, gender, and presence of comorbidities on the persistence of post-COVID syndrome, and explore any correlation between the severity of COVID-19 disease and the persistence of post-COVID symptoms. We designed a survey containing structured questions evaluating post-COVID symptoms beyond three weeks (post-acute COVID phase), six weeks (post-COVID phase), and 12 weeks of acute illness. It was administered online.&#xa0; Results Prevalence of post-COVID symptoms both after three and six weeks&#xa0;was reported to be 16.67% and 7.37%, respectively. The most common symptoms to persist were musculoskeletal symptoms (fatigue), followed by upper respiratory symptoms. Disease severity (p&lt;0.05), BMI (p&lt;0.05), and comorbidities were seen to affect post-COVID symptoms significantly, whereas gender and age of the patient had no significant effect. Disease severity significantly affected the persistence of post-COVID symptoms up to 12 weeks; however, this effect does not hold true in long COVID haulers. Also, the risk of developing persistent post-acute COVID symptoms was more in moderate to severe disease than in mild disease. Conclusion The pandemic might be close to over, but it is not out of our lives yet, and the persistence of post-COVID symptoms is exigent.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022, Uniyal et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uniyal</LastName><ForeName>Nidhi</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Government Doon Medical College, Dehradun, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sethi</LastName><ForeName>Yashendra</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Government Doon Medical College, Dehradun, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Pradeep C</ForeName><Initials>PC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Government Doon Medical College, Dehradun, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sayana</LastName><ForeName>Ashutosh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Government Doon Medical College, Dehradun, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeet</LastName><ForeName>Narayan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Government Doon Medical College, Dehradun, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agarwal</LastName><ForeName>Anurag</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Tuberculosis and Chest Medicine, Government Doon Medical College, Dehradun, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rawat</LastName><ForeName>Vijay</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Statistics, Shri Guru Ram Rai Degree College, Dehradun, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acute covid illness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long covid haulers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post covid syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute covid</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36046290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9417061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.27345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A'Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. BMJ. 2020;370:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a Multistate Health Care Systems Network - United States, March-June 2020. Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, et al. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69:993&#x2013;998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-infective and chronic fatigue syndromes precipitated by viral and non-viral pathogens: prospective cohort study. Hickie I, Davenport T, Wakefield D, et al. BMJ. 2006;333:575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1569956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16950834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-infectious disease syndrome. Bannister BA. Postgrad Med J. 1988;64:559&#x2013;567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2428896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3074289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS: prognosis, outcome and sequelae. Chan KS, Zheng JP, Mok YW, Li YM, Liu YN, Chu CM, Ip MS. Respirology. 2003;8:36&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7169213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15018132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term bone and lung consequences associated with hospital-acquired severe acute respiratory syndrome: a 15-year follow-up from a prospective cohort study. Zhang P, Li J, Liu H, et al. Bone Res. 2020;8:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7018717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32128276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome on the physical profile and quality of life. Lau HM, Lee EW, Wong CN, Ng GY, Jones AY, Hui DS. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2005;86:1134&#x2013;1140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15954051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stress and psychological distress among SARS survivors 1 year after the outbreak. Lee AM, Wong JG, McAlonan GM, et al. Can J Psychiatry. 2007;52:233&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17500304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serious long-term health consequences of Q-fever and Legionnaires' disease. van Loenhout JA, van Tiel HH, van den Heuvel J, et al. J Infect. 2014;68:527&#x2013;533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24468188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. Garrigues E, Janvier P, Kherabi Y, et al. J Infect. 2020;81:4&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Carvalho-Schneider C, Laurent E, Lemaignen A, et al. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:258&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up: results from a prospective UK cohort. Arnold DT, Hamilton FW, Milne A, et al. Thorax. 2021;76:399&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>'Long-COVID': a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, et al. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 symptoms: longitudinal evolution and persistence in outpatient settings. Nehme M, Braillard O, Alcoba G, Aebischer Perone S, Courvoisier D, Chappuis F, Guessous I. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174:723&#x2013;725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7741180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33284676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thyroid function abnormalities in the acute phase of COVID-19: a cross-sectional hospital-based study from North India. Sethi Y, Uniyal N, Maheshwari S, Sinha R, Goel A. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9188379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35706733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manifestations of thyroid disease post COVID-19 illness: report of Hashimoto thyroiditis, Graves' disease, and subacute thyroiditis. Feghali K, Atallah J, Norman C. J Clin Transl Endocrinol Case Rep. 2021;22:100094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8387132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34462717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute and long-COVID-19 symptoms in patients with mild diseases: a systematic review. van Kessel SA, Olde Hartman TC, Lucassen PL, van Jaarsveld CH. Fam Pract. 2022;39:159&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8414057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34268556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Defining post-COVID symptoms (post-acute COVID, long COVID, persistent post-COVID): an integrative classification. Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Florencio LL. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:2621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, Villapol S. Sci Rep. 2021;11:16144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-COVID-19 syndrome among symptomatic COVID-19 patients: A prospective cohort study in a tertiary care center of Bangladesh. Mahmud R, Rahman MM, Rassel MA, Monayem FB, Sayeed SK, Islam MS, Islam MM. PLoS One. 2021;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8031743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33831043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anxiety and depression symptoms after COVID-19 infection: results from the COVID Symptom Study app. Klaser K, Thompson EJ, Nguyen LH, et al. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2021;92:1254&#x2013;1258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8599635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34583944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Determinants of persistent post-COVID-19 symptoms: value of a novel COVID-19 symptom score. Galal I, Hussein AA, Amin MT, et al. 2021;15:10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, et al. PLoS One. 2020;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of ivermectin mass drug administration on the COVID-19 pandemic. Uniyal N, Pandey HC, Sayana A, et al. Int J Health Sci. 2022;6:450&#x2013;462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A five-day course of ivermectin for the treatment of COVID-19 may reduce the duration of illness. Ahmed S, Karim MM, Ross AG, et al. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;103:214&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7709596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33278625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Increased production of interleukin-6 by adherent and non-adherent mononuclear cells during 'natural fatigue' but not following 'experimental fatigue' in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. Gupta S, Aggarwal S, Starr A. Int J Mol Med. 1999;3:209&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9917531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>