<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38396274</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-7558</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of behavioral medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Behav Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Longer-Term Mental Health Consequences of COVID-19 Infection: Moderation by Race and Socioeconomic Status.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12529-024-10271-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">While evidence suggests that the mental health symptoms of COVID-19 can persist for several months following infection, little is known about the longer-term mental health effects and whether certain sociodemographic groups may be particularly impacted. This cross-sectional study aimed to characterize the longer-term mental health consequences of COVID-19 infection and examine whether such consequences are more pronounced in Black people and people with lower socioeconomic status.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">277 Black and White adults (age&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;30 years) with a history of COVID-19 (tested positive&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;6 months prior to participation) or no history of COVID-19 infection completed a 45-minute online questionnaire battery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">People with a history of COVID-19 had greater depressive (d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.24), anxiety (d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.34), post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) (d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.32), and insomnia (d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.31) symptoms than those without a history of COVID-19. These differences remained for anxiety, PTSD, and insomnia symptoms after adjusting for age, sex, race, education, income, employment status, body mass index, and smoking status. No differences were detected for perceived stress and general psychopathology. People with a history of COVID-19 had more than double the odds of clinically significant symptoms of anxiety (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.22) and PTSD (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.40). Education, but not race, income, or employment status, moderated relationships of interest such that COVID-19 status was more strongly and positively associated with all the mental health outcomes for those with fewer years of education.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The mental health consequences of COVID-19 may be significant, widespread, and persistent for at least 6 months post-infection and may increase as years of education decreases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. International Society of Behavioral Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Williams</LastName><ForeName>Michelle K</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis (IUPUI), 402 North Blackford Street, LD100E, 46202, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crawford</LastName><ForeName>Christopher A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis (IUPUI), 402 North Blackford Street, LD100E, 46202, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zapolski</LastName><ForeName>Tamika C</ForeName><Initials>TC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis (IUPUI), 402 North Blackford Street, LD100E, 46202, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hirsh</LastName><ForeName>Adam T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis (IUPUI), 402 North Blackford Street, LD100E, 46202, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stewart</LastName><ForeName>Jesse C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis (IUPUI), 402 North Blackford Street, LD100E, 46202, Indianapolis, IN, USA. jstew@iupui.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Behav Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9421097</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1070-5503</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health Disparities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Insomnia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Posttraumatic Stress</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38396274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12529-024-10271-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12529-024-10271-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hopkins. Johns Hopkins COVID-19 Dashboard. https://coronavirus.jhu.edu/map.html . Accessed March 1, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datta SD, Talwar A, Lee JT. A proposed Framework and Timeline of the Spectrum of Disease due to SARS-CoV-2 infection: Illness beyond Acute Infection and Public Health Implications. JAMA. 2020;324(22):2251&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33206133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, et al. Short-term and long-term rates of Postacute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a systematic review. JAMA Netw open. 2021;4(10):e2128568&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34643720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8515212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV, Jayadevan R, Sashidharan S, Long COVID. An overview. Diabetes Metabolic Syndrome. 2021;15(3):869&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8056514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, et al. Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020;370:m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, et al. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Global Health. 2021;6(9):e005427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M et al. Bidirectional associations between COVID-19 and psychiatric disorder: retrospective cohort studies of 62 354 COVID-19 cases in the USA. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, et al. Anxiety and depression in COVID-19 survivors: role of inflammatory and clinical predictors. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;89:594&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7390748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez R et al. Short-term neuropsychiatric outcomes and quality of life in COVID-19 survivors. J Intern Med. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7833295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paz C, et al. Anxiety and depression in patients with confirmed and suspected COVID-19 in Ecuador. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2020;74(10):554&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappelmann N, Dantzer R, Khandaker GM. Interleukin-6 as potential mediator of long-term neuropsychiatric symptoms of COVID-19. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2021;131:105295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34119855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8172271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szcze&#x15b;niak D, et al. The SARS-CoV-2 and mental health: from biological mechanisms to social consequences. Prog Neuro-psychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2021;104:110046&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldini T et al. Cerebral venous thrombosis and severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Neurol. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. medRxiv. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;ng&#xfc;r D, Perlis R, Goff D. Psychiatry and COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(12):1149&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32960247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assari S, Habibzadeh P. The COVID-19 emergency response should include a Mental Health Component. Arch Iran Med. 2020;23(4):281&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32271604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noorullah A. Mounting toll of Coronavirus Cases Raises Concerns for Mental Health Professionals. J Coll Physicians Surg Pak. 2020;30(7):677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32811593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE et al. Characterizing long COVID in an International Cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. medRxiv. 2020; 2020.12.24.20248802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez F et al. Racial and Ethnic Differences in Presentation and Outcomes for Patients Hospitalized with COVID-19: Findings from the American Heart Association&#x2019;s COVID-19 Cardiovascular Disease Registry. Circulation. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkins RB, Charles EJ, Mehaffey JH. Socio-economic status and COVID-19-related cases and fatalities. Public Health. 2020;189:129&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33227595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen JT, Krieger N. Revealing the unequal burden of COVID-19 by income, Race/Ethnicity, and Household Crowding: US County Versus Zip Code analyses. J Public Health Manag Pract. 2021; S43&#x2013;s56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Rand AM. The precious and the precocious: understanding cumulative disadvantage and cumulative advantage over the life course. Gerontologist. 1996;36(2):230&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8920094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adesogan O, et al. COVID-19 stress and the Health of Black americans in the Rural South. Clin Psychol Sci. 2021;10(6):1111&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Link BG, Phelan J. Social conditions as fundamental causes of disease. J Health Soc Behav. 1995; p. 80&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall LR, et al. Income differences and COVID-19: impact on Daily Life and Mental Health. Popul Health Manage. 2021;25(3):384&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assari S. Unequal gain of Equal resources across racial groups. Int J Health Policy Manag. 2018;7(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29325397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubian A, Najand B, Assari S. Black americans&#x2019; diminished health returns of employment during COVID-19 pandemic. Int J Travel Med Global Health. 2022;10(3):114&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger E, et al. Multi-cohort study identifies social determinants of systemic inflammation over the life course. Nat Commun. 2019;10(1):773&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30770820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6377676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumer Y, et al. Health disparities in COVID-19: addressing the Role of Social Determinants of Health in Immune System Dysfunction to turn the Tide. Front Public Health. 2020;8:559312&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33134238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7578341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stepanikova I, Bateman LB, Oates GR. Systemic inflammation in midlife: race, socioeconomic status, and perceived discrimination. Am J Prev Med. 2017;52(1S1):63&#x2013;S76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ransing R, et al. Infectious disease outbreak related stigma and discrimination during the COVID-19 pandemic: drivers, facilitators, manifestations, and outcomes across the world. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;89:555&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32731007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7384410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dar SA, et al. Stigma in coronavirus disease-19 survivors in Kashmir, India: a cross-sectional exploratory study. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(11):e0240152&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33253177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7703941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra KK, Arora VK. Covid-19 and social stigma: role of scientific community. Indian J Tuberc. 2020;67(3):284&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32825854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7362777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne P, James A. Placing poverty-inequality at the centre of psychiatry. BJPsych Bull. 2020;44(5):187&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32981561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7525584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galea S, Abdalla SM. COVID-19 pandemic, unemployment, and civil unrest: underlying deep racial and socioeconomic divides. JAMA. 2020;324(3):227&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, et al. Increased psychological distress, loneliness, and unemployment in the spread of COVID-19 over 6 months in Germany. Med (Kaunas Lithuania). 2021;57(1):53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora T, et al. The prevalence of psychological consequences of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. J Health Psychol. 2022;27(4):805&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33118376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IDSA, Post. COVID/Long COVID. https://www.idsociety.org/covid-19-real-time-learning-network/disease-manifestations--complications/post-covid-syndrome/ . Accessed on February 5, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buhrmester M, Kwang T, Gosling SD. Amazon&#x2019;s mechanical Turk: a New source of Inexpensive, yet High-Quality, data? Perspect Psychol Sci. 2011;6(1):3&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26162106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litman L, Robinson J, Abberbock T. TurkPrime.com: a versatile crowdsourcing data acquisition platform for the behavioral sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2017;49(2):433&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27071389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qualtrics Q. 2005: Provo, Utah, USA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kees J, et al. An analysis of Data Quality: professional panels, student subject pools, and Amazon&#x2019;s mechanical Turk. J Advertising. 2017;46(1):141&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB. The PHQ-9: validity of a brief depression severity measure. J Gen Intern Med. 2001;16(9):606&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11556941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1495268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;we B, et al. Validation and standardization of the generalized anxiety disorder screener (GAD-7) in the general population. Med Care. 2008;46(3):266&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18388841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sveen J, Bondjers K, Willebrand M. Psychometric properties of the PTSD Checklist for DSM-5: a pilot study. Eur J Psychotraumatology. 2016;7:30165&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastien CH, Vallieres A, Morin CM. Validation of the Insomnia Severity Index as an outcome measure for insomnia research. Sleep Med. 2001;2(4):297&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11438246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EH. Review of the psychometric evidence of the perceived stress scale. Asian Nurs Res. 2012;6(4):121&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derogatis LR, Rickels K, Rock AF. The SCL-90 and the MMPI: a step in the validation of a new self-report scale. Br J Psychiatry. 1976;128:280&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1252693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL. The PHQ-9: a new depression diagnostic and severity measure. Psychiatric Annals. 2002;32(9):509&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, et al. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166(10):1092&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16717171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Using the PTSD Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5). https://www.ptsd.va.gov/professional/assessment/adult-sr/ptsd-checklist.asp . Accessed on January 29, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin CM, et al. The Insomnia Severity Index: psychometric indicators to detect insomnia cases and evaluate treatment response. Sleep. 2011;34(5):601&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21532953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3079939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagnon C, et al. Validation of the Insomnia Severity Index in primary care. J Am Board Fam Med. 2013;26(6):701&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24204066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S. Perceived stress in a probability sample of the United States. The social psychology of health. Thousand Oaks, CA, US: Sage Publications, Inc; 1988. pp. 31&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derogatis LR, Lipman RS, Covi L. SCL-90: an outpatient psychiatric rating scale&#x2013;preliminary report. Psychopharmacol Bull. 1973;9(1):13&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4682398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson DE, et al. Reliability and validity of measures from the behavioral risk factor Surveillance System (BRFSS). Soz Praventivmed. 2001;46(Suppl 1):3&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders JB, et al. Development of the Alcohol Use disorders Identification Test (AUDIT): WHO Collaborative Project on early detection of persons with harmful alcohol Consumption&#x2013;II. Addiction. 1993;88(6):791&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8329970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simons D, et al. The association of smoking status with SARS-CoV-2 infection, hospitalization and mortality from COVID-19: a living rapid evidence review with bayesian meta-analyses (version 7). Addiction. 2021;116(6):1319&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33007104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pijls BG, et al. Demographic risk factors for COVID-19 infection, severity, ICU admission and death: a meta-analysis of 59 studies. BMJ Open. 2021;11(1):e044640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33431495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanijahani A, et al. A systematic review of racial/ethnic and socioeconomic disparities in COVID-19. Int J Equity Health. 2021;20(1):248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34819081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8611382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alegr&#xed;a M, et al. Social Determinants of Mental Health: where we are and where we need to go. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2018;20(11):95&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30221308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6181118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith PH, Mazure CM, McKee SA. Smoking and mental illness in the U.S. population. Tob Control. 2014;23(e2):e147&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24727731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brotto LA, et al. The influence of sex, gender, age, and ethnicity on psychosocial factors and substance use throughout phases of the COVID-19 pandemic. PLoS ONE. 2021;16:e0259676. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0259676 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0259676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34807908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8608308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong A, et al. Cardiometabolic risk factors for COVID-19 susceptibility and severity: a mendelian randomization analysis. medRxiv: Preprint Serv Health Sci. 2020. 2020.08.26.20182709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes AF. Introduction to Mediation, Moderation, and conditional process analysis. 2nd ed. New York: The Guilford; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiken LS, West SG. Multiple regression: testing and interpreting interactions. Multiple regression: testing and interpreting interactions. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage; 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>People with Certain Medical Conditions. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/need-extra-precautions/people-with-medical-conditions.html . Accessed February 25, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. 2nd ed. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Earlbaum Associates; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Q, et al. Clinical sequelae of COVID-19 survivors in Wuhan, China: a single-centre longitudinal study. Clin Microbiol Infection: Official Publication Eur Soc Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2021;27(1):89&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, et al. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398(10302):747&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8389999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr&#xf9; G, et al. Long-COVID syndrome? A study on the persistence of neurological, psychological and physiological symptoms. Healthc (Basel Switzerland). 2021;9(5):575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badenoch JB, et al. Persistent neuropsychiatric symptoms after COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Commun. 2021;4(1):fcab297&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35169700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8833580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, et al. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8(5):416&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8023694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594(7862):259&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers JP, et al. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: a systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;7(7):611&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7234781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tansey CM, et al. One-year outcomes and Health Care Utilization in survivors of severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome. Arch Intern Med. 2007;167(12):1312&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17592106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes LD, Ingram J, Sculthorpe NF. More than 100 persistent symptoms of SARS-CoV-2 (long COVID): a scoping review. Front Med. 2021; 8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sze S, et al. Ethnicity and clinical outcomes in COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;29:100630&#x2013;0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33200120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Burdens of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 by severity of acute infection, demographics and health status. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):6571&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34772922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8589966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed F, et al. A narrative review of Stigma related to Infectious Disease outbreaks: what can be learned in the Face of the Covid-19 pandemic? Front Psychiatry. 2020;11:565919&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33343414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7738431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross CE, Wu CL. Education, age, and the cumulative advantage in health. J Health Soc Behav. 1996;37(1):104&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8820314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zajacova A, Lawrence EM. The Relationship between Education and Health: reducing disparities through a Contextual Approach. Annu Rev Public Health. 2018;39(1):273&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29328865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5880718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faulkner J, et al. Physical activity, mental health and well-being of adults during initial COVID-19 containment strategies: a multi-country cross-section. Al Anal J Sci Med Sport. 2021;24(4):320&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#x142;&#x105;bska D, et al. Fruit and Vegetable Intake and Mental Health in adults: a systematic review. Nutrients. 2020;12(1):115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31906271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7019743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozbay F et al. Social support and resilience to stress: from neurobiology to clinical practice. Psychiatry (Edgmont (Pa: Township)). 2007;(5):35&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becerra X. Annual Update of the HHS Poverty Guidelines. 2022; https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2022/01/21/2022-01166/annual-update-of-the-hhs-poverty-guidelines . Accessed March 1, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitaker M, et al. Persistent COVID-19 symptoms in a community study of 606,434 people in England. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):1957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35413949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9005552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geyer S, et al. Education, income, and occupational class cannot be used interchangeably in social epidemiology. Empirical evidence against a common practice. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2006;60(9):804&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16905727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2566032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iob E, Steptoe A, Zaninotto P. Mental health, financial, and social outcomes among older adults with probable COVID-19 infection: a longitudinal cohort study. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2022;119(27):e2200816119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35763577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9271189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. Employment Situation Summary. https://www.bls.gov/news.release/empsit.nr0.htm . Accessed March 1, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert R, et al. Misclassification of outcome in case&#x2013;control studies: methods for sensitivity analysis. Stat Methods Med Res. 2014;25(5):2377&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25217446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomason ME et al. Social determinants of health exacerbate disparities in COVID-19 illness severity and lasting symptom complaints. medRxiv: Preprint Serv Health Sci 2021; p. 2021.07.16.21260638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assari S, Social Determinants of Depression. The intersections of race, gender, and Socioeconomic Status. Brain Sci. 2017;7(12):156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29186800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5742759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>