<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36582565</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Review of Long COVID With a Special Focus on Its Cardiovascular Manifestations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e31933</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e31933</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e31933</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.31933</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The novel&#xa0;severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) virus has been the cause of the century's worst pandemic so far: coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). It has led to unprecedented mortality and morbidity, resulting in devastating consequences worldwide. The acute manifestations of COVID-19 including respiratory as well as multisystem involvement have been&#xa0;causes of great concern among physicians. However, the long-term effects of the coronavirus have left many patients battling with chronic symptoms, ranging from extreme fatigue to cardiomyopathy. In this article, we review the chronic manifestations of COVID-19 with a focus on cardiovascular manifestations. We discuss the pathophysiology, post-acute sequelae, clinical manifestations, approach to the laboratory diagnosis of cardiovascular manifestations of long COVID, and a proposed multidisciplinary treatment method. We also explore the relationship between vaccination and the long COVID syndrome.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022, Yousif et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yousif</LastName><ForeName>Elamein</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Al Ahli Hospital, Doha, QAT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Premraj</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Al Ahli Hospital, Doha, QAT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardio vascular disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long term sequelae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute sequelae of covid-19</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36582565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9793803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.31933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO: weekly epidemiological update on COVID-19 - 2 November 2022.  [
Nov;
2022 
]. 2022. https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/weekly-epidemiological-update-on-covid-19---2-november-2022 https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/weekly-epidemiological-update-on-covid-19---2-november-2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. Nature. 2021;594:259&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fauci introduces new acronym for long COVID.  [
Nov;
2022 
]. 2021. https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/946419 https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/946419</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19.  [
Nov;
2022 
]. 2021. https://app.magicapp.org/ https://app.magicapp.org/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Office for National Statistics: prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK.  [
Nov;
2022 
]. 2022. https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/3november2022. https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/3november2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-COVID syndrome and severity of COVID-19: a cross-sectional epidemiological evaluation from North India. Uniyal N, Sethi Y, Sharma PC, Sayana A, Jeet N, Agarwal A, Rawat V. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9417061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36046290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of long COVID in a national cohort: longitudinal measures from disease onset until 8 months' follow-up. Petersen MS, Kristiansen MF, Hanusson KD, et al. Int J Infect Dis. 2022;122:437&#x2013;441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9222150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35753603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence and correlates of long COVID symptoms among US adults. Perlis RH, Santillana M, Ognyanova K, et al. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9614581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36301542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. J Infect Dis. 2022;226:1593&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>How common is long COVID? Why studies give different answers. Ledford H. Nature. 2022;606:852&#x2013;853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35725828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, et al. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6:5427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Subramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, et al. Nat Med. 2022;28:1706&#x2013;1714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors for long COVID: analyses of 10 longitudinal studies and electronic health records in the UK [PREPRINT] Thompson EJ, Williams DM, Walker AJ, et al. medRxiv. 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiac postacute sequelae symptoms of SARS-CoV-2 in community-dwelling adults: cross-sectional study. Ogungbe O, Gilotra NA, Davidson PM, Farley JE, Dennison Himmelfarb CR, Post WS, Commodore-Mensah Y. Open Heart. 2022;9:0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical assessment of endothelial function in convalescent COVID-19 patients: a meta-analysis with meta-regressions. Ambrosino P, Sanduzzi Zamparelli S, Mosella M, et al. Ann Med. 2022;54:3234&#x2013;3249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9673781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36382632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-COVID and post-COVID health complications: an up-to-date review on clinical conditions and their possible molecular mechanisms. Silva Andrade B, Siqueira S, de Assis Soares WR, et al. Viruses. 2021;13:700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 and cardiovascular autonomic dysfunction: what do we know? Bisaccia G, Ricci F, Recce V, et al. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis. 2021;8:156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8621226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34821709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, et al. Cell. 2022;185:881&#x2013;895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early clues regarding the pathogenesis of long-COVID. Peluso MJ, Deeks SG. Trends Immunol. 2022;43:268&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8901423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35272932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Immunoglobulin signature predicts risk of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Cervia C, Zurbuchen Y, Taeschler P, et al. Nat Commun. 2022;13:446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8789854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35078982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent clotting protein pathology in long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) is accompanied by increased levels of antiplasmin. Pretorius E, Vlok M, Venter C, Bezuidenhout JA, Laubscher GJ, Steenkamp J, Kell DB. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2021;20:172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8381139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34425843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence and impact of myocardial injury in patients hospitalized with COVID-19 infection. Lala A, Johnson KW, Januzzi JL, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76:533&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7279721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32517963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of clinical and subclinical myocarditis in competitive athletes with recent SARS-CoV-2 infection: results from the Big Ten COVID-19 Cardiac Registry. Daniels CJ, Rajpal S, Greenshields JT, et al. JAMA Cardiol. 2021;6:1078&#x2013;1087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8160916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34042947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High prevalence of pericardial involvement in college student athletes recovering from COVID-19. Brito D, Meester S, Yanamala N, et al. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2021;14:541&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7641597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33223496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term cardiac pathology in individuals with mild initial COVID-19 illness. Puntmann VO, Martin S, Shchendrygina A, et al. Nat Med. 2022;28:2117&#x2013;2123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9556300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36064600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>'Long-COVID': a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, et al. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 with a cardiovascular focus. Raman B, Bluemke DA, L&#xfc;scher TF, Neubauer S. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:1157&#x2013;1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8903393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35176758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characteristics and impact of long Covid: findings from an online survey. Ziauddeen N, Gurdasani D, O'Hara ME, Hastie C, Roderick P, Yao G, Alwan NA. PLoS One. 2022;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8903286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35259179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prospective case-control study of cardiovascular abnormalities 6 months following mild COVID-19 in healthcare workers. Joy G, Artico J, Kurdi H, et al. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2021;14:2155&#x2013;2166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8105493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33975819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, Villapol S. Sci Rep. 2021;11:16144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Electrocardiographic manifestations of COVID-19. Long B, Brady WJ, Bridwell RE, Ramzy M, Montrief T, Singh M, Gottlieb M. Am J Emerg Med. 2021;41:96&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7771377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33412365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment of prolonged physiological and behavioral changes associated with COVID-19 infection. Radin JM, Quer G, Ramos E, Baca-Motes K, Gadaleta M, Topol EJ, Steinhubl SR. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8264646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34232306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiac dysfunction and arrhythmias 3 months after hospitalization for COVID-19. Ingul CB, Grimsmo J, Mecinaj A, et al. J Am Heart Assoc. 2022;11:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9238505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35048715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The long COVID: findings of 24 rhythmic Holter in patients suffering from palpitations. Hammami R, Bahloul A, Charfeddine S, Gargouri R, Abid L. Arch Cardiovasc Dis Suppl. 2021;14:82&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persisting adverse ventricular remodeling in COVID-19 survivors: a longitudinal echocardiographic study. Moody WE, Liu B, Mahmoud-Elsayed HM, et al. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2021;34:562&#x2013;566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33539950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiopulmonary recovery after COVID-19: an observational prospective multicentre trial. Sonnweber T, Sahanic S, Pizzini A, et al. Eur Respir J. 2021;57:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echocardiographic assessment of COVID19 sequelae in survivors with elevated cardiac biomarkers. R&#xf3;denas-Alesina E, Rodr&#xed;guez-Palomares J, Bach-Oller M, et al. Int J Cardiol. 2022;360:104&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9050195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35490788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes of cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in patients recently recovered from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Puntmann VO, Carerj ML, Wieters I, et al. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:1265&#x2013;1273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiac MRI in patients with prolonged cardiorespiratory symptoms after mild to moderate COVID-19. Kravchenko D, Isaak A, Zimmer S, et al. Radiology. 2021;301:0&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8369880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34374593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longitudinal changes of cardiac and aortic imaging phenotypes following COVID-19 in the UK Biobank Cohort [PREPRINT] Bai W, Raman B, Petersen SE, et al. medRxiv. 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiac function in relation to functional status and fatigue in patients with post-COVID syndrome. Baum P, Do L, Deterding L, et al. Sci Rep. 2022;12:19575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9664421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36380000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delayed catastrophic thrombotic events in young and asymptomatic post COVID-19 patients. Fan BE, Umapathi T, Chua K, et al. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2021;51:971&#x2013;977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7648538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33159640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment of pulmonary arterial circulation 3 months after hospitalization for SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia: dual-energy CT (DECT) angiographic study in 55 patients. Remy-Jardin M, Duthoit L, Perez T, et al. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;34:100778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33817609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Use of cardiopulmonary stress testing for patients with unexplained dyspnea post-coronavirus disease. Mancini DM, Brunjes DL, Lala A, Trivieri MG, Contreras JP, Natelson BH. JACC Heart Fail. 2021;9:927&#x2013;937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8629098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34857177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) and other autonomic disorders after COVID-19 infection: a case series of 20 patients. Blitshteyn S, Whitelaw S. Immunol Res. 2021;69:205&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8009458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33786700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2022 ACC Expert Consensus Decision Pathway on Cardiovascular Sequelae of COVID-19 in Adults: Myocarditis and Other Myocardial Involvement, Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection, and Return to Play: A Report of the American College of Cardiology Solution Set Oversight Committee. Gluckman TJ, Bhave NM, Allen LA, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79:1717&#x2013;1756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8926109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35307156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PCNA: post-acute COVID-19 and cardiovascular health. PCNA.  [
Nov;
2022 
]. 2022. https://pcna.net/post-acute-sequelae-of-covid-19-and-cardiovascular-health/ https://pcna.net/post-acute-sequelae-of-covid-19-and-cardiovascular-health/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association between BNT162b2 vaccination and reported incidence of post-COVID-19 symptoms: cross-sectional study 2020-21, Israel. Kuodi P, Gorelik Y, Zayyad H, et al. NPJ Vaccines. 2022;7:101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9411827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36028498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors and disease profile of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection in UK users of the COVID Symptom Study app: a prospective, community-based, nested, case-control study. Antonelli M, Penfold RS, Merino J, et al. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:43&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34480857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myocarditis after BNT162b2 and mRNA-1273 vaccination. Larson KF, Ammirati E, Adler ED, et al. Circulation. 2021;144:506&#x2013;508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8340725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34133884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>