<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35144991</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1399-3003</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The European respiratory journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur Respir J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>European Respiratory Society statement on long COVID follow-up.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2102174</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1183/13993003.02174-2021</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Patients diagnosed with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) associated with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection frequently experience symptom burden post-acute infection or post-hospitalisation. We aimed to identify optimal strategies for follow-up care that may positively impact the patient's quality of life (QoL). A European Respiratory Society (ERS) Task Force convened and prioritised eight clinical questions. A targeted search of the literature defined the timeline of "long COVID" as 1-6&#x2005;months post-infection and identified clinical evidence in the follow-up of patients. Studies meeting the inclusion criteria report an association of characteristics of acute infection with persistent symptoms, thromboembolic events in the follow-up period, and evaluations of pulmonary physiology and imaging. Importantly, this statement reviews QoL consequences, symptom burden, disability and home care follow-up. Overall, the evidence for follow-up care for patients with long COVID is limited.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9;The authors 2022.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Antoniou</LastName><ForeName>Katerina M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Molecular and Cellular Pneumonology, Dept of Respiratory Medicine, School of Medicine, University of Crete, Heraklion, Greece kantoniou@uoc.gr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vasarmidi</LastName><ForeName>Eirini</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Molecular and Cellular Pneumonology, Dept of Respiratory Medicine, School of Medicine, University of Crete, Heraklion, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Inserm, Physiopathologie et &#xc9;pid&#xe9;miologie des Maladies Respiratoires, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>These authors contributed equally.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Russell</LastName><ForeName>Anne-Marie</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0468-3537</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine and Health, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>These authors contributed equally.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andrejak</LastName><ForeName>Claire</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service de Pneumologie, CHU Amiens-Picardie, UR 4294 AGIR, Universit&#xe9; Picardie Jules-Verne, Amiens, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crestani</LastName><ForeName>Bruno</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2961-3455</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Inserm, Physiopathologie et &#xc9;pid&#xe9;miologie des Maladies Respiratoires, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre de R&#xe9;f&#xe9;rence des Maladies Pulmonaires Rares (site Constitutif), AP-HP, Service de Pneumologie, H&#xf4;pital Bichat, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delcroix</LastName><ForeName>Marion</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8394-9809</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept of Pneumonology, KU Leuven University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dinh-Xuan</LastName><ForeName>Anh Tuan</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8651-5176</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AP-HP Centre, H&#xf4;pital Cochin, Respiratory Physiology Unit, Thoracic Diseases Dept, Universit&#xe9; de Paris, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poletti</LastName><ForeName>Venerino</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonology Unit, Thoracic Diseases Dept, G.B. Morgagni Hospital, Forli, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept of Respiratory Diseases and Allergy, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sverzellati</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Radiology, Dept of Surgical Sciences, University Hospital of Parma, Parma, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vitacca</LastName><ForeName>Michele</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9389-7915</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istituti Clinici Scientifici Maugeri IRCCS, Respiratory Rehabilitation of the Institute of Lumezzane, Brescia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Witzenrath</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept of Internal Medicine/Infectious Diseases and Respiratory Medicine, Charite - Universitatsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tonia</LastName><ForeName>Thomy</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Social and Preventive Medicine, University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spanevello</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept of Medicine and Surgery, University of Insubria, Varese, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept of Medicine and Cardiopulmonary Rehabilitation, Maugeri Care and Research Institute, IRCCS Tradate, Varese, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur Respir J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8803460</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0903-1936</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest: K.M. Antoniou declares consulting fees, payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events and support for attending meetings and/or travel from Boehringer Ingelheim and Roche, in the 36&#x2005;months prior to manuscript submission; and an unpaid role as Secretary of the European Respiratory Society Interstitial Lung Diseases Assembly. E. Vasarmidi declares no competing interests. A-M. Russell declares payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events, and support for attending meetings and/or travel from Boehringer Ingelheim, Roche and the Irish Lung Fibrosis Association, in the 36&#x2005;months prior to manuscript submission. C. Andrejak declares an honorarium for a lecture on COVID-19 for &#x201c;Avanc&#xe9;es en Pneumologie&#x201d; (Actuality on Respiratory Disease) funded by AstraZeneca; support for attending meetings and/or travel from Aeris Medical, SOS Oxyg&#xe8;ne and Vitalaire; and participation on an advisory board on the French COVID Cohort, an institutional epidemiological study, in the 36&#x2005;months prior to manuscript submission; in addition, they are a member of the French Public Health Council (COVID treatment group) and participate on an advisory board for an prospective cohort study on COVID sequelae (SEQ COV). B. Crestani reports grants to their institution from Boehringer Ingelheim and Roche; consulting fees from Apellis, Boehringer Ingelheim, Roche and Sanofi; payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events, and support for attending meetings and/or travel from Boehringer Ingelheim, Roche, Novartis and Sanofi; and paid participation on a data safety monitoring board or advisory board for Apellis, Boehringer Ingelheim, Roche and Sanofi, in the 36&#x2005;months prior to manuscript submission. M. Delcroix declares no competing interests. A.T. Dinh-Xuan declares payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations or educational events from Chiesi, Circassia, GlaxoSmithKline, Novartis and Sanofi, in the 36&#x2005;months prior to manuscript submission. V. Poletti declares no competing interests. N. Sverzellati declares payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events from Boehringer Ingelheim, Roche and Chiesi; and support for attending meetings and/or travel from Boehringer Ingelheim, in the 36&#x2005;months prior to manuscript submission. M. Vitacca declares no competing interests. M. Witzenrath declares grant funding from Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft, Bundesministerium f&#xfc;r Bildung und Forschung, Deutsche Gesellschaft f&#xfc;r Pneumologie, European Respiratory Society, Marie Curie Foundation, Else Kr&#xf6;ner Fresenius Stiftung, Capnetz Stiftung, International Max Planck Research School, Quark Pharma, Takeda Pharma, Noxxon, Pantherna, Silence Therapeutics, Vaxxilon, Actelion, Bayer Health Care, Biotest and Boehringer Ingelheim; consulting fees from Noxxon, Pantherna, Silence Therapeutics, Vaxxilon, Aptarion, GlaxoSmithKline, Sinoxa and Biotest; payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events from AstraZeneca, Berlin-Chemie, Chiesi, Novartis, Teva, Actelion, Boehringer Ingelheim, GlaxoSmithKline, Biotest and Bayer Health Care, in the 36&#x2005;months prior to manuscript submission; and three patents relating to modulation of immune response in acute lung injury, inhibition of Ang-2 expression and treatment of SARS-CoV-2-infected lung cells, respectively. T. Tonia acts as a European Respiratory Society Methodologist. A. Spanevello declares payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events, and support for attending meetings and/or travel from Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, GlaxoSmithKline, AstraZeneca, Menarini, Guidotti and Chiesi, in the 36&#x2005;months prior to manuscript submission.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35144991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9349784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02174-2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">13993003.02174-2021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chalmers JD, Crichton ML, Goeminne PC, et al. . Management of hospitalised adults with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a European Respiratory Society living guideline. Eur Respir J 2021; 57: 2100048. doi:10.1183/13993003.00048-2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00048-2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7947358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spruit MA, Holland AE, Singh SJ, et al. . COVID-19: interim guidance on rehabilitation in the hospital and post-hospital phase from a European Respiratory Society- and American Thoracic Society-coordinated international task force. Eur Respir J 2020; 56: 2002197. doi:10.1183/13993003.02197-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02197-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32817258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen DJA, Ekstr&#xf6;m M, Currow DC, et al. . COVID-19: guidance on palliative care from a European Respiratory Society international task force. Eur Respir J 2020; 56: 2002583. doi:10.1183/13993003.02583-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02583-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7366176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32675211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard. 2022. https://covid19.who.int
Date last accessed: 4 May 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. . Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med 2021; 27: 601&#x2013;615. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F, et al. . Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA 2020; 324: 603. doi:10.1001/jama.2020.12603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.12603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Waterer G, Pe&#xf1;alvo JL, et al. . Nefer, Sinuhe and clinical research assessing post COVID-19 condition. Eur Respir J 2021; 57: 2004423. doi:10.1183/13993003.04423-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.04423-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7778876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33380509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, et al. . 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet 2021; 397: 220&#x2013;232. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A'Court C, et al. . Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ 2020; 370: m3026. doi:10.1136/bmj.m3026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m3026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, et al. . Defining post-COVID symptoms (post-acute COVID, long COVID, persistent post-COVID): an integrative classification. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021; 18: 2621. doi:10.3390/ijerph18052621</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18052621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi N. Long covid: how to define it and how to manage it. BMJ 2020; 370: m3489. doi:10.1136/bmj.m3489</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m3489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32895219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladds E, Rushforth A, Wieringa S, et al. . Persistent symptoms after Covid-19: qualitative study of 114 &#x201c;long Covid&#x201d; patients and draft quality principles for services. BMC Health Serv Res 2020; 20: 1144. doi:10.1186/s12913-020-06001-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-020-06001-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7750006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33342437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amenta EM, Spallone A, Rodriguez-Barradas MC, et al. . Postacute COVID-19: an overview and approach to classification. Open Forum Infect Dis 2020; 7: ofaa509. doi:10.1093/ofid/ofaa509</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ofid/ofaa509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33403218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence, Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network, and the Royal College of General Practitioners . COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. NICE guideline (NG188). 2020. www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188
Last updated: 11 November 2021. Date last accessed: 3 March 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health Research . Living with Covid19 &#x2013; second review. 2020. https://evidence.nihr.ac.uk/themedreview/living-with-covid19-second-review
Date last accessed: 17 May 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahase E. Long covid could be four different syndromes, review suggests. BMJ 2020; 371: m3981. doi:10.1136/bmj.m3981</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m3981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33055076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrejak C, Cottin V, Crestani B, et al. . Guide de prise en charge des s&#xe9;quelles respiratoires post infection &#xe0; SARS-CoV-2. Propositions de prise en charge &#xe9;labor&#xe9;es par la Soci&#xe9;t&#xe9; de Pneumologie de Langue Fran&#xe7;aise. Version du 10 novembre 2020. [Guide for management of patients with possible respiratory sequelae after a SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia. Support proposals developed by the French-speaking Respiratory Medicine Society. Version of 10 November 2020.]. Rev Mal Respir 2021; 38: 114&#x2013;121. doi:10.1016/j.rmr.2020.11.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmr.2020.11.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7691188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33280941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George PM, Barratt SL, Condliffe R, et al. . Respiratory follow-up of patients with COVID-19 pneumonia. Thorax 2020; 75: 1009&#x2013;1016. doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-215314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-215314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32839287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dowds J, O'Brien K, et al. . Persistent poor health post-COVID-19 is not associated with respiratory complications or initial disease severity. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2021; 18: 997&#x2013;1003. doi:10.1513/AnnalsATS.202009-1175OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1513/AnnalsATS.202009-1175OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8456724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez O, Merino E, Leon-Ramirez J-M, et al. . Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: a Mediterranean cohort study. J Infect 2021; 82: 378&#x2013;383. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2021.01.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2021.01.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7802523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paderno A, Mattavelli D, Rampinelli V, et al. . Olfactory and gustatory outcomes in COVID-19: a prospective evaluation in nonhospitalized subjects. Otolaryngol Neck Surg 2020; 163: 1144&#x2013;1149. doi:10.1177/0194599820939538</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0194599820939538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7331108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32600175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Fan Y, Alwalid O, et al. . Six-month follow-up chest CT findings after severe COVID-19 pneumonia. Radiology 2021; 299: E177&#x2013;E186. doi:10.1148/radiol.2021203153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2021203153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7841877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guler SA, Ebner L, Aubry-Beigelman C, et al. . Pulmonary function and radiological features 4&#x2005;months after COVID-19: first results from the national prospective observational Swiss COVID-19 lung study. Eur Respir J 2021; 57: 2003690. doi:10.1183/13993003.03690-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.03690-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8082329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33419891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao B, Liu Z, Tang L, et al. . Longitudinal clinical and radiographic evaluation reveals interleukin-6 as an indicator of persistent pulmonary injury in COVID-19. Int J Med Sci 2021; 18: 29&#x2013;41. doi:10.7150/ijms.49728</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/ijms.49728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7738960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33390771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Zhou H, Zhou Y, et al. . Risk factors associated with disease severity and length of hospital stay in COVID-19 patients. J Infect 2020; 81: e95&#x2013;e97. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2020.04.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2020.04.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7162771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32305490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong AW, Shah AS, Johnston JC, et al. . Patient-reported outcome measures after COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Eur Respir J 2020; 56: 2003276. doi:10.1183/13993003.03276-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.03276-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7530908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33008936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo X, Jian W, Su Z, et al. . Abnormal pulmonary function in COVID-19 patients at time of hospital discharge. Eur Respir J 2020; 55: 2001217. doi:10.1183/13993003.01217-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.01217-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32381497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellan M, Soddu D, Balbo PE, et al. . Respiratory and psychophysical sequelae among patients with COVID-19 four months after hospital discharge. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4: e2036142. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.36142</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.36142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7841464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33502487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Shang Y, Song W, et al. . Follow-up study of the pulmonary function and related physiological characteristics of COVID-19 survivors three months after recovery. EClinicalMedicine 2020; 25: 100463. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100463</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meiners S, Eickelberg O, K&#xf6;nigshoff M. Hallmarks of the ageing lung. Eur Respir J 2015; 45: 807&#x2013;827. doi:10.1183/09031936.00186914</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00186914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25657021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venturelli S, Benatti SV, Casati M, et al. . Surviving COVID-19 in Bergamo province: a post-acute outpatient re-evaluation. Epidemiol Infect 2021; 149: e32. doi:10.1017/S0950268821000145</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0950268821000145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patell R, Bogue T, Koshy A, et al. . Postdischarge thrombosis and hemorrhage in patients with COVID-19. Blood 2020; 136: 1342&#x2013;1346. doi:10.1182/blood.2020007938</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.2020007938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32766883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salisbury R, Iotchkova V, Jaafar S, et al. . Incidence of symptomatic, image-confirmed venous thromboembolism following hospitalization for COVID-19 with 90-day follow-up. Blood Adv 2020; 4: 6230&#x2013;6239. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2020003349</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2020003349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7757009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33351117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher A, Balfanz P, Cornelissen C, et al. . Follow up of patients with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): pulmonary and extrapulmonary disease sequelae. Respir Med 2020; 174: 106197. doi:10.1016/j.rmed.2020.106197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2020.106197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33120193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demelo-Rodr&#xed;guez P, Ordieres-Ortega L, Ji Z, et al. . Long-term follow-up of patients with venous thromboembolism and COVID-19: analysis of risk factors for death and major bleeding. Eur J Haematol 2021; 106: 716&#x2013;723. doi:10.1111/ejh.13603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ejh.13603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33608914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackermann M, Verleden SE, Kuehnel M, et al. . Pulmonary vascular endothelialitis, thrombosis, and angiogenesis in Covid-19. N Engl J Med 2020; 383: 120&#x2013;128. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2015432</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2015432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7412750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konstantinides SV, Meyer G, Becattini C, et al. . 2019 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and management of acute pulmonary embolism developed in collaboration with the European Respiratory Society (ERS). Eur Heart J 2020; 41: 543&#x2013;603. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehz405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehz405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31504429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delcroix M, Torbicki A, Gopalan D, et al. . ERS statement on chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension. Eur Respir J 2021; 57: 2002828.doi:10.1183/13993003.02828-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02828-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33334946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhawan RT, Gopalan D, Howard L, et al. . Beyond the clot: perfusion imaging of the pulmonary vasculature after COVID-19. Lancet Respir Med 2021; 9: 107&#x2013;116. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30407-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30407-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33217366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gali&#xe8; N, Humbert M, Vachiery J-L, et al. . 2015 ESC/ERS Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary hypertension: The Joint Task Force for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Pulmonary Hypertension of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) and the European Respiratory Society (ERS). Eur Respir J 2015; 46: 903&#x2013;975. doi:10.1183/13993003.01032-2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.01032-2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26318161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gali&#xe8; N, Humbert M, Vachiery J-L, et al. . 2015 ESC/ERS Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary hypertension: The Joint Task Force for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Pulmonary Hypertension of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) and the European Respiratory Society (ERS). Eur Heart J 2016; 37: 67&#x2013;119. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehv317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehv317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26320113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cort&#xe9;s-Telles A, L&#xf3;pez-Romero S, Figueroa-Hurtado E, et al. . Pulmonary function and functional capacity in COVID-19 survivors with persistent dyspnoea. Respir Physiol Neurobiol 2021; 288: 103644. doi:10.1016/j.resp.2021.103644</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resp.2021.103644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7910142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33647535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B, Peters JB, Brink M, et al. . Comprehensive health assessment three months after recovery from acute COVID-19. Clin Infect Dis 2021; 73: e1089&#x2013;e1098. doi:10.1093/cid/ciaa1750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciaa1750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah AS, Wong AW, Hague CJ, et al. . A prospective study of 12-week respiratory outcomes in COVID-19-related hospitalisations. Thorax 2021; 76: 402&#x2013;404. doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerum TV, Aal&#xf8;kken TM, Br&#xf8;nstad E, et al. . Dyspnoea, lung function and CT findings 34&#x2005;months after hospital admission for COVID-19. Eur Respir J 2021; 57: 2003448. doi:10.1183/13993003.03448-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.03448-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puchner B, Sahanic S, Kirchmair R, et al. . Beneficial effects of multi-disciplinary rehabilitation in postacute COVID-19: an observational cohort study. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 2021; 57: 189&#x2013;198. doi:10.23736/S1973-9087.21.06549-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.21.06549-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33448756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Ben&#xed;tez ID, Carmona P, et al. . Pulmonary function and radiologic features in survivors of critical COVID-19. Chest 2021; 160: 187&#x2013;198. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2021.02.062</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2021.02.062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7930807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33676998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco J-R, Cobos-Ceballos M-J, Navarro F, et al. . Pulmonary long-term consequences of COVID-19 infections after hospital discharge. Clin Microbiol Infect 2021; 27: 892&#x2013;896. doi:10.1016/j.cmi.2021.02.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmi.2021.02.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7920814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33662544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truffaut L, Demey L, Bruyneel AV, et al. . Post-discharge critical COVID-19 lung function related to severity of radiologic lung involvement at admission. Respir Res 2021; 22: 29. doi:10.1186/s12931-021-01625-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-021-01625-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7819622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33478527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasio F, Barbuto S, Scarnecchia E, et al. . Medium-term impact of COVID-19 on pulmonary function, functional capacity and quality of life. Eur Respir J 2021; 58: 2004015. doi:10.1183/13993003.04015-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.04015-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7877327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33574080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Cassar MP, Tunnicliffe EM, et al. . Medium-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on multiple vital organs, exercise capacity, cognition, quality of life and mental health, post-hospital discharge. EClinicalMedicine 2021; 31: 100683. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100683</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33490928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Zhong L, Li H, et al. . A follow-up study of lung function and chest computed tomography at 64&#x2005;months after discharge in patients with coronavirus disease 2019. Can Respir J 2021; 2021: 6692409. doi:10.1155/2021/6692409</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/6692409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7881736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33628349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smet J, Stylemans D, Hanon S, et al. . Clinical status and lung function 10&#x2005;weeks after severe SARS-CoV-2 infection. Respir Med 2021; 176: 106276. doi:10.1016/j.rmed.2020.106276</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2020.106276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7701883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33278758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin W, Chen S, Zhang Y, et al. . Diffusion capacity abnormalities for carbon monoxide in patients with COVID-19 at 3-month follow-up. Eur Respir J 2021; 58: 2003677. doi:10.1183/13993003.03677-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.03677-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7877322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33574077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Zhou M, Luo P, et al. . Plasma metabolomic profiling of patients recovered from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) with pulmonary sequelae 34&#x2005;months after discharge. Clin Infect Dis 2021; 73: 2228&#x2013;2239. doi:10.1093/cid/ciab147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33596592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnweber T, Sahanic S, Pizzini A, et al. . Cardiopulmonary recovery after COVID-19: an observational prospective multicentre trial. Eur Respir J 2021; 57: 2003481. doi:10.1183/13993003.03481-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.03481-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sar-van der Brugge S, Talman S, Boonman-de Winter L, et al. . Pulmonary function and health-related quality of life after COVID-19 pneumonia. Respir Med 2021; 176: 106272. doi:10.1016/j.rmed.2020.106272</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2020.106272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7701891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33302142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Graaf MA, Antoni ML, ter Kuile MM, et al. . Short-term outpatient follow-up of COVID-19 patients: a multidisciplinary approach. EClinicalMedicine 2021; 32: 100731. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.100731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.100731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7843037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33532720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang L, Yang B, Jiang N, et al. . Three-month follow-up study of survivors of coronavirus disease 2019 after discharge. J Korean Med Sci 2020; 35: e418. doi:10.3346/jkms.2020.35.e418</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3346/jkms.2020.35.e418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7721559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33289374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trinkmann F, M&#xfc;ller M, Reif A, et al. . Residual symptoms and lower lung function in patients recovering from SARS-CoV-2 infection. Eur Respir J 2021; 57: 2003002. doi:10.1183/13993003.03002-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.03002-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7821834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33479105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curci C, Pisano F, Bonacci E, et al. . Early rehabilitation in post-acute COVID-19 patients: data from an Italian COVID-19 rehabilitation unit and proposal of a treatment protocol. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 2020; 56: 633&#x2013;641. doi:10.23736/S1973-9087.20.06339-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.20.06339-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32667150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermann M, Pekacka-Egli A-M, Witassek F, et al. . Feasibility and efficacy of cardiopulmonary rehabilitation after COVID-19. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 2020; 99: 865&#x2013;869. doi:10.1097/PHM.0000000000001549</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000001549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7406212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32732746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Chen R, Geng Q, et al. . Cardiopulmonary exercise testing might be helpful for interpretation of impaired pulmonary function in recovered COVID-19 patients. Eur Respir J 2021; 57: 2004265. doi:10.1183/13993003.04265-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.04265-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7758779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33361097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debeaumont D, Boujibar F, Ferrand-Devouge E, et al. . Cardiopulmonary exercise testing to assess persistent symptoms at 64&#x2005;months in people with COVID-19 who survived hospitalization &#x2013; a pilot study. Phys Ther 2021; 101: pzab099. doi:10.1093/ptj/pzab099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/pzab099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7989156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33735374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crameri GAG, Bielecki M, Z&#xfc;st R, et al. . Reduced maximal aerobic capacity after COVID-19 in young adult recruits, Switzerland, May 2020. Euro Surveill 2020; 25; 2001542. doi:10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2020.25.36.2001542</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2020.25.36.2001542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7502899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32914744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fumagalli A, Misuraca C, Bianchi A, et al. . Pulmonary function in patients surviving to COVID-19 pneumonia. Infection 2021; 49: 153&#x2013;157. doi:10.1007/s15010-020-01474-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s15010-020-01474-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7386387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>You J, Zhang L, Ni-jia-Ti M, et al. . Anormal pulmonary function and residual CT abnormalities in rehabilitating COVID-19 patients after discharge. J Infect 2020; 81: e150&#x2013;e152. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2020.06.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2020.06.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7273134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32512021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Zhao X, Wang Y, et al. . Damaged lung gas exchange function of discharged COVID-19 patients detected by hyperpolarized 129 Xe MRI. Sci Adv 2021; 7: eabc8180. doi:10.1126/sciadv.abc8180</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.abc8180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7775756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33219111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barisione G, Brusasco V. Lung diffusing capacity for nitric oxide and carbon monoxide following mild-to-severe COVID-19. Physiol Rep 2021; 9: e14748. doi:10.14814/phy2.14748</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.14748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33625799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel K, Straudi S, Yee Sien N, et al. . Applying the WHO ICF framework to the outcome measures used in the evaluation of long-term clinical outcomes in coronavirus outbreaks. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2020; 17: 6476. doi:10.3390/ijerph17186476</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17186476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7558385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32899534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Castro R, Vasconcello-Castillo L, Alsina-Restoy X, et al. . Respiratory function in patients post-infection by COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pulmonology 2021; 27: 328&#x2013;337. doi:10.1016/j.pulmoe.2020.10.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pulmoe.2020.10.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7687368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33262076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>So M, Kabata H, Fukunaga K, et al. . Radiological and functional lung sequelae of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Pulm Med 2021; 21: 97. doi:10.1186/s12890-021-01463-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-021-01463-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7983097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33752639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Tan C, Wu J, et al. . Impact of coronavirus disease 2019 on pulmonary function in early convalescence phase. Respir Res 2020; 21: 163. doi:10.1186/s12931-020-01429-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-020-01429-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32600344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Zhang W, Yang Y, et al. . Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: a randomized controlled study. Complement Ther Clin Pract 2020; 39: 101166. doi:10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101166</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman DG, Badal T, King GG, et al. . Caution in interpretation of abnormal carbon monoxide diffusion capacity in COVID-19 patients. Eur Respir J 2021; 57: 2003263. doi:10.1183/13993003.03263-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.03263-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7651835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33154026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes JMB, Pride NB. Examination of the carbon monoxide diffusing capacity (DlCO) in relation to its Kco and Va components. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2012; 186: 132&#x2013;139. doi:10.1164/rccm.201112-2160CI</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.201112-2160CI</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22538804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alharthy A, Abuhamdah M, Balhamar A, et al. . Residual lung injury in patients recovering from COVID-19 critical illness: a prospective longitudinal point-of-care lung ultrasound study. J Ultrasound Med 2020; 40: 1823&#x2013;1838. doi:10.1002/jum.15563</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jum.15563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33185316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogliani P, Calzetta L, Coppola A, et al. . Are there pulmonary sequelae in patients recovering from COVID-19? Respir Res 2020; 21: 286. doi:10.1186/s12931-020-01550-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-020-01550-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7598236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33126869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel N, Goyal N, Kumar R. Clinico-radiological evaluation of post COVID-19 at a tertiary pulmonary care centre in Delhi, India. Monaldi Arch Chest Dis 2021; 91: 1682. doi:10.4081/monaldi.2021.1682</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/monaldi.2021.1682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33691394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y, Xia L, Wang Y, et al. . Dynamic changes in computed tomography manifestations of 105 patients with novel coronavirus pneumonia in Wuhan, China. J Int Med Res 2020; 48: 030006052097291. doi:10.1177/0300060520972913</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0300060520972913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7686644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33213239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai M, Liu X, Zhu X, et al. . Temporal changes of CT findings between non-severe and severe cases of COVID-19 pneumonia: a multi-center, retrospective, longitudinal study. Int J Med Sci 2020; 17: 2653&#x2013;2662. doi:10.7150/ijms.51159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/ijms.51159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7645333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33162793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabatabaei SMH, Rajebi H, Moghaddas F, et al. . Chest CT in COVID-19 pneumonia: what are the findings in mid-term follow-up? Emerg Radiol 2020; 27: 711&#x2013;719. doi:10.1007/s10140-020-01869-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10140-020-01869-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7649573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33165674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu N, He G, Yang X, et al. . Dynamic changes of chest CT follow-up in coronavirus disease-19 (COVID-19) pneumonia: relationship to clinical typing. BMC Med Imaging 2020; 20: 92. doi:10.1186/s12880-020-00491-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12880-020-00491-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7403785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32758155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Jin C, Wu CC, et al. . Organizing pneumonia of COVID-19: time-dependent evolution and outcome in CT findings. PLoS One 2020; 15: e0240347. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0240347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0240347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7657520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avanzato VA, Matson MJ, Seifert SN, et al. . Case study: prolonged infectious SARS-CoV-2 shedding from an asymptomatic immunocompromised individual with cancer. Cell 2020; 183: 1901&#x2013;1912. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2020.10.049</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.10.049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7640888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33248470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong W, Brieva C, May M, et al. . A double-edged sword: prolonged detection of SARS-COV-2 in patients receiving cancer directed therapy. Semin Oncol 2021; 48: 166&#x2013;170. doi:10.1053/j.seminoncol.2020.11.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.seminoncol.2020.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33334607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Piper-Vallillo AJ, Bindal P, et al. . Time to SARS-CoV-2 clearance among patients with cancer and COVID-19. Cancer Med 2021; 10: 1545&#x2013;1549. doi:10.1002/cam4.3708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cam4.3708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7940218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33560590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveh Y, Simkins J, Vianna R, et al. . A less restrictive policy for liver transplantation in coronavirus disease 2019 positive patients, based upon cycle threshold values. Transplant Proc 2021; 53: 1126&#x2013;1131. doi:10.1016/j.transproceed.2021.01.035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.transproceed.2021.01.035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7816591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33610305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waghmare A, Abidi MZ, Boeckh M, et al. . Guidelines for COVID-19 management in hematopoietic cell transplantation and cellular therapy recipients. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant 2020; 26: 1983&#x2013;1994. doi:10.1016/j.bbmt.2020.07.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbmt.2020.07.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7386267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32736007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cevik M, Tate M, Lloyd O, et al. . SARS-CoV-2, SARS-CoV, and MERS-CoV viral load dynamics, duration of viral shedding, and infectiousness: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Microbe 2021; 2: e13&#x2013;e22. doi:10.1016/S2666-5247(20)30172-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2666-5247(20)30172-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33521734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Cruz RF, Waller MD, Perrin F, et al. . Chest radiography is a poor predictor of respiratory symptoms and functional impairment in survivors of severe COVID-19 pneumonia. ERJ Open Res 2021; 7: 00655-2020. doi:10.1183/23120541.00655-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00655-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7585700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33575312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues E, Janvier P, Kherabi Y, et al. . Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. J Infect 2020; 81: e4&#x2013;e6. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2020.08.029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2020.08.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs LG, Gourna Paleoudis E, Lesky-Di Bari D, et al. . Persistence of symptoms and quality of life at 35&#x2005;days after hospitalization for COVID-19 infection. PLoS One 2020; 15: e0243882. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0243882</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0243882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7732078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M, Lazzeri M, Guffanti E, et al. . Italian suggestions for pulmonary rehabilitation in COVID-19 patients recovering from acute respiratory failure: results of a Delphi process. Monaldi Arch Chest Dis 2020; 90: 1444. doi:10.4081/monaldi.2020.1444</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/monaldi.2020.1444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32573175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite VF, Rampim DB, Jorge VC, et al. . Persistent symptoms and disability after COVID-19 hospitalization: data from a comprehensive telerehabilitation program. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2021; 102: 1308&#x2013;1316. doi:10.1016/j.apmr.2021.03.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2021.03.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7943375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33711279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apea VJ, Wan YI, Dhairyawan R, et al. . Ethnicity and outcomes in patients hospitalised with COVID-19 infection in East London: an observational cohort study. BMJ Open 2021; 11: e042140. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2020-042140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-042140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7813387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33455936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado FVC, Meys R, Delbressine JM, et al. . Construct validity of the post-COVID-19 Functional Status Scale in adult subjects with COVID-19. Health Qual Life Outcomes 2021; 19: 40. doi:10.1186/s12955-021-01691-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-021-01691-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7856622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33536042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matalon N, Dorman-Ilan S, Hasson-Ohayon I, et al. . Trajectories of post-traumatic stress symptoms, anxiety, and depression in hospitalized COVID-19 patients: a one-month follow-up. J Psychosom Res 2021; 143: 110399. doi:10.1016/j.jpsychores.2021.110399</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2021.110399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7885629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33618149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demeco A, Marotta N, Barletta M, et al. . Rehabilitation of patients post-COVID-19 infection: a literature review. J Int Med Res 2020; 48: 030006052094838. doi:10.1177/0300060520948382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0300060520948382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7450453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32840156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valent A, Dudoignon E, Ressaire Q, et al. . Three-month quality of life in survivors of ARDS due to COVID-19: a preliminary report from a French academic centre. Anaesth Crit Care Pain Med 2020; 39: 740&#x2013;741. doi:10.1016/j.accpm.2020.10.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.accpm.2020.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7547571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33049394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arab-Zozani M, Hashemi F, Safari H, et al. . Health-related quality of life and its associated factors in COVID-19 patients. Osong Public Health Res Perspect 2020; 11: 296&#x2013;302. doi:10.24171/j.phrp.2020.11.5.05</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24171/j.phrp.2020.11.5.05</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7577388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33117634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taboada M, Moreno E, Cari&#xf1;ena A, et al. . Quality of life, functional status, and persistent symptoms after intensive care of COVID-19 patients. Br J Anaesth 2021; 126: e110&#x2013;e113. doi:10.1016/j.bja.2020.12.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2020.12.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agostini F, Mangone M, Ruiu P, et al. . Rehabilitation setting during and after Covid-19: an overview on recommendations. J Rehabil Med 2021; 53: jrm00141. doi:10.2340/16501977-2776</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/16501977-2776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8772378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33284353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dowds J, O'Brien K, et al. . Persistent poor health post-COVID-19 is not associated with respiratory complications or initial disease severity. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2021; 18: 997&#x2013;1003. doi:10.1513/AnnalsATS.202009-1175OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1513/AnnalsATS.202009-1175OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8456724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT, Hamilton FW, Milne A, et al. . Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up: results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax 2021; 76: 399&#x2013;401. doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216086</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monti G, Leggieri C, Fominskiy E, et al. . Two-months quality of life of COVID-19 invasively ventilated survivors; an Italian single-center study. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand 2021; 65: 912&#x2013;920. doi:10.1111/aas.13812</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aas.13812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33655487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willi S, L&#xfc;thold R, Hunt A, et al. . COVID-19 sequelae in adults aged less than 50&#x2005;years: a systematic review. Travel Med Infect Dis 2021; 40: 101995. doi:10.1016/j.tmaid.2021.101995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tmaid.2021.101995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7898978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33631340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, et al. . Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network &#x2013; United States, March&#x2013;June 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2020; 69: 993&#x2013;998. doi:10.15585/mmwr.mm6930e1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm6930e1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baricich A, Borg MB, Cuneo D, et al. . Midterm functional sequelae and implications in rehabilitation after COVID-19: a cross-sectional study. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 2021; 57: 199&#x2013;207. doi:10.23736/S1973-9087.21.06699-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.21.06699-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33565741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belli S, Balbi B, Prince I, et al. . Low physical functioning and impaired performance of activities of daily life in COVID-19 patients who survived hospitalisation. Eur Respir J 2020; 56: 2002096. doi:10.1183/13993003.02096-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02096-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7411272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32764112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel SY, Mehrotra A, Huskamp HA, et al. . Variation in telemedicine use and outpatient care during the COVID-19 pandemic in the United States: study examines variation in total US outpatient visits and telemedicine use across patient demographics, specialties, and conditions during the COVID-19 pandemic. Health Aff 2021; 40: 349&#x2013;358. doi:10.1377/hlthaff.2020.01786</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1377/hlthaff.2020.01786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33523745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attipoe-Dorcoo S, Delgado R, Gupta A, et al. . Mobile health clinic model in the COVID-19 pandemic: lessons learned and opportunities for policy changes and innovation. Int J Equity Health 2020; 19: 73. doi:10.1186/s12939-020-01175-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12939-020-01175-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32429920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen K, Patel M, Lawrence C, et al. . Delivering telerehabilitation to COVID-19 inpatients: a retrospective chart review suggests it is a viable option. HSS J 2020; 16: 64&#x2013;70. doi:10.1007/s11420-020-09774-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11420-020-09774-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7364751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32837409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhadi M, Msherghi A, Elhadi A, et al. . Utilization of telehealth services in Libya in response to the COVID-19 pandemic: cross-sectional analysis. JMIR Med Inform 2021; 9: e23335. doi:10.2196/23335</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/23335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7919841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33606654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luks AM, Swenson ER. Pulse oximetry for monitoring patients with COVID-19 at home. Potential pitfalls and practical guidance. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2020; 17: 1040&#x2013;1046. doi:10.1513/AnnalsATS.202005-418FR</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1513/AnnalsATS.202005-418FR</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7462317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32521167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faezipour M, Abuzneid A. Smartphone-based self-testing of COVID-19 using breathing sounds. Telemed E-Health 2020; 26: 1202&#x2013;1205. doi:10.1089/tmj.2020.0114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/tmj.2020.0114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32487005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebbert JO, Ramar P, Tulledge-Scheitel SM, et al. . Patient preferences for telehealth services in a large multispecialty practice. J Telemed Telecare 2021; in press [10.1177/1357633X20980302]. doi:10.1177/1357633X20980302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1357633X20980302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1357633X20980302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoel V, von Zweck C, Ledgerd R, et al. . Was a global pandemic needed to adopt the use of telehealth in occupational therapy? Work 2021; 68: 13&#x2013;20. doi:10.3233/WOR-205268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/WOR-205268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33337401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Huidobro D, Rivera S, Valderrama Chang S, et al. . System-wide accelerated implementation of telemedicine in response to COVID-19: mixed methods evaluation. J Med Internet Res 2020; 22: e22146. doi:10.2196/22146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/22146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7541041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32903195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isautier JM, Copp T, Ayre J, et al. . People's experiences and satisfaction with telehealth during the COVID-19 pandemic in Australia: cross-sectional survey study. J Med Internet Res 2020; 22: e24531. doi:10.2196/24531</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/24531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7732356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33156806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barkai G, Gadot M, Amir H, et al. . Patient and clinician experience with a rapidly implemented large-scale video consultation program during COVID-19. Int J Qual Health Care 2021; 33: mzaa165. doi:10.1093/intqhc/mzaa165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzaa165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7799005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33313891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eddine IS, Zedan HS. Telehealth role during the COVID-19 pandemic: lessons learned from health care providers in Saudi Arabia. Telemed E-Health 2021; 27: 1249&#x2013;1259. doi:10.1089/tmj.2020.0489</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/tmj.2020.0489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33448900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian W, Wen L, Zhou Q, et al. . Digital health technologies respond to the COVID-19 pandemic in a tertiary hospital in China: development and usability study. J Med Internet Res 2020; 22: e24505. doi:10.2196/24505</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/24505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7690252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33141679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa CS, Trigueiro-Barbosa M, Aguiar R, et al. . What do asthmatic patients think about telemedicine visits? Eur Ann Allergy Clin Immunol 2021; 53: 138&#x2013;142. doi:10.23822/EurAnnACI.1764-1489.182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23822/EurAnnACI.1764-1489.182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33191719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An MH, You SC, Park RW, et al. . Using an extended technology acceptance model to understand the factors influencing telehealth utilization after flattening the COVID-19 curve in South Korea: cross-sectional survey study. JMIR Med Inform 2021; 9: e25435. doi:10.2196/25435</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/25435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7801132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33395397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondylakis H, Katehakis DG, Kouroubali A, et al. . COVID-19 mobile apps: a systematic review of the literature. J Med Internet Res 2020; 22: e23170. doi:10.2196/23170</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/23170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7732358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33197234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wynn R. E-health in Norway before and during the initial phase of the Covid-19 pandemic. Stud Health Technol Inform 2020; 272: 9&#x2013;12. doi:10.3233/SHTI200480</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/SHTI200480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32604587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manyati TK, Mutsau M. Exploring the effectiveness of telehealth interventions for diagnosis, contact tracing and care of Corona Virus Disease of 2019 (COVID19) patients in sub Saharan Africa: a rapid review. Health Technol 2021; 11: 341&#x2013;348. doi:10.1007/s12553-020-00485-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12553-020-00485-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7870280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33585154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philip P, Dupuy L, Morin CM, et al. . Smartphone-based virtual agents to help individuals with sleep concerns during COVID-19 confinement: feasibility study. J Med Internet Res 2020; 22: e24268. doi:10.2196/24268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/24268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7752183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33264099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jetty A, Jabbarpour Y, Westfall M, et al. . Capacity of primary care to deliver telehealth in the United States. J Am Board Fam Med 2021; 34: Suppl., S48&#x2013;S54. doi:10.3122/jabfm.2021.S1.200202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3122/jabfm.2021.S1.200202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33622818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsutsui M, Gerayeli F, Sin DD. Pulmonary rehabilitation in a post-COVID-19 world: telerehabilitation as a new standard in patients with COPD. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis 2021; 16: 379&#x2013;391. doi:10.2147/COPD.S263031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/COPD.S263031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33642858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings SC, Manning KM, Bettger JP, et al. . Rapid transition to telehealth group exercise and functional assessments in response to COVID-19. Gerontol Geriatr Med 2020; 6: 233372142098031. doi:10.1177/2333721420980313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2333721420980313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33403222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qureshi AZ, Ullah S, Aldajani AA, et al. . Telerehabilitation guidelines in Saudi Arabia. Telemed E-Health 2021; 27: 1087&#x2013;1098. doi:10.1089/tmj.2020.0355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/tmj.2020.0355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franzosa E, Gorbenko K, Brody AA, et al. . &#x201c;At home, with care&#x201d;: lessons from New York City home-based primary care practices managing COVID-19. J Am Geriatr Soc 2021; 69: 300&#x2013;306. doi:10.1111/jgs.16952</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgs.16952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8285037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33179761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf8;rgensen BB, Gregersen M, Pallesen SH, et al. . A group-based real-time videoconferencing telerehabilitation programme in recently discharged geriatric patients: a feasibility study. Eur Geriatr Med 2021; 12: 801&#x2013;808. doi:10.1007/s41999-020-00444-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41999-020-00444-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7863611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33544388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisk M, Livingstone A, Pit SW. Telehealth in the context of COVID-19: changing perspectives in Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States. J Med Internet Res 2020; 22: e19264. doi:10.2196/19264</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/19264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7286230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32463377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leochico CFD, Espiritu AI, Ignacio SD, et al. . Challenges to the emergence of telerehabilitation in a developing country: a systematic review. Front Neurol 2020; 11: 1007. doi:10.3389/fneur.2020.01007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2020.01007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7505991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33013666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seligman WH, Fialho L, Sillett N, et al. . Which outcomes are most important to measure in patients with COVID-19 and how and when should these be measured? Development of an international standard set of outcomes measures for clinical use in patients with COVID-19: a report of the International Consortium for Health Outcomes Measurement (ICHOM) COVID-19 Working Group. BMJ Open 2021; 11: e051065. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2021-051065</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-051065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8593274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34782342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, McAuley H, Harrison EM, et al. . Physical, cognitive, and mental health impacts of COVID-19 after hospitalisation (PHOSP-COVID): a UK multicentre, prospective cohort study. Lancet Respir Med 2021; 9: 1275&#x2013;1287. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00383-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00383-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34627560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antoniou KM, Raghu G, Tzilas V, et al. . Management of patients with interstitial lung disease in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic. Respiration 2020; 99: 625&#x2013;627. doi:10.1159/000509523</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000509523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7490496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32841954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montani D, Savale L, Beurnier A, et al. . Multidisciplinary approach for post-acute COVID-19 syndrome: time to break down the walls. Eur Respir J 2021; 58: 2101090. doi:10.1183/13993003.01090-2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.01090-2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8112007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33958429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laine C, Cotton D. COVID-19: evaluation and care of patients with persistent symptoms following acute SARS-CoV-2 infection. Ann Intern Med 2021; 174: 1159&#x2013;1160. doi:10.7326/M21-2342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M21-2342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8276272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34115532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paneroni M, Vitacca M, Bernocchi P, et al. . Feasibility of tele-rehabilitation in survivors of COVID-19 pneumonia. Pulmonology 2022; 28: 152&#x2013;154. doi:10.1016/j.pulmoe.2021.03.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pulmoe.2021.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8045455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33893061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suso-Mart&#xed; L, La Touche R, Herranz-G&#xf3;mez A, et al. . Effectiveness of telerehabilitation in physical therapist practice: an umbrella and mapping review with meta&#x2013;meta-analysis. Phys Ther 2021; 101: pzab075. doi:10.1093/ptj/pzab075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/pzab075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7928612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33611598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudatsir M, Fajar JK, Wulandari L, et al. . Predictors of COVID-19 severity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. F1000Research 2021; 9: 1107. doi:10.12688/f1000research.26186.2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/f1000research.26186.2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7607482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33163160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells AU, Devaraj A, Desai SR. Interstitial lung disease after COVID-19 infection: a catalog of uncertainties. Radiology 2021; 299: E216&#x2013;E218. doi:10.1148/radiol.2021204482</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2021204482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7841875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33502279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. . Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med 2021; 27: 626&#x2013;631. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von der Th&#xfc;sen J, Eerden M. Histopathology and genetic susceptibility in COVID-19 pneumonia. Eur J Clin Invest 2020; 50: e13259. doi:10.1111/eci.13259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/eci.13259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32353898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>