<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39245151</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-2742</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>89</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of infection</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Infect</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Antecedent and persistent symptoms in COVID-19 and other respiratory illnesses: Insights from prospectively collected data in the BRACE trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>106267</StartPage><MedlinePgn>106267</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jinf.2024.106267</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0163-4453(24)00201-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Some individuals have a persistence of symptoms following both COVID-19 (post-acute COVID-19 syndrome; PACS) and other viral infections. This study used prospectively collected data from an international trial to compare symptoms following COVID-19 and non-COVID-19 respiratory illness, to identify factors associated with the risk of PACS, and to explore symptom patterns before and after COVID-19 and non-COVID-19 respiratory illnesses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Data from a multicentre randomised controlled trial (BRACE trial) involving healthcare workers across four countries were analysed. Symptom data were prospectively collected over 12 months, allowing detailed characterisation of symptom patterns. Participants with COVID-19 and non-COVID-19 respiratory illness episodes were compared, focussing on symptom severity, duration (including PACS using NICE and WHO definitions), and pre-existing symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Compared to those with a non-COVID-19 illness, participants with COVID-19 had significantly more severe illness (OR 7&#xb7;4, 95%CI 5&#xb7;6-9&#xb7;7). Symptom duration meeting PACS definitions occurred in a higher proportion of COVID-19 cases than non-COVID-19 respiratory controls using both the NICE definition (2&#xb7;5% vs 0&#xb7;5%, OR 6&#xb7;6, 95%CI 2&#xb7;4-18&#xb7;3) and the WHO definition (8&#xb7;8% vs 3&#xb7;7%, OR 2&#xb7;5, 95%CI 1&#xb7;4-4&#xb7;3). When considering only participants with COVID-19, age 40-59 years (aOR 2&#xb7;8, 95%CI 1&#xb7;3-6&#xb7;2), chronic respiratory disease (aOR 5&#xb7;5, 95%CI 1&#xb7;3-23&#xb7;1), and pre-existing symptoms (aOR 3&#xb7;0, 95%CI 1&#xb7;4-6&#xb7;3) were associated with an increased risk of developing PACS. Symptoms associated with PACS were also reported by participants in the months preceding their COVID-19 or non-COVID-19 respiratory illnesses (32% fatigue and muscle ache, 11% intermittent cough and shortness of breath).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Healthcare workers with COVID-19 were more likely to have severe&#xa0;and longer-lasting symptoms than those with a non-COVID-19 respiratory illness, with a higher proportion meeting the WHO or NICE definitions of PACS. Age, chronic respiratory disease, and pre-existing symptoms increased the risk of developing PACS following COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDonald</LastName><ForeName>Ellie</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Group, Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia. Electronic address: ellie.mcdonald@mcri.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pittet</LastName><ForeName>Laure F</ForeName><Initials>LF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Group, Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia; Department of Paediatrics, The University of Melbourne, Parkville, Victoria, Australia; Immunology, Vaccinology, Rheumatology and Infectious Diseases Unit, Geneva University Hospitals and Faculty of Medicine, Geneva, Switzerland. Electronic address: laure.pittet@mcri.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barry</LastName><ForeName>Simone E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Medicine, Royal Adelaide Hospital, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia; Precision Medicine Theme, South Australian Health and Medical Research Institute, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia. Electronic address: simone.barry@sa.gov.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bonten</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ECRAID, European Clinical Research Alliance on Infectious Diseases, Utrecht, the Netherlands; Julius Center for Health Sciences and Primary Care, University Medical Centre Utrecht, Utrecht University, the Netherlands. Electronic address: m.j.m.bonten@umcutrecht.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campbell</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exeter Collaboration for Academic Primary Care, University of Exeter Medical School, Exeter, United Kingdom. Electronic address: john.campbell@exeter.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Croda</LastName><ForeName>Julio</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology of Microbial Diseases, Yale School of Public Health, New Haven, CT, USA; Fiocruz Mato Grosso do Sul, Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o Oswaldo Cruz, Campo Grande, Brazil; Universidade Federal de Mato Grosso do Sul, Campo Grande, Brazil. Electronic address: juliocroda@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Croda</LastName><ForeName>Mariana G</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade Federal de Mato Grosso do Sul, Campo Grande, Brazil. Electronic address: mgcroda@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dalcolmo</LastName><ForeName>Margareth Pretti</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Refer&#xea;ncia Professor H&#xe9;lio Fraga, ENSP/FIOCRUZ (Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o Oswaldo Cruz), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Electronic address: margarethdalcolmo@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davidson</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Melbourne Children's Trial Centre, Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia. Electronic address: andrew.davidson@mcri.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Almeida E Val</LastName><ForeName>Fernando F</ForeName><Initials>FF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tropical Medicine Foundation Dr Heitor Vieira Dourado, Brazil. Electronic address: ffaval@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dos Santos</LastName><ForeName>Glauce</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Refer&#xea;ncia Professor H&#xe9;lio Fraga, ENSP/FIOCRUZ (Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o Oswaldo Cruz), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Electronic address: glaucedossantos@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gardiner</LastName><ForeName>Kaya</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Group, Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia; Research Operations, The Royal Children's Hospital Melbourne, Parkville, Victoria, Australia. Electronic address: kaya.gardiner@mcri.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gell</LastName><ForeName>Grace</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Group, Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia. Electronic address: grace.gell2@rch.org.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gwee</LastName><ForeName>Amanda</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, The University of Melbourne, Parkville, Victoria, Australia; Infectious Diseases, Royal Children's Hospital Melbourne, Parkville, Victoria, Australia; Antimicrobials Group, Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia. Electronic address: amanda.gwee@rch.org.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krastev</LastName><ForeName>Ann</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Group, Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia. Electronic address: ann.krastev@mcri.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lacerda</LastName><ForeName>Marcus Vin&#xed;cius Guimaraes</ForeName><Initials>MVG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o de Medicina Tropical Dr Heitor Vieira Dourado, Manaus, Brazil; Instituto Le&#xf4;nidas &amp; Maria Deane, Oswaldo Cruz Foundation Ministry of Health, Manaus, Brazil; University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA. Electronic address: marcuslacerda.br@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lucas</LastName><ForeName>Michaela</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, Pathwest, Queen Elizabeth II Medical Centre, Nedlands, Western Australia, Australia; Department of Immunology, Perth Children's Hospital, Nedlands, Western Australia, Australia; Department of Immunology, Sir Charles Gairdner Hospital, Nedlands, Western Australia, Australia; School of Medicine, University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia. Electronic address: michaela.lucas@uwa.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lynn</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Precision Medicine Theme, South Australian Health and Medical Research Institute, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia; Flinders Health and Medical Research Institute, Flinders University, Bedford Park, South Australia, Australia. Electronic address: david.lynn@sahmri.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manning</LastName><ForeName>Laurens</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia; Department of Infectious Diseases, Fiona Stanley Hospital, Murdoch, Western Australia, Australia; Wesfarmers Centre for Vaccines and Infectious Diseases, Telethon Kids Institute, Nedlands, Western Australia, Australia. Electronic address: laurens.manning@uwa.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McPhate</LastName><ForeName>Nick</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Group, Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia. Electronic address: ncphate.n@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perrett</LastName><ForeName>Kirsten P</ForeName><Initials>KP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, The University of Melbourne, Parkville, Victoria, Australia; Department of Allergy and Immunology, Royal Children's Hospital Melbourne, Parkville, Victoria, Australia; Population Allergy Group, Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia. Electronic address: kirsten.perrett@rch.org.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Post</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, Prince of Wales Hospital, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia; School of Clinical Medicine, University of New South Wales, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia. Electronic address: Jeffrey.Post@health.nsw.gov.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prat-Aymerich</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ECRAID, European Clinical Research Alliance on Infectious Diseases, Utrecht, the Netherlands; Julius Center for Health Sciences and Primary Care, University Medical Centre Utrecht, Utrecht University, the Netherlands. Electronic address: C.PratAymerich-2@umcutrecht.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quinn</LastName><ForeName>Lynne E</ForeName><Initials>LE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exeter Clinical Trials Unit, Faculty of Health and Life Sciences, University of Exeter, St Luke's Campus, Heavitreee Road, Exeter, UK. Electronic address: lynned@me.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Richmond</LastName><ForeName>Peter C</ForeName><Initials>PC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia; Wesfarmers Centre for Vaccines and Infectious Diseases, Telethon Kids Institute, Nedlands, Western Australia, Australia; Department of Immunology and General Paediatrics, Perth Children's Hospital, Nedlands, Western Australia, Australia. Electronic address: peter.richmond@uwa.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wood</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas J</ForeName><Initials>NJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Health, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia; National Centre for Immunisation Research and Surveillance of Vaccine Preventable Disease, Westmead, New South Wales, Australia; Sydney Children's Hospital Network, Westmead, New South Wales, Australia. Electronic address: nicholas.wood@health.nsw.gov.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Messina</LastName><ForeName>Nicole L</ForeName><Initials>NL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Group, Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia; Department of Paediatrics, The University of Melbourne, Parkville, Victoria, Australia. Electronic address: nicole.messina@mcri.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Curtis</LastName><ForeName>Nigel</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Group, Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia; Department of Paediatrics, The University of Melbourne, Parkville, Victoria, Australia; Infectious Diseases, Royal Children's Hospital Melbourne, Parkville, Victoria, Australia. Electronic address: nigel.curtis@rch.org.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>BRACE Trial Consortium Group</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Infect</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7908424</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0163-4453</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012141" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Tract Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006282" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Personnel</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Age</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic respiratory disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthcare workers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multicentre study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-COVID-19 respiratory illness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Persistent symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PACS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pre-existing symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective data</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Symptom duration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Symptom patterns</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Symptom severity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39245151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11489119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2024.106267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0163-4453(24)00201-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Choutka J., Jansari V., Hornig M., Iwasaki A. Unexplained post-acute infection syndromes. Nat Med. 2022;28(5):911&#x2013;923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35585196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rando H.M., Bennett T.D., Byrd J.B., Bramante C., Callahan T.J., Chute C.G., et al. Challenges in defining Long COVID: striking differences across literature, Electronic Health Records, and patient-reported information. medRxiv [Preprint] 2021 doi: 10.1101/2021.03.20.21253896. PMID: PMC8010765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.03.20.21253896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A., Bernabei R., Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T., Jolley S.E., Karlson E.W., Levitan E.B., Levy B., McComsey G.A., et al. Development of a definition of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA. 2023;329(22):1934&#x2013;1946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10214179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) SIGNSaRCoGPR. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano J.B., Murthy S., Marshall J.C., Relan P., Diaz J.V. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(4):e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodin P., Casari G., Townsend L., O'Farrelly C., Tancevski I., Loffler-Ragg J., et al. Studying severe long COVID to understand post-infectious disorders beyond COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28(5):879&#x2013;882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35383311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atchison C.J., Davies B., Cooper E., Lound A., Whitaker M., Hampshire A., et al. Long-term health impacts of COVID-19 among 242,712 adults in England. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):6588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10598213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37875536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H.E., Assaf G.S., McCorkell L., Wei H., Low R.J., Re'em Y., et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottlieb M., Spatz E.S., Yu H., Wisk L.E., Elmore J.G., Gentile N.L., et al. Long COVID clinical phenotypes up to 6 months after infection identified by latent class analysis of self-reported symptoms. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2023;10(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10327879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37426952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter R.S., Nieters A., Krausslich H.G., Brockmann S.O., Gopel S., Kindle G., et al. Post-acute sequelae of covid-19 six to 12 months after infection: population based study. BMJ. 2022;379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9557001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36229057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastie C.E., Lowe D.J., McAuley A., Mills N.L., Winter A.J., Black C., et al. Natural history of long-COVID in a nationwide, population cohort study. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):3504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10263377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37311808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballering A.V., van Zon S.K.R., Olde Hartman T.C., Rosmalen J.G.M. Lifelines Corona Research I. Persistence of somatic symptoms after COVID-19 in the Netherlands: an observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022;400(10350):452&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9352274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35934007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M., Dercon Q., Luciano S., Geddes J.R., Husain M., Harrison PJ. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 2021;18(9) doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1003773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1003773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pittet L.F., Messina N.L., Gardiner K., Orsini F., Abruzzo V., Bannister S., et al. BCG vaccination to reduce the impact of COVID-19 in healthcare workers: protocol for a randomised controlled trial (BRACE trial) BMJ Open. 2021;11(10)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8557250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34711598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pittet L.F., Messina N.L., Orsini F., Moore C.L., Abruzzo V., Barry S., et al. Randomized trial of BCG vaccine to protect against Covid-19 in health care workers. N Engl J Med. 2023;388(17):1582&#x2013;1596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10497190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37099341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris P.A., Taylor R., Minor B.L., Elliott V., Fernandez M., O'Neal L., et al. The REDCap consortium: building an international community of software platform partners. J Biomed Inform. 2019;95</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7254481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31078660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris P.A., Taylor R., Thielke R., Payne J., Gonzalez N., Conde J.G. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)&#x2014;a metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform. 2009;42(2):377&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2700030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18929686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Report of the WHO-China Joint Mission on Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19); 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>StataCorp . StataCorp LLC; College Station, TX: 2023. Stata Statistical Software: Release 18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Costa V.G., Saivish M.V., Santos D.E.R., de Lima Silva R.F., Moreli M.L. Comparative epidemiology between the 2009 H1N1 influenza and COVID-19 pandemics. J Infect Public Health. 2020;13(12):1797&#x2013;1804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7553061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33121906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y., Choi T., Al-Aly Z. Long-term outcomes following hospital admission for COVID-19 versus seasonal influenza: a cohort study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2024;24(3):239&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38104583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H.E., McCorkell L., Vogel J.M., Topol E.J. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown M., Gerrard J., McKinlay L., Marquess J., Sparrow T., Andrews R. Ongoing symptoms and functional impairment 12 weeks after testing positive for SARS-CoV-2 or influenza in Australia: an observational cohort study. BMJ Public Health. 2023;1(1) doi: 10.1136/bmjph-2023-000060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjph-2023-000060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B., Mohn K.G., Brokstad K.A., Zhou F., Linchausen D.W., Hansen B.A., et al. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med. 2021;27(9):1607&#x2013;1613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertozzi G., Ferrara M., Maiese A., Di Fazio N., Delogu G., Frati P., et al. COVID-19 and H1N1-09: a systematic review of two pandemics with a focus on the lung at autopsy. Front Biosci. 2022;27(6):182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35748258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zang C., Zhang Y., Xu J., Bian J., Morozyuk D., Schenck E.J., et al. Data-driven analysis to understand long COVID using electronic health records from the RECOVER initiative. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):1948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10080528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37029117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>