<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37466117</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Persistent post-COVID-19 neuromuscular symptoms.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>350</StartPage><EndPage>355</EndPage><MedlinePgn>350-355</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27940</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Neuromuscular symptoms may develop or persist after resolution of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection. Besides residual sensorimotor symptoms associated with acute neuromuscular complications of coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19), such as Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome, critical illness neuromyopathy, and rhabdomyolysis, patients may report persistent autonomic symptoms, sensory symptoms, and muscle symptoms in the absence of these acute complications, including palpitations, orthostatic dizziness and intolerance, paresthesia, myalgia, and fatigue. These symptoms may be associated with long COVID, also known as post-COVID-19 conditions or postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection, which may significantly impact quality of life. Managing these symptoms represents a challenge for health-care providers. Recent advances have identified small-fiber neuropathy as a potential etiology that may underlie autonomic dysfunction and paresthesia in some long COVID patients. The pathogenic mechanisms underlying myalgia and fatigue remain elusive and need to be investigated. Herein we review the current state of knowledge regarding the evaluation and management of patients with persistent post-COVID-19 neuromuscular symptoms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abrams</LastName><ForeName>Rory M C</ForeName><Initials>RMC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Lan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Boston University School of Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Susan C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2275-1342</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063806" MajorTopicYN="N">Myalgia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010292" MajorTopicYN="N">Paresthesia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054969" MajorTopicYN="Y">Primary Dysautonomias</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myalgia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID-19 conditions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">small-fiber neuropathy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37466117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO Director-General's opening remarks at the media briefing on COVID-19. https://www.who.int/director-general/speeches/detail/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-the-media-briefing-on-covid-19---11-march-2020. Accessed July 20, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Sanchez CM, Diaz-Maroto I, Fernandez-Diaz E, et al. Neurologic manifestations in hospitalized patients with COVID-19: the ALBACOVID registry. Neurology. 2020;95:e1060-e1070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varatharaj A, Thomas N, Ellul MA, et al. Neurological and neuropsychiatric complications of COVID-19 in 153 patients: a UK-wide surveillance study. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;7:875-882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M, et al. Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:683-690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paliwal VK, Garg RK, Gupta A, Tejan N. Neuromuscular presentations in patients with COVID-19. Neurol Sci. 2020;41:3039-3056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi Consensus. October 6, 2021. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1. Accessed July 20, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath A. Long-haul COVID. Neurology. 2020;95:559-560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601-615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021;11:16144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rass V, Beer R, Schiefecker AJ, et al. Neurological outcomes 1 year after COVID-19 diagnosis: a prospective longitudinal cohort study. Eur J Neurol. 2022;29:1685-1696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taga A, Lauria G. COVID-19 and the peripheral nervous system. A 2-year review from the pandemic to the vaccine era. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2022;27:4-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suh J, Amato AA. Neuromuscular complications of coronavirus disease-19. Curr Opin Neurol. 2021;34:669-674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan NA. The road to addressing long Covid. Science. 2021;373:491-493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hope AA, Evering TH. Postacute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection. Infect Dis Clin North Am. 2022;36:379-395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth A, Chan PS, Jonas W. Addressing the long COVID crisis: integrative health and long COVID. Glob Adv Health Med. 2021;10:21649561211056597. doi:10.1177/21649561211056597</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L. Small fiber neuropathy. Semin Neurol. 2019;39:570-577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shouman K, Vanichkachorn G, Cheshire WP, et al. Autonomic dysfunction following COVID-19 infection: an early experience. Clin Auton Res. 2021;31:385-394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams RMC, Simpson DM, Navis A, Jette N, Zhou L, Shin SC. Small fiber neuropathy associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Muscle Nerve. 2022;65:440-443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burakgazi AZ. Small-fiber neuropathy possibly associated with COVID-19. Case Rep Neurol. 2022;14:208-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gemignani F. Small fiber neuropathy and SARS-CoV-2 infection. Another piece in the long COVID puzzle? Muscle Nerve. 2022;65:369-370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oaklander AL, Mills AJ, Kelley M, et al. Peripheral neuropathy evaluations of patients with prolonged long COVID. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2022;9:9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Shen D, Zhou H, Liu J, Chen S. Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection: causality or coincidence? Lancet Neurol. 2020;19:383-384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toscano G, Palmerini F, Ravaglia S, et al. Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome associated with SARS-CoV-2. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:2574-2576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andalib S, Biller J, Di Napoli M, et al. Peripheral nervous system manifestations associated with COVID-19. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2021;21:9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams RMC, Desland F, Lehrer H, et al. A case of Elsberg syndrome in the setting of asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Clin Neuromuscul Dis. 2021;22:228-231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galassi G, Marchioni A. Acute neuromuscular syndromes with respiratory failure during COVID-19 pandemic: where we stand and challenges ahead. J Clin Neurosci. 2022;101:264-275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Sanctis P, Doneddu PE, Vigano L, Selmi C, Nobile-Orazio E. Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. A systematic review. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27:2361-2370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutierrez-Ortiz C, Mendez-Guerrero A, Rodrigo-Rey S, et al. Miller Fisher syndrome and polyneuritis cranialis in COVID-19. Neurology. 2020;95:e601-e605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finsterer J, Scorza FA, Scorza C, Fiorini A. COVID-19 associated cranial nerve neuropathy: a systematic review. Bosn J Basic Med Sci. 2022;22:39-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijdicks EF, Klein CJ. Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome. Mayo Clin Proc. 2017;92:467-479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxley TJ, Mocco J, Majidi S, et al. Large-vessel stroke as a presenting feature of Covid-19 in the Young. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:e60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J, Kremer S, Merdji H, et al. Neurologic features in severe SARS-CoV-2 infection. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:2268-2270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velioglu SK, Ozmenoglu M, Boz C. Cerebral infarction following intravenous immunoglobulin therapy for Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2001;10:290-292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams RMC, Kim BD, Markantone DM, et al. Severe rapidly progressive Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome in the setting of acute COVID-19 disease. J Neurovirol. 2020;26:797-799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filosto M, Cotti Piccinelli S, Gazzina S, et al. Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome and COVID-19: an observational multicentre study from two Italian hotspot regions. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2021;92:751-756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keddie S, Pakpoor J, Mousele C, et al. Epidemiological and cohort study finds no association between COVID-19 and Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome. Brain. 2021;144:682-693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palaiodimou L, Stefanou MI, Katsanos AH, et al. Prevalence, clinical characteristics and outcomes of Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome spectrum associated with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28:3517-3529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidon AC, Amato AA. COVID-19 and neuromuscular disorders. Neurology. 2020;94:959-969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan WJ, Ni ZY, Hu Y, et al. Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:1708-1720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj L, Kannapadi NV, Briggs J, et al. Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: a meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci. 2022;434:120162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220-232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hejb&#xf8;l EK, Harbo T, Agergaard J, et al. Myopathy as a cause of fatigue in long-term post-COVID-19 symptoms: evidence of skeletal muscle histopathology. Eur J Neurol. 2022;29:2832-2841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T, Hittle M, Goodman SN. Assessment of the frequency and variety of persistent symptoms among patients with COVID-19: a systematic review. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2111417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, et al. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0240784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416-427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long COVID-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares MN, Eggelbusch M, Naddaf E, et al. Skeletal muscle alterations in patients with acute Covid-19 and post-acute sequelae of Covid-19. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022;13:11-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agergaard J, Leth S, Pedersen TH, et al. Myopathic changes in patients with long-term fatigue after COVID-19. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132:1974-1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Giorgio MR, Di Noia S, Morciano C, Conte D. The impact of SARS-CoV-2 on skeletal muscles. Acta Myol. 2020;39:307-312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh I, Joseph P, Heerdt PM, et al. Persistent exertional intolerance after COVID-19: insights from invasive cardiopulmonary exercise testing. Chest. 2022;161:54-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis Z, Book G, Litvin C, Kalivas B. The COVID-19 pandemic and zinc-induced copper deficiency: an important link. Am J Med. 2022;135:e290-e291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N, Gross JB Jr, Ahlskog JE. Copper deficiency myelopathy produces a clinical picture like subacute combined degeneration. Neurology. 2004;63:33-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N. Copper deficiency myelopathy (human swayback). Mayo Clin Proc. 2006;81:1371-1384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calderon-Ospina CA, Nava-Mesa MO, Paez-Hurtado AM. Update on safety profiles of vitamins B1, B6, and B12: a narrative review. Ther Clin Risk Manag. 2020;16:1275-1288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradbury J, Wilkinson S, Schloss J. Nutritional support during long COVID: A Systematic scoping review. J Integr Complement Med. 2023. doi:10.1089/jicm.2022.0821</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>