<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">36800878</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK589255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>European Observatory on Health Systems and Policies</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Copenhagen (Denmark)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="whopb47">Addressing backlogs and managing waiting lists during and beyond the COVID-19 pandemic</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Ginneken</LastName><ForeName>Ewout</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Observatory on Health Systems and Policies, Berlin University of Technology, Berlin, Germany</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reed</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuffield Trust, London, UK</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siciliani</LastName><ForeName>Luigi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Economics and Related Studies, University of York, UK</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eriksen</LastName><ForeName>Astrid</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Berlin University of Technology, Berlin, Germany</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schlepper</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuffield Trust, London, UK</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tille</LastName><ForeName>Florian</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Observatory on Health Systems and Policies, London, UK</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zapata</LastName><ForeName>Tomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>World Health Organization Regional Office for Europe, Copenhagen, Denmark</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><CollectionTitle book="whopbcollect">European Observatory Policy Briefs</CollectionTitle><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><Language>eng</Language><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>COVID-19 meant non-emergency procedures were postponed which led to backlogs of care (and particularly hospital and specialist care) in virtually all countries. These jeopardize health outcomes. Countries still struggle to understand the extent of backlogs but they are testing policies in practice and are generating lessons on what works. Drivers that <i>increase</i> the backlog include: -. Supply-side factors, such as: low numbers of health workers (even pre-COVID); lower productivity due to staff exhaustion; the extra cost of providing treatment safely; and weakened incentives for some care. -. Demand-side factors include: new technologies; the ageing of the population and the rise of chronic conditions (including long COVID). Drivers that <i>decrease</i> the backlog include: -. Supply-side factors, such as: sufficient workforce and infrastructure; extra funding; and more efficient new technologies and digital solutions. -. On the demand side, fear of infection may reduce demand, although this may also increase unmet need. Restoring care to previous levels is not enough to overcome the backlogs but three broad groups of (overlapping) strategies are helping: -. <b>Increasing workforce and staffing</b> with new professional roles and competencies; flexible recruitment and training; and improved work conditions and compensation. -. <b>Improving productivity, management of capacity and demand</b>, separating planned and unplanned care; introducing tailored financial incentives; expanding access to telehealth; careful prioritization; and spreading patients to fit available capacity. -. <b>Investing in capital, infrastructure and new models of care</b>, for example, by upgrading health facilities or digital infrastructure; investing in primary and community care; or expanding home care. Policy-makers can reduce the risks associated with these strategies by: -. Pairing improvements in workforce planning and availability with policies to support and protect health workers. -. Monitoring policies to rationalize health care delivery, reduce waste or use digital solutions to ensure they do not (inadvertently) increase inequalities in utilization and health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; World Health Organization 2022 (acting as the host organization for, and secretariat of, the European Observatory on Health Systems and Policies).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="whopb47" part="fm.ack">Acknowledgements</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="whopb47" part="fm.s1">Acronyms</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="whopb47" part="fm.s2">Foreword</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="whopb47" part="fm.s3">Executive summary</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="whopb47" part="chapter">POLICY BRIEF</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="whopb47" part="rl1">References</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="whopb47" part="note1">The Policy Brief Series</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Waiting Lists</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health Care Facilities, Manpower, and Services</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health Policy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health Systems Plans</Keyword></KeywordList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36800878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>