<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37468320</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1573</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Phytotherapy research : PTR</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phytother Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Culinary spices and herbs in managing early and long-COVID-19 complications: A comprehensive review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4908</StartPage><EndPage>4931</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4908-4931</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ptr.7957</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Human race is preparing for the upsurge and aftermath of COVID-19 pandemic complicated by novel variants, new waves, variable mortality rate, and post-COVID complications. Despite use of repurposed drugs, symptomatic treatments and licensing of multiple vaccines, the daily number of cases and rate of transmission are significant. Culinary spices and herbs have been historically used in pandemic and non-pandemic times to reduce respiratory viral burden. Specific food items and culinary spices can boost the levels of protective immunity and also offer therapeutic benefits against impervious bugs via well-known as well as less-known but scientifically testable mechanisms. Here, we analyzed the phytochemicals profile of Ayurvedic herbs and inferred from the clinical trials/observational studies to provide a focused and succinct perspective on the relevance of "food-based" traditional decoction to moderate COVID-19 disease and long-COVID via modulation of immunity and reinstatement of homeostasis. We also underscore the druggable targets in pathogenesis of COVID-19 which are relevant to the ongoing clinical trials using spices and herbs. This information will provide a strong scientific rationale for standardization of the traditional herbs-based therapies and adopting the use of herbs, spices, and their formulations for reducing SARS-CoV-2 transmission, long-COVID symptoms, and COVID-19 disease progression.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maurya</LastName><ForeName>Dharmendra Kumar</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0909-363X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiation Biology &amp; Health Sciences Division, Bhabha Atomic Research Centre, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Homi Bhabha National Institute, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Deepak</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7529-5574</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiation Biology &amp; Health Sciences Division, Bhabha Atomic Research Centre, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Homi Bhabha National Institute, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Department of Atomic Energy, Govt. of India</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Phytother Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904486</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0951-418X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005502" MajorTopicYN="N">Food</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ayurvedic Kwath</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anti-viral</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">culinary spices and herbs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunomodulation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37468320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.7957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Adluri, U. S. P., &amp; Tripathi, A. C. (2020). Understanding COVID-19 pandemic-A comprehensive Ayurvedic perspective. Journal of Ayurveda and Integrative Medicine, 13, 100348. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaim.2020.08.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agbaje, E. O., Adeneye, A. A., &amp; Daramola, A. O. (2009). Biochemical and toxicological studies of aqueous extract of Syzigium aromaticum (L.) Merr. &amp; Perry (Myrtaceae) in rodents. African Journal of Traditional, Complementary, and Alternative Medicines: AJTCAM, 6(3), 241-254. https://doi.org/10.4314/ajtcam.v6i3.57162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam, S., Bhuiyan, F. R., Emon, T. H., &amp; Hasan, M. (2021). Prospects of nutritional interventions in the care of COVID-19 patients. Heliyon, 7(2), e06285. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2021.e06285</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkhatib, M., Salpini, R., Carioti, L., Ambrosio, F. A., D'Anna, S., Duca, L., Costa, G., Bellocchi, M. C., Piermatteo, L., Artese, A., Santoro, M. M., Alcaro, S., Svicher, V., &amp; Ceccherini-Silberstein, F. (2022). Update on SARS-CoV-2 omicron variant of concern and its peculiar mutational profile. Microbiology Spectrum, 10(2), e0273221. https://doi.org/10.1128/spectrum.02732-21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amalraj, A., Pius, A., Gopi, S., &amp; Gopi, S. (2016). Biological activities of curcuminoids, other biomolecules from turmeric and their derivatives-A review. Journal of Traditional and Complementary Medicine, 7(2), 205-233. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtcme.2016.05.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaral-Machado, L., Oliveira, W. N., Moreira-Oliveira, S. S., Pereira, D. T., Alencar, &#xc9;. N., Tsapis, N., &amp; Egito, E. S. T. (2020). Use of natural products in asthma treatment. Evidence-Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine: eCAM, 2020, 1021258. https://doi.org/10.1155/2020/1021258</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amit, K., Anu, R., Sandip, C., Ruchi, T., Latheef, S. K., &amp; Kuldeep, D. (2013). Ocimum sanctum (Tulsi): A miracle herb and boon to medical science-A review. International Journal of Agronomy and Plant Production, 4(7), 1580-1589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amorim, J. L., Simas, D. L. R., Pinheiro, M. M. G., Moreno, D. S. A., Alviano, C. S., da Silva, A. J. R., &amp; Fernandes, P. D. (2016). Anti-inflammatory properties and chemical characterization of the essential oils of four citrus species. PLoS One, 11(4), e0153643. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0153643</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anagha, K., Deshpande, M., Priya, L., &amp; Meera, M. (2014). Scope of Glycyrrhiza glabra (Yashtimadhu) as an antiviral agent: A review. International Journal of Current Microbiology and Applied Sciences, 1(12), 657-665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora, R., Chawla, R., Marwah, R., Arora, P., Sharma, R. K., Kaushik, V., Goel, R., Kaur, A., Silambarasan, M., Tripathi, R. P., &amp; Bhardwaj, J. R. (2011). Potential of complementary and alternative medicine in preventive management of novel H1N1 flu (swine flu) pandemic: Thwarting potential disasters in the bud. Evidence-Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine: eCAM, 2011, 586506. https://doi.org/10.1155/2011/586506</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arun, H. S. K. (2020). Molecular docking of natural compounds from Tulsi (Ocimum sanctum) and neem (Azadirachta indica) against SARS-CoV-2 protein targets. BEMS Reports, 6(1), 11-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashraf, S., Ashraf, S., Ashraf, M., Imran, M. A., Kalsoom, L., Siddiqui, U. N., Farooq, I., Akmal, R., Akram, M. K., Ashraf, S., Ghufran, M., Majeed, N., Habib, Z., Rafique, S., Abdin, Z. U., Arshad, S., Shahab, M. S., Ahmad, S., Zheng, H., &#x2026; DOCTORS LOUNGE Consortium. (2023). Honey and Nigella sativa against COVID-19 in Pakistan (HNS-COVID-PK): A multicenter placebo-controlled randomized clinical trial. Phytotherapy Research, 37(2), 627-644. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.7640</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayurveda, C. C. f. R. I., &amp; Siddha. (1987). Pharmacopoeial Standards for Ayurvedic Formulations. Central Council for Research in Ayurveda and Siddha (India).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayush, T. M. O. (2020). Ayurveda's immunity boosting measures for self care during COVID 19 crisis. Retrieved from http://ayush.gov.in/event/ayurveda-immunity-boosting-measures-self-care-during-covid-19-crisis</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaei, F., Nassiri-Asl, M., &amp; Hosseinzadeh, H. (2020). Curcumin (a constituent of turmeric): New treatment option against COVID-19. Food Science &amp; Nutrition, 8(10), 5215-5227. https://doi.org/10.1002/fsn3.1858</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailly, C., &amp; Vergoten, G. (2020). Glycyrrhizin: An alternative drug for the treatment of COVID-19 infection and the associated respiratory syndrome? Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics, 214, 107618. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pharmthera.2020.107618</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bano, N., Ahmed, A., Tanveer, M., Khan, G., &amp; Ansari, M. (2017). Pharmacological evaluation of Ocimum sanctum. Journal of Bioequivalence &amp; Bioavailability, 9(3), 387-392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartholomew, M. (2002). James Lind's treatise of the scurvy (1753). Postgraduate Medical Journal, 78(925), 695-696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhapkar, V., Sawant, T., &amp; Bhalerao, S. (2022). A critical analysis of CTRI registered AYUSH studies for COVID-19. Journal of Integrative and Complementary Medicine, 13(1), 100370. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaim.2020.10.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, Z., Zhang, G., Tang, B., Liu, Y., Fu, X., &amp; Zhang, X. (2015). Promising anti-influenza properties of active constituent of Withania somnifera Ayurvedic herb in targeting neuraminidase of H1N1 influenza: Computational study. Cell Biochemistry and Biophysics, 72(3), 727-739. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12013-015-0524-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caraka (1890). Charaka-samhita: Translated into English (pp. 1890-1914). Avinash Chandra Kaviratna.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caristi, C., Bellocco, E., Gargiulli, C., Toscano, G., &amp; Leuzzi, U. (2006). Flavone-di-C-glycosides in citrus juices from southern Italy. Food Chemistry, 95(3), 431-437. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodchem.2005.01.031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaieb, K., Hajlaoui, H., Zmantar, T., Kahla-Nakbi, A. B., Rouabhia, M., Mahdouani, K., &amp; Bakhrouf, A. (2007). The chemical composition and biological activity of clove essential oil, Eugenia caryophyllata (Syzigium aromaticum L. Myrtaceae): A short review. Phytotherapy Research, 21(6), 501-506. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.2124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, J. S., Wang, K. C., Yeh, C. F., Shieh, D. E., &amp; Chiang, L. C. (2013). Fresh ginger (Zingiber officinale) has anti-viral activity against human respiratory syncytial virus in human respiratory tract cell lines. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 145(1), 146-151. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jep.2012.10.043</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, N., Zhou, M., Dong, X., Qu, J., Gong, F., Han, Y., Qiu, Y., Wang, J., Liu, Y., Wei, Y., Xia, J., Yu, T., Zhang, X., &amp; Zhang, L. (2020). Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of 99 cases of 2019 novel coronavirus pneumonia in Wuhan, China: A descriptive study. The Lancet, 395(10223), 507-513. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(20)30211-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Childs, C. E., Calder, P. C., &amp; Miles, E. A. (2019). Diet and immune function. Nutrients, 11(8), 1933. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu11081933</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinatl, J., Morgenstern, B., Bauer, G., Chandra, P., Rabenau, H., &amp; Doerr, H. W. (2003). Glycyrrhizin, an active component of liquorice roots, and replication of SARS-associated coronavirus. The Lancet, 361(9374), 2045-2046. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(03)13615-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coppock, D., Violet, P. C., Vasquez, G., Belden, K., Foster, M., Mullin, B., Magee, D., Mikell, I., Shah, L., Powers, V., Curcio, B., Daskalakis, C., Monti, D., &amp; Levine, M. (2022). Pharmacologic ascorbic acid as early therapy for hospitalized patients with COVID-19: A randomized clinical trial. Life (Basel), 12(3), 453. https://doi.org/10.3390/life12030453</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes-Rojas, D. F., de Souza, C. R., &amp; Oliveira, W. P. (2014). Clove (Syzygium aromaticum): A precious spice. Asian Pacific Journal of Tropical Biomedicine, 4(2), 90-96. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2221-1691(14)60215-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, J., Gu, L., Su, Y., Wang, Q., Zhao, Y., Chen, X., Deng, H., Li, W., Wang, G., &amp; Li, K. (2018). Inhibition of curcumin on influenza a virus infection and influenzal pneumonia via oxidative stress, TLR2/4, p38/JNK MAPK and NF-&#x3ba;B pathways. International Immunopharmacology, 54, 177-187. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intimp.2017.11.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daneshi-Maskooni, M., Keshavarz, S. A., Mansouri, S., Qorbani, M., Alavian, S. M., Badri-Fariman, M., Jazayeri-Tehrani, S. A., &amp; Sotoudeh, G. (2017). The effects of green cardamom on blood glucose indices, lipids, inflammatory factors, paraxonase-1, sirtuin-1, and irisin in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease and obesity: Study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials, 18(1), 260. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13063-017-1979-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darshan, S., &amp; Doreswamy, R. (2004). Patented antiinflammatory plant drug development from traditional medicine. Phytotherapy Research: PTR, 18(5), 343-357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, L., &amp; Kuttan, G. (1998). Suppressive effect of cyclophosphamide-induced toxicity by Withania somnifera extract in mice. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 62(3), 209-214. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0378-8741(98)00039-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai, V. R., Ramkrishnan, R., Chintalwar, G. J., &amp; Sainis, K. B. (2007). G1-4A, an immunomodulatory polysaccharide from Tinospora cordifolia, modulates macrophage responses and protects mice against lipopolysaccharide induced endotoxic shock. International Immunopharmacology, 7(10), 1375-1386. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intimp.2007.06.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devpura, G., Tomar, B. S., Nathiya, D., Sharma, A., Bhandari, D., Haldar, S., Balkrishna, A., &amp; Varshney, A. (2021). Randomized placebo-controlled pilot clinical trial on the efficacy of ayurvedic treatment regime on COVID-19 positive patients. Phytomedicine, 84, 153494. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.phymed.2021.153494</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duke, J. A. (1992). Handbook of phytochemical constituents of GRAS herbs and other economical. CRC Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsayed, Y., &amp; Khan, N. A. (2020). Immunity-boosting spices and the novel coronavirus. ACS Chemical Neuroscience, 11(12), 1696-1698. https://doi.org/10.1021/acschemneuro.0c00239</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estari, M., Venkanna, L., &amp; Reddy, A. S. (2012). In vitro anti-HIV activity of crude extracts from Tinospora cordifolia. BMC Infectious Diseases, 12(1), P10. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2334-12-S1-P10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambhir, L., Checker, R., Sharma, D., Thoh, M., Patil, A., Degani, M., Gota, V., &amp; Sandur, S. K. (2015). Thiol dependent NF-&#x3ba;B suppression and inhibition of T-cell mediated adaptive immune responses by a naturally occurring steroidal lactone Withaferin a. Toxicology and Applied Pharmacology, 289(2), 297-312. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.taap.2015.09.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganguly, B., Umapathi, V., &amp; Rastogi, S. K. (2018). Nitric oxide induced by Indian ginseng root extract inhibits infectious bursal disease virus in chicken embryo fibroblasts in vitro. Journal of Animal Science and Technology, 60, 2. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40781-017-0156-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, Y., Lv, X., Yang, H., Peng, L., &amp; Ci, X. (2020). Isoliquiritigenin exerts antioxidative and anti-inflammatory effects via activating the KEAP-1/Nrf2 pathway and inhibiting the NF-kappaB and NLRP3 pathways in carrageenan-induced pleurisy. Food &amp; Function, 11(3), 2522-2534. https://doi.org/10.1039/c9fo01984g</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghazi Zahedi, S., Koohdani, F., Qorbani, M., Siassi, F., Keshavarz, A., Nasli-Esfahani, E., Aghasi, M., Khoshamal, H., &amp; Sotoudeh, G. (2020). The effects of green cardamom supplementation on blood pressure and endothelium function in type 2 diabetic patients: A study protocol for a randomized controlled clinical trial. Medicine, 99(18), e11005. https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000011005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghoke, S. S., Sood, R., Kumar, N., Pateriya, A. K., Bhatia, S., Mishra, A., Dixit, R., Singh, V. K., Desai, D. N., Kulkarni, D. D., Dimri, U., &amp; Singh, V. P. (2018). Evaluation of antiviral activity of Ocimum sanctum and Acacia arabica leaves extracts against H9N2 virus using embryonated chicken egg model. BMC Complementary and Alternative Medicine, 18(1), 174. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12906-018-2238-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorgani, L., Mohammadi, M., Najafpour, G. D., &amp; Nikzad, M. (2017). Piperine-The bioactive compound of black pepper: From isolation to medicinal formulations. Comprehensive Reviews in Food Science and Food Safety, 16(1), 124-140. https://doi.org/10.1111/1541-4337.12246</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh, T., Jimenez, J. L., Prather, K. A., Tufekci, Z., Fisman, D., &amp; Schooley, R. (2021). Ten scientific reasons in support of airborne transmission of SARS-CoV-2. The Lancet, 397(10285), 1603-1605. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00869-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;ez, C. M., Souza, R. O. D., Fischer, P., Le&#xe3;o, M. F. d. M., Duarte, J. A., Boligon, A. A., Athayde, M. L., Zuravski, L., de Oliveira, L. F. S., &amp; Machado, M. M. (2017). Evaluation of basil extract (Ocimum basilicum L.) on oxidative, anti-genotoxic and anti-inflammatory effects in human leukocytes cell cultures exposed to challenging agents. Brazilian Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences, 53(1), e15098. https://doi.org/10.1590/s2175-97902017000115098</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guldiken, B., Ozkan, G., Catalkaya, G., Ceylan, F. D., Ekin Yalcinkaya, I., &amp; Capanoglu, E. (2018). Phytochemicals of herbs and spices: Health versus toxicological effects. Food and Chemical Toxicology, 119, 37-49. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fct.2018.05.050</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, A., &amp; Singh, S. (2014). Evaluation of anti-inflammatory effect of Withania somnifera root on collagen-induced arthritis in rats. Pharmaceutical Biology, 52(3), 308-320. https://doi.org/10.3109/13880209.2013.835325</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, P. K., Sonewane, K., Rajan, M., Patil, N. J., Agrawal, T., Banerjee, E. R., Chauhan, N. S., &amp; Kumar, A. (2021). Scientific rationale of Indian AYUSH ministry advisory for COVID-19 prevention, prophylaxis, and immunomodulation. Advances in Traditional Medicine, 23, 321-345. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13596-021-00574-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haridas, M., Sasidhar, V., Nath, P., Abhithaj, J., Sabu, A., &amp; Rammanohar, P. (2021). Compounds of Citrus medica and Zingiber officinale for COVID-19 inhibition: in silico evidence for cues from Ayurveda. Future Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences, 7(1), 13. https://doi.org/10.1186/s43094-020-00171-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison, A. G., Lin, T., &amp; Wang, P. (2020). Mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2 transmission and pathogenesis. Trends in Immunology, 41(12), 1100-1115. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.it.2020.10.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horv&#xe1;th, G., &amp; &#xc1;cs, K. (2015). Essential oils in the treatment of respiratory tract diseases highlighting their role in bacterial infections and their anti-inflammatory action: A review. Flavour and Fragrance Journal, 30(5), 331-341. https://doi.org/10.1002/ffj.3252</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsiang, C. Y., Lo, H. Y., Huang, H. C., Li, C. C., Wu, S. L., &amp; Ho, T. Y. (2013). Ginger extract and zingerone ameliorated trinitrobenzene sulphonic acid-induced colitis in mice via modulation of nuclear factor-&#x3ba;B activity and interleukin-1&#x3b2; signalling pathway. Food Chemistry, 136(1), 170-177. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodchem.2012.07.124 https://www.worldometers.info/coronavirus accessed on 24 May 2023. https://iiim.res.in/cured/ayush.php as accessed on 03 March 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C., Wang, Y., Li, X., Ren, L., Zhao, J., Hu, Y., Zhang, L., Fan, G., Xu, J., Gu, X., Cheng, Z., Yu, T., Xia, J., Wei, Y., Wu, W., Xie, X., Yin, W., Li, H., Liu, M., &#x2026; Cao, B. (2020). Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. The Lancet, 395(10223), 497-506. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>India. Department of Ayurveda, Y., Naturopathy, U., Siddha, &amp; Homoeopathy. (2007). The ayurvedic pharmacopoeia of India: Formulations. Part 2. Government of India, Ministry of Health and Family Welfare, Department of Ayurveda, Yoga &amp; Naturopathy, Unani, Siddha, and Homoeopathy.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamshidi, N., &amp; Cohen, M. M. (2017). The clinical efficacy and safety of Tulsi in humans: A systematic review of the literature. Evidence-Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine: eCAM, 2017, 9217567. https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/9217567</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi, V. K., Joshi, A., &amp; Dhiman, K. S. (2017). The Ayurvedic pharmacopoeia of India, development and perspectives. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 197, 32-38. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jep.2016.07.030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapewangolo, P., Omolo, J. J., Bruwer, R., Fonteh, P., &amp; Meyer, D. (2015). Antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activity of Ocimum labiatum extract and isolated labdane diterpenoid. Journal of Inflammation, 12(1), 4. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12950-015-0049-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashyap, V. K., Dhasmana, A., Yallapu, M. M., Chauhan, S. C., &amp; Jaggi, M. (2020). Withania somnifera as a potential future drug molecule for COVID-19. Future Drug Discovery, 2(4), FDD50. https://doi.org/10.4155/fdd-2020-0024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kataria, S., Sharma, P., Ram, J. P., Deswal, V., Singh, M., Rana, R., Singhal, R., Tripathi, A., Kumar, K., &amp; Trehan, N. (2021). A pilot clinical study of an add on Ayurvedic formulation containing Guduchi and Pippali in mild to moderate Covid-19. Journal of Ayurveda and Integrative Medicine, 13, 100454. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaim.2021.05.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaushik, S., Jangra, G., Kundu, V., Yadav, J. P., &amp; Kaushik, S. (2020). Anti-viral activity of Zingiber officinale (Ginger) ingredients against the Chikungunya virus. Virus, 31(3), 1-7. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13337-020-00584-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedl, R. M. (2021). Down but far from out: The durability of SARS-CoV-2 immunity after asymptomatic infection. The Journal of Experimental Medicine, 218(5). https://doi.org/10.1084/jem.20210359</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khattry, N., Gawande, J., Patil, P., Bagal, B., Kannan, S., Chiplunkar, S., &amp; Gota, V. (2012). Curcumin decreases cytokine levels involved in mucositis in autologous transplant setting: A pharmacokinetic-pharmacodynamic study. Blood, 120, 3039. https://doi.org/10.1182/blood.V120.21.3039.3039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, D., Liao, J., Scales, N. B., Martini, C., Luan, X., Abu-Arish, A., Robert, R., Luo, Y., McKay, G. A., Nguyen, D., Tewfik, M. A., Poirier, C. D., Matouk, E., Ianowski, J. P., Frenkiel, S., &amp; Hanrahan, J. W. (2021). Large pH oscillations promote host defense against human airways infection. The Journal of Experimental Medicine, 218(4). https://doi.org/10.1084/jem.20201831</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H. M., Lee, E. H., Hong, S. H., Song, H. J., Shin, M. K., Kim, S. H., &amp; Shin, T. Y. (1998). Effect of Syzygium aromaticum extract on immediate hypersensitivity in rats. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 60(2), 125-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S. H., Hong, J. H., Yang, W. K., Geum, J. H., Kim, H. R., Choi, S. Y., Kang, Y. M., An, H. J., &amp; Lee, Y. C. (2020). Herbal combinational medication of Glycyrrhiza glabra, Agastache rugosa containing Glycyrrhizic acid, Tilianin inhibits neutrophilic lung inflammation by affecting CXCL2, interleukin-17/STAT3 signal pathways in a murine model of COPD. Nutrients, 12(4), 926. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu12040926</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S. H., Pei, Q. M., Jiang, P., Yang, M., Qian, X. J., &amp; Liu, J. B. (2017). Role of licochalcone a in VEGF-induced proliferation of human airway smooth muscle cells: Implications for asthma. Growth Factors, 35(1), 39-47. https://doi.org/10.1080/08977194.2017.1338694</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, T.-H., Jeon, S.-R., Kang, J. W., &amp; Kwon, S. (2022). Complementary and alternative medicine for Long COVID: Scoping review and bibliometric analysis. Evidence-Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine, 2022, 7303393. https://doi.org/10.1155/2022/7303393</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirthana, V., Venkataiah, B., &amp; Murthy, M. (2020). COVID 19 in ayurvedic perspective. International Journal of Health &amp; Allied Sciences, 9(5), 91-96. https://doi.org/10.4103/ijhas.IJHAS_110_20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koehler, M., Ray, A., Moreira, R. A., Juniku, B., Poma, A. B., &amp; Alsteens, D. (2021). Molecular insights into receptor binding energetics and neutralization of SARS-CoV-2 variants. Nature Communications, 12(1), 6977. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-27325-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, V., Dhanjal, J. K., Bhargava, P., Kaul, A., Wang, J., Zhang, H., Kaul, S. C., Wadhwa, R., &amp; Sundar, D. (2020). Withanone and Withaferin-a are predicted to interact with transmembrane protease serine 2 (TMPRSS2) and block entry of SARS-CoV-2 into cells. Journal of Biomolecular Structure &amp; Dynamics, 1-13, 1-13. https://doi.org/10.1080/07391102.2020.1775704</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunnumakkara, A. B., Rana, V., Parama, D., Banik, K., Girisa, S., Henamayee, S., Thakur, K. K., Dutta, U., Garodia, P., Gupta, S. C., &amp; Aggarwal, B. B. (2021). COVID-19, cytokines, inflammation, and spices: How are they related? Life Sciences, 284, 119201. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lfs.2021.119201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunnumakkara, A. B., Sailo, B. L., Banik, K., Harsha, C., Prasad, S., Gupta, S. C., Bharti, A. C., &amp; Aggarwal, B. B. (2018). Chronic diseases, inflammation, and spices: How are they linked? Journal of Translational Medicine, 16(1), 14. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967-018-1381-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurokawa, M., Hozumi, T., Basnet, P., Nakano, M., Kadota, S., Namba, T., Kawana, T., &amp; Shiraki, K. (1998). Purification and characterization of eugeniin as an anti-herpesvirus compound from Geum japonicum and Syzygium aromaticum. The Journal of Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics, 284(2), 728-735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazzaro, B. P., &amp; Schneider, D. S. (2014). The genetics of immunity. Genetics, 197(2), 467-470. https://doi.org/10.1534/genetics.114.165449</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Bert, N., Clapham, H. E., Tan, A. T., Chia, W. N., Tham, C. Y. L., Lim, J. M., Kunasegaran, K., Tan, L. W. L., Dutertre, C. A., Shankar, N., Lim, J. M. E., Sun, L. J., Zahari, M., Tun, Z. M., Kumar, V., Lim, B. L., Lim, S. H., Chia, A., Tan, Y. J., &#x2026; Tam, C. C. (2021). Highly functional virus-specific cellular immune response in asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection. The Journal of Experimental Medicine, 218(5), e20202617. https://doi.org/10.1084/jem.20202617</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., Geng, M., Peng, Y., Meng, L., &amp; Lu, S. (2020). Molecular immune pathogenesis and diagnosis of COVID-19. Journal of Pharmaceutical Analysis, 10(2), 102-108. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpha.2020.03.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z., Zhong, J. Y., Gao, E. N., &amp; Yang, H. (2014). Effects of glycyrrhizin acid and licorice flavonoids on LPS-induced cytokines expression in macrophage. Zhongguo Zhong Yao Za Zhi, 39(19), 3841-3845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv, Y., An, Z., Chen, H., Wang, Z., &amp; Liu, L. (2014). Mechanism of curcumin resistance to human cytomegalovirus in HELF cells. BMC Complementary and Alternative Medicine, 14, 284. https://doi.org/10.1186/1472-6882-14-284</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddi, R., Kandula, V. L., Vallepu, B., Navuluri, H., Kolluri, H., &amp; Vunnam, D. T. (2018). Preliminary phytochemical analysis and Invitro anti-viral activity of Ethanolic extract of whole plant of Tinospora cordifolia (Thunb.) Miers against hepatitis-A virus. International Journal of Scientific Research in Biological Sciences, 5, 3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majdalawieh, A. F., &amp; Carr, R. I. (2010). In vitro investigation of the potential immunomodulatory and anti-cancer activities of black pepper (Piper nigrum) and cardamom (Elettaria cardamomum). Journal of Medicinal Food, 13(2), 371-381. https://doi.org/10.1089/jmf.2009.1131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurya, D. K. (2021). Evaluation of Yashtimadhu (Glycyrrhiza glabra) active phytochemicals against novel coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2). Austin Journal of Pharmacology and Therapeutics, 9(6). https://doi.org/10.26420/austinjpharmacolther.2021.1153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurya, D. K., &amp; Sharma, D. (2020). Evaluation of traditional ayurvedic Kadha for prevention and management of the novel coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) using in silico approach. Journal of Biomolecular Structure &amp; Dynamics, 1-16, 3949-3964. https://doi.org/10.1080/07391102.2020.1852119</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta, M., Gohil, D., Khattry, N., Kumar, R., Sandur, S., Sharma, D., Checker, R., Agarwal, B., Jha, D., Majumdar, A., &amp; Gota, V. (2020). Prevention of acute graft-versus-host-disease by Withaferin a via suppression of AKT/mTOR pathway. International Immunopharmacology, 84, 106575. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intimp.2020.106575</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merad, M., &amp; Martin, J. C. (2020). Pathological inflammation in patients with COVID-19: A key role for monocytes and macrophages. Nature Reviews Immunology, 20(6), 355-362. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41577-020-0331-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milani, G. P., Macchi, M., &amp; Guz-Mark, A. (2021). Vitamin C in the treatment of COVID-19. Nutrients, 13(4), 1172. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu13041172</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miryan, M., Bagherniya, M., Sahebkar, A., Soleimani, D., Rouhani, M. H., Iraj, B., &amp; Askari, G. (2020). Effects of curcumin-piperine co-supplementation on clinical signs, duration, severity, and inflammatory factors in patients with COVID-19: A structured summary of a study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials, 21(1), 1027. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13063-020-04924-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra, A., Bentur, S. A., Thakral, S., Garg, R., &amp; Duggal, B. (2021). The use of integrative therapy based on yoga and ayurveda in the treatment of a high-risk case of COVID-19/SARS-CoV-2 with multiple comorbidities: A case report. Journal of Medical Case Reports, 15(1), 95. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13256-020-02624-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mondal, S., Varma, S., Bamola, V. D., Naik, S. N., Mirdha, B. R., Padhi, M. M., Mehta, N., &amp; Mahapatra, S. C. (2011). Double-blinded randomized controlled trial for immunomodulatory effects of Tulsi (Ocimum sanctum Linn.) leaf extract on healthy volunteers. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 136(3), 452-456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morvaridzadeh, M., Fazelian, S., Agah, S., Khazdouz, M., Rahimlou, M., Agh, F., Potter, E., Heshmati, S., &amp; Heshmati, J. (2020). Effect of ginger (Zingiber officinale) on inflammatory markers: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Cytokine, 135, 155224. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cyto.2020.155224</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mounce, B. C., Cesaro, T., Carrau, L., Vallet, T., &amp; Vignuzzi, M. (2017). Curcumin inhibits Zika and chikungunya virus infection by inhibiting cell binding. Antiviral Research, 142, 148-157. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.antiviral.2017.03.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nag, A., &amp; Chowdhury, R. R. (2020). Piperine, an alkaloid of black pepper seeds can effectively inhibit the antiviral enzymes of dengue and Ebola viruses, an in silico molecular docking study. Virus, 31(3), 308-315. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13337-020-00619-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunwande, I. A., Olawore, N. O., Ekundayo, O., Walker, T. M., Schmidt, J. M., &amp; Setzer, W. N. (2005). Studies on the essential oils composition, antibacterial and cytotoxicity of Eugenia uniflora L. International Journal of Aromatherapy, 15(3), 147-152. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijat.2005.07.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey, V. K., Amin, P. J., &amp; Shankar, B. S. (2014). G1-4A, a polysaccharide from Tinospora cordifolia induces peroxynitrite dependent killer dendritic cell (KDC) activity against tumor cells. International Immunopharmacology, 23(2), 480-488. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intimp.2014.09.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey, V. K., Shankar, B. S., &amp; Sainis, K. B. (2012). G1-4 A, an arabinogalactan polysaccharide from Tinospora cordifolia increases dendritic cell immunogenicity in a murine lymphoma model. International Immunopharmacology, 14(4), 641-649. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intimp.2012.09.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panossian, A., &amp; Brendler, T. (2020). The role of Adaptogens in prophylaxis and treatment of viral respiratory infections. Pharmaceuticals, 13(9), 236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panossian, A., &amp; Wikman, G. (2009). Evidence-based efficacy of adaptogens in fatigue, and molecular mechanisms related to their stress-protective activity. Current Clinical Pharmacology, 4(3), 198-219. https://doi.org/10.2174/157488409789375311</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pastorino, G., Cornara, L., Soares, S., Rodrigues, F., &amp; Oliveira, M. (2018). Liquorice (Glycyrrhiza glabra): A phytochemical and pharmacological review. Phytotherapy Research: PTR, 32(12), 2323-2339. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.6178</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil, D., Gautam, M., Mishra, S., Karupothula, S., Gairola, S., Jadhav, S., Pawar, S., &amp; Patwardhan, B. (2013). Determination of withaferin A and withanolide A in mice plasma using high-performance liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry: Application to pharmacokinetics after oral administration of Withania somnifera aqueous extract. Journal of Pharmaceutical and Biomedical Analysis, 80, 203-212. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpba.2013.03.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patwardhan, B., &amp; Sarwal, R. (2021). Significance of AYUSH: India's first line of defence against COVID-19. Journal of Ayurveda and Integrative Medicine, 12(2), 227-228. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaim.2021.05.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paules, C. I., &amp; Fauci, A. S. (2021). COVID-19: The therapeutic landscape. Medicine, 2(5), 493-497. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.medj.2021.04.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paules, C. I., Marston, H. D., &amp; Fauci, A. S. (2020). Coronavirus infections-more than just the common cold. Journal of the American Medical Association, 323, 707-708. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.0757</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pebam, M., Sushma, M. V., Sankaranarayanan, S. A., Thanekar, A. M., Koyande, N., &amp; Rengan, A. K. (2022). Antiviral perspectives of economically important Indian medicinal plants and spices. Proceedings of the Indian National Science Academy, 88(3), 392-416. https://doi.org/10.1007/s43538-022-00099-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson, C. T., Denniston, K., &amp; Chopra, D. (2017). Therapeutic uses of Triphala in Ayurvedic medicine. Journal of Alternative and Complementary Medicine, 23(8), 607-614. https://doi.org/10.1089/acm.2017.0083</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ping, Y. H., Yeh, H., Chu, L. W., Lin, Z. H., Hsu, Y. C., Lin, L. C., Hsu, C. H., Fu, S. L., &amp; Lin, T. Y. (2022). The traditional Chinese medicine formula Jing guan fang for preventing SARS-CoV-2 infection: From clinical observation to basic research. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 13, 744439. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2022.744439</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pires, N., Gota, V., Gulia, A., Hingorani, L., Agarwal, M., &amp; Puri, A. (2020). Safety and pharmacokinetics of Withaferin-A in advanced stage high grade osteosarcoma: A phase I trial. Journal of Ayurveda and Integrative Medicine, 11(1), 68-72. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaim.2018.12.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabu, P. C., Panchapakesan, S., &amp; Raj, C. D. (2013). Acute and sub-acute oral toxicity assessment of the hydroalcoholic extract of Withania somnifera roots in Wistar rats. Phytotherapy Research: PTR, 27(8), 1169-1178. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.4854</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prajapati, S. K., Malaiya, A., Mishra, G., Jain, D., Kesharwani, P., Mody, N., Ahmadi, A., Paliwal, R., &amp; Jain, A. (2022). An exhaustive comprehension of the role of herbal medicines in pre- and post-COVID manifestations. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 296, 115420. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jep.2022.115420</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad, S., &amp; Tyagi, A. K. (2015). Ginger and its constituents: Role in prevention and treatment of gastrointestinal cancer. Gastroenterology Research and Practice, 2015, 142979. https://doi.org/10.1155/2015/142979</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghu, R., Sharma, D., Ramakrishnan, R., Khanam, S., Chintalwar, G. J., &amp; Sainis, K. B. (2009). Molecular events in the activation of B cells and macrophages by a non-microbial TLR4 agonist, G1-4A from Tinospora cordifolia. Immunology Letters, 123(1), 60-71. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.imlet.2009.02.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmani, A. H., Alsahli, M. A., Aly, S. M., Khan, M. A., &amp; Aldebasi, Y. H. (2018). Role of curcumin in disease prevention and treatment. Advanced Biomedical Research, 7, 38. https://doi.org/10.4103/abr.abr_147_16</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopal, K., Byran, G., Jupudi, S., &amp; Vadivelan, R. (2020). Activity of phytochemical constituents of black pepper, ginger, and garlic against coronavirus (COVID-19): An in silico approach. International Journal of Health &amp; Allied Sciences, 9(5), 43-50. https://doi.org/10.4103/ijhas.IJHAS_55_20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopal, K., Varakumar, P., Baliwada, A., &amp; Byran, G. (2020). Activity of phytochemical constituents of Curcuma longa (turmeric) and Andrographis paniculata against coronavirus (COVID-19): An in silico approach. Future Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences, 6(1), 104. https://doi.org/10.1186/s43094-020-00126-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasool, M., &amp; Varalakshmi, P. (2006). Immunomodulatory role of Withania somnifera root powder on experimental induced inflammation: An in vivo and in vitro study. Vascular Pharmacology, 44(6), 406-410. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vph.2006.01.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts, N., Brown, R. E., Buja, L. M., &amp; Weerasinghe, P. (2020). Molecular mechanisms of curcumin in COVID-19 treatment and prevention: A Global Health perspective. Medical Research Archives, 8(10). https://doi.org/10.18103/mra.v8i10.2248</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Runfeng, L., Yunlong, H., Jicheng, H., Weiqi, P., Qinhai, M., Yongxia, S., Chufang, L., Jin, Z., Zhenhua, J., Haiming, J., Kui, Z., Shuxiang, H., Jun, D., Xiaobo, L., Xiaotao, H., Lin, W., Nanshan, Z., &amp; Zifeng, Y. (2020). Lianhuaqingwen exerts anti-viral and anti-inflammatory activity against novel coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2). Pharmacological Research, 156, 104761. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.phrs.2020.104761</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saber-Moghaddam, N., Salari, S., Hejazi, S., Amini, M., Taherzadeh, Z., Eslami, S., Rezayat, S. M., Jaafari, M. R., &amp; Elyasi, S. (2021). Oral nano-curcumin formulation efficacy in management of mild to moderate hospitalized coronavirus disease-19 patients: An open label nonrandomized clinical trial. Phytotherapy Research: PTR, 35, 2616-2623. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.7004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safa, O., Hassani-Azad, M., Farashahinejad, M., Davoodian, P., Dadvand, H., Hassanipour, S., &amp; Fathalipour, M. (2020). Effects of licorice on clinical symptoms and laboratory signs in moderately ill patients with pneumonia from COVID-19: A structured summary of a study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials, 21(1), 790. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13063-020-04706-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saggam, A., Limgaokar, K., Borse, S., Chavan-Gautam, P., Dixit, S., Tillu, G., &amp; Patwardhan, B. (2021). Withania somnifera (L.) Dunal: Opportunity for clinical repurposing in COVID-19 management. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 12, 623795. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2021.623795</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saini, A., Sharma, S., &amp; Chhibber, S. (2009). Induction of resistance to respiratory tract infection with Klebsiella pneumoniae in mice fed on a diet supplemented with tulsi (Ocimum sanctum) and clove (Syzgium aromaticum) oils. Journal of Microbiology, Immunology, and Infection, 42(2), 107-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah, M. R., Fatima, S., Khan, S. N., Ullah, S., Himani, G., Wan, K., Lin, T., Lau, J. Y. N., Liu, Q., &amp; Lam, D. S. C. (2022). Jinhua Qinggan granules for non-hospitalized COVID-19 patients: A double-blind, placebo-controlled, and randomized controlled trial. Frontiers in Medicine (Lausanne), 9, 928468. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2022.928468</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahidi, F., &amp; Ambigaipalan, P. (2015). Phenolics and polyphenolics in foods, beverages and spices: Antioxidant activity and health effects-A review. Journal of Functional Foods, 18, 820-897. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jff.2015.06.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, K. K., Partap, U., Mistry, N., Marathe, Y., Wang, M., Shaikh, S., D'Costa, P., Gupta, G., Bromage, S., Hemler, E. C., Kain, K. C., Dholakia, Y., &amp; Fawzi, W. W. (2022). Randomised trial to determine the effect of vitamin D and zinc supplementation for improving treatment outcomes among patients with COVID-19 in India: Trial protocol. BMJ Open, 12(8), e061301. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2022-061301</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, T., Wilhelm, E., Bell, B., &amp; Dumais, N. (2017). NF-&#x3ba;B-dependent inhibition of HIV-1 transcription by Withaferin A. HIV Current Research, 2(1), 119. https://doi.org/10.4172/2572-0805.1000119</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shree, P., Mishra, P., Selvaraj, C., Singh, S. K., Chaube, R., Garg, N., &amp; Tripathi, Y. B. (2020). Targeting COVID-19 (SARS-CoV-2) main protease through active phytochemicals of ayurvedic medicinal plants-Withania somnifera (Ashwagandha), Tinospora cordifolia (Giloy) and Ocimum sanctum (Tulsi)-A molecular docking study. Journal of Biomolecular Structure and Dynamics, 1-14, 190-203. https://doi.org/10.1080/07391102.2020.1810778</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, M., Jayant, K., Singh, D., Bhutani, S., Poddar, N. K., Chaudhary, A. A., Khan, S. U., Adnan, M., Siddiqui, A. J., Hassan, M. I., Khan, F. I., Lai, D., &amp; Khan, S. (2022). Withania somnifera (L.) Dunal (Ashwagandha) for the possible therapeutics and clinical management of SARS-CoV-2 infection: Plant-based drug discovery and targeted therapy. Frontiers in Cellular and Infection Microbiology, 12, 933824. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcimb.2022.933824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, R., Goel, S., Bourgeade, P., Aleya, L., &amp; Tewari, D. (2021). Ayurveda Rasayana as antivirals and immunomodulators: Potential applications in COVID-19. Environmental Science and Pollution Research International, 28(40), 55925-55951. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-021-16280-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, R. S., Singh, A., Kaur, H., Batra, G., Sarma, P., Kaur, H., Bhattacharyya, A., Sharma, A. R., Kumar, S., Upadhyay, S., Tiwari, V., Avti, P., Prakash, A., &amp; Medhi, B. (2021). Promising traditional Indian medicinal plants for the management of novel coronavirus disease: A systematic review. Phytotherapy Research: PTR, 35(8), 4456-4484. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.7150</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soni, M. K., &amp; Sharma, O. (2018). Importance of rasayan in immunity (vyadhikshamatva). World Journal of Pharmaceutical and Medical Research, 4(3), 196-198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivas, N., Sali, K., &amp; Bajoria, A. (2016). Therapeutic aspects of Tulsi unraveled: A review. Journal of Indian Academy of Oral Medicine and Radiology, 28(1), 17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stojanovi&#x107;-Radi&#x107;, Z., Pej&#x10d;i&#x107;, M., Dimitrijevi&#x107;, M., Aleksi&#x107;, A., Anil Kumar, V. N., Salehi, B., Cho, W. C., &amp; Sharifi-Rad, J. (2019). Piperine-A major principle of black pepper: A review of its bioactivity and studies. Applied Sciences, 9(20), 4270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakar, A., Panara, K., Goyal, M., Kumari, R., &amp; Sungchol, K. (2022). AYUSH (Indian system of medicines) therapeutics for COVID-19: A living systematic review and meta-analysis (first update). Journal of Integrative and Complementary Medicine, 29, 139-155. https://doi.org/10.1089/jicm.2022.0559</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakar, A., Panara, K., Shah, H., Kalsariya, B., Ruparel, S., Jain, N., Bhatt, P., Jani, D., Dodia, R., Patel, F., Salve, R., Chaudhari, S., Raghavani, H., Vyas, J., Goyal, M., &amp; Bhinde, S. (2022). Guduchi Ghanavati (Ayurveda medication) improves the perceived immunity in individuals at risk of SARS-CoV-2: A multicentred, controlled, before-and-after study. European Journal of Integrative Medicine, 53, 102131. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eujim.2022.102131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tragoolpua, Y., &amp; Jatisatienr, A. (2007). Anti-herpes simplex virus activities of Eugenia caryophyllus (Spreng.) Bullock &amp; S. G. Harrison and essential oil, eugenol. Phytotherapy Research, 21(12), 1153-1158. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.2226</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi, B. (2008). Charaka-Samhita of Agnivesa, Sootra Sthana. Chapter 11, Verse 36 (1st ed.). Chaukhamba Surbharati Prakashan.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhyay, A. K., Kumar, K., Kumar, A., &amp; Mishra, H. S. (2010). Tinospora cordifolia (Willd.) Hook. f. and Thoms. (Guduchi)-Validation of the Ayurvedic pharmacology through experimental and clinical studies. International Journal of Ayurveda Research, 1(2), 112-121. https://doi.org/10.4103/0974-7788.64405</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Sand, L., Bormann, M., Alt, M., Schipper, L., Heilingloh, C. S., Steinmann, E., Todt, D., Dittmer, U., Elsner, C., Witzke, O., &amp; Krawczyk, A. (2021). Glycyrrhizin effectively inhibits SARS-CoV-2 replication by inhibiting the viral Main protease. Viruses, 13(4), 609. https://doi.org/10.3390/v13040609</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Sand, L., Bormann, M., Alt, M., Schipper, L., Heilingloh, C. S., Todt, D., Dittmer, U., Elsner, C., Witzke, O., &amp; Krawczyk, A. (2020). Glycyrrhizin effectively neutralizes SARS-CoV-2 in vitro by inhibiting the viral main protease. bioRxiv, 2020.2012.2018.423104. https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.12.18.423104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, S. K., Jain, V., &amp; Katewa, S. S. (2009). Blood pressure lowering, fibrinolysis enhancing and antioxidant activities of cardamom (Elettaria cardamomum). Indian Journal of Biochemistry &amp; Biophysics, 46(6), 503-506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vicidomini, C., Roviello, V., &amp; Roviello, G. N. (2021). Molecular basis of the therapeutical potential of clove (Syzygium aromaticum L.) and clues to its anti-COVID-19 utility. Molecules, 26(7), 1880. https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules26071880</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang-Sheng, C., Jie, A., Jian-Jun, L., Lan, H., Zeng-Bao, X., &amp; Chang-Qing, L. (2017). Piperine attenuates lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced inflammatory responses in BV2 microglia. International Immunopharmacology, 42, 44-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White, P. T., Subramanian, C., Motiwala, H. F., &amp; Cohen, M. S. (2016). Natural Withanolides in the treatment of chronic diseases. Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology, 928, 329-373. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-41334-1_14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilhelm, C., Surendar, J., &amp; Karagiannis, F. (2021). Enemy or ally? Fasting as an essential regulator of immune responses. Trends in Immunology, 42(5), 389-400. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.it.2021.03.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z., Shi, L., Wang, Y., Zhang, J., Huang, L., Zhang, C., Liu, S., Zhao, P., Liu, H., Zhu, L., Tai, Y., Bai, C., Gao, T., Song, J., Xia, P., Dong, J., Zhao, J., &amp; Wang, F.-S. (2020). Pathological findings of COVID-19 associated with acute respiratory distress syndrome. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine, 8(4), 420-422. https://doi.org/10.1016/s2213-2600(20)30076-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, B., Liu, M., Liu, P., Peng, Y., Huang, J., Li, M., Wang, Y., Xu, L., Sun, S., Qi, X., Ling, Y., Li, J., Zhang, W., Mao, E., &amp; Qu, J. (2021). High dose intravenous vitamin C for preventing the disease aggravation of moderate COVID-19 pneumonia. A retrospective propensity matched before-after study. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 12, 638556. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2021.638556</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziauddin, M., Phansalkar, N., Patki, P., Diwanay, S., &amp; Patwardhan, B. (1996). Studies on the immunomodulatory effects of Ashwagandha. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 50(2), 69-76. https://doi.org/10.1016/0378-8741(95)01318-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo, J., Dowell, A. C., Pearce, H., Verma, K., Long, H. M., Begum, J., Aiano, F., Amin-Chowdhury, Z., Hoschler, K., Brooks, T., Taylor, S., Hewson, J., Hallis, B., Stapley, L., Borrow, R., Linley, E., Ahmad, S., Parker, B., Horsley, A., &#x2026; Moss, P. (2021). Robust SARS-CoV-2-specific T cell immunity is maintained at 6 months following primary infection. Nature Immunology, 22(5), 620-626. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41590-021-00902-8</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>