<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37732339</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2037-7452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of translational myology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Transl Myol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comments on: Effect of physical activity on long COVID fatigue.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11804</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4081/ejtm.2023.11804</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The authors of the Comments on: Effect of physical activity on long COVID fatigue by Daungsupawong F. and Wiwanitkit V. (2023) have highlighted certain aspects of future research that need to be considered before any conclusions can be drawn regarding the effect of previous physical activity and/or fitness on the course of long-COVID. We can only agree with this need, although we hope that the effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection will become less and less burdensome to manage. As we hypothesise in the last part of the article by Coscia et al. (2023), we think it is crucial to identify the molecular mechanism underlying the atrophic effect (if any) of the described disease states, which could originate from a local inflammatory storm induced by Spike binding to the ACE-2 receptor in muscle. When studies on muscle from patients will be available in sufficient numbers, we will be able to try to answer the still open questions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coscia</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine Service of the San Candido-Innichen and Brunico-Bruneck Hospitals, Bolzano-Bozen, San Candido. francesco.coscia1@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Filippo</LastName><ForeName>Ester Sara</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience Imaging and Clinical Sciences, University "G. d'Annunzio" of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti, Italy; IIM-Interuniversity Institute of Myology, University "G. d'Annunzio" of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti. es.difilippo@unich.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gigliotti</LastName><ForeName>Paola Virginia</ForeName><Initials>PV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Sport Physiology San Candido-Innichen, University of Perugia, San Candido. pao.gigliotti@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan&#xf2;-Illic</LastName><ForeName>Giorgio</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IIM-Interuniversity Institute of Myology, University "G. d'Annunzio" of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti, Italy; Campus of Free University of Alcatraz, Free University of Alcatraz, Santa Cristina di Gubbio, Gubbio, Italy; A&amp;C M-C Foundation for Translational Myology, Padova. fanoillic@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Transl Myol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2037-7452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>We confirm that we have read the Journal&#x2019;s position on issues involved in ethical publication and affirm that this report is consistent with those guidelines. <b>T</b>he authors of the Comments on: Effect of physical activity on long COVID fatigue by Daungsupawong F. and Wiwanitkit V. have highlighted certain aspects of future research that need to be considered before any conclusions can be drawn regarding the effect of previous physical activity and/or fitness on the course of long-COVID (comorbidities, vaccinations). We can only agree with this need, although we hope that the effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection will become less and less burdensome to manage in the near future. However, muscle fatigue that is not relieved by rest is a common symptom of many established or questionable viral diseases. The use of the exercise approach to alleviate muscular symptoms has also been attempted under these conditions, but with at least dubious, if not contradictory, results. One only has to read the debate on the subject in the case of ME/CFS patients to understand the difficulty of giving a meaningful answer to the question: does planned physical activity help or harm the duration and intensity of the symptom of chronic fatigue? As we hypothesise in the last part of our article, we think it is crucial to identify the molecular mechanism underlying the atrophic effect (if any) of the described disease states, which could originate from a local (muscular) inflammatory storm induced by Spike binding to the ACE-2 receptor in muscle. When studies on muscle material from patients are available in sufficient numbers, we will be able to try to answer the question posed above.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37732339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10583140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/ejtm.2023.11804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Daungsupawong F, Wiwanitkit V. Comments on: Effect of physical activity on long COVID fatigue Eur J Transl Myol. 2023. Sep 15. doi: 1.4081/ejtm.2023.11722. Online ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10583139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37731386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks DF. Converging Evidence of Similar Symptomatology of ME/CFS and PASC Indicating Multisystemic Dyshomeostasis. Biomedicines. 2023. Jan 11;11(1):180. doi: 10.3390/biomedicines11010180. PMID: 36672687; PMCID: PMC9855891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9855891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36672687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph P, Singh I, Oliveira R, Capone CA, Mullen MP, Cook DB, Stovall MC, Squires J, Madsen K, Waxman AB, Systrom DM. Exercise Pathophysiology in Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome and Postacute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2: More in Common Than Not? Chest. 2023. Sep;164(3):717-726. doi: 10.1016/j.chest.2023.03.049. Epub 2023 Apr 11. PMID: 37054777; PMCID: PMC10088277..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10088277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37054777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coscia F, Di Filippo ES, Gigliotti PV, Fano Illic G. Effect of physical activity on long COVID fatigue: an unsolved enigma. Eur J Transl Myol. 2023. Sep 4. doi: 10.4081/ejtm.2023.11639. Online ahead of print. PMID: 37667865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10583148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37667865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrandi PJ, Alway SE, Mohamed JS. The interaction between SARS-CoV-2 and ACE2 may have consequences for skeletal muscle viral susceptibility and myopathies. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2020. Oct 1;129(4):864-867. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00321.2020. Epub 2020 Jul 16. PMID: 32673162; PMCID: PMC7832004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32673162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>