<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38847905</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1435-1463</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>131</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neural transmission (Vienna, Austria : 1996)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neural Transm (Vienna)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical and diagnostic features of long-COVID patients presenting with neurologic symptoms in Chicago.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>961</StartPage><EndPage>969</EndPage><MedlinePgn>961-969</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00702-024-02789-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long COVID, a condition characterized by persistent symptoms after COVID-19 infection, is increasingly being recognized worldwide. Neurologic symptoms are frequently reported in survivors of COVID-19, making it crucial to better understand this phenomenon both on a societal scale and for the quality of life of these patients. Between January 1, 2020, and July 31, 2022, Illinois&#xa0;(IL) had a standardized cumulative death rate that ranked it 24th out of the 51 states in the United States (US). However, the US had one of the highest per capita COVID-19 death rates among large, high-income countries. [Bollyky T. et al. 2023] As a result of the increased number of COVID-19 infections, there was a rise in the number of patients experiencing Long COVID. At our neuro-infectious disease clinic in Chicago&#xa0;(IL), we observed an increasing number of patients presenting with cognitive and other neurologic symptoms after contracting COVID-19. Initially, we needed to provide these individuals with a better understanding of their condition and expected outcomes. We were thus motivated to further evaluate this group of patients for any patterns in presentation, neurologic findings, and diagnostic testing that would help us better understand this phenomenon. We aim to contribute to the growing body of research on Long COVID, including its presentation, diagnostic testing results, and outcomes to enlighten the long COVID syndrome. We hypothesize that the neurological symptoms resulting from long COVID persist for over 12 months. We conducted a retrospective analysis of clinical data from 44 patients with long-COVID. Cognitive symptoms were the most common presenting concern. Abnormalities in Montreal Cognitive Assessment, electroencephalogram, serum autoantibody testing, and cerebrospinal fluid were found in minority subsets of our cohort. At 12 months, most patients continue to experience neurologic symptoms, though more than half reported moderate or marked improvement compared to initial presentation. Although most of the patients in this study did not show a consistent occurrence of symptoms suggesting a cohesive underlying etiology, our clinical data demonstrated some features of Long COVID patients in Chicago (IL) that could lead to new research avenues, helping us better understand this syndrome that affects patients worldwide.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Austria, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brandes</LastName><ForeName>Lauren E</ForeName><Initials>LE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Rush University Medical Center, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orme</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Rush University Medical Center, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bermeo-Ovalle</LastName><ForeName>Adriana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Rush University Medical Center, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sierra Morales</LastName><ForeName>Fabian</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9673-644X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Rush University Medical Center, Chicago, USA. fabian_sierramorales@rush.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Austria</Country><MedlineTA>J Neural Transm (Vienna)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9702341</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0300-9564</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002641" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Chicago</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009422" MajorTopicYN="N">Nervous System Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychiatric symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-COVID syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38847905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-024-02789-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00702-024-02789-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Akbarialiabad H, Tghrir MH, Abdollahi A, Ghahramani N, Kumar M (2021) Long COVID, a comprehensive systematic scoping review. Infection 1&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1007/s15010-021-01666-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali ST, Kang AK, Patel TR, Clark JR, Perez-Giraldo GS, Orban ZS, Lim PH, Jimenez M, Graham EL, Batra A, Liotta EM, Koralnik IJ (2022) Evolution of neurologic symptoms in non-hospitalized COVID-19 long haulers. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 9(7):950&#x2013;961. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.51570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.51570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35607826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9268866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apple AC, Oddi A, Peluso MJ, Asken BM, Henrich TJ (2022) Risk factors and abnormal cerebrospinal fluid associate with cognitive symptoms after mild COVID-19. Ann Clin Transl Neur 9:221&#x2013;226. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.51498</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.51498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armangue T, Spatola M, Vlagea A, Mattozzi S, C&#xe1;rceles-Cordon M, Martinez-Heras E, Llufriu S, Muchart J, Erro ME, Abraira L, Moris G, Monros-Gim&#xe9;nez L, Corral-Corral &#xcd;, Montejo C, Toledo M, Bataller L, Secondi G, Ari&#xf1;o H, Mart&#xed;nez-Hern&#xe1;ndez E, Juan M, Marcos MA, Alsina L, Saiz A, Rosenfeld MR, Graus F, Dalmau J, Spanish Herpes Simplex Encephalitis Study Group (2018) Frequency, symptoms, risk factors, and outcomes of autoimmune encephalitis after herpes simplex encephalitis: a prospective observational study and retrospective analysis. Lancet Neurol 17(9):760&#x2013;772. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30244-8 Epub 2018 Jul 23. PMID: 30049614; PMCID: PMC6128696</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30244-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30049614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6128696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azor HA, Atchison A, Trender C, Hellyer W, Giunchiglia P, Husain V, Cooke M, Cooper S, Lound E, Chadeau-Hyam ADA, Elliott P (2024) Cognition and Memory after Covid-19 in a large community sample. N Engl J Med 390:806&#x2013;818</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2311330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38416429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7615803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM (2020) Deleterious outcomes in long-hauler COVID-19: the effects of SARS-CoV 2 on the CNS in chronic COVID syndrome. Acs Chem Neurosci 11:4017&#x2013;4020. https://doi.org/10.1021/acschemneuro.0c00725</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acschemneuro.0c00725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33275404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker HA, Safavynia SA, Evered LA (2020) The Third Wave: impending cognitive and functional decline in COVID-19 survivors. Brit J Anaesth 126:44&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2020.09.045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2020.09.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33187638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozzali M, Grassini A, Morana G, Zotta M, Cabras S (2021) Focal seizures with impaired awareness as long-term neurological complication of COVID-19: a case report. Neurol Sci 42:2619&#x2013;2623. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10072-021-05233-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xfc;ssow H, Timmis K (2021) COVID-19: long covid and its societal consequences. Environ Microbiol. https://doi.org/10.1111/1462-2920.15634</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1462-2920.15634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34729893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8652514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P, Torocastro M, Panagopoulos D (2020) Autonomic dysfunction in &#x2018;long COVID&#x2019;: rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin Med 21, clinmed.2020&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;0896. https://doi.org/10.7861/clinmed.2020-0896</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ (2021) Characterizing Long COVID in an International Cohort: 7 Months of Symptoms and Their Impact. Medrxiv 2020.12.24.20248802. https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.12.24.20248802</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G et al (2022) SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature 604:697&#x2013;707</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-022-04569-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9046077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doykov I, H&#xe4;llqvist J, Gilmour KC, Grandjean L, Mills K, Heywood WE (2020) &#x2018;The long tail of Covid-19&#x2019; - The detection of a prolonged inflammatory response after a SARS-CoV-2 infection in asymptomatic and mildly affected patients. F1000Res. 19;9:1349. https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.27287.2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egbert AR, Cankurtaran S, Karpiak S (2020) Brain abnormalities in COVID-19 acute/subacute phase: a rapid systematic review. Brain Behav Immun 89:543&#x2013;554. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2020.07.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2020.07.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32682993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7366124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fereidan-Esfahani M, Tobin WO (2021b) Cyclophosphamide in treatment of tumefactive multiple sclerosis. Multiple Scler Relat Disorders 47:102627. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msard.2020.102627</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2020.102627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrucci R, Dini M, Groppo E, Rosci C, Reitano MR, Bai F, Poletti B, Brugnera A, Silani V, Monforte AD, Priori A (2021) Long-lasting cognitive abnormalities after COVID-19. Brain Sci 11:235. https://doi.org/10.3390/brainsci11020235</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci11020235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33668456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7917789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford N, Agedew A, Dalton F, Perrine SJ, Saydah G (2024) Notes from the field: long COVID prevalence among adults &#x2014; United States, 2022. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 73:135&#x2013;136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm7306a4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foucard C, San-Galli A, Tarrano C, Chaumont H, Lannuzel A, Roze E (2021) Acute cerebellar ataxia and myoclonus with or without opsoclonus: a para-infectious syndrome associated with COVID-19. Eur J Neurol 28(10):3533&#x2013;3536. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.14726</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33492711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franke C, Ferse C, Kreye J, Reincke S, Sanchez-Sendin E, Rocco A, Steinbrenner M, Angermair S, Treskatsch S, Zickler D, Eckardt K, Dersch R, Hosp J, Audebert H, Endres M, Ploner J, Pr&#xfc;&#xdf; H (2021) High frequency of cerebrospinal fluid autoantibodies in COVID-19 patients with neurological symptoms. Brain Behav Immun 93:415&#x2013;419 Epub 2020 Dec 24. PMID: 33359380; PMCID: PMC7834471</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2020.12.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P, Tahmasebi N, Gant V, Gupta R (2022) Long COVID following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: characteristic T cell alterations and response to antihistamines. J Investig Med 70:61&#x2013;67</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jim-2021-002051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham EL, Clark JR, Orban ZS, Lim PH, Szymanski AL, Taylor C, DiBiase RM, Jia DT, Balabanov R, Ho SU, Batra A, Liotta EM, Koralnik IJ (2021) Persistent neurologic symptoms and cognitive dysfunction in non-hospitalized Covid-19 long haulers. Ann Clin Transl Neur 8:1073&#x2013;1085. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.51350</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.51350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampshire A, Azor A, Atchison C, Trender W, Hellyer P, Giunchiglia V, Husain M, Cooke G, Cooper E, Lound A, Donnelly C, Chadeau-Hyam M, Ward H, Elliott P (2024) Cognition and memory after Covid-19 in a large community sample. N Engl J Med 390:806&#x2013;818. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2311330</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarius S, Pache F, K&#xf6;rtvelyessy P, Jel&#x10d;i&#x107; I, Stettner M, Franciotta D, Keller E, Neumann B, Ringelstein M, Senel M, Regeniter A, Kalantzis R, Willms JF, Berthele A, Busch M, Capobianco M, Eisele A, Reichen I, Dersch R, Rauer S, Sandner K, Ayzenberg I, Gross CC, Hegen H, Khalil M, Kleiter I, Lenhard T, Haas J, Aktas O, Angstwurm K, Kleinschnitz C, Lewerenz J, Tumani H, Paul F, Stangel M, Ruprecht K Wildemann B; in cooperation with the German Society for Cerebrospinal Fluid Diagnostics and Clinical Neurochemistry. 2022. Cerebrospinal fluid findings in COVID-19: a multicenter study of 150 lumbar punctures in 127 patients. J Neuroinflammation. 20;19(1):19. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12974-021-02339-0 . PMID: 35057809; PMCID: PMC8771621</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanjwal K, Jamal S, Kichloo A, Grubb BP (2020) New-onset Postural Orthostatic Tachycardia Syndrome following Coronavirus Disease 2019 infection. J Innovations Cardiac Rhythm Manage 11:4302&#x2013;4304. https://doi.org/10.19102/icrm.2020.111102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19102/icrm.2020.111102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Bitna-Ha, Kim SW, Chang HH, Kwon KT, Bae S, Hwang S (2022) Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome in patients after 12 months from COVID-19 infection in Korea. BMC Infect Dis 22(1):93. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12879-022-07062-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-022-07062-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35086489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8793328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J et al Distinguishing features of Long COVID identified through immune profiling</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang K, Pr&#xfc;ss H (2017) Frequencies of neuronal autoantibodies in healthy controls. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflammation 4(NA). https://doi.org/10.1212/NXI.0000000000000386</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li X, Geng D, Mei N, Wu PY, Huang CC, Jia T, Zhao Y, Wang D, Xiao A, Yin B (2020) Cerebral micro-structural changes in COVID-19 patients &#x2013; an MRI-based 3-month follow-up study. Eclinicalmedicine 25:100484. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7396952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maga&#xf1;a S, Keegan M, Weinshenker B, Erickson B, Pittock S, Lennon V, Rodriguez M, Thomsen K, Weigand S, Mandrekar J, Linbo L Lucchinetti C.Beneficial plasma Exchange Response in Central Nervous System Inflammatory Demyelination. Arch Neurol, 68(7), 870. https://doi.org/10.1001/archneurol.2011.34</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martimbianco ALC, Pacheco RL, Bagattini AN, Riera R (2021) Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID-19: a systematic review. Int J Clin Pract e14357. https://doi.org/10.1111/ijcp.14357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijcp.14357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo Clinic Laboratory website, GAD65 antibody Assay https://www.mayocliniclabs.com/test-catalog/overview/81596#Clinical-and-Interpretive</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monti G, Giovannini G, Marudi A, Bedin R, Melegari A, Simone AM, Santangelo M, Pignatti A, Bertellini E, Trenti T, Meletti S (2020) Anti-NMDA receptor encephalitis presenting as new onset refractory status epilepticus in COVID-19. Seizure 81:18&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seizure.2020.07.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2020.07.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32688169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7362825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najjar S, Najjar A, Chong DJ, Pramanik BK, Kirsch C, Kuzniecky RI, Pacia SV, Azhar S (2020) Central nervous system complications associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection: integrative concepts of pathophysiology and case reports. J Neuroinflamm 17:231. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12974-020-01896-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12974-020-01896-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, Cook JR, Nordvig AS, Shalev D, Sehrawat TS, Ahluwalia N, Bikdeli B, Dietz D, Der-Nigoghossian C, Liyanage-Don N, Rosner GF, Bernstein EJ, Mohan S, Beckley AA, Seres DS, Wan EY (2021) Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med 27:601&#x2013;615. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8893149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo D, Vasto S, Scalisi L, Cottone S, Cambula G, Rizzo M, Giacomazza D, Picone P (2021) Post-acute COVID-19 neurological syndrome: a New Medical Challenge. J Clin Med 10(9):1947. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10091947</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm10091947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34062770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8124354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavli A, Theodoridou M, Maltezou HC (2021) Post-COVID syndrome: incidence, clinical spectrum, and challenges for primary healthcare professionals. Arch Med Res. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arcmed.2021.03.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arcmed.2021.03.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33962805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8093949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C et al (2022) Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Immunol 23:210&#x2013;216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-021-01113-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preprint at medRxiv (2022) https://doi.org/10.1101/2022.08.09.22278592</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugin D, Vargas MI, Thieffry C, Schibler M, Grosgurin O, Pugin J, Lalive PH (2020) COVID-19-related encephalopathy responsive to high-dose glucocorticoids. Neurology 95(12):543&#x2013;546. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000010354</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000010354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32680950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiken S et al (2022) Alzheimer&#x2019;s-like signaling in brains of COVID-19 patients. Alzheimers Dement 18:955&#x2013;965</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/alz.12558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35112786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolandsson O, Hampe CS, Wennberg P, Radtke J, Langenberg C, Wareham N, EPIC-InterAct Study Group (2015) Prevalence and Regional Distribution of Autoantibodies against GAD65Ab in a European Population without Diabetes: the EPIC-InterAct study. Diabetes Care 38(8):e114&#x2013;e115. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc15-0305</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc15-0305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26207060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4512134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salle V (2021) Coronavirus-induced autoimmunity. Clin Immunol Orlando Fla 226:108694&#x2013;108694 Doi:1 0.1016/j.clim.2021.108694</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clim.2021.108694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Servier C, Porcher R, Pane I, Ravaud P, Tran VT (2023) Trajectories of the evolution of post-COVID-19 condition, up to two years after symptoms onset. Int J Infect Diseases: IJID : Official Publication Int Soc Infect Dis 133:67&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2023.05.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2023.05.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sian-Hulsmann J, Riederer P (2024) Virus-induced brain pathology and the neuroinflammation-inflammation continuum: the neurochemists view. J Neural Transm (Vienna). Jan 23. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00702-023-02723-5 . Epub ahead of print. PMID: 38261034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smyth D, Kyaw KM, Legister A, MacFarlane G, Sankar UU, Patel M, Clough C, Kulendran A, Mulroy E (2021) Post-COVID-19 opsoclonus-myoclonus syndrome and encephalopathy associated with leucine-rich glioma-inactivated 1 (LGI-1) antibodies. J Neurol Sci 430:119982. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2021.119982</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2021.119982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34543933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8440042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spudich S, Nath A (2022) Nervous system consequences of COVID-19. Science 375:267&#x2013;269</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abm2052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35050660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valencia Sanchez C, Theel E, Binnicker M, Toledano M, McKeon A (2021) Autoimmune Encephalitis after SARS-CoV-2 infection: case frequency, findings, and outcomes. Neurology 97:e2262&#x2013;e2268. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000012931</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000012931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34635560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8671045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widmann CN, Wieberneit M, Bieler L, Bernsen S, Gr&#xe4;fenk&#xe4;mper R, Brosseron F, Schmeel C, Tacik P, Skowasch D, Radbruch A, Heneka MT (2021) Longitudinal neurocognitive and Pulmonological Profile of Long COVID-19: protocol for the COVIMMUNE-Clin study. Jmir Res Protoc 10:e30259. https://doi.org/10.2196/30259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/30259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34559059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8589042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>