<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35902374</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5948</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of occupational and environmental medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Occup Environ Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sleep Quality and Mental Health Consequences of COVID-19 Pandemic in the Aviation Community in Greece.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e567</StartPage><EndPage>e574</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e567-e574</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JOM.0000000000002616</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this study was to assess the mental health and sleep quality of aviation workers in Greece during the pandemic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A cross-sectional study of aviation workers in Greece was conducted.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Sleep disturbances were observed in 25.4% of our 548 participants, whereas 8.2% and 5.8% reported at least mild depressive and anxiety symptoms, respectively. The impact of the pandemic on their mental health was their primary concern, which increased for many active pilots according to their workload. Those infected mainly faced daily tiredness and fatigue. Smoking habits and high body mass index were a predisposition for more physical symptoms. Cabin crew and women generally yielded worse scores than the other groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Fear of infection could explain mental health issues, whereas physical symptoms of those infected could be attributed to long-COVID (coronavirus disease) syndrome. Flight attendants' lower ratings may be due to more occupational exposure.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 American College of Occupational and Environmental Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karkala</LastName><ForeName>Aliki</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Aeromedical Center of Thessaloniki, Ethnikis Antistaseos 44, Thessaloniki, Greece (Dr Karkala); Medical Physics and Digital Innovation Lab, School of Health Sciences, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Thessaloniki, Greece (Dr Moschonas); Foundation for Research and Technology-Hellas, Vassilika Vouton, Heraklion, Greece, Current: Medical Physics and Digital Innovation Lab, School of Health Sciences, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Thessaloniki, Greece (Mr Sykas); Medical Physics and Digital Innovation Lab, School of Health Sciences, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki and Aeromedical Center of Thessaloniki, Thessaloniki, Greece (Mrs Karagianni); Medical Physics and Digital Innovation Lab, School of Health Sciences, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece (Mrs Gilou); Hellenic Civil Aviation Authority, Athens, Greece (Dr Papaefthymiou); Aeromedical Center of Thessaloniki, Ethnikis Antistaseos, Thessaloniki, Greece (Dr Kourtidou-Papadeli).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moschonas</LastName><ForeName>Stavros</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sykas</LastName><ForeName>Georgios</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karagianni</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gilou</LastName><ForeName>Sotiria</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Papaefthymiou</LastName><ForeName>Odysseas</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kourtidou-Papadeli</LastName><ForeName>Chrysoula</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Occup Environ Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9504688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1076-2752</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001359" MajorTopicYN="Y">Aviation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006115" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Greece</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008603" MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000089943" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep Quality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35902374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9426318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JOM.0000000000002616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00043764-202209000-00020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kamal M, Abo Omirah M, Hussein A, Saeed H. Assessment and characterisation of post&#x2013;COVID-19 manifestations. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:e13746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S Barnett J Brill SE, et al. . &#x2018;Long-COVID&#x2019;: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT Hamilton FW Milne A, et al. . Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up: results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax. 2021;76:399&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao Y, Sun Y, Meng S, Shi J, Lu L. 2019-nCoV epidemic: address mental health care to empower society. Lancet. 2020;395:e37&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7133594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32043982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santini ZI Jose PE York Cornwell E, et al. . Social disconnectedness, perceived isolation, and symptoms of depression and anxiety among older Americans (NSHAP): a longitudinal mediation analysis. Lancet Public Health. 2020;5:e62&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31910981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mak IW, Chu CM, Pan PC, Yiu MG, Chan VL. Long-term psychiatric morbidities among SARS survivors. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2009;31:318&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7112501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19555791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tracy M, Norris FH, Galea S. Differences in the determinants of posttraumatic stress disorder and depression after a mass traumatic event. Depress Anxiety. 2011;28:666&#x2013;675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3145817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21618672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanberg CR. The individual experience of unemployment. Annu Rev Psychol. 2012;63:369&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21721936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Sanguino C Aus&#xed;n B Castellanos M&#xc1;, et al. . Mental health consequences during the initial stage of the 2020 coronavirus pandemic (COVID-19) in Spain. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:172&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7219372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32405150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Zhao N. Generalized anxiety disorder, depressive symptoms and sleep quality during COVID-19 outbreak in China: a Web-based cross-sectional survey. Psychiatry Res 2020:112954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7152913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naja F, Hamadeh R. Nutrition amid the COVID-19 pandemic: a multi-level framework for action. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2020;74:1117&#x2013;1121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7167535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32313188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YN Liu ZR Li SQ, et al. . Burden of sleep disturbance during COVID-19 pandemic: a systematic review. Nat Sci Sleep. 2021;13:933&#x2013;966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8253893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34234598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casagrande M, Favieri F, Tambelli R, Forte G. The enemy who sealed the world: effects quarantine due to the COVID-19 on sleep quality, anxiety, and psychological distress in the Italian population. Sleep Med. 2020;75:12&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanton R To QG Khalesi S, et al. . Depression, anxiety and stress during COVID-19: associations with changes in physical activity, sleep, tobacco and alcohol use in Australian adults. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:4065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7312903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32517294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cahill J, Cullen P, Anwer S, Gaynor K. The impact of the COVID 19 pandemic on aviation workers and the aviation system. 29th International Symposium on Aviation Psychology. 2021;164&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nhamo G, Dube K, Chikodzi D. COVID-19 and implications for the aviation sector: a global perspective. In: Counting the Cost of COVID-19 on the Global Tourism Industry. Cham, Switzerland: Springer. 2020:89&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimmer P. Aviation and the COVID-19 pandemic: flying to the &#x2018;next normal&#x2019;. J Int Trade Logist Law. 2020;6:119&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Lee J, Fitzgerald HN, Oosterhoff B, Sevi B, Shook NJ. Job insecurity and financial concern during the COVID-19 pandemic are associated with worse mental health. J Occup Environ Med. 2020;62:686&#x2013;691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32890205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson D, Driller M, Johnston B, Gill N. The effectiveness of a 17-week lifestyle intervention on health behaviors among airline pilots during COVID-19. J Sport Health Sci. 2021;10:333&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7957121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33221534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon S, Garbi D, Ben Bassat S, Shapira S, Shelef L. Mental adaptation to capsule work during COVID-19 outbreak: the case of Israeli air force career personnel [published online November 19, 2020]. Mil Med. 2020;usaa424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33210718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNeely E, Mordukhovich I, Tideman S, Gale S, Coull B. Estimating the health consequences of flight attendant work: comparing flight attendant health to the general population in a cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health. 2018;18:346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5865289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29566648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf6;rlich Y, Stadelmann D. Mental health of flying cabin crews: depression, anxiety, and stress before and during the COVID-19 pandemic. Front Psychol. 2020;11:581496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7773923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33391100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Que J Shi L Deng J, et al. . Psychological impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on healthcare workers: a cross-sectional study in China. Gen Psychiatr. 2020;33:e100259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7299004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32596640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai J Ma S Wang Y, et al. . Factors associated with mental health outcomes among health care workers exposed to coronavirus disease 2019. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3:e203976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7090843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32202646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrero San Martin A, Parra Serrano J, Diaz Cambriles T, et al. . Sleep characteristics in health workers exposed to the COVID-19 pandemic. Sleep Med, 2020;75:388&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32950884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu K, Wei X. Analysis of psychological and sleep status and exercise rehabilitation of front-line clinical staff in the fight against COVID-19 in China. Med Sci Monit Basic Res. 2020;26:e924085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7241216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32389999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu HY Chen PY Chuang LP, et al. . Diagnostic accuracy of the Berlin questionnaire, STOP-BANG, STOP, and Epworth Sleepiness Scale in detecting obstructive sleep apnea: a bivariate meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev. 2017;36:57&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27919588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Buchner A, Lang A-G. G*Power Version 3.1.7 [computer software]. Uiversit&#xe4;t Kiel, Germany; 2013: Available at: http://www.psycho.uni-duesseldorf.de/abteilungen/aap/gpower3/download-and-register. Accessed May 4, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parlapani E Holeva V Voitsidis P, et al. . Psychological and behavioral responses to the COVID-19 pandemic in Greece. Front Psychiatry. 2020;11:821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7466648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32973575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fountoulakis KN Apostolidou MK Atsiova MB, et al. . Self-reported changes in anxiety, depression and suicidality during the COVID-19 lockdown in Greece. J Affect Disord. 2021;279:624&#x2013;629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7605790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33190113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levis B Benedetti A Ioannidis JP, et al. . Patient Health Questionnaire-9 scores do not accurately estimate depression prevalence: individual participant data meta-analysis. J Clin Epidemiol. 2020;122:115&#x2013;128.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32105798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper CL, Sloan S. Occupational and psychosocial stress among commercial aviation pilots. J Occup Med. 1985;27:570&#x2013;576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4032093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu AC, Donnelly-McLay D, Weisskopf MG, McNeely E, Betancourt TS, Allen JG. Airplane pilot mental health and suicidal thoughts: a cross-sectional descriptive study via anonymous Web-based survey. Environ Health. 2016;15:121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5157081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27974043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bor R, Eriksen C, Oakes M, Scragg P. Pilot Mental Health Assessment and Support: A Practitioner's Guide. London: Routledge; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tay D, Du K, Ho J, Liu F, Chan C, Cao C. The Aviation Industry: tackling the turbulence caused by COVID-19. IETI Trans Econ Manag. 2020;1:44&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilic B. Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the mental states of airline pilots in Turkey. J Aviat. 2022;6:50&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asmundson GJG, Taylor S. How health anxiety influences responses to viral outbreaks like COVID-19: what all decision-makers, health authorities, and health care professionals need to know. J Anxiety Disord. 2020;71:102211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32179380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pongpirul K, Kaewpoungngam K, Chotirosniramit K, Theprugsa S. Commercial airline protocol during COVID-19 pandemic: an experience of Thai Airways International. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0237299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7410241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32760126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Chen Y, Qiu L, Lin X, Ke X, Chen G. Infection prevention and control in aviation during COVID-19 pandemic&#x2014;a qualitative study.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mboreha CA, Jilin C, Kumar CG. Risk and preventing of COVID-19 in a commercial aircraft cabin: an overview. Int J Eng Appl Sci Technol. 2020;5:661&#x2013;670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappuccio FP Taggart FM Kandala NB, et al. . Meta-analysis of short sleep duration and obesity in children and adults. Sleep. 2008;31:619&#x2013;626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2398753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18517032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y Wang Y Shao C, et al. . COVID-19 infection: the perspectives on immune responses. Cell Death Differ. 2020;27:1451&#x2013;1454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7091918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32205856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiGiovanni C, Conley J, Chiu D, Zaborski J. Factors influencing compliance with quarantine in Toronto during the 2003 SARS outbreak. Biosecur Bioterror. 2004;2:265&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15650436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawryluck L, Gold WL, Robinson S, Pogorski S, Galea S, Styra R. SARS control and psychological effects of quarantine, Toronto, Canada. Emerg Infect Dis. 2004;10:1206&#x2013;1212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3323345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15324539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsang WHT, Scudds RJ, Chan EYL. Psychosocial impact of SARS. Emerg Infect Dis. 2004;10:1326&#x2013;1327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3323309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15338536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong J Lipsitz O Nasri F, et al. . Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on mental health in the general population: a systematic review. J Affect Disord. 2020;277:55&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7413844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32799105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Wandelt S, Zhang A. How did COVID-19 impact air transportation? A first peek through the lens of complex networks. J Air Transp Manag. 2020;89:101928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32952320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner A, Page A, LaMontagne AD. Cause and effect in studies on unemployment, mental health and suicide: a meta-analytic and conceptual review. Psychol Med. 2014;44:909&#x2013;917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23834819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TJ, von dem Knesebeck O. Is an insecure job better for health than having no job at all? A systematic review of studies investigating the health-related risks of both job insecurity and unemployment. BMC Public Health. 2015;15:985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4589035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26419739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connor J Madhavan S Mokashi M, et al. . Health risks and outcomes that disproportionately affect women during the COVID-19 pandemic: a review. Soc Sci Med. 2020;266:113364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7487147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32950924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert PR. Why is depression more prevalent in women? J Psychiatry Neurosci. 2015;40:219&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4478054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26107348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#xfc;ksek H, &#xc7;elik M, Keser A. The mediator role of well-being in the effect of COVID-19 anxiety on occupational commitment: research in the aviation sector. Int J Occup Saf Ergon. 2022;1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35322753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahrami H, BaHammam AS, Bragazzi NL, Saif Z, Faris M, Vitiello MV. Sleep problems during the COVID-19 pandemic by population: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Sleep Med. 2021;17:299&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7853219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33108269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrilli RM, Roach GD, Dawson D, Lamond N. The sleep, subjective fatigue, and sustained attention of commercial airline pilots during an international pattern. Chronobiol Int. 2006;23:1357&#x2013;1362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17190718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florea C Topalidis P Hauser T, et al. . Sleep during COVID-19 lockdown: a cross-cultural study investigating job system relevance. Biochem Pharmacol. 2021;191:114463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7872856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingram J, Maciejewski G, Hand CJ. Changes in diet, sleep, and physical activity are associated with differences in negative mood during COVID-19 lockdown. Front Psychol 2020:588604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7492645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32982903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voitsidis P Gliatas I Bairachtari V, et al. . Insomnia during the COVID-19 pandemic in a Greek population. Psychiatry Res. 2020;289:113076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7217074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32434093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trakada A Nikolaidis PT Andrade MDS, et al. . Sleep during &#x201c;lockdown&#x201d; in the COVID-19 pandemic. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:9094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7729605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33291468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilditch CJ, Flynn-Evans EE. Fatigue, schedules, sleep, and sleepiness in U.S. commercial pilots during COVID-19. Aerosp Med Hum Perform. 2022;93:433&#x2013;441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35551720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaehne A, Unbehaun T, Feige B, Lutz UC, Batra A, Riemann D. How smoking affects sleep: a polysomnographical analysis. Sleep Med. 2012;13:1286&#x2013;1292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23026505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papazisis Z, Nikolaidis PT, Trakada G. Sleep, physical activity, and diet of adults during the second lockdown of the COVID-19 pandemic in Greece. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:7292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8305576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34299743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sar-van der Brugge S Talman S Boonman-de Winter L, et al. . Pulmonary function and health-related quality of life after COVID-19 pneumonia. Respir Med. 2021;176:106272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7701891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33302142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udina C, Ars J, Morandi A, Vilar&#xf3; J, C&#xe1;ceres C, Inzitari M. Rehabilitation in adult post&#x2013;COVID-19 patients in post-acute care with therapeutic exercise. J Frailty Aging. 2021;10:297&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7876526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34105716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delbressine JM Machado FVC Go&#xeb;rtz YMJ, et al. . The impact of post&#x2013;COVID-19 syndrome on self-reported physical activity. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:6017. Published June 3, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8199934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34205086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godeau D, Petit A, Richard I, Roquelaure Y, Descatha A. Return-to-work, disabilities and occupational health in the age of COVID-19. Scand J Work Environ Health. 2021;47:408&#x2013;409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8259700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34003294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V de-la-Llave-Rinc&#xf3;n AI, et al. . Anxiety, depression and poor sleep quality as long-term post-COVID sequelae in previously hospitalized patients: a multicenter study. J Infect. 2021;83:496&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8236125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34192525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grout A, Leggat PA. Cabin crew health and fitness-to-fly: opportunities for re-evaluation amid COVID-19. Travel Med Infect Dis. 2021;40:101973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9760509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths RF, Powell DM. The occupational health and safety of flight attendants. Aviat Space Environ Med. 2012;83:514&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22606869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalla V. Time warped: the flexibilization and maximization of flight attendant working time. Can Rev Sociol. 2004;41:345&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu HY, King B. Impacts of misbehaving air passengers on frontline employees: role stress and emotional labor. Int J Contemp Hosp Manag. 2017;29:1793&#x2013;1813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nogues S, Tremblay DG, Mansour S. Job demands and job resources among Western airline cabin crews: a comparative study of Canadian, German, and French flight attendants. J Aviat Aerosp Educ Res. 2021;30:89&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>