<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38406111</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Unveiling the Clinical Spectrum of Post-COVID-19 Conditions: Assessment and Recommended Strategies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e52827</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e52827</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e52827</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.52827</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>SARS-CoV-2 caused the pandemic of the rapidly evolving COVID-19. As of December 6, 2023, there were 765,152,854 COVID-19-recovering cases. Long-term consequences known as "long COVID" and "post-COVID-19 conditions" (PCCs) or "post-acute COVID-19 syndrome" are being reported more frequently in a subset of recovering patients. Systemic, neuropsychiatric, cardio-respiratory, and gastrointestinal symptoms are the most prevalent. The management of PCCs poses unique challenges due to the lack of official guidelines and the complex nature of the illness. This abstract highlights key principles derived from recent reviews and expert recommendations to provide healthcare professionals with a comprehensive approach to manage post-COVID-19 patients. Preventive medicine plays a crucial role in managing PCCs. While no specific medications are available for treatment, preventive measures such as COVID-19 vaccination, adherence to precautionary measures, regular consultations with medical professionals, monitoring symptoms and progress, and seeking information on symptom management are essential to assist patients in their recovery and improve their quality of life. Medical management requires transparent goal-setting and collaborative decision-making based on the patient's symptoms, comorbidities, and treatment objectives. Treatment plans for post-COVID-19 patients should focus on patient education, using registries and calendars to track symptoms and triggers, providing support and reassurance, and offering holistic support through peer networks and supportive psychotherapy techniques. Symptomatic and rehabilitative care, including well-established symptom management techniques, physical rehabilitation programs, and addressing mental health and well-being, are vital components of post-COVID-19 management. Lifestyle factors such as stress reduction, nutrition, and sleep should be incorporated into managing underlying medical conditions in post-COVID-19 patients. Regular follow-up visits and referrals to specialists are recommended to monitor the patient's progress and address specific organ system involvement or additional care needs. In summary, for the effective management of PCCs, a holistic approach should include preventive measures, patient education, supportive psychotherapy, symptomatic and rehabilitative care, medical management, counseling on lifestyle elements, and appropriate follow-up plans. However, it is crucial to stay updated with evolving guidelines and recommendations from healthcare authorities to provide the most effective and evidence-based care to post-COVID-19 patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Assiri et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Assiri</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Preventive Services, Saudi Ministry of Health, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alamaa</LastName><ForeName>Tareef</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Therapeutic Services, Saudi Ministry of Health, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elenezi</LastName><ForeName>Faisal</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Assistant Agency for Hospital Affairs, Saudi Ministry of Health, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alsagheir</LastName><ForeName>Aeshah</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Quality Index Measuring, Saudi Ministry of Health, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alzubaidi</LastName><ForeName>Lamya</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Assistant Agency for Hospital Affairs, Saudi Ministry of Health, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>TIeyjeh</LastName><ForeName>Imad</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases, King Fahad Medical City, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alhomod</LastName><ForeName>Abdulazia S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Seha Virtual Hospital, Saudi Ministry of Health, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaffas</LastName><ForeName>Eisha M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mental Health and Social Services, Saudi Ministry of Health, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amer</LastName><ForeName>Samar A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health and Community Medicine, Zagazig University, Zagazig, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Administration of Health Programs and Non-communicable Diseases, Saudi Ministry of Health, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical assessment tools</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">education management solutions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-covid-19 conditions (pccs)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">review article</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38406111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10884364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.52827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO COVID-19 Dashboard.  [
Dec;
2023 
]. 2023. https://data.who.int/dashboards/covid19/cases?n=c https://data.who.int/dashboards/covid19/cases?n=c</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long haulers-what is the evidence for post-Covid fatigue? Stengel A, Malek N, Zipfel S, Goepel S. Front Psychiatry. 2021;12:677934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8175784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34093286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covid symptoms, symptom clusters, and predictors for becoming a long-hauler: looking for clarity in the haze of the pandemic (Preprint) Huang Y, Pinto MD, Borelli JL, et al. medRxiv. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9510954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36154716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symptoms and functional impairment assessed 8 months after mild COVID-19 among health care workers. Havervall S, Rosell A, Phillipson M, Mangsbo SM, Nilsson P, Hober S, Th&#xe5;lin C. JAMA. 2021;325:2015&#x2013;2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8027932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33825846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of Ongoing Symptoms Following Coronavirus (COVID-19) Infection in the UK: 1 April 2021.  [
Aug;
2023 
];https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/1april2021 2021 infection</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Late conditions diagnosed 1-4 months following an initial coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) encounter: a matched-cohort study using inpatient and outpatient administrative data-United States, 1 March-30 June 2020. Chevinsky JR, Tao G, Lavery AM, et al. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8135331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33909072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health care utilization and clinical characteristics of nonhospitalized adults in an integrated health care system 28-180 days after Covid-19 diagnosis - Georgia, May 2020-March 2021. Hernandez-Romieu AC, Leung S, Mbanya A, et al. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2021;70:644&#x2013;650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8084119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33914727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection in individuals not requiring hospital admission: a Danish population-based cohort study. Lund LC, Hallas J, Nielsen H, et al. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21:1373&#x2013;1382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8110209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33984263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, et al. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID-19: a systematic review. Cabrera Martimbianco AL, Pacheco RL, Bagattini &#xc2;M, Riera R. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8236920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33977626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Challenges in defining long COVID: striking differences across literature, electronic health records, and patient-reported information (Preprint) Rando HM, Bennett TD, Byrd JB, et al. medRxiv. 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of coronavirus disease 2019 on pulmonary function in early convalescence phase. Huang Y, Tan C, Wu J, et al. Respir Res. 2020;21:163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32600344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early experiences of rehabilitation for individuals post-COVID to improve fatigue, breathlessness exercise capacity and cognition - a cohort study. Daynes E, Gerlis C, Chaplin E, Gardiner N, Singh SJ. Chron Respir Dis. 2021;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8114752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33957805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covid-19: how many variants are there, and what do we know about them? Mahase E. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34413059/ BMJ. 2021;374:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34413059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 Variants of Concern as of 5 January 2024.  [
Jan;
2024 
]. 2024. https://www.ecdc.europa.eu/en/covid-19/variants-concern https://www.ecdc.europa.eu/en/covid-19/variants-concern</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathophysiology of post-COVID syndromes: a new perspective. Batiha GE, Al-Kuraishy HM, Al-Gareeb AI, Welson NN. Virol J. 2022;19:158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9548310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36210445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE guideline on long covid. Sivan M, Taylor S. BMJ. 2020;371:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33361141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Histopathological observations in COVID-19: a systematic review. Deshmukh V, Motwani R, Kumar A, Kumari C, Raza K. J Clin Pathol. 2021;74:76&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32817204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tissue distribution of ACE2 protein, the functional receptor for SARS coronavirus. A first step in understanding SARS pathogenesis. Hamming I, Timens W, Bulthuis ML, Lely AT, Navis G, van Goor H. J Pathol. 2004;203:631&#x2013;637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7167720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15141377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Body localization of ACE-2: on the trail of the keyhole of SARS-CoV-2. Salamanna F, Maglio M, Landini MP, Fini M. Front Med (Lausanne) 2020;7:594495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7744810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33344479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis (Preprint) L&#xf3;pez-Le&#xf3;n S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, Villapol S. SSRN. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 and multiorgan failure: a narrative review on potential mechanisms. Mokhtari T, Hassani F, Ghaffari N, Ebrahimi B, Yarahmadi A, Hassanzadeh G. J Mol Histol. 2020;51:613&#x2013;628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7533045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33011887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Immediate and long-term consequences of COVID-19 infections for the development of neurological disease. Heneka MT, Golenbock D, Latz E, Morgan D, Brown R. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2020;12:69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32498691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term health consequences of COVID-19. Del Rio C, Collins LF, Malani P. http://JAMA. 2020. 10.1001/jama.2020.19719. JAMA. 2020;324:1723&#x2013;1724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8019677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: a Mediterranean cohort study. Moreno-P&#xe9;rez O, Merino E, Leon-Ramirez JM, et al. J Infect. 2021;82:378&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7802523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et al.  https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.12.24.20248802v2 (Accessed March. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent COVID-19 symptoms at least one month after diagnosis: a national survey. Tleyjeh IM, Kashour T, Riaz M, et al. J Infect Public Health. 2022;15:578&#x2013;585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9020835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35477145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence and correlates of chronic fatigue syndrome and post-traumatic stress disorder after the outbreak of the COVID-19. Simani L, Ramezani M, Darazam IA, Sagharichi M, Aalipour MA, Ghorbani F, Pakdaman H. J Neurovirol. 2021;27:154&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7852482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33528827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-COVID-19 fatigue: a systematic review. Joli J, Buck P, Zipfel S, Stengel A. Front Psychiatry. 2022;13:947973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9403611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36032234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Three-month follow-up study of survivors of coronavirus disease 2019 after discharge. Liang L, Yang B, Jiang N, et al. J Korean Med Sci. 2020;35:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7721559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33289374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Depression as a mediator of chronic fatigue and post-traumatic stress symptoms in Middle East respiratory syndrome survivors. Lee SH, Shin HS, Park HY, et al. Psychiatry Investig. 2019;16:59&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6354037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30605995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Stanford Hall consensus statement for post-COVID-19 rehabilitation. Barker-Davies RM, O'Sullivan O, Senaratne KP, et al. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:949&#x2013;959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7418628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32475821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mental morbidities and chronic fatigue in severe acute respiratory syndrome survivors: long-term follow-up. Lam MH, Wing YK, Yu MW, et al. Arch Intern Med. 2009;169:2142&#x2013;2147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20008700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chronic widespread musculoskeletal pain, fatigue, depression and disordered sleep in chronic post-SARS syndrome; a case-controlled study. Moldofsky H, Patcai J. BMC Neurol. 2011;11:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3071317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21435231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musculoskeletal symptoms and related factors in postacute COVID-19 patients. Bak&#x131;lan F, G&#xf6;kmen &#x130;G, Ortanca B, et al. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8420386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34387911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Functional limitations post-COVID-19: a comprehensive assessment strategy. Torres-Castro R, Solis-Navarro L, Sitj&#xe0;-Rabert M, Vilar&#xf3; J. Arch Bronconeumol. 2021;57:7&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7455248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34629627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The post-COVID-19 functional status scale: a tool to measure functional status over time after COVID-19. Klok FA, Boon GJ, Barco S, et al. Eur Respir J. 2020;56:2001494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Respiratory and psychophysical sequelae among patients with COVID-19 four months after hospital discharge. Bellan M, Soddu D, Balbo PE, et al. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7841464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33502487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Follow-up study of the pulmonary function and related physiological characteristics of COVID-19 survivors three months after recovery. Zhao YM, Shang YM, Song WB, et al. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CT features of COVID-19 patients with two consecutive negative RT-PCR tests after treatment. Fu Z, Tang N, Chen Y, et al. Sci Rep. 2020;10:11548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7360570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32665633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Follow-up chest radiographic findings in patients with MERS-CoV after recovery. Das KM, Lee EY, Singh R, et al. Indian J Radiol Imaging. 2017;27:342&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5644332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29089687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blockade of IL-6 Trans signaling attenuates pulmonary fibrosis. Le TT, Karmouty-Quintana H, Melicoff E, et al. J Immunol. 2014;193:3755&#x2013;3768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4169999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25172494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lung transplantation for patients with severe COVID-19. Bharat A, Querrey M, Markov NS, et al. Sci Transl Med. 2020;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8050952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characterization of the inflammatory response to severe COVID-19 illness. McElvaney OJ, McEvoy NL, McElvaney OF, et al. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020;202:812&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32584597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Patients Suffer Long-Term Lung and Heart Damage but It Can Improve With Time.  [
Dec;
2022 
]. 2020. https://www.ersnet.org/news-and-features/news/covid-19-patients-suffer-long-term-lung-and-heart-damage-but-it-can-improve-with-time/#:~:text=COVID%2D19%20patients%20can%20suffer,European%20Respiratory%20Society%20International%20Congress. https://www.ersnet.org/news-and-features/news/covid-19-patients-suffer-long-term-lung-and-heart-damage-but-it-can-improve-with-time/#:~:text=COVID%2D19%20patients%20can%20suffer,European%20Respiratory%20Society%20International%20Congress.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes of cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in patients recently recovered from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Puntmann VO, Carerj ML, Wieters I, et al. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:1265&#x2013;1273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiovascular magnetic resonance findings in competitive athletes recovering from COVID-19 infection. Rajpal S, Tong MS, Borchers J, Zareba KM, Obarski TP, Simonetti OP, Daniels CJ. JAMA Cardiol. 2021;6:116&#x2013;118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7489396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32915194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incidence of thrombotic complications in critically ill ICU patients with COVID-19. Klok FA, Kruip MJ, van der Meer NJ, et al. Thromb Res. 2020;191:145&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32291094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altered lipid metabolism in recovered SARS patients twelve years after infection. Wu Q, Zhou L, Sun X, et al. Sci Rep. 2017;7:9110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5567209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28831119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiovascular complications in the post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PACS) Elseidy SA, Awad AK, Vorla M, Fatima A, Elbadawy MA, Mandal D, Mohamad T. Int J Cardiol Heart Vasc. 2022;40:101012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8958273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35355927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 and neurological disorders: are neurodegenerative or neuroimmunological diseases more vulnerable? Ferini-Strambi L, Salsone M. J Neurol. 2021;268:409&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7372546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32696341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. Garrigues E, Janvier P, Kherabi Y, et al. J Infect. 2020;81:0&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post COVID-19 neurological complications; a meta-analysis. Ahmed JO, Ahmad SA, Hassan MN, et al. Ann Med Surg (Lond) 2022;76:103440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8891214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35261766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236&#x2009;379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastrointestinal sequelae 90 days after discharge for COVID-19. Weng J, Li Y, Li J, et al. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;6:344&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7943402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33711290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The prevalence of gastrointestinal symptoms, abnormal liver function, digestive system disease and liver disease in COVID-19 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Dong ZY, Xiang BJ, Jiang M, Sun MJ, Dai C. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2021;55:67&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7713642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33116063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 gastrointestinal manifestations: a systematic review. Silva FA, Brito BB, Santos ML, et al. Rev Soc Bras Med Trop. 2020;53:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7723378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33263693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manifestations and prognosis of gastrointestinal and liver involvement in patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Mao R, Qiu Y, He JS, et al. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;5:667&#x2013;678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7217643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32405603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastrointestinal post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Meringer H, Mehandru S. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;19:345&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8981882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35383321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diabetic ketoacidosis precipitated by Covid-19 in a patient with newly diagnosed diabetes mellitus. Chee YJ, Ng SJ, Yeoh E. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2020;164:108166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32339533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>New-onset diabetes in Covid-19. Rubino F, Amiel SA, Zimmet P, et al. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:789&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7304415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence and impact of diabetes among people infected with SARS-CoV-2. Fadini GP, Morieri ML, Longato E, Avogaro A. J Endocrinol Invest. 2020;43:867&#x2013;869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7103097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32222956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can SARS-CoV-2 virus use multiple receptors to enter host cells? Gadanec LK, McSweeney KR, Qaradakhi T, Ali B, Zulli A, Apostolopoulos V. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7863934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33498183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical Olfactory Working Group Consensus Statement on the Treatment of Post Infectious Olfactory Dysfunction. Addison AB, Wong B, Ahmed T. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2021;10:91&#x2013;674900004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Position paper on olfactory dysfunction. Hummel T, Whitcroft KL, Andrews P, et al. Rhinol Suppl. 2017;54:1&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29528615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potential pathogenesis of ageusia and anosmia in COVID-19 patients. Vaira LA, Salzano G, Fois AG, Piombino P, De Riu G. Int Forum Allergy Rhinol. 2020;10:1103&#x2013;1104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32342636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treatment recommendations for persistent smell and taste dysfunction following COVID-19-the coming deluge. Levy JM. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2020;146:733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7775865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32614399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taste dysfunction and long COVID-19. Srinivasan M. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2021;11:716563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8317431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34336725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Human taste cells express ACE2: a portal for SARS-CoV-2 infection (Preprint) Doyle ME, Appleton A, Liu QR, Yao Q, Mazucanti CH, Egan JM. bioRxiv. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8179718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34102107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonadal dysfunction in systemic diseases. Karagiannis A, Harsoulis F. http://10.1530/eje.1.01886 pmid:15817904. Eur J Endocrinol. 2005;152:501&#x2013;513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menstrual changes after COVID-19 vaccination and/or SARS-CoV-2 infection and their demographic, mood, and lifestyle determinants in Arab women of childbearing age, 2021. Amer AA, Amer SA, Alrufaidi KM, et al. Front Reprod Health. 2022;4:927211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36303671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Immune responses in the human female reproductive tract. Monin L, Whettlock EM, Male V. Immunology. 2020;160:106&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7218661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31630394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term cognitive impairment after acute respiratory distress syndrome: a review of clinical impact and pathophysiological mechanisms. Sasannejad C, Ely EW, Lahiri S. Crit Care. 2019;23:352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6852966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31718695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Co-infections: potentially lethal and unexplored in COVID-19. Cox MJ, Loman N, Bogaert D, O'Grady J. Lancet Microbe. 2020;1:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32835323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and kidney diseases: what do we know? Copur S, Berkkan M, Basile C, Tuttle K, Kanbay M. J Nephrol. 2022;35:795&#x2013;805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8924729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35294747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Carvalho-Schneider C, Laurent E, Lemaignen A, et al. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:258&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>As their numbers grow, COVID-19 "long haulers" stump experts. Rubin R. JAMA. 2020;324:1381&#x2013;1383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32965460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-Covid syndrome: Incidence, clinical spectrum, and challenges for primary healthcare professionals. Pavli A, Theodoridou M, Maltezou HC. Arch Med Res. 2021;52:575&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8093949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33962805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 and its sequelae: a platform for optimal patient care, discovery and training. Becker RC. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2021;51:587&#x2013;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7838017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33501596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of 99 cases of 2019 novel coronavirus pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a descriptive study. Chen N, Zhou M, Dong X, et al. Lancet. 2020;395:507&#x2013;513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7135076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32007143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psychophysical evaluation of chemosensory functions 5&#xa0;weeks after olfactory loss due to COVID-19: a prospective cohort study on 72 patients. Le Bon SD, Pisarski N, Verbeke J, et al. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2021;278:101&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7402072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32754871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID or Post-COVID Conditions.  [
Nov;
2023 
]. 2023. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of coagulation function by rotation thromboelastometry in critically ill patients with severe COVID-19 pneumonia. Pavoni V, Gianesello L, Pazzi M, Stera C, Meconi T, Frigieri FC. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2020;50:281&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32394236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preoperative risk assessment--from routine tests to individualized investigation. B&#xf6;hmer AB, Wappler F, Zwissler B. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2014;111:437&#x2013;445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4095591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25008311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical and immunological assessment of asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infections. Long QX, Tang XJ, Shi QL, et al. Nat Med. 2020;26:1200&#x2013;1204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32555424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emergency Use ICD Codes for COVID-19 Disease Outbreak.  [
Sep;
2023 
]. 2024. https://www.who.int/standards/classifications/classification-of-diseases/emergency-use-icd-codes-for-covid-19-disease-outbreak https://www.who.int/standards/classifications/classification-of-diseases/emergency-use-icd-codes-for-covid-19-disease-outbreak</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A'Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. BMJ. 2020;370:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. Nature. 2021;594:259&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long Covid-19: proposed primary care clinical guidelines for diagnosis and disease management. Sis&#xf3;-Almirall A, Brito-Zer&#xf3;n P, Conangla Ferr&#xed;n L, et al. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:4350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33923972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A multidisciplinary NHS Covid-19 service to manage post-COVID-19 syndrome in the community. Parkin A, Davison J, Tarrant R, et al. J Prim Care Community Health. 2021;12:21501327211010994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8064663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33880955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Johns Hopkins post-acute COVID-19 team (PACT): a multidisciplinary, collaborative, ambulatory framework supporting COVID-19 survivors. Brigham E, O'Toole J, Kim SY, et al. Am J Med. 2021;134:462&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7801819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33444589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapid design and implementation of post-COVID-19 clinics. Santhosh L, Block B, Kim SY, et al. Chest. 2021;160:671&#x2013;677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8010340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33811910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An integrated multidisciplinary model of COVID-19 recovery care. O'Brien H, Tracey MJ, Ottewill C, et al. Ir J Med Sci. 2021;190:461&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7475726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32894436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early experiences of rehabilitation for individuals post-COVID to improve fatigue, breathlessness exercise capacity and cognition - A cohort study. Daynes E, Gerlis C, Chaplin E, Gardiner N, Singh SJ. Chron Respir Dis. 2021;18:14799731211015691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8114752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33957805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chronic fatigue syndrome in the emergency department. Timbol CR, Baraniuk JN. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33957805/ Open Access Emerg Med. 2019;11:15&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6333158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30666170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Single-cell transcriptome analysis of the novel coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) associated gene ACE2 expression in normal and non-obstructive azoospermia (NOA) human male testes. Liu X, Chen Y, Tang W, et al. Sci China Life Sci. 2020;63:1006&#x2013;1015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32361911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overview of COVID-19 Vaccines.  [
Oct;
2023 
]. 2024. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/different-vaccines/overview-COVID-19-vaccines.html https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/different-vaccines/overview-COVID-19-vaccines.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, et al. J Med Virol. 2021;93:1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>