<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37924708</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2352-3964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>98</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>EBioMedicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>EBioMedicine</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Probing long COVID through a proteomic lens: a comprehensive two-year longitudinal cohort study of hospitalised survivors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>104851</StartPage><MedlinePgn>104851</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">104851</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ebiom.2023.104851</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2352-3964(23)00417-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">As a debilitating condition that can impact a whole spectrum of people and involve multi-organ systems, long COVID has aroused the most attention than ever. However, mechanisms of long COVID are not clearly understood, and underlying biomarkers that can affect the long-term consequences of COVID-19 are paramount to be identified.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Participants for the current study were from a cohort study of COVID-19 survivors discharged from hospital between Jan 7, and May 29, 2020. We profiled the proteomic of plasma samples from hospitalised COVID-19 survivors at 6-month, 1-year, and 2-year after symptom onset and age and sex matched healthy controls. Fold-change of &gt;2 or &lt;0.5, and false-discovery rate adjusted P value of 0.05 were used to filter differentially expressed proteins (DEPs). In-genuity pathway analysis was performed to explore the down-stream effects in the dataset of significantly up- or down-regulated proteins. Proteins were integrated with long-term consequences of COVID-19 survivors to explore potential biomarkers of long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The proteomic of 709 plasma samples from 181 COVID-19 survivors and 181 matched healthy controls was profiled. In both COVID-19 and control group, 114 (63%) were male. The results indicated four major recovery modes of biological processes. Pathways related to cell-matrix interactions and cytoskeletal remodeling and hypertrophic cardiomyopathy and dilated cardiomyopathy pathways recovered relatively earlier which was before 1-year after infection. Majority of immune response pathways, complement and coagulation cascade, and cholesterol metabolism returned to similar status of matched healthy controls later but before 2-year after infection. Fc receptor signaling pathway still did not return to status similar to healthy controls at 2-year follow-up. Pathways related to neuron generation and differentiation showed persistent suppression across 2-year after infection. Among 98 DEPs from the above pathways, evidence was found for association of 11 proteins with lung function recovery, with the associations consistent at two consecutive or all three follow-ups. These proteins were mainly enriched in complement and coagulation (COMP, PLG, SERPINE1, SRGN, COL1A1, FLNA, and APOE) and hypertrophic/dilated cardiomyopathy (TPM2, TPM1, and AGT) pathways. Two DEPs (APOA4 and LRP1) involved in both neuron and cholesterol pathways showed associations with smell disorder.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The study findings provided molecular insights into potential mechanism of long COVID, and put forward biomarkers for more precise intervention to reduce burden of long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">National Natural Science Foundation of China; Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences (CAMS) Innovation Fund for Medical Sciences; Clinical Research Operating Fund of Central High Level Hospitals; the Talent Program of the Chinese Academy of Medical Science; Training Program of the Big Science Strategy Plan; Ministry of Science and Technology of the People's Republic of China; New Cornerstone Science Foundation; Peking Union Medical College Education Foundation; Research Funds from Health@InnoHK Program.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoying</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine; State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity; National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases; Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences; Department of Clinical Research and Data Management, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Beijing, PR China; Changping Laboratory, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Siyuan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Complex Severe and Rare Diseases, Clinical Research Institute, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Science &amp; Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Wanying</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine; State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity; National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases; Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences; Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Caihong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuhan Jinyintan Hospital, Tongji Medical College of Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, Hubei Province, PR China; Wuhan Research Center for Communicable Disease Diagnosis and Treatment, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Wuhan, Hubei Province, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Respiratory Disease Pathogenomics, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, PR China; NHC Key Laboratory of Systems Biology of Pathogens and Christophe Merieux Laboratory, Institute of Pathogen Biology, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zai</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changping Laboratory, Beijing, PR China; Institute of Clinical Medical Sciences, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Haibo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changping Laboratory, Beijing, PR China; National Center for Respiratory Medicine; State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity; National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases; Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences; Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Complex Severe and Rare Diseases, Clinical Research Institute, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Science &amp; Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, PR China; Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Capital Medical University, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Yuhan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foreseen Biotechnology, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Weijian</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foreseen Biotechnology, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changping Laboratory, Beijing, PR China; State Key Laboratory of Complex Severe and Rare Diseases, Clinical Research Institute, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Science &amp; Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Complex Severe and Rare Diseases, Clinical Research Institute, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Science &amp; Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, PR China; Department of Infectious Disease, The Affiliated Yantai Yuhuangding Hospital of Qingdao University, Yantai, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yeming</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changping Laboratory, Beijing, PR China; State Key Laboratory of Complex Severe and Rare Diseases, Clinical Research Institute, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Science &amp; Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Lixue</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, Beijing Hospital, National Center of Gerontology, Institute of Geriatric Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chinese Academy of Medical Science (CAMS) Oxford Institute (COI), University of Oxford, Oxford, UK; MRC Human Immunology Unit, MRC Weatherall Institute of Molecular Medicine, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Dingyu</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuhan Jinyintan Hospital, Tongji Medical College of Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, Hubei Province, PR China; Wuhan Research Center for Communicable Disease Diagnosis and Treatment, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Wuhan, Hubei Province, PR China; Hubei Clinical Research Center for Infectious Diseases, Wuhan, Hubei Province, PR China. Electronic address: 1813886398@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Catherine C L</ForeName><Initials>CCL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Complex Severe and Rare Diseases, Clinical Research Institute, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Science &amp; Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, PR China; Tsinghua University-Peking University Joint Center for Life Sciences, Beijing, PR China. Electronic address: catclw321@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changping Laboratory, Beijing, PR China; National Center for Respiratory Medicine; State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity; National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases; Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences; Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Beijing, PR China; Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Capital Medical University, Beijing, PR China; Tsinghua University-Peking University Joint Center for Life Sciences, Beijing, PR China. Electronic address: caobin_ben@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>EBioMedicine</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101647039</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2352-3964</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>97C5T2UQ7J</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002784">Cholesterol</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002311" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiomyopathy, Dilated</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040901" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteomics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017741" MajorTopicYN="N">Survivors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002784" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholesterol</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lung function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Proteomic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery modes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests We declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37924708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10660018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2023.104851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2352-3964(23)00417-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization WHO Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) dashboard. https://covid19.who.int/table</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H.E., McCorkell L., Vogel J.M., Topol E.J. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H., Raza S., Nowell J., Young M., Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine R.L. Addressing the long-term effects of COVID-19. JAMA. 2022;328(9):823&#x2013;824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35921084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S.J., Baldwin M.M., Daynes E., et al. Respiratory sequelae of COVID-19: pulmonary and extrapulmonary origins, and approaches to clinical care and rehabilitation. Lancet Respir Med. 2023;11(8):709&#x2013;725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10198676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37216955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C., Huang L., Wang Y., et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2023;401(10393):e21&#x2013;e33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10258565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37321233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L., Yao Q., Gu X., et al. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398(10302):747&#x2013;758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L., Li X., Gu X., et al. Health outcomes in people 2 years after surviving hospitalisation with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10(9):863&#x2013;876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9094732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35568052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Burden of Disease Long C.C., Wulf Hanson S., Abbafati C., et al. Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA. 2022;328(16):1604&#x2013;1615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T., Hittle M., Goodman S.N. Assessment of the frequency and variety of persistent symptoms among patients with COVID-19: a systematic review. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8155823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34037731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almas T., Malik J., Alsubai A.K., et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and its prolonged effects: an updated systematic review. Ann Med Surg (Lond) 2022;80</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9197790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35721785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu X., Huang L., Cui D., et al. Association of acute kidney injury with 1-year outcome of kidney function in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a cohort study. eBioMedicine. 2022;76</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8776508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35074630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B., Mohn K.G., Brokstad K.A., et al. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med. 2021;27(9):1607&#x2013;1613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramakrishnan R.K., Kashour T., Hamid Q., Halwani R., Tleyjeh I.M. Unraveling the mystery surrounding post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8278217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34276671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao X.H., He Z.C., Li T.Y., et al. Pathological evidence for residual SARS-CoV-2 in pulmonary tissues of a ready-for-discharge patient. Cell Res. 2020;30(6):541&#x2013;543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7186763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32346074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong S.J., Halim A., Halim M., et al. Inflammatory and vascular biomarkers in post-COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of over 20 biomarkers. Rev Med Virol. 2023;33(2):e2424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36708022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y., Yuan D., Chen D.G., et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185(5):881&#x2013;895.e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayakumar B., Boustani K., Ogger P.P., et al. Immuno-proteomic profiling reveals aberrant immune cell regulation in the airways of individuals with ongoing post-COVID-19 respiratory disease. Immunity. 2022;55(3):542&#x2013;556.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8789571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35151371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Yao H., Zhang N., et al. Proteomic analysis identifies prolonged disturbances in pathways related to cholesterol metabolism and myocardium function in the COVID-19 recovery stage. J&#xa0;Proteome Res. 2021;20(7):3463&#x2013;3474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34080435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Zhang N., Zhang J., et al. Immune response pattern across the asymptomatic, symptomatic and convalescent periods of COVID-19. Biochim Biophys Acta Proteins Proteom. 2021;1870(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8580567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34774760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovarik J.J., Bileck A., Hagn G., et al. A&#xa0;multi-omics based anti-inflammatory immune signature characterizes long COVID-19 syndrome. iScience. 2023;26(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9719844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36507225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C., Huang L., Wang Y., et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahler D.A., Wells C.K. Evaluation of clinical methods for rating dyspnea. Chest. 1988;93(3):580&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3342669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herdman M., Gudex C., Lloyd A., et al. Development and preliminary testing of the new five-level version of EQ-5D (EQ-5D-5L) Qual Life Res. 2011;20(10):1727&#x2013;1736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3220807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21479777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabin R., de Charro F. EQ-5D: a measure of health status from the EuroQol Group. Ann Med. 2001;33(5):337&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11491192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie W., Wu Y., Wang W., et al. A&#xa0;longitudinal study of carotid plaque and risk of ischemic cardiovascular disease in the Chinese population. J&#xa0;Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2011;24(7):729&#x2013;737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21440416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi B., Sudry T., Flaks-Manov N., et al. Long covid outcomes at one year after mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: nationwide cohort study. BMJ. 2023;380</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9832503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36631153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballering A.V., van Zon S.K.R., olde Hartman T.C., Rosmalen J.G.M. Persistence of somatic symptoms after COVID-19 in The Netherlands: an observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022;400(10350):452&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9352274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35934007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standardization of spirometry, 1994 update. American thoracic society. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1995;152(3):1107&#x2013;1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7663792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian W., Zhang N., Jin R., et al. Immune suppression in the early stage of COVID-19 disease. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):5859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7673112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33203833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enright P.L., Sherrill D.L. Reference equations for the six-minute walk in healthy adults. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1998;158(5 Pt 1):1384&#x2013;1387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9817683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefranc M.P. Immunoglobulin and T Cell receptor genes: IMGT(&#xae;) and the birth and rise of immunoinformatics. Front Immunol. 2014;5:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3913909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24600447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stros M., Polanska E.V., Hlavacova T., Skladal P. Progress in assays of HMGB1 levels in human plasma-the potential prognostic value in COVID-19. Biomolecules. 2022;12(4):544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9031208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35454134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wulandari S., Hartono, Wibawa T. The role of HMGB1 in COVID-19-induced cytokine storm and its potential therapeutic targets: a review. Immunology. 2023;169(2):117&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9880760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36571562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afzali B., Noris M., Lambrecht B.N., Kemper C. The state of complement in COVID-19. Nat Rev Immunol. 2022;22(2):77&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8672651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34912108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georg P., Astaburuaga-Garcia R., Bonaguro L., et al. Complement activation induces excessive T cell cytotoxicity in severe COVID-19. Cell. 2022;185(3):493&#x2013;512.e25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8712270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35032429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali Y.M., Ferrari M., Lynch N.J., et al. Lectin pathway mediates complement activation by SARS-CoV-2 proteins. Front Immunol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8287855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34290717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holter J.C., Pischke S.E., de Boer E., et al. Systemic complement activation is associated with respiratory failure in COVID-19 hospitalized patients. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2020;117(40):25018&#x2013;25025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7547220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32943538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J., Gerber G.F., Chen H., et al. Complement dysregulation is associated with severe COVID-19 illness. Haematologica. 2022;107(5):1095&#x2013;1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9052917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34289657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conway E.M., Mackman N., Warren R.Q., et al. Understanding COVID-19-associated coagulopathy. Nat Rev Immunol. 2022;22(10):639&#x2013;649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9362465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35931818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang S., Tanaka T., Inoue H., et al. IL-6 trans-signaling induces plasminogen activator inhibitor-1 from vascular endothelial cells in cytokine release syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2020;117(36):22351&#x2013;22356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi G., Plebani M., Henry B.M. Thrombocytopenia is associated with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) infections: a meta-analysis. Clin Chim Acta. 2020;506:145&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32178975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen B., Yi X., Sun Y., et al. Proteomic and metabolomic characterization of COVID-19 patient sera. Cell. 2020;182(1):59&#x2013;72.e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7254001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32492406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yatim N., Boussier J., Chocron R., et al. Platelet activation in critically ill COVID-19 patients. Ann Intensive Care. 2021;11(1):113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8286043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monje M., Iwasaki A. The neurobiology of long COVID. Neuron. 2022;110(21):3484&#x2013;3496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9537254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36288726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E., Zhang C., Israelow B., et al. Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 in human and mouse brain. J&#xa0;Exp Med. 2021;218(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T. Neurological infection with SARS-CoV-2 - the story so far. Nat Rev Neurol. 2021;17(2):65&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7789883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33414554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavassolifar M.J., Aghdaei H.A., Sadatpour O., et al. New insights into extracellular and intracellular redox status in COVID-19 patients. Redox Biol. 2023;59</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9715463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36493512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu B., Lei Y., Ren X., et al. SOD1 is a possible predictor of COVID-19 progression as revealed by plasma proteomics. ACS Omega. 2021;6(26):16826&#x2013;16836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8247781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34250342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karki P., Birukova A.A. Microtubules as major regulators of endothelial function: implication for lung injury. Front Physiol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8582326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34777018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya D., Reis R., Volcic M., et al. Actin cytoskeleton remodeling primes RIG-I-like receptor activation. Cell. 2022;185(19):3588&#x2013;3602.e21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9680832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36113429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tschope C., Ammirati E., Bozkurt B., et al. Myocarditis and inflammatory cardiomyopathy: current evidence and future directions. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2021;18(3):169&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7548534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33046850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sette A., Crotty S. Adaptive immunity to SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19. Cell. 2021;184(4):861&#x2013;880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7803150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodin P. Immune determinants of COVID-19 disease presentation and severity. Nat Med. 2021;27(1):28&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33442016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang A., Stacey H.D., D'Agostino M.R., Tugg Y., Marzok A., Miller M.S. Beyond neutralization: Fc-dependent antibody effector functions in SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Rev Immunol. 2023;23(6):381&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9761659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36536068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler E.S., Gilchuk P., Yu J., et al. Human neutralizing antibodies against SARS-CoV-2 require intact Fc effector functions for optimal therapeutic protection. Cell. 2021;184(7):1804&#x2013;1820.e16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7879018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33691139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suryadevara N., Shrihari S., Gilchuk P., et al. Neutralizing and protective human monoclonal antibodies recognizing the N-terminal domain of the SARS-CoV-2 spike protein. Cell. 2021;184(9):2316&#x2013;2331.e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7962591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33773105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begin P., Callum J., Jamula E., et al. Convalescent plasma for hospitalized patients with COVID-19: an open-label, randomized controlled trial. Nat Med. 2021;27(11):2012&#x2013;2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8604729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34504336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zohar T., Loos C., Fischinger S., et al. Compromised humoral functional evolution tracks with SARS-CoV-2 mortality. Cell. 2020;183(6):1508&#x2013;1519.e12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7608014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33207184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faridl M., Mellyani K., Khoirunnisa K., et al. RNA sequence analysis of nasopharyngeal swabs from asymptomatic and mildly symptomatic patients with COVID-19. Int J Infect Dis. 2022;122:449&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9233886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35760384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R., Xiao H., Guo R., Li Y., Shen B. The role of C5a in acute lung injury induced by highly pathogenic viral infections. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2015;4(5):e28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4451266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26060601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S., Zhao G., Liu C., et al. Inhibition of complement activation alleviates acute lung injury induced by highly pathogenic avian influenza H5N1 virus infection. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol. 2013;49(2):221&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23526211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Li X., Huang L., et al. Lung-function trajectories in COVID-19 survivors after discharge: a two-year longitudinal cohort study. eClinicalMedicine. 2022;54</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9514976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36188433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig A.M., Sanders E.C. Potential neuroinvasive pathways of SARS-CoV-2: deciphering the spectrum of neurological deficit seen in coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19) J&#xa0;Med Virol. 2020;92(10):1845&#x2013;1857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7300748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32492193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M., Yoo S.J., Clijsters M., et al. Visualizing in deceased COVID-19 patients how SARS-CoV-2 attacks the respiratory and olfactory mucosae but spares the olfactory bulb. Cell. 2021;184(24):5932&#x2013;5949.e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8564600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34798069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrini L., Albecka A., Mallery D.L., et al. SARS-CoV-2 infects the brain choroid plexus and disrupts the blood-CSF barrier in human brain organoids. Cell Stem Cell. 2020;27(6):951&#x2013;961.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7553118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33113348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M., Clijsters M., Choi S., et al. Anatomical barriers against SARS-CoV-2 neuroinvasion at vulnerable interfaces visualized in deceased COVID-19 patients. Neuron. 2022;110(23):3919&#x2013;3935.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9647025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36446381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Castaneda A., Lu P., Geraghty A.C., et al. Mild respiratory COVID can cause multi-lineage neural cell and myelin dysregulation. Cell. 2022;185(14):2452&#x2013;2468.e16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9189143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35768006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginhoux F., Greter M., Leboeuf M., et al. Fate mapping analysis reveals that adult microglia derive from primitive macrophages. Science. 2010;330(6005):841&#x2013;845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3719181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20966214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villeda S.A., Luo J., Mosher K.I., et al. The ageing systemic milieu negatively regulates neurogenesis and cognitive function. Nature. 2011;477(7362):90&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21886162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E., Vlok M., Venter C., et al. Persistent clotting protein pathology in long COVID/Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) is accompanied by increased levels of antiplasmin. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2021;20(1):172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8381139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34425843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruger A., Vlok M., Turner S., et al. Proteomics of fibrin amyloid microclots in long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) shows many entrapped pro-inflammatory molecules that may also contribute to a failed fibrinolytic system. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9491257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36131342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>