<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37101566</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2691-3704</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JACS Au</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JACS Au</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Well-Defined Heparin Mimetics Can Inhibit Binding of the Trimeric Spike of SARS-CoV-2 in a Length-Dependent Manner.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1185</StartPage><EndPage>1195</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1185-1195</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/jacsau.3c00042</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The emergence of new SARS-CoV-2 variants and the dangers of long-covid necessitate the development of broad-acting therapeutics that can reduce viral burden. SARS-CoV-2 employs heparan sulfate (HS) as an initial cellular attachment factor, and therefore, there is interest in developing heparin as a therapeutic for SARS-CoV-2. Its use is, however, complicated by structural heterogeneity and the risk of causing bleeding and thrombocytopenia. Here, we describe the preparation of well-defined heparin mimetics by a controlled head-to-tail assembly of HS oligosaccharides having an alkyne or azide moiety by copper-catalyzed azide-alkyne cycloaddition (CuAAC). Alkyne- and azide-containing sulfated oligosaccharides were prepared from a common precursor by modifying an anomeric linker with 4-pentynoic acid and by enzymatic extension with an <i>N</i>-acetyl-glucosamine having an azide moiety at C-6 (GlcNAc6N<sub>3</sub>), respectively, followed by CuAAC. The process of enzymatic extension with GlcNAc6N<sub>3</sub> followed by CuAAC with the desired alkyne-containing oligosaccharides could be repeated to give compounds composed of 20 and 27 monosaccharides, respectively. The heparin mimetics could inhibit the binding of the SARS-CoV-2 spike or RBD to immobilized heparin or to Vero E6 cells. The inhibitory potency increased with increasing chain length, and a compound composed of four sulfated hexasaccharides linked by triazoles had a similar potency as unfractionated heparin. Sequence analysis and HS microarray binding studies with a wide range of RBDs of variants of concern indicate that they have maintained HS-binding capabilities and selectivities. The heparin mimetics exhibit no or reduced binding to antithrombin-III and platelet factor 4, respectively, which are associated with side effects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Lifeng</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4735-954X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Biology and Drug Discovery, Utrecht Institute for Pharmaceutical Sciences, Utrecht University, 3584 CG Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chopra</LastName><ForeName>Pradeep</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6003-4574</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Complex Carbohydrate Research Center, The University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia 30602, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomris</LastName><ForeName>Ilhan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Biology and Drug Discovery, Utrecht Institute for Pharmaceutical Sciences, Utrecht University, 3584 CG Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Woude</LastName><ForeName>Roosmarijn</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Biology and Drug Discovery, Utrecht Institute for Pharmaceutical Sciences, Utrecht University, 3584 CG Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0310-5946</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Complex Carbohydrate Research Center, The University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia 30602, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Vries</LastName><ForeName>Robert P</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1586-4464</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Biology and Drug Discovery, Utrecht Institute for Pharmaceutical Sciences, Utrecht University, 3584 CG Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boons</LastName><ForeName>Geert-Jan</ForeName><Initials>GJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3111-5954</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Biology and Drug Discovery, Utrecht Institute for Pharmaceutical Sciences, Utrecht University, 3584 CG Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Complex Carbohydrate Research Center, The University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia 30602, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bijvoet Center for Biomolecular Research, Utrecht University, 3584 CG Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemistry Department, The University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia 30602, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JACS Au</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101775714</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2691-3704</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing financial interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37101566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10089289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacsau.3c00042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cascella M.; Rajnik M.; Aleem A.; Dulebohn S. C.; Di Napoli R.. Features, evaluation, and treatment of coronavirus (COVID-19); StatPearls Publishing LLC.: Treasure Island (FL), 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32150360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang J.; Wan Y.; Luo C.; Ye G.; Geng Q.; Auerbach A.; Li F. Cell entry mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2020, 117, 11727&#x2013;11734. 10.1073/pnas.2003138117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2003138117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7260975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32376634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walls A. C.; Park Y. J.; Tortorici M. A.; Wall A.; McGuire A. T.; Veesler D. Structure, function, and antigenicity of the SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein. Cell 2020, 181, 281&#x2013;292. 10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32155444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clausen T. M.; Sandoval D. R.; Spliid C. B.; Pihl J.; Perrett H. R.; Painter C. D.; Narayanan A.; Majowicz S. A.; Kwong E. M.; McVicar R. N.; Thacker B. E.; Glass C. A.; Yang Z.; Torres J. L.; Golden G. J.; Bartels P. L.; Porell R. N.; Garretson A. F.; Laubach L.; Feldman J.; Yin X.; Pu Y.; Hauser B. M.; Caradonna T. M.; Kellman B. P.; Martino C.; Gordts P.; Chanda S. K.; Schmidt A. G.; Godula K.; Leibel S. L.; Jose J.; Corbett K. D.; Ward A. B.; Carlin A. F.; Esko J. D. SARS-CoV-2 infection depends on cellular heparan sulfate and ACE2. Cell 2020, 183, 1043&#x2013;1057. 10.1016/j.cell.2020.09.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.09.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7489987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32970989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S. Y.; Jin W.; Sood A.; Montgomery D. W.; Grant O. C.; Fuster M. M.; Fu L.; Dordick J. S.; Woods R. J.; Zhang F.; Linhardt R. J. Characterization of heparin and severe acute respiratory syndrome-related coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) spike glycoprotein binding interactions. Antiviral Res. 2020, 181, 10487310.1016/j.antiviral.2020.104873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.antiviral.2020.104873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7347485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32653452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L.; Chopra P.; Li X.; Bouwman K. M.; Tompkins S. M.; Wolfert M. A.; de Vries R. P.; Boons G. J. Heparan sulfate proteoglycans as attachment factor for SARS-CoV-2. ACS Cent. Sci. 2021, 7, 1009&#x2013;1018. 10.1021/acscentsci.1c00010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acscentsci.1c00010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8227597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34235261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mycroft-West C. J.; Su D.; Pagani I.; Rudd T. R.; Elli S.; Gandhi N. S.; Guimond S. E.; Miller G. J.; Meneghetti M. C. Z.; Nader H. B.; Li Y.; Nunes Q. M.; Procter P.; Mancini N.; Clementi M.; Bisio A.; Forsyth N. R.; Ferro V.; Turnbull J. E.; Guerrini M.; Fernig D. G.; Vicenzi E.; Yates E. A.; Lima M. A.; Skidmore M. A. Heparin inhibits cellular invasion by SARS-CoV-2: Structural dependence of the interaction of the spike S1 receptor-binding domain with heparin. Thromb. Haemost. 2020, 120, 1700&#x2013;1715. 10.1055/s-0040-1721319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0040-1721319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7869224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33368089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chittum J. E.; Sankaranarayanan N. V.; O&#x2019;Hara C. P.; Desai U. R. On the selectivity of heparan sulfate recognition by SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein. ACS Med. Chem. Lett. 2021, 12, 1710&#x2013;1717. 10.1021/acsmedchemlett.1c00343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsmedchemlett.1c00343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8525342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34786180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuurs Z. P.; Hammond E.; Elli S.; Rudd T. R.; Mycroft-West C. J.; Lima M. A.; Skidmore M. A.; Karlsson R.; Chen Y. H.; Bagdonaite I.; Yang Z.; Ahmed Y. A.; Richard D. J.; Turnbull J.; Ferro V.; Coombe D. R.; Gandhi N. S. Evidence of a putative glycosaminoglycan binding site on the glycosylated SARS-CoV-2 spike protein N-terminal domain. Comput. Struct. Biotechnol. J. 2021, 19, 2806&#x2013;2818. 10.1016/j.csbj.2021.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csbj.2021.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8093007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33968333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tandon R.; Sharp J. S.; Zhang F.; Pomin V. H.; Ashpole N. M.; Mitra D.; McCandless M. G.; Jin W.; Liu H.; Sharma P.; Linhardt R. J. Effective inhibition of SARS-CoV-2 entry by heparin and enoxaparin derivatives. J. Virol. 2021, 95, e01987&#x2013;20. 10.1128/JVI.01987-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.01987-20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7925120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33173010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kearns F. L.; Sandoval D. R.; Casalino L.; Clausen T. M.; Rosenfeld M. A.; Spliid C. B.; Amaro R. E.; Esko J. D. Spike-heparan sulfate interactions in SARS-CoV-2 infection. Curr. Opin. Struct. Biol. 2022, 76, 10243910.1016/j.sbi.2022.102439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sbi.2022.102439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9257145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35926454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paiardi G.; Richter S.; Oreste P.; Urbinati C.; Rusnati M.; Wade R. C. The binding of heparin to spike glycoprotein inhibits SARS-CoV-2 infection by three mechanisms. J. Biol. Chem. 2022, 298, 10150710.1016/j.jbc.2021.101507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbc.2021.101507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8683219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34929169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X.; Bie L.; Gao J. Structural insights into the cofactor role of heparin/heparan sulfate in binding between the SARS-CoV-2 spike protein and host angiotensin-converting enzyme II. J. Chem. Inf. Model. 2022, 62, 656&#x2013;667. 10.1021/acs.jcim.1c01484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jcim.1c01484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35060381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Partridge L. J.; Urwin L.; Nicklin M. J. H.; James D. C.; Green L. R.; Monk P. N. ACE2-independent interaction of SARS-CoV-2 spike protein with human epithelial cells is inhibited by unfractionated heparin. Cells 2021, 10, 1419.10.3390/cells10061419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells10061419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8229176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34200372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon P. S.; Oh H.; Kwon S. J.; Jin W.; Zhang F.; Fraser K.; Hong J. J.; Linhardt R. J.; Dordick J. S. Sulfated polysaccharides effectively inhibit SARS-CoV-2 in vitro. Cell Discovery 2020, 6, 5010.1038/s41421-020-00192-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41421-020-00192-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7378085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32714563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guimond S. E.; Mycroft-West C. J.; Gandhi N. S.; Tree J. A.; Le T. T.; Spalluto C. M.; Humbert M. V.; Buttigieg K. R.; Coombes N.; Elmore M. J.; Wand M.; Nystrom K.; Said J.; Setoh Y. X.; Amarilla A. A.; Modhiran N.; Sng J. D. J.; Chhabra M.; Young P. R.; Rawle D. J.; Lima M. A.; Yates E. A.; Karlsson R.; Miller R. L.; Chen Y. H.; Bagdonaite I.; Yang Z.; Stewart J.; Nguyen D.; Laidlaw S.; Hammond E.; Dredge K.; Wilkinson T. M. A.; Watterson D.; Khromykh A. A.; Suhrbier A.; Carroll M. W.; Trybala E.; Bergstrom T.; Ferro V.; Skidmore M. A.; Turnbull J. E. Synthetic heparan sulfate mimetic pixatimod (PG545) potently inhibits SARS-CoV-2 by disrupting the spike-ACE2 interaction. ACS Cent. Sci. 2022, 8, 527&#x2013;545. 10.1021/acscentsci.1c01293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acscentsci.1c01293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9136977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35647275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arungundram S.; Al-Mafraji K.; Asong J.; Leach F. E. III; Amster I. J.; Venot A.; Turnbull J. E.; Boons G. J. Modular synthesis of heparan sulfate oligosaccharides for structure-activity relationship studies. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2009, 131, 17394&#x2013;17405. 10.1021/ja907358k.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja907358k</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2820250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19904943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong C.; Venot A.; Li X.; Lu W.; Xiao W.; Wilkes J. L.; Salanga C. L.; Handel T. M.; Wang L.; Wolfert M. A.; Boons G. J. Heparan sulfate microarray reveals that heparan sulfate-protein binding exhibits different ligand requirements. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2017, 139, 9534&#x2013;9543. 10.1021/jacs.7b01399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.7b01399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5588662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28651046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L.; Chopra P.; Boons G. J. Modular synthesis of heparan sulfate oligosaccharides having N-acetyl and N-sulfate moieties. J. Org. Chem. 2020, 85, 16082&#x2013;16098. 10.1021/acs.joc.0c01881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.joc.0c01881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33334107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra P.; Joshi A.; Wu J.; Lu W.; Yadavalli T.; Wolfert M. A.; Shukla D.; Zaia J.; Boons G. J. 3-O-Sulfation of heparan sulfate modulates protein binding and lyase degradation. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 2021, 118, e201293511810.1073/pnas.2012935118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2012935118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7826381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33441484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber M.; Bujotzek A.; Haag R. Quantifying the rebinding effect in multivalent chemical ligand-receptor systems. J. Chem. Phys. 2012, 137, 05411110.1063/1.4739501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.4739501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22894336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong V.; Presolski S. I.; Ma C.; Finn M. G. Analysis and optimization of copper-catalyzed azide-alkyne cycloaddition for bioconjugation. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2009, 48, 9879&#x2013;9883. 10.1002/anie.200905087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.200905087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3410708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19943299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L.; Chopra P.; Boons G. J. Chemoenzymatic synthesis of heparan sulfate oligosaccharides having a domain structure. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2022, 61, e20221111210.1002/anie.202211112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202211112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9828060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36148891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavaroche A. A. E.; Springer J.; Kooy F.; Boeriu C.; Eggink G. In vitro synthesis of heparosan using recombinant Pasteurella multocida heparosan synthase PmHS2. Appl. Microbiol. Biotechnol. 2010, 85, 1881&#x2013;1891. 10.1007/s00253-009-2214-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00253-009-2214-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2811250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19756580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavaroche A. A.; van den Broek L. A.; Springer J.; Boeriu C.; Eggink G. Analysis of the polymerization initiation and activity of Pasteurella multocida heparosan synthase PmHS2, an enzyme with glycosyltransferase and UDP-sugar hydrolase activity. J. Biol. Chem. 2011, 286, 1777&#x2013;1785. 10.1074/jbc.M110.136754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M110.136754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3023472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21084307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y.; Li Y.; Yu H.; Sugiarto G.; Thon V.; Hwang J.; Ding L.; Hie L.; Chen X. Tailored design and synthesis of heparan sulfate oligosaccharide analogues using sequential one-pot multienzyme systems. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2013, 52, 11852&#x2013;11856. 10.1002/anie.201305667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.201305667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3943747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24038939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amanat F.; Stadlbauer D.; Strohmeier S.; Nguyen T. H. O.; Chromikova V.; McMahon M.; Jiang K.; Arunkumar G. A.; Jurczyszak D.; Polanco J.; Bermudez-Gonzalez M.; Kleiner G.; Aydillo T.; Miorin L.; Fierer D. S.; Lugo L. A.; Kojic E. M.; Stoever J.; Liu S. T. H.; Cunningham-Rundles C.; Felgner P. L.; Moran T.; Garcia-Sastre A.; Caplivski D.; Cheng A. C.; Kedzierska K.; Vapalahti O.; Hepojoki J. M.; Simon V.; Krammer F. A serological assay to detect SARS-CoV-2 seroconversion in humans. Nat. Med. 2020, 26, 1033&#x2013;1036. 10.1038/s41591-020-0913-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-020-0913-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8183627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouwman K. M.; Tomris I.; Turner H. L.; van der Woude R.; Shamorkina T. M.; Bosman G. P.; Rockx B.; Herfst S.; Snijder J.; Haagmans B. L.; Ward A. B.; Boons G. J.; de Vries R. P. Multimerization- and glycosylation-dependent receptor binding of SARS-CoV-2 spike proteins. PLoS Pathog. 2021, 17, e100928210.1371/journal.ppat.1009282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1009282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7895411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33556147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelbach A. L.; Zhang F.; Kwon S. J.; Bates J. T.; Farmer A. P.; Dordick J. S.; Wang C.; Linhardt R. J. Interactions between heparin and SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein RBD from omicron and other variants. Front. Mol. Biosci. 2022, 9, 91288710.3389/fmolb.2022.912887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmolb.2022.912887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9420978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36046608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray E.; Hogwood J.; Mulloy B. In Heparin - A Century of Progress. Handbook of Experimental Pharmacology; 2012/05/09 ed.; Springer: Berlin, Heidelberg, 2012; Vol. 207, p 43&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22566220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjork I.; Olson S. T.; Shore J. D. In Heparin: Chemical and Biological Properties, Clinical Applications; Lane D. A.; Lindahl U., Eds.; CRC Press, Inc.: Boca Raton, FL, 1989, p 229&#x2013;255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F.; McLellan J. S.; Ayala A. M.; Leahy D. J.; Linhardt R. J. Kinetic and structural studies on interactions between heparin or heparan sulfate and proteins of the Hedgehog signaling pathway. Biochemistry 2007, 46, 3933&#x2013;3941. 10.1021/bi6025424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/bi6025424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4135481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17348690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J.; Liu X.; Malhotra A.; Li Q.; Zhang F.; Linhardt R. J. Novel method for measurement of heparin anticoagulant activity using SPR. Anal. Biochem. 2017, 526, 39&#x2013;42. 10.1016/j.ab.2017.03.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ab.2017.03.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5553204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28322799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F.; Datta P.; Dordick J. S.; Linhardt R. J. Evaluating heparin products for heparin-induced thrombocytopenia using surface plasmon resonance. J. Pharm. Sci. 2020, 109, 975&#x2013;980. 10.1016/j.xphs.2019.10.040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xphs.2019.10.040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31705871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochran S.; Li C. P.; Ferro V. A surface plasmon resonance-based solution affinity assay for heparan sulfate-binding proteins. Glycoconj. J. 2009, 26, 577&#x2013;587. 10.1007/s10719-008-9210-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10719-008-9210-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19034645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J.; Kong Y.; Zhang F.; Linhardt R. J. Impact of temperature on heparin and protein interactions. Biochem. Physiol. 2018, 07, 24110.4172/2168-9652.1000241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2168-9652.1000241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6156718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30271699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikhailov D.; Young H. C.; Linhardt R. J.; Mayo K. H. Heparin dodecasaccharide binding to platelet factor-4 and growth-related protein-alpha. Induction of a partially folded state and implications for heparin-induced thrombocytopenia. J. Biol. Chem. 1999, 274, 25317&#x2013;25329. 10.1074/jbc.274.36.25317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.274.36.25317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10464257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hippensteel J. A.; LaRiviere W. B.; Colbert J. F.; Langouet-Astrie C. J.; Schmidt E. P. Heparin as a therapy for COVID-19: current evidence and future possibilities. Am. J. Physiol.: Lung Cell. Mol. Physiol. 2020, 319, L211&#x2013;L217. 10.1152/ajplung.00199.2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajplung.00199.2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7381711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32519894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangiafico M.; Caff A.; Costanzo L. The role of heparin in COVID-19: An update after two years of pandemics. J. Clin. Med. 2022, 11, 3099.10.3390/jcm11113099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm11113099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9180990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35683485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J.; Thorp S. C. Cell surface heparan sulfate and its roles in assisting viral infections. Med. Res. Rev. 2002, 22, 1&#x2013;25. 10.1002/med.1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/med.1026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11746174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Pasquale V.; Quiccione M. S.; Tafuri S.; Avallone L.; Pavone L. M. Heparan sulfate proteoglycans in viral infection and treatment: A special focus on SARS-CoV-2. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2021, 22, 6574.10.3390/ijms22126574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22126574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8235362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34207476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling J.; Li J.; Khan A.; Lundkvist A.; Li J. P. Is heparan sulfate a target for inhibition of RNA virus infection?. Am. J. Physiol.: Cell Physiol. 2022, 322, C605&#x2013;C613. 10.1152/ajpcell.00028.2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00028.2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8977144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35196165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lever R.; Page C. P. Novel drug development opportunities for heparin. Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 2002, 1, 140&#x2013;148. 10.1038/nrd724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrd724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12120095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oduah E. I.; Linhardt R. J.; Sharfstein S. T. Heparin: Past, present, and future. Pharmaceuticals 2016, 9, 38.10.3390/ph9030038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ph9030038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5039491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27384570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh Y. I.; Sheng G. J.; Chang S. K.; Hsieh-Wilson L. C. Tailored glycopolymers as anticoagulant heparin mimetics. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2013, 52, 11796&#x2013;11799. 10.1002/anie.201306968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.201306968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3943734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24123787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J.; Cai C.; Wang L.; Yang C.; Jiang H.; Li M.; Xu D.; Li G.; Li C.; Yu G. Chemoenzymatic synthesis of heparan sulfate mimetic glycopolymers and their interactions with the receptor for advanced glycation end-product. ACS Macro Lett. 2019, 8, 1570&#x2013;1574. 10.1021/acsmacrolett.9b00780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsmacrolett.9b00780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35619400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J.; Liang L.; Yang W.; Ramadan S.; Baryal K.; Huo C. X.; Bernard J. J.; Liu J.; Hsieh-Wilson L.; Zhang F.; Linhardt R. J.; Huang X. Expedient synthesis of a library of heparan sulfate-like &#x201c;head-to-tail&#x201d; linked multimers for structure and activity relationship studies. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2022, 61, e20220973010.1002/anie.202209730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202209730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9675719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36199167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>