<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34765889</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2574-0954</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiovascular endocrinology &amp; metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiovasc Endocrinol Metab</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The microvascular hypothesis underlying neurologic manifestations of long COVID-19 and possible therapeutic strategies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>193</StartPage><EndPage>203</EndPage><MedlinePgn>193-203</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/XCE.0000000000000253</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>With the ongoing distribution of the coronavirus disease (COVID) vaccines, the pandemic of our age is ending, leaving the world to deal with its well-documented aftereffects. Long COVID comprises a variety of symptoms, of which the neurological component prevails. The most permeating theory on the genesis of these symptoms builds upon the development of microvascular dysfunction similar to that seen in numerous vascular diseases such as diabetes. This can occur through the peripheral activation of angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 receptors, or through exacerbations of pro-inflammatory cytokines that can remain in circulation even after the infection diminishes. Several drugs have been identified to act on the neurovascular unit to promote repair, such as gliptins, and others. They also succeeded in improving neurologic outcome in diabetic patients. The repurposing of such drugs for treatment of long COVID-19 can possibly shorten the time to recovery of long COVID-19 syndrome.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Research Accessibility Team (RAT)</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiovasc Endocrinol Metab</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101730894</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2574-0954</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microvascular dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurologic manifestations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurovascular regenerative drugs</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34765889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/XCE.0000000000000253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Zheng Y, Gou X, Pu K, Chen Z, Guo Q, et al. . Prevalence of comorbidities and its effects in patients infected with SARS-CoV-2: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Infect Dis 2020; 94:91&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32173574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu YC, Kuo RL, Shih SR. COVID-19: The first documented coronavirus pandemic in history. Biomed J 2020; 43:328&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7199674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong E, Du H, Gardner L. An interactive web-based dashboard to track COVID-19 in real time. Lancet Infect Dis 2020; 20:533&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32087114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apicella M, Campopiano MC, Mantuano M, Mazoni L, Coppelli A, Del Prato S. COVID-19 in people with diabetes: understanding the reasons for worse outcomes. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2020; 8:782&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7367664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32687793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbdelMassih AF, Kamel A, Mishriky F, Ismail H-A, El Qadi L, Malak L, et al. . Is it infection or rather vascular inflammation ? Game-changer insights and recommendations from patterns of multi-organ involvement and affected subgroups in COVID-19. Cardiovasc Endocrinol Metab 2020; 9:110&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7410022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32803145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali A, Vijayan R. Dynamics of the ACE2-SARS-CoV-2/SARS-CoV spike protein interface reveal unique mechanisms. Sci Rep 2020; 10:14214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7449962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32848162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shovlin CL, Vizcaychipi MP. Vascular inflammation and endothelial injury in SARS-CoV-2 infection: the overlooked regulatory cascades implicated by the ACE2 gene cluster. QJM 2020. [Epub ahead of print]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32777054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hikmet F, M&#xe9;ar L, Edvinsson &#xc5;, Micke P, Uhl&#xe9;n M, Lindskog C. The protein expression profile of ACE2 in human tissues. Mol Syst Biol 2020; 16:e9610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin S, O&#x2019;Connor R, Sivan M. Long COVID and chronic COVID syndromes. J Med Virol 2021; 93:1242&#x2013;1243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33034893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paice JA, Dahlin C, Wholihan D, Mazanec P, Long CO, Thaxton C, Greer K. Palliative care for people with COVID-19-related symptoms. J Hosp Palliat Nurs 2020; 22:421&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32925492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morley JE. COVID-19 &#x2014; the long road to recovery. J Nutr Health Aging 2020; 24:917&#x2013;919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7597432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33155615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker RC. Anticipating the long-term cardiovascular effects of COVID-19. J Thromb Thrombolysis 2020; 50:512&#x2013;524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7467860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32880795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bektas A, Schurman SH, Franceschi C, Ferrucci L. A public health perspective of aging: do hyper-inflammatory syndromes such as COVID-19, SARS, ARDS, cytokine storm syndrome, and post-ICU syndrome accelerate short- and long-term inflammaging? Immun Ageing 2020; 17:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7443812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32849908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM. Deleterious outcomes in Long-Hauler COVID-19: the effects of SARS-CoV-2 on the CNS in chronic COVID syndrome. ACS Chem Neurosci 2020; 11:4017&#x2013;4020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33275404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boss&#xf9; P, Toppi E, Sterbini V, Spalletta G. Implication of aging related chronic neuroinflammation on COVID-19 pandemic. J Pers Med 2020; 10:E102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7563730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32858874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurology TL. The neurological impact of COVID-19. Lancet Neurol 2020; 19:471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7250550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32470408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLean MA, Kamintsky L, Leck ED, Friedman A. The potential role of microvascular pathology in the neurological manifestations of coronavirus infection. Fluids Barriers CNS 2020; 17:55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7481544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32912226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avogaro A, Fadini GP. The effects of dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibition on microvascular diabetes complications. Diabetes Care 2014; 37:2884&#x2013;2894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kytikova OY, Perelman JM, Novgorodtseva TP, Denisenko YK, Kolosov VP, Antonyuk MV, Gvozdenko TA. Peroxisome proliferator-activated receptors as a therapeutic target in asthma. PPAR Res 2020; 2020:8906968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7201810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32395125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SY, Jeng C, Kao SC, Yu JJ, Liu DZ. Improved haemorrheological properties by Ginkgo Biloba extract (Egb 761) in type 2 diabetes mellitus complicated with retinopathy. Clin Nutr 2004; 23:615&#x2013;621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15297098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith B, Kelly C, Deary V. Altered smell and taste: anosmia, parosmia and the impact of long Covid-19. medRxiv Preprint. 2020;2020.11.26.20239152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8462678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34559820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cain WS, Gent JF, Goodspeed RB, Leonard G. Evaluation of olfactory dysfunction in the Connecticut Chemosensory Clinical Research Center. Laryngoscope 1988; 98:83&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3336267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han AY, Mukdad L, Long JL, Lopez IA. Anosmia in COVID-19: mechanisms and significance. Chem Senses 2020; 45:423&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7449368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32556089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampaio Rocha-Filho PA, Voss L. Persistent headache and persistent anosmia associated with COVID-19. Headache 2020; 60:1797&#x2013;1799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7436496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konstantinidis I, Delides A, Tsakiropoulou E, Maragoudakis P, Sapounas S, Tsiodras S. Short-term follow-up of self-isolated COVID-19 patients with smell and taste dysfunction in Greece: two phenotypes of recovery. ORL J Otorhinolaryngol Relat Spec 2020; 82:295&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7649691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33049753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galv&#xe1;n-Tejada CE, Herrera-Garc&#xed;a CF, Godina-Gonz&#xe1;lez S, Villagrana-Ba&#xf1;uelos KE, Amaro JDDL, Herrera-Garc&#xed;a K, et al. . Persistence of covid-19 symptoms after recovery in mexican population. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2020; 17:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7765113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33327641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burges Watson DL, Campbell M, Hopkins C, Smith B, Kelly C, Deary V. Altered smell and taste: anosmia, parosmia and the impact of long Covid-19. medRxiv Preprint. 2020:1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8462678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34559820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menni C, Valdes AM, Freidin MB, Sudre CH, Nguyen LH, Drew DA, et al. . Real-time tracking of self-reported symptoms to predict potential COVID-19. Nat Med 2020; 26:1037&#x2013;1040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7751267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32393804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Melo GD, Lazarini F, Levallois S, Hautefort C, Michel V, Larrous F, et al. . COVID-19-associated olfactory dysfunction reveals SARS-CoV-2 neuroinvasion and persistence in the olfactory system. bioRxiv Preprint. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaira LA, Deiana G, Fois AG, Pirina P, Madeddu G, De Vito A, et al. . Objective evaluation of anosmia and ageusia in COVID-19 patients: single-center experience on 72 cases. Head Neck 2020; 42:1252&#x2013;1258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32342566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan CH, Prajapati DP, Ritter ML, DeConde AS. Persistent smell loss following undetectable SARS-CoV-2. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2020; 163:923&#x2013;925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8809452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32513065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsivgoulis G, Fragkou PC, Lachanis S, Palaiodimou L, Lambadiari V, Papathanasiou M, et al. . Olfactory bulb and mucosa abnormalities in persistent COVID-19-induced anosmia: a magnetic resonance imaging study. Eur J Neurol 2021; 28:e6&#x2013;e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32939911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins C, Surda P, Whitehead E, Kumar BN. Early recovery following new onset anosmia during the COVID-19 pandemic - an observational cohort study. J Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2020; 49:26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7196882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32366299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arag&#xe3;o MFVV, Leal MC, Cartaxo Filho OQ, Fonseca TM, Valen&#xe7;a MM. Anosmia in COVID-19 associated with injury to the olfactory bulbs evident on MRI. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol 2020; 41:1703&#x2013;1706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7583088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32586960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welge-L&#xfc;ssen A, Wolfensberger M. Olfactory disorders following upper respiratory tract infections. Adv Otorhinolaryngol 2006; 63:125&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16733337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki M, Saito K, Min WP, Vladau C, Toida K, Itoh H, Murakami S. Identification of viruses in patients with postviral olfactory dysfunction. Laryngoscope 2007; 117:272&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7165544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang CS. Olfactory neuropathy in severe acute respiratory syndrome: report of A case. Acta Neurol Taiwan 2006; 15:26&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16599281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MH, Perl DP, Nair G, Li W, Maric D, Murray H, et al. . Microvascular injury in the brains of patients with Covid-19. N Engl J Med 2021; 384:481&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7787217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33378608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavriatopoulou M, Korompoki E, Fotiou D, Ntanasis-Stathopoulos I, Psaltopoulou T, Kastritis E, et al. . Organ-specific manifestations of COVID-19 infection. Clin Exp Med 2020; 20:493&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32720223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang M, Li MD, Buch K, Yoon BC, Applewhite BP, Leslie-Mazwi TM, et al. . Risk of acute cerebrovascular events in patients with COVID-19 infection. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol 2020; 41:E92&#x2013;E93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7658821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32855192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaunmuktane Z, Mahadeva U, Green A, Sekhawat V, Barrett NA, Childs L, et al. . Microvascular injury and hypoxic damage: emerging neuropathological signatures in COVID-19. Acta Neuropathol 2020; 140:397&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7340758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32638079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SJ, Windon MJ, Lin SY. The association between diabetes and olfactory impairment in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Laryngoscope Investig Otolaryngol 2019; 4:465&#x2013;475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6793600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31637288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan JYK, Garc&#xed;a-Esquinas E, Ko OH, Tong MCF, Lin SY. The association between diabetes and olfactory function in adults. Chem Senses 2017; 43:59&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29126164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallab HF, Doty RL. Anosmia and hypogeusia in Churg-Strauss syndrome. BMJ Case Rep 2014; 2014:bcr2014203959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4025378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24825557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge H, Wang X, Yuan X, Xiao G, Wang C, Deng T, et al. . The epidemiology and clinical information about COVID-19. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis 2020; 39:1011&#x2013;1019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7154215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32291542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obradovic J. 7T MRI: new vision of microvascular abnormalities in multiple sclerosis yulin. Bone 2005; 23:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciurleo R, De Salvo S, Bonanno L, Marino S, Bramanti P, Caminiti F. Parosmia and neurological disorders: a neglected association. Front Neurol 2020; 11:543275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7681001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33240192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacharias H, Magliano M, Sandhu K, Weatherall M. A case of anosmia. Rheumatol Adv Pract 2018; 2 (Suppl 1):rky033.010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M, Hu Y, Chen S, He Q, et al. . Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol 2020; 77:683&#x2013;690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7149362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Shan KS, Abdollahi S, Nace T. Anosmia and ageusia as the only indicators of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Cureus 2020; 2019:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7263711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32494532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munhoz RP, Pedroso JL, Nascimento FA, Almeida SM, Barsottini OGP, Cardoso FEC, Teive HAG. Neurological complications in patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection: a systematic review. Arq Neuropsiquiatr 2020; 78:290&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32490966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Planchuelo-G&#xf3;mez &#xc1;, Trigo J, de Luis-Garc&#xed;a R, Guerrero &#xc1;L, Porta-Etessam J, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D. Deep phenotyping of headache in hospitalized COVID-19 patients via principal component analysis. Front Neurol 2020; 11:583870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7773780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33391152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu HQ, Yuan B, An YW, Chen KJ, Hu Q, Hu XP, et al. . Clinical characteristics and follow-up analysis of 324 discharged COVID-19 patients in Shenzhen during the recovery period. Int J Med Sci 2021; 18:347&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7757147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33390803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal M, Abo Omirah M, Hussein A, Saeed H. Assessment and characterisation of post-COVID-19 manifestations. Int J Clin Pract 2021; 75:e13746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caronna E, Ballv&#xe9; A, Llaurad&#xf3; A, Gallardo VJ, Ariton DM, Lallana S, et al. . Headache: a striking prodromal and persistent symptom, predictive of COVID-19 clinical evolution. Cephalalgia 2020; 40:1410&#x2013;1421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7645597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33146036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brun G, Hak JF, Coze S, Kaphan E, Carvelli J, Girard N, Stellmann JP. COVID-19-white matter and globus pallidum lesions: demyelination or small-vessel vasculitis? Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2020; 7:e777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7286652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32444427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, McAuley DF, Brown M, Sanchez E, Tattersall RS, Manson JJ; HLH Across Speciality Collaboration, UK. COVID-19: consider cytokine storm syndromes and immunosuppression. Lancet 2020; 395:1033&#x2013;1034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga Z, Flammer AJ, Steiger P, Haberecker M, Andermatt R, Zinkernagel AS, et al. . Endothelial cell infection and endotheliitis in COVID-19. Lancet 2020; 395:1417&#x2013;1418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Madhavan MV, Sehgal K, Nair N, Mahajan S, Sehrawat TS, et al. . Extrapulmonary manifestations of COVID-19. Nat Med 2020; 26:1017&#x2013;1032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32651579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrario CM, Jessup J, Chappell MC, Averill DB, Brosnihan KB, Tallant EA, et al. . Effect of angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibition and angiotensin II receptor blockers on cardiac angiotensin-converting enzyme 2. Circulation 2005; 111:2605&#x2013;2610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15897343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emanuel AL, Nieuwenhoff MD, Klaassen ES, Verma A, Kramer MH, Strijers R, et al. . Relationships between type 2 diabetes, neuropathy, and microvascular dysfunction: evidence from patients with cryptogenic axonal polyneuropathy. Diabetes Care 2017; 40:583&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28202549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stirban A. Microvascular dysfunction in the context of diabetic neuropathy. Curr Diab Rep 2014; 14:541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25189434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arap A, Siqueira SR, Silva CB, Teixeira MJ, Siqueira JT. Trigeminal pain and quantitative sensory testing in painful peripheral diabetic neuropathy. Arch Oral Biol 2010; 55:486&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20435295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tana C, Tafuri E, Tana M, Martelletti P, Negro A, Affaitati G, et al. . New insights into the cardiovascular risk of migraine and the role of white matter hyperintensities: is gold all that glitters? J Headache Pain 2013; 14:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3620371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23565964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widyadharma IPE, Sari NNSP, Pradnyaswari KE, Yuwana KT, Adikarya IPGD, Tertia C, et al. . Pain as clinical manifestations of COVID-19 infection and its management in the pandemic era: a literature review. Egypt J Neurol Psychiatr Neurosurg 2020; 56:121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7767578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33390724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozdag Acarli AN, Samanci B, Ekizoglu E, Cakar A, Sirin NG, Gunduz T, et al. . Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) From the Point of View of Neurologists: Observation of Neurological Findings and Symptoms During the Combat Against a Pandemic. Noro psikiyatri arsivi 2020; 57:154&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7285636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32550783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finnerup NB, Haroutounian S, Kamerman P, Baron R, Bennett DLH, Bouhassira D, et al. . Neuropathic pain: an updated grading system for research and clinical practice. Pain 2016; 157:1599&#x2013;1606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4949003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27115670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak P. Post COVID-19 syndrome associated with orthostatic cerebral hypoperfusion syndrome, small fiber neuropathy and benefit of immunotherapy: a case report. Eneurologicalsci 2020; 21:100276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7502253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32984564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aksan F, Nelson EA, Swedish KA. A COVID-19 patient with intense burning pain. J Neurovirol 2020; 26:800&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7416991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32779108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Needham E, Newcombe V, Michell A, Thornton R, Grainger A, Anwar F, et al. . Mononeuritis multiplex: an unexpectedly frequent feature of severe COVID-19. J Neurol 2021; 268:2685&#x2013;2689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7690651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33244712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilo S, Berghoff M, Hilz M, Freeman R. Neural and endothelial control of the microcirculation in diabetic peripheral neuropathy. Neurology 2000; 54:1246&#x2013;1252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10746593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F; Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA 2020; 324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, et al. . Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol 2021; 93:1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, Dunne J, Mooney A, Gaffney F, et al. . Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One 2020; 15:e0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers JP, Chesney E, Oliver D, Pollak TA, McGuire P, Fusar-Poli P, et al. . Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: a systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet Psychiatry 2020; 7:611&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7234781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth K, Scheibenbogen C. A unifying hypothesis of the pathophysiology of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS): recognitions from the finding of autoantibodies against &#xdf;2-adrenergic receptors. Autoimmun Rev 2020; 19:102527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32247028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nava E, Llorens S. The paracrine control of vascular motion. A historical perspective. Pharmacol Res 2016; 113:125&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27530204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Zhu H, Guo Q, Qian T, Zhang P, Li S, et al. . Overlapping mechanisms of peripheral nerve regeneration and angiogenesis following sciatic nerve transection. Front Cell Neurosci 2017; 11:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5649188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29085283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyama J, Higashi Y, Node K. Do incretins improve endothelial function? Cardiovasc Diabetol 2014; 13:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3898564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24428883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma AK, Sharma A, Kumari R, Kishore K, Sharma D, Srinivasan BP, et al. . Sitagliptin, sitagliptin and metformin, or sitagliptin and amitriptyline attenuate streptozotocin-nicotinamide induced diabetic neuropathy in rats. J Biomed Res 2012; 26:200&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3596070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23554750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pantanetti P, Cangelosi G, Ambrosio G. Potential role of incretins in diabetes and COVID-19 infection: a hypothesis worth exploring. Intern Emerg Med 2020; 15:779&#x2013;782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7317260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32592113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciavarella C, Motta I, Valente S, Pasquinelli G. Pharmacological (or synthetic) and nutritional agonists of PPAR-&#x3b3; as candidates for cytokine storm modulation in COVID-19 disease. Molecules 2020; 25:E2076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7248959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32365556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatti A, Lazzari M, Gianfelice V, Di Paolo A, Sabato E, Sabato AF. Palmitoylethanolamide in the treatment of chronic pain caused by different etiopathogenesis. Pain Med 2012; 13:1121&#x2013;1130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22845893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsalem M, Haddad M, Aldossary SA, Kalbouneh H, Azab B, Dweik A, et al. . Effects of dual peroxisome proliferator-activated receptors &#x3b1; and &#x3b3; activation in two rat models of neuropathic pain. PPAR Res 2019; 2019:2630232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6500665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31139213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Li S, Sun D. Calcium dobesilate and micro-vascular diseases. Life Sci 2019; 221:348&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30769115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szabo ME, Haines D, Garay E, Chiavaroli C, Farine JC, Hannaert P, et al. . Antioxidant properties of calcium dobesilate in ischemic/reperfused diabetic rat retina. Eur J Pharmacol 2001; 428:277&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11675046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson-Berka JL, Tan G, Binger KJ, Sutton L, McMaster K, Deliyanti D, et al. . Aliskiren reduces vascular pathology in diabetic retinopathy and oxygen-induced retinopathy in the transgenic (mRen-2)27 rat. Diabetologia 2011; 54:2724&#x2013;2735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21755314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dushay JR, Tecilazich F, Kafanas A, Magargee ML, Auster ME, Gnardellis C, et al. . Aliskiren improves vascular smooth muscle function in the skin microcirculation of type 2 diabetic patients with normal renal function. J Renin Angiotensin Aldosterone Syst 2015; 16:344&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5287335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23670354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Chopp M, Szalad A, Lu XR, Jia LF, Lu M, et al. . Tadalafil promotes the recovery of peripheral neuropathy in type II diabetic mice. PLoS One 2016; 11:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4954704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27438594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Zhang Z, Zhang RL, Cui Y, LaPointe MC, Silver B, Chopp M. Tadalafil, a long-acting type 5 phosphodiesterase isoenzyme inhibitor, improves neurological functional recovery in a rat model of embolic stroke. Brain Res 2006; 1118:192&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16959227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obata H. Analgesic mechanisms of antidepressants for neuropathic pain. Int J Mol Sci 2017; 18:E2483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5713449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29160850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>