<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36850042</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2702</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-traumatic stress symptoms six months after ICU admission with COVID-19: Prospective observational study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103</StartPage><EndPage>114</EndPage><MedlinePgn>103-114</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocn.16665</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this study was to investigate the prevalence of post-traumatic stress symptoms, and to identify possible predictive factors in Norwegian intensive care unit survivors, 6&#xa0;months after admission to the intensive care unit with COVID-19.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The SARS CoV-2 virus causing COVID-19 has spread worldwide since it was declared a pandemic in March 2020. The most severely ill patients have been treated in the intensive care due to acute respiratory failure and also acute respiratory distress syndrome. It is well documented that these severe conditions can lead to complex and long-lasting symptoms, such as psychological distress, and was, therefore, investigated for the specific COVID-19 population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Prospective observational study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Clinical data and patient reported outcome measures were collected by the Norwegian Intensive Care and Pandemic Registry and by the study group 6&#xa0;months after admission to an intensive care unit.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 222 COVID-19 patients admitted to Norwegian intensive care units between 10 March and 6 July 2020, 175 survived. The study sample consisted of 131 patients who responded to at least one patient reported outcome measure at 6&#xa0;months following admission. The primary outcome was self-reported post-traumatic stress symptoms, using the Impact of Event Scale-6 (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;89). Of those, 22.5% reported post-traumatic stress symptoms 6&#xa0;months after admission. Female gender, younger age and having a high respiratory rate at admission were statistically significant predictive factors for reporting post-traumatic stress symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The result is in accordance with previously published research with comparable populations, suggesting that for many COVID-19 survivors psychological distress is a part of the post-acute sequelae. Results from the present study should be replicated in larger datasets.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RELEVANCE TO CLINICAL PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This project provides important insight to post-acute sequelae after COVID-19 that patients may experience after critical illness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Journal of Clinical Nursing published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fjone</LastName><ForeName>Kristina Struksnes</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0821-2572</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research and Development, Division of Emergencies and Critical Care, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Oslo Metropolitan University, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buanes</LastName><ForeName>Eirik Alnes</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1295-6734</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Norwegian Intensive Care and Pandemic Registry, Haukeland University Hospital, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sm&#xe5;stuen</LastName><ForeName>Milada Cvancarova</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8947-8649</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research and Development, Division of Emergencies and Critical Care, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Oslo Metropolitan University, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laake</LastName><ForeName>Jon Henrik</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6157-5359</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research and Development, Division of Emergencies and Critical Care, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia and Intensive Care Medicine, Division of Emergencies and Critical Care, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stubberud</LastName><ForeName>Jan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9592-8589</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research, Lovisenberg Diaconal Hospital, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hofs&#xf8;</LastName><ForeName>Kristin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5854-8461</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research and Development, Division of Emergencies and Critical Care, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lovisenberg Diaconal University College, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Postoperative and Intensive Care Nursing, Division of Emergencies and Critical Care, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>312712/CR, 2020</GrantID><Agency>Norges Forskningsr&#xe5;d</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9207302</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0962-1067</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013313" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007362" MajorTopicYN="N">Intensive Care Units</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post COVID-19 condition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-intensive care syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-traumatic stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-traumatic stress disorder</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36850042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.16665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, H., Patel, K., Greenwood, D. C., Halpin, S., Lewthwaite, P., Salawu, A., Eyre, L., Breen, A., O'Connor, R., Jones, A., &amp; Sivan, M. (2020). Long-term clinical outcomes in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus outbreaks after hospitalisation or ICU admission: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Rehabilitation Medicine, 52(5), jrm00063. https://doi.org/10.2340/16501977-2694</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aranda, J., Oriol, I., Martin, M., Feria, L., Vazquez, N., Rhyman, N., Vall-Llosera, E., Pallares, N., Coloma, A., Pestana, M., Loureiro, J., Guell, E., Borjabad, B., Leon, E., Franz, E., Domenech, A., Pintado, S., Contra, A., Cortes, M. D. S., &#x2026; Carratala, J. (2021). Long-term impact of COVID-19 associated acute respiratory distress syndrome. The Journal of Infection, 83(5), 581-588. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2021.08.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong, R. A., Kane, A. D., Kursumovic, E., Oglesby, F. C., &amp; Cook, T. M. (2021). Mortality in patients admitted to intensive care with COVID-19: An updated systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. Anaesthesia, 76(4), 537-548. https://doi.org/10.1111/anae.15425</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellani, G., Laffey, J. G., Pham, T., Fan, E., Brochard, L., Esteban, A., Gattinoni, L., van Haren, F., Larsson, A., McAuley, D. F., Ranieri, M., Rubenfeld, G., Thompson, B. T., Wrigge, H., Slutsky, A. S., Pesenti, A., &amp; LUNG SAFE Investigators; ESICM Trials Group. (2016). Epidemiology, patterns of care, and mortality for patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome in intensive care units in 50 countries. JAMA, 315(8), 788-800. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2016.0291</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bienvenu, O. J., Friedman, L. A., Colantuoni, E., Dinglas, V. D., Sepulveda, K. A., Mendez-Tellez, P., Shanholz, C., Pronovost, P. J., &amp; Needham, D. M. (2018). Psychiatric symptoms after acute respiratory distress syndrome: A 5-year longitudinal study. Intensive Care Medicine, 44(1), 38-47. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00134-017-5009-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, S. M., Bose, S., Banner-Goodspeed, V., Beesley, S. J., Dinglas, V. D., Hopkins, R. O., Jackson, J. C., Mir-Kasimov, M., Needham, D. M., &amp; Sevin, C. M. (2019). Approaches to addressing post-intensive care syndrome among intensive care unit survivors. A narrative review. Annals of the American Thoracic Society, 16(8), 947-956. https://doi.org/10.1513/AnnalsATS.201812-913FR</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buanes, E. A., Kv&#xe5;le, R., &amp; Barrat-Due, A. (2021). Norsk Intensiv-Og Pandemiregister &#xc5;rsrapport for 2020 Med Plan for Forbetringstiltak Versjon 1.1. https://helse-bergen.no/seksjon/intensivregister/Documents/%C3%85rsrapporter%20i%20NIR/NIR%20%C3%85rsrapport%202020.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew, M. S., Kattainen, S., Haase, N., Buanes, E. A., Kristinsdottir, L. B., Hofs&#xf8;, K., Laake, J. H., Kv&#xe5;le, R., H&#xe4;stbacka, J., Reinikainen, M., Bendel, S., Varpula, T., Walther, S., Perner, A., Flaatten, H. K., &amp; Sigurdsson, M. I. (2022). A descriptive study of the surge response and outcomes of ICU patients with COVID-19 during first wave in Nordic countries. Acta Anaesthesiologica Scandinavica, 66(1), 56-64. https://doi.org/10.1111/aas.13983</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotes, J. E. (1987). Medical research COUNCIL questionnaire on respiratory symptoms (1986). The Lancet, 330(8566), 1028. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(87)92593-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotes, J. E., &amp; Chinn, D. J. (2007). MRC questionnaire (MRCQ) on respiratory symptoms. Occupational Medicine, 57(5), 388. https://doi.org/10.1093/occmed/kqm051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook, H., Raza, S., Nowell, J., Young, M., &amp; Edison, P. (2021). Long covid-Mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ, 374, n1648. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n1648</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davydow, D. S., Desai, S. V., Needham, D. M., &amp; Bienvenu, O. J. (2008). Psychiatric morbidity in survivors of the acute respiratory distress syndrome: A systematic review. Psychosomatic Medicine, 70(4), 512-519. https://doi.org/10.1097/PSY.0b013e31816aa0dd</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davydow, D. S., Gifford, J. M., Desai, S. V., Needham, D. M., &amp; Bienvenu, O. J. (2008). Posttraumatic stress disorder in general intensive care unit survivors: A systematic review. General Hospital Psychiatry, 30(5), 421-434 https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2572638/pdf/nihms70149.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhont, S., Derom, E., Van Braeckel, E., Depuydt, P., &amp; Lambrecht, B. N. (2020). The pathophysiology of &#x2018;happy&#x2019; hypoxemia in COVID-19. Respiratory Research, 21(1), 198. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12931-020-01462-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dijkstra-Kersten, S. M. A., Kok, L., Kerckhoffs, M. C., Cremer, O. L., de Lange, D. W., van Dijk, D., Needham, D. M., &amp; Slooter, A. J. C. (2020). Neuropsychiatric outcome in subgroups of intensive care unit survivors: Implications for after-care. Journal of Critical Care, 55, 171-176. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcrc.2019.11.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eid, J., Larsson, G., Johnsen, B. H., Laberg, J. C., Bartone, P. T., &amp; Carlstedt, B. (2009). Psychometric properties of the Norwegian impact of event scale-revised in a non-clinical sample. Nordic Journal of Psychiatry, 63(5), 426-432. https://doi.org/10.1080/08039480903118190</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott, D., Davidson, J. E., Harvey, M. A., Bemis-Dougherty, A., Hopkins, R. O., Iwashyna, T. J., Wagner, J., Weinert, C., Wunsch, H., Bienvenu, O. J., Black, G., Brady, S., Brodsky, M. B., Deutschman, C., Doepp, D., Flatley, C., Fosnight, S., Gittler, M., Gomez, B. T., &#x2026; Needham, D. M. (2014). Exploring the scope of post-intensive care syndrome therapy and care: Engagement of non-critical care providers and survivors in a second stakeholders meeting. Critical Care Medicine, 42(12), 2518-2526. https://doi.org/10.1097/ccm.0000000000000525</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, E., Dowdy, D. W., Colantuoni, E., Mendez-Tellez, P. A., Sevransky, J. E., Shanholtz, C., Himmelfarb, C. R., Desai, S. V., Ciesla, N., Herridge, M. S., Pronovost, P. J., &amp; Needham, D. M. (2014). Physical complications in acute lung injury survivors: A two-year longitudinal prospective study. Critical Care Medicine, 42(4), 849-859. https://doi.org/10.1097/ccm.0000000000000040</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fazzini, B., Battaglini, D., Carenzo, L., Pelosi, P., Cecconi, M., &amp; Puthucheary, Z. (in press). (2022). Physical and psychological impairment in survivors of acute respiratory distress syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. British Journal of Anaesthesia, 129, 801-814. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2022.08.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil Cuesta, J., Aavitsland, P., Englund, H., Gudlaugsson, &#xd3;., Hauge, S. H., Lyytik&#xe4;inen, O., Sigmundsd&#xf3;ttir, G., Tegnell, A., Virtanen, M., Krause, T. G., &amp; Nordic influenza comparison group. (2016). Pandemic vaccination strategies and influenza severe outcomes during the influenza a(H1N1)pdm09 pandemic and the post-pandemic influenza season: The Nordic experience. Euro Surveillance, 21(16), 30208. https://doi.org/10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2016.21.16.30208</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampshire, A., Trender, W., Chamberlain, S. R., Jolly, A. E., Grant, J. E., Patrick, F., Mazibuko, N., Williams, S. C. R., Barnby, J. M., Hellyer, P., &amp; Mehta, M. A. (2021). Cognitive deficits in people who have recovered from COVID-19. EClinicalMedicine, 39, 101044. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heesakkers, H., van der Hoeven, J. G., Corsten, S., Janssen, I., Ewalds, E., Simons, K. S., Westerhof, B., Rettig, T. C. D., Jacobs, C., van Santen, S., Slooter, A. J. C., van der Woude, M. C. E., van den Boogaard, M., &amp; Zegers, M. (2022). Clinical outcomes among patients with 1-year survival following intensive care unit treatment for COVID-19. JAMA, 327(6), 559-565. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2022.0040</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosey, M. M., Leoutsakos, J.-M. S., Li, X., Dinglas, V. D., Bienvenu, O. J., Parker, A. M., Hopkins, R. O., Needham, D. M., &amp; Neufeld, K. J. (2019). Screening for posttraumatic stress disorder in ARDS survivors: Validation of the impact of event Scale-6 (IES-6). Critical Care, 23(1), 276. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-019-2553-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosey, M. M., &amp; Needham, D. M. (2020). Survivorship after COVID-19 ICU stay. Nature Reviews. Disease Primers, 6(1), 60. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41572-020-0201-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst, S. A. (2014). Declaration of Helsinki and protection for vulnerable research participants. JAMA, 311(12), 1252. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2014.1272</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latronico, N., Peli, E., Calza, S., Rodella, F., Novelli, M. P., Cella, A., Marshall, J., Needham, D. M., Rasulo, F. A., &amp; Piva, S. (2021). Physical, cognitive and mental health outcomes in 1-year survivors of COVID-19-associated ARDS. Thorax, 77, 300-303. https://doi.org/10.1136/thoraxjnl-2021-218064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Launois, C., Barbe, C., Bertin, E., Nardi, J., Perotin, J.-M., Dury, S., Lebargy, F., &amp; Deslee, G. (2012). The modified Medical Research Council scale for the assessment of dyspnea in daily living in obesity: A pilot study. BMC Pulmonary Medicine, 12(1), 61. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2466-12-61</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, M., Kang, J., &amp; Jeong, Y. J. (2020). Risk factors for post-intensive care syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Australian Critical Care, 33(3), 287-294. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aucc.2019.10.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahler, D. A., &amp; Wells, C. K. (1988). Evaluation of clinical methods for rating dyspnea. Chest, 93(3), 580-586. https://doi.org/10.1378/chest.93.3.580</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marra, A., Pandharipande, P. P., Girard, T. D., Patel, M. B., Hughes, C. G., Jackson, J. C., Thompson, J. L., Chandrasekhar, R., Ely, E. W., &amp; Brummel, N. E. (2018). Co-occurrence of post-intensive care syndrome problems among 406 survivors of critical illness. Critical Care Medicine, 46(9), 1393-1401. https://doi.org/10.1097/CCM.0000000000003218</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins, S., Ferreira, A. R., Fernandes, J., Vieira, T., Fontes, L., Coimbra, I., Paiva, J. A., &amp; Fernandes, L. (2022). Depressive and anxiety symptoms in severe COVID-19 survivors: A prospective cohort study. The Psychiatric Quarterly, 93, 891-903. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11126-022-09998-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkelsen, M. E., Still, M., Anderson, B. J., Bienvenu, O. J., Brodsky, M. B., Brummel, N., Butcher, B., Clay, A. S., Felt, H., Ferrante, L. E., Haines, K. J., Harhay, M. O., Hope, A. A., Hopkins, R. O., Hosey, M., Hough, C. T. L., Jackson, J. C., Johnson, A., Khan, B., &#x2026; Sevin, C. M. (2020). Society of Critical Care Medicine's international consensus conference on prediction and identification of long-term impairments after critical illness. Critical Care Medicine, 48(11), 1670-1679. https://doi.org/10.1097/ccm.0000000000004586</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mykletun, A., Stordal, E., &amp; Dahl, A. A. (2001). Hospital anxiety and depression (HAD) scale: Factor structure, item analyses and internal consistency in a large population. British Journal of Psychiatry, 179(6), 540-544. https://doi.org/10.1192/bjp.179.6.540</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagarajan, R., Krishnamoorthy, Y., Basavarachar, V., &amp; Dakshinamoorthy, R. (2022). Prevalence of post-traumatic stress disorder among survivors of severe COVID-19 infections: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Affective Disorders, 299, 52-59. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jad.2021.11.040</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine, Z. (2020). Remote MoCA testing. MoCA Test Inc Retrieved 2021.02.21 from https://www.mocatest.org/remote-moca-testing/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Needham, D. M. (2020). Improving long-term outcomes research for acute respiratory failure. The outcomes after critical illness and surgery (OACIS). Group at Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine Retrieved 2020.12.04 from https://www.improvelto.com/instruments/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Needham, D. M., Sepulveda, K. A., Dinglas, V. D., Chessare, C. M., Friedman, L. A., Bingham, C. O., 3rd, &amp; Turnbull, A. E. (2017). Core outcome measures for clinical research in acute respiratory failure survivors. An international modified Delphi consensus study. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, 196(9), 1122-1130. https://doi.org/10.1164/rccm.201702-0372OC</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neville, T. H., Hays, R. D., Tseng, C. H., Gonzalez, C. A., Chen, L., Hong, A., Yamamoto, M., Santoso, L., Kung, A., Schwab, K., Chang, S. Y., Qadir, N., Wang, T., &amp; Wenger, N. S. (2022). Survival after severe COVID-19: Long-term outcomes of patients admitted to an intensive care unit. Journal of Intensive Care Medicine, 37, 1019-1028. https://doi.org/10.1177/08850666221092687</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandharipande, P. P., Girard, T. D., Jackson, J. C., Morandi, A., Thompson, J. L., Pun, B. T., Brummel, N. E., Hughes, C. G., Vasilevskis, E. E., Shintani, A. K., Moons, K. G., Geevarghese, S. K., Canonico, A., Hopkins, R. O., Bernard, G. R., Dittus, R. S., &amp; Ely, E. W. (2013). Long-term cognitive impairment after critical illness. New England Journal of Medicine, 369(14), 1306-1316. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa1301372</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker, A. M., Brigham, E., Connolly, B., McPeake, J., Agranovich, A. V., Kenes, M. T., Casey, K., Reynolds, C., Schmidt, K. F. R., Kim, S. Y., Kaplin, A., Sevin, C. M., Brodsky, M. B., &amp; Turnbull, A. E. (2021). Addressing the post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: A multidisciplinary model of care. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine, 9, 1328-1341. https://doi.org/10.1016/s2213-2600(21)00385-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker, A. M., Sricharoenchai, T., Raparla, S., Schneck, K. W., Bienvenu, O. J., &amp; Needham, D. M. (2015). Posttraumatic stress disorder in critical illness survivors: A Metaanalysis. Critical Care Medicine, 43(5), 1121-1129. https://doi.org/10.1097/ccm.0000000000000882</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj, L., Kannapadi, N. V., Briggs, J., Seal, S. M., Battaglini, D., Fanning, J., Suen, J., Robba, C., Fraser, J., &amp; Cho, S. M. (2022). Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: A meta-analysis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 434, 120162. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2022.120162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pun, B. T., Badenes, R., Heras La Calle, G., Orun, O. M., Chen, W., Raman, R., Simpson, B. K., Wilson-Linville, S., Hinojal Olmedillo, B., Vallejo de la Cueva, A., van der Jagt, M., Navarro Casado, R., Leal Sanz, P., Orhun, G., Ferrer G&#xf3;mez, C., N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez V&#xe1;zquez, K., Pi&#xf1;eiro Otero, P., Taccone, F. S., Gallego Curto, E., &#x2026; Pandharipande, P. P. (2021). Prevalence and risk factors for delirium in critically ill patients with COVID-19 (COVID-D): A multicentre cohort study. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine, 9(3), 239-250. https://doi.org/10.1016/s2213-2600(20)30552-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Righy, C., Rosa, R. G., da Silva, R. T. A., Kochhann, R., Migliavaca, C. B., Robinson, C. C., Teche, S. P., Teixeira, C., Bozza, F. A., &amp; Falavigna, M. (2019). Prevalence of post-traumatic stress disorder symptoms in adult critical care survivors: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Critical Care, 23(1), 213. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-019-2489-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schandl, A., Hedman, A., Lyng&#xe5;, P., Fathi Tachinabad, S., Svefors, J., Ro&#xeb;l, M., Geborek, A., Franko, M. A., S&#xf6;derberg, M., Eva Joelsson, A., &amp; Darlington, P. (2021). Long-term consequences in critically ill COVID-19 patients: A prospective cohort study. Acta Anaesthesiologica Scandinavica, 65, 1285-1292. https://doi.org/10.1111/aas.13939</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah, W., Hillman, T., Playford, E. D., &amp; Hishmeh, L. (2021). Managing the long term effects of covid-19: Summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ, 372, n136. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n136</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan, M., &amp; Taylor, S. (2020). NICE guideline on long covid. BMJ, 371, m4938. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m4938</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snaith, R. P. (2003). The hospital anxiety and depression scale. Health and Quality of Life Outcomes, 1, 29. https://doi.org/10.1186/1477-7525-1-29</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thoresen, S., Tambs, K., Hussain, A., Heir, T., Johansen, V. A., &amp; Bisson, J. I. (2010). Brief measure of posttraumatic stress reactions: Impact of event Scale-6. Social Psychiatry, 45(3), 405-412. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00127-009-0073-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm, E., Altman, D. G., Egger, M., Pocock, S. J., G&#xf8;tzsche, P. C., &amp; Vandenbroucke, J. P. (2007). Strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement: Guidelines for reporting observational studies. BMJ, 335(7624), 806-808. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.39335.541782.AD</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, D., Hu, B., Hu, C., Zhu, F., Liu, X., Zhang, J., Wang, B., Xiang, H., Cheng, Z., Xiong, Y., Zhao, Y., Li, Y., Wang, X., &amp; Peng, Z. (2020). Clinical Characteristics of 138 Hospitalized Patients With 2019 Novel Coronavirus-Infected Pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA, 323(11), 1061-1069. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.1585</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. (2020). WHO director-General's opening remarks at the media briefing on COVID-19 - 11 march 2020. World Health Organization Retrieved 2021-08-18 from https://www.who.int/director-general/speeches/detail/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-the-media-briefing-on-covid-19---11-march-2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. (2021). A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021. World Health Organization Retrieved 24 October 2021 from https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, A., Nyenhuis, D., Black Sandra, E., Law Lorraine, S. N., Lo Eugene, S. K., Kwan Pauline, W. L., Au, L., Chan Anne, Y. Y., Wong Lawrence, K. S., Nasreddine, Z., &amp; Mok, V. (2015). Montreal cognitive assessment 5-minute protocol is a brief, valid, reliable, and feasible cognitive screen for telephone administration. Stroke, 46(4), 1059-1064. https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.114.007253</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, S., Luo, D., &amp; Xiao, Y. (2020). Survivors of COVID-19 are at high risk of posttraumatic stress disorder. Global Health Research and Policy, 5(1), 29. https://doi.org/10.1186/s41256-020-00155-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigmond, A. S., &amp; Snaith, R. P. (1983). The hospital anxiety and depression scale. Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavica, 67(6), 361-370. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0447.1983.tb09716.x</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>