<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37771872</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2222-0682</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of methodology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Methodol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-COVID-19 cholangiopathy: Systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>296</StartPage><EndPage>322</EndPage><MedlinePgn>296-322</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5662/wjm.v13.i4.296</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic has had a profound impact on global health, primarily characterized by severe respiratory illness. However, emerging evidence suggests that COVID-19 can also lead to secondary sclerosing cholangitis (SC), referred to as post-COVID-19 cholangiopathy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To synthesize currently reported cases to assess the current state of knowledge on post-COVID-19 cholangiopathy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Medical Subject Headings and Health Sciences Descriptors were used to retrieve relevant studies, which were combined using Boolean operators. Searches were conducted on electronic databases including Scopus, Web of Science, and MEDLINE (PubMed). Studies published in English, Spanish, or Portuguese were included, with no restrictions on the publication date. Additionally, the reference lists of retrieved studies were manually searched. Simple descriptive analyses were used to summarize the results. Then the data were extracted and assessed based on Reference Citation Analysis (https://www.referencecitationanalysis.com/).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The initial search yielded a total of 192 articles. After screening, 85 articles were excluded due to duplication, leaving 107 articles for further review. Of these, 63 full-length articles met the inclusion criteria and were included in the analyses. Most of the patients were male and exhibited elevated liver function tests (93.8%). Magnetic resonance imaging revealed duct thickening with contrast enhancement (47.7%), as well as beading of the intrahepatic ducts (45.7%) with peribiliary contrast enhancement on diffusion (28.7%). Liver biopsy results confirmed SC in most cases (74.4%). Sixteen patients underwent liver transplantation, with three experiencing successful outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Post-COVID-19 cholangiopathy is a serious condition that is expected to become increasingly concerning in the coming years, particularly considering long COVID syndromes. Although liver transplantation has been proposed as a potential treatment option, more research is necessary to establish its efficacy and explore other potential treatments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2023. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rasheed</LastName><ForeName>Mazen Abdalla</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Acute Medicine, University of South Wales, Cardiff CF37 1DL, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ballotin</LastName><ForeName>Vin&#xed;cius Remus</ForeName><Initials>VR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Universidade de Caxias do Sul, Caxias do Sul 95070-560, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bigarella</LastName><ForeName>Lucas Goldmann</ForeName><Initials>LG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Universidade de Caxias do Sul, Caxias do Sul 95070-560, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soldera</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Acute Medicine, University of South Wales, Cardiff CF37 1DL, United Kingdom. jonathansoldera@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Methodol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101628739</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2222-0682</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cholangiopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus disease 2019</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Liver function tests</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Liver transplantation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37771872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10523251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5662/wjm.v13.i4.296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cucinotta D, Vanelli M. WHO Declares COVID-19 a Pandemic. Acta Biomed. 2020;91:157&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7569573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32191675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cascella M, Rajnik M, Aleem A, Dulebohn SC, Di Napoli R. Features, Evaluation, and Treatment of Coronavirus (COVID-19). 2023 Jan 9. In: StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2023 Jan-</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32150360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma O, Sultan AA, Ding H, Triggle CR. A Review of the Progress and Challenges of Developing a Vaccine for COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2020;11:585354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7591699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33163000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N, Zhou M, Dong X, Qu J, Gong F, Han Y, Qiu Y, Wang J, Liu Y, Wei Y, Xia J, Yu T, Zhang X, Zhang L. Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of 99 cases of 2019 novel coronavirus pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a descriptive study. Lancet. 2020;395:507&#x2013;513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7135076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32007143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durazo FA, Nicholas AA, Mahaffey JJ, Sova S, Evans JJ, Trivella JP, Loy V, Kim J, Zimmerman MA, Hong JC. Post-Covid-19 Cholangiopathy-A New Indication for Liver Transplantation: A Case Report. Transplant Proc. 2021;53:1132&#x2013;1137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7953456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33846012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Liu J, Lu M, Yang D, Zheng X. Liver injury during highly pathogenic human coronavirus infections. Liver Int. 2020;40:998&#x2013;1004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32170806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson KD, Harris C, Cain JK, Hummer C, Goyal H, Perisetti A. Pulmonary and Extra-Pulmonary Clinical Manifestations of COVID-19. Front Med (Lausanne) 2020;7:526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7438449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32903492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Hu B, Hu C, Zhu F, Liu X, Zhang J, Wang B, Xiang H, Cheng Z, Xiong Y, Zhao Y, Li Y, Wang X, Peng Z. Clinical Characteristics of 138 Hospitalized Patients With 2019 Novel Coronavirus-Infected Pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA. 2020;323:1061&#x2013;1069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veerankutty FH, Sengupta K, Vij M, Rammohan A, Jothimani D, Murali A, Rela M. Post-COVID-19 cholangiopathy: Current understanding and management options. World J Gastrointest Surg. 2023;15:788&#x2013;798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10277943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37342848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soldera J, Bosi GR. Haemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis following a COVID-19 infection: case report. J Infect Dev Ctries. 2023;17:302&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37023430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanny B, Alkhero M, Alani M, Stenberg D, Saharan A, Saab S. Post-COVID-19 Cholangiopathy: A Systematic Review. J Clin Exp Hepatol. 2023;13:489&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9618303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36337085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bethineedi LD, Suvvari TK. Post COVID-19 cholangiopathy - A deep dive. Dig Liver Dis. 2021;53:1235&#x2013;1236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8349694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34412993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faruqui S, Okoli FC, Olsen SK, Feldman DM, Kalia HS, Park JS, Stanca CM, Figueroa Diaz V, Yuan S, Dagher NN, Sarkar SA, Theise ND, Kim S, Shanbhogue K, Jacobson IM. Cholangiopathy After Severe COVID-19: Clinical Features and Prognostic Implications. Am J Gastroenterol. 2021;116:1414&#x2013;1425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33993134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, Shamseer L, Tetzlaff JM, Akl EA, Brennan SE, Chou R, Glanville J, Grimshaw JM, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Lalu MM, Li T, Loder EW, Mayo-Wilson E, McDonald S, McGuinness LA, Stewart LA, Thomas J, Tricco AC, Welch VA, Whiting P, Moher D. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu WL, Cho CC, Lung PF, Hung EH, Hui JW, Chau HH, Chan AW, Ahuja AT. Ketamine-related cholangiopathy: a retrospective study on clinical and imaging findings. Abdom Imaging. 2014;39:1241&#x2013;1246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24934474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Tymowski C, D&#xe9;pret F, Dudoignon E, Legrand M, Mallet V Keta-Cov Research Group. Ketamine-induced cholangiopathy in ARDS patients. Intensive Care Med. 2021;47:1173&#x2013;1174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8315088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34313797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batts KP. Ischemic cholangitis. Mayo Clin Proc. 1998;73:380&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9559044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka A. IgG4-Related Sclerosing Cholangitis and Primary Sclerosing Cholangitis. Gut Liver. 2019;13:300&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6529173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30205418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manganis CD, Chapman RW, Culver EL. Review of primary sclerosing cholangitis with increased IgG4 levels. World J Gastroenterol. 2020;26:3126&#x2013;3144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7336326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32684731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballotin VR, Bigarella LG, Riva F, Onzi G, Balbinot RA, Balbinot SS, Soldera J. Primary sclerosing cholangitis and autoimmune hepatitis overlap syndrome associated with inflammatory bowel disease: A case report and systematic review. World J Clin Cases. 2020;8:4075&#x2013;4093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7520795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brambilla B, Barbosa AM, Scholze CDS, Riva F, Freitas L, Balbinot RA, Balbinot S, Soldera J. Hemophagocytic Lymphohistiocytosis and Inflammatory Bowel Disease: Case Report and Systematic Review. Inflamm Intest Dis. 2020;5:49&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7315217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32596254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai X, Hu L, Zhang Y, Han W, Lu Z, Ke A, Zhou J, Shi G, Fang N, Fan J. Specific ACE2 expression in cholangiocytes may cause liver damage after 2019-nCoV infection. 2020 Preprint. Available from: bioRxiv:931766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhaliwal A, Dhindsa BS, Esquivel RG. COVID Bile Duct: Biliary Cast Syndrome as a Complication of SARS-CoV-2 Infection. J Gastrointest Surg. 2022;26:1806&#x2013;1807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8926087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35296958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayorqu&#xed;n-Aguilar JM, Lara-Reyes A, Revuelta-Rodr&#xed;guez LA, Flores-Garc&#xed;a NC, Ruiz-Marg&#xe1;in A, Jim&#xe9;nez-Ferreira MA, Mac&#xed;as-Rodr&#xed;guez RU. Secondary sclerosing cholangitis after critical COVID-19: Three case reports. World J Hepatol. 2022;14:1678&#x2013;1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9453459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36157873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graciolli AM, De Bortoli BR, Maslonek C, Gremelmier EMC, Henrich CF, Salgado K, Balbinot RA, Balbinot SS, Soldera J. Post-COVID-19 cholangiopathy. Dig Med Res. :2023. In press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soldera J, Balbinot RA, Balbinot SS. Billiary casts in post-COVID-19 cholangiopathy. Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2023;46:319&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9476357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36116722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkarni AV, Khelgi A, Sekaran A, Reddy R, Sharma M, Tirumalle S, Gora BA, Somireddy A, Reddy J, Menon B, Reddy DN, Rao NP. Post-COVID-19 Cholestasis: A Case Series and Review of Literature. J Clin Exp Hepatol. 2022;12:1580&#x2013;1590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9187855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35719861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth NC, Kim A, Vitkovski T, Xia J, Ramirez G, Bernstein D, Crawford JM. Post-COVID-19 Cholangiopathy: A Novel Entity. Am J Gastroenterol. 2021;116:1077&#x2013;1082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33464757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Yuan S, Schooling CM, Larsson SC. A Mendelian randomization study of genetic predisposition to autoimmune diseases and COVID-19. Sci Rep. 2022;12:17703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9587049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36271292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunyady P, Streller L, R&#xfc;ther DF, Groba SR, Bettinger D, Fitting D, Hamesch K, Marquardt JU, M&#xfc;cke VT, Finkelmeier F, Sekandarzad A, Wengenmayer T, Bounidane A, Weiss F, Peiffer KH, Schlevogt B, Zeuzem S, Waidmann O, Hollenbach M, Kirstein MM, Kluwe J, K&#xfc;tting F, M&#xfc;cke MM. Secondary Sclerosing Cholangitis Following Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19): A Multicenter Retrospective Study. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76:e179&#x2013;e187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9278244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35809032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weaver M, McHenry S, Das KK. COVID-19 and Jaundice. Gastroenterology. 2021;160:e1&#x2013;e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33039462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartl L, Haslinger K, Angerer M, Semmler G, Schneeweiss-Gleixner M, Jachs M, Simbrunner B, Bauer DJM, Eigenbauer E, Strassl R, Breuer M, Kimberger O, Laxar D, Lampichler K, Halilbasic E, St&#xe4;ttermayer AF, Ba-Ssalamah A, Mandorfer M, Scheiner B, Reiberger T, Trauner M. Progressive cholestasis and associated sclerosing cholangitis are frequent complications of COVID-19 in patients with chronic liver disease. Hepatology. 2022;76:1563&#x2013;1575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9347407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35596929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duengelhoef P, Hartl J, R&#xfc;ther D, Steinmann S, Brehm TT, Weltzsch JP, Glaser F, Schaub GM, Sterneck M, Sebode M, Weiler-Normann C, Addo MM, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Haag F, Schramm C, Schulze Zur Wiesch J, Lohse AW. SARS-CoV-2 vaccination response in patients with autoimmune hepatitis and autoimmune cholestatic liver disease. United European Gastroenterol J. 2022;10:319&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9004241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35289983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>John BV, Bastaich D, Webb G, Brevini T, Moon A, Ferreira RD, Chin AM, Kaplan DE, Taddei TH, Serper M, Mahmud N, Deng Y, Chao HH, Sampaziotis F, Dahman B. Ursodeoxycholic acid is associated with a reduction in SARS-CoV-2 infection and reduced severity of COVID-19 in patients with cirrhosis. J Intern Med. 2023;293:636&#x2013;647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37018129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heucke N, Keitel V. COVID-19-associated cholangiopathy: What is left after the virus has gone? Hepatology. 2022;76:1560&#x2013;1562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9350171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35822670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazerbachi F, Servin-Abad LA, Nassani N, M&#xf6;nkem&#xfc;ller K. Endosonographic and ERCP findings in COVID-19 critical illness cholangiopathy. Rev Esp Enferm Dig. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36205332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho JY, Lee YS, Kim SS, Song DS, Lee JH, Kim JH. Forms of cholangitis to be considered after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Clin Mol Hepatol. 2022;28:929&#x2013;930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9597223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36096495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu XQ, Zhang XX. [Concerns about COVID-19-associated liver injury] Zhonghua Gan Zang Bing Za Zhi. 2022;30:473&#x2013;476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35764538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders D, Bomman S, Irani S. COVID-19-Induced Bile Duct Casts and Cholangitis: A Case Report. Cureus. 2021;13:e14560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8055170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33889467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez Romero-Salazar F, Veras Lista M, G&#xf3;mez-Dom&#xed;nguez E, Ibarrola-Andr&#xe9;s C, Mu&#xf1;oz G&#xf3;mez R, Fern&#xe1;ndez V&#xe1;zquez I. SARS-CoV-2 vaccine, a new autoimmune hepatitis trigger? Rev Esp Enferm Dig. 2022;114:567&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35373571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wall AE, McKenna GJ, Onaca N, Ruiz R, Bayer J, Fernandez H, Martinez E, Gupta A, Askar M, Spak CW, Testa G. Utilization of a SARS-CoV-2-positive donor for liver transplantation. Proc (Bayl Univ Med Cent) 2022;35:62&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8682856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34970035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghafoor S, Germann M, J&#xfc;ngst C, M&#xfc;llhaupt B, Reiner CS, Stocker D. Imaging features of COVID-19-associated secondary sclerosing cholangitis on magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography: a retrospective analysis. Insights Imaging. 2022;13:128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9358102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35939241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh B, Kaur P, Maroules M. Autoimmune Hepatitis-Primary Biliary Cholangitis Overlap Syndrome Triggered by COVID-19. Eur J Case Rep Intern Med. 2021;8:002264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7977057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33768072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seifert M, Kneiseler G, Dechene A. Secondary Sclerosing Cholangitis due to Severe COVID-19: An Emerging Disease Entity? Digestion. 2023;104:306&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10025365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36889285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee A, Wein AN, Doyle MBM, Chapman WC. Liver transplantation for post-COVID-19 sclerosing cholangitis. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8395362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34446515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha-Silva M, de Fran&#xe7;a EVC, Greca RD, Mazo DFC, da Costa LBE, de Moraes PBS, Veiga CT, Assis-Mendon&#xe7;a GR, Boin IFSF, Stucchi RSB, Sev&#xe1;-Pereira T. Autoimmune hepatitis and primary biliary cholangitis overlap syndrome after COVID-19. Autops Case Rep. 2023;13:e2023422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10075219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37034275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamid S, Alvares da Silva MR, Burak KW, Chen T, Drenth JPH, Esmat G, Gaspar R, LaBrecque D, Lee A, Macedo G, McMahon B, Ning Q, Reau N, Sonderup M, van Leeuwen DJ, Armstrong D, Yurdaydin C. WGO Guidance for the Care of Patients With COVID-19 and Liver Disease. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2021;55:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7713641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33230011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroepfl V, Treml B, Freund MC, Profanter C. Early detection of COVID-19 cholangiopathy using cholangioscopy-a&#xa0;case report of two critically ill patients. Eur Surg. 2022;54:326&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9510572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36189108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graciolli AM, Bortoli BR, Gremelmier EMC, Henrich CF, Salgado K, Balbinot RA, Balbinot SS, Nesello RGF, Soldera J. Post-COVID-19 Cholangiopathy: a novel clinical entity. Rev AMRIGS. 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keta-Cov research group. Intravenous ketamine and progressive cholangiopathy in COVID-19 patients. J Hepatol. 2021;74:1243&#x2013;1244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7893247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33617925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zdanowicz K, Bobrus-Chociej A, Kopiczko A, U&#x15b;cinowicz M, Tomczuk-Ostapczuk M, Janica J, &#x141;otowska JM, Bia&#x142;okoz-Kalinowska I, Lebensztejn DM. Autoimmune sclerosing cholangitis might be triggered by SARS-CoV-2 infection in a child - a case report. Cent Eur J Immunol. 2022;47:183&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9894089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36751389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz S, Lang C, Harlander M, &#x160;tupnik T, Slambrouck JV, Ceulemans LJ, Ius F, Gottlieb J, Kuhnert S, Hecker M, Aigner C, Kneidinger N, Verschuuren EA, Smits JM, Tschernko E, Schaden E, Faybik P, Markstaller K, Trauner M, Jaksch P, Hoetzenecker K. Gamma-glutamyltransferase is a strong predictor of secondary sclerosing cholangitis after lung transplantation for COVID-19 ARDS. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2022;41:1501&#x2013;1510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9249665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35907758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keskin O, Kav T, Vahabov C, Usta B, Sivri B, Parlak E. Clinical and Endoscopic Consequences of Delay in Stent Exchange Procedures With ERCP During the Covid-19 Pandemic. Surg Laparosc Endosc Percutan Tech. 2022;32:714&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36044333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartoli A, Gitto S, Sighinolfi P, Cursaro C, Andreone P. Primary biliary cholangitis associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Hepatol. 2021;74:1245&#x2013;1246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7892314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33610679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira FB, Mourato M, Bragan&#xe7;a S, Paulo JB, Sismeiro R, Pereira A, M&#xf3;nica AN, Louren&#xe7;o LC, Cardoso M. COVID-19-associated secondary sclerosing cholangitis - A case series of 4 patients. Clin Res Hepatol Gastroenterol. 2022;46:102048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9636600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36347499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;tikofer S, Lenggenhager D, Wendel Garcia PD, Maggio EM, Haberecker M, Reiner CS, Br&#xfc;llmann G, Buehler PK, Gubler C, M&#xfc;llhaupt B, J&#xfc;ngst C, Morell B. Secondary sclerosing cholangitis as cause of persistent jaundice in patients with severe COVID-19. Liver Int. 2021;41:2404&#x2013;2417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34018314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafar M, Gordon K, Macken L, Parvin J, Heath S, Whibley M, Tibble J. COVID-19 Vaccination-Induced Cholangiopathy and Autoimmune Hepatitis: A Series of Two Cases. Cureus. 2022;14:e30304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9565316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36258805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otani K, Watanabe T, Higashimori A, Suzuki H, Kamiya T, Shiotani A, Sugimoto M, Nagahara A, Fukudo S, Motoya S, Yamaguchi S, Zhu Q, Chan FKL, Hahm KB, Tablante MC, Prachayakul V, Abdullah M, Ang TL, Murakami K International Gastrointestinal Consensus Symposium Study Group. A Questionnaire-Based Survey on the Impact of the COVID-19 Pandemic on Gastrointestinal Endoscopy in Asia. Digestion. 2022;103:7&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8678234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34758472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cesar Machado MC, Filho RK, El Bacha IAH, de Oliveira IS, Ribeiro CMF, de Souza HP, Parise ER. Post-COVID-19 Secondary Sclerosing Cholangitis: A Rare but Severe Condition with no Treatment Besides Liver Transplantation. Am J Case Rep. 2022;23:e936250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9394546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35978523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steiner J, Kaufmann-B&#xfc;hler AK, Fuchsj&#xe4;ger M, Schemmer P, Talaki&#x107; E. Secondary sclerosing cholangitis in a young COVID-19 patient resulting in death: A case report. World J Gastrointest Surg. 2022;14:1411&#x2013;1417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9827572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36632122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gourjault C, Tarhini H, Rahi M, Thy M, Le Pluart D, Rioux C, Parisey M, Ismael S, Aidibi AAR, Paradis V, Ghosn J, Yazdanpanah Y, Lescure FX, Gervais A. Cholangitis in three critically ill patients after a severe CoVID-19 infection. IDCases. 2021;26:e01267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8406543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34485077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tafreshi S, Whiteside I, Levine I, D'Agostino C. A case of secondary sclerosing cholangitis due to COVID-19. Clin Imaging. 2021;80:239&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8314797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34364072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonhardt S, J&#xfc;rgensen C, Frohme J, Grajecki D, Adler A, Sigal M, Leonhardt J, Voll JM, Kruse JM, K&#xf6;rner R, Eckardt KU, Janssen HJ, Gebhardt V, Schmittner MD Pa-COVID-19 collaborative study group, Frey C, M&#xfc;ller-Ide H, Bauer M, Thibeault C, Kurth F, Sander LE, M&#xfc;ller T, Tacke F. Hepatobiliary long-term consequences of COVID-19: dramatically increased rate of secondary sclerosing cholangitis in critically ill COVID-19 patients. Hepatol Int. 2023:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10148013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37119516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zengarini C, Pileri A, Salamone FP, Piraccini BM, Vitale G, La Placa M. Subacute cutaneous lupus erythematosus induction after SARS-CoV-2 vaccine in a patient with primary biliary cholangitis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2022;36:e179&#x2013;e180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9011449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34807495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wendel-Garcia PD, Erlebach R, Hofmaenner DA, Camen G, Schuepbach RA, J&#xfc;ngst C, M&#xfc;llhaupt B, Bartussek J, Buehler PK, Andermatt R, David S. Long-term ketamine infusion-induced cholestatic liver injury in COVID-19-associated acute respiratory distress syndrome. Crit Care. 2022;26:148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9125956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35606831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mor&#xe3;o B, Rev&#xe9;s JB, Nascimento C, Loureiro R, Gl&#xf3;ria L, Palmela C. Secondary Sclerosing Cholangitis in a Critically Ill Patient with Severe SARS-CoV-2 Infection: A Possibly Emergent Entity during the Current Global Pandemic. GE Port J Gastroenterol. 2022;27:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9059009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35528723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SK, Kwon JH, Yoon N, Nam SW, Sung PS. Autoimmune liver disease represented as primary biliary cholangitis after SARS-CoV-2 infection: A need for population-based cohort study. Clin Mol Hepatol. 2022;28:926&#x2013;928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9597224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36064307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikoupour H, Arasteh P, Gholami S, Nikeghbalian S. Liver transplantation and COVID-19: a case report and cross comparison between two identical twins with COVID-19. BMC Surg. 2020;20:181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7414266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32770973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnstadt B, Zillinger C, Treitl M, Allescher HD. Corona again? SSC after a severe COVID-disease. Z Gastroenterol. 2021;59:1304&#x2013;1308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34666402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meersseman P, Blondeel J, De Vlieger G, van der Merwe S, Monbaliu D Collaborators Leuven Liver Transplant program. Secondary sclerosing cholangitis: an emerging complication in critically ill COVID-19 patients. Intensive Care Med. 2021;47:1037&#x2013;1040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34185115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raes M, De Becker A, Blanckaert J, Balthazar T, De Ridder S, Mekeirele M, Verbrugge FH, Poelaert J, Taccone FS. Veno-venous extra-corporeal membrane oxygenation in a COVID-19 patient with cold-agglutinin haemolytic anaemia: A case report. Perfusion. 2022:2676591221127932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9490382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36128692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fajardo J, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez E, Szafranska J, Poca M, Lobo D, Mart&#xed;n B, Hern&#xe1;ndez D, Roig C, Huerta A, Corominas H, S&#xe1;nchez-Cab&#xfa;s S, Soriano G. We report a patient who presented intrahepatic cholangitis and cholecystitis after SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;36:2037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34105805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pizarro Vega NM, Valer Lopez-Fando P, de la Poza G&#xf3;mez G, Piqueras Alcol B, Gil Santana M, Ruiz Fuentes P, Rodr&#xed;guez Amado MA, Bermejo San Jos&#xe9; F. Secondary sclerosing cholangitis: A complication after severe COVID-19 infection. Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2023;46:462&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9188449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35569544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knooihuizen SAI, Aday A, Lee WM. Ketamine-Induced Sclerosing Cholangitis (KISC) in a Critically Ill Patient With COVID-19. Hepatology. 2021;74:519&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33226658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou T, Fronhoffs F, Dold L, Strassburg CP, Weism&#xfc;ller TJ. New-onset autoimmune hepatitis following mRNA COVID-19 vaccination in a 36-year-old woman with primary sclerosing cholangitis - should we be more vigilant? J Hepatol. 2022;76:218&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8384483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34450237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muehlenberg K, Tannapfel A, Pech O. [80-year-old patient with jaundice after a severe Covid-19 infection] Dtsch Med Wochenschr. 2021;146:13&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33395721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soldera J, Salgado K. Ischemic Gastropathy in a Covid-19 pneumonia patient. Revista da AMRIGS. 65:58&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas M, Rodr&#xed;guez Y, Zapata E, Hern&#xe1;ndez JC, Anaya JM. Cholangiopathy as part of post-COVID syndrome. J Transl Autoimmun. 2021;4:100116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8406516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34485887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caballero-Alvarado J, Zavaleta Corvera C, Merino Bacilio B, Ruiz Caballero C, Lozano-Peralta K. Post-COVID cholangiopathy: A narrative review. Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2023;46:474&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9512521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36174796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franzini TAP, Guedes MMF, Rocha HLOG, Fleury CA, Bestetti AM, Moura EGH. Cholangioscopy in a post-COVID-19 cholangiopathy patient. Arq Gastroenterol. 2022;59:321&#x2013;323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35830050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roda S, Ricciardi A, Maria Di Matteo A, Zecca M, Morbini P, Vecchia M, Chiara Pieri T, Giordani P, Tavano A, Bruno R. Post-acute coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID 19) syndrome: HLH and cholangiopathy in a lung transplant recipient. Clin Infect Pract. 2022;15:100144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9040417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35498053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tebar DMCE, Reis LS, Mineiro GN, Pereira MLDeM, Piassa MLP, Salvajolli RR. Secondary Sclerosing Cholangitis after severe COVID-19: a new possibility in the critically ill patient. Brazilian Journal of Health Review . 2022;5:20&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santisteban Arenas MT, Osorio Castrill&#xf3;n LM, Guevara Casallas LG, Ni&#xf1;o Ram&#xed;rez SF. [Post-COVID-19 severe cholangiopathy: report of 6 cases] Rev Gastroenterol Peru. 2022;42:53&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35896075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>