<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37266140</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2045-8932</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pulmonary circulation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pulm Circ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID syndrome after SARS-CoV-2 survival in patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension and chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e12244</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e12244</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e12244</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/pul2.12244</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) and chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension (CTEPH) patients have a more severe COVID-19 course than the general population. Many patients report different persistent symptoms after SARS-CoV-2 infection. The aim of our study is to analyze the prevalence of long COVID-19 symptoms and assess if COVID-19 affects pulmonary hypertension (PH) prognosis. PAH/CTEPH patients who survived COVID-19 for at least 3 months before visiting the PH centers were included in the study. The patients were assessed for symptoms in acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection and persisting in follow-up visit, WHO functional class, 6-min walk distance, NT-proBNP concentration. The COMPERA 2.0 model was used to calculate 1-year risk of death due to PH at baseline and at follow-up. Sixty-nine patients-54 (77.3%) with PAH and 15 (21.7%) with CTEPH, 68% women, with a median age of 47.5 years (IQR 37-68)-were enrolled in the study. About 17.1% of patients were hospitalized due to COVID-19 but none in an ICU. At follow-up (median: 155 days after onset of SARS-CoV-2 symptoms), 62% of patients reported at least 1 COVID-19-related symptom and 20% at least 5 symptoms. The most frequently reported symptoms were: fatigue (30%), joint pain (23%), muscle pain (17%), nasal congestion (17%), anosmia (13%), insomnia (13%), and dyspnea (12%). Seventy-two percent of PH patients had a low or intermediate-low risk of 1-year death due to PH at baseline, and 68% after COVID-19 at follow-up. Over 60% of PAH/CTEPH patients who survived COVID-19 suffered from long COVID-19 syndrome, but the calculated 1-year risk of death due to PH did not change significantly after surviving mild or moderate COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Pulmonary Circulation published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Pulmonary Vascular Research Institute.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wieteska-Mi&#x142;ek</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6848-5698</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Circulation, Thromboembolic Diseases and Cardiology, European Health Centre Otwock Centre of Postgraduate Medical Education, Member of ERN Lung Warsaw Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ku&#x15b;mierczyk-Droszcz</LastName><ForeName>Beata</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Congenital Heart Disease National Institute of Cardiology Warsaw Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Betkier-Lipi&#x144;ska</LastName><ForeName>Katarzyna</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Internal Diseases Military Institute of Medicine-National Research Institute Warsaw Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Szmit</LastName><ForeName>Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3075-1943</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Circulation, Thromboembolic Diseases and Cardiology, European Health Centre Otwock Centre of Postgraduate Medical Education, Member of ERN Lung Warsaw Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardio-Oncology Department, Centre of Postgraduate Education Institute of Hematology Warsaw Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Florczyk</LastName><ForeName>Micha&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4995-9645</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Circulation, Thromboembolic Diseases and Cardiology, European Health Centre Otwock Centre of Postgraduate Medical Education, Member of ERN Lung Warsaw Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zieli&#x144;ski</LastName><ForeName>Piotr</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5662-8866</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Military Institute of Medicine-National Research Institute Legionowo Hospital Legionowo Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffman</LastName><ForeName>Piotr</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Congenital Heart Disease National Institute of Cardiology Warsaw Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krzesi&#x144;ki</LastName><ForeName>Pawe&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1909-0993</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Internal Diseases Military Institute of Medicine-National Research Institute Warsaw Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurzyna</LastName><ForeName>Marcin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6746-469X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Circulation, Thromboembolic Diseases and Cardiology, European Health Centre Otwock Centre of Postgraduate Medical Education, Member of ERN Lung Warsaw Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pulm Circ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101557243</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-8932</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID&#x2010;19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary arterial hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk of death</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37266140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10232226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pul2.12244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PUL212244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Humbert M, Kovacs G, Hoeper MM, Badagliacca R, Berger RMF, Brida M, Carlsen J, Coats AJS, Escribano&#x2010;Subias P, Ferrari P, Ferreira DS, Ghofrani HA, Giannakoulas G, Kiely DG, Mayer E, Meszaros G, Nagavci B, Olsson KM, Pepke&#x2010;Zaba J, Quint JK, R&#xe5;degran G, Simonneau G, Sitbon O, Tonia T, Toshner M, Vachiery JL, Vonk Noordegraaf A, Delcroix M, Rosenkranz S, Schwerzmann M, Dinh&#x2010;Xuan AT, Bush A, Abdelhamid M, Aboyans V, Arbustini E, Asteggiano R, Barber&#xe0; JA, Beghetti M, &#x10c;elutkien&#x117; J, Cikes M, Condliffe R, de Man F, Falk V, Fauchier L, Gaine S, Gali&#xe9; N, Gin&#x2010;Sing W, Granton J, Gr&#xfc;nig E, Hassoun PM, Hellemons M, Jaarsma T, Kjellstr&#xf6;m B, Klok FA, Konradi A, Koskinas KC, Kotecha D, Lang I, Lewis BS, Linhart A, Lip GYH, L&#xf8;chen ML, Mathioudakis AG, Mindham R, Moledina S, Naeije R, Nielsen JC, Olschewski H, Opitz I, Petersen SE, Prescott E, Rakisheva A, Reis A, Risti&#x107; AD, Roche N, Rodrigues R, Selton&#x2010;Suty C, Souza R, Swift AJ, Touyz RM, Ulrich S, Wilkins MR, Wort SJ. 2022 ESC/ERS guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary hypertension. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:3618&#x2013;731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36017548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonneau G, Montani D, Celermajer DS, Denton CP, Gatzoulis MA, Krowka M, Williams PG, Souza R. Haemodynamic definitions and updated clinical classification of pulmonary hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2019;53:1801913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6351336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30545968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopec G, Kurzyna M, Mroczek E, Chrzanowski &#x141;, Mularek&#x2010;Kubzdela T, Skoczylas I, Ku&#x15b;mierczyk B, Pruszczyk P, B&#x141;aszczak P, Lewicka E, Karasek D, Mizia&#x2010;Stec K, Tomaszewski M, Jache&#x107; W, Ptaszy&#x144;ska&#x2010;Kopczy&#x144;ska K, Peregud&#x2010;Pogorzelska M, Doboszy&#x144;ska A, Pawlak A, G&#x105;sior Z, Zab&#x141;ocka W, Ryczek R, Widejko&#x2010;Pietkiewicz, Walig&#xf3;ra M, Darocha S, Furdal M, Ciurzy&#x144;ski M, Kasprzak JD, Grabka M, Kami&#x144;ski K, Hoffman P, Podolec P, Torbicki A. Characterization of patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension: data from the polish registry of pulmonary hypertension (BNP&#x2010;PL). J Clin Med. 2020;9:173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7019268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31936377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delcroix M, Torbicki A, Gopalan D, Sitbon O, Klok FA, Lang I, Jenkins D, Kim NH, Humbert M, Jais X, Vonk Noordegraaf A, Pepke&#x2010;Zaba J, Br&#xe9;not P, Dorfmuller P, Fadel E, Ghofrani HA, Hoeper MM, Jansa P, Madani M, Matsubara H, Ogo T, Gr&#xfc;nig E, D'Armini A, Galie N, Meyer B, Corkery P, Meszaros G, Mayer E, Simonneau G. ERS statement on chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2021;57:2002828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33334946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopec G, Dzikowska&#x2010;Diduch O, Mroczek E, Mularek&#x2010;Kubzdela T, Chrzanowski &#x141;, Skoczylas I, Tomaszewski M, Peregud&#x2010;Pogorzelska M, Karasek D, Lewicka E, Jache&#x107; W, G&#x105;sior Z, B&#x141;aszczak P, Ptaszy&#x144;ska&#x2010;Kopczy&#x144;ska K, Mizia&#x2010;Stec K, Biederman A, Zieli&#x144;ski D, Przybylski R, K&#x119;dzierski P, Walig&#xf3;ra M, Roik M, Grabka M, Or&#x141;owska J, Araszkiewicz A, Banaszkiewicz M, S&#x141;awek&#x2010;Szmyt S, Darocha S, Mago&#x144; W, D&#x105;browska&#x2010;Kugacka A, St&#x119;pniewski J, Jonas K, Kami&#x144;ski K, Kasprzak JD, Podolec P, Pruszczyk P, Torbicki A, Kurzyna M. Characteristics and outcomes of patients with chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension in the era of modern therapeutic approaches: data from the polish multicenter registry (BNP&#x2010;PL). Ther Adv Chronic Dis. 2021;12:20406223211002961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8010818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33854746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organiozation General Director&#x2010;Speaches
. General's opening remarks at the media briefing on COVID&#x2010;19&#x2010;11 March 2020. [cited 2023 Feb 2]. Available from: https://www.who.int/director-general/speeches/detail/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-the-media-briefing-on-covid-19---11-march-2020
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuche J, P&#xe9;rez&#x2010;Olivares C, Segura de la Cal T, Jim&#xe9;nez L&#xf3;pez&#x2010;Guarch C, Arribas Ynsaurriaga F, Escribano Sub&#xed;as P. Curso cl&#xed;nico de la COVID&#x2010;19 en pacientes con hipertensi&#xf3;n arterial pulmonar. Rev Esp Cardiol. 2020;73:775&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7321018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32834367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montani D, Certain MC, Weatherald J, Ja&#xef;s X, Bulifon S, Noel&#x2010;Savina E, Nieves A, Renard S, Traclet J, Bouvaist H, Riou M, de Groote P, Moceri P, Bertoletti L, Favrolt N, Guillaumot A, Jutant EM, Beurnier A, Boucly A, Ebstein N, Jevnikar M, Pichon J, Keddache S, Preda M, Roche A, Solinas S, Seferian A, Reynaud&#x2010;Gaubert M, Cottin V, Savale L, Humbert M, Sitbon O, Kais A, Elise AM, C&#xe9;line C, Ari C, Claire D, Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric G, Anne G, S&#xe9;bastien H, Delphine HL, Jocelyn I, Bouchra L, Pascal M, Jean&#x2010;Claude M, Patrice P, Gr&#xe9;goire P, Roger R, Servettaz A. COVID&#x2010;19 in patients with pulmonary hypertension: a national prospective cohort study. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2022;206:573&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9716894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35549842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belge C, Quarck R, Godinas L, Montani D, Escribano Subias P, Vachi&#xe9;ry JL, Nashat H, Pepke&#x2010;Zaba J, Humbert M, Delcroix M. COVID&#x2010;19 in pulmonary arterial hypertension and chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension: a reference centre survey. ERJ Open Res. 2020;6:00520&#x2010;2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7682715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33263061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JD, Burger CD, Delossantos GB, Grinnan D, Ralph DD, Rayner SG, Ryan JJ, Safdar Z, Ventetuolo CE, Zamanian RT, Leary PJ. A survey&#x2010;based estimate of COVID&#x2010;19 incidence and outcomes among patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension or chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension and impact on the process of care. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2020;17:1576&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7706604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32726561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farmakis IT, Karyofyllis P, Frantzeskaki F, Demerouti E, Anthi A, Arvanitaki A, Pitsiou G, Naka KK, Bechlioulis A, Thomaidi A, Avgeropoulou A, Brili S, Mitrouska I, Manginas A, Orfanos SE, Tsangaris I, Giannakoulas G. Incidence and outcomes of COVID&#x2010;19 in patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension and chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension: data from the Hellenic pulmOnary hyPertension rEgistry (HOPE). Hellenic J Cardiol. 2022;64:93&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8619882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34843997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wieteska&#x2010;Milek M, Kusmierczyk&#x2010;Droszcz B, Ryczek R, Szmit S, Florczyk M, Ma&#x144;czak R, Betkier&#x2010;Lipi&#x144;ska K, Hoffman P, Krzesi&#x144;ski P, Torbicki A, Kurzyna M. Outcomes of COVID&#x2010;19 in patients vaccinated and unvaccinated against SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 and suffering from pulmonary arterial hypertension and chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension. Pol Arch Intern Med. 2023;133:16406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36602859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badagliacca R, Papa S, D'Alto M, Ghio S, Agostoni P, Ameri P, Argiento P, Brunetti ND, Casamassima V, Casu G, Cedrone N, Confalonieri M, Corda M, Correale M, D'Agostino C, De Michele L, Famoso G, Galgano G, Greco A, Lombardi CM, Manzi G, Madonna R, Mercurio V, Mul&#xe8; M, Paciocco G, Romaniello A, Romeo E, Scelsi L, Serra W, Stolfo D, Toma M, Vatrano M, Vitulo P, Vizza CD. The paradox of pulmonary arterial hypertension in Italy in the COVID&#x2010;19 era: is risk of disease progression around the corner? Eur Respir J. 2022;60:2102276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9535117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35301247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farmakis IT, Giannakoulas G. Management of COVID&#x2010;19 in patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension. Heart Fail Clin. 2023;19:107&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9364740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36435565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driggin E, Maddox TM, Ferdinand KC, Kirkpatrick JN, Ky B, Morris AA, Mullen JB, Parikh SA, Philbin DM, Vaduganathan M. ACC health policy statement on cardiovascular disease considerations for COVID&#x2010;19 vaccine prioritization. JACC. 2021;77:1938&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7880623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33587998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A'Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. Management of post&#x2010;acute covid&#x2010;19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020;370:m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, Hishmeh L. Managing the long term effects of covid&#x2010;19: summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ. 2021;372:n136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis. 2021;53:737&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naeije R, Caravita S. Phenotyping long COVID. Eur Respir J. 2021;58:2101763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8287735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34244323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Alberts J, Oben J, Cuthbertson DJ, Wootton D, Crooks M, Gabbay M, Brady M, Hishmeh L, Attree E, Heightman M, Banerjee R, Banerjee A. Multiorgan impairment in low&#x2010;risk individuals with post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome: a prospective, community&#x2010;based study. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e048391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang L, Yang B, Jiang N, Fu W, He X, Zhou Y, Ma WL, Wang X. Three&#x2010;month follow&#x2010;up study of survivors of coronavirus disease 2019 after discharge. J Korean Med Sci. 2020;35:e418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7721559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33289374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen MS, Kristiansen MF, Hanusson KD, Danielsen ME, &#xe1; Steig B, Gaini S, Str&#xf8;m M, Weihe P. Long COVID in the Faroe Islands: a longitudinal study among nonhospitalized patients. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e4058&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7799340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33252665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, Ghanima W, Olsen MK, Gilboe HM, Einvik G. Persistent symptoms 1.5&#x2010;6 months after COVID&#x2010;19 in non&#x2010;hospitalised subjects: a population&#x2010;based cohort study. Thorax. 2021;76:405&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues E, Janvier P, Kherabi Y, Le Bot A, Hamon A, Gouze H, Doucet L, Berkani S, Oliosi E, Mallart E, Corre F, Zarrouk V, Moyer JD, Galy A, Honsel V, Fantin B, Nguyen Y. Post&#x2010;discharge persistent symptoms and health&#x2010;related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID&#x2010;19. J Infect. 2020;81:e4&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laboratories ATSCoPSfCPF . ATS statement: guidelines for the six&#x2010;minute walk test. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2002;166:111&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12091180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeper MM, Pausch C, Olsson KM, Huscher D, Pittrow D, Gr&#xfc;nig E, Staehler G, Vizza CD, Gall H, Distler O, Opitz C, Gibbs JSR, Delcroix M, Ghofrani HA, Park DH, Ewert R, Kaemmerer H, Kabitz HJ, Skowasch D, Behr J, Milger K, Halank M, Wilkens H, Seyfarth HJ, Held M, Dumitrescu D, Tsangaris I, Vonk&#x2010;Noordegraaf A, Ulrich S, Klose H, Claussen M, Lange TJ, Rosenkranz S. COMPERA 2.0: a refined four&#x2010;stratum risk assessment model for pulmonary arterial hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2022;60:2102311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9260123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34737226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stubbs H, Lua S, Brewis M, Johnson M, Church C. COMPERA 2.0 risk stratification in medically managed chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2022;60:2200313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35798358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Li X, Jin Q, Luo Q, Zhao Q, Yang T, Zeng Q, Yan L, Duan A, Huang Z, Hu M, Xiong C, Zhao Z, Liu Z. The original and two new derivative versions of the COMPERA 2.0 risk assessment model: useful tools for guiding balloon pulmonary angioplasty. Respir Res. 2022;23:312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9664665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36376902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulica R, Cefali F, Motschwiller C, Fenton R, Barroso A, Sterman D. COVID&#x2010;19 in pulmonary artery hypertension (PAH) patients: observations from a large PAH center in New York city. Diagnostics. 2021;11:128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7829711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, Kang L, Guo L, Liu M, Zhou X, Luo J, Huang Z, Tu S, Zhao Y, Chen L, Xu D, Li Y, Li C, Peng L, Li Y, Xie W, Cui D, Shang L, Fan G, Xu J, Wang G, Wang Y, Zhong J, Wang C, Wang J, Zhang D, Cao B. 6&#x2010;month consequences of COVID&#x2010;19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li X, Geng D, Mei N, Wu PY, Huang CC, Jia T, Zhao Y, Wang D, Xiao A, Yin B. Cerebral micro&#x2010;structural changes in COVID&#x2010;19 patients&#x2014;an MRI&#x2010;based 3&#x2010;month follow&#x2010;up study. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnweber T, Sahanic S, Pizzini A, Luger A, Schwabl C, Sonnweber B, Kurz K, Koppelst&#xe4;tter S, Haschka D, Petzer V, Boehm A, Aichner M, Tymoszuk P, Lener D, Theurl M, Lorsbach&#x2010;K&#xf6;hler A, Tancevski A, Schapfl A, Schaber M, Hilbe R, Nairz M, Puchner B, H&#xfc;ttenberger D, Tschurtschenthaler C, A&#xdf;hoff M, Peer A, Hartig F, Bellmann R, Joannidis M, Gollmann&#x2010;Tepek&#xf6;yl&#xfc; C, Holfeld J, Feuchtner G, Egger A, Hoermann G, Schroll A, Fritsche G, Wildner S, Bellmann&#x2010;Weiler R, Kirchmair R, Helbok R, Prosch H, Rieder D, Trajanoski Z, Kronenberg F, W&#xf6;ll E, Weiss G, Widmann G, L&#xf6;ffler&#x2010;Ragg J, Tancevski I. Cardiopulmonary recovery after COVID&#x2010;19: an observational prospective multicentre trial. Eur Respir J. 2021;57:2003481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, Pujol JC, Klaser K, Antonelli M, Canas LS, Molteni E, Modat M, Jorge Cardoso M, May A, Ganesh S, Davies R, Nguyen LH, Drew DA, Astley CM, Joshi AD, Merino J, Tsereteli N, Fall T, Gomez MF, Duncan EL, Menni C, Williams FMK, Franks PW, Chan AT, Wolf J, Ourselin S, Spector T, Steves CJ. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nature Med. 2021;27:626&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, Dunne J, Mooney A, Gaffney F, O'Connor L, Leavy D, O'Brien K, Dowds J, Sugrue JA, Hopkins D, Martin&#x2010;Loeches I, Ni Cheallaigh C, Nadarajan P, McLaughlin AM, Bourke NM, Bergin C, O'Farrelly C, Bannan C, Conlon N. Persistent fatigue following SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boucly A, Weatherald J, Savale L, de Groote P, Cottin V, Pr&#xe9;vot G, Chaouat A, Picard F, Horeau&#x2010;Langlard D, Bourdin A, Jutant EM, Beurnier A, Jevnikar M, Ja&#xef;s X, Simonneau G, Montani D, Sitbon O, Humbert M. External validation of a refined four&#x2010;stratum risk assessment score from the French pulmonary hypertension registry. Eur Respir J. 2022;59:2102419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9245192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34737227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>