<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38656671</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-4927</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biochemical genetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biochem Genet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identification of Age-Related Characteristic Genes Involved in Severe COVID-19 Infection Among Elderly Patients Using Machine Learning and Immune Cell Infiltration Analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10528-024-10802-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Elderly patients infected with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 are at higher risk of severe clinical manifestation, extended hospitalization, and increased mortality. Those patients are more likely to experience persistent symptoms and exacerbate the condition of basic diseases with long COVID-19 syndrome. However, the molecular mechanisms underlying severe COVID-19 in the elderly patients remain unclear. Our study aims to investigate the function of the interaction between disease-characteristic genes and immune cell infiltration in patients with severe COVID-19 infection. COVID-19 datasets (GSE164805 and GSE180594) and aging dataset (GSE69832) were obtained from the Gene Expression Omnibus database. The combined different expression genes (DEGs) were subjected to Gene Ontology (GO) functional enrichment analysis, Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) pathway and Diseases Ontology functional enrichment analysis, Gene Set Enrichment Analysis, machine learning, and immune cell infiltration analysis. GO and KEGG enrichment analyses revealed that the eight DEGs (IL23A, PTGER4, PLCB1, IL1B, CXCR1, C1QB, MX2, ALOX12) were mainly involved in inflammatory mediator regulation of TRP channels, coronavirus disease-COVID-19, and cytokine activity signaling pathways. Three-degree algorithm (LASSO, SVM-RFE, KNN) and correlation analysis showed that the five DEGs up-regulated the immune cells of macrophages M0/M1, memory B cells, gamma delta T cell, dendritic cell resting, and master cell resisting. Our study identified five hallmark genes that can serve as disease-characteristic genes and target immune cells infiltrated in severe COVID-19 patients among the elderly population, which may contribute to the study of pathogenesis and the evaluation of diagnosis and prognosis in aging patients infected with severe COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Huan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Xijing Hospital, Fourth Military Medical University, No. 127 Chang le West Road, Xi'an, 710032, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, The Second People's Hospital of Shaan xi Province, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Jin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Xijing Hospital, Fourth Military Medical University, No. 127 Chang le West Road, Xi'an, 710032, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Xijing Hospital, Fourth Military Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xing</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Xijing Hospital, Fourth Military Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wen</LastName><ForeName>Ziying</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Xijing Hospital, Fourth Military Medical University, No. 127 Chang le West Road, Xi'an, 710032, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Fengxia</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Xijing Hospital, Fourth Military Medical University, No. 127 Chang le West Road, Xi'an, 710032, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Boyong</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Xijing Hospital, Fourth Military Medical University, No. 127 Chang le West Road, Xi'an, 710032, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Xijing Hospital, Fourth Military Medical University, No. 127 Chang le West Road, Xi'an, 710032, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Cui</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Xijing Hospital, Fourth Military Medical University, No. 127 Chang le West Road, Xi'an, 710032, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Xijing Hospital, Fourth Military Medical University, No. 127 Chang le West Road, Xi'an, 710032, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ning</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoxuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Xijing Hospital, Fourth Military Medical University, No. 127 Chang le West Road, Xi'an, 710032, Shaanxi, China. ningxx01@fmmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 2021E010</GrantID><Agency>Health Research Project of Shaanxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 82270715</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No.2023-ZDLSF-15</GrantID><Agency>Key Research and Development Program of Shaanxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Biochem Genet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0126611</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0006-2928</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Differentially expressed genes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immune cell infiltration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38656671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10528-024-10802-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10528-024-10802-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>COvid-19 Multi-omics Blood ATlas (COMBAT) Consortium. (2022) A blood atlas of COVID-19 defines hallmarks of disease severity and specificity. Cell. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2022.01.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbouti A, Evangelou K, Pateras IS, Papoudou-Bai A, Patereli A, Stefanaki K, Rontogianni D, Mu&#xf1;oz-Esp&#xed;n D, Kanavaros P, Gorgoulis VG (2019) In situ evidence of cellular senescence in thymic epithelial cells (TECs) during human thymic involution. Mech Ageing Dev 177:88&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mad.2018.02.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mad.2018.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29490231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betancor G, Jimenez-Guarde&#xf1;o JM, Lynham S, Antrobus R, Khan H, Sobala A, Dicks MDJ, Malim MH (2021) MX2-mediated innate immunity against HIV-1 is regulated by serine phosphorylation. Nat Microbiol 6(8):1031&#x2013;1042. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41564-021-00937-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41564-021-00937-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34282309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7611661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian Z, Vong CM, Wong PK, Wang S (2022) Fuzzy KNN method with adaptive nearest neighbors. IEEE Trans Cybern 52(6):5380&#x2013;5393. https://doi.org/10.1109/TCYB.2020.3031610</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCYB.2020.3031610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33232252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blake JA, Dolan M, Drabkin H, Hill DP, Li N, Sitnikov D, Bridges S, Burgess S, Buza T, McCarthy F, Peddinti D, Pillai L, Carbon S, Dietze H, Ireland A, Lewis SE, Mungall CJ, Gaudet P, Chrisholm RL, Fey P, Kibbe WA, Basu S, Siegele DA, McIntosh BK, Renfro DP, Zweifel AE, Hu JC, Brown NH, Tweedie S, Alam-Faruque Y, Apweiler R, Auchinchloss A, Axelsen K, Bely B, Blatter MC, Bonilla C, Bouguerleret L, Boutet E, Breuza L, Bridge A, Chan WM, Chavali G, Coudert E, Dimmer E, Estreicher A, Famiglietti L, Feuermann M, Gos A, Gruaz-Gumowski N, Hieta R, Hinz C, Hulo C, Huntley R, James J, Jungo F, Keller G, Laiho K, Legge D, Lemercier P, Lieberherr D, Magrane M, Martin MJ, Masson P, Mutowo-Muellenet P, O&#x2019;Donovan C, Pedruzzi I, Pichler K, Poggioli D, Porras Mill&#xe1;n P, Poux S, Rivoire C, Roechert B, Sawford T, Schneider M, Stutz A, Sundaram S, Tognolli M, Xenarios I, Foulgar R, Lomax J, Roncaglia P, Khodiyar VK, Lovering RC, Talmud PJ, Chibucos M, Giglio MG, Chang HY, Hunter S, McAnulla C, Mitchell A, Sangrador A, Stephan R, Harris MA, Oliver SG, Rutherford K, Wood V, Bahler J, Lock A, Kersey PJ, McDowall DM, Staines DM, Dwinell M, Shimoyama M, Laulederkind S, Hayman T, Wang SJ, Petri V, Lowry T, D&#x2019;Eustachio P, Matthews L, Balakrishnan R, Binkley G, Cherry JM, Costanzo MC, Dwight SS, Engel SR, Fisk DG, Hitz BC, Hong EL, Karra K, Miyasato SR, Nash RS, Park J, Skrzypek MS, Weng S, Wong ED, Berardini TZ, Huala E, Mi H, Thomas PD, Chan J, Kishore R, Sternberg P, Van Auken K, Howe D, Westerfield M (2013) Gene Ontology annotations and resources. Nucleic Acids Res 41:D530&#x2013;D535. https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gks1050</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gks1050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23161678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao X, Li W, Wang T, Ran D, Davalos V, Planas-Serra L, Pujol A, Esteller M, Wang X, Yu H (2022) Accelerated biological aging in COVID-19 patients. Nat Commun 13(1):2135. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-022-29801-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-29801-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35440567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9018863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Agnillo F, Walters K-A, Xiao Y, Sheng Z-M, Scherler K, Park J, Gygli S, Rosas LA, Sadtler K, Kalish H, Blatti CA, Zhu R, Gatzke L, Bushell C, Memoli MJ, O&#x2019;Day SJ, Fischer TD, Hammond TC, Lee RC, Cash JC, Powers ME, O&#x2019;Keefe GE, Butnor KJ, Rapkiewicz AV, Travis WD, Layne SP, Kash JC, Taubenberger JK (2021) Lung epithelial and endothelial damage, loss of tissue repair, inhibition of fibrinolysis, and cellular senescence in fatal COVID-19. Sci Transl Med. https://doi.org/10.1126/scitranslmed.abj7790</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.abj7790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34648357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11000440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhayni K, Zibara K, Issa H, Kamel S, Bennis Y (2022) Targeting CXCR1 and CXCR2 receptors in cardiovascular diseases. Pharmacol Ther 237:108257. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pharmthera.2022.108257</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pharmthera.2022.108257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35908611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domizio JD, Gulen MF, Saidoune F, Thacker VV, Yatim A, Sharma K, Nass T, Guenova E, Schaller M, Conrad C, Goepfert C, de Leval L, Cv G, Berezowska S, Dubois A, Gilliet M, Ablasser A (2022) The cGAS-STING pathway drives type I IFN immunopathology in COVID-19. Nature 603(7899):145&#x2013;151. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-022-04421-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-022-04421-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35045565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8891013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egolf S, Zou J, Anderson A, Simpson CL, Aubert Y, Prouty S, Ge K, Seykora JT, Capell BC (2021) MLL4 mediates differentiation and tumor suppression through ferroptosis. Sci Adv. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.abj9141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.abj9141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34890228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8664260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu YW, Xu HS, Liu SJ (2022) COVID-19 and neurodegenerative diseases. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci 26(12):4535&#x2013;4544. https://doi.org/10.26355/eurrev_202206_29093</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26355/eurrev_202206_29093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35776055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieshaber-Bouyer R, Exner T, Hackert NS, Radtke FA, Jelinsky SA, Halyabar O, Wactor A, Karimizadeh E, Brennan J, Schettini J, Jonsson H, Rao DA, Henderson LA, M&#xfc;ller-Tidow C, Lorenz H-M, Wabnitz G, Lederer JA, Hadjipanayis A, Nigrovic PA (2022) Ageing and interferon gamma response drive the phenotype of neutrophils in the inflamed joint. Ann Rheum Dis 81(6):805&#x2013;814. https://doi.org/10.1136/annrheumdis-2021-221866</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2021-221866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35168946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;nes G&#xfc;nsel G, Conlon TM, Jeridi A, Kim R, Ert&#xfc;z Z, Lang NJ, Ansari M, Novikova M, Jiang D, Strunz M, Gaianova M, Hollauer C, Gabriel C, Angelidis I, Doll S, Pestoni JC, Edelmann SL, Kohlhepp MS, Guillot A, Bassler K, Van Eeckhoutte HP, Kayalar &#xd6;, Konyalilar N, Kanashova T, Rodius S, Ballester-L&#xf3;pez C, Genes Robles CM, Smirnova N, Rehberg M, Agarwal C, Krikki I, Piavaux B, Verleden SE, Vanaudenaerde B, K&#xf6;nigshoff M, Dittmar G, Bracke KR, Schultze JL, Watz H, Eickelberg O, Stoeger T, Burgstaller G, Tacke F, Heissmeyer V, Rinkevich Y, Bayram H, Schiller HB, Conrad M, Schneider R, Yildirim A&#xd6; (2022) The arginine methyltransferase PRMT7 promotes extravasation of monocytes resulting in tissue injury in COPD. Nat Commun 13(1):1303. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-022-28809-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-28809-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35288557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8921220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haffke M, Freitag H, Rudolf G, Seifert M, Doehner W, Scherbakov N, Hanitsch L, Wittke K, Bauer S, Konietschke F, Paul F, Bellmann-Strobl J, Kedor C, Scheibenbogen C, Sotzny F (2022) Endothelial dysfunction and altered endothelial biomarkers in patients with post-COVID-19 syndrome and chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). J Transl Med 20(1):138. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967-022-03346-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-022-03346-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35317812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8938726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, Walshaw C, Kemp S, Corrado J, Singh R, Collins T, O&#x2019;Connor RJ, Sivan M (2021) Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol 93(2):1013&#x2013;1022. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.26368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S, Cai N, Pacheco PP, Narrandes S, Wang Y, Xu W (2018) Applications of support vector machine (SVM) learning in cancer genomics. Cancer Genomics Proteomics 15(1):41&#x2013;51</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29275361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irizar H, Go&#xf1;i J, Alzualde A, Castillo-Trivi&#xf1;o T, Olascoaga J, Lopez de Munain A, Otaegui D (2015) Age gene expression and coexpression progressive signatures in peripheral blood leukocytes. Exp Gerontol 72:50&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.exger.2015.09.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2015.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26362218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji L, Guo W (2023) Single-cell RNA sequencing highlights the roles of C1QB and NKG7 in the pancreatic islet immune microenvironment in type 1 diabetes mellitus. Pharmacol Res 187:106588. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.phrs.2022.106588</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2022.106588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36464147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanehisa M, Furumichi M, Tanabe M, Sato Y, Morishima K (2017) KEGG: new perspectives on genomes, pathways, diseases and drugs. Nucleic Acids Res 45(D1):D353&#x2013;D361. https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkw1092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkw1092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27899662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koelle K, Martin MA, Antia R, Lopman B, Dean NE (2022) The changing epidemiology of SARS-CoV-2. Science 375(6585):1116&#x2013;1121. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.abm4915</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abm4915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35271324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9009722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koff WC, Williams MA (2020) Covid-19 and immunity in aging populations&#x2014;a new research agenda. N Engl J Med 383(9):804&#x2013;805. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMp2006761</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMp2006761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32302079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Park S, Jeong HW, Ahn JY, Choi SJ, Lee H, Choi B, Nam SK, Sa M, Kwon J-S, Jeong SJ, Lee HK, Park SH, Park S-H, Choi JY, Kim S-H, Jung I, Shin E-C (2020) Immunophenotyping of COVID-19 and influenza highlights the role of type I interferons in development of severe COVID-19. Sci Immunol. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciimmunol.abd1554</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciimmunol.abd1554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33361161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8101131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levi M, Thachil J, Iba T, Levy JH (2020) Coagulation abnormalities and thrombosis in patients with COVID-19. Lancet Haematol 7(6):e438&#x2013;e440. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2352-3026(20)30145-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-3026(20)30145-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32407672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7213964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang S, Guo H, Ma K, Li X, Wu D, Wang Y, Wang W, Zhang S, Cui Y, Liu Y, Sun L, Zhang B, Xin M, Zhang N, Zhou H, Liu Y, Wang J, Liu L (2021) A PLCB1-PI3K-AKT signaling axis activates EMT to promote cholangiocarcinoma progression. Cancer Res 81(23):5889&#x2013;5903. https://doi.org/10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-21-1538</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-21-1538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9397629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Chen Y, Lin R, Han K (2020) Clinical features of COVID-19 in elderly patients: a comparison with young and middle-aged patients. J Infect 80(6):e14&#x2013;e18. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2020.03.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2020.03.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32171866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7102640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Shen Y, Cavdar O, Huang J, Fang H (2023a) Angiotensin II-induced vascular endothelial cells ferroptosis via P53-ALOX12 signal axis. Clin Exp Hypertens 45(1):2180019. https://doi.org/10.1080/10641963.2023.2180019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10641963.2023.2180019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36860117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Liang Q, Ren Y, Guo C, Ge X, Wang L, Cheng Q, Luo P, Zhang Y, Han X (2023b) Immunosenescence: molecular mechanisms and diseases. Signal Transduct Target Ther 8(1):200. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41392-023-01451-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41392-023-01451-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37179335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10182360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, McAuley DF, Brown M, Sanchez E, Tattersall RS, Manson JJ (2020) COVID-19: consider cytokine storm syndromes and immunosuppression. Lancet 395(10229):1033&#x2013;1034. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30628-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30628-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7270045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata N, Takeuchi T, Masuoka H, Aoki R, Ishikane M, Iwamoto N, Sugiyama M, Suda W, Nakanishi Y, Terada-Hirashima J, Kimura M, Nishijima T, Inooka H, Miyoshi-Akiyama T, Kojima Y, Shimokawa C, Hisaeda H, Zhang F, Yeoh YK, Ng SC, Uemura N, Itoi T, Mizokami M, Kawai T, Sugiyama H, Ohmagari N, Ohno H (2023) Human gut microbiota and its metabolites impact immune responses in COVID-19 and its complications. Gastroenterology 164(2):272&#x2013;288. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2022.09.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2022.09.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36155191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naser MN, Al-Ghatam R, Darwish AH, Alqahtani MM, Alahmadi HA, Mohamed KA, Hasan NK, Perez NS (2021) Risk factors, predictions, and progression of acute kidney injury in hospitalized COVID-19 patients: an observational retrospective cohort study. PLoS ONE 16(9):e0257253. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0257253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0257253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34587189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8480894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T, Hittle M, Goodman SN (2021) Assessment of the frequency and variety of persistent symptoms among patients with COVID-19: a systematic review. JAMA Netw Open 4(5):e2111417. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.11417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.11417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34037731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8155823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman AM, Liu CL, Green MR, Gentles AJ, Feng W, Xu Y, Hoang CD, Diehn M, Alizadeh AA (2015) Robust enumeration of cell subsets from tissue expression profiles. Nat Methods 12(5):453&#x2013;457. https://doi.org/10.1038/nmeth.3337</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nmeth.3337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25822800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4739640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrobon AJ, Teixeira FME, Sato MN (2020) Immunosenescence and inflammaging: risk factors of severe COVID-19 in older people. Front Immunol 11:579220. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2020.579220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2020.579220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33193377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7656138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polidori MC, Sies H, Ferrucci L, Benzing T (2021) COVID-19 mortality as a fingerprint of biological age. Ageing Res Rev 67:101308. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arr.2021.101308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2021.101308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33621704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7896489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retuerto M, Lled&#xf3; A, Fernandez-Varas B, Guerrero-L&#xf3;pez R, Usategui A, Lalueza A, Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a R, Mancebo E, Paz-Artal E, Sastre L, Perona R, Pablos JL (2022) Shorter telomere length is associated with COVID-19 hospitalization and with persistence of radiographic lung abnormalities. Immun Ageing 19(1):38. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12979-022-00294-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12979-022-00294-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35996190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9394033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Vazquez R, Gu&#xed;o-Carri&#xf3;n A, Zapatero-Gaviria A, Mart&#xed;nez P, Blasco MA (2021) Shorter telomere lengths in patients with severe COVID-19 disease. Aging. https://doi.org/10.18632/aging.202463</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.202463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7835063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santoro A, Bientinesi E, Monti D (2021) Immunosenescence and inflammaging in the aging process: age-related diseases or longevity? Ageing Res Rev 71:101422. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arr.2021.101422</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2021.101422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34391943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt CA, Tchkonia T, Niedernhofer LJ, Robbins PD, Kirkland JL, Lee S (2023) COVID-19 and cellular senescence. Nat Rev Immunol 23(4):251&#x2013;263. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41577-022-00785-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-022-00785-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36198912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schriml LM, Munro JB, Schor M, Olley D, McCracken C, Felix V, Baron JA, Jackson R, Bello SM, Bearer C, Lichenstein R, Bisordi K, Dialo NC, Giglio M, Greene C (2022) The Human disease ontology 2022 update. Nucleic Acids Res 50(D1):D1255&#x2013;D1261. https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkab1063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkab1063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34755882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen B, Yi X, Sun Y, Bi X, Du J, Zhang C, Quan S, Zhang F, Sun R, Qian L, Ge W, Liu W, Liang S, Chen H, Zhang Y, Li J, Xu J, He Z, Chen B, Wang J, Yan H, Zheng Y, Wang D, Zhu J, Kong Z, Kang Z, Liang X, Ding X, Ruan G, Xiang N, Cai X, Gao H, Li L, Li S, Xiao Q, Lu T, Zhu Y, Liu H, Chen H, Guo T (2020) Proteomic and metabolomic characterization of COVID-19 patient sera. Cell. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2020.05.032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.05.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33357448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8043252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sozen B, Jorgensen V, Weatherbee BAT, Chen S, Zhu M, Zernicka-Goetz M (2021) Reconstructing aspects of human embryogenesis with pluripotent stem cells. Nat Commun 12(1):5550. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-25853-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-25853-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34548496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8455697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Tamayo P, Mootha VK, Mukherjee S, Ebert BL, Gillette MA, Paulovich A, Pomeroy SL, Golub TR, Lander ES, Mesirov JP (2005) Gene set enrichment analysis: a knowledge-based approach for interpreting genome-wide expression profiles. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 102(43):15545&#x2013;15550</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0506580102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16199517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1239896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syed MN, Shin DB, Wan MT, Winthrop KL, Gelfand JM (2020) The risk of respiratory tract infections in patients with psoriasis treated with interleukin 23 pathway-inhibiting biologics: a meta-estimate of pivotal trials relevant to decision making during the COVID-19 pandemic. J Am Acad Dermatol 83(5):1523&#x2013;1526. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaad.2020.06.1014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2020.06.1014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32622891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7331500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teijeira &#xc1;, Garasa S, Gato M, Alfaro C, Migueliz I, Cirella A, de Andrea C, Ochoa MC, Otano I, Etxeberria I, Andueza MP, Nieto CP, Resano L, Azpilikueta A, Allegretti M, de Pizzol M, Ponz-Sarvis&#xe9; M, Rouzaut A, Sanmamed MF, Schalper K, Carleton M, Mellado M, Rodriguez-Ruiz ME, Berraondo P, Perez-Gracia JL, Melero I (2020) CXCR1 and CXCR2 chemokine receptor agonists produced by tumors induce neutrophil extracellular traps that interfere with immune cytotoxicity. Immunity. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.immuni.2020.03.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2020.03.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32289253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibshirani R (1996) Regression shrinkage and selection via the lasso: a retrospective. J R Stat Soc Ser B: Stat Methodol 58(1):267&#x2013;288</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.2517-6161.1996.tb02080.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utrero-Rico A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Cuadrado C, Chivite-Lacaba M, Cabrera-Marante O, Laguna-Goya R, Almendro-Vazquez P, D&#xed;az-Pedroche C, Ruiz-Ruig&#xf3;mez M, Lalueza A, Folgueira MD, V&#xe1;zquez E, Quintas A, Berges-Buxeda MJ, Mart&#xed;n-Rodriguez M, Dopazo A, Serrano-Hern&#xe1;ndez A, Aguado JM, Paz-Artal E (2021) Alterations in circulating monocytes predict COVID-19 severity and include chromatin modifications still detectable six months after recovery. Biomedicines. https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines9091253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines9091253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34829769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8614904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y-X, Niklasch M, Liu T, Wang Y, Shi B, Yuan W, Baumert TF, Yuan Z, Tong S, Nassal M, Wen Y-M (2020) Interferon-inducible MX2 is a host restriction factor of hepatitis B virus replication. J Hepatol 72(5):865&#x2013;876. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhep.2019.12.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2019.12.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31863794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Fu P, Li J, Jing Z, Wang Q, Zhao D, Zhou C (2021) Changes in psychological distress before and during the COVID-19 pandemic among older adults: the contribution of frailty transitions and multimorbidity. Age Ageing 50(4):1011&#x2013;1018. https://doi.org/10.1093/ageing/afab061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afab061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33710264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Yang Z, Yu H, Lin W, Wu R, Yang H, Yang K (2022a) Predicting diagnostic gene expression profiles associated with immune infiltration in patients with lupus nephritis. Front Immunol 13:839197. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2022.839197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.839197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36532018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9755505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Dong C, Han Y, Gu Z, Sun C (2022b) Immunosenescence, aging and successful aging. Front Immunol 13:942796. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2022.942796</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.942796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35983061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9379926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Zhang F, Shi Y, Chen Y, Shi B, Yu G (2022) Causal association of epigenetic aging and COVID-19 severity and susceptibility: a bidirectional Mendelian randomization study. Front Med 9:989950. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2022.989950</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.989950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Meng Y, Wang K, Zhang X, Chen W, Sheng J, Qiu Y, Diao H, Li L (2021) Inflammation and antiviral immune response associated with severe progression of COVID-19. Front Immunol 12:631226. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.631226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.631226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33679778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7930228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Wan Y, Zuo T, Yeoh YK, Liu Q, Zhang L, Zhan H, Lu W, Xu W, Lui GCY, Li AYL, Cheung CP, Wong CK, Chan PKS, Chan FKL, Ng SC (2022a) Prolonged impairment of short-chain fatty acid and L-isoleucine biosynthesis in gut microbiome in patients with COVID-19. Gastroenterology. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2021.10.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2021.10.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36592730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9759874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Wang J, Liu Z, Zhang L, Jing J, Han L, Gao A (2022b) Iron-dependent ferroptosis participated in benzene-induced anemia of inflammation through IRP1-DHODH-ALOX12 axis. Free Radic Biol Med 193(Pt 1):122&#x2013;133. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2022.10.273</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2022.10.273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36244588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Sun X, Tan S, Luo C, Zhou J, Zhang S, Li Z, Lin H, Zhang W (2022) M2 macrophage-related gene signature in chronic rhinosinusitis with nasal polyps. Front Immunol 13:1047930. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2022.1047930</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.1047930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36466903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9712459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinatizadeh MR, Zarandi PK, Ghiasi M, Kooshki H, Mohammadi M, Amani J, Rezaei N (2023) Immunosenescence and inflamm-ageing in COVID-19. Ageing Res Rev 84:101818. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arr.2022.101818</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2022.101818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36516928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>