<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35447302</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1090-2139</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>103</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Brain, behavior, and immunity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Brain Behav Immun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Six-month sequelae of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection: A retrospective cohort study of 10,024 breakthrough infections.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>154</StartPage><EndPage>162</EndPage><MedlinePgn>154-162</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bbi.2022.04.013</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0889-1591(22)00111-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Vaccination has proven effective against infection with SARS-CoV-2, as well as death and hospitalisation following COVID-19 illness. However, little is known about the effect of vaccination on other acute and post-acute outcomes of COVID-19. Data were obtained from the TriNetX electronic health records network (over 81 million patients mostly in the USA). Using a retrospective cohort study and time-to-event analysis, we compared the incidences of COVID-19 outcomes between individuals who received a COVID-19 vaccine (approved for use in the USA) at least 2&#xa0;weeks before SARS-CoV-2 infection and propensity score-matched individuals unvaccinated for COVID-19 but who had received an influenza vaccine. Outcomes were ICD-10 codes representing documented COVID-19 sequelae in the 6&#xa0;months after a confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection (recorded between January 1 and August 31, 2021, i.e. before the emergence of the Omicron variant). Associations with the number of vaccine doses (1 vs. 2) and age (&lt;60 vs.&#xa0;&#x2265;&#xa0;60&#xa0;years-old) were assessed. Among 10,024 vaccinated individuals with SARS-CoV-2 infection, 9479 were matched to unvaccinated controls. Receiving at least one COVID-19 vaccine dose was associated with a significantly lower risk of respiratory failure, ICU admission, intubation/ventilation, hypoxaemia, oxygen requirement, hypercoagulopathy/venous thromboembolism, seizures, psychotic disorder, and hair loss (each as composite endpoints with death to account for competing risks; HR 0.70-0.83, Bonferroni-corrected p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05), but not other outcomes, including long-COVID features, renal disease, mood, anxiety, and sleep disorders. Receiving 2 vaccine doses was associated with lower risks for most outcomes. Associations between prior vaccination and outcomes of SARS-CoV-2 infection were marked in those &lt;60&#xa0;years-old, whereas no robust associations were observed in those &#x2265;60&#xa0;years-old. In summary, COVID-19 vaccination is associated with lower risk of several, but not all, COVID-19 sequelae in those with breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. The findings may inform service planning, contribute to forecasting public health impacts of vaccination programmes, and highlight the need to identify additional interventions for COVID-19 sequelae.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taquet</LastName><ForeName>Maxime</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK; Oxford Health NHS Foundation Trust, Oxford, UK. Electronic address: maxime.taquet@medsci.ox.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dercon</LastName><ForeName>Quentin</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK; MRC Cognition &amp; Brain Sciences Unit, University of Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harrison</LastName><ForeName>Paul J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK; Oxford Health NHS Foundation Trust, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Brain Behav Immun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8800478</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0889-1591</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000086663">COVID-19 Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000711908">SARS-CoV-2 variants</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086663" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014611" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccination</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electronic health records</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35447302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9013695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2022.04.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0889-1591(22)00111-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agrawal U., Katikireddi S.V., McCowan C., Mulholland R.H., Azcoaga-Lorenzo A., Amele S., Fagbamigbe A.F., Vasileiou E., Grange Z., Shi T., Kerr S., Moore E., Murray J.L.K., Shah S.A., Ritchie L., O'Reilly D., Stock S.J., Beggs J., Chuter A., Torabi F., Akbari A., Bedston S., McMenamin J., Wood R., Tang R.S.M., de Lusignan S., Hobbs F.D.R., Woolhouse M., Simpson C.R., Robertson C., Sheikh A. COVID-19 hospital admissions and deaths after BNT162b2 and ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccinations in 2&#xb7;57 million people in Scotland (EAVE II): a prospective cohort study. Lancet Respiratory Med. 2021;9(12):1439&#x2013;1449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8480963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34599903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z., Xie Y., Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequalae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021 doi: 10.1038/s41586-021-03553-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-021-03553-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M., Penfold R.S., Merino J., Sudre C.H., Molteni E., Berry S., Canas L.S., Graham M.S., Klaser K., Modat M., Murray B., Kerfoot E., Chen L., Deng J., &#xd6;sterdahl M.F., Cheetham N.J., Drew D.A., Nguyen L.H., Pujol J.C., Hu C., Selvachandran S., Polidori L., May A., Wolf J., Chan A.T., Hammers A., Duncan E.L., Spector T.D., Ourselin S., Steves C.J. Risk factors and disease profile of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection in UK users of the COVID Symptom Study app: a prospective, community-based, nested, case-control study. Lancet Infect. Dis. 2022;22(1):43&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34480857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin P.C. An introduction to propensity score methods for reducing the effects of confounding in observational studies. Multivariate Behav. Res. 2011;46(3):399&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3144483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21818162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahl A., Johnson S., Maine G., Garcia M.H., Nimmagadda S., Qu L., Chen N.-W. Vaccination reduces need for emergency care in breakthrough COVID-19 infections: a multicenter cohort study. The Lancet Regional Health - Americas. 2021;4:100065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8428472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34522911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt A.A., Nafady-Hego H., Chemaitelly H., Abou-Samra A.-B., Khal A.A., Coyle P.V., Kanaani Z.A., Kaleeckal A.H., Latif A.N., Masalmani Y.A., Bertollini R., Raddad L.J.A. Outcomes among patients with breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection after vaccination. Int. J. Infect. Dis. 2021;110:353&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8349447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34375762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabezas C., Coma E., Mora-Fernandez N., Li X., Martinez-Marcos M., Fina F., Fabregas M., Hermosilla E., Jover A., Contel J.C., Lejardi Y., Enfedaque B., Argimon J.M., Medina-Peralta M., Prieto-Alhambra D. Associations of BNT162b2 vaccination with SARS-CoV-2 infection and hospital admission and death with covid-19 in nursing homes and healthcare workers in Catalonia: prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;374</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8371258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34407952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey J.A., Schwartz B.S., Stewart W.F., Adler N.E. Using electronic health records for population health research: a review of methods and applications. Annu. Rev. Public Health. 2016;37(1):61&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6724703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26667605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty S.E., Guo Y., Heath K., Dasmari&#xf1;as M.C., Jubilo K.G., Samranvedhya J., Lipsitch M., Cohen K. Risk of clinical sequelae after the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8132065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lusignan S., Dorward J., Correa A., Jones N., Akinyemi O., Amirthalingam G., Andrews N., Byford R., Dabrera G., Elliot A., Ellis J., Ferreira F., Lopez Bernal J., Okusi C., Ramsay M., Sherlock J., Smith G., Williams J., Howsam G., Zambon M., Joy M., Hobbs F.D.R. Risk factors for SARS-CoV-2 among patients in the Oxford Royal College of General Practitioners Research and Surveillance Centre primary care network: a cross-sectional study. Lancet Infect. Dis. 2020;20(9):1034&#x2013;1042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glatman-Freedman A., Bromberg M., Dichtiar R., Hershkovitz Y., Keinan-Boker L. The BNT162b2 vaccine effectiveness against new COVID-19 cases and complications of breakthrough cases: a nation-wide retrospective longitudinal multiple cohort analysis using individualised data. EBioMedicine. 2021;72:103574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8445746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34537449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas E.J., Angulo F.J., McLaughlin J.M., Anis E., Singer S.R., Khan F., Brooks N., Smaja M., Mircus G., Pan K., Southern J.o., Swerdlow D.L., Jodar L., Levy Y., Alroy-Preis S. Impact and effectiveness of mRNA BNT162b2 vaccine against SARS-CoV-2 infections and COVID-19 cases, hospitalisations, and deaths following a nationwide vaccination campaign in Israel: an observational study using national surveillance data. Lancet. 2021;397(10287):1819&#x2013;1829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8099315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33964222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haukoos J.S., Lewis R.J. The propensity score. JAMA. 2015;314:1637&#x2013;1638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4866501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26501539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyams C., Marlow R., Maseko Z., King J., Ward L., Fox K., Heath R., Tuner A., Friedrich Z., Morrison L., Ruffino G., Antico R., Adegbite D., Szasz-Benczur Z., Garcia Gonzalez M., Oliver J., Danon L., Finn A. Effectiveness of BNT162b2 and ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 COVID-19 vaccination at preventing hospitalisations in people aged at least 80 years: a test-negative, case-control study. Lancet Infect. Dis. 2021;21(11):1539&#x2013;1548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34174190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latkin C.A., Dayton L., Yi G., Colon B., Kong X., Camacho-Rivera M. Mask usage, social distancing, racial, and gender correlates of COVID-19 vaccine intentions among adults in the US. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(2):e0246970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7886161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33592035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manja V., AlBashir S., Guyatt G. Criteria for use of composite end points for competing risks-a systematic survey of the literature with recommendations. J. Clin. Epidemiol. 2017;82:4&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27965044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateo-Urdiales A., Spila Alegiani S., Fabiani M., Pezzotti P., Filia A., Massari M., Riccardo F., Tallon M., Proietti V., Del Manso M., Puopolo M., Spuri M., Morciano C., D&#x2019;Ancona F.(., Da Cas R., Battilomo S., Bella A., Menniti-Ippolito F. Risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection and subsequent hospital admission and death at different time intervals since first dose of COVID-19 vaccine administration, Italy, 27 December 2020 to mid-April 2021. Euro Surveill. 2021;26(25) doi: 10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2021.26.25.2100507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2021.26.25.2100507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8229378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34169819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEwen A.E., Cohen S., Bryson-Cahn C., Liu C., Pergam S.A., Lynch J., Schippers A., Strand K., Whimbey E., Mani N.S., Zelikoff A.J., Makarewicz V.A., Brown E.R., Bakhash S.A.M., Baker N.R., Castor J., Livingston R.J., Huang M.-L., Jerome K.R., Greninger A.L., Roychoudhury P. Variants of concern are overrepresented among post-vaccination breakthrough infections of SARS-CoV-2 in Washington State. Clin. Infect. Dis. 2021 doi: 10.1093/cid/ciab581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34166484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nixon, D.F., Ndhlovu, L.C., 2021. Vaccine breakthrough infections with SARS-CoV-2 variants. N. Engl. J. Med.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34077640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyberg T., Twohig K.A., Harris R.J., Seaman S.R., Flannagan J., Allen H., Charlett A., De Angelis D., Dabrera G., Presanis A.M. Risk of hospital admission for patients with SARS-CoV-2 variant B.1.1.7: cohort analysis. BMJ. 2021;373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8204098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34130987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polack F.P., Thomas S.J., Kitchin N., Absalon J., Gurtman A., Lockhart S., Perez J.L., P&#xe9;rez Marc G., Moreira E.D., Zerbini C., Bailey R., Swanson K.A., Roychoudhury S., Koury K., Li P., Kalina W.V., Cooper D., Frenck R.W., Hammitt L.L., T&#xfc;reci &#xd6;., Nell H., Schaefer A., &#xdc;nal S., Tresnan D.B., Mather S., Dormitzer P.R., &#x15e;ahin U., Jansen K.U., Gruber W.C. Safety and efficacy of the BNT162b2 mRNA Covid-19 vaccine. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020;383(27):2603&#x2013;2615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7745181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33301246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roest, S., Hoek, R.A.S., Manintveld, O.C., 2021. BNT162b2 mRNA covid-19 vaccine in a nationwide mass vaccination setting. N. Engl. J. Med.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33882226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royston P., Parmar M.K.B. Flexible parametric proportional-hazards and proportional-odds models for censored survival data, with application to prognostic modelling and estimation of treatment effects. Stat. Med. 2002;21(15):2175&#x2013;2197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12210632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegrist C.-A., Aspinall R. B-cell responses to vaccination at the extremes of age. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2009;9(3):185&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19240757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M., Dercon Q., Luciano S., Geddes J.R., Husain M., Harrison P.J., Kretzschmar M.E.E. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: A 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 2021;18(9):e1003773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M., Geddes J.R., Husain M., Luciano S., Harrison P.J. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson E.J., Walker A.J., Bhaskaran K., Bacon S., Bates C., Morton C.E., Curtis H.J., Mehrkar A., Evans D., Inglesby P., Cockburn J., McDonald H.I., MacKenna B., Tomlinson L., Douglas I.J., Rentsch C.T., Mathur R., Wong A.Y.S., Grieve R., Harrison D., Forbes H., Schultze A., Croker R., Parry J., Hester F., Harper S., Perera R., Evans S.J.W., Smeeth L., Goldacre B. OpenSAFELY: factors associated with COVID-19 death in 17 million patients. Nature. 2020 doi: 10.1038/s41586-020-2521-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-020-2521-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32640463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu K., Werner A.P., Koch M., Choi A., Narayanan E., Stewart-Jones G.B.E., Colpitts T., Bennett H., Boyoglu-Barnum S., Shi W., Moliva J.I., Sullivan N.J., Graham B.S., Carfi A., Corbett K.S., Seder R.A., Edwards D.K. Serum neutralizing activity elicited by mRNA-1273 vaccine. N. Engl. J. Med. 2021;384(15):1468&#x2013;1470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33730471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>