<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39478809</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2396-8923</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology methods &amp; protocols</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Methods Protoc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cluster analysis identifies long COVID subtypes in Belgian patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>bpae076</StartPage><MedlinePgn>bpae076</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">bpae076</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/biomethods/bpae076</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus infection presents complications known as long COVID, a multisystemic organ disease which allows multidimensional analysis. This study aims to uncover clusters of long COVID cases and establish their correlation with the clinical classification developed at the Clinical Research Unit of Brugmann University Hospital, Brussels. Such an endeavour is instrumental in customizing patient management strategies tailored to the unique needs of each distinct group. A two-stage multidimensional exploratory analysis was performed on a retrospective cohort of 205 long COVID patients, involving a factorial analysis of mixed data, and then hierarchical clustering post component analysis. The study's sample comprised 76% women, with an average age of 44.5&#x2009;years. Three clinical forms were identified: long, persistent, and post-viral syndrome. Multidimensional analysis using demographic, clinical, and biological variables identified three clusters of patients. Biological data did not provide sufficient differentiation between clusters. This emphasizes the importance of identifying or classifying long COVID patients according to their predominant clinical syndrome. Long COVID phenotypes, as well as clinical forms, appear to be associated with distinct pathophysiological mechanisms or genetic predispositions. This underscores the need for further research.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2024. Published by Oxford University Press.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mfouth Kemajou</LastName><ForeName>Pamela</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-5934-0555</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Centre for Research in Epidemiology, Biostatistics and Clinical Research, Universit&#xe9; Libre de Bruxelles (ULB), B-1070 Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Besse-Hammer</LastName><ForeName>Tatiana</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universite Libre de Bruxelles (ULB), B-1070, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Unit, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Brugmann, 1020, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lebouc</LastName><ForeName>Claire</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Unit, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Brugmann, 1020, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coppieters</LastName><ForeName>Yves</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Centre for Research in Epidemiology, Biostatistics and Clinical Research, Universit&#xe9; Libre de Bruxelles (ULB), B-1070 Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Methods Protoc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101693064</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2396-8923</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical forms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clusters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phenotypes</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39478809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11522879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/biomethods/bpae076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">bpae076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Morens DM, Fauci AS.. Emerging pandemic diseases: how we got to COVID-19. Cell 2020;182:1077&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7428724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32846157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai AD, Lavelle M, Boursiquot BC, Wan EY.. Long-term complications of COVID-19. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol 2022;322:C1&#x2013;C11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8721906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34817268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond) 2021;53:737&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization (WHO). https://www.who.int/europe/news-room/fact-sheets/item/post-covid-19-condition (19 October 2023, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanares-Zapatero D, Chalon P, Kohn L. et al. Pathophysiology and mechanism of long COVID: a comprehensive review. Ann Med 2022;54:1473&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35594336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ.. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol 2023;21:133&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Mahoney LL, Routen A, Gillies C. et al. The prevalence and long-term health effects of Long Covid among hospitalised and non-hospitalised populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine 2023;55:101762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9714474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36474804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hereth B, Tubig P, Sorrels A. et al. Long covid and disability: a brave new world. BMJ 2022;378:e069868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35914783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kervevan J, Staropoli I, Slama D. et al. Divergent adaptive immune responses define two types of long COVID. Front Immunol 2023;14:1221961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10408302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37559726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ, Liu S.. Proposed subtypes of post-COVID-19 syndrome (or long-COVID) and their respective potential therapies. Rev Med Virol 2022;32:e2315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34888989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong AW, Tran KC, Binka M. et al. Use of latent class analysis and patient reported outcome measures to identify distinct long COVID phenotypes: a longitudinal cohort study. PLoS One 2023;18:e0286588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10237387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37267379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kisiel MA, Lee S, Malmquist S. et al. Clustering analysis identified three long COVID phenotypes and their association with general health status and working ability. J Clin Med 2023;12:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10253616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37297812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reese JT, Blau H, Casiraghi E. et al. Generalisable long COVID subtypes: findings from the NIH N3C and RECOVER programmes. eBioMedicine 2023;87:104413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9769411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36563487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayani S, Castanares-Zapatero D, De Pauw R. et al. Classification of post COVID-19 condition symptoms: a longitudinal study in the Belgian population. BMJ Open 2023;13:e072726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10565235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37802617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny G, McCann K, O'Brien C, All-Ireland Infectious Diseases (AIID) Cohort Study Group et al.Identification of distinct long COVID clinical phenotypes through cluster analysis of self-reported symptoms. Open Forum Infect Dis 2022;9:ofac060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8900926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35265728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera JA, Thorpe LE, Simon NM. et al. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 symptom phenotypes and therapeutic strategies: a prospective, observational study. PLoS One 2022;17:e0275274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9521913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36174032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinicci M, Graziani L, Tilli M. et al. Infection with SARS-CoV-2 variants is associated with different long COVID phenotypes. Viruses 2022;14:2367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9698829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36366465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahanic S, Tymoszuk P, Ausserhofer D. et al. Phenotyping of acute and persistent coronavirus disease 2019 features in the outpatient setting: exploratory analysis of an international cross-sectional online survey. Clin Infect Dis 2022;75:e418&#x2013;e431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8767855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34849652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottlieb M, Spatz ES, Yu H, INSPIRE Group et al.Long COVID clinical phenotypes up to 6 months after infection identified by latent class analysis of self-reported symptoms. Open Forum Infect Dis 2023;10:ofad277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10327879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37426952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE. National Institute for Health and Care Excellence: Clinical Guidelines. COVID-19 Rapid Guideline: Managing the Long-Term Effects of COVID-19. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE; ), 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
WHO. Coronavirus disease (COVID-19): post COVID-19 condition. https://www.who.int/news-room/questions-and-answers/item/coronavirus-disease-(covid-19)-post-covid-19-condition (3 July 2024, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L. et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine 2021;38:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Parthasarathy S, Leung JM. et al. Distinct temporal trajectories and risk factors for Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Front Med 2023;10:1227883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10614284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37908849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torrell G, Puente D, Jacques-Avi&#xf1;&#xf3; C. et al. Characterisation, symptom pattern and symptom clusters from a retrospective cohort of Long COVID patients in primary care in Catalonia. BMC Infect Dis 2024;24:82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10789045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38225587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanou M-I, Palaiodimou L, Bakola E. et al. Neurological manifestations of long-COVID syndrome: a narrative review. Ther Adv Chronic Dis 2022;13:20406223221076890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8859684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35198136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hala&#xe7;l&#x131; BA-O, Topeli AA-O. Implementation of post-intensive care outpatient clinic (I-POINT) for critically ill COVID-19 survivors. Turk J Med Sci 2021;51:3350&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8771014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34333907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chippa V, Aleem A, Anjum F.. Post-Acute Coronavirus (COVID-19) Syndrome. BTI&#x2014;StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing, 2024, NBK570608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechner-Scott J, Levy M, Hawkes C. et al. Long COVID or post COVID-19 syndrome. Mult Scler Relat Disord 2021;55:103268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8447548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34601388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumantri S, Rengganis I.. Immunological dysfunction and mast cell activation syndrome in long COVID. Asia Pac Allergy 2023;13:50&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10166245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37389095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tackey C, Slepian PM, Clarke H, Mittal N. Post-viral pain, fatigue, and sleep disturbance syndromes: current knowledge and future directions. Can J Pain 2023;7:2272999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10795785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38239826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrell CJ, Howard CR, Murphy FA.. Fenner and White's Medical Virology. Academic Press; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arun S, Storan A, Myers B.. Mast cell activation syndrome and the link with long COVID. Br J Hosp Med (Lond) 2022;83:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35938771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reese JT, Blau H, Casiraghi E, RECOVER Consortium et al.Generalisable long COVID subtypes: findings from the NIH N3C and RECOVER programmes. eBioMedicine 2023;87:104413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9769411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36563487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchida T, Yoshimura N, Ishizuka K. et al. Five cluster classifications of long COVID and their background factors: a cross-sectional study in Japan. Clin Exp Med 2023; 23:3663&#x2013; 70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10081305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37027067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selleron B, Chenivesse C.. Hyperventilation syndrome, definition, diagnostic and therapy. Rev Mal Respir 2023;40:499&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37179152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allado EA-O, Poussel MA-O, Hamroun A. et al. Is there a relationship between hyperventilation syndrome and history of acute SARS-CoV-2 infection? A cross-sectional study. 10.3390/healthcare10112154</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare10112154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9690850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36360494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubois B, Touchon J, Portet F. et al. The "5 words": a simple and sensitive test for the diagnosis of Alzheimer's disease. Presse Med 2002;31:1696&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12467149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacus JP, Hamon-Vilcot B, Basset-Berges MF. et al. Five-word test: insufficiently sensitive but very specific for organic memory disorders. Presse Med 2006;35:948&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16783252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derouesn&#xe9; C, Dealberto MJ, Boyer P. et al. Empirical evaluation of the &#x2018;Cognitive Difficulties Scale&#x2019; for assessment of memory complaints in general practice: a study of 1628 cognitively normal subjects aged 45&#x2013;75 years. Int J Geriat Psychiatry 1993;8:599&#x2013;607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dardenne S, Delrieu J, Sourdet S. et al. Memory complaints and cognitive decline: data from the GUIDAGE study1. J Alzheimers Dis 2017;60:1567&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28984580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torki E, Hoseininasab F, Moradi M. et al. The demographic, laboratory and genetic factors associated with long Covid-19 syndrome: a case&#x2013;control study. Clin Exp Med 2024;24:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10794331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38231284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin JX, Agbana YL, Sun ZS. et al. Increased interleukin-6 is associated with long COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Infect Dis Pover 2023;12:43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10123579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37095536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boc&#xe9;r&#xe9;an C, Dupret E.. A validation study of the hospital anxiety and depression scale (HADS) in a large sample of French employees. BMC Psychiatry 2014;14:354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4476305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25511175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard EB, Jones-Alexander J, Buckley TC, Forneris CA.. Psychometric properties of the PTSD checklist (PCL). Behav Res Ther 1996;34:669&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8870294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herman B, Wong MCS, Chantharit P. et al. Longitudinal study of disease severity and external factors in cognitive failure after COVID-19 among Indonesian population. Sci Rep 2023;13:19405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10632387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37938599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rast P, Zimprich D, Van Boxtel M, Jolles J.. Factor structure and measurement invariance of the cognitive failures questionnaire across the adult life span. Assessment 2009;16:145&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19066391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gierk B, Kohlmann S, Kroenke K. et al. The somatic symptom scale&#x2013;8 (SSS-8). JAMA Intern Med 2014;174:399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24276929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard S, Gauthier JG, Ivers H. et al. Psychometric properties of the french version of the state-trait anxiety inventory (form Y) adapted for older adults. Can J Aging 1998;17:440&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y-P, Gorenstein C.. Psychometric properties of the beck depression inventory-II: a comprehensive review. Rev Bras Psiquiatr 2013;35:416&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24402217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horowitz M, Wilner N, Alvarez W.. Impact of event scale: a measure of subjective stress. Psychosom Med 1979;41:209&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">472086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scher CD, Stein MB, Asmundson GJ. et al. The childhood trauma questionnaire in a community sample: psychometric properties and normative data. J Trauma Stress 2001;14:843&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11776429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigo S, Barbic F, Khalaf K. et al. The long-COVID autonomic syndrome in hospitalized patients: a one-year prospective cohort study. Eur J Intern Med 2024;120:38&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37652756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware JE, Snow KK, Kosinski M, Gandek B.. SF-36 Health Survey. Manual and Interpretation Guide. Boston: The Health Institute, New England Medical Center, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendershott TR, Zhu D, Llanes S, Poston KL.. Domain-specific accuracy of the Montreal Cognitive Assessment subsections in Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2017;38:31&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5400012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28215728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik H, Shao S, Tran KC. et al. Evaluating fatigue in patients recovering from COVID-19: validation of the fatigue severity scale and single item screening questions. Health Qual Life Outcomes 2022;20:170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9792925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36575437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huskisson EC. Measurement of pain. Lancet 1974;2: 1127&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4139420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez C, Galvez R, Huelbes S. et al. Validity and reliability of the Spanish version of the DN4 (Douleur Neuropathique 4 questions) questionnaire for differential diagnosis of pain syndromes associated to a neuropathic or somatic component. Health Qual Life Outcomes 2017;5:66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2217518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18053212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crisafulli E, Clini EM.. Measures of dyspnea in pulmonary rehabilitation. Multidiscip Respir Med 2010;5:202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3463047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22958431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husson FL, Pag&#xe8;s J.. Analyse de donn&#xe9;es avec R, 2nd edn. France: Presses Universitaires de Rennes, 2016, 240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pazukhina E, Andreeva M, Spiridonova E, Sechenov StopCOVID Research Team et al.Prevalence and risk factors of post-COVID-19 condition in adults and children at 6 and 12&#x2009;months after hospital discharge: a prospective, cohort study in Moscow (StopCOVID). BMC Med 2022;20:244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9257572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35794549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurner C, Stengel A.. Long-COVID syndrome: physical-mental interplay in the spotlight. Inflammopharmacology 2023;31:559&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9996557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36892678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meintrup D, Nowak-Machen M, Borgmann S.. A comparison of Germany and the United Kingdom indicates that more SARS-CoV-2 circulation and less restrictions in the warm season might reduce overall COVID-19 burden. Life 2022;12:953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9322333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35888043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahmer T, Borzikowsky C, Lieb W, NAPKON study group et al.Severity, predictors and clinical correlates of Post-COVID syndrome (PCS) in Germany: a prospective, multi-centre, population-based cohort study. EClinicalMedicine 2022;51:101549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9289961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35875815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ, Halim A, Halim M. et al. Inflammatory and vascular biomarkers in post-COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of over 20 biomarkers. Rev Med Virol 2023;33:e2424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36708022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danesh V, Arroliga AC, Bourgeois JA. et al. Symptom clusters seen in adult COVID-19 recovery clinic care seekers. J Gen Intern Med 2023;38:442&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9663188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36376627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitaker M, Elliott J, Chadeau-Hyam M. et al. Persistent COVID-19 symptoms in a community study of 606,434 people in England. Nat Commun 2022;13:1957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9005552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35413949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Kelly JD, Lu S. et al. Persistence, magnitude, and patterns of postacute symptoms and quality of life following onset of SARS-CoV-2 infection: cohort description and approaches for measurement. Open Forum Infect Dis 2022;9:ofab640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8755302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35106317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateu L, Tebe C, Loste C. et al. Determinants of the onset and prognosis of the Post-COVID-19 Condition: a 2-year prospective observational cohort study. Lancet Reg Health Eur 2023;33:100724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10636281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37954002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballouz T, Menges D, Kaufmann M. et al. Post COVID-19 condition after wildtype, delta, and omicron SARS-CoV-2 infection and prior vaccination: pooled analysis of two population-based cohorts. PLoS ONE 2023;18:e0281429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9946205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36812215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny G, McCann K, O'Brien C, All Ireland Infectious Diseases Cohort Study et al.Impact of vaccination and variants of concern on long COVID clinical phenotypes. BMC Infect Dis 2023;23:804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10655269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37974068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziauddeen N, Gurdasani D, O'Hara ME. et al. Characteristics and impact of Long Covid: findings from an online survey. PLoS One 2022;17:e0264331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8903286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35259179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverberg JI, Zyskind I, Naiditch H. et al. Predictors of chronic COVID-19 symptoms in a community-based cohort of adults. PLoS ONE 2022;17:e0271310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9352033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35925904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer A, Zhang L, Elb&#xe9;ji A. et al. Long COVID symptomatology after 12 months and its impact on quality of life according to initial coronavirus disease 2019 disease severity. Open Forum Infect Dis 2022;9:ofac397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9379809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35983269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hakeim HK, Abed AK, Almulla AF. et al. Anxiety due to Long COVID is partially driven by activation of the tryptophan catabolite (TRYCAT) pathway. Asian J Psychiatr 2023;88:103723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37567082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreli F, Gaino F, Russo E. et al. Long-standing gustatory and olfactory dysfunction in COVID-19 patients: a prospective study. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol 2022;279:4633&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9244308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35767055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyata Y, Suzuki K, Nagano T. et al. Cellular immunity reflects the persistent symptoms among COVID-19 recovered patients in Japan. Sci Rep 2023;13:11071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10329673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37422499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velichkovsky BB, Razvaliaeva AY, Khlebnikova AA. et al. Attention and memory after COVID-19 as measured by neuropsychological tests: systematic review and meta-analysis. Acta Psychol (Amst) 2023;233:103838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9834202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36657196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damiano RF, Rocca C. C D A, Serafim A. D P. et al. Cognitive impairment in long-COVID and its association with persistent dysregulation in inflammatory markers. Front Immunol 2023;14:1174020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10242059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37287969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H, Lu S, Chen J. et al. The landscape of cognitive function in recovered COVID-19 patients. J Psychiatr Res 2020;129:98&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7324344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32912598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busatto GF, de Araujo AL, Castaldelli-Maia JM, HCFMUSP Covid-19 Study Group et al.Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: relationship of central nervous system manifestations with physical disability and systemic inflammation. Psychol Med 2022;52:2387&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9151630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35521752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahanic S, Tymoszuk P, Luger AK. et al. COVID-19 and its continuing burden after 12 months: a longitudinal observational prospective multicentre trial. ERJ Open Res 2023;9:00317&#x2013;2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10030059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36960350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vartanian K, Fish D, Kenton N. et al. Integrating patient-reported physical, mental, and social impacts to classify long COVID experiences. Sci Rep 2023;13:16288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10539528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37770554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Bae S, Chang HH, Kim SW.. Long COVID prevalence and impact on quality of life 2 years after acute COVID-19. Sci Rep 2023;13:11207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10336045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37433819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson RC, Simons NW, Wilkins L, Mount Sinai COVID-19 Biobank Team et al.Molecular states during acute COVID-19 reveal distinct etiologies of long-term sequelae. Nat Med 2023;29:236&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9873574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36482101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruffieux H, Hanson AL, Lodge S, Cambridge Institute of Therapeutic Immunology and Infectious Disease-National Institute of Health Research (CITIID-NIHR) BioResource COVID-19 Collaboration et al.A patient-centric modeling framework captures recovery from SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Immunol 2023;24:349&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9892000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36717723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong S-W, Goh YS, Torres-Ruesta A, NCID Study Group et al.Prolonged inflammation in patients hospitalized for coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) resolves 2 years after infection. J Med Virol 2023;95:e28774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37212320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang M, Wu X, Jing H. et al. The intersection of obesity and (long) COVID-19: hypoxia, thrombotic inflammation, and vascular endothelial injury. Front Cardiovasc Med 2023;10:1062491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9941162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36824451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adingupu DD, Soroush A, Hansen A. et al. Brain hypoxia, neurocognitive impairment, and quality of life in people post-COVID-19. J Neurol 2023;270:3303&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10200033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37210689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hingorani KS, Bhadola S, Cervantes-Arslanian AM.. COVID-19 and the brain. Trends Cardiovasc Med 2022;32:323&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9022395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35461991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito S, Shahbaz S, Luo X. et al. Metabolomic and immune alterations in long COVID patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. Front Immunol 2024;15:1341843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10830702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38304426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer L, Laksono BM, de Vrij FMS. et al. The neuroinvasiveness, neurotropism, and neurovirulence of SARS-CoV-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8890977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35279295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocyigit BF, Akyol A.. The relationship between COVID-19 and fibromyalgia syndrome: prevalence, pandemic effects, symptom mechanisms, and COVID-19 vaccines. Clin Rheumatol 2022;41:3245&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35804273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caz&#xe9; AB, Cerqueira-Silva T, Bomfim AP. et al. Prevalence and risk factors for long COVID after mild disease: a cohort study with a symptomatic control group. J Glob Health 2023;13:06015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10173895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37166260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal SM, Landers DB, Hollenberg SM. et al. Prospective evaluation of autonomic dysfunction in post-acute sequela of COVID-19. J Am Coll Cardiol 2022;79:2325&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8976261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35381331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>