<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38737442</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2391-5463</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Open medicine (Warsaw, Poland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Open Med (Wars)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Factors influencing cardiovascular system-related post-COVID-19 sequelae: A single-center cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20240950</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20240950</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20240950</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/med-2024-0950</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">COVID-19 sequelae are long-term symptoms of COVID-19. Cardiovascular disease is not only a risk factor for the occurrence of COVID-19 sequelae but also a potential result directly or indirectly caused by COVID-19 infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The aim of this study is to investigate the cardiovascular system-related symptoms of outpatients and inpatients of the Cardiovascular Department of the Affiliated Hospital of Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine after recovery from novel coronavirus infection, analyze the influencing factors, and symptom characteristics of related symptoms, and thereby provide a basis for further formulating a reasonable diagnosis and treatment plan.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">From January 15, 2023 to February 15, 2023, 452 recovered patients with novel coronavirus infection who were admitted to the Cardiovascular Department of the Affiliated Hospital of Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine due to symptoms of the cardiovascular system (complaints of chest pain and palpitations) were involved in this study. A unified questionnaire was used to record the general information, past medical history, characteristics of chest pain or palpitations, and other COVID-19-related sequelae of the selected patients. All data were statistically analyzed by SPSS 26.0 statistical software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 226 patients with cardiovascular symptoms and 226 patients without cardiovascular symptoms were included in this study. After univariate and multivariate logistic regression analysis, women (OR 2.081, 95% CI = 1.358-3.189) and young people (OR 2.557, 95% CI = 1.44-4.54) had a higher risk of cardiovascular symptoms; prehypertension (OR 1.905, 95% CI = 1.091-3.329) and hypertension (OR 2.287, 95% CI = 1.433-3.649) increased the risk of cardiovascular symptoms; patients with history of previous cardiovascular disease (OR 1.862, 95% CI = 1.16-2.988) and history of diabetes (OR 2.138, 95% CI = 1.058-4.319) had a higher risk of developing cardiovascular symptoms. The main symptoms related to COVID-19 sequelae reported by all 452 patients were fatigue (76.8%), shortness of breath (54.2%), dry mouth and bitter mouth (46.0%), gastrointestinal symptoms (42.7%), sleep disturbances (37.4%), sweating (31.9%), chills (29%), dizziness (25.7%), confusion of brain fog (25.2%), and tinnitus (14.6%). Compared with patients without cardiovascular symptoms, patients with cardiovascular symptoms were more likely to have shortness of breath (OR 3.521, 95% CI = 2.226-5.472), gastrointestinal symptoms (OR 2.039, 95% CI = 1.226-3.393), and dry mouth and bitter mouth (OR 1.918, 95% CI = 1.229-2.992). The differences were statistically significant (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In this new coronavirus infection, women, young people, the elderly, people with prehypertension, hypertension, and patients with a history of cardiovascular disease and diabetes have a higher risk of developing cardiovascular symptoms, and patients with cardiovascular symptoms are more likely to develop other COVID-19 sequelae.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 the author(s), published by De Gruyter.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong Province, 250014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Dongli</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Affiliated Hospital of Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong Province, 250014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yongzhi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular, Affiliated Hospital of Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong Province, 250014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Na</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Affiliated Hospital of Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong Province, 250014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Tianshu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong Province, 250014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Ruixia</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong Province, 250014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>First School of Clinical Medicine, Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong Province, 250014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Chuanhua</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular, Affiliated Hospital of Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong Province, 250014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Affiliated Hospital of Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Open Med (Wars)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101672167</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">novel coronavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">novel coronavirus infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sequelae</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest: The authors declared no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38737442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11087739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/med-2024-0950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">med-2024-0950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Thompson EJ, Williams DM, Walker AJ, Mitchell RE, Niedzwiedz CL, Yang TC, et al. Long COVID burden and risk factors in 10 UK longitudinal studies and electronic health records. Nat Commun. 2022;13:3528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9240035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35764621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patone M, Mei XW, Handunnetthi L, Dixon S, Zaccardi F, Shankar-Hari M, et al. Risk of myocarditis after sequential doses of COVID-19 vaccine and SARS-CoV-2 infection by age and sex. Circulation. 2022;146:743&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9439633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35993236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osmanov IM, Spiridonova E, Bobkova P, Gamirova A, Shikhaleva A, Andreeva M, et al. Risk factors for post-COVID-19 condition in previously hospitalised children using the ISARIC global follow-up protocol: a prospective cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2022;59:2101341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8576804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34210789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucciarelli V, Nasi M, Bianco F, Seferovic J, Ivkovic V, Gallina S, et al. Depression pandemic and cardiovascular risk in the COVID-19 era and long COVID syndrome: Gender makes a difference. Trends Cardiovasc Med. 2022;32:12&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8490128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34619336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng F, Dai C, Cai P, Wang J, Xu L, Li J, et al. A comparison study of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 IgG antibody between male and female COVID&#x2010;19 patients: A possible reason underlying different outcome between sex. J Med Virol. 2020;92:2050&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32383183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed MS, Moulin TC, Schi&#xf6;th HB. Sex differences in COVID-19: the role of androgens in disease severity and progression. Endocrine. 2021;71:3&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7657570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33179220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bienvenu LA, Noonan J, Wang X, Peter K. Higher mortality of COVID-19 in males: sex differences in immune response and cardiovascular comorbidities. Cardiovasc Res. 2020;116:2197&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33063089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F, Tomasoni D, Falcinella C, Barbanotti D, Castoldi R, Mul&#xe8; G, et al. Female gender is associated with long COVID syndrome: a prospective cohort study. Clin Microbiol Infec. 2022;28:611.e9&#x2013;e16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Yang J, Zhao F, Zhi L, Wang X, Liu L, et al. Prevalence and impact of cardiovascular metabolic diseases on COVID-19 in China. Clin Res Cardiol. 2020;109:531&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7087935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32161990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Chen C, Yan JT, Zhou N, Zhao JP, Wang DW. Analysis of myocardial injury in patients with COVID-19 and association between concomitant cardiovascular diseases and severity of COVID-19. Zhonghua Xinxueguanbing Zazhi. 2020;48:567&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32141280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elseidy SA, Awad AK, Vorla M, Fatima A, Elbadawy MA, Mandal D, et al. Cardiovascular complications in the post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PACS). IJC Heart Vasc. 2022;40:101012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8958273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35355927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salabei JK, Asnake ZT, Ismail ZH, Charles K, Stanger G-T, Abdullahi AH, et al. COVID-19 and the cardiovascular system: an update. Am J Med Sci. 2022;364:139&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8830924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35151635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siripanthong B, Asatryan B, Hanff TC, Chatha SR, Khanji MY, Ricci F, et al. The pathogenesis and long-term consequences of COVID-19 cardiac injury. JACC: Basic Transl Sci. 2022;7:294&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8828362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35165665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djouss&#xe9; L, Lee I-M, Buring JE, Gaziano JM. Alcohol consumption and risk of cardiovascular disease and mortality in women: Potential mediating mechanisms. Circulation. 2009;120:237&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2745640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19597054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson SC, Burgess S, Mason AM, Micha&#xeb;lsson K. Alcohol consumption and cardiovascular disease. Circ Genomic Precis Med. 2020;13:e002814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7299220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32367730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosoff DB, Charlet K, Jung J, Lee J, Muench C, Luo A, et al. Association of high-intensity Binge drinking with lipid and liver function enzyme levels. JAMA Netw Open. 2019;2:e195844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6575145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31199452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brien SE, Ronksley PE, Turner BJ, Mukamal KJ, Ghali WA. Effect of alcohol consumption on biological markers associated with risk of coronary heart disease: systematic review and meta-analysis of interventional studies. BMJ. 2011;342:d636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3043110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21343206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>