<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37126363</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4644</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>124</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cellular biochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cell Biochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intrinsic factors behind long-COVID: I. Prevalence of the extracellular vesicles.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>656</StartPage><EndPage>673</EndPage><MedlinePgn>656-673</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcb.30415</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>It can be argued that the severity of COVID-19 has decreased in many countries. This could be a result of the broad coverage of the population by vaccination campaigns, which often reached an almost compulsory status in many places. Furthermore, significant roles were played by the multiple mutations in the body of the virus, which led to the emergence of several new SARS-CoV-2 variants with enhanced infectivity but dramatically reduced pathogenicity. However, the challenges associated with the development of various side effects and their persistence for long periods exceeding 20 months as a result of the SARS-CoV-2 infection, or taking available vaccines against it, are spreading horizontally and vertically in number and repercussions. For example, the World Health Organization announced that there are more than 17 million registered cases of long-COVID (also known as post-COVID syndrome) in the European Union countries alone. Furthermore, by using the PubMed search engine, one can find that more than 10&#x2009;000 articles have been published focusing exclusively on long-COVID. In light of these enormous and ever-increasing numbers of cases and published articles, most of which are descriptive of the various long-COVID symptoms, the need to know the reasons behind this phenomenon raises several important questions. Is long-COVID caused by the continued presence of the virus or one/several of its components in the recovering individual body for long periods of time, which urges the body to respond in a way that leads to long-COVID development? Or are there some latent and limited reasons related to the recovering patients themselves? Or is it a sum of both? Many observations support a positive answer to the first question, whereas others back the second question but typically without releasing a fundamental reason/signal behind it. Whatever the answer is, it seems that the real reasons behind this widespread phenomenon remain unclear. This report opens a series of articles, in which we will try to shed light on the underlying causes that could be behind the long-COVID phenomenon.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Maradny</LastName><ForeName>Yousra A</ForeName><Initials>YA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Protein Research Department, Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology Research Institute, City of Scientific Research and Technological Applications (SRTA-City), New Borg EL-Arab, Alexandria, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rubio-Casillas</LastName><ForeName>Alberto</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biology Laboratory, Autl&#xe1;n Regional Preparatory School, University of Guadalajara, Autl&#xe1;n, Jalisco, Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uversky</LastName><ForeName>Vladimir N</ForeName><Initials>VN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine and USF Health Byrd Alzheimer's Research Institute, Morsani College of Medicine, University of South Florida, Tampa, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Redwan</LastName><ForeName>Elrashdy M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Protein Research Department, Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology Research Institute, City of Scientific Research and Technological Applications (SRTA-City), New Borg EL-Arab, Alexandria, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biological Science Department, Faculty of Science, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cell Biochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8205768</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0730-2312</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000711908">SARS-CoV-2 variants</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000067128" MajorTopicYN="Y">Extracellular Vesicles</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apoptotic bodies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exosomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">extracellular vesicles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microvesicles</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37126363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcb.30415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nature Med. 2021;27(4):601-615. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsoularis I, Fonseca-Rodr&#xed;guez O, Farrington P, et al. Risks of deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, and bleeding after covid-19: nationwide self-controlled cases series and matched cohort study. BMJ. 2022;377:e069590. doi:10.1136/bmj-2021-069590</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahase E. Covid-19: one in eight adults develops long covid symptoms, study suggests. BMJ. 2022;378:o1946. doi:10.1136/bmj.o1946</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogaki A, Ikegaya Y, Koyama R. Extracellular vesicles taken up by astrocytes. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(19):10553. doi:10.3390/ijms221910553</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaborowski MP, Balaj L, Breakefield XO, Lai CP. Extracellular vesicles: composition, biological relevance, and methods of study. BioScience. 2015;65(8):783-797. doi:10.1093/biosci/biv084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreu Z, Y&#xe3;nez-Mo M. Tetraspanins in extracellular vesicle formation and function. Front Immunol. 2014;5:442. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2014.00442</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalra H, Drummen G, Mathivanan S. Focus on extracellular vesicles: introducing the next small big thing. Int J Mol Sci. 2016;17(2):170. doi:10.3390/ijms17020170</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathivanan S, Ji H, Simpson RJ. Exosomes: extracellular organelles important in intercellular communication. J Proteomics. 2010;73(10):1907-1920. doi:10.1016/j.jprot.2010.06.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Li S, Li L, et al. Exosome and exosomal microRNA: trafficking, sorting, and function. Genomics Insights. 2015;13(1):17-24. doi:10.1016/j.gpb.2015.02.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle L, Wang M. Overview of extracellular vesicles, their origin, composition, purpose, and methods for exosome isolation and analysis. Cells. 2019;8(7):727. doi:10.3390/cells8070727</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valadi H, Ekstr&#xf6;m K, Bossios A, Sj&#xf6;strand M, Lee JJ, L&#xf6;tvall JO. Exosome-mediated transfer of mRNAs and microRNAs is a novel mechanism of genetic exchange between cells. Nature Cell Biol. 2007;9(6):654-659. doi:10.1038/ncb1596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolte-&#x2018;t Hoen E, Cremer T, Gallo RC, Margolis LB. Extracellular vesicles and viruses: are they close relatives? Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2016;113(33):9155-9161. doi:10.1073/pnas.1605146113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urbanelli L, Buratta S, Tancini B, et al. The role of extracellular vesicles in viral infection and transmission. Vaccines. 2019;7(3):102. doi:10.3390/vaccines7030102</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baietti MF, Zhang Z, Mortier E, et al. Syndecan-syntenin-ALIX regulates the biogenesis of exosomes. Nature Cell Biol. 2012;14(7):677-685. doi:10.1038/ncb2502</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrowski M, Carmo NB, Krumeich S, et al. Rab27a and Rab27b control different steps of the exosome secretion pathway. Nature Cell Biol. 2010;12(1):19-30. doi:10.1038/ncb2000</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassanpour M, Rezaie J, Nouri M, Panahi Y. The role of extracellular vesicles in COVID-19 virus infection. Infect Genet Evol. 2020;85:104422. doi:10.1016/j.meegid.2020.104422</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elrashdy F, Aljaddawi AA, Redwan EM, Uversky VN. On the potential role of exosomes in the COVID-19 reinfection/reactivation opportunity. J Biomol Struct Dyn. 2021;39(15):5831-5842. doi:10.1080/07391102.2020.1790426</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Kodidela S, Tadrous E, et al. Extracellular vesicles in viral replication and pathogenesis and their potential role in therapeutic intervention. Viruses. 2020;12(8):887. doi:10.3390/v12080887</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosset FL, Dreux M. HCV transmission by hepatic exosomes establishes a productive infection. J Hepatol. 2014;60(3):674-675. doi:10.1016/j.jhep.2013.10.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bukong TN, Momen-Heravi F, Kodys K, Bala S, Szabo G. Exosomes from hepatitis C infected patients transmit HCV infection and contain replication competent viral RNA in complex with Ago2-miR122-HSP90. PLoS Pathog. 2014;10(10):e1004424. doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1004424</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Z, Hensley L, McKnight KL, et al. A pathogenic picornavirus acquires an envelope by hijacking cellular membranes. Nature. 2013;496(7445):367-371. doi:10.1038/nature12029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao Z, Qiao Y, Li X, et al. Exosomes exploit the virus entry machinery and pathway to transmit alpha interferon-induced antiviral activity. J Virol. 2018;92(24):e01578-18. doi:10.1128/JVI.01578-18</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodidela S, Gerth K, Sinha N, Kumar A, Kumar P, Kumar S. Circulatory astrocyte and neuronal EVs as potential biomarkers of neurological dysfunction in HIV-infected subjects and alcohol/tobacco users. Diagnostics. 2020;10(6):349. doi:10.3390/diagnostics10060349</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raymond AD, Diaz P, Chevelon S, et al. Microglia-derived HIV Nef+ exosome impairment of the blood-brain barrier is treatable by nanomedicine-based delivery of Nef peptides. J Neurovirol. 2016;22(2):129-139. doi:10.1007/s13365-015-0397-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeMarino C, Pleet ML, Cowen M, et al. Antiretroviral drugs alter the content of extracellular vesicles from HIV-1-infected cells. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):7653. doi:10.1038/s41598-018-25943-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukers DF, Meij P, Vervoort MBHJ, et al. Direct immunosuppressive effects of EBV-encoded latent membrane protein 1. J Immunol. 2000;165(2):663-670. doi:10.4049/jimmunol.165.2.663</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaei G, Zare N, Mihanfar A, Ansari MHK. Exosomes and COVID-19: challenges and opportunities. Comp Clin Pathol. 2022;31(2):347-354. doi:10.1007/s00580-021-03311-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Chen S, Bihl J. Exosome-mediated transfer of ACE2 (angiotensin-converting enzyme 2) from endothelial progenitor cells promotes survival and function of endothelial cell. Oxid Med Cell Longevity. 2020;2020:1-11. doi:10.1155/2020/4213541</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry F, Morin-Dewaele M, Majidipur A, et al. Proviral role of human respiratory epithelial cell-derived small extracellular vesicles in SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Extracell Vesicles. 2022;11(10):e12269. doi:10.1002/jev2.12269</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Moore MJ, Vasilieva N, et al. Angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 is a functional receptor for the SARS coronavirus. Nature. 2003;426(6965):450-454. doi:10.1038/nature02145</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hantak MP, Qing E, Earnest JT, Gallagher T. Tetraspanins: architects of viral entry and exit platforms. J Virol. 2019;93(6):e01429-17. doi:10.1128/JVI.01429-17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez-L&#xf3;pez MD, Gilsanz A, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-M&#xf3; M, et al. The sheddase activity of ADAM17/TACE is regulated by the tetraspanin CD9. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2011;68(19):3275-3292. doi:10.1007/s00018-011-0639-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earnest JT, Hantak MP, Li K, McCray Jr. PB, Perlman S, Gallagher T. The tetraspanin CD9 facilitates MERS-coronavirus entry by scaffolding host cell receptors and proteases. PLoS Pathog. 2017;13(7):e1006546. doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1006546</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healy EF. How tetraspanin-mediated cell entry of SARS-CoV-2 can dysregulate the shedding of the ACE2 receptor by ADAM17. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2022;593:52-56. doi:10.1016/j.bbrc.2022.01.038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson CB, Farzan M, Chen B, Choe H. Mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2 entry into cells. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2022;23(1):3-20. doi:10.1038/s41580-021-00418-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Shennawy L, Hoffmann AD, Dashzeveg NK, et al. Circulating ACE2-expressing extracellular vesicles block broad strains of SARS-CoV-2. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):405. doi:10.1038/s41467-021-27893-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133-146. doi:10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deeks SG, Mustapic M, et al. SARS-CoV-2 and mitochondrial proteins in neural-derived exosomes of COVID-19. Ann Neurol. 2022;91(6):772-781. doi:10.1002/ana.26350</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurunathan S, Kang MH, Kim JH. Diverse effects of exosomes on COVID-19: a perspective of progress from transmission to therapeutic developments. Front Immunol. 2021;12:716407. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.716407</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon Y, Nukala SB, Srivastava S, et al. Detection of viral RNA fragments in human iPSC cardiomyocytes following treatment with extracellular vesicles from SARS-CoV-2 coding sequence overexpressing lung epithelial cells. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2020;11(1):514. doi:10.1186/s13287-020-02033-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunasekaran M, Bansal S, Ravichandran R, et al. Respiratory viral infection in lung transplantation induces exosomes that trigger chronic rejection. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2020;39(4):379-388. doi:10.1016/j.healun.2019.12.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh S, Dellibovi-Ragheb TA, Kerviel A, et al. &#x3b2;-Coronaviruses use lysosomes for egress instead of the biosynthetic secretory pathway. Cell. 2020;183(6):1520-1535.e14. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2020.10.039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowal J, Tkach M, Th&#xe9;ry C. Biogenesis and secretion of exosomes. Curr Opin Cell Biol. 2014;29:116-125. doi:10.1016/j.ceb.2014.05.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Gioia S, Daniello V, Conese M. Extracellular vesicles'&#xa0;role in the pathophysiology and as biomarkers in cystic fibrosis and COPD. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;24(1):228. doi:10.3390/ijms24010228</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Wang X, Zhang N, et al. Extracellular vesicles of Clonorchis sinensis promote IL-6 and TNF-&#x3b1; secretion via the toll-like receptor 9-mediated ERK pathway in biliary epithelial cells. Dev&#xa0;Comp&#xa0;Immunol. 2023;139:104555. doi:10.1016/j.dci.2022.104555</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed Y, El-Maradny YA, Saleh AK, Nayl AA, El-Gendi H, El-Fakharany EM. A comprehensive insight into current control of COVID-19: immunogenicity, vaccination, and treatment. Biomed Pharmacother. 2022;153:113499. doi:10.1016/j.biopha.2022.113499</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castelli V, Cimini A, Ferri C. Cytokine storm in COVID-19: &#x201c;When You Come Out of the Storm, You Won't Be the Same Person Who Walked in&#x201d;. Front Immunol. 2020;11:2132. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2020.02132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coperchini F, Chiovato L, Croce L, Magri F, Rotondi M. The cytokine storm in COVID-19: an overview of the involvement of the chemokine/chemokine-receptor system. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2020;53:25-32. doi:10.1016/j.cytogfr.2020.05.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadjadj J, Yatim N, Barnabei L, et al. Impaired type I interferon activity and inflammatory responses in severe COVID-19 patients. Science. 2020;369(6504):718-724. doi:10.1126/science.abc6027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco-Melo D, Nilsson-Payant BE, Liu WC, et al. Imbalanced host response to SARS-CoV-2 drives development of COVID-19. Cell. 2020;181(5):1036-1045. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2020.04.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bussani R, Schneider E, Zentilin L, et al. Persistence of viral RNA, pneumocyte syncytia and thrombosis are hallmarks of advanced COVID-19 pathology. EBioMedicine. 2020;61:103104. doi:10.1016/j.ebiom.2020.103104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceulemans LJ, Khan M, Yoo SJ, et al. Persistence of SARS-CoV-2 RNA in lung tissue after mild COVID-19. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9(8):e78-e79. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00240-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BK, Francisco EB, Yogendra R, et al. Persistence of SARS CoV-2 S1 protein in CD16+ monocytes in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) up to 15 months post-infection. Front Immunol. 2022;12:746021. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.746021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swank Z, Senussi Y, Manickas-Hill Z, et al. Persistent circulating severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 spike is associated with post-acute coronavirus disease 2019 sequelae. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76(3):e487-e490. doi:10.1093/cid/ciac722</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bussani R, Zentilin L, Correa R, et al. Persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection in patients seemingly recovered from COVID-19. J Pathol. 2023;259(3):254-263. doi:10.1002/path.6035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astin R, Banerjee A, Baker MR, et al. Long COVID: mechanisms, risk factors and recovery. Exp Physiol. 2023;108(1):12-27. doi:10.1113/EP090802</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins-Gon&#xe7;alves R, Campos MM, Palhinha L, et al. Persisting platelet activation and hyperactivity in COVID-19 survivors. Circ Res. 2022;131(11):944-947. doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.122.321659</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherif ZA, Gomez CR, Connors TJ, Henrich TJ, Reeves WB. Pathogenic mechanisms of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC). eLife. 2023;12:e86002. doi:10.7554/eLife.86002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Chen R, Yao M, et al. COVID-19 plasma exosomes promote proinflammatory immune responses in peripheral blood mononuclear cells. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):21779. doi:10.1038/s41598-022-26457-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Files JK, Sarkar S, Fram TR, et al. Duration of post-COVID-19 symptoms are associated with sustained SARS-CoV-2 specific immune responses. JCI Insight. 2021;6(15):e151544. doi:10.1172/jci.insight.151544</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troyer Z, Alhusaini N, Tabler CO, et al. Extracellular vesicles carry SARS-CoV-2 spike protein and serve as decoys for neutralizing antibodies. J Extracell Vesicles. 2021;10(8):e12112. doi:10.1002/jev2.12112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craddock V, Mahajan A, Spikes L, et al. Persistent circulation of soluble and extracellular vesicle-linked Spike protein in individuals with postacute sequelae of COVID-19. J Med Virol. 2023;95(2):e28568. doi:10.1002/jmv.28568</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M, et al. Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(6):683-690. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.1127</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uversky VN, Elrashdy F, Aljadawi A, Ali SM, Khan RH, Redwan EM. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection reaches the human nervous system: how? J Neurosci Res. 2021;99(3):750-777. doi:10.1002/jnr.24752</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zalpoor H, Akbari A, Samei A, et al. The roles of Eph receptors, neuropilin-1, P2X7, and CD147 in COVID-19-associated neurodegenerative diseases: inflammasome and JaK inhibitors as potential promising therapies. Cell Mol Biol Lett. 2022;27(1):10. doi:10.1186/s11658-022-00311-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zalpoor H, Shapourian H, Akbari A, Shahveh S, Haghshenas L. Increased neuropilin-1 expression by COVID-19: a possible cause of long-term neurological complications and progression of primary brain tumors. Hum Cell. 2022;35(4):1301-1303. doi:10.1007/s13577-022-00716-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesce E, Manfrini N, Cordiglieri C, et al. Exosomes recovered from the plasma of COVID-19 patients expose SARS-CoV-2 Spike-derived fragments and contribute to the adaptive immune response. Front Immunol. 2022;12:785941. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.785941</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdanpanah N, Rezaei N. Autoimmune complications of COVID-19. J Med Virol. 2022;94(1):54-62. doi:10.1002/jmv.27292</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagu P, Parashar A, Behl T, Mehta V. CNS implications of COVID-19: a comprehensive review. Rev Neurosci. 2021;32(2):219-234. doi:10.1515/revneuro-2020-0070</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murta V, Villarreal A, Ramos AJ. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 impact on the central nervous system: are astrocytes and microglia main players or merely bystanders. ASN Neuro. 2020;12:175909142095496. doi:10.1177/1759091420954960</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merad M, Martin JC. Pathological inflammation in patients with COVID-19: a key role for monocytes and macrophages. Nat Rev Immunol. 2020;20(6):355-362. doi:10.1038/s41577-020-0331-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakubec M, Maple-Gr&#xf8;dem J, Akbari S, Nesse S, Halskau &#xd8;, Mork-Jansson AE. Plasma-derived exosome-like vesicles are enriched in lyso-phospholipids and pass the blood-brain barrier. PLoS One. 2020;15(9):e0232442. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0232442</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F, et al. SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature. 2022;604(7907):697-707. doi:10.1038/s41586-022-04569-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krasemann S, Haferkamp U, Pfefferle S, et al. The blood-brain barrier is dysregulated in COVID-19 and serves as a CNS entry route for SARS-CoV-2. Stem Cell Rep. 2022;17(2):307-320. doi:10.1016/j.stemcr.2021.12.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sur S, Khatun M, Steele R, Isbell TS, Ray R, Ray RB. Exosomes from COVID-19 patients carry tenascin-C and fibrinogen-&#x3b2; in triggering inflammatory signals in cells of distant organ. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(6):3184. doi:10.3390/ijms22063184</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Zhao T, Deng R, Xia X, Li B, Wang X. A study of differential circRNA and lncRNA expressions in COVID-19-infected peripheral blood. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):7991. doi:10.1038/s41598-021-86134-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furuno M, Pang KC, Ninomiya N, et al. Clusters of internally primed transcripts reveal novel long noncoding RNAs. PLoS Genet. 2006;2(4):e37. doi:10.1371/journal.pgen.0020037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salzman J, Gawad C, Wang PL, Lacayo N, Brown PO. Circular RNAs are the predominant transcript isoform from hundreds of human genes in diverse cell types. PLoS One. 2012;7(2):e30733. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0030733</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Sun T, An J, et al. Potential roles of exosomes in Parkinson's disease: from pathogenesis, diagnosis, and treatment to prognosis. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2020;8:86. doi:10.3389/fcell.2020.00086</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leta V, Rodr&#xed;guez-Violante M, Abundes A, et al. Parkinson's disease and post-COVID-19 syndrome: the Parkinson's&#xa0;long-COVID spectrum. Mov Disorders. 2021;36(6):1287-1289. doi:10.1002/mds.28622</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mysiris DS, Vavougios GD, Karamichali E, et al. Post-COVID-19 Parkinsonism and Parkinson's disease pathogenesis: the exosomal cargo hypothesis. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(17):9739. doi:10.3390/ijms23179739</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiandaca MS, Kapogiannis D, Mapstone M, et al. Identification of preclinical Alzheimer's disease by a profile of pathogenic proteins in neurally derived blood exosomes: a case-control study. Alzheimer's Demen. 2015;11(6):600-607 e601. doi:10.1016/j.jalz.2014.06.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetzl EJ, Boxer A, Schwartz JB, et al. Low neural exosomal levels of cellular survival factors in Alzheimer's disease. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2015;2(7):769-773. doi:10.1002/acn3.211</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winston CN, Goetzl EJ, Akers JC, et al. Prediction of conversion from mild cognitive impairment to dementia with neuronally derived blood exosome protein profile. Alzheimer's Dement: Diagn Assess Dis Monit. 2016;3:63-72. doi:10.1016/j.dadm.2016.04.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetzl EJ, Ledreux A, Granholm AC, et al. Neuron-derived exosome proteins may contribute to progression from repetitive mild traumatic brain injuries to chronic traumatic encephalopathy. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:452. doi:10.3389/fnins.2019.0045</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun B, Tang N, Peluso MJ, et al. Characterization and biomarker analyses of post-COVID-19 complications and neurological manifestations. Cells. 2021;10(2):386. doi:10.3390/cells10020386</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciaccio M, Lo Sasso B, Scazzone C, et al. COVID-19 and Alzheimer's disease. Brain Sci. 2021;11(3):305. doi:10.3390/brainsci11030305</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman MA, Islam K, Rahman S, Alamin M. Neurobiochemical cross-talk between COVID-19 and Alzheimer's disease. Mol Neurobiol. 2021;58(3):1017-1023. doi:10.1007/s12035-020-02177-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagheri-Hosseinabadi Z, Ostad Ebrahimi H, Bahrehmand F, Taghipour G, Abbasifard M. The relationship between serum levels of interleukin-2 and IL-8 with circulating microRNA-10b in patients with COVID-19. Iran&#xa0;J&#xa0;Immunol: IJI. 2021;18(1):65-73. doi:10.22034/iji.2021.88780.1904</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blount GS, Coursey L, Kocerha J. MicroRNA networks in cognition and dementia. Cells. 2022;11(12):1882. doi:10.3390/cells11121882</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Q, Wang Q, Zhao B, et al. Identification of a SARS-CoV-2 virus-encoded small non-coding RNA in association with the neurological disorders in COVID-19 patients. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2022;7(1):107. doi:10.1038/s41392-022-00969-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Hossinger A, Heum&#xfc;ller SE, et al. Highly efficient intercellular spreading of protein misfolding mediated by viral ligand-receptor interactions. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):5739. doi:10.1038/s41467-021-25855-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pezzini A, Padovani A. Lifting the mask on neurological manifestations of COVID-19. Nat Rev Neurol. 2020;16(11):636-644. doi:10.1038/s41582-020-0398-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tereshchenko LG, Bishop A, Fisher-Campbell N, et al. Risk of cardiovascular events after COVID-19. Am J Cardiol. 2022;179:102-109. doi:10.1016/j.amjcard.2022.06.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nature Med. 2022;28(3):583-590. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-01689-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noh JY, Yoon JG, Seong H, et al. Asymptomatic infection and atypical manifestations of COVID-19: comparison of viral shedding duration. J Infect. 2020;81(5):816-846. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2020.05.035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Nilsson-Payant BE, Han Y, et al. Cardiomyocytes recruit monocytes upon SARS-CoV-2 infection by secreting CCL2. Stem Cell Rep. 2021;16(10):2565. doi:10.1016/j.stemcr.2021.09.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikdoust F, Pazoki M, Mohammadtaghizadeh M, Aghaali MK, Amrovani M. Exosomes: potential player in endothelial dysfunction in cardiovascular disease. Cardiovasc Toxicol. 2022;22(3):225-235. doi:10.1007/s12012-021-09700-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdi A, AlOtaiby S, Badarin FA, Khraibi A, Hamdan H, Nader M. Interaction of SARS-CoV-2 with cardiomyocytes: insight into the underlying molecular mechanisms of cardiac injury and pharmacotherapy. Biomed Pharmacother. 2022;146:112518. doi:10.1016/j.biopha.2021.112518</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beddingfield BJ, Iwanaga N, Chapagain PP, et al. The integrin binding peptide, ATN-161, as a novel therapy for SARS-CoV-2 infection. JACC: Basic&#xa0;Transl Sci. 2021;6(1):1-8. doi:10.1016/j.jacbts.2020.10.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson EL, Alkass K, Bergmann O, Maguire JJ, Roderick HL, Davenport AP. Genes encoding ACE2, TMPRSS2 and related proteins mediating SARS-CoV-2 viral entry are upregulated with age in human cardiomyocytes. J Mol Cell Cardiol. 2020;147:88-91. doi:10.1016/j.yjmcc.2020.08.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thum T. SARS-CoV-2 receptor ACE2 expression in the human heart: cause of a post-pandemic wave of heart failure? Eur Heart J. 2020;41(19):1807-1809. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa410</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tertel T, Tomi&#x107; S, &#x110;oki&#x107; J, et al. Serum-derived extracellular vesicles: novel biomarkers reflecting the disease severity of COVID-19 patients. J Extracell Vesicles. 2022;11(8):e12257. doi:10.1002/jev2.12257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, Chen W, Zhang Z, et al. CD147-spike protein is a novel route for SARS-CoV-2 infection to host cells. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2020;5(1):283. doi:10.1038/s41392-020-00426-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell RD, Winkler EA, Singh I, et al. Apolipoprotein E controls cerebrovascular integrity via cyclophilin A. Nature. 2012;485(7399):512-516. doi:10.1038/nature11087</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Ma Z, Zhang Y, et al. The role of cyclophilins in viral infection and the immune response. J Infect. 2022;85(4):365-373. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2022.08.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathy JE, Ma S, Compton T, Lin K. Combinations of cyclophilin inhibitor NIM811 with hepatitis C Virus NS3-4A Protease or NS5B polymerase inhibitors enhance antiviral activity and suppress the emergence of resistance. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2008;52(9):3267-3275. doi:10.1128/AAC.00498-08</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawlotsky JM. COVID-19 pandemic: time to revive the cyclophilin inhibitor alisporivir. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71(16):2191-2194. doi:10.1093/cid/ciaa587</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zulian A, Rizzo E, Schiavone M, et al. NIM811, a cyclophilin inhibitor without immunosuppressive activity, is beneficial in collagen VI congenital muscular dystrophy models. Hum Mol Gen. 2014;23(20):5353-5363. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddu254</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan P, Zhao H, Zhang X, et al. Cyclophilin a signaling induces pericyte-associated blood-brain barrier disruption after subarachnoid hemorrhage. J Neuroinflammation. 2020;17(1):16. doi:10.1186/s12974-020-1699-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao MM, Yang WL, Yang FY, et al. Cathepsin L plays a key role in SARS-CoV-2 infection in humans and humanized mice and is a promising target for new drug development. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6(1):134. doi:10.1038/s41392-021-00558-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Chen T, Zhou Y. Mediators of SARS-CoV-2 entry are preferentially enriched in cardiomyocytes. Hereditas. 2021;158(1):4. doi:10.1186/s41065-020-00168-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pironti G, Andersson DC, Lund LH. Mechanistic and therapeutic implications of extracellular vesicles as a potential link between Covid-19 and cardiovascular disease manifestations. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2021;9:640723. doi:10.3389/fcell.2021.640723</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruscella P, Bottini S, Baudesson C, Pawlotsky JM, Feray C, Trabucchi M. Viruses and miRNAs: more friends than foes. Front Microbiol. 2017;8:824. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2017.00824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro-Rodrigues TM, Laundos TL, Pereira-Carvalho R, et al. Exosomes secreted by cardiomyocytes subjected to ischaemia promote cardiac angiogenesis. Cardiovasc Res. 2017;113(11):1338-1350. doi:10.1093/cvr/cvx118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie X, Fan J, Li H, et al. miR-217 promotes cardiac hypertrophy and dysfunction by targeting PTEN. Mol Ther Nucleic Acids. 2018;12:254-266. doi:10.1016/j.omtn.2018.05.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu L, Wang H, Li B, et al. A critical role of cardiac fibroblast-derived exosomes in activating renin angiotensin system in cardiomyocytes. J Mol Cell Cardiol. 2015;89(Pt B):268-279. doi:10.1016/j.yjmcc.2015.10.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donyavi T, Bokharaei-Salim F, Baghi HB, et al. Acute and post-acute phase of COVID-19: analyzing expression patterns of miRNA-29a-3p, 146a-3p, 155-5p, and let-7b-3p in PBMC. Int Immunopharmacol. 2021;97:107641. doi:10.1016/j.intimp.2021.107641</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keikha R, Hashemi-Shahri SM, Jebali A. The relative expression of miR-31, miR-29, miR-126, and miR-17 and their mRNA targets in the serum of COVID-19 patients with different grades during hospitalization. Eur J Med Res. 2021;26(1):75. doi:10.1186/s40001-021-00544-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MAAK, Sany MRU, Islam MS, Islam ABMMK. Epigenetic regulator miRNA pattern differences among SARS-CoV, SARS-CoV-2, and SARS-CoV-2 world-wide isolates delineated the mystery behind the epic pathogenicity and distinct clinical characteristics of pandemic COVID-19. Front Genet. 2020;11:765. doi:10.3389/fgene.2020.00765</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg A, Seeliger B, Derda AA, et al. Circulating cardiovascular microRNAs in critically ill COVID-19 patients. Eur J Heart Fail. 2021;23(3):468-475. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2096</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulzele S, Sahay B, Yusufu I, et al. COVID-19 virulence in aged patients might be impacted by the host cellular MicroRNAs abundance/profile. Aging Dis. 2020;11(3):509-522. doi:10.14336/AD.2020.0428</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centa A, Fonseca AS, da Silva Ferreira SG, et al. Deregulated miRNA expression is associated with endothelial dysfunction in post-mortem lung biopsies of COVID-19 patients. Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol. 2021;320(3):L405-L412. doi:10.1152/ajplung.00457.2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devreese KMJ. COVID-19-related laboratory coagulation findings. Int J Lab Hematol. 2021;43(suppl 1):36-42. doi:10.1111/ijlh.13547</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao D, Zhou F, Luo L, et al. Haematological characteristics and risk factors in the classification and prognosis evaluation of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet Haematol. 2020;7(9):e671-e678. doi:10.1016/S2352-3026(20)30217-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing H, Wu X, Xiang M, Liu L, Novakovic VA, Shi J. Pathophysiological mechanisms of thrombosis in acute and long COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2022;13:992384. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2022.992384</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Yu C, Jing H, et al. Long COVID: the nature of thrombotic sequelae determines the necessity of early anticoagulation. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2022;12:861703. doi:10.3389/fcimb.2022.861703</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gisby JS, Buang NB, Papadaki A, et al. Multi-omics identify falling LRRC15 as a COVID-19 severity marker and persistent pro-thrombotic signals in convalescence. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):7775. doi:10.1038/s41467-022-35454-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noris M, Benigni A, Remuzzi G. The case of complement activation in COVID-19 multiorgan impact. Kidney Int. 2020;98(2):314-322. doi:10.1016/j.kint.2020.05.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messner CB, Demichev V, Wendisch D, et al. Ultra-high-throughput clinical proteomics reveals classifiers of COVID-19 infection. Cell Systems. 2020;11(1):11-24.e4. doi:10.1016/j.cels.2020.05.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satterfield BA, Bhatt DL, Gersh BJ. Cardiac involvement in the long-term implications of COVID-19. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2022;19(5):332-341. doi:10.1038/s41569-021-00631-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaid Y, Puhm F, Allaeys I, et al. Platelets can associate with SARS-Cov-2 RNA and are hyperactivated in COVID-19. Circ Res. 2020;127(11):1404-1418. doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.120.317703</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puhm F, Flamand L, Boilard E. Platelet extracellular vesicles in COVID-19: potential markers and makers. J Leukoc Biol. 2022;111(1):63-74. doi:10.1002/JLB.3MIR0221-100R</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambardella J, Kansakar U, Sardu C, et al. Exosomal miR-145 and miR-885 regulate thrombosis in COVID-19. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2023;384(1):109-115. doi:10.1124/jpet.122.001209</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campello E, Radu CM, Simion C, et al. Longitudinal trend of plasma concentrations of extracellular vesicles in patients hospitalized for COVID-19. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2022;9:770463. doi:10.3389/fcell.2021.770463</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeloye D, Elneima O, Daines L, et al. The long-term sequelae of COVID-19: an international consensus on research priorities for patients with pre-existing and new-onset airways disease. Lancet Respir&#xa0;Med. 2021;9(12):1467-1478. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00286-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajabi H, Mortazavi D, Konyalilar N, et al. Forthcoming complications in recovered COVID-19 patients with COPD and asthma; possible therapeutic opportunities. Cell Commun Signaling. 2022;20(1):173. doi:10.1186/s12964-022-00982-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saheb Sharif-Askari N, Saheb Sharif-Askari F, Alabed M, et al. Airways expression of SARS-CoV-2 receptor, ACE2, and TMPRSS2 is lower in children than adults and increases with smoking and COPD. Mol Ther Methods Clin Dev. 2020;18:1-6. doi:10.1016/j.omtm.2020.05.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JC, Sausville EL, Girish V, et al. Cigarette smoke exposure and inflammatory signaling increase the expression of the SARS-CoV-2 receptor ACE2 in the respiratory tract. Dev Cell. 2020;53(5):514-529.e3. doi:10.1016/j.devcel.2020.05.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Y, Cheng C, Wei Y, Yang F, Li G. The role of exosomes in inflammatory diseases and tumor-related inflammation. Cells. 2022;11(6):1005. doi:10.3390/cells11061005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Yan J, Tong L, Liu S, Zhang Y. The role of exosomes from BALF in lung disease. J Cell Physiol. 2022;237(1):161-168. doi:10.1002/jcp.30553</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alipoor SD, Mirsaeidi M. SARS-CoV-2 cell entry beyond the ACE2 receptor. Mol Biol Rep. 2022;49(11):10715-10727. doi:10.1007/s11033-022-07700-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao K, Tan Q, Ma Y, et al. Proteomics of extracellular vesicles in plasma reveals the characteristics and residual traces of COVID-19 patients without underlying diseases after 3 months of recovery. Cell Death Dis. 2021;12(6):541. doi:10.1038/s41419-021-03816-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein SR, Ramelli SC, Grazioli A, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence in the human body and brain at autopsy. Nature. 2022;612(7941):758-763. doi:10.1038/s41586-022-05542-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roingeard P, Eymieux S, Burlaud-Gaillard J, Hourioux C, Patient R, Blanchard E. The double-membrane vesicle (DMV): a virus-induced organelle dedicated to the replication of SARS-CoV-2 and other positive-sense single-stranded RNA viruses. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2022;79(8):425. doi:10.1007/s00018-022-04469-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia B, Pan X, Luo RH, et al. Extracellular vesicles mediate antibody-resistant transmission of SARS-CoV-2. Cell Discov. 2023;9(1):2. doi:10.1038/s41421-022-00510-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collis H (2022). WHO urges action as 17M long COVID cases estimated in Europe region.&#xa0; Accessed February 2, 2023. https://www.politico.eu/article/who-urges-action-as-17m-long-covid-cases-estimated-in-europe-region/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach K (2022). New data shows long Covid is keeping as many as 4 million people out of work.&#xa0; Accessed February 2, 2023. https://www.brookings.edu/research/new-data-shows-long-covid-is-keeping-as-many-as-4-million-people-out-of-work/</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>