<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38269219</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nutritional and Wellness Strategies for Neurological and Psychiatric Recovery From Post-COVID Syndrome and Post-acute Sequelae of COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e51076</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e51076</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e51076</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.51076</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The post-COVID syndrome was officially recognized as a disability under the Americans with Disabilities Act, indicating that this syndrome has made a significant impact on our populace. Also, post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) is a term that describes the long-term health problems that some people experience after being infected with the virus that causes COVID-19. These problems can last for weeks, months, or even years, and can affect various parts of the body, such as the heart, lungs, brain, and blood vessels. This narrative review paper utilized the PubMed database to explore the pathophysiology of post-COVID syndrome's neurological and psychiatric symptoms and PASC&#xa0;and make therapeutic connections to the known mechanisms of various nutritional, supplemental, and wellness approaches. Searches were queried on the PubMed database between March 29&#xa0;and April 16, 2022, using the phrases "long-covid,"&#xa0;"post-COVID syndrome,"&#xa0;"Vitamin D covid,"&#xa0;"vitamin C covid,"&#xa0;"omega-3 covid,"&#xa0;"kynurenine covid,"&#xa0;"whole-body hyperthermia,"&#xa0;"mushrooms immunity,"&#xa0;"n-acetyl cysteine covid,"&#xa0;"mushrooms cognition,"&#xa0;"sugar consumption inflammation," and "covid microbiome."&#xa0;Articles were screened for their relevance to the discussion of post-COVID syndrome's neurological and psychiatric pathophysiology at the discretion of the principal researcher. There were no limitations regarding publication years, but articles from 2005 to April 2022 were cited. Micro-ischemic disease, neuropathy, autoimmune processes, mast-cell activation, and impaired blood-brain barriers have all been implicated in the pathological processes of this syndrome with varying degrees of supportive evidence. The common denominators, however, are inflammation and oxidative stress. Therefore, a beneficial approach to dealing with the complications of post-COVID syndrome would be to reduce the exacerbations of these common denominators with lifestyle and nutritional changes. Replenishing nutritional deficiencies, supplementing with N-acetylcysteine, decreasing consumption of refined sugars, preventing dysbiosis of the microbiome, performing exercises, increasing dietary intake of mushrooms, utilizing beneficial herbs such as rosemary, and increasing the core body temperature through whole-body hyperthermia seem&#xa0;to show potential for efficacy in this pursuit. Considering the safety and evidence-based connections of the therapies explored for dealing with the post-Covid syndrome, it could be of great benefit and of little harm to our patients to include these considerations in formulating post-Covid treatment plans.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023, Schaefer et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schaefer</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foundational Sciences, Nova Southeastern University Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Osteopathic Medicine, Clearwater, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khanna</LastName><ForeName>Deepesh</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foundational Sciences, Nova Southeastern University Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Osteopathic Medicine, Clearwater, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid microbiome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kynurenine covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-covid syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurological and psychiatric complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">omega-3 covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pathophysiology of post-covid syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post covid neurological</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-covid-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vitamin c covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vitamin d covid</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38269219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10806386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.51076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard.  [
Dec;
2023 
];Organization Organization, W. H. https://covid19.who.int/ 2023 1:2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID Data Tracker.  [
Dec;
2023 
];CDC (2023. https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#datatracker-home 2023 1:2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC Science behind Long COVID.  [
Dec;
2023 
];https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-science.html 2023 1:2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The lasting effects of COVID-19 on the progression of metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease (MASLD) Backer S, Khanna D. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10576539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37842470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID syndrome: a scoping review. Sobczak A, Castellano B, Castellano C, Khanna D. https://scholar.google.com/citations?view_op=view_citation&amp;hl=en&amp;user=t41RJyoAAAAJ&amp;sortby=pubdate&amp;citation_for_view=t41RJyoAAAAJ:dfsIfKJdRG4C APHA. 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurological complications of COVID-19 infection. Brauer T, Khanna D. https://scholar.google.com/citations?view_op=view_citation&amp;hl=en&amp;user=t41RJyoAAAAJ&amp;sortby=pubdate&amp;citation_for_view=t41RJyoAAAAJ:zA6iFVUQeVQC APHA. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11341106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39176347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-COVID syndrome: incidence, clinical spectrum, and challenges for primary healthcare professionals. Pavli A, Theodoridou M, Maltezou HC. Arch Med Res. 2021;52:575&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8093949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33962805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent neurologic symptoms and cognitive dysfunction in non-hospitalized Covid-19 "long haulers". Graham EL, Clark JR, Orban ZS, et al. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2021;8:1073&#x2013;1085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33755344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laboratory and point-of-care testing for COVID- 19: a review of recent developments . Kalia R, Kaila R, Kahar P, Khanna D. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9517582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36185888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A review of COVID-19 in relation to metabolic syndrome: obesity, hypertension, diabetes, and dyslipidemia. Makhoul E, Aklinski JL, Miller J, et al. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9420458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36051728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Socioeconomic determinants of COVID-19 incidence and mortality in Florida. Backer S, Rezene A, Kahar P, Khanna D. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8944399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35371770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of COVID-19 on pregnant women and newborns: a review. Patel BM, Khanna D, Khanna S, Hapshy V, Khanna P, Kahar P, Parmar MS. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9676047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36415402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comprehensive review of SARS-CoV-2 vaccines: Pfizer, Moderna &amp; Johnson &amp; Johnson. Patel R, Kaki M, Potluri VS, Kahar P, Khanna D. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2022;18:2002083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8862159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35130825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of vitamin C in human immunity and its treatment potential against COVID- 19: a review article . Moore A, Khanna D. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9925039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36793827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A survey of public health failures during COVID-19. Dominquez BC, Hernandez A, Fernandez-Pacheco A, Taylor L, Kahar P, Khanna D. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9833812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36644033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Transcranial doppler ultrasound evidence of active cerebral embolization in COVID-19. Batra A, Clark JR, LaHaye K, et al. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;30:105542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33341023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessing brain capillaries in coronavirus disease 2019. Nauen DW, Hooper JE, Stewart CM, Solomon IH. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78:760&#x2013;762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7881367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33576767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: an overview. Raveendran AV, Jayadevan R, Sashidharan S. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15:869&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathogenesis of dysgeusia in COVID-19 patients: a scoping review. Mahmoud MM, Abuohashish HM, Khairy DA, Bugshan AS, Khan AM, Moothedath MM. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2021;25:1114&#x2013;1134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Could SARS-CoV-2 Spike protein be responsible for long-COVID syndrome? Theoharides TC. Mol Neurobiol. 2022;59:1850&#x2013;1861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8757925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35028901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of SARS-CoV-2 proteins on vascular permeability. Rauti R, Shahoha M, Leichtmann-Bardoogo Y, et al. Elife. 2021;10:69314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8545399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34694226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood-brain barrier breakdown in the aging human hippocampus. Montagne A, Barnes SR, Sweeney MD, et al. Neuron. 2015;85:296&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4350773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25611508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D and marine omega 3 fatty acid supplementation and incident autoimmune disease: VITAL randomized controlled trial. Hahn J, Cook NR, Alexander EK, et al. BMJ. 2022;376:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8791065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The use of IV vitamin C for patients with COVID-19: a case series. Hiedra R, Lo KB, Elbashabsheh M, et al. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2020;18:1259&#x2013;1261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7441798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32662690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N-acetylcysteine in depressive symptoms and functionality: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Fernandes BS, Dean OM, Dodd S, Malhi GS, Berk M. J Clin Psychiatry. 2016;77:0&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27137430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N-acetylcysteine augmentation therapy for moderate-to-severe obsessive-compulsive disorder: randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Paydary K, Akamaloo A, Ahmadipour A, Pishgar F, Emamzadehfard S, Akhondzadeh S. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2016;41:214&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26931055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 and selenium deficiency: a systematic review . Fakhrolmobasheri M, Mazaheri-Tehrani S, Kieliszek M, Zeinalian M, Abbasi M, Karimi F, Mozafari AM. Biol Trace Elem Res. 2022;200:3945&#x2013;3956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8569840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34739678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D and COVID-19: an overview of recent evidence. Ghelani D, Alesi S, Mousa A. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:10559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8509048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34638897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regarding: "the effect of omega-3 fatty acid supplementation on clinical and biochemical parameters of critically ill patients with COVID-19: a randomized clinical trial". Nakata T, Ariie T, Taito S. J Transl Med. 2021;19:282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34193209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acid supplementation improves neurologic recovery and attenuates white matter injury after experimental traumatic brain injury. Pu H, Guo Y, Zhang W, et al. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2013;33:1474&#x2013;1484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3764381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23801244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relationship between C-reactive protein and glucose levels in community-dwelling subjects without diabetes: the Hisayama Study. Doi Y, Kiyohara Y, Kubo M, et al. Diabetes Care. 2005;28:1211&#x2013;1213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15855593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High-glucose or -fructose diet cause changes of the gut microbiota and metabolic disorders in mice without body weight change. Do MH, Lee E, Oh MJ, Kim Y, Park HY. Nutrients. 2018;10:761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6024874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29899272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Individuals with obesity and COVID-19: a global perspective on the epidemiology and biological relationships. Popkin BM, Du S, Green WD, et al. Obes Rev. 2020;21:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32845580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gut microbiota dynamics in a prospective cohort of patients with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Liu Q, Mak JW, Su Q, et al. Gut. 2022;71:544&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skeletal muscle PGC-1&#x3b1;1 modulates kynurenine metabolism and mediates resilience to stress-induced depression. Agudelo Leandro Z, Femen&#xed;a T, Orhan F, et al. Cell. 2015;160:351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25259918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Increased Kynurenine indicates a fatal course of COVID-19. Mangge H, Herrmann M, Meinitzer A, et al. Antioxidants (Basel) 2021;10:1960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8750518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34943063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The association between mushroom consumption and mild cognitive impairment: A community-based cross-sectional study in Singapore. Feng L, Cheah IK, Ng MM, et al. J Alzheimers Dis. 2019;68:197&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30775990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mushrooms and immunity. Motta F, Gershwin ME, Selmi C. J Autoimmun. 2021;117:102576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33276307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurogenesis-dependent antidepressant-like activity of Hericium erinaceus in an animal model of depression. Chong PS, Poon CH, Roy J, et al. Chin Med. 2021;16:132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8650354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34876186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higher mushroom consumption is associated with lower risk of cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. Ba DM, Ssentongo P, Beelman RB, Muscat J, Gao X, Richie JP. Adv Nutr. 2021;12:1691&#x2013;1704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8483951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33724299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potential therapeutic use of the rosemary diterpene carnosic acid for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease, Parkinson&#x2019;s disease, and Long-COVID through NRF2 activation to counteract the NLRP3 inflammasome. Satoh T, Trudler D, Oh CK, Lipton SA. Antioxidants (Basel) 2022;11:124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8772720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35052628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The impact of whole-body hyperthermia interventions on mood and depression - are we ready for recommendations for clinical application? Hanusch KU, Janssen CW. Int J Hyperthermia. 2019;36:573&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31159624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of sauna bathing on stress-related genes expression in athletes and non-athletes. Zychowska M, P&#xf3;&#x142;rola P, Chru&#x15b;ci&#x144;ski G, Zieli&#x144;ska J, G&#xf3;ral-P&#xf3;&#x142;rola J. Ann Agric Environ Med. 2017;24:104&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28378983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>