<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36949968</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Review of Stellate Ganglion Block as an Adjunctive Treatment Modality.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e35174</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e35174</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e35174</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.35174</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Peripheral nerve blocks are becoming increasingly used as adjunctive treatment modalities for a variety of conditions refractory to medical management. Right or left stellate ganglion blocks (SGB) are a specific type of peripheral nerve block that target the sympathetic blockade of neuronal impulses using the injection of local anesthetic and steroids into nerve bundles in the cervical area. This review article is intended to summarize the common uses of stellate ganglion blocks and explain the procedural technique, which has evolved with technological advances in ultrasonography. The similarities between these disease processes are centered around sympathetic hyperactivity. This sympathetic overdrive state is created by increased levels of nerve growth factor (NGF), which causes a cascade of sympathetic sprouting resulting in increased norepinephrine (NE) systemically. Reversal of this cascade by local anesthetic injection into the stellate ganglion thereby reduces NGF and sympathetic sprouting subsequently lowering overall norepinephrine levels. This is the unifying theory by which SGB is able to provide resolution for the varied clinical conditions described in this article.&#xa0; This review article discusses the physiology of several conditions where stellate ganglion blocks are being investigated as an adjunct treatment modality, including anosmia, PTSD, long-COVID, chronic fatigue syndrome, menopausal hot flashes, and ventricular tachyarrhythmias. Overall, the current literature supporting the use of stellate ganglion blocks for several esoteric conditions is limited; however, case reports to date have shown promising evidence-based results supporting their use as an adjunctive treatment among patients with refractory symptoms to existing treatment algorithms. In conclusion, SGB should be considered among patients with refractory symptoms for medical management in the conditions discussed in this article. Further research is needed to delineate which patients will benefit from the use of SGB, the use of subsequent blocks and timelines in between injections, and unilateral versus bilateral blockade.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023, Kirkpatrick et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kirkpatrick</LastName><ForeName>Kennedy</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston , USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Mashfee H</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Krishna B</ForeName><Initials>KB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology and Interventional Pain, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adjunctive therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anosmia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hot flashes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">menopause</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peripheral nerve block</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ptsd</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sgb</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stellate ganglion block</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ventricular tachycardia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36949968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10029323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.35174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Piraccini E, Munakomi S, Chang KV. Treasure Island: StatPearls; 2022. Stellate Ganglion Blocks.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29939575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrotra M, Reddy V, Singh P. Vol. 19. Treasure Island: StatPearls Publishing; 2022. Neuroanatomy, Stellate Ganglion; p. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30969629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervical sympathetic and stellate ganglion blocks. Elias M. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16906187/ Pain Physician. 2000;3:294&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16906187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellate ganglion block for long Covid symptom management: a case report. Khan MH, Kirkpatrick KP, Deng Y, Shah KB. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9822527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36628048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ultrasound-guided stellate ganglion block: safety and efficacy. Narouze S. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 2014;18:424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24760493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A unifying theory linking the prolonged efficacy of the stellate ganglion block for the treatment of chronic regional pain syndrome (CRPS), hot flashes, and posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) Lipov EG, Joshi JR, Sanders S, Slavin KV. Med Hypotheses. 2009;72:657&#x2013;661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19237252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellate ganglion blockade (SGB) for refractory index finger pain - a case report. Hey M, Wilson I, Johnson MI. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2011;54:181&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21493175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modulation of NGF by cortisol and the Stellate Ganglion Block - is this the missing link between memory consolidation and PTSD? Lipov E, Kelzenberg B, Rothfeld C, Abdi S. Med Hypotheses. 2012;79:750&#x2013;753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22998954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novel mechanism of action hypothesized for stellate ganglion block related to melatonin. Uchida K, Tateda T, Hino H. Med Hypotheses. 2002;59:446&#x2013;449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12208186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A review of the use of stellate ganglion block in the treatment of PTSD. Lipov E, Ritchie EC. https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11920-015-0599-4. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2015;17:599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26073361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therapeutic potential of stellate ganglion block in orofacial pain: a mini review. Jeon Y. J Dent Anesth Pain Med. 2016;16:159&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5586552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28884148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of sonoanatomy relevant to performing stellate ganglion blocks using anterior and lateral simulated approaches: an observational study. Bhatia A, Flamer D, Peng PW. Can J Anaesth. 2012;59:1040&#x2013;1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22956268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ultrasound imaging for stellate ganglion block: direct visualization of puncture site and local anesthetic spread. A pilot study. Kapral S, Krafft P, Gosch M, Fleischmann D, Weinstabl C. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7577781/ Reg Anesth. 1995;20:323&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7577781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ultrasound-guided pain interventions - a review of techniques for peripheral nerves. Soneji N, Peng PW. Korean J Pain. 2013;26:111&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3629336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23614071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>[Complications and side effects of stellate ganglion blockade. Results of a questionnaire survey] Wulf H, Maier C. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1570888/ Anaesthesist. 1992;41:146&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1570888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ultrasound-guided interventional procedures in pain medicine: a review of anatomy, sonoanatomy, and procedures: part I: nonaxial structures. Peng PW, Narouze S. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2009;34:458&#x2013;474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19920421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Complications associated with stellate ganglion nerve block: a systematic review. Goel V, Patwardhan AM, Ibrahim M, Howe CL, Schultz DM, Shankar H. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9034660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30992414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severe hypertension after stellate ganglion block. Kimura T, Nishiwaki K, Yokota S, Komatsu T, Shimada Y. Br J Anaesth. 2005;94:840&#x2013;842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15849210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Transient cough attacks after right stellate ganglion block. Atici S, Akoz K. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2010;35:318&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20460973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blocks of the sympathetic nervous system. Naveira FA, Snell JA, Rauck RL. https://rapm.bmj.com/content/35/3/318-319.citation-tools Phys Med Rehabil. 1996;10:245&#x2013;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retropharyngeal or cervicomediastinal haematomas following stellate ganglion block. Okuda Y, Urabe K, Kitajima T. Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2003;20:757&#x2013;759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12974602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Life-threatening airway obstruction due to retropharyngeal and cervicomediastinal hematomas following stellate ganglion block. Takanami I, Abiko T, Koizumi S. Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2009;57:311&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19629898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serious cervical hematoma after stellate ganglion block. Uchida T, Nakao S, Morimoto M, Iwamoto T. J Anesth. 2015;29:321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25256578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudden unexpected death following stellate ganglion block. Kashiwagi M, Ikeda N, Tsuji A, Kudo K. Leg Med. 1999;1:262&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12935479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ultrasound imaging to estimate risk of esophageal and vascular puncture after conventional stellate ganglion block. Siegenthaler A, Mlekusch S, Schliessbach J, Curatolo M, Eichenberger U. https://rapm.bmj.com/content/37/2/224.info. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2012;37:224&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22157739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The vertebral artery is unlikely to be the sole source of vascular complications occurring during stellate ganglion block. Huntoon MA. Pain Pract. 2010;10:25&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19761512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A rare case of accidental arterial local anesthetic injection under ultrasound-guided stellate ganglion block. Fujiwara S, Komasawa N, Kido H, Minami T. J Clin Anesth. 2016;29:3&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26897437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonas DE, Cusack K, Forneris CA, et al. Rockville: Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality; 2013. Psychological and Pharmacological Treatments for Adults With Posttraumatic Stress Disorder [PTSD]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23658937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The successful use of left-sided stellate ganglion block in patients that fail to respond to right-sided stellate ganglion block for the treatment of post-traumatic stress disorder symptoms: a retrospective analysis of 205 patients. Lipov E, Candido K. Mil Med. 2021;186:319&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33861326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Use of stellate ganglion block for refractory post-traumatic stress disorder: a review of published cases. Navaie M, Keefe MS, Hickey AH, McLay RN, Ritchie EC, Abdi S. J Anesth Clin Res. 2014;5:2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of stellate ganglion block treatment on posttraumatic stress disorder symptoms: a randomized clinical trial. Rae Olmsted KL, Bartoszek M, Mulvaney S, et al. JAMA Psychiatry. 2020;77:130&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6865253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31693083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dysregulation of the right brain: a fundamental mechanism of traumatic attachment and the psychopathogenesis of posttraumatic stress disorder. Schore AN. Aust N Z J Psychiatry. 2002;36:9&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11929435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The successful use of left-sided stellate ganglion block in patients that fail to respond to right-sided stellate ganglion block for the treatment of post-traumatic stress disorder symptoms: a retrospective analysis of 205 patients. Mulvaney SW, Lynch JH, Curtis KE, Ibrahim TS. Mil Med. 2022;187:0&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33580677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anosmia: a clinical review. Boesveldt S, Postma EM, Boak D, et al. Chem Senses. 2017;42:513&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5863566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28531300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olfactory outcomes in chronic rhinosinusitis with nasal polyposis after medical treatments: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Banglawala SM, Oyer SL, Lohia S, Psaltis AJ, Soler ZM, Schlosser RJ. Int Forum Allergy Rhinol. 2014;4:986&#x2013;994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25400017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of smell and taste problems. Mann NM. Cleve Clin J Med. 2002;69:329&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11996203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of olfactory training in patients with olfactory loss. Hummel T, Rissom K, Reden J, H&#xe4;hner A, Weidenbecher M, H&#xfc;ttenbrink KB. Laryngoscope. 2009;119:496&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19235739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term results of stellate ganglion block in patients with olfactory dysfunction. Moon HS, Chon JY, Lee SH, Ju YM, Sung CH. Korean J Pain. 2013;26:57&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3546212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23342209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellate ganglion block for anosmia and dysgeusia due to long COVID. Chauhan G, Upadhyay A, Khanduja S, Emerick T. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9450932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36106285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The efficacy of stellate ganglion block in olfactory disorder following upper respiratory tract infection. Lee NS, Yoon HR, Park JW, et al.  https://www.kjorl.org/journal/view.php?number=2604 Korean J Otorhinolaryngol-Head Neck Surg. 2003;46:568&#x2013;571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellate ganglion block reduces symptoms of long COVID: a case series. Liu LD, Duricka DL. J Neuroimmunol. 2022;362:577784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8653406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34922127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chronic fatigue syndrome: diagnosis and treatment. Yancey JR, Thomas SM. https://www.aafp.org/pubs/afp/issues/2012/1015/p741.html. Am Fam Physician. 2012;86:741&#x2013;746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23062157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sequelae in adults at 6 months after COVID-19 infection. Logue JK, Franko NM, McCulloch DJ, McDonald D, Magedson A, Wolf CR, Chu HY. http://10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.0830 JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33606031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>From inflammation to sickness and depression: when the immune system subjugates the brain. Dantzer R, O'Connor JC, Freund GG, Johnson RW, Kelley KW. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2008;9:46&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2919277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18073775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orthostatic symptoms and reductions in cerebral blood flow in long-haul COVID-19 patients: similarities with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Campen CL, Rowe PC, Visser FC. Medicina (Kaunas) 2021;58</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8778312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35056336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Local anesthetics as a therapeutic tool for post COVID-19 patients: a case report. Vinyes D, Mu&#xf1;oz-Sellart M, Caballero TG. Medicine (Baltimore) 2022;101:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11132361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35839020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscle injections with lidocaine improve resting fatigue and pain in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. Staud R, Kizer T, Robinson ME. J Pain Res. 2017;10:1477&#x2013;1486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5499959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28721090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of menopause-associated vasomotor symptoms: current treatment options, challenges and future directions. Pachman DR, Jones JM, Loprinzi CL. Int J Womens Health. 2010;2:123&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2971731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21072305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menopausal symptoms in women treated for breast cancer: the prevalence and severity of symptoms and their perceived effects on quality of life. Gupta P, Sturdee DW, Palin SL, Majumder K, Fear R, Marshall T, Paterson I. Climacteric. 2006;9:49&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16428125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathophysiology and treatment of hot flashes. Shanafelt TD, Barton DL, Adjei AA, Loprinzi CL. Mayo Clin Proc. 2002;77:1207&#x2013;1218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12440557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellate ganglion block may relieve hot flashes by interrupting the sympathetic nervous system. Lipov EG, Lipov S, Joshi JR, Santucci VD, Slavin KV, Beck Vigue SG. Med Hypotheses. 2007;69:758&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17425958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilot evaluation of a stellate ganglion block for the treatment of hot flashes. Pachman DR, Barton D, Carns PE, et al. Support Care Cancer. 2011;19:941&#x2013;947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3107341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20496155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellate ganglion block for the management of hot flashes and sleep disturbances in breast cancer survivors: an uncontrolled experimental study with 24 weeks of follow-up. Haest K, Kumar A, Van Calster B, et al. Ann Oncol. 2012;23:1449&#x2013;1454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22039079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of stellate ganglion block on vasomotor symptoms: findings from a randomized controlled clinical trial in postmenopausal women. Walega DR, Rubin LH, Banuvar S, Shulman LP, Maki PM. Menopause. 2014;21:807&#x2013;814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4110158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24496086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of the effects of stellate ganglion block and paroxetine on hot flashes and sleep disturbance in breast cancer survivors. Rahimzadeh P, Imani F, Nafissi N, Ebrahimi B, Faiz SH. Cancer Manag Res. 2018;10:4831&#x2013;4837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6208490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30464591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellate ganglion block as a treatment for vasomotor symptoms: clinical application. Lee YS, Wie C, Pew S, Kling JM. Cleve Clin J Med. 2022;89:147&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35232827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellate ganglion blockade: an intervention for the management of ventricular arrhythmias. Ganesh A, Qadri YJ, Boortz-Marx RL, et al. Curr Hypertens Rep. 2020;22:100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7646199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33097982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autonomic modulation for the treatment of ventricular arrhythmias: therapeutic use of percutaneous stellate ganglion blocks. Fudim M, Boortz-Marx R, Patel CB, Sun AY, Piccini JP. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2017;28:446&#x2013;449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28019045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellate ganglion blockade for the treatment of refractory ventricular arrhythmias. Fudim M, Qadri YJ, Waldron NH, et al. JACC Clin Electrophysiol. 2020;6:562&#x2013;571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32439042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>