<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37929759</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0144-6657</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>63</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The British journal of clinical psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Clin Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19 and mental health in the UK: Depression, anxiety and insomnia and their associations with persistent physical symptoms and risk and vulnerability factors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>92</StartPage><EndPage>104</EndPage><MedlinePgn>92-104</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/bjc.12446</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Mental health problems and persistent COVID-19 symptoms were prevalent in the context of COVID-19. However, despite the long-observed association between physical symptoms and mental health problems, such association has not been adequately examined in the context of COVID-19. Our understanding of wider patterns of risk and vulnerability factors for mental health also remains limited. This study investigated the associations between general mental health, and persistent physical symptoms, and additional risk and vulnerability factors in the context of COVID-19.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Two hundred fourteen adults, living in the UK, recruited via social media, completed the online survey and were included in the analyses. Correlation and regression analyses were conducted to examine the associations of persistent physical symptoms and risk and vulnerability factors with measures of general mental health including depressive symptoms, anxiety and insomnia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">78.5% of the participants reported between 1 and 26 persistent symptoms, and about 28%-92% of them associated these symptoms with COVID-19 infection. Persistent physical symptoms were uniquely associated with all measures of mental health, &#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;.19-.32. Mental health history and worries were the most prominent risk factors, |&#x3b2;|&#x2009;=&#x2009;.12-.43.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">People who experience more persistent physical symptoms post-COVID-19 have poorer mental health. It may be important to consider and discuss the recovery from COVID-19 beyond a negative COVID-19 test. Multidisciplinary interventions that address the complex impact of COVID-19 for people with long COVID are needed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. British Journal of Clinical Psychology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Psychological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0038-9266</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Middlesex University, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCracken</LastName><ForeName>Lance M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9734-0153</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Clin Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8105533</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0144-6657</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008603" MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007319" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006113" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United Kingdom</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">persistent symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">&#x2018;long COVID&#x2019;</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37929759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjc.12446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Alwan, N. A. (2020). A negative COVID-19 test does not mean recovery. Nature, 584(7820), 170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastien, C. H., Valli&#xe8;res, A., &amp; Morin, C. M. (2001). Validation of the insomnia severity index as an outcome measure for insomnia research. Sleep Medicine, 2(4), 297-307. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1389-9457(00)00065-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blix, I., Birkeland, M. S., &amp; Thoresen, S. (2021). Worry and mental health in the COVID-19 pandemic: Vulnerability factors in the general Norwegian population. BMC Public Health, 21(1), 1-10. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-021-10927-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, S., Jones, P. B., Underwood, B. R., Moore, A., Bullmore, E. T., Banerjee, S., Osimo, E. F., Deakin, J. B., Hatfield, C. F., &amp; Thompson, F. J. (2020). The early impact of COVID-19 on mental health and community physical health services and their patients' mortality in Cambridgeshire and Peterborough, UK. Journal of Psychiatric Research, 131, 244-254. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychires.2020.09.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GOV.UK. (2022). Population of England and Wales. https://www.ethnicity-facts-figures.service.gov.uk/uk-population-by-ethnicity/national-and-regional-populations/population-of-england-and-wales/latest</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, J. H., Womack, K. N., Tenforde, M. W., Files, D. C., Gibbs, K. W., Shapiro, N. I., Prekker, M. E., Erickson, H. L., Steingrub, J. S., &amp; Qadir, N. (2022). Associations between persistent symptoms after mild COVID-19 and long-term health status, quality of life, and psychological distress. Influenza and Other Respiratory Viruses, 16(4), 680-689. https://doi.org/10.1111/irv.12980</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes, S. C., Villatte, M., Levin, M., &amp; Hildebrandt, M. (2011). Open, aware, and active: Contextual approaches as an emerging trend in the behavioral and cognitive therapies. Annual Review of Clinical Psychology, 7, 141-168. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-032210-104449</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knolle, F., Ronan, L., &amp; Murray, G. K. (2021). The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on mental health in the general population: A comparison between Germany and the UK. BMC Psychology, 9(1), 60. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40359-021-00565-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke, K., Jackson, J. L., &amp; Judith Chamberlin, P. A. (1997). Depressive and anxiety disorders in patients presenting with physical complaints: Clinical predictors and outcome. The American Journal of Medicine, 103(5), 339-347. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0002-9343(97)00241-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke, K., Spitzer, R. L., Williams, J. B., Linzer, M., Hahn, S. R., de Gruy, F. V., III, &amp; Brody, D. (1994). Physical symptoms in primary care. Predictors of psychiatric disorders and functional impairment. Archives of Family Medicine, 3(9), 774-779. https://doi.org/10.1001/archfami.3.9.774</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke, K., Spitzer, R. L., &amp; Williams, J. B. W. (2001). The PHQ-9: Validity of a brief depression severity measure. Journal of General Internal Medicine, 16(9), 606-613. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson, G. E., Booth-Kewley, S., Merrill, L. L., &amp; Stander, V. A. (2001). Physical symptoms as indicators of depression and anxiety. Military Medicine, 166(9), 796-799. https://doi.org/10.1093/milmed/166.9.796</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon, S., Wegman-Ostrosky, T., Perelman, C., Sepulveda, R., Rebolledo, P. A., Cuapio, A., &amp; Villapol, S. (2021). More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Scientific Reports, 11(1), 16144. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magn&#xfa;sd&#xf3;ttir, I., Lovik, A., Unnarsd&#xf3;ttir, A. B., McCartney, D., Ask, H., K&#xf5;iv, K., Christoffersen, L. A. N., Johnson, S. U., Hauksd&#xf3;ttir, A., &amp; Fawns-Ritchie, C. (2022). Acute COVID-19 severity and mental health morbidity trajectories in patient populations of six nations: An observational study. The Lancet Public Health, 7(5), e406-e416. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2468-2667(22)00042-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCracken, L. M., Badinlou, F., Buhrman, M., &amp; Brocki, K. C. (2020). Psychological impact of COVID-19 in the Swedish population: Depression, anxiety, and insomnia and their associations to risk and vulnerability factors. European Psychiatry, 63(1), e81. https://doi.org/10.1192/j.eurpsy.2020.81</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCracken, L. M., Badinlou, F., Buhrman, M., &amp; Brocki, K. C. (2021). The role of psychological flexibility in the context of COVID-19: Associations with depression, anxiety, and insomnia. Journal of Contextual Behavioral Science, 19, 28-35. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcbs.2020.11.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin, C. M., Belleville, G., B&#xe9;langer, L., &amp; Ivers, H. (2011). The insomnia severity index: Psychometric indicators to detect insomnia cases and evaluate treatment response. Sleep, 34(5), 601-608. https://doi.org/10.1093/sleep/34.5.601</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor, R. C., Wetherall, K., Cleare, S., McClelland, H., Melson, A. J., Niedzwiedz, C. L., O'Carroll, R. E., O'Connor, D. B., Platt, S., &amp; Scowcroft, E. (2021). Mental health and well-being during the COVID-19 pandemic: Longitudinal analyses of adults in the UK COVID-19 mental health &amp; wellbeing study. The British Journal of Psychiatry, 218(6), 326-333. https://doi.org/10.1192/bjp.2020.212</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. (2023). Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK. https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/30march2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieh, C., Budimir, S., Delgadillo, J., Barkham, M., Fontaine, J. R., &amp; Probst, T. (2021). Mental health during COVID-19 lockdown in the United Kingdom. Psychosomatic Medicine, 83(4), 328-337. https://doi.org/10.1097/PSY.0000000000000871</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#x142;omecka, M. B., Gobbi, S., Neckels, R., Radzi&#x144;ski, P., Sk&#xf3;rko, B., Lazzeri, S., Almazidou, K., Dedi&#x107;, A., Bakalovi&#x107;, A., &amp; Hrusti&#x107;, L. (2020). Mental health impact of COVID-19: A global study of risk and resilience factors. Frontiers in Psychiatry, 11, 581426. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2020.581426</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price, J. R., Mitchell, E., Tidy, E., &amp; Hunot, V. (2008). Cognitive behaviour therapy for chronic fatigue syndrome in adults. The Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, 2008(3), CD001027. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD001027.pub2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salisbury, H. (2023). Helen Salisbury: Unexplained symptoms aren't always long COVID. BMJ, 380, p654. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.p654</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanbehzadeh, S., Zanjari, N., Yassin, M., Yassin, Z., &amp; Tavahomi, M. (2023). Association between long COVID, functional activity, and health-related quality of life in older adults. BMC Geriatrics, 23(1), 40. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12877-023-03757-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer, R. L., Kroenke, K., Williams, J. B. W., &amp; L&#xf6;we, B. (2006). A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: The GAD-7. Archives of Internal Medicine, 166(10), 1092-1097. https://doi.org/10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swedish National Agency for Medical and Social Evaluation. (2020). Prolonged symptoms of COVID-19. https://www.sbu.se/319</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xee;sl&#x103;, A., Stadelmann, C., Watkins, E., Zinbarg, R. E., &amp; Fl&#xfc;ckiger, C. (2022). The relation between worry and mental health in nonclinical population and individuals with anxiety and depressive disorders: A meta-analysis. Cognitive Therapy and Research, 46(3), 480-501. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10608-021-10288-4</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>