<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39400651</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2210-6014</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of epidemiology and global health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Epidemiol Glob Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID-19 and Coexistence of Fatigue and Depression: A Cross-sectional Study from Saudi Arabia.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s44197-024-00312-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) is associated with various manifestations even after infection resolution. This study aimed to assess the prevalence of post-COVID-19 fatigue and its predictors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a nationwide cross-sectional study among Polymerase Chain Reaction test confirmed COVID-19 cases in Saudi Arabia from July 2021 to February 2022. We collected data through telephonic interviews covering socio-demographics, comorbidities, body mass index, smoking, illness severity, and COVID-19 vaccination status. We assessed fatigue using Fatigue Severity Scale while depression was assessed using Patient Health Questionnaire-2. Logistic regression was employed to analyze the relationship between post-COVID-19 fatigue and depression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The analysis included 361 participants with a mean age of 37&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;10.5 years, among whom 43% were female. Approximately 10% had comorbidities, and 21% were current smokers. Nearly two-thirds (68%) of the participants reported mild illness. The prevalence of perceived fatigue was 22.7%, while fatigue measured by the Fatigue Severity Scale was 14.4%. The multivariable logistic regression model revealed that COVID-19 severity and depression were significant predictors of post-COVID-19 fatigue; adjusted odds ratio 1.87 (95% CI: 1.10 to 3.18) and 14.3 (95% CI: 4.55 to 45.0), respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings suggest a higher prevalence of perceived fatigue compared to that measured by the Fatigue Severity Scale, underscoring the importance of using a valid assessment tool for fatigue among COVID-19 patients to ensure proper management. The significant association between post-COVID-19 fatigue and depression highlights the need for psychological assessment of COVID-19 patients to enhance their post-infection quality of life.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alharbi</LastName><ForeName>Abdulrahman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine Academy, Qassim Health Cluster, Qassim, Saudi Arabia. ah.alharbi06@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almogbel</LastName><ForeName>Faisal</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine Academy, Qassim Health Cluster, Qassim, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rabbani</LastName><ForeName>Unaib</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine Academy, Qassim Health Cluster, Qassim, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Memish</LastName><ForeName>Ziad A</ForeName><Initials>ZA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine, Alfaisal University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubert Department of Global Health, Rollins School of Public Health, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Epidemiol Glob Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101592084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2210-6006</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Saudi arabia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39400651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44197-024-00312-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s44197-024-00312-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO. Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard 2023 [updated 2023/8; cited April 14, 2024. https://covid19.who.int/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Docherty AB, Harrison EM, Green CA, Hardwick HE, Pius R, Norman L et al. Features of 20 133 UK patients in hospital with covid-19 using the ISARIC WHO Clinical Characterisation Protocol: prospective observational cohort study. BMJ. 2020;369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y, et al. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020;395:497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7159299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO, Post. COVID-19 condition (Long COVID) 2022 [updated 7 December 2022. https://www.who.int/europe/news-room/fact-sheets/item/post-covid-19-condition</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malkova A, Kudryavtsev I, Starshinova A, Kudlay D, Zinchenko Y, Glushkova A, et al. Post COVID-19 syndrome in patients with Asymptomatic/Mild form. Pathogens. 2021;1:11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Herck M, Ymj Gr, Houben-Wilke S, Fvc M, Meys R, Delbressine JM, et al. Severe fatigue in long COVID: web-based quantitative follow-up study in members of Online Long COVID Support groups. J Med Internet Res. 2021;1:9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willi S, L&#xfc;thold R, Hunt A, H&#xe4;nggi NV, Sejdiu D, Scaff C et al. COVID-19 sequelae in adults aged less than 50 years: A systematic review. Travel medicine and infectious disease. 2021;40:101995.10.1016/j.tmaid.2021.101995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, Dunne J, Mooney A, Gaffney F, et al. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS ONE. 2020;1:11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simani L, Ramezani M, Darazam IA, Sagharichi M, Aalipour MA, Ghorbani F, et al. Prevalence and correlates of chronic fatigue syndrome and post-traumatic stress disorder after the outbreak of the COVID-19. J Neurovirol. 2021;1:27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alotibi WM, Alzeer Z, Alfarhan IF, Alharbi AD, Alhaqbani FA, Almutairi AS et al. The incidence of long-term fatigue in patients who Achieved Remission from COVID-19 at King Abdulaziz Medical City. Cureus. 2023;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlRadini FA, Alamri F, Aljahany MS, Almuzaini Y, Alsofayan Y, Khan A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 condition in Saudi Arabia: a national representative study. J Infect Public Health. 2022;1:15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tleyjeh IM, Saddik B, AlSwaidan N, AlAnazi A, Ramakrishnan RK, Alhazmi D et al. Prevalence and predictors of Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome (PACS) after hospital discharge: A cohort study with 4 months median follow-up. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0260568.10.1371/journal.pone.0260568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickie I, Davenport T, Wakefield D, Vollmer-Conna U, Cameron B, Vernon SD, et al. Post-infective and chronic fatigue syndromes precipitated by viral and non-viral pathogens: prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2006;333:575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.38933.585764.AE</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16950834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1569956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salit IE. Post-infectious fatigue. Can Family Physician Medecin De Famille Canadien. 1987;33:1217&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan O O. Long-term sequelae following previous coronavirus epidemics. Clin Med. 2021;21:e68&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.7861/clinmed.2020-0204 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7861/clinmed.2020-0204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tansey CM, Louie M, Loeb M, Gold WL, Muller MP, De Jager JA, et al. One-year outcomes and health care utilization in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome. Arch Intern Med. 2007;167:1312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.167.12.1312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17592106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Shin HS, Park HY, Kim JL, Lee JJ, Lee H, et al. Depression as a mediator of chronic fatigue and post-traumatic stress symptoms in Middle East Respiratory Syndrome survivors. Psychiatry Investig. 2019;1:16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchi M, Grenzi P, Serafini V, Capoccia F, Rossi F, Marrino P et al. Psychiatric symptoms in Long-COVID patients: a systematic review. Front Psychiatry. 2023;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homann S, Mikuteit M, Niewolik J, Behrens GMN, St&#xf6;lting A, M&#xfc;ller F et al. Effects of Pre-Existing Mental Conditions on Fatigue and Psychological Symptoms Post-COVID-19. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19.10.3390/ijerph19169924.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badinlou F, Lundgren T, Jansson-Fr?jmark M. Mental health outcomes following COVID-19 infection: impacts of post-COVID impairments and fatigue on depression, anxiety, and insomnia? A web survey in Sweden. BMC Psychiatry. 2022;22:743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Johani MS, Khalil R, Al-Mohaimeed YA, Al-Mundarij OM, Al-Samani AS, Al-Saqry OS, et al. Post-COVID-19 fatigue and health-related quality of life in Saudi Arabia: a population-based study. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1254723. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2023.1254723 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1254723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37869192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10585179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garout MA, Saleh SAK, Adly HM, Abdulkhaliq AA, Khafagy AA, Abdeltawab MR et al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome: assessment of short- and long-term post-recovery symptoms in recovered cases in Saudi Arabia. Infection. 2022;50:1431&#x2013;&#x2009;9.10.1007/s15010-022-01788-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samannodi M, Alwafi H, Naser AY, Al Qurashi AA, Qedair JT, Salawati E et al. Determinants of Post-COVID-19 Conditions among SARS-CoV-2-Infected Patients in Saudi Arabia: A Web-Based Cross-Sectional Study. Diseases (Basel, Switzerland). 2022;10.10.3390/diseases10030055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tleyjeh IM, Saddik B, Ramakrishnan RK, AlSwaidan N, AlAnazi A, Alhazmi D et al. Long term predictors of breathlessness, exercise intolerance, chronic fatigue and well-being in hospitalized patients with COVID-19: A cohort study with 4 months median follow-up. Journal of infection and public health. 2022;15:21&#x2013;&#x2009;8.10.1016/j.jiph.2021.11.016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Althomali OW, Amin J, Shaik DH, Alghamdi W, Ibrahim AA, Hussein HM et al. Short-Term and Long-Term Impact of COVID-19 on Quality of Life and Psychological Outcomes in Saudi Arabia: A Comparative Cross-Sectional Study. Journal of multidisciplinary healthcare. 2024;17:505&#x2013;&#x2009;15.10.2147/jmdh.S449152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Health. COVID-19 Treatment Guidelines: Clinical Spectrum of SARS-CoV-2 Infection 2023 [updated August, 2023; cited August 19, 2023. https://www.covid19treatmentguidelines.nih.gov/overview/clinical-spectrum/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Sobayel HI, Al-Hugail HA, Alsaif RM, Albawardi NM, Alnahdi AH, Daif AM, et al. Validation of an arabic version of fatigue severity scale. Saudi Med J. 2016;1:37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krupp LB, Larocca NG, Muir Nash J, Steinberg AD. The fatigue severity scale. Application to patients with multiple sclerosis and systemic lupus erythematosus. Arch Neurol. 1989;46:1121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneur.1989.00520460115022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2803071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlHadi AN, AlAteeq DA, Al-Sharif E, Bawazeer HM, Alanazi H, AlShomrani AT, et al. An arabic translation, reliability, and validation of Patient Health Questionnaire in a Saudi sample. Ann Gen Psychiatry. 2017;6:16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12991-017-0139-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Jbw W. The Patient Health Questionnaire-2: validity of a two-item depression screener. Med Care. 2003;41:1284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.MLR.0000093487.78664.3C</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14583691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shendy W, Ezzat MM, Elaidy DA, Elsherif AA. Prevalence of fatigue in patients post Covid-19. Eur J Mol Clin Med. 2021;1330?40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, Ghanima W, Olsen MK, Gilboe HM, Einvik G. Prevalence and determinants of fatigue after COVID-19 in non-hospitalized subjects: a Population-based study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;2:18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, Palladini M, De Lorenzo R, Bravi B, Poletti S, Furlan R, et al. One-year mental health outcomes in a cohort of COVID-19 survivors. J Psychiatr Res. 2022;1:145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin ES, Gold LS, Hough CL, Katz PP, Bunnell AE, Wysham KD, et al. Patient-reported functional outcomes 30?Days after hospitalization for COVID-19. PM&amp;R. 2022;1:14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staudt A, J?rres RA, Hinterberger T, Lehnen N, Loew T, Budweiser S. Associations of Post-acute COVID syndrome with physiological and clinical measures 10 months after hospitalization in patients of the first wave. Eur J Intern Med. 2022;1:95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal A, Iqbal K, Ali SA, Azim D, Farid E, Baig MD, et al. The COVID-19 sequelae: a cross-sectional evaluation of post-recovery symptoms and the need for Rehabilitation of COVID-19 survivors. Cureus. 2021;2:2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peghin M, Palese A, Venturini M, De Martino M, Gerussi V, Graziano E, et al. Post-COVID-19 symptoms 6 months after acute infection among hospitalized and non-hospitalized patients. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;1:27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Wang F, Shen Y, Zhang X, Cen Y, Wang B, et al. Symptoms and Health outcomes among survivors of COVID-19 infection 1 year after Discharge from hospitals in Wuhan, China. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(9):e2127403&#x2013;2127403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.27403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34586367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8482055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreto APA, Duarte LC, Cerqueira-Silva T, Mab F, Camelier A, Tavares NM et al. Post-Acute COVID Syndrome, the Aftermath of Mild to Severe COVID-19 in Brazilian Patients. medRxiv. 2021 06 07 21258520. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strain WD, Sherwood O, Banerjee A, Van der Togt V, Hishmeh L, Rossman J. The impact of COVID vaccination on symptoms of long COVID: an International Survey of people with lived experience of long COVID. Vaccines (Basel). 2022;10:652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vaccines10050652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35632408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>General Authority for Statistics. Saudi Census 2022 Riyadh, Saudi Arabia2022 [updated 2022/2; cited February, 17, 2024. https://portal.saudicensus.sa/portal/public/1/17?type=TABLE</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liyanage-Don NA, Cornelius T, Sanchez JE, Trainor A, Moise N, Wainberg M, et al. Psychological distress, persistent physical symptoms, and Perceived Recovery after COVID-19 illness. J Gen Intern Med. 2021;1:36.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>