<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36623520</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-8595</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The lancet. Diabetes &amp; endocrinology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Risks and burdens of incident dyslipidaemia in long COVID: a cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>120</StartPage><EndPage>128</EndPage><MedlinePgn>120-128</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00355-2</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-8587(22)00355-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Non-clinical evidence and a few human studies with short follow-ups suggest increased risk of dyslipidaemia in the post-acute phase of COVID-19 (ie, &gt;30 days after SARS-CoV-2 infection). However, detailed large-scale controlled studies with longer follow-ups and in-depth assessment of the risks and burdens of incident dyslipidaemia in the post-acute phase of COVID-19 are not yet available. We, therefore, aimed to examine the risks and 1-year burdens of incident dyslipidaemia in the post-acute phase of COVID-19 among people who survive the first 30 days of SARS-CoV-2 infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this cohort study, we used the national health-care databases of the US Department of Veterans Affairs to build a cohort of 51&#x2008;919 participants who had a positive COVID-19 test and survived the first 30 days of infection between March 1, 2020, and Jan 15, 2021; a non-infected contemporary control group (n=2&#x2009;647&#x2009;654) that enrolled patients between March 1, 2020, and Jan 15, 2021; and a historical control group (n=2&#x2009;539&#x2009;941) that enrolled patients between March 1, 2018, and Jan 15, 2019. Control groups had no evidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection, and participants in all three cohorts were free of dyslipidaemia before cohort enrolment. We then used inverse probability weighting using predefined and algorithmically-selected high dimensional variables to estimate the risks and 1-year burdens of incident dyslipidaemia, lipid-lowering medications use, and a composite of these outcomes. We reported two measures of risk: hazard ratios (HRs) and burden per 1000 people at 12 months. Additionally, we estimated the risks and burdens of incident dyslipidaemia outcomes in mutually exclusive groups based on the care setting of the acute infection (ie, participants who were non-hospitalised, hospitalised, or admitted to intensive care during the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS">In the post-acute phase of the SARS-CoV-2 infection, compared with the non-infected contemporary control group, those in the COVID-19 group had higher risks and burdens of incident dyslipidaemia, including total cholesterol greater than 200 mg/dL (hazard ratio [HR] 1&#xb7;26, 95% CI 1&#xb7;22-1&#xb7;29; burden 22&#xb7;46, 95% CI 19&#xb7;14-25&#xb7;87 per 1000 people at 1 year), triglycerides greater than 150 mg/dL (1&#xb7;27, 1&#xb7;23-1&#xb7;31; 22&#xb7;03, 18&#xb7;85-25&#xb7;30), LDL cholesterol greater than 130 mg/dL (1&#xb7;24, 1&#xb7;20-1&#xb7;29; 18&#xb7;00, 14&#xb7;98-21&#xb7;11), and HDL cholesterol lower than 40 mg/dL (1&#xb7;20, 1&#xb7;16-1&#xb7;25; 15&#xb7;58, 12&#xb7;52-18&#xb7;73). The risk and burden of a composite of these abnormal lipid laboratory outcomes were 1&#xb7;24 (95% CI 1&#xb7;21-1&#xb7;27) and 39&#xb7;19 (95% CI 34&#xb7;71-43&#xb7;73), respectively. There was also increased risk and burden of incident lipid-lowering medications use (HR 1&#xb7;54, 95% CI 1&#xb7;48-1&#xb7;61; burden 25&#xb7;50, 95% CI 22&#xb7;61-28&#xb7;50). A composite of any dyslipidaemia outcome (laboratory abnormality or lipid-lowering medications use) yielded an HR of 1&#xb7;31 (95% CI 1&#xb7;28-1&#xb7;34) and a burden of 54&#xb7;03 (95% CI 49&#xb7;21-58&#xb7;92). The risks and burdens of these post-acute outcomes increased in a graded fashion corresponding to the severity of the acute phase of COVID-19 infection (ie, whether patients were non-hospitalised, hospitalised, or admitted to intensive care). The results were consistent in analyses comparing the COVID-19 group to the non-infected historical control group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION">Our findings suggest increased risks and 1-year burdens of incident dyslipidaemia and incident lipid-lowering medications use in the post-acute phase of COVID-19 infection. Post-acute care for those with COVID-19 should involve attention to dyslipidaemia as a potential post-acute sequela of SARS-CoV-2 infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING">US Department of Veterans Affairs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Evan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Epidemiology Center, Research and Development Service, VA Saint Louis Health Care System, Saint Louis, MO, USA; Veterans Research and Education Foundation of Saint Louis, Saint Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Epidemiology Center, Research and Development Service, VA Saint Louis Health Care System, Saint Louis, MO, USA; Veterans Research and Education Foundation of Saint Louis, Saint Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Aly</LastName><ForeName>Ziyad</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Epidemiology Center, Research and Development Service, VA Saint Louis Health Care System, Saint Louis, MO, USA; Nephrology Section, Medicine Service, VA Saint Louis Health Care System, Saint Louis, MO, USA; Veterans Research and Education Foundation of Saint Louis, Saint Louis, MO, USA; Department of Medicine, Washington University School of Medicine, Saint Louis, MO, USA; Institute for Public Health, Washington University in Saint Louis, Saint Louis, MO, USA. Electronic address: ziyad.alaly@va.gov.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101618821</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-8587</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008076">Cholesterol, HDL</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2023 Feb;11(2):68-69. doi: 10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00389-8</RefSource><PMID Version="1">36623516</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008076" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholesterol, HDL</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050171" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dyslipidemias</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests We declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36623520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9873268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00355-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-8587(22)00355-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Luo P, Xu J, et al. Plasma metabolomic profiles in recovered COVID-19 patients without previous underlying diseases 3 months after discharge. J Inflamm Res. 2021;14:4485&#x2013;4501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8434912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34522117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorokin AV, Karathanasis SK, Yang ZH, Freeman L, Kotani K, Remaley AT. COVID-19-associated dyslipidemia: implications for mechanism of impaired resolution and novel therapeutic approaches. FASEB J. 2020;34:9843&#x2013;9853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32588493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roccaforte V, Daves M, Lippi G, Spreafico M, Bonato C. Altered lipid profile in patients with COVID-19 infection. J Lab Precis Med. 2021;6:2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z, Wang H, Cui G, et al. Alterations in the human oral and gut microbiomes and lipidomics in COVID-19. Gut. 2021;70:1253&#x2013;1265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8042598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Yao H, Zhang N, et al. Proteomic analysis identifies prolonged disturbances in pathways related to cholesterol metabolism and myocardium function in the COVID-19 recovery stage. J Proteome Res. 2021;20:3463&#x2013;3474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34080435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feingold KR. In: Endotext. Anawalt B, Boyce A, Chrousos G, et al., editors. MDText.com; South Dartmouth, MA: 2000. Lipid and lipoprotein levels in patients with COVID-19 infections.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fijen LM, Grefhorst A, Levels JHM, Cohn DM. Severe acquired hypertriglyceridemia following COVID-19. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14:e246698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8587683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34764129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deuel JW, Lauria E, Lovey T, et al. Persistence, prevalence, and polymorphism of sequelae after COVID-19 in unvaccinated, young adults of the Swiss Armed Forces: a longitudinal, cohort study (LoCoMo) Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:1694&#x2013;1702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9411260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36030795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAIR Health  A detailed study of patients with long-haul COVID. An analysis of private healthcare claims. 2021. https://s3.amazonaws.com/media2.fairhealth.org/whitepaper/asset/A%20Detailed%20Study%20of%20Patients%20with%20Long-Haul%20COVID--An%20Analysis%20of%20Private%20Healthcare%20Claims--A%20FAIR%20Health%20White%20Paper.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Xian H, Lian M, Al-Aly Z. Geographic variation and US county characteristics associated with rapid kidney function decline. Kidney Int Rep. 2016;2:5&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5678675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29142937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Li T, Xian H, Yan Y, Al-Aly Z. Higher blood urea nitrogen is associated with increased risk of incident diabetes mellitus. Kidney Int. 2018;93:741&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29241622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Yan Y, Al-Aly Z. Burden of cause-specific mortality associated with PM2.5 air pollution in the United States. JAMA Netw Open. 2019;2:e1915834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6902821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31747037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Yan Y, Xian H, Li T, Al-Aly Z. Estimates of all cause mortality and cause specific mortality associated with proton pump inhibitors among US veterans: cohort study. BMJ. 2019;365:l1580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6538974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31147311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Xian H, Li T, Al-Aly Z. Association between monocyte count and risk of incident CKD and progression to ESRD. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2017;12:603&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5383390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28348030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Gibson A, McGill J, Yan Y, Maddukuri G, Al-Aly Z. Comparative effectiveness of the sodium-glucose co-transporter-2 inhibitor empagliflozin vs. other antihyperglycemics on risk of major adverse kidney events. Diabetes Care. 2020;43:2785&#x2013;2795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7576413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32912850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Gibson AK, McGill JB, Maddukuri G, Al-Aly Z. Comparative effectiveness of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors vs sulfonylureas in patients with type 2 diabetes. JAMA Intern Med. 2021;181:1043&#x2013;1053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8240007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34180939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Cai M, Xie Y, Gibson AK, Maddukuri G, Al-Aly Z. Acute kidney injury in a national cohort of hospitalized US veterans with COVID-19. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020;16:14&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7792643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33199414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Gibson AK, et al. Comparative effectiveness of SGLT2 inhibitors, GLP-1 receptor agonists, DPP-4 inhibitors, and sulfonylureas on risk of kidney outcomes: emulation of a target trial using health care databases. Diabetes Care. 2020;43:2859&#x2013;2869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32938746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Gibson AK, McGill JB, Maddukuri G, Al-Aly Z. Clinical Implications of estimated glomerular filtration rate dip following sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitor initiation on cardiovascular and kidney outcomes. J Am Heart Assoc. 2021;10:e020237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8483543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34013739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Veterans Affairs  COVID-19: shared data resource. 2020. https://vhacdwdwhweb100.vha.med.va.gov/phenotype/index.php/COVID-19:Shared_Data_Resource#Acknowledgements_COVID-19_Shared_Data_Resource</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kind AJH, Buckingham WR. Making Neighborhood-disadvantage metrics accessible&#x2014;the neighborhood atlas. N Engl J Med. 2018;378:2456&#x2013;2458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6051533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29949490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594:259&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Burdens of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 by severity of acute infection, demographics and health status. Nat Commun. 2021;12:6571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8589966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34772922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Xu E, Al-Aly Z. Kidney outcomes in long COVID. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;32:2851&#x2013;2862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8806085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34470828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28:583&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35132265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Al-Aly Z. Risks of mental health outcomes in people with COVID-19: cohort study. BMJ. 2022;376:e068993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8847881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35172971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneeweiss S, Rassen JA, Glynn RJ, Avorn J, Mogun H, Brookhart MA. High-dimensional propensity score adjustment in studies of treatment effects using health care claims data. Epidemiology. 2009;20:512&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3077219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19487948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olvey EL, Clauschee S, Malone DC. Comparison of critical drug-drug interaction listings: the Department of Veterans Affairs medical system and standard reference compendia. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2010;87:48&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19890252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene M, Steinman MA, McNicholl IR, Valcour V. Polypharmacy, drug-drug interactions, and potentially inappropriate medications in older adults with human immunodeficiency virus infection. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2014;62:447&#x2013;453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4043391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24576251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Xu E, Al-Aly Z. Kidney outcomes in long COVID. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;32:2851&#x2013;2862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8806085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34470828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin PC. An introduction to propensity score methods for reducing the effects of confounding in observational studies. Multivariate Behav Res. 2011;46:399&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3144483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21818162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin DB. Using propensity scores to help design observational studies: application to the tobacco litigation. Health Serv Outcomes Res Methodol. 2001;2:169&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd-Jones DM, Braun LT, Ndumele CE, et al. Use of risk assessment tools to guide decision-making in the primary prevention of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease: a special report from the American Heart Association and American College of Cardiology. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;73:3153&#x2013;3167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30423392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funk MJ, Westreich D, Wiesen C, St&#xfc;rmer T, Brookhart MA, Davidian M. Doubly robust estimation of causal effects. Am J Epidemiol. 2011;173:761&#x2013;767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3070495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21385832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Bowe B, Xie Y. Long COVID after breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med. 2022;28:1461&#x2013;1467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9307472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35614233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Risks and burdens of incident diabetes in long COVID: a cohort study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2022;10:311&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8937253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35325624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han CY, Chiba T, Campbell JS, et al. Reciprocal and coordinate regulation of serum amyloid A versus apolipoprotein A-I and paraoxonase-1 by inflammation in murine hepatocytes. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2006;26:1806&#x2013;1813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16709944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan S, Chu H, Chan JF, et al. SREBP-dependent lipidomic reprogramming as a broad-spectrum antiviral target. Nat Commun. 2019;10:120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6328544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30631056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merad M, Blish CA, Sallusto F, Iwasaki A. The immunology and immunopathology of COVID-19. Science. 2022;375:1122&#x2013;1127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35271343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farley SE, Kyle JE, Leier HC, et al. A global lipid map reveals host dependency factors conserved across SARS-CoV-2 variants. Nat Commun. 2022;13:3487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9203258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35715395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masana L, Correig E, Ibarretxe D, et al. Low HDL and high triglycerides predict COVID-19 severity. Sci Rep. 2021;11:7217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8010012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Reyes A, Martinez-Armenta C, Espinosa-Vel&#xe1;zquez R, et al. NLRP3 inflammasome: the stormy link between obesity and COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2020;11:570251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7662564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33193349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Pan Y, Yin Y, Chen W, Li X. Association of dyslipidemia with the severity and mortality of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a meta-analysis. Virol J. 2021;18:157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8314261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34315474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atmosudigdo IS, Lim MA, Radi B, et al. Dyslipidemia increases the risk of severe COVID-19: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression. Clin Med Insights Endocrinol Diabetes. 2021;14 1179551421990675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8842489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35173508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu E, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Long-term neurologic outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28:2406&#x2013;2415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9671811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36138154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Acute and postacute sequelae associated with SARS-CoV-2 reinfection. Nat Med. 2022;28:2398&#x2013;2405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9671810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36357676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal Z, Ho JH, Adam S, et al. Managing hyperlipidaemia in patients with COVID-19 and during its pandemic: an expert panel position statement from HEART UK. Atherosclerosis. 2020;313:126&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7490256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33045618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Maddukuri G, Al-Aly Z. Comparative evaluation of clinical manifestations and risk of death in patients admitted to hospital with covid-19 and seasonal influenza: cohort study. BMJ. 2021;371:m4677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7735416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33323357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Agarwal A, Alwan N, Luyckx VA. Long COVID: long-term health outcomes and implications for policy and research. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2022 https://doi.org/10.1038%2Fs41581-022-00652-2 published online Nov 1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9628426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36319780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z. Diabetes after SARS-Co-V 2 infection. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2023;11:11&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9714974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36463908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention  COVID data tracker. 2023. https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#variant-proportions</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>