<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39296896</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-858X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Med (Lausanne)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Translation and cultural adaptation of the COVID-19 Yorkshire Rehabilitation Scale into German.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1401491</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1401491</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1401491</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fmed.2024.1401491</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Experts estimate that in up to 10% of the infected, SARS-CoV-2 would cause persistent symptoms, activity limitations and reduced quality of life. Referred to as long COVID, these conditions might, in the future, specifically impact German-speaking countries due to their higher rates of unvaccinated people compared to other Western countries. Accurate measurement of symptom burden and its consequences is needed to manage conditions such as long COVID, and several tools have been developed to do so. However, no patient-reported instrument existed in the German language at the time of writing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study, therefore, aimed to develop a German version of the COVID-19 Yorkshire Rehabilitation Scale (C19-YRS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We conducted a translation and qualitative evaluation, including cultural adaptation, of the C19-YRS and assessed its face validity. After creating a preliminary version, 26 individuals (14 women [53%]) participated in cognitive interviews (January 2022 to March 2022). Using cognitive debriefing interviews, we ensured the content's comprehensibility. The matrix-framework method guided the qualitative data analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Compared to the original English version, adaptations were necessary, resulting in changes to the introductory text, while the items for recording persistent symptoms were hardly changed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The German version of the C19-YRS is expected to support standardized long COVID care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Sperl, Stamm, Mosor, Ritschl, Sivan, Hoffmann and Gantschnig.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sperl</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Outcomes Research, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ludwig Boltzmann Institute for Arthritis and Rehabilitation, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stamm</LastName><ForeName>Tanja</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Outcomes Research, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ludwig Boltzmann Institute for Arthritis and Rehabilitation, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mosor</LastName><ForeName>Erika</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Outcomes Research, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ludwig Boltzmann Institute for Arthritis and Rehabilitation, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ritschl</LastName><ForeName>Valentin</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Outcomes Research, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ludwig Boltzmann Institute for Arthritis and Rehabilitation, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sivan</LastName><ForeName>Manoj</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academic Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, University of Leeds, Leeds, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffmann</LastName><ForeName>Kathryn</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Primary Care Medicine, Center for Public Health, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gantschnig</LastName><ForeName>Brigitte</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Occupational Therapy, School of Health Sciences, ZHAW Zurich University of Applied Sciences, Winterthur, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, University Hospital, Inselspital, University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Med (Lausanne)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101648047</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-858X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-term consequences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient-reported outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (PASC)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>TS has received grant/research support from AbbVie and Roche, has been a consultant for AbbVie and Sanofi Genzyme, and has been a paid speaker for AbbVie, Novartis, Roche, Sanofi, and Takeda. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest. The author(s) declared that they were an editorial board member of Frontiers, at the time of submission. This had no impact on the peer review process and the final decision.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39296896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11409085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2024.1401491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Davis H, McCorkell L, Vogel J, Topol E. Long COVID: Major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. (2023) 21:133&#x2013;46. 10.1038/s41579-022-00846-22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00846-22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard. Geneva: WHO; (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baricich A, Borg M, Cuneo D, Cadario E, Azzolina D, Balbo P, et al. Midterm functional sequelae and implications in rehabilitation after COVID-19: A cross-sectional study. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. (2021) 57:199&#x2013;207. 10.23736/S1973-9087.21.06699-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.21.06699-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33565741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin S, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. (2021) 93:1013&#x2013;22. 10.1002/jmv.26368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: A cohort study. Lancet. (2021) 397:220&#x2013;32. 10.1016/S0140-673632656-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-673632656-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill S, Brown J, Denneny E, Hare S, et al. &#x2018;Long-COVID&#x2019;: A cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. (2021) 76:396&#x2013;8. 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-215818</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-215818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez R, Balanz&#xe1;-Mart&#xed;nez V, Luperdi S, Estrada I, Latorre A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Jim&#xe9;nez P, et al. Short-term neuropsychiatric outcomes and quality of life in COVID-19 survivors. J Intern Med. (2021) 290:621&#x2013;31. 10.1111/joim.13262</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joim.13262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33533521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miskowiak K, Johnsen S, Sattler S, Nielsen S, Kunalan K, Rungby J, et al. Cognitive impairments four months after COVID-19 hospital discharge: Pattern, severity and association with illness variables. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. (2021) 46:39&#x2013;48. 10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.03.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.03.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33823427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B, Peters J, Brink M, Schoon Y, Bleeker-Rovers C, Schers H, et al. Comprehensive health assessment 3 months after recovery from acute coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Clin Infect Dis. (2020) 73:e1089&#x2013;98. 10.1093/cid/ciaa1750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciaa1750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan M, McGroder C, Stevens J, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. (2021) 27:601&#x2013;15. 10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Bermingham C, Pouwels K, Glickman M, Nafilyan V, Zaccardi F, et al. Trajectory of long covid symptoms after covid-19 vaccination: Community based cohort study. BMJ. (2022) 377:e069676. 10.1136/bmj-2021-069676</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2021-069676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35584816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azzolini E, Levi R, Sarti R, Pozzi C, Mollura M, Mantovani A, et al. Association between BNT162b2 vaccination and long COVID after infections not requiring hospitalization in health care workers. JAMA. (2022) 328:676&#x2013;8. 10.1001/jama.2022.11691</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.11691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9250078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35796131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byambasuren O, Stehlik P, Clark J, Alcorn K, Glasziou P. Effect of covid-19 vaccination on long covid: Systematic review. BMJ Med. (2023) 2:e000385. 10.1136/bmjmed-2022-000385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjmed-2022-000385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9978692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36936268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Acute and postacute sequelae associated with SARS-CoV-2 reinfection. Nat Med. (2022) 28:2398&#x2013;405. 10.1038/s41591-022-02051-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-02051-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9671810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36357676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stamm T, Partheym&#xfc;ller J, Mosor E, Ritschl V, Kritzinger S, Eberl J. Coronavirus vaccine hesitancy among unvaccinated Austrians: Assessing underlying motivations and the effectiveness of interventions based on a cross-sectional survey with two embedded conjoint experiments. Lancet Reg Health Eur. (2022) 17:100389. 10.1016/j.lanepe.2022.100389</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanepe.2022.100389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9023089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35475036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladds E, Rushforth A, Wieringa S, Taylor S, Rayner C, Husain L, et al. Developing services for long COVID: Lessons from a study of wounded healers. Clin Med (Lond). (2021) 21:59&#x2013;65. 10.7861/clinmed.2020-0962</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7861/clinmed.2020-0962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33479069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkin A, Davison J, Tarrant R, Ross D, Halpin S, Simms A, et al. A multidisciplinary NHS COVID-19 service to manage post-COVID-19 syndrome in the community. J Prim Care Community Health. (2021) 12:21501327211010994. 10.1177/21501327211010994</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21501327211010994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8064663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33880955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M. The self-report version and digital format of the COVID-19 Yorkshire rehabilitation scale (C19-YRS) for long COVID or Post-COVID syndrome assessment and monitoring. Adv Clin Neurosci Rehabil. (2021) 20:9348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor R, Preston N, Parkin A, Makower S, Ross D, Gee J, et al. The COVID-19 Yorkshire rehabilitation scale (C19-YRS): Application and psychometric analysis in a post-COVID-19 syndrome cohort. J Med Virol. (2022) 94:1027&#x2013;34. 10.1002/jmv.27415</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.27415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34676578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvert M, Blazeby J, Altman D, Revicki D, Moher D, Brundage M, et al. Reporting of patient-reported outcomes in randomized trials: The CONSORT PRO extension. JAMA. (2013) 309:814&#x2013;22. 10.1001/jama.2013.879</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23443445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingham C, Noonan V, Auger C, Feldman D, Ahmed S, Bartlett S. Montreal accord on patient-reported outcomes (PROs) use series - Paper 4: Patient-reported outcomes can inform clinical decision making in chronic care. J Clin Epidemiol. (2017) 89:136&#x2013;41. 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2017.04.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2017.04.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6529209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28433678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaton D, Bombardier C, Guillemin F, Ferraz M. Guidelines for the process of cross-cultural adaptation of self-report measures. Spine. (1976) 2000:3186&#x2013;91. 10.1097/00007632-200012150-00014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00007632-200012150-00014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11124735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins D. Cognitive interviewing: Origin, purpose and limitations. In: Collins D. editor. Cognitive interviewing practice. Thousand Oaks, CA: SAGE; (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthoine E, Moret L, Regnault A, S&#xe9;bille V, Hardouin J. Sample size used to validate a scale: A review of publications on newly-developed patient reported outcomes measures. Health Qual Life Outcomes. (2014) 12:176. 10.1186/s12955-014-0176-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-014-0176-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4275948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25492701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokkink L, Terwee C, Patrick D, Alonso J, Stratford P, Knol D, et al. The COSMIN study reached international consensus on taxonomy, terminology, and definitions of measurement properties for health-related patient-reported outcomes. J Clin Epidemiol. (2010) 63:737&#x2013;45. 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.02.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.02.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20494804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stamm T. Study protocol for the registry for post/long COVID-19 conditions in Austria. Vienna: Ethikkommission Medizinische Universit&#xe4;t Wien; (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray M. Conductive cognitive interviews. In: Collins D. editor. Cognitive interviewing practice. Thousand Oaks, CA: SAGE; (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;ardenne J. Developing interview protocol. In: Collins D. editor. Cognitive interviewing practice. Thousand Oaks, CA: SAGE; (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins D, Gray M. Sampling and recruitment. In: Collins D. editor. Cognitive interviewing practice. Thousand Oaks, CA: SAGE; (2015). 4 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green J, Thorogood N. Qualitative methods for health research. 2nd ed. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications; (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles M, Huberman A. Qualitative data analysis: An expanded sourcebook. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications; (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer L, Ritchie J, O&#x2019;Connor W. Analysis: Practices, principles and processes. 1st ed. In: Ritchie J, Lewis J. editors. Qualitative research practice. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications; (2003). p. 199&#x2013;218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;ardenne J, Collins D. Data management. In: Collins D. editor. Cognitve interviewing practice. Thousand Oaks, CA: SAGE; (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins D. Analysis and interpretation. In: Collins D. editor. Cognitive interviewing practice. Thousand Oaks, CA: SAGE; (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Streiner D, Norman G, Cairney J. Health measurement scales. A practical guide to their development and use. 5th ed. Oxford: Oxford University Press; (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wild D, Grove A, Martin M, Eremenco S, McElroy S, Verjee-Lorenz A, et al. Principles of good practice for the translation and cultural adaptation process for patient-reported outcomes (PRO) measures: Report of the ISPOR task force for translation and cultural adaptation. Value Health. (2005) 8:94&#x2013;104. 10.1111/j.1524-4733.2005.04054.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1524-4733.2005.04054.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15804318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedli T, Gantschnig B. Testing the iMTA productivity costs questionnaie (iPCQ) for the use with chronic disease patients in Switzerland. Int J Health Profess. (2022) 9:25&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulze C, Page J, Lilja M, Kottorp A. Cross-cultural validity of the German version of the pediatric evaluation of disability inventory (PEDI-G)-a Rasch model application. Child Care Health Dev. (2017) 43:48&#x2013;58. 10.1111/cch.12401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cch.12401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27592707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nittas V, Gao M, West E, Ballouz T, Menges D, Wulf Hanson S, et al. Long COVID through a public health lens: An umbrella review. Public Health Rev. (2022) 43:1604501. 10.3389/phrs.2022.1604501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/phrs.2022.1604501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8963488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35359614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Axelsson M, Kottorp A, Carlson E, Gudmundsson P, Kumlien C, Jakobsson J. Translation and validation of the Swedish version of the IPECC-SET 9 item version. J Interprof Care. (2022) 36:900&#x2013;7. 10.1080/13561820.2022.2034762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13561820.2022.2034762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35175872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamwesiga J, von Koch L, Kottorp A, Guidetti S. Cultural adaptation and validation of stroke impact scale 3.0 version in Uganda: A small-scale study. SAGE Open Med. (2016) 4:2050312116671859. 10.1177/2050312116671859</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2050312116671859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5046200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27746913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell J. Research design. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage; (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guba E, Lincoln Y. Competing paradigms in qualitative research. In: Denzin N, Lincoln Y. editors. Handbook of qualitative research. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications; (1994). p. 105&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkmann S, Kvale S. InterViews. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications; (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vet H, Terwee C, Mokkink L, Knol D. Measurement in medicine: A practical guide. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; (2011).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>