<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37696788</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5948</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of occupational and environmental medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Occup Environ Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID and Occupational Medicine Practice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>5</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-5</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JOM.0000000000002961</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Howard</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, US Department of Health and Human Services, Washington, District of Columbia (J.H.); Division of Occupational and Environmental Medicine, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland (M.C.); and Occupational Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota (G.V.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cloeren</LastName><ForeName>Marianne</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vanichkachorn</LastName><ForeName>Greg</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Occup Environ Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9504688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1076-2752</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009787" MajorTopicYN="Y">Occupational Medicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Howard, Cloeren, and Vanichkachorn have no relationships/conditions/circumstances that present potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37696788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JOM.0000000000002961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00043764-202401000-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>US Department of Health and Human Services. Fact Sheet: End of the COVID-19 Public Health Emergency . May 9, 2023. Available at: https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2023/05/09/fact-sheet-end-of-the-covid-19-public-health-emergency.html . Accessed August 5, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danesh V, Arroliga AC, Bourgeois JA, et al. Symptom clusters seen in adult COVID-19 recovery clinic care seekers. J Gen Intern Med 2023;38:442&#x2013;449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV. WHO case definition working group on post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis 2022;22:e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, Nicholson T, Akrami A, et al. A core outcome set for post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition in adults for use in clinical practice and research: an international Delphi consensus study. Lancet Respir Med 2022;10:715&#x2013;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Post COVID-19 condition (long COVID). December 7, 2022. Available at: https://www.who.int/europe/news-room/fact-sheets/item/post-covid-19-condition . Accessed August 3, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Long COVID or post-COVID conditions. December 16, 2022. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html/ . Accessed July 5, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EclinicalMedicine 2021;38:101019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parotto M, Gy&#xf6;ngy&#xf6;si M, Howe K, et al. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19: understanding and addressing the burden of multisystem manifestations. Lancet Respir Med 2023;11:739&#x2013;754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross R, Re VL 3rd. Disentangling the postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2: E Unibus Pluram (from one many). JAMA 2023;329:1918&#x2013;1919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley SE, Karlson EW, et al. Development of a definition of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA 2023;329:1934&#x2013;1946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: 3 years in. Lancet 2023;401:795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballouz T, Menges D, Anagnostopoulos A. Recovery and symptom trajectories up to two years after SARS-CoV-2 infection: population based, longitudinal cohort study. BMJ 2023;381:e074425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledford H. How common is long COVID? Why studies give different answers. Nature 2022;606:852&#x2013;853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua MJ, Gonakoti S, Shariff R, et al. Prevalence and characteristics of long COVID 7&#x2013;12 months after hospitalization among patients from an urban safety-net hospital: a pilot study [published online March 24, 2023]. AJPM Focus 2023;2:100091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Bowe B, Xie Y. Long COVID after breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med 2022;28:1461&#x2013;1467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull-Otterson L, Baca S, Saydah S, et al. Post-COVID conditions among adult COVID-19 survivors aged 18&#x2013;64 and &gt;65 years&#x2014;United States, March 2020&#x2013;November 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly 2022;71:713&#x2013;717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Ling S, Lui LMW, et al. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in post&#x2013;COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun 2022;101:93&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F, Tomasoni D, Falcinella C, et al. Female gender is associated with long COVID syndrome: a prospective cohort study. Clin Microbiol Infect 2021;28:611.e9&#x2013;611.e16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampasian V, Elghazly H, Chattopadhyay R, et al. Risk factors associated with post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Intern Med 2023;183:566&#x2013;580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell 2022;185:881&#x2013;895.e20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Q, Joyce EE, Ebrahimi OV, et al. COVID-19 illness severity and 2-year prevalence of physical symptoms: an observational study in Iceland, Sweden, Norway and Denmark. medRxiv 2023. medRxiv 2023.04.18.23288720. doi:10.1101/2023.04.18.23288720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.04.18.23288720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards F, Hamilton FW. Impact of COVID-19 vaccination on long COVID. BMJ Med 2023;2:e000470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuodi P, Gorelik Y, Zayyad H, et al. Association between BNT162b2 vaccination and reported incidence of post&#x2013;COVID-19 symptoms: cross-sectional study 2020&#x2013;21, Israel. NPJ Vaccines 2022;7:101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marra AR, Sampaio VS, Ozahata MC, et al. Risk factors for long coronavirus disease 2019 (long COVID) among healthcare personnel, Brazil, 2020&#x2013;2022. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol 2023;1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Bosworth ML, King S, et al. Risk of long COVID in people infected with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 after 2 doses of a coronavirus disease 2019 vaccine: community-based, matched cohort study. Open Forum Infect Dis 2022;9:ofac464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Penfold RS, Merino J, et al. Risk factors and disease profile of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection in UK users of the COVID symptom study app: a prospective, community-based, nested, case-control study. Lancet Infect Dis 2022;22:43&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Harrison PJ. Six-month sequelae of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection: a retrospective cohort study of 10,024 breakthrough infections. Brain Behav Immun 2022;103:154&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosworth ML, Shenhuy B, Walker AS, et al. Risk of new onset long COVID following reinfection with SARS-CoV-2: community-based cohort study. medRxiv 2023. medRxiv 2023.04.13.23288522. doi:10.1101/2023.04.13.23288522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.04.13.23288522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwasaki A, Putrino D. Why we need a deeper understanding of the pathophysiology of long COVID. Lancet 2023;23:393&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein SR, Ramelli SC, Grazioli A, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence in the human body and brain at autopsy. Nature 2022;612:758&#x2013;763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swank Z, Senussi Y, Manickas-Hill, Z et al. Persistent circulating severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 spike is associated with post-acute coronavirus disease 19 sequelae. Clin Infect Dis . 2023:76:e487&#x2013;e490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deveau T-M, Munter SE, et al. Chronic viral coinfections differentially affect the likelihood of developing long COVID. J Clin Invest 2023;133:e163669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner S, Khan MA, Putrino D, Woodcock A, Kell DB, Pretorius E. Long COVID: pathophysiological factors and abnormalities of coagulation. Trends Endocrinol Metab 2023;34:321&#x2013;344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): an overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front Microbiol 2021;12:698169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Choi T, Al-Aly Z. Molnupiravir and risk of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19: cohort study. BMJ 2023;381:e074572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Choi T, Al-Aly Z. Association of treatment with nirmatrelvir and the risk of post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition. JAMA Intern Med 2023;183:554&#x2013;564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramante CT, Buse JB, Liebovitz DM, et al. Outpatient treatment of COVID-19 and incidence of post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition over 10 months (COVID-OUT): a multicentre, randomised, quadruple-blind, parallel-group phase 3 trial. Lancet Infect Dis 2023. S1473-3099(23)00299-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller MR, Ganesh R, Hurt RT, Beckman TJ. Post-COVID conditions. Mayo Clin Proc 2023;98:1071&#x2013;1078.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE). COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the longterm effects of COVID-19. Version 1.20. March 11, 2022. Available at: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188/resources/covid19-rapid-guideline-managing-the-longterm-effects-of-covid19-pdf-51035515742 . Accessed July 5, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright J, Astill SL, Sivian M. The relationship between physical activity and long COVID: a cross-sectional study. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022;19:5093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallegos M, Morgan ML, Burgos-Videla C, Caycho-Rodriguez T, Martino P, Cervigni M. The impact of long COVID on people's capacity to work. Ann Work Expos Health 2023;67:801&#x2013;804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach K. New Evidence Is Showing That Long COVID Is Keeping as Many as 4 Million People Out of Work . Brookings. August 24, 2022. Available at: https://www.brookings.edu/articles/new-data-shows-long-covid-is-keeping-as-many-as-4-million-people-out-of-work/ . Accessed July 5, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>New York State Insurance Fund. Shining a light on long COVID: an analysis of workers' compensation data. January 24, 2023. Available at: https://ww3.nysif.com/en/FooterPages/Column1/AboutNYSIF/NYSIF_News/2023/20230124LongCovid/ . Accessed July 5, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Health and Human Services. Guidance on &#x201c;Long COVID&#x201d; as a Disability Under the ADA, Section 504, and Section 1557 . July 26, 2021. Available at: https://www.hhs.gov/civil-rights/for-providers/civil-rights-covid19/guidance-long-covid-disability/index.html#footnote10_0ac8mdc . Accessed July 5, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller K, Konicki D, Larson P, Hudson TW, Yarborough C; the ACOEM Expert Panel on Functional Outcomes. Advancing value-based medicine: why integrating functional outcomes with clinical measures is critical to our health care future. J Occup Environ Med 2017;59:e57&#x2013;e62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurisic M, Bean M, Harbaugh J, et al. The personal physician's role in helping patients with medical conditions stay at work or return to work. J Occup Environ Med 2017;59:e125&#x2013;e131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin DW. ACOEM responds to DHHS' National Research Action Plan on Long COVID . Letter to Admiral Rachel Levine, Assistant Secretary of Health, US Department of Health and Human Services, Washington, DC. October 17, 2022. Available at: https://acoem.org/Advocacy/Public-Comments/ACOEM-Responds-to-DHHS'-National-Research-Action-Plan-on-Long-COVID . Accessed August 3, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, as amended. Available at: https://www.ada.gov/law-and-regs/ada/ . Accessed August 3, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Equal Employment Opportunity Commission. What you should know about COVID-19, the ADA, the Rehabilitation Act, and other EEO laws. Updated on May 15, 2023. Available at: https://www.eeoc.gov/wysk/what-you-should-know-about-covid-19-and-ada-rehabilitation-act-and-other-eeo-laws . Accessed August 3, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batiste LC; US Department of Labor. Workers with long COVID-19: you may be entitled to workplace accommodations. July 6, 2021. Available at: https://blog.dol.gov/2021/07/06/workers-with-long-covid-19-may-be-entitled-to-accommodations . Accessed August 3, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Family and Medical Leave Act. 29 USC Section 2601 et seq. Accessed August 3, 2023. Available at: https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-29/subtitle-B/chapter-V/subchapter-C/part-825 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A. Comply with ADA, FMLA when worker is a &#x2018;COVID-19 long hauler&#x2019;. Society for Human Resource Management (SHRM). March 1, 2021. Available at: https://www.shrm.org/resourcesandtools/legal-and-compliance/employment-law/pages/coronavirus-ada-fmla-covid-19-long-hauler.aspx#:~:text=Individuals%20with%20severe%20COVID%2D19 ,be%20protected%20by%20the%20FMLA. Accessed August 3, 3023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Job Accommodation Network. Accommodation and compliance: long COVID. Available at: https://askjan.org/disabilities/Long-COVID.cfm?csSearch=4456665_1/ . Accessed August 3, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowenstein F. How managers can support employees with long COVID. MIT Sloan Management Review March 14, 2022. Available at: https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/how-managers-can-support-employees-with-long-covid/ . Accessed August 3, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernacki EJ, Hunt DL, Tsourmas NF, et al. Attributes of long duration COVID-19 workers' compensation claims. J Occup Environ Med 2022;64:e327&#x2013;e322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Chen L, Yu Y. Medical treatments and cost of COVID-19 claims and an early look at &#x201c;long COVID&#x201d; in the California workers' compensation system. California Workers' Compensation Insurance Rating Bureau 2022. Available at: https://www.wcirb.com/sites/default/files/documents/wcirb-longcovid-impactreport-ar-2.pdf . Accessed August 3, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters C, Dulon M, Westermann C, Kozak A, Nienhaus A. Long-term effects of COVID-19 on workers in health and social services in Germany. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022;19:6983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohn L, Dauvrin M, Detollen a J, et al. Long COVID and return to work: a qualitative study. Occup Med (Lond) 2022;kqac119. doi:10.1093/occmed/Kqac119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/occmed/Kqac119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madan I, Briggs T, Chew-Graham C. Supporting patients with long COVID return to work. Br J Gen Pract 2021;71:508&#x2013;509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gyllensten K, Holm A, Sanden H. Workplace factors that promote and hinder work ability and return to work among individuals with long-term effects of COVID-19: a qualitative study. Work 2023;75:1101&#x2013;1112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker M, Sawant HB, Flannery T, et al. Effect of using a structured pacing protocol on post-exertional symptom exacerbation and health status in a longitudinal cohort with post&#x2013;COVID-19 syndrome. J Med Virol 2023;95:e28373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink M, Vink-Niese F. Is it useful to question the recovery behaviour of patients with ME/CFS or long COVID? Healthcare (Basel) 2022;10:392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeMars J, Brown DA, Angelidis I, et al. What is safe long COVID rehabilitation? J Occup Rehabil 2023;33:227&#x2013;230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Postacute sequelae of COVID-19 at 2 years. Nat Med 2023.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>