<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37152805</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0047-2727</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>222</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of public economics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Public Econ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impacts of Covid-19 absences on workers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>104889</StartPage><MedlinePgn>104889</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jpubeco.2023.104889</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We show that Covid-19 illnesses and related work absences persistently reduce labor supply. Using an event study, we estimate that workers with week-long Covid-19 absences are 7 percentage points less likely to be in the labor force one year later compared to otherwise-similar workers who do not miss a week of work for health reasons. Our estimates suggest Covid-19 absences have reduced the U.S.&#xa0;labor force by approximately 500,000 people (0.2 percent of adults) and imply an average labor supply loss per Covid-19 absence equivalent to $9,000 in forgone earnings, about 90 percent of which reflects losses beyond the initial absence week.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goda</LastName><ForeName>Gopi Shah</ForeName><Initials>GS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stanford Institute for Economic Policy Research and NBER, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soltas</LastName><ForeName>Evan J</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MIT Department of Economics, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P30 AG012810</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Public Econ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101084660</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0047-2727</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Labor supply</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Participation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Work absence</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37152805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10113603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpubeco.2023.104889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0047-2727(23)00071-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abraham, Katharine, Rendell, Lea, 2023. Where Are the Missing Workers?, Brookings Papers on Economic Activity Conference Draft March 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackley Calvin A., Lundberg Dielle J., Ma Lei, Elo Irma T., Preston Samuel H., Stokes Andrew C. County-level estimates of excess mortality associated with COVID-19 in the United States. SSM-Popul. Health. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8730693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35018297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams-Prassl Abi, Boneva Teodora, Golin Marta, Rauh Christopher. Inequality in the impact of the coronavirus shock: evidence from real time surveys. J. Public Econ. 2020;189</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Economic costs of diabetes in the US in 2017. Diab. Care. 2018;41(5):917&#x2013;928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5911784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29567642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani Daniel, Khunti Kamlesh, Nafilyan Vah&#xe9;, Maddox Thomas, Humberstone Ben, Diamond Ian, Banerjee Amitava. Post-covid syndrome in individuals admitted to hospital with covid-19: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;372</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8010267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach Katie. Report; Brookings Institution: 2022. New Data Shows Long Covid is Keeping As Many As 4 Million People Out of Work.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biasi, Barbara, Dahl, Michael S., Moser, Petra, 2021. Career Effects of Mental Health, Technical Report, National Bureau of Economic Research.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe Benjamin, Xie Yan, Evan Xu., Al-Aly Ziyad. Kidney outcomes in long COVID. J. Am. Soc. Nephrol. 2021;32(11):2851&#x2013;2862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8806085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34470828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cattaneo, Matias D., Crump, Richard K., Farrell, Max H., Feng, Yingjie, 2019. On Binscatter, arXiv Preprint arXiv:1902.09608 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cengiz Doruk, Dube Arindrajit, Lindner Attila, Zipperer Ben. The effect of minimum wages on low-wage jobs. Q. J. Econ. 2019;134(3):1405&#x2013;1454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chetty Raj, Friedman John, Hendren Nathaniel. National Bureau of Economic Research; 2020. Michael Stepner, and the Opportunity Insights Team, The Economic Impacts of Covid-19: Evidence from A New Public Database Built Using Private Sector Data. Working Paper.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11189622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38911676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coibion Olivier, Gorodnichenko Yuriy, Weber Michael. National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper; 2020. Labor Markets During the COVID-19 Crisis: A Preliminary View. Technical Report 27017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutler David M. The costs of long COVID. JAMA Health Forum. 2022;3(5) e221809&#x2013;e221809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36219031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutler David M., Summers Lawrence H. The COVID-19 pandemic and the $16 trillion virus. J. Am. Med. Assoc. 2020;324(15):1495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7604733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33044484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, Hannah E., Assaf, Gina S., McCorkell, Lisa, Wei, Hannah, Low, Ryan J., Re&#x2019;em, Yochai, Redfield, Signe, Austin, Jared P., Akrami, Athena, 2021. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMed., 38, 101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobkin, Carlos, Finkelstein, Amy, Kluender, Raymond, Notowidigdo, Matthew J., 2018. The economic consequences of hospital admissions. Am. Econ. Rev., 108 (2), 308&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30091560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domash Alex, Summers Lawrence H. National Bureau of Economic Research; 2022. How Tight are US Labor Markets? Working Paper 29739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dube Arindrajit, Girardi Daniele, Jord&#xe0; &#xd2;scar, Taylor Alan M. A local projections approach to differences-in-differences event studies. Working Paper. 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans Rachael Andrea, McAuley Hamish, Harrison Ewen M., Shikotra Aarti, Singapuri Amisha, Sereno Marco, Elneima Omer, Docherty Annemarie B., Lone Nazir I., Leavy Olivia C., et al. Physical, cognitive and mental health impacts of COVID-19 following hospitalisation: a multi-centre prospective cohort study. The Lancet Respir. Med. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34627560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faust Jeremy S., Chengan Du., Mayes Katherine Dickerson, Li Shu-Xia, Lin Zhenqiu, Barnett Michael L., Krumholz Harlan M. Mortality from drug overdoses, homicides, unintentional injuries, motor vehicle crashes, and suicides during the pandemic, March&#x2013;August 2020. J. Am. Med. Assoc. 2021;326(1):84&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8140390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34019096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer Kai, James Reade J., Benedikt Schmal W. D&#xfc;sseldorf Institute for Competition Economics (DICE), Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf; 2021. The Long Shadow of an Infection: COVID-19 and Performance at Work. Working Paper.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flood Sarah, King Miriam, Rodgers Renae, Steven Ruggles J., Warren Robert, Westberry Michael. IPUMS; Minneapolis, MN: 2021. Integrated Public Use Microdata Series, Current Population Survey: Version 9.0 [dataset]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-G&#xf3;mez, Pilar, Van Kippersluis, Hans, O&#x2019;Donnell, Owen, Van Doorslaer, Eddy, 2013. Long-term and spillover effects of health shocks on employment and income. J. Human Resour., 48 (4), 873&#x2013;909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4110210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25067853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goda, Gopi Shah, Jackson, Emilie, Hersch Nicholas, Lauren, See Stith, Sarah, 2022. The Impact of Covid-19 on Older Workers&#x2019; Employment and Social Security Spillovers, J. Population Econ.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9251032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35814291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groenewold Matthew R., Burrer Sherry L., Ahmed Faruque, Uzicanin Amra, Luckhaupt Sara E. Health-related workplace absenteeism among full-time workers&#x2014;United States, 2017&#x2013;18 influenza season. Morb. Mortal. Wkly Rep. 2019;68(26):577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6613571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31269013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff Destin, Sun Ashley, Ssentongo Anna E., Ba Djibril M., Parsons Nicholas, Poudel Govinda R., Lekoubou Alain, Oh John S., Ericson Jessica E., Ssentongo Paddy, et al. Short-term and long-term rates of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection, a Systematic Review. JAMA Network Open. 2021;4(10) e2128568&#x2013;e2128568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34643720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta Arpit, Morrison Edward R., Fedorenko Catherine, Ramsey Scott. Center for Law and Economic Studies, Columbia University; 2017. Leverage Default, and Mortality: Evidence from Cancer Diagnoses. Working Paper 514,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ham, Dasom I., 2022. Long-Haulers and Labor Market Outcomes, Institute Working Paper 60, Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou&#x161;teck&#xe1; Anna, Koh Dongya, Santaeul&#xe0;lia-Llopis Ra&#xfc;l. Contagion at work: occupations, industries and human contact. J. Public Econ. 2021;200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller Sarah, Wherry Laura R., Foster Diana Greene. National Bureau of Economic Research; 2020. The Economic Consequences of Being Denied an Abortion. Working Paper 26662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mongey Simon, Pilossoph Laura, Weinberg Alexander. Which workers bear the burden of social distancing? J. Econ. Inequal. 2021;19(3):509&#x2013;526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8328128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34366750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montenovo, Laura, Jiang, Xuan, Rojas, Felipe Lozano, Schmutte, Ian M., Simon, Kosali I., Weinberg, Bruce A., Wing, Coady, 2022. Determinants of Disparities in COVID-19 Job Losses, Demography, (9961471), 935&#x2013;945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9177772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35583671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinby Laura, Rutledge Matthew S., Wettstein Gal. Technical Report; Center for Retirement Research at Boston College: 2021. How Has COVID-19 Affected the Labor Force Participation of Older Workers?</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheiner Louise, Salwati Nasiha. Hutchins Center; 2022. How Much Is Long COVID Reducing Labor Force Participation? Not Much (So Far) Working Paper 80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Hummy, McKenna, Ryan, Chen, Angela T., David, Guy, Smith-McLallen, Aaron, 2021. The impact of the non-essential business closure policy on covid-19 infection rates. Int. J. Health Econ. Manage., 21 (4), 387&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8012742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33792808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stepner Michael. Working Paper; 2019. The Insurance Value of Redistributive Taxes and Transfers.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Yan, Evan Xu., Al-Aly Ziyad. Risks of mental health outcomes in people with covid-19: cohort study. BMJ. 2022;376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8847881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35172971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Yan, Evan Xu., Bowe Benjamin, Al-Aly Ziyad. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat. Med. 2022;28(3):583&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35132265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yabroff, K. Robin, Lund, Jennifer, Kepka, Deanna, Mariotto, Angela, 2011. Economic burden of cancer in the United States: estimates, projections, and future research. Cancer Epidemiol. Prevent. Biomark., 20 (10), 2006&#x2013;2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3191884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21980008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziauddeen, Nida, Gurdasani, Deepti, O&#x2019;Hara, Margaret E., Hastie, Claire, Roderick, Paul, Yao, Guiqing, Alwan, Nisreen A., 2022. Characteristics and impact of long covid: findings from an online survey. PloS One, 17 (3), e0264331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8903286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35259179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>