<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37388814</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2233-8276</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Asia Pacific allergy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Asia Pac Allergy</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The pathophysiology of postacute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): Possible role for persistent inflammation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>77</StartPage><EndPage>84</EndPage><MedlinePgn>77-84</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5415/apallergy.0000000000000106</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">As the SARS-CoV-2-induced pandemic wanes, a substantial number of patients with acute Corona Virus-induced disease (COVID-19 continue to have symptoms for a prolonged time after initial infection. These patients are said to have postacute sequelae of COVID (PASC) or "long COVID". The underlying pathophysiology of this syndrome is poorly understood and likely quite heterogeneous. The role of persistent, possibly deviant inflammation as a major factor in comorbidity is suspected.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To review data that address the relative importance of inflammation in the pathophysiology spectrum of PASC and to address how this would impact diagnosis and approach to therapy in patients identified as having such inflammatory abnormalities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A review of public databases, including PubMed, MeSH, NLM catalog, and clinical trial databases such as clinicaltrials.gov.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The literature supports a prominent role for various forms and types of inflammation in the pathophysiologic spectrum of PASC. Such inflammation can be persistent ant CoV-2-specific responses, new onset autoimmune responses, or a loss of normal immunoregulation resulting in widespread, sustained inflammatory pathologies that can affect both broad constitutional symptoms (such as fatigue, neurocognitive dysfunction, and anxiety/depression) and organ-specific dysfunction and/or failure.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">PASC is a significant clinical entity with similarities to and differences from other postviral syndromes. Significant research efforts are ongoing to better understand specific aberrant inflammatory pathways present in individual patients for the purpose of developing and implementing effective therapies and ultimately prophylaxis strategies to prevent the progression of COVID-19 as well as likely future viral illnesses and pandemics.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023. Asia Pacific Association of Allergy, Asthma and Clinical Immunology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marshall</LastName><ForeName>Gailen D</ForeName><Initials>GD</Initials><Suffix>Jr</Suffix><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, The University of Mississippi Medical Center, Jackson, MS, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>U54 GM115428</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Asia Pac Allergy</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101561954</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2233-8276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pathophysiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postacute sequelae of COVID</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no financial conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37388814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10287107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5415/apallergy.0000000000000106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Miyah Y, Benjelloun M, Lairini S, Lahrichi A. COVID-19 impact on public health, environment, human psychology, global socioeconomy, and education. Sci World J 2022;2022:5578284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8767375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35069037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard.
http://covid19.who.int last accessed May 12, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hope AA, Evering TH. Postacute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection. Infect Dis Clin North Am 2022;36:379-395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8843334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35636906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanichkachorn G, Newcomb R, Cowl CT, Murad MH, Breeher L, Miller S, Trenary M, Neveau D, Higgins S. Post-COVID-19 Syndrome (Long Haul Syndrome): description of a multidisciplinary clinic at Mayo clinic and characteristics of the initial patient cohort. Mayo Clin Proc 2021;96:1782-1791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8112396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34218857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma P, Bharti S, Garg I. Post COVID fatigue: can we really ignore it? Indian J Tuberc 2022;69:238-241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8220285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35379408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Ling S, Lui LMW, Lee Y, Gill H, Teopiz KM, Rodrigues NB, Subramaniapillai M, Di Vincenzo JD, Cao B, Lin K, Mansur RB, Ho RC, Rosenblat JD, Miskowiak KW, Vinberg M, Maletic V, McIntyre RS. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun 2022;101:93-135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chippa V, Aleem A, Anjum F. Post Acute Coronavirus (COVID-19) syndrome. 2023. Feb 3. In: StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Mahoney LL, Routen A, Gillies C, Ekezie W, Welford A, Zhang A, Karamchandani U, Simms-Williams N, Cassambai S, Ardavani A, Wilkinson TJ, Hawthorne G, Curtis F, Kingsnorth AP, Almaqhawi A, Ward T, Ayoubkhani D, Banerjee A, Calvert M, Shafran R, Stephenson T, Sterne J, Ward H, Evans RA, Zaccardi F, Wright S, Khunti K. The prevalence and long-term health effects of Long Covid among hospitalised and non-hospitalised populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. E Clin Med 2022;55:101762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9714474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36474804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV; WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis 2022;22:e102-e107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CC, Hsu CK, Yen MY, Lee PI, Ko WC, Hsueh PR. Long COVID: an inevitable sequela of SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Microbiol Immunol Infect 2023;56:1-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9576029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36283919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny G, Townsend L, Savinelli S, Mallon PWG. Long COVID: clinical characteristics, proposed pathogenesis and potential therapeutic targets. Front Mol Biosci 2023;10:1157651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10171433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37179568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estiri H, Strasser ZH, Brat GA, Semenov YR, Patel CJ, Murphy SN; Consortium for Characterization of COVID-19 by EHR (4CE). Evolving phenotypes of non-hospitalized patients that indicate long COVID. BMC Med 2021;19:249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34565368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherif ZA, Gomez CR, Connors TJ, Henrich TJ, Reeves WB; RECOVER Mechanistic Pathway Task Force. Pathogenic mechanisms of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC). Elife 2023;12:e86002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10032659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36947108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barash M, Ramalingam V. Post-COVID interstitial lung disease and other lung sequelae. Clin Chest Med 2023;44:263-277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9983785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37085219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sewanan LR, Clerkin KJ, Tucker NR, Tsai EJ. How does COVID-19 affect the heart? Curr Cardiol Rep 2023;25:171-184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9999058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36897483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi RB, Wu ZH. Association between COVID-19 and chronic liver disease: mechanism, diagnosis, damage, and treatment. World J Virol 2023;12:22-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9896589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36743657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copur S, Berkkan M, Basile C, Tuttle K, Kanbay M. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and kidney diseases: what do we know? J Nephrol 2022;35:795-805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8924729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35294747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wrona M, Skrypnik D. New-onset diabetes mellitus, hypertension, dyslipidaemia as sequelae of COVID-19 infection-systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022;19:13280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9602450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36293857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny G, McCann K, O&#x2019;Brien C, Savinelli S, Tinago W, Yousif O, Lambert JS, O'Broin C, Feeney ER, De Barra E, Doran P, Mallon PWG; All-Ireland Infectious Diseases (AIID) Cohort Study Group. Identification of distinct long COVID Clinical phenotypes through cluster analysis of self-reported symptoms. Open Forum Infect Dis 2022;9:ofac060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8900926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35265728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P, Torocastro M, Panagopoulos D, Sutton R, Lim PB. Autonomic dysfunction in &#x201c;long COVID&#x201d;: rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin Med (Lond) 2021;21:e63-e67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arun S, Storan A, Myers B. Mast cell activation syndrome and the link with long COVID. Br J Hosp Med (Lond) 2022;83:1-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35938771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ 2021;374:n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astin R, Banerjee A, Baker MR, Dani M, Ford E, Hull JH, Lim PB, McNarry M, Morten K, O'Sullivan O, Pretorius E, Raman B, Soteropoulos DS, Taquet M, Hall CN. Long COVID: mechanisms, risk factors and recovery. Exp Physiol 2023;108:12-27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10103775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36412084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, Myles P, Williams T, Gokhale KM, Taverner T, Chandan JS, Brown K, Simms-Williams N, Shah AD, Singh M, Kidy F, Okoth K, Hotham R, Bashir N, Cockburn N, Lee SI, Turner GM, Gkoutos GV, Aiyegbusi OL, McMullan C, Denniston AK, Sapey E, Lord JM, Wraith DC, Leggett E, Iles C, Marshall T, Price MJ, Marwaha S, Davies EH, Jackson LJ, Matthews KL, Camaradou J, Calvert M, Haroon S. Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat Med 2022;28:1706-1714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledford H. Long-COVID treatments: why the world is still waiting. Nature 2022;608:258-260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35945375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Files JK, Sarkar S, Fram TR, Boppana S, Sterrett S, Qin K, Bansal A, Long DM, Sabbaj S, Kobie JJ, Goepfert PA, Erdmann N. Duration of post-COVID-19 symptoms is associated with sustained SARS-CoV-2-specific immune responses. JCI Insight 2021;6:e151544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8410022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34143754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danesh V, Arroliga AC, Bourgeois JA, Boehm LM, McNeal MJ, Widmer AJ, McNeal TM, Kesler SR. Symptom clusters seen in adult COVID-19 recovery clinic care seekers. J Gen Intern Med 2023;38:442-449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9663188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36376627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokhtari T, Hassani F, Ghaffari N, Ebrahimi B, Yarahmadi A, Hassanzadeh G. COVID-19 and multiorgan failure: a narrative review on potential mechanisms. J Mol Histol 2020;51:613-628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7533045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33011887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vojdani A, Vojdani E, Saidara E, Maes M. Persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection, EBV, HHV-6 and other factors may contribute to inflammation and autoimmunity in long COVID. Viruses 2023;15:400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9967513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36851614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Toro A, Bozzani A, Tavazzi G, Urtis M, Giuliani L, Pizzoccheri R, Aliberti F, Fergnani V, Arbustini E. Long COVID: long-term effects? Eur Heart J Suppl 2021;23(Suppl E):E1-E5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8503490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34650349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PHOSP-COVID Collaborative Group. Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet Respir Med 2022;10:761-775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9034855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35472304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubio-Rivas M, Mora-Luj&#xe1;n JM, Formiga F, Ar&#xe9;valo-Ca&#xf1;as C, Lebr&#xf3;n Ramos JM, Villalba Garc&#xed;a MV, Fonseca Aizpuru EM&#xaa;, D&#xed;ez-Manglano J, Arnalich Fern&#xe1;ndez F, Romero Cabrera JL, Garc&#xed;a Garc&#xed;a GM, Pesqueira Fontan PM, Vargas N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez JA, Freire Castro SJ, Loureiro Amigo J, de Los Reyes Pascual P&#xe9;rez M, Alcal&#xe1; Pedrajas JN, Encinas-S&#xe1;nchez D, Mella P&#xe9;rez C, Ena J, Gracia Guti&#xe9;rrez A, Esteban Giner MJ, Varona JF, Mill&#xe1;n N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez-Cort&#xe9;s J, Casas-Rojo J-M; SEMI-COVID-19 Network. WHO ordinal scale and inflammation risk categories in COVID-19. Comparative study of the severity scales. J Gen Intern Med 2022;37:1980-1987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8992782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35396659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maamar M, Artime A, Pariente E, Fierro P, Ruiz Y, Guti&#xe9;rrez S, Tobalina M, D&#xed;az-Salazar S, Ramos C, Olmos JM, Hern&#xe1;ndez JL. Post-COVID-19 syndrome, low-grade inflammation and inflammatory markers: a cross-sectional study. Curr Med Res Opin 2022;38:901-909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8935459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35166141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gim&#xe9;nez-Orenga K, Pierquin J, Brunel J, Charvet B, Mart&#xed;n-Mart&#xed;nez E, Perron H, Oltra E. HERV-W ENV antigenemia and correlation of increased anti-SARS-CoV-2 immunoglobulin levels with post-COVID-19 symptoms. Front Immunol 2022;13:1020064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9647063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36389746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churilov LP, Normatov MG, Utekhin VJ. Molecular mimicry between SARS-CoV-2 and human endocrinocytes: a prerequisite of post-COVID-19 endocrine autoimmunity? Pathophysiology 2022;29:486-494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9504401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36136066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez P, Tempio F, Fuentes C, Merino C, Vargas L, Simon V, Ramirez-Pereira M, Rojas V, Tobar E, Landskron G, Araya JP, Navarrete M, Bastias C, Tordecilla R, Varas MA, Maturana P, Marcoleta AE, Allende ML, Naves R, Hermoso MA, Salazar-Onfray F, Lopez M, Bono MR, Osorio F. Dysregulated immune responses in COVID-19 patients correlating with disease severity and invasive oxygen requirements. Front Immunol 2021;12:769059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8567168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34745145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang HP, Sun YL, Wang YF, Yazici D, Azkur D, Ogulur I, Azkur AK, Yang Z-W, Chen X-X, Zhang A-Z, Hu J-Q, Liu G-H, Akdis M, Akdis CA, Gao Y-D. Recent developments in the immunopathology of COVID-19. Allergy 2023;78:369-388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10108124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36420736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherne MD, Gentry AB, Nemudraia A, Nemudryi A, Hedges JF, Walk H, Blackwell K, Snyder DT, Jerome M, Madden W, Hashimi M, Sebrell TA, King DB, Plowright RK, Jutila MA, Wiedenheft B, Bimczok D. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 is detected in the gastrointestinal tract of asymptomatic endoscopy patients but is unlikely to pose a significant risk to healthcare personnel. Gastro Hep Adv 2022;1:844-852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9225937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35765598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson BA, Visvabharathy L, Ali ST, Kang AK, Patel TR, Clark JR, Lim PH, Orban ZS, Hwang SS, Mattoon D, Batra A, Liotta EM, Koralnik IJ. Plasma biomarkers of neuropathogenesis in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 and those with postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2022;9:e1151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8901169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35256481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Anglin K, Durstenfeld MS, Martin JN, Kelly JD, Hsue PY, Henrich TJ, Deeks SG. Effect of oral nirmatrelvir on long COVID symptoms: 4 cases and rationale for systematic studies. Pathog Immun 2022;7:95-103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9254867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35800257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aric&#xf2; E, Bracci L, Castiello L, Urbani F, Casanova JL, Belardelli F. Exploiting natural antiviral immunity for the control of pandemics: lessons from Covid-19. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev 2022;63:23-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8675148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34955389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang KT, Hsu BC, Chen DY. Autoimmune and rheumatic manifestations associated with COVID-19 in adults: an updated systematic review. Front Immunol 2021;12:645013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7994612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33777042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boaventura P, Macedo S, Ribeiro F, Jaconiano S, Soares P. Post-COVID-19 condition: where are we now? Life (Basel) 2022;12:517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9029703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35455008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahabi M, Ghazanfari T, Sepehrnia S. Molecular mimicry, hyperactive immune system, and SARS-COV-2 are three prerequisites of the autoimmune disease triangle following COVID-19 infection. Int Immunopharmacol 2022;112:109183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9393178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36182877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vojdani A, Kharrazian D. Potential antigenic cross-reactivity between SARS-CoV-2 and human tissue with a possible link to an increase in autoimmune diseases. Clin Immunol 2020;217:108480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7246018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32461193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantej J, Bednarek M, Sitko K, &#x15a;wi&#x119;to&#x144; M, Tukaj S. Autoantibodies to heat shock protein 60, 70, and 90 are not altered in the anti-SARS-CoV-2 IgG-seropositive humans without or with mild symptoms. Cell Stress Chaperones 2021;26:735-740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8172177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34080135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucchese G, Fl&#xf6;el A. SARS-CoV-2 and Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome: molecular mimicry with human heat shock proteins as potential pathogenic mechanism. Cell Stress Chaperones 2020;25:731-735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7387880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marino Gammazza A, L&#xe9;gar&#xe9; S, Lo Bosco G, Fucarino A, Angileri F, Conway de Macario E, Macario AJ, Cappello F. Human molecular chaperones share with SARS-CoV-2 antigenic epitopes potentially capable of eliciting autoimmunity against endothelial cells: possible role of molecular mimicry in COVID-19. Cell Stress Chaperones 2020;25:737-741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7402394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32754823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubchenko S, Kril I, Nadizhko O, Matsyura O, Chopyak V. Herpesvirus infections and post-COVID-19 manifestations: a pilot observational study. Rheumatol Int 2022;42:1523-1530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9159383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35650445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B, Huang S, Yin L. The cytokine storm and COVID-19. J Med Virol 2021;93:250-256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32592501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva Andrade B, Siqueira S, de Assis Soares WR, de Souza Rangel F, Santos NO, Dos Santos Freitas A, Ribeiro da Silveira P, Tiwari S, Alzahrani KJ, G&#xf3;es-Neto A, Azevedo V, Ghosh P, Barh D. Long-COVID and Post-COVID health complications: an up-to-date review on clinical conditions and their possible molecular mechanisms. Viruses 2021;13:700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galli SJ, Gaudenzio N, Tsai M. Mast cells in inflammation and disease: recent progress and ongoing concerns. Annu Rev Immunol 2020;38:49-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32340580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzankov A, Duncavage E, Craig FE, Kelemen K, King RL, Orazi A, Quintanilla-Martinez L, Reichard KK, Rimsza LM, Wang SA, Horny H-P, George TI. Mastocytosis. Am J Clin Pathol 2021;155:239-266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33313644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson CW, Pratt CM, Rupprecht CP, Pattanaik D, Krishnaswamy G. Mastocytosis and mast cell activation disorders: clearing the air. Int J Mol Sci 2021;22:11270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8540348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34681933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocat&#xfc;rk E, Salman A, Cherrez-Ojeda I, Criado PR, Peter J, Comert-Ozer E, Abuzakouk M, Agondi RC, Al-Ahmad M, Altrichter S, Arnaout R, Arruda LK, Asero R, Bauer A, Ben-Shoshan M, Bernstein JA, Bizjak M, Boccon-Gibod I, Bonnekoh H, Bouillet L, Brzoza Z, Busse P, Campos RA, Carne E, Conlon N, Criado RF, de Souza Lima EM, Demir S, Dissemond J, Do&#x11f;an G&#xfc;naydin S, Dorofeeva I, Ensina LF, Erta&#x15f; R, Ferrucci SM, Figueras-Nart I, Fomina D, Franken SM, Fukunaga A, Gim&#xe9;nez-Arnau AM, Godse K, Gon&#xe7;alo M, Gotua M, Grattan C, Guillet C, Inomata N, Jakob T, Karakaya G, Kasperska-Zaj&#x105;c A, Katelaris CH, Ko&#x161;nik M, Krasowska D, Kulthanan K, Kumaran MS, Lang C, Larco-Sousa JI, Lazaridou E, Leslie TA, Lippert U, Llosa OC, Makris M, Marsland A, Medina IV, Meshkova R, Palitot EB, Parisi CAS, Pickert J, Ramon GD, Rodr&#xed;guez-Gonzalez M, Rosario N, Rudenko M, Rutkowski K, S&#xe1;nchez J, Schliemann S, Sekerel BE, Serpa FS, Serra-Baldrich E, Song Z, Soria A, Staevska M, Staubach P, Tagka A, Takahagi S, Thomsen SF, Treudler R, Vadasz Z, Valle SOR, Van Doorn MBA, Vestergaard C, Wagner N, Wang D, Wang L, Wedi B, Xepapadaki P, Y&#xfc;cel E, Zalewska-Janowska A, Zhao Z, Zuberbier T, Maurer M. The global impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the management and course of chronic urticaria. Allergy 2021;76:816-830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33284457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstock LB, Brook JB, Walters AS, Goris A, Afrin LB, Molderings GJ. Mast cell activation symptoms are prevalent in Long-COVID. Int J Infect Dis 2021;112:217-226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34563706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wechsler JB, Butuci M, Wong A, Kamboj AP, Youngblood BA. Mast cell activation is associated with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Allergy 2022;77:1288-1291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9299596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34820848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MH, Perl DP, Steiner J, Pasternack N, Li W, Maric D, Safavi F, Horkayne-Szakaly I, Jones R, Stram MN, Moncur JT, Hefti M, Folkerth RD, Nath A. Neurovascular injury with complement activation and inflammation in COVID-19. Brain 2022;145:2555-2568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9278212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35788639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone RW, Tisdall P, Fremont-Smith P, Liu Y, Huang X-P, White KM, Miorin L, Moreno E, Alon A, Delaforge E, Hennecker CD, Wang G, Pottel J, Blair RV, Roy CJ, Smith N, Hall JM, Tomera KM, Shapiro G, Mittermaier A, Kruse AC, Garc&#xed;a-Sastre A, Roth BL, Glasspool-Malone J, Ricke DO. COVID-19: famotidine, histamine, mast cells, and mechanisms. Front Pharmacol 2021;12:633680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8021898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33833683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P, Tahmasebi N, Gant V, Gupta R. Long COVID following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: characteristic T cell alterations and response to antihistamines. J Investig Med 2022;70:61-67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8494538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol 2023;21:133-146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Kulzhabayeva D, Rodrigues NB, Di Vincenzo JD, Gill H, Subramaniapillai M, Lui LMW, Cao B, Mansur RB, Ho RC, Burke MJ, Rhee TG, Rosenblat JD, McIntyre RS. COVID-19 vaccination for the prevention and treatment of long COVID: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun 2023;111:211-229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10067136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36990297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Abell&#xe1;n J, Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Padilla S, Garc&#xed;a JA, Agull&#xf3; V, Lozano V, Ena N, Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;nchez L, Guti&#xe9;rrez F, Masi&#xe1; M. Immunologic phenotype of patients with long-COVID syndrome of 1-year duration. Front Immunol 2022;13:920627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9451924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36090973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dioverti V, Salto-Alejandre S, Haidar G. Immunocompromised patients with protracted COVID-19: a review of &#x201c;Long Persisters&#x201d;. Curr Transplant Rep 2022;9:209-218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9660019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36407883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond) 2021;53:737-754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> Study # NCT05576662  http://clinicaltrials.gov last accessed May 12, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Study # NCT05668091 http://cliicaltrials.gov last accessed May 12, 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation> Study #NCT05543590  http://clinicaltrials.gov last accessed May 12, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugh ND, Edwall D, Lindmark L, Kousoulas KG, Iyer AV, Haron MH, Pasco DS. Oral administration of a Spirulina extract enriched for Braun-type lipoproteins protects mice against influenza A (H1N1) virus infection. Phytomedicine 2015;22:271-276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25765832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> Study #NCT04944121  http://clinicaltrials.gov last accessed May 12, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation> Study #NCT05356936  http://clinicaltrials.gov last accessed May 12, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong TL, Weitzer DJ. Long COVID and Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS)-a systemic review and comparison of clinical presentation and symptomatology. Medicina (Kaunas) 2021;57:418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8145228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33925784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>