<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38723183</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-6623</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>165</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pain</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pain</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Small fibre neuropathy frequently underlies the painful long-COVID syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2002</StartPage><EndPage>2010</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2002-2010</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000003259</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Approximately 10% to 20% of individuals with previous SARS-CoV-2 infection may develop long-COVID syndrome, characterized by various physical and mental health issues, including pain. Previous studies suggested an association between small fibre neuropathy and pain in long-COVID cases. In this case-control study, our aim was to identify small fibre neuropathy in patients experiencing painful long-COVID syndrome. Clinical data, quantitative sensory testing, and skin biopsies were collected from 26 selected patients with painful long-COVID syndrome. We also examined 100 individuals with past COVID-19 infection, selecting 33 patients with painless long-COVID syndrome, characterized mainly by symptoms such as brain fog and fatigue, and 30 asymptomatic post-COVID-19 controls. Demographic and clinical variables were compared among these groups. Among the 26 patients with painful long-COVID syndrome, 12 had skin biopsy and/or quantitative sensory testing abnormalities compatible with small fibre neuropathy. Demographic and clinical data did not differ across patients with small fibre neuropathy, patients with painless long-COVID syndrome, and asymptomatic post-COVID-19 controls. This case-control study showed that approximately 50% of patients experiencing painful long-COVID syndrome had small fibre neuropathy. However, in our patient cohort, this specific post-COVID-19 complication was unrelated to demographic and COVID-19 clinical variables. Approximately half of our sample of patients with painful long-COVID symptoms met diagnostic criteria for small fibre neuropathy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 International Association for the Study of Pain.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Falco</LastName><ForeName>Pietro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neuroscience, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Litewczuk</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neuroscience, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Stefano</LastName><ForeName>Giulia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neuroscience, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Galosi</LastName><ForeName>Eleonora</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neuroscience, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leone</LastName><ForeName>Caterina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neuroscience, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Stefano</LastName><ForeName>Gianfranco</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neuroscience, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Pietro</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neuroscience, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tramontana</LastName><ForeName>Lorenzo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neuroscience, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ciardi</LastName><ForeName>Maria Rosa</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Infectious Diseases, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasculli</LastName><ForeName>Patrizia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Infectious Diseases, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zingaropoli</LastName><ForeName>Maria Antonella</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Infectious Diseases, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arendt-Nielsen</LastName><ForeName>Lars</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Neuroplasticity and Pain, SMI, School of Medicine, Aalborg University, Aalborg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Mech-Sense, Clinical Institute, Aalborg University Hospital, Aalborg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center North Denmark, Clinical Institute, Aalborg University Hospital, Aalborg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Truini</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2630-7647</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neuroscience, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pain</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7508686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0304-3959</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071075" MajorTopicYN="Y">Small Fiber Neuropathy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016022" MajorTopicYN="N">Case-Control Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012867" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001706" MajorTopicYN="N">Biopsy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38723183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000003259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006396-990000000-00593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abrams RM, Simpson DM, Navis A, Jette N, Zhou L, Shin SC. Small fiber neuropathy associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Muscle Nerve 2022;65:440&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backonja MM, Attal N, Baron R, Bouhassira D, Drangholt M, Dyck PJ, Edwards RR, Freeman R, Gracely R, Haanpaa MH, Hansson P, Hatem SM, Krumova EK, Jensen TS, Maier C, Mick G, Rice AS, Rolke R, Treede R-D, Serra J, Toelle T, Tugnoli V, Walk D, Walalce MS, Ware M, Yarnitsky D, Ziegleret D. Value of quantitative sensory testing in neurological and pain disorders: NeuPSIG consensus. PAIN 2013;154:1807&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron R, Maier C, Attal N, Binder A, Bouhassira D, Cruccu G, Finnerup NB, Haanp&#xe4;&#xe4; M, Hansson P, H&#xfc;llemann P, Jensen TS, Freynhagen R, Kennedy JD, Magerl W, Mainka T, Reimer M, Rice ASC, Segerdahl M, Serra J, Sindrup S, Sommer C, T&#xf6;lle T, Vollert J, Treede RD; German Neuropathic Pain Research Network (DFNS), and the EUROPAIN, and NEUROPAIN consortia. Peripheral neuropathic pain: a mechanism-related organizing principle based on sensory profiles. PAIN 2017;158:261&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouhassira D, Attal N, Fermanian J, Alchaar H, Gautron M, Masquelier E, Rostaing S, Lanteri-Minet M, Collin E, Grisart J, Boureau F. Development and validation of the neuropathic pain symptom inventory. PAIN 2004;108:248&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devigili G, Rinaldo S, Lombardi R, Cazzato D, Marchi M, Salvi E, Eleopra R, Lauria G. Diagnostic criteria for small fibre neuropathy in clinical practice and research. Brain 2019;142:3728&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di SG, Falco P, Galosi E, De Stefano G, Di Pietro G, Leone C, Litewczuk D, Tramontana L, Strano S, Truini A. Pain associated with COVID-19 vaccination is unrelated to skin biopsy abnormalities. PAIN Rep 2023;8:e1089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Stefano G, Falco P, Galosi E, Di Pietro G, Leone C, Truini A. A systematic review and meta-analysis of neuropathic pain associated with coronavirus disease 2019. Eur J Pain 2023;27:44&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasolino A, Di Stefano G, Leone C, Galosi E, Gioia C, Lucchino B, Terracciano A, Di Franco M, Cruccu G, Truini A. Small-fibre pathology has no impact on somatosensory system function in patients with fibromyalgia. PAIN 2020;161:2385&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leone C, Galosi E, Esposito N, Falco P, Fasolino A, Di Pietro G, Di Stefano G, Camerota F, Vollert J, Truini A. Small-fibre damage is associated with distinct sensory phenotypes in patients with fibromyalgia and small-fibre neuropathy. Eur J Pain 2023;27:163&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magdy R, Eid RA, Fathy W, Abdel-Aziz MM, Ibrahim RE, Yehia A, Sheemy MS, Hussein M. Characteristics and risk factors of persistent neuropathic pain in recovered COVID-19 patients. Pain Med 2022;23:774&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFarland AJ, Yousuf MS, Shiers S, Price TJ. Neurobiology of SARS-CoV-2 interactions with the peripheral nervous system: implications for COVID-19 and pain. Pain Rep 2021;6:e885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak P, Mukerji SS, Alabsi HS, Systrom D, Marciano SP, Felsenstein D, Mullally WJ, Pilgrim DM. Multisystem involvement in post-acute sequelae of coronavirus disease 19. Ann Neurol 2022;91:367&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oaklander AL, Mills AJ, Kelley M, Toran LS, Smith B, Dalakas MC, Nath A. Peripheral neuropathy evaluations of patients with prolonged Long COVID. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2022;9:e1146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojeda A, Calvo A, Cu&#xf1;at T, Mellado-Artigas R, Comino-Trinidad O, Aliaga J, Arias M, Ferrando C, Martinez-Pall&#xed; G, D&#xfc;rsteler C. Characteristics and influence on quality of life of new-onset pain in critical COVID-19 survivors. Eur J Pain 2022;26:680&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierangeli G, Turrini A, Giannini G, Del Sorbo F, Calandra-Buonaura G, Guaraldi P, Bacchi Reggiani ML, Cortelli P. Translation and linguistic validation of the composite autonomic symptom score COMPASS 31. Neurol Sci 2015;36:1897&#x2013;902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Provitera V, Gibbons CH, Wendelschafer-Crabb G, Donadio V, Vitale DF, Loavenbruck A, Stancanelli A, Caporaso G, Liguori R, Wang N, Santoro L, Kennedy WR, Nolano M. The role of skin biopsy in differentiating small-fiber neuropathy from ganglionopathy. Eur J Neurol 2018;25:848&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Provitera V, Gibbons CH, Wendelschafer-Crabb G, Donadio V, Vitale DF, Stancanelli A, Caporaso G, Liguori R, Wang N, Santoro L, Kennedy WR, Nolano M. A multi-center, multinational age- and gender-adjusted normative dataset for immunofluorescent intraepidermal nerve fiber density at the distal leg. Eur J Neurol 2016;23:333&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolke R, Baron R, Maier C, T&#xf6;lle TR, Treede DR, Beyer A, Binder A, Birbaumer N, Birklein F, B&#xf6;tef&#xfc;r IC, Braune S, Flor H, Huge V, Klug R, Landwehrmeyer GB, Magerl W, Maih&#xf6;fner C, Rolko C, Schaub C, Scherens A, Sprenger T, Valet M, Wasserka B. Quantitative sensory testing in the German Research Network on Neuropathic Pain (DFNS): standardized protocol and reference values. PAIN 2006;123:231&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safavi F, Gustafson L, Walitt B, Lehky T, Dehbashi S, Wiebold A, Mina Y, Shin S, Pan B, Polydefkis M, Oaklander AL, Nath A. Neuropathic symptoms with SARS-CoV-2 vaccination. medRxiv 2022 [epub ahead of print].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiers S, Ray PR, Wangzhou A, Sankaranarayanan I, Tatsui CE, Rhines LD, Li Y, Uhelski ML, Dougherty PM, Price TJ. ACE2 and SCARF expression in human DRG nociceptors: implications for SARS-CoV-2 virus neurological effects. PAIN 2020;161:2494&#x2013;501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xdc;&#xe7;eyler N, Zeller D, Kahn AK, Kewenig S, Kittel-Schneider S, Schmid A, Casanova-Molla J, Reiners K, Sommer C. Small fibre pathology in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. Brain 2013;136:1857&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollert J, Maier C, Attal N, Bennett DLH, Bouhassira D, Enax-Krumova EK, Finnerup NB, Freynhagen R, Gierthm&#xfc;hlen J, Haanp&#xe4;&#xe4; M, Hansson P, H&#xfc;llemann P, Jensen TS, Magerl W, Ramirez JD, Rice ASC, Schuh-Hofer S, Segerdahl M, Serra J, Shillo PR, Sindrup S, Tesfaye S, Themistocleous AC, T&#xf6;lle TR, Treede RD, Baron R. Stratifying patients with peripheral neuropathic pain based on sensory profiles: algorithm and sample size recommendations. PAIN 2017;158:1446&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe F, Clauw DJ, Fitzcharles M-A, Goldenberg DL, H&#xe4;user W, Katz RL, Mease PJ, Russell AS, Russell IJ, Walitt B. 2016 Revisions to the 2010/2011 fibromyalgia diagnostic criteria. Semin Arthritis Rheum 2016;46:319&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Treatment Guidelines Panel. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) treatment guidelines. New York: National Institutes of Health. Available at: https://www.covid19treatmentguidelines.nih.gov/ . Accessed May 20, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post COVID-19 condition (long COVID). Available at: https://www.who.int/europe/news-room/fact-sheets/item/post-covid-19-condition#:&#x223c;:text=Definition,months%20with%20no%20other%20explanation . Accessed May 20, 2023.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>