<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37706263</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1654</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Reviews in medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rev Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lactate dehydrogenase contribution to symptom persistence in long COVID: A pooled analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2477</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2477</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/rmv.2477</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>There's critical need for risk predictors in long COVID. This meta-analysis evaluates the evidence for an association between plasma lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) and long COVID and explores the contribution of LDH to symptoms persistent across the distinct post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) domains. PubMed, EMBASE, Web of Science, and Google Scholar were searched for articles published up to 20 March 2023 for studies that reported data on LDH levels in COVID-19 survivors with and without PASC. Random-effect meta-analysis was employed to estimate the standardized mean difference (SMD) with corresponding 95% confidence interval of each outcome. There were a total of 8289 study participants (3338 PASC vs. 4951 controls) from 46 studies. Our meta-analysis compared to the controls showed a significant association between LDH elevation and Resp-PASC [SMD&#xa0;=&#xa0;1.07, 95%CI&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.72, 1.41, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.01] but not Cardio-PASC [SMD&#xa0;=&#xa0;1.79, 95%CI&#xa0;=&#xa0;-0.02, 3.61, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.05], Neuro-PASC [SMD&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.19, 95%CI&#xa0;=&#xa0;-0.24, 0.61, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.40], and Gastrointestinal-PASC [SMD&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.45, 95%CI&#xa0;=&#xa0;-1.08, 1.98, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.56]. This meta-analysis suggests elevated LDH can be used for predicting Resp-PASC, but not Cardio-PASC, Neuro-PASC or gastrointestinal-PASC. Thus, elevated plasma LDH following COVID infection may be considered as a disease biomarker.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Reviews in Medical Virology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Udeh</LastName><ForeName>Raphael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9476-6677</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, Faculty of Science, University of Technology Sydney, Ultimo, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Utrero-Rico</LastName><ForeName>Alberto</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8814-8410</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dolja-Gore</LastName><ForeName>Xenia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7085-8024</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rahmati</LastName><ForeName>Masoud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4792-027X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Faculty of Literature and Human Sciences, Lorestan University, Khoramabad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Faculty of Literature and Humanities, Vali-E-Asr University of Rafsanjan, Rafsanjan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McEVoy</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5505-5557</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>La Trobe Rural Health School, College of Science, Health and Engineering, La Trobe University, Bendigo, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kenna</LastName><ForeName>Tony</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6844-3463</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Immunology &amp; Infection Control, Queensland University of Technology, Bendigo, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Rev Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1052-9276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.1.1.27</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007770">L-Lactate Dehydrogenase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007770" MajorTopicYN="N">L-Lactate Dehydrogenase</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010949" MajorTopicYN="N">Plasma</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D039781" MajorTopicYN="N">PubMed</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lactate dehydrogenase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pooled analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID-19 condition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37706263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rmv.2477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):1-4. Health Organization [2022). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et&#xa0;al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):601-615. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmati M, Udeh R, Yon DK, et&#xa0;al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of long- term sequelae of COVID-19 2-year after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a call to action for neurological, physical, and psychological sciences. J Med Virol. 2023;95(6):e28852. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.28852</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farhana A, Lappin SL. Biochemistry, lactate dehydrogenase. In: StatPearls. StatPearls Publishing; 2022. [Internet].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry BM, Aggarwal G, Wong J, et&#xa0;al. Lactate dehydrogenase levels predict coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) severity and mortality: a pooled analysis. Am J Emerg Med. 2020;38(9):1722-1726. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajem.2020.05.073</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manosalva C, Quiroga J, Hidalgo AI, et&#xa0;al. Role of lactate in inflammatory processes: friend or foe. Front Immunol. 2022;12:808799. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.808799</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Qi M, Yang M. Current status and future perspectives of lactate dehydrogenase detection and medical implications: a review. Biosensors. 2022;12(12):1145. https://doi.org/10.3390/bios12121145</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pucino V, Bombardieri M, Pitzalis C, Mauro C. Lactate at the crossroads of metabolism, inflammation, and autoimmunity. Eur J&#xa0;Immunol. 2017;47(1):14-21. https://doi.org/10.1002/eji.201646477</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan TN, Naqvi SS, Rehman MU, et&#xa0;al. Ginger ring compounds as an inhibitor of spike binding protein of alpha, beta, gamma and delta variants of SARS-CoV-2: an in-silico study. Narra J. 2023;3(1). https://doi.org/10.52225/narra.v3i1.98</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, et&#xa0;al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185(5):881-895. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2022.01.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahriani M, Ilmawan M, Fajar JK, et&#xa0;al. Persistence of long COVID symptoms in COVID-19 survivors worldwide and its potential pathogenesis-a systematic review and meta-analysis. Narra J. 2021;1(2). https://doi.org/10.52225/narraj.v1i2.36</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan WJ, Ni ZY, Hu Y, et&#xa0;al. Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(18):1708-1720. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa2002032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y, Zhang H, Mu S, et&#xa0;al. Lactate dehydrogenase, an independent risk factor of severe COVID-19 patients: a retrospective and observational study. Aging. 2020;12(12):11245-11258. https://doi.org/10.18632/aging.103372</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen XY, Huang MY, Xiao ZW, Yang S, Chen XQ. Lactate dehydrogenase elevations is associated with severity of COVID-19: a meta-analysis. Crit Care. 2020;24(1):1-3. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-020-03161-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fialek B, Pruc M, Smereka J, et&#xa0;al. Diagnostic value of lactate dehydrogenase in COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cardiol J. 2022;29(5):751-758. https://doi.org/10.5603/cj.a2022.0056</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martha JW, Wibowo A, Pranata R. Prognostic value of elevated lactate dehydrogenase in patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Postgrad Med. 2022;98(1160):422-427. https://doi.org/10.1136/postgradmedj-2020-139542</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antoniou KM, Vasarmidi E, Russell AM, et&#xa0;al. European Respiratory&#xa0;Society statement on long COVID follow-up. Eur Respir J.&#xa0;2022;60(2):2102174. https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.02174-2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG, PRISMA Group T. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Ann Intern Med. 2009;151(4):264-269. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2009.06.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson J, Welch V, Losos M, Tugwell PJ. The Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) for Assessing the Quality of Nonrandomised Studies in Meta-Analyses. Vol 2. Ottawa Hospital Research Institute; 2011:1-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn Z, Moola S, Riitano D, Lisy K. The development of a critical appraisal tool for use in systematic reviews addressing questions of prevalence. Int J Health Pol Manag. 2014;3(3):123-128. https://doi.org/10.15171/ijhpm.2014.71</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murad MH, Wang Z, Chu H, Lin L. When continuous outcomes are measured using different scales: guide for meta-analysis and interpretation. BMJ. 2019:364. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.k4817</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan X, Wang W, Liu J, Tong T. Estimating the sample mean and standard deviation from the sample size, median, range and/or interquartile range. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2014;14:1-3. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2288-14-135</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Smith GD, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ. 1997;315(7109):629-634. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F, Tomasoni D, Falcinella C, et&#xa0;al. Female gender is associated with long COVID syndrome: a prospective cohort study. Clin Microbiol Infection. 2022;28(4):611.e9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2021.11.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco JR, Cobos-Ceballos MJ, Navarro F, et&#xa0;al. Pulmonary long-term consequences of COVID-19 infections after hospital discharge. Clin Microbiol Infection. 2021;27(6):892-896. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2021.02.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente I, Sinatti G, Cirella A, Santini SJ, Balsano C. Alteration of inflammatory parameters and psychological post-traumatic syndrome in long-COVID patients. Int J Environ Res Publ Health. 2022;19(12):7103. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19127103</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortellini A, Gennari A, Pommeret F, et&#xa0;al. COVID-19 Sequelae and the Host Pro- Inflammatory Response: An Analysis from the OnCovid Registry. JNCI Journal of the National Cancer Institute; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eray A, Murat K, Abdullah G, et&#xa0;al. Follow-up study of anti-SARS-CoV-2 IgG antibody response in COVID-19 patients up to 6 months after infection. Future Microbiol. 2022;17(13):1043-1049. https://doi.org/10.2217/fmb-2022-0006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Ryan-Murua P, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a M, Arendt-Nielsen L, Torres-Macho J. Serological biomarkers at hospital admission are not related to long-term post-COVID fatigue and dyspnea in COVID-19 survivors. Respiration. 2022;101(7):1-8. https://doi.org/10.1159/000524042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Fan Y, Alwalid O, et&#xa0;al. Six-month follow-up chest CT findings after severe COVID-19 pneumonia. Radiology. 2021;299:E177-E186. https://doi.org/10.1148/radiol.2021203153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Zhao P, Tang D, et&#xa0;al. Cardiac involvement in patients recovered from COVID-2019 identified using magnetic resonance imaging. Cardiovasc Imag. 2020;13(11):2330-2339. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcmg.2020.05.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo A, Moj&#xf3;n D, Bardaj&#xed; A, et&#xa0;al. Myocardial injury as a prognostic factor in mid-and long-term follow-up of COVID-19 survivors. J Clin Med. 2021;10(24):5900. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10245900</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia X, Han X, Cao Y, et&#xa0;al. Quantitative inspiratory-expiratory chest CT findings in COVID-19 survivors at the 6- month follow-up. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):1-2. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-11237-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerget B, &#xc7;elik E, Kerget F, et&#xa0;al. Evaluation of 3- month follow-up of patients with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. J Med Virol. 2022;94(5):2026-2034. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.27579</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazar M, Barbu EC, Chitu CE, et&#xa0;al. Interstitial lung fibrosis following COVID-19 pneumonia. Diagnostics. 2022;12(8):2028. https://doi.org/10.3390/diagnostics12082028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee I, Kim J, Yeo Y, et&#xa0;al. Prognostic factors for pulmonary fibrosis following pneumonia in patients with COVID-19: a prospective study. J Clin Med. 2022;11(19):5913. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm11195913</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang L, Yang B, Jiang N, et&#xa0;al. Three-month follow-up study of survivors of coronavirus disease 2019 after discharge. J Kor Med Sci. 2020;35(47). https://doi.org/10.3346/jkms.2020.35.e418</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Likhvantsev V, Landoni G, Kuzovlev A, et&#xa0;al. One year health-related quality of life after discharge: a prospective cohort study among COVID-19 ICU survivors. Signa Vitae. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Lv F, Huang Y, Xiao K. Follow-up study of the chest CT characteristics of COVID-19 survivors seven months after recovery. Front Med. 2021;8:636298. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2021.636298</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu JQ, Lu JY, Wang W, et&#xa0;al. Clinical predictors of acute cardiac injury and normalization of troponin after hospital discharge from COVID-19. EBioMedicine. 2022;76:103821. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ebiom.2022.103821</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maamar M, Artime A, Pariente E, et&#xa0;al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome, low-grade inflammation and inflammatory markers: a cross-sectional study. Curr Med Res Opin. 2022;38(6):1-9. https://doi.org/10.1080/03007995.2022.2042991</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGroder CF, Zhang D, Choudhury MA, et&#xa0;al. Pulmonary fibrosis&#xa0;4 months after COVID-19 is associated with severity of illness and blood leucocyte telomere length. Thorax. 2021;76(12):1242-1245. https://doi.org/10.1136/thoraxjnl-2021-217031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez-Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Ramos-Hern&#xe1;ndez C, Garc&#xed;a-R&#xed;o F, et&#xa0;al. Alterations in respiratory function test three months after hospitalisation for COVID-19 pneumonia: value of determining nitric oxide diffusion. J Clin Med. 2021;10(10):2119. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10102119</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez-Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Ramos-Hern&#xe1;ndez C, Garc&#xed;a-R&#xed;o F, et&#xa0;al. Evolution and long-term respiratory sequelae after severe COVID-19 pneumonia: nitric oxide diffusion measurement value. Respir Res;24(1):1-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan F, Yang L, Liang B, et&#xa0;al. Chest CT patterns from diagnosis to&#xa0;1 year of follow-up in patients with COVID-19. Radiology.&#xa0;2022;302(3):709-719. https://doi.org/10.1148/radiol.2021211199</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry AH, Wani AH, Shah NN, Jehangir M. Medium-term chest computed tomography (CT) follow-up of COVID-19 pneumonia patients after recovery to assess the rate of resolution and determine the potential predictors of persistent lung changes. Egypt J Radiol Nucl Med. 2021;52(1):1-9. https://doi.org/10.1186/s43055-021-00434-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi R, Basile M, Salzillo C, et&#xa0;al. Myocardial injury portends a higher risk of mortality and long-term cardiovascular sequelae after hospital discharge in COVID-19 survivors. J Clin Med. 2022;11(19):5964. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm11195964</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rincon-Alvarez E, Gonzalez-Garcia M, Ali-Munive A, et&#xa0;al. Risk factors for persistent tomographic abnormalities at 6 months of follow-up in a cohort of hospitalized patients with moderate and severe COVID-19 living at high altitude. Front Med. 2023;10:133. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2023.1110535</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salerno D, Oriaku I, Darnell M, et&#xa0;al. Association of abnormal pulmonary vasculature on CT scan for COVID-19 infection with decreased diffusion capacity in follow up: a retrospective cohort study. PLoS One. 2021;16(10):e0257892. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0257892</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santus P, Flor N, Saad M, et&#xa0;al. Trends over time of lung function and radiological abnormalities in COVID-19 pneumonia: a prospective, observational, cohort study. J Clin Med. 2021;10(5):1021. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10051021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sibila O, Albacar N, Perea L, et&#xa0;al. Lung function sequelae in COVID-19 patients 3 months after hospital discharge. Arch Bronconeumol. 2021;57:59-61. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arbres.2021.01.036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sibila O, Perea L, Albacar N, et&#xa0;al. Elevated plasma levels of epithelial and endothelial cell markers in COVID-19 survivors with reduced lung diffusing capacity six months after hospital discharge. Respir Res. 2021;23(1):1-0. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12931-022-01955-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabatabaei SM, Rajebi H, Moghaddas F, Ghasemiadl M, Talari H. Chest CT in COVID-19 pneumonia: what are the findings in mid-term follow-up? Emerg Radiol. 2020;27(6):711-719. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10140-020-01869-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiele K, Balfanz P, M&#xfc;ller T, et&#xa0;al. Cardiopulmonary work up of&#xa0;patients with and without fatigue 6 months after COVID-19. Sci&#xa0;Rep. 2022;12(1):18038. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-22876-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, et&#xa0;al. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One. 2020;15(11):e0240784. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0240784</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varghese J, Sandmann S, Ochs K, et&#xa0;al. Persistent symptoms and lab abnormalities in patients who recovered from COVID-19. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):1-8. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-91270-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallis TJ, Heiden E, Horno J, et&#xa0;al. Risk factors for persistent abnormality on chest radiographs at 12-weeks post hospitalisation with PCR confirmed COVID-19. Respir Res. 2021;22(1):1-9. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12931-021-01750-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallis TJ, Welham B, Kong A, et&#xa0;al. Predicting the risk of chest radiograph abnormality 12-weeks post hospitalisation with SARS CoV-2 PCR confirmed COVID-19. Respir Res. 2022;23(1):1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng J, Li Y, Li J, et&#xa0;al. Gastrointestinal sequelae 90 days after discharge for COVID-19. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;6(5):344-346. https://doi.org/10.1016/s2468-1253(21)00076-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Deng KQ, Li C, et&#xa0;al. Cardiac involvement in recovered patients from COVID-19: a preliminary 6-month follow-up study. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2021;8:654405. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcvm.2021.654405</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Zhou M, Luo P, et&#xa0;al. Plasma metabolomic profiling of patients recovered from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) with pulmonary sequelae 3 months after discharge. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73(12):2228-2239. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciab147</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin X, Xi X, Min X, et&#xa0;al. Long-term chest CT follow-up in COVID-19 survivors: 102-361 days after onset. Ann Transl Med. 2021;9(15):1231. https://doi.org/10.21037/atm-21-1438</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Bai W, Yue J, et&#xa0;al. Eight months follow-up study on pulmonary function, lung radiographic, and related physiological characteristics in COVID-19 survivors. Sci Rep. 2021a;11(1):1-3. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-93191-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Luo P, Xu J, et&#xa0;al. Plasma metabolomic profiles in recovered COVID-19 patients without previous underlying diseases 3 months after discharge. J Inflamm Res. 2021;14:4485-4501. https://doi.org/10.2147/jir.s325853</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao YM, Shang YM, Song WB, et&#xa0;al. Follow-up study of the pulmonary function and related physiological characteristics of COVID-19 survivors three months after recovery. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100463. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100463</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Yang C, An X, et&#xa0;al. Follow-up study on COVID-19 survivors one year after discharge from hospital. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;112:173-182. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2021.09.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M, Tan X, Luo P, et&#xa0;al. Changes in glomerular filtration rate and metabolomic differences in severely ill coronavirus disease survivors 3 months after discharge. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Basis Dis. 2022;1868(1):166289. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbadis.2021.166289</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zollner A, Koch R, Jukic A, et&#xa0;al. Postacute COVID-19 is characterized by gut viral antigen persistence in inflammatory bowel diseases. Gastroenterology. 2022;163(2):495-506.e8. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2022.04.037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuschlag D, Grandt D, Custodis F, Braun C, H&#xe4;user W. Spontaneously reported persistent symptoms related to coronavirus disease 2019 one year after hospital discharge: a retrospective cohort single-center study. Der Schmerz. 2022;36(5):315-325. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00482-022-00626-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni W, Yang X, Yang D, et&#xa0;al. Role of angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) in COVID-19. Crit Care. 2020;24(1):1-0. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-020-03120-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon JJ, Heyman B, Ko JP, Condos R, Lynch DA. CT of post-acute lung complications of COVID-19. Radiology. 2021;301(2):E383-E395. https://doi.org/10.1148/radiol.2021211396</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das KM, Lee EY, Singh R, et&#xa0;al. Follow-up chest radiographic findings in patients with MERS-CoV after recovery. Indian J Radiol&#xa0;Imaging. 2017;27(03):342-349. https://doi.org/10.4103/ijri.ijri_469_16</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603-605. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.12603</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed H, Patel K, Greenwood DC, et&#xa0;al. Long-term clinical outcomes in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS) outbreaks after hospitalisation or ICU admission: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Rehabil Med. 2020;52(5):1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Li J, Liu H, et&#xa0;al. Long-term bone and lung consequences associated with hospital-acquired severe acute respiratory syndrome: a 15-year follow-up from a prospective cohort study. Bone Res. 2020;8(1):8. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41413-020-0084-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmati M, Koyanagi A, Banitalebi E, et&#xa0;al. The effect of SARS-CoV-2 infection on cardiac function in post-COVID-19 survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2023;95(1):e28325. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.28325</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramadan MS, Bertolino L, Zampino R, et&#xa0;al. Cardiac sequelae after coronavirus disease 2019 recovery: a systematic review. Clin Microbiol Infection. 2021;27(9):1250-1261. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2021.06.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik P, Patel U, Mehta D, et&#xa0;al. Biomarkers and outcomes of COVID-19 hospitalisations: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Evid-Based Med. 2021;26(3):107-108. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjebm-2020-111536</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kojima K, Yoon H, Okishio K, Tsuyuguchi K. Increased lactate dehydrogenase reflects the progression of COVID-19 pneumonia on chest computed tomography and predicts subsequent severe disease. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):1012. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-28201-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou JN, Sun L, Wang BR, et&#xa0;al. The characteristics and evolution of pulmonary fibrosis in COVID-19 patients as assessed by AI-assisted chest HRCT. PLoS One. 2021;16(3):e0248957. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0248957</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Lv F, Huang Y, Xiao K. Follow-up study of the chest CT characteristics of COVID-19 survivors seven months after recovery. Front Med. 2021;8:636298. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2021.636298</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks GA. Cell-cell and intracellular lactate shuttles. J Physiol. 2009;587(23):5591-5600. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2009.178350</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kottmann RM, Kulkarni AA, Smolnycki KA, et&#xa0;al. Lactic acid is elevated in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis and induces myofibroblast differentiation via pH-dependent activation of transforming growth factor-&#x3b2;. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2012;186(8):740-751. https://doi.org/10.1164/rccm.201201-0084oc</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palsson-McDermott EM, O'neill LA. The Warburg effect then and now: from cancer to inflammatory diseases. Bioessays. 2013;35(11):965-973. https://doi.org/10.1002/bies.201300084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberti MV, Locasale JW. The Warburg effect: how does it benefit cancer cells? Trends Biochem Sci. 2016;41(3):211-218. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tibs.2015.12.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Li X, Gu X, et&#xa0;al. Health outcomes in people 2 years after surviving hospitalisation with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10(9):863-876. https://doi.org/10.1016/s2213-2600(22)00126-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Codo AC, Davanzo GG, de Brito Monteiro L, et&#xa0;al. Elevated glucose levels favor SARS-CoV-2 infection and monocyte response through a HIF- 1&#x3b1;/glycolysis-dependent axis. Cell metab. 2020;32(3):437-446. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2020.07.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajaz S, McPhail MJ, Singh KK, et&#xa0;al. Mitochondrial metabolic manipulation by SARS-CoV-2 in peripheral blood mononuclear cells of patients with COVID-19. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2021;320(1):C57-C65. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpcell.00426.2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Icard P, Lincet H, Wu Z, et&#xa0;al. The key role of Warburg effect in SARS-CoV-2 replication and associated inflammatory response. Biochimie. 2021;180:169-177. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biochi.2020.11.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montefusco L, Ben Nasr M, D&#x2019;Addio F, et&#xa0;al. Acute and long-term disruption of glycometabolic control after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Metab. 2021;3(6):774-785. https://doi.org/10.1038/s42255-021-00407-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Boer E, Petrache I, Goldstein NM, et&#xa0;al. Decreased fatty acid oxidation and altered lactate production during exercise in patients&#xa0;with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Am J Respir Crit Care Med.&#xa0;2022;205(1):126-129. https://doi.org/10.1164/rccm.202108-1903le</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guntur VP, Nemkov T, de Boer E, et&#xa0;al. Signatures of mitochondrial dysfunction and impaired fatty acid metabolism in plasma of patients with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC). Metabolites. 2022;12(11):1026. https://doi.org/10.3390/metabo12111026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding J, Karp JE, Emadi A. Elevated lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) can be a marker of immune suppression in cancer: interplay between hematologic and solid neoplastic clones and their microenvironments. Cancer Biomark. 2017;19(4):353-363. https://doi.org/10.3233/cbm-160336</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>See&#xdf;le J, Waterboer T, Hippchen T, et&#xa0;al. Persistent symptoms in adult patients 1 year after coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a prospective cohort study. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;74(7):1191-1198. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciab611</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Abell&#xe1;n J, Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Padilla S, et&#xa0;al. Immunologic phenotype of patients with long-COVID syndrome of 1-year duration. Front Immunol. 2022;13. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2022.920627</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son K, Jamil R, Chowdhury A, et&#xa0;al. Circulating anti-nuclear autoantibodies in COVID-19 survivors predict long COVID symptoms. Eur Respir J. 2023;61(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneko N, Kuo HH, Boucau J, et&#xa0;al. Loss of Bcl-6-expressing T follicular helper cells and germinal centers in COVID-19. Cell. 2020;183(1):143-157. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2020.08.025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia C, Zurbuchen Y, Taeschler P, et&#xa0;al. Immunoglobulin signature predicts risk of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):1-2. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-27797-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy WJ, Longo DL. A possible role for anti-idiotype antibodies in SARS-CoV-2 infection and vaccination. N Engl J Med. 2022;386(4):394-396. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmcibr2113694</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB, et&#xa0;al. Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Immunol. 2022;23(2):210-216. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41590-021-01113-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groh V, Br&#xfc;hl A, El-Gabalawy H, Nelson JL, Spies T. Stimulation of&#xa0;T cell autoreactivity by anomalous expression of NKG2D and&#xa0;its MIC ligands in rheumatoid arthritis. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2003;100(16):9452-9457. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1632807100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ausiello CM, Urbani F, La Sala A, Funaro A, Malavasi F. CD38 ligation induces discrete cytokine mRNA expression in human cultured lymphocytes. Eur J Immunol. 1995;25(5):1477-1480. https://doi.org/10.1002/eji.1830250554</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong SW, Fong SW, Young BE, et&#xa0;al. Persistent symptoms and association with inflammatory cytokine signatures in recovered coronavirus disease 2019 patients. In: Open forum infectious diseases. Vol 8. Oxford University Press; 2021.ofab156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Melo GD, Lazarini F, Levallois S, et&#xa0;al. COVID-19-related anosmia is associated with viral persistence and inflammation in human olfactory epithelium and brain infection in hamsters. Sci Transl Med. 2021;13(596):eabf8396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Boer E, Petrache I, Mohning MP. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing. JAMA. 2022;327(13):1284-1285. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2022.2037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parikh S, Goldstein A, Koenig MK, et&#xa0;al. Diagnosis and management of mitochondrial disease: a consensus statement from the Mitochondrial Medicine Society. Genet Med. 2015;17(9):689-701. https://doi.org/10.1038/gim.2014.177</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai YJ, Liu SH, Manachevakul S, Lee TA, Kuo CT, Bello D. Biomarkers in long COVID-19: a systematic review. Front Med. 2023;10:7. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2023.1085988</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ, Halim A, Halim M, et&#xa0;al. Inflammatory and vascular biomarkers in post-COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of over 20 biomarkers. Rev Med Virol. 2023;33(2):e2424. https://doi.org/10.1002/rmv.2424</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabowo NA, Megantara MA, Apriningsih H. The role of N-acetylcysteine in decreasing neutrophil-lymphocyte ratio in COVID-19 patients: a double-blind, randomized controlled trial. Narra J. 2023;3(2):e121. https://doi.org/10.52225/narra.v3i2.121</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>