<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36866647</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-277X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human nutrition and dietetics : the official journal of the British Dietetic Association</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Nutr Diet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Developing a consensus to support health and social care professionals and patients manage nutrition in the context of COVID-19 recovery.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1242</StartPage><EndPage>1252</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1242-1252</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jhn.13163</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The long-term effects on people who have had COVID-19 affect nutrition and can be influenced by diet conversely. Specific nutritional guidelines, however, were scarce at the beginning of 2020, and empirical literature was also lacking. Conventional research methodologies needed to be adapted to review the available literature that could be relevant to the United Kingdom and policy documents as well as collect the views of health and care staff. The aim of this paper is to describe the method to develop consensus statements from experts to address the necessary nutritional support and what emerged from this.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A nominal group technique (NGT) was adapted to the virtual world; we purposefully selected a range of professionals (dietitians, nurses, occupational therapists, etc.) and patients with long-term effects of COVID to present them with the most updated evidence and aim to reach key guidelines to address COVID-19 recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We were able to reach consensus statements that were developed and reviewed by relevant healthcare staff at the front line to address the nutritional needs of patients recovering from COVID-19 and those suffering from its long-term effects. This adapted NGT process led us to understand that a virtual repository of concise guidelines and recommendations was needed. This was developed to be freely accessed by both patients recovering from COVID-19 and health professionals who manage them.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">We successfully obtained key consensus statements from the adapted NGT, which showed the need for the nutrition and COVID-19 knowledge hub. This hub has been developed, updated, reviewed, endorsed and improved across the subsequent 2 years.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Journal of Human Nutrition and Dietetics published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Dietetic Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tronco Hernandez</LastName><ForeName>Yessica Abigail</ForeName><Initials>YA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6262-8659</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Professions, Faculty of Health, University of Plymouth, Plymouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Julian</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dietetics, Glasgow Royal Infirmary, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weekes</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth C</ForeName><Initials>EC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guy's &amp; St Thomas NHS and Foundation Trust, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murphy</LastName><ForeName>Jane</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3531-5566</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Social Sciences at Bournemouth University, Bournemouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frost</LastName><ForeName>Gary</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Metabolism, Digestion and Reproduction, Faculty of Medicine, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hickson</LastName><ForeName>Mary</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7996-0095</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Professions, Faculty of Health, University of Plymouth, Plymouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Nutr Diet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904840</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0952-3871</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006282" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012944" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Support</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003695" MajorTopicYN="N">Delivery of Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nominal group technique</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutritional guidelines</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36866647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jhn.13163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Pavli A, Theodoridou M, Maltezou H Post-COVID syndrome: incidence, clinical spectrum, and challenges for primary healthcare professionals. Arch Med Res. 2021;52:575-81. [cited 2022 Mar 16]. Available from: https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0188440921000813?casa_token=Gz0CvyrRxuIAAAAA:OIX-ZMKT_28-ZucIWsv_id44ScxYCmRnqeenRRAerMsWYw3KqjEgyvkfH0uSIdG-h0g50VOSWw</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler MJ, Barrientos RM. The impact of nutrition on COVID-19 susceptibility and long-term consequences. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:53-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re'em Y, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. medRxiv 2021;38(2021):101019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabetakis I, Lordan R, Norton C, Tsoupras A. COVID-19: the inflammation link and the role of nutrition in potential mitigation. Nutrients. 2020;12(5):1466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond CM The development of evidence-based guidelines for over-the-counter treatment of vulvovaginal candidiasis. Pharm World Sci. 2003;25:177-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tully MP, Cantrill JA. Exploring the domains of appropriateness of drug therapy, using the nominal group technique. Pharm World Sci. 2002;24(4):128-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bissell P, Ward PR, Noyce PR. Appropriateness measurement: application to advice-giving in community pharmacies. Soc Sci Med. 2000;51(3):343-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiligsmann M, van Durme D, Geusens P, Dellaert T, Dirksen, van der Weijden T, et al. Nominal group technique to select attributes for discrete choice experiments: an example for drug treatment choice in osteoporosis. Patient Prefer Adherence. 2013;7:133-139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMillan SS, King M, Tully MP. How to use the nominal group and Delphi techniques. Int J Clin Pharm. 2016;38(3):655-62. [cited 2020 Nov 12]. Available from: http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11096-016-0257-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delbeq A, Van de Ven A, Gustafson D Group techniques for program planning: a guide to nominal groups and Delphi process [Internet]. 2004 [cited 2022 Mar 16]. Available from: https://sites.google.com/a/umn.edu/avandeven/publications/books/group-techniques-for-program-planning</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latif J, Elizabeth Weekes C, Julian A, Frost G, Murphy J, Abigail Tronco-Hernandez Y, et al. Strategies to ensure continuity of nutritional care in patients with COVID-19 infection on discharge from hospital: a rapid review. Clin Nutr ESPEN [Internet]. 2021;47:106-16. [cited 2021 Dec 1]. Available from: https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2405457721011244</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence V, Hickson M, Weekes CE, Julian A, Frost G, Murphy J. A UK survey of nutritional care pathways for patients with COVID-19 prior to and post-hospital stay. J Hum Nutr Diet. 2021;34(4):660-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence V, HIckson M, Weekes E, Julian A, Frost G, Murphy J. A UK survey of nutritional care pathways for Covid-19 patients post hospital stay. J Hum Nutr Diet. 2020;34(4):660-669. https://doi.org/10.1111/jhn.12896</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence J. Model and process for nutrition and dietetic practice [Internet]. In: Dietetic and Nutrition Case Studies. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd; 2016 [cited 2021 Dec 1]. pp 1-7. Available from: https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/9781119163411.ch1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMillan SS, Kelly F, Sav A, Kendall E, King MA, Whitty JA, et al. Using the nominal group technique: how to analyse across multiple groups. Health Serv Outcomes Res Method. 2014;14(3):92-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foth T, Efstathiou N, Vanderspank-Wright B, Ufholz LA, D&#xfc;tthorn N, Zimansky M, et al. The use of Delphi and nominal group technique in nursing education: a review. Int J Nurs Stud. 2016;60:112-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drennan V, Walters K, Lenihan P, Cohen S, Myerson S, Iliffe S, et al. Priorities in identifying unmet need in older people attending general practice: a nominal group technique study. Fam Pract. 2007;24(5):454-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh HF, Shannon SE. Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qual Health Res. 2005;15(9):1277-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke V, Braun V. Thematic analysis. J Posit Psychol. 2017;12(3):297-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gausman J, Langer A. Sex and gender disparities in the COVID-19 pandemic. J Womens Health. 2020;29(4):465-6.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>