<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38404605</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1546-993X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Integrative medicine (Encinitas, Calif.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Integr Med (Encinitas)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neuroplasticity Intervention, Amygdala and Insula Retraining (AIR), Significantly Improves Overall Health and Functioning Across Various Chronic Conditions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20</StartPage><EndPage>28</EndPage><MedlinePgn>20-28</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Chronic conditions, sometimes referred to as functional somatic disorders, such as myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS), fibromyalgia (FM), and more recently, long COVID (LC), affect millions of people worldwide. Yet, after decades of research and testing, the etiology and treatment for many of these diseases is still unclear. Recently, a consortium of clinicians and researchers have proposed that while many different chronic conditions exist, the root cause of each may be a similar brain-body connection, as the brain responds to perceived biological threats and transmits danger signals to the body that manifest as somatic symptoms. This hypothesis suggests that treating chronic conditions requires an approach that addresses the neural networks involved. One such method, known as Amygdala and Insula Retraining (AIR), otherwise known as The Gupta Program, has shown promise in recent years for treating such conditions, including ME/CFS, FM, and LC. The present study aimed to demonstrate that AIR could be an effective approach for numerous other chronic illnesses (e.g., Lyme disease, mold illness, mast cell activation syndrome [MCAS]) and others. This novel and exploratory research examined self-reported health and functioning levels before and after using AIR. A series of paired-sample <i>t</i> tests with Bonferroni correction demonstrated that after 3+ months of using AIR (the minimum recommended time for the intervention), participants experienced a significant increase in overall health and functioning for 14 of 16 conditions tested (<i>P</i> &lt; .001 for all but one, which was <i>P</i> = .001) and approached significance for the remaining two conditions (<i>P</i> = .039 and <i>P</i> = .005). Of the 14 signficant findings, 11 had a large effect size and three had a medium effect size. Naturally, this study has limitations. It was a cross-sectional design with a small convenience sample and self-reported data. Future research with larger samples and randomized controlled trials is needed to provide further evidence of AIR's effectiveness. Nonetheless, these preliminary findings suggest that AIR is a viable method for improving the health of people suffering from chronic conditions, and clinicians and researchers might consider incorporating AIR into their protocols for these patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 InnoVision Professional Media Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bratty</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AB Research Consulting, Shelter Island Heights, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Integr Med (Encinitas)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101196303</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1546-993X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest Alexandra J. Bratty is the CEO of AB Research Consulting, which provides consulting services to The Gupta Program, the commercial version of the Amygdala and Insula Retraining (AIR) intervention. Her company was compensated for this work by independent donors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38404605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10886399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">imcj-22-20</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kozlowska K, Scher S, Helgeland H. Functional somatic symptoms in children and adolescents. A stress-system approach to assessment and treatment. Palgrave Macmillan;. 2020, doi:10.1007/978-3-030-46184-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;user W, Ablin J, Fitzcharles MA, et al. . Fibromyalgia. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2015;1(1):15022. doi:10.1038/nrdp.2015.22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27189527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH, Crooks MG. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is Long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;199(2):113-119. doi:10.1007/s00408-021-00423-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vyas J, Muirhead N, Singh R, Ephgrave R, Finlay AY. Impact of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) on the quality of life of people with ME/CFS and their partners and family members: an online cross-sectional survey. BMJ Open. 2022;12(5):e058128. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2021-058128</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9062824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35501074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solve ME. What are ME/CFS &amp; long COVID?
2022. https://solvecfs.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Mahoney L.L., Routen A., Gillies C., Ekezie W., Welford A., Zhang A., et al. . The prevalence and long-term health effects of Long Covid among hospitalized and non-hospitalized populations: A systematic review and meta-analysis. eClinicalMedicine. 2023, 55:101762. DOI:10.1016/j.eclinm.2022. 101762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9714474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36474804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutler DM. The costs of Long COVID. JAMA Health Forum. 2022;3(5):e221809. doi:10.1001/jamahealthforum.2022.1809</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36219031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleinst&#xe4;uber M, Witth&#xf6;ft M, Steffanowski A, van Marwijk H, Hiller W, Lambert MJ. Pharmacological interventions for somatoform disorders in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;(11):CD010628. PMID:25379990 doi:10.1002/14651858.CD010628.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11023023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25379990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Dessel N, den Boeft M, van der Wouden JC, et al. . Non-pharmacological interventions for somatoform disorders and medically unexplained physical symptoms (MUPS) in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;(11):CD011142. PMID:25362239 doi:10.1002/14651858.CD011142.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10984143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25362239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Oslo Chronic Fatigue Consortium. Alme T.E., Andreasson A., Asprusten T.T., Bakken A.K., Beadsworth M.J., et al. Chronic fatigue syndromes: Real illnesses that people can recover from. Scandinavian Journal of Primary Health Care;. 2023, doi:10.1080/02813432.2023.2235609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11001335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37740918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toussaint LL, Whipple MO, Abboud LL, Vincent A, Wahner-Roedler DL. A mind-body technique for symptoms related to fibromyalgia and chronic fatigue. Explore (NY). 2012;8(2):92-98. doi:10.1016/j.explore.2011.12.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22385563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanabria-Mazo JP, Montero-Marin J, Feliu-Soler A, et al. . Mindfulness-based program plus amygdala and insula retraining (MAIR) for the treatment of women with Fibromyalgia: A pilot randomized controlled trial. J Clin Med. 2020;9(10):32-46. doi:10.3390/jcm9103246</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7599726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33050630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toussaint LL, Bratty AJ. Amygdala and insula retraining (AIR) significantly reduces fatigue and increases energy in people with long COVID. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2023;2023:7068326. doi:10.1155/2023/7068326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10365910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37492483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A. Unconscious amygdalar fear conditioning in a subset of chronic fatigue syndrome patients. Med Hypotheses. 2002;59(6):727-735. doi:10.1016/S0306-9877(02)00321-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12445517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A. Can amygdala retraining techniques improve the well-being of patients with chronic fatigue syndrome? Journal of Holistic Healthcare. 2010;7(2):12-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attard R, Dingli P, Doggen CJM, Cassar K, Farrugia R, Bezzina Wettinger S. The impact of frequency, pattern, intensity, and type of alcohol consumption, and its combined effect with smoking on inflammation, lipid profile, and the risk of myocardial infarction. J Public Health (Berl). 2021;29(3):611-624. doi:10.1007/s10389-019-01172-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger G, Dixon J. Beyond obesity and lifestyle: a review of 21st century chronic disease determinants. BioMed Res Int. 2014;2014:731685. n. pag. doi:10.1155/2014/731685</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3997940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24804239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furman D, Campisi J, Verdin E, et al. . Chronic inflammation in the etiology of disease across the life span. Nat Med. 2019;25(12):1822-1832. PMID:31806905 doi:10.1038/s41591-019-0675-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7147972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31806905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Mejiba SE, Zhai Z, Akram H, et al. . Inhalation of environmental stressors &amp; chronic inflammation: autoimmunity and neurodegeneration. Mutat Res. 2009;674(1-2):62-72. PMID:18977456 doi:10.1016/j.mrgentox.2008.09.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2676865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18977456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hildebrandt X, Ibrahim M, Peltzer N. Cell death and inflammation during obesity: &#x201c;Know my methods, WAT(son).&#x201d;
Cell Death Differ
2022. 
302
[Internet]. 2022 Sep 29 [cited 2023 Dec 11];30(2):279&#x2013;92. Available from: https://www.nature.com/articles/s41418-022-01062-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9520110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36175539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller ES, Apple CG, Kannan KB, et al. . Chronic stress induces persistent low-grade inflammation. Am J Surg.
2019;218(4):677-683. Accessed December 11, 2023. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31378316/ doi:10.1016/j.amjsurg.2019.07.006
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6768696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31378316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourriyahi H, Yazdanpanah N, Saghazadeh A, Rezaei N. Loneliness: An Immunometabolic Syndrome. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(22):12162. doi:10.3390/ijerph182212162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8618012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34831917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty SS, D D, S H, et al. . Environmental pollutants and their effects on human health. Heliyon. 2023;9(9):e19496. PMID:37662771 doi:10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e19496</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10472068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37662771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang YC, Schorpp K, Harris KM. Social support, social strain and inflammation: Evidence from a national longitudinal study of U.S. adults. Soc Sci Med [Internet]. 2014. [cited 2023 Dec 11];107:124. Available from: /pmc/articles/PMC4028709/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4028709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24607674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeDoux J. The emotional brain, fear, and the amygdala. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2003;23(4-5):727-738. PMID:14514027 doi:10.1023/A:1025048802629</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14514027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JJ, Jung MW. Neural circuits and mechanisms involved in Pavlovian fear conditioning: a critical review. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2006;30(2):188-202. doi:10.1016/j.neubiorev.2005.06.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4342048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16120461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;imi&#x107; G, Tkal&#x10d;i&#x107; M, Vuki&#x107; V, et al. . Understanding Emotions: Origins and Roles of the Amygdala. Biomolecules. 2021;11(6):823. PMID:34072960 doi:10.3390/biom11060823</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8228195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34072960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolls A. Immunoception: the insular cortex perspective. Cell Mol Immunol. 2023;20(11):1270-1276. doi:10.1038/s41423-023-01051-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10616063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37386172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benarroch EE. Insular cortex: functional complexity and clinical correlations. Neurology. 2019;93(21):932-938. PMID:31645470 doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000008525</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31645470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrlich I, Humeau Y, Grenier F, Ciocchi S, Herry C, L&#xfc;thi A. Amygdala inhibitory circuits and the control of fear memory. Neuron. 2009;62(6):757-771. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2009.05.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19555645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doenlen R, Kr&#xfc;gel U, Wirth T, et al. . Electrical activity in rat cortico-limbic structures after single or repeated administration of lipopolysaccharide or staphylococcal enterotoxin B. Proc Biol Sci. 2011;278(1713):1864-1872. doi:10.1098/rspb.2010.2040</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3097828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21106598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacheco-L&#xf3;pez G, Niemi MB, Kou W, H&#xe4;rting M, Fandrey J, Schedlowski M. Neural substrates for behaviorally conditioned immunosuppression in the rat. J Neurosci. 2005;25(9):2330-2337. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4230-04.2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6726099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15745959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koren T, Yifa R, Amer M, et al. . Insular cortex neurons encode and retrieve specific immune responses. Cell. 2021;184(24):5902-5915.e17. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2021.10.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34752731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabin R, de Charro F. EQ-5D: a measure of health status from the EuroQol Group. Ann Med. 2001;33(5):337-343. doi:10.3109/07853890109002087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11491192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason LA, Torres-Harding S, Friedberg F, et al. . Non-pharmacologic Interventions for CFS: A Randomized Trial. J Clin Psychol Med Settings. 2007;14(4):275-296. doi:10.1007/s10880-007-9090-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, G&#xf8;tzsche PC. Is the placebo powerless? An analysis of clinical trials comparing placebo with no treatment. N Engl J Med. 2001;344(21):1594-1602. doi:10.1056/NEJM200105243442106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11372012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, G&#xf8;tzsche PC. Placebo interventions for all clinical conditions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2004;(3):CD003974. . Update in: Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2010;(1):CD003974. PMID: 15266510. doi:10.1002/14651858.CD003974.pub3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15266510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vase L, Riley JL, III, Price DD. A comparison of placebo effects in clinical analgesic trials versus studies of placebo analgesia. Pain. 2002;99(3):443-452. PMID:12406519 doi:10.1016/S0304-3959(02)00205-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12406519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardestani SK, Karkhaneh M, Stein E, et al. . Systematic Review of Mind-Body Interventions to Treat Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Medicina (Kaunas)
[Internet]. 2021 Jul 1 [cited 2024 Jan 24];57(7). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34202826/Theadom A, Cropley M, Smith HE, Feigin VL, Mcpherson K. Mind and body therapy for fibromyalgia. Cochrane database. Syst Rev. 2015;2015(4). Internet. Accessed January 24, 2024. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25856658/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8305555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34202826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandan JS, Brown KR, Simms-Williams N, et al. TLC Study . Non-Pharmacological Therapies for Post-Viral Syndromes, Including Long COVID: A Systematic Review. Int J Environ Res Public Health.
2023;20(4):3477. Accessed January 24, 2024. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36834176/ doi:10.3390/ijerph20043477
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9967466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36834176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veronese N, Bonica R, Cotugno S, et al. . Interventions for Improving Long COVID-19 Symptomatology: A Systematic Review. Viruses.
2022;14(9):1863. Accessed January 24, 2024. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36146672/ doi:10.3390/v14091863
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9502379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36146672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swainston K, Thursby S, Bell B, Poulter H, Dismore L, Copping L. What psychological interventions are effective for the management of persistent physical symptoms (PPS)? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Health Psychol [Internet]. 2023. Feb 1 [cited 2024 Jan 24];28(1):80. Available from: /pmc/articles/PMC10084386/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10084386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35837827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeDoux JE. The Emotional Brain: The Mysterious Underpinnings of Emotional Life. Simon &amp; Schuster; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenster R.J., Lebois L.A.M., Ressler K.J., Suh J. Brain circuit dysfunction in post-traumatic disorder: From mouse to man. National Review Neuroscience. 208, 19(9), 535-551. doi:10.1038/s41583-018-0039-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6148363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30054570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ader R, Cohen N. Psychoneuroimmunology: conditioning and stress. Annu Rev Psychol. 1993;44(1):53-85. PMID:8434895 doi:10.1146/annurev.ps.44.020193.000413</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8434895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grupe DW, Nitschke JB. Uncertainty is associated with biased expectancies and heightened responses to aversion. Emotion. 2011;11(2):413-424. doi:10.1037/a0022583</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3086262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21500909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandel ER, Schwartz JH, Jessell TM, Siegelbaum SA, Hudspeth AJ, Mack S, eds. Principles of neural science. 5th ed. McGraw-Hill Education; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledoux J. The emotional brain: The mysterious underpinnings of emotional life. (Phoenix). 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maren S. Neurobiology of Pavlovian fear conditioning. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2001;24(1):897-931. PMID:11520922 doi:10.1146/annurev.neuro.24.1.897</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11520922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chudler EH, Dong WK. The role of the basal ganglia in nociception and pain. Pain.
1995;60(1):3-38. Accessed December 22, 2023. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7715939/ doi:10.1016/0304-3959(94)00172-B
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7715939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin LM, Liberzon I. The neurocircuitry of fear, stress, and anxiety disorders. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2010;35(1):169-191. PMID:19625997 doi:10.1038/npp.2009.83</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3055419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19625997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. What is ME/CFS?
2023. https://www.cdc.gov/me-cfs/about/index.html#:~:text=An%20estimated%20836%2C000%20to%202.5,medical%20bills%20and%20lost%20incomes</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Onghia M, Ciaffi J, Ruscitti P, et al. . The economic burden of fibromyalgia: A systematic literature review. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2022;56:152060. PMID:35849890 doi:10.1016/j.semarthrit.2022.152060</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35849890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Fibromyalgia.
https://www.cdc.gov/arthritis/types/fibromyalgia.htm#:~:text=This%20is%20called%20abnormal%20pain,2%25%20of%20the%20adult%20population</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirin AA. A preliminary estimate of the economic impact of long COVID in the United States. Fatigue. 2022;10(4):190-199. doi:10.1080/21641846.2022.212 4064</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>