<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36304538</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2297-055X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in cardiovascular medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Cardiovasc Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The potential of heparin-induced extracorporeal LDL/fibrinogen precipitation (H.E.L.P.)-apheresis for patients with severe acute or chronic COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1007636</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1007636</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1007636</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fcvm.2022.1007636</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Patients with long COVID and acute COVID should benefit from treatment with H.E.L.P. apheresis, which is in clinical use for 37 years. COVID-19 can cause a severe acute multi-organ illness and, subsequently, in many patients the chronic illness long-COVID/PASC. The alveolar tissue and adjacent capillaries show inflammatory and procoagulatory activation with cell necrosis, thrombi, and massive fibrinoid deposits, namely, unsolvable microthrombi, which results in an obstructed gas exchange. Heparin-induced extracorporeal LDL/fibrinogen precipitation (H.E.L.P.) apheresis solves these problems by helping the entire macro- and microcirculation extracorporeally. It uses unfractionated heparin, which binds the spike protein and thereby should remove the virus (debris). It dissolves the forming microthrombi without bleeding risk. It removes large amounts of fibrinogen (coagulation protein), which immediately improves the oxygen supply in the capillaries. In addition, it removes the precursors of both the procoagulatory and the fibrinolytic cascade, thus de-escalating the entire hemostaseological system. It increases myocardial, cerebral, and pulmonary blood flow rates, and coronary flow reserve, facilitating oxygen exchange in the capillaries, without bleeding risks. Another factor in COVID is the "cytokine storm" harming microcirculation in the lungs and other organs. Intervention by H.E.L.P. apheresis could prevent uncontrollable coagulation and inflammatory activity by removing cytokines such as interleukin (IL)-6, IL-8, and TNF-&#x3b1;, and reduces C-reactive protein, and eliminating endo- and ecto-toxins, without touching protective IgM/IgG antibodies, leukocyte, or platelet function. The therapy can be used safely in combination with antiviral drugs, antibiotics, anticoagulants, or antihypertensive drugs. Long-term clinical experience with H.E.L.P. apheresis shows it cannot inflict harm upon patients with COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Jaeger, Arron, Kalka-Moll and Seidel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaeger</LastName><ForeName>Beate Roxane</ForeName><Initials>BR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lipidzentrum Nordrhein, M&#xfc;lheim, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arron</LastName><ForeName>Hayley Emma</ForeName><Initials>HE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiological Sciences, Faculty of Science, Stellenbosch University, Stellenbosch, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalka-Moll</LastName><ForeName>Wiltrud M</ForeName><Initials>WM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r infektiologische und mikrobiologische Beratung (Infactio&#xae;), Bedburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seidel</LastName><ForeName>Dietrich</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut t&#xfc;r Klinische Chemie und Laboratoriumsmedizin, Ludwig-Maximilians-Universit&#xe4;t M&#xfc;nchen, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Cardiovasc Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653388</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2297-055X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">H.E.L.P. apheresis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fibrinogen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heparin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rheology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Authors BJ and DS filed a patent of the use of HELP Apheresis for long COVID to avoid misuse. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36304538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9592739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2022.1007636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhou P, Yang XL, Wang XG, Hu B, Zhang L, Zhang W, et al. . A pneumonia outbreak associated with a new coronavirus of probable bat origin. Nature. (2020) 579:270&#x2013;3. 10.1038/s41586-020-2012-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-020-2012-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Zhou P, Wei Y, Yue H, Wang Y, Hu M, et al. . Histopathologic changes and SARS-CoV-2 immunostaining in the lung of a patient with COVID-19. Ann Intern Med. (2020) 172:629&#x2013;632. 10.7326/L20-0895</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/L20-0895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7081173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32163542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiologisches Bulletin 14/2020. Schwereeinsch&#xe4;tzung von COVID-19 mit Vergleichsdaten zu Pneumonien aus dem Krankenhaussentinel f&#xfc;r schwere akute Atemwegserkrankungen am RKI (ICOSARI) [Severity assessment of COVID-19 with comparative data on pneumonia from the hospital sentinel for severe acute respiratory diseases at the RKI (ICOSARI)]. (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatraju PK, Ghassemieh BJ, Nichols M, Kim R, Jerome KR, Nalla AK, et al. . Covid-19 in critically ill patients in the seattle region&#x2014;case series. NEJM. (2020) 382:2012&#x2013;2022. 10.1056/NEJMoa2004500</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2004500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7143164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32227758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga Z, Flammer AJ, Steiger P, Haberecker M, Andermatt R, Zinkernagel AS, et al. . Endothelial cell infection and endothelitis in COVID-19. Lancet. (2020) 395:1417&#x2013;1418. 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30937-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30937-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Moore MJ, Vasilieva N, Sui J, Wong SK, Berne MA, et al. . Angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 is a functional receptor for the SARS coronavirus. Nature. (2003) 426:450&#x2013;4. 10.1038/nature02145</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature02145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14647384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuba K, Imai Y, Rao S, Gao H, Guo F, Guan B, et al. . A crucial role of angiotensin converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) in SARS coronavirus-induced lung injury. Nat Med. (2005) 11:875&#x2013;9. 10.1038/nm1267</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm1267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16007097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M, Kleine-Weber H, Schroeder S, Kr&#xfc;ger N, Herrler T, Erichsen S, et al. . SARS-CoV-2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and is blocked by a clinically proven protease inhibitor. Cell. (2020) 181:271&#x2013;80.e8. 10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madjid M, Safavi-Naeini P, Solomon SD, Vardeny O. Potential effects of coronaviruses on the cardiovascular system: a review. JAMA Cardiol. (2020) 5:831&#x2013;40. 10.1001/jamacardio.2020.1286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2020.1286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32219363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo T, Fan Y, Chen M, Wu X, Zhang L, He T, et al. . Cardiovascular implications of fatal outcomes of patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiol. (2019) 5:811&#x2013;8. 10.1001/jamacardio.2020.1017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2020.1017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7101506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32219356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inciardi RM, Lupi L, Zaccone G, Italia L, Raffo M, Tomasoni D, et al. . Cardiac involvement in a patient with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiol. (2020) 5:819&#x2013;24. 10.1001/jamacardio.2020.1096</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2020.1096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7364333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32219357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Jin Z. An acute respiratory infection runs into the most common noncommunicable epidemic-COVID-19 and cardiovascular diseases. JAMA Cardiol. (2020) 5:743&#x2013;4. 10.1001/jamacardio.2020.0934</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2020.0934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32211809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parra-Medina R, Herrera S, Mejia J. Systematic review of microthrombi in COVID-19 autopsies. Acta Haematol. (2021) 144:476&#x2013;83. 10.1159/000515104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000515104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8089413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33873184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caputo I, Caroccia B, Frasson I, Poggio E, Zamberlan S, Morpurgo M, et al. . Angiotensin II promotes SARS-CoV-2 infection via upregulation of ACE2 in human bronchial cells. Int J Mol Sci. (2022) 23:5125. 10.3390/ijms23095125</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23095125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9102833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35563515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viles-Gonzalez JF, Fuster V, Badimon JJ. Links between inflammation and thrombogenicity in atherosclerosis. Curr Mol Med. (2006) 6:489&#x2013;99. 10.2174/156652406778018707</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/156652406778018707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16918370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morel O, Kessler L, Ohlmann P, Bareiss P. Diabetes and the platelet: toward new therapeutic paradigms for diabetic atherothrombosis. Atherosclerosis. (2010) 212:367&#x2013;76. 10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2010.03.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2010.03.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20394927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiva-Blanch G, Pe&#xf1;a E, Cubedo J, Garc&#xed;a-Arguinzonis M, Pan&#xe9; A, Gil PA, et al. . Molecular mapping of platelet hyperreactivity in diabetes: the stress proteins complex HSPA8/Hsp90/CSK2&#x3b1; and platelet aggregation in diabetic and normal platelets. Transl Res. (2021) 235:1&#x2013;14. 10.1016/j.trsl.2021.04.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trsl.2021.04.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Q, Wang B, Mao J. The pathogenesis and treatment of the &#x2018;Cytokine Storm&#x2019; in COVID-19. J. Infect. (2020) 80:607&#x2013;13. 10.1016/j.jinf.2020.03.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2020.03.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32283152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mycroft-West C, Su D, Elli S, Guimond S, Miller G, Turnbull J, et al. . The 2019 coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) surface protein (Spike) S1 receptor binding domain undergoes conformational change upon heparin binding. BioRxiv. (2020). 10.1101/2020.02.29.971093</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.02.29.971093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araos J, Alegr&#xed;a L, Garc&#xed;a P, Damiani F, Tapia P, Soto D, et al. . Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation improves survival in a novel 24-hour pig model of severe acute respiratory distress syndrome. Am J Transl Res. (2016) 8:2826&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4931177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27398166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neto AS, Schmidt M, Azevedo LCP, Bein T, Brochard L, Beutel G, et al. . Associations between ventilator settings during extracorporeal membrane oxygenation for refractory hypoxemia and outcome in patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome: a pooled individual patient data analysis. Intensive Care Med. (2016) 42:1672&#x2013;84. 10.1007/s00134-016-4507-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-016-4507-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27586996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helmerhorst HJ, Schultz MJ, van der Voort PH, de Jonge E, van Westerloo DJ. Bench-to-bedside review: the effects of hyperoxia during critical illness. Crit Care. (2015) 19:284. 10.1186/s13054-015-0996-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-015-0996-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4538738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26278383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helmerhorst HJ, Roos-Blom MJ, van Westerloo DJ, de Jonge E. Association between arterial hyperoxia and outcome in subsets of critical illness: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression of cohort studies. Crit Care Med. (2015) 43:1508&#x2013;19. 10.1097/CCM.0000000000000998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0000000000000998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25855899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenhauer T, Armstrong VW, Wieland H, Fuchs C, Nebendahl K, Scheler F, et al. . Selective continuous elimination of low density lipoproteins (LDL) by heparin precipitation: first clinical application. Trans Am Soc Artif Organs. (1986) 32:104&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3778691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidel D, Armstrong VW, Schuff-Werner P, Eisenhauer T. Removal of low-density lipoproteins (LDL) and fibrinogen by precipitation with heparin at low pH: clinical application and experience. J Clin Apheresis. (1988) 4:78&#x2013;81. 10.1002/jca.2920040207</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jca.2920040207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3294231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidel D, Armstrong VW, Schuff-Werner P. The HELP-LDL-Apheresis multicentre study, an angiographically assessed trial on the role of LDL-apheresis in the secondary prevention of coronary heart disease. I evaluation of safety and cholesterol-lowering effects during the first 12 months. Eur J Clin Inv. (1991) 21:375&#x2013;83. 10.1111/j.1365-2362.1991.tb01384.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2362.1991.tb01384.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1936104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuff-Werner P, Gohlke H, Bartmann U, Baggio G, Corti MC, Dinsenbacher A, et al. . The HELP-LDL-apheresis multicentre study, an angiographically assessed trial on the role of LDL-apheresis in the secondary prevention of coronary heart disease. II Final evaluation of the effect of regular treatment on LDL-cholesterol plasma concentrations and the Course of Coronary Heart Disease. Eur J Clin Invest. (1994) 24:724&#x2013;32. 10.1111/j.1365-2362.1994.tb01068.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2362.1994.tb01068.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7890009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiery J, Walli AK, Janning G, Seidel D. Low-density lipoprotein plasmaphaeresis with and without lovastatin in the treatment of the homozygous form of familial hypercholesterolaemia. Eur J Pediatr. (1990) 149:716&#x2013;21. 10.1007/BF01959530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01959530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2209665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaeger BR, Tsobanelis T, Bengel F, Schwaiger M, Seidel D. Long-term prevention of premature coronary atherosclerosis in homozygous familial hypercholesterolemia. J Pediatrics. (2002) 141:125&#x2013;8. 10.1067/mpd.2002.124384</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12091863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellwig KP, Schmidt HK, Brettschneider-Meyer A, Meyer H, Jaeger BR, Walli AK, et al. . Coronary heart disease in childhood in familial hypercholesteremia. Maximum therapy with LDL apheresis. Internist. (2003) 44:476&#x2013;80. 10.1007/s00108-002-0832-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12914404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuff-Werner P. Clinical Long-Term Results of H.E.L.P.-Apheresis. Z Kardiol. (2003) 92: III 28&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14663598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaeger BR, Richter Y, Nagel D, Heigl F, Vogt A, Roeseler E, et al. . Longitudinal cohort study on the effectiveness of lipid apheresis treatment to reduce high lipoprotein (a) levels and prevent major adverse coronary events. Nat Clin Pract Cardiovasc Med. (2009) 6:229&#x2013;39. 10.1038/ncpcardio1456</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncpcardio1456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19234501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaeger BR, Bengel FM, Odaka K, Uberfuhr P, Labarrere CA, Bengsch S, et al. . Changes in myocardial vasoreactivity after drastic reduction of plasma fibrinogen and cholesterol: a clinical study in long-term heart transplant survivors using positron emission tomography. J Heart Lung Transplant. (2005) 24:2022&#x2013;30. 10.1016/j.healun.2005.05.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.healun.2005.05.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16364844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JW, Merz M, Braun P. Regression of transplant coronary artery disease during low-density lipoprotein apheresis. JHLT. (1997) 16:290&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9087872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaeger BR, Meiser B, Nagel D, Uberfuhr P, Thiery J, Brandl U, et al. . Aggressive lowering of fibrinogen and cholesterol in the prevention of graft vessel disease after heart transplantation. Circulation. (1997) 96: II 154&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9386091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaeger BR, Braun P, Nagel D, Park JW, Gysan DB, Oberhoffer M, et al. . A combined treatment of statins and HELP apheresis for treatment of cardiac allograft vasculopathy. Atherosclerosis Suppl. (2002) 141:331&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labarrere CA, Woods JR, Hardin JW, Campana GL, Ortiz MA, Jaeger BR, et al. . Early Prediction of cardiac allograft vasculopathy and heart transplant failure. Am J Transplant. (2011) 11:528&#x2013;35. 10.1111/j.1600-6143.2010.03401.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-6143.2010.03401.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21219580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labarrere CA, Woods JR, Hardin JW, Jaeger BR, Zembala M, Deng MC, et al. . Early inflammatory markers are independent predictors of cardiac allograft vasculopathy in heart-transplant recipients. PLoS ONE. (2014) 9:e113260. 10.1371/journal.pone.0113260</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0113260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4260824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25490200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labarrere CA, Jaeger BR, Kassab GS. Cardiac allograft vasculopathy: microvascular arteriolar capillaries (Capioles) and survival. Front Biosc. (2017) 9:110&#x2013;28. 10.2741/e790</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2741/e790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27814594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberhoffer M, Eifert S, Jaeger B, Blessing F, Beiras-Fernandez A, Seidel D, et al. . Postoperative heparin-mediated extracorporeal low-density lipoprotein fibrinogen precipitation aphaeresis prevents early graft occlusion after coronary artery bypass grafting. Surg J. (2016) 2:e5&#x2013;9. 10.1055/s-0036-1584167</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0036-1584167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5553466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28824983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Walli AK, Schulze A, Blessing F, Fraunberger P, Thaler C, et al. . Heparin-mediated extracorporeal low density lipoprotein precipitation as a possible therapeutic approach in preeclampsia. Transfus Apheres Sci. (2006) 35:103&#x2013;10. 10.1016/j.transci.2006.05.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.transci.2006.05.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17081803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contini C, P&#xfc;tz G, Pecks U, Winkler K. Apheresis as emerging treatment option in severe early onset preeclampsia. Atheroscler Suppl. (2019) 40:61&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.atherosclerosissup.2019.08.028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atherosclerosissup.2019.08.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31818451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walzl M, Lechner H, Walzl B, Schied G. Improved neurological recovery of cerebral infarctions after plasmapheretic reduction of lipids and fibrinogen. Stroke. (1993) 24:1447&#x2013;51. 10.1161/01.STR.24.10.1447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.STR.24.10.1447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8378944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walzl B, Walzl M, Valetitsch H, Lechner H. Increased cerebral perfusion following reduction of fibrinogen and lipid fractions. Haemostasis. (1995) 25:137&#x2013;43. 10.1159/000217153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000217153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7607582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaeger BR. The HELP System for the treatment of atherothrombotic disorders: a review. Therap Apheres Dialy. (2003) 7:391&#x2013;6. 10.1046/j.1526-0968.2003.00072.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1526-0968.2003.00072.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12887720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaeger BR, Kreuzer E, Knez A, Leber A, Uberfuhr P, B&#xf6;rner M, et al. . Case reports on emergency treatment of cardiovascular syndromes through heparin-mediated low-density lipoprotein/fibrinogen precipitation: a new approach to augment cerebral and myocardial salvage. Therap Apheres. (2002) 6:394&#x2013;98. 10.1046/j.1526-0968.2002.00427.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1526-0968.2002.00427.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12423536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan TZ, Pottle A, Pennell DJ, Barbir MS. The impact of lipoprotein apheresis in patients with refractory angina and raised Lipoprotein(a): objectives and methods of a randomised controlled trial. Atheroscler Suppl. (2015) 18:103&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.atherosclerosissup.2015.02.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atherosclerosissup.2015.02.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25936312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bengsch S, Boos KS, Nagel D, Seidel D, Inthorn D. Extracorporeal plasma treatment for the removal of endotoxin in patients with sepsis: clinical results of a pilot study. Shock. (2005) 23:494&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15897800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samtleben W, Bengsch S, Boos KS, Seidel D. HELP Apheresis in the treatment of sepsis. Artif Organs. (1998) 22:43&#x2013;6. 10.1046/j.1525-1594.1998.06011.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1525-1594.1998.06011.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9456225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaeger BR, Goehring P, Schirmer J, Uhrig S, Lohse P, Kreuzer E, et al. . Consistent lowering of clotting factors for the treatment of acute cardiovascular syndromes and hypercoagulability: a different pathophysiological approach. Therap Apheres. (2001) 5:252&#x2013;9. 10.1046/j.1526-0968.2001.00350.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1526-0968.2001.00350.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11724509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaeger BR, Labarrere CA. Fibrinogen and atherothrombosis: vulnerable plaque or vulnerable patient? Herz. (2003) 28:530-8. 10.1007/s00059-003-2497-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00059-003-2497-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14569394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paiardi G, Richter S, Oreste P, Urbinati C, Rusnati M, Wade RC. The binding of heparin to spike glycoprotein inhibits SARS-CoV-02 infection by three mechanisms. J Biol Chem. (2022) 298:101507. 10.1016/j.jbc.2021.101507</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbc.2021.101507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8683219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34929169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellwig KP, Baller D, Gleichmann U, Moll D, Betker S, Weise R, et al. . Improvement of coronary vasodilatation capacity through single LDL apheresis. Atherosclerosis. (1998) 139:173&#x2013;8. 10.1016/S0021-9150(98)00055-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0021-9150(98)00055-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9699905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfefferkorn TK, Kn&#xfc;ppel HP, Jaeger BR, Thiery J, Hamann GF. Increased cerebral CO2 reactivity after heparin-mediated extracorporeal LDL precipitation (HELP) in patients with coronary heart disease and hyperlipidemia. Stroke. (1999) 30:1802&#x2013;6. 10.1161/01.STR.30.9.1802</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.STR.30.9.1802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10471427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Personal observation of Dr Beate R . Jaeger</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss P. The T cell immune response against SARS-CoV-2. Nat Immunol. (2022) 23:186&#x2013;93. 10.1038/s41590-021-01122-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-021-01122-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grobbelaar LM, Venter C, Vlok M, Ngoepe M, Laubscher GJ, Lourens PJ, et al. . SARS-CoV-2 spike protein S1 induces fibrin(ogen)resistent to fibrinolysis: implications for microclot formation in COVID-19. Biosci Rep. (2021) 41:BSR20210611. 10.1042/BSR20210611</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/BSR20210611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8380922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34328172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E, Vlok M, Venter C, Bezuidenhout JA, Laubscher GJ, Steenkamp J, et al. . Persistent clotting protein pathology in long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) is accompanied by increased levels of antiplasmin. Cardiovasc Diabetol. (2021) 20:172. 10.1186/s12933-021-01359-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-021-01359-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8381139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34425843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrara JL, Abhyankar S, Gilliland DG: Cytokine storm of graft-versus-host disease: a critical effector role for interleukin-1. Transplant Proc. (1993) 2:1216&#x2013;1217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8442093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinrich PC, Behrmann I, Haan S, Hermanns HM, M&#xfc;ller-Newen G, Schaper F. Principles of interleukin (IL)-6-type cytokine signalling and its regulation. Biochem J. (2003) 374:1&#x2013;20. 10.1042/bj20030407</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/bj20030407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1223585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12773095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones SA, Novick D, Horiuchi S, Yamamoto N, Szalai AJ, Fuller GM. C-reactive protein: a physiological activator of interleukin-6 receptor shedding. J Exp Med. (1999) 189:599&#x2013;604. 10.1084/jem.189.3.599</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1084/jem.189.3.599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2192917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9927522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiusa MML, Carvalho-Filho MA, Annichino-Bizzacchi JM, De Paula EV. Causes and consequences of coagulation activation in sepsis: an evolutionary medicine perspective. BMJ Med. (2015) 13:105. 10.1186/s12916-015-0327-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-015-0327-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4422540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25943883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): an overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front Microbiol. (2021) 12:1494. 10.3389/fmicb.2021.698169</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2021.698169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna C, Cristoni S, Petrillo M, Querci M, Piazza O, Van den Eede G. Toxin-like peptides in plasma, urine and faecal samples from COVID-19 patients. F1000Res. (2021) 10:550. 10.12688/f1000research.54306.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/f1000research.54306.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8772524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35106136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon JH, Lee C. Cholesterol is important for the entry process of porcine deltacoronavirus. Arch Virol. (2018) 163:3119&#x2013;24. 10.1007/s00705-018-3967-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00705-018-3967-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7087128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30051343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>