<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39474404</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2219-2840</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>37</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of gastroenterology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID and gut candidiasis: What is the existing relationship?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4104</StartPage><EndPage>4114</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4104-4114</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3748/wjg.v30.i37.4104</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Since the beginning of the coronavirus disease (COVID) 2019 pandemic, thousands of articles on the topic have been published, and although there is a growing trend of research on another associated condition, long coronavirus disease, important points still remain to be clarified in this respect. Robust evidence has suggested a relevant link between new clinical discoveries and molecular mechanisms that could be associated with the manifestations of different signs and symptoms involving cases of long COVID. However, one of the existing gaps that requires further investigation concerns a possible relationship between gut candidiasis and long COVID. While recent studies also suggest an interplay between the occurrence of these two conditions, it is not yet fully clear how this may happen, as well as the specifics regarding the possible pathophysiological mechanisms involved. In this connection and with the advent of a potential strengthening of the body of evidence supporting the hypothesis of a link between gut candidiasis and long COVID, a better understanding of the clinical presentation, pathophysiology and clinical management of such a relationship should be essential and useful for both, additional advances towards more targeted research and appropriate case management. Knowing more about the signs, symptoms, and complications associated with cases of long COVID is essential in order to more effectively mitigate the related burden and provide a higher quality of care and life for the affected population. In light of this and the need for better outcomes, here we review and discuss the content on different aspects of long COVID, including its pathophysiology and the existing evidence of a potential relationship between such a condition and gut candidiasis, as well as suggest propositions for future related research.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2024. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bistagnino</LastName><ForeName>Filippo</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biotechnology and Translational Medicine, International Medical School, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Milan 20054, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pizzi</LastName><ForeName>Davide</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biotechnology and Translational Medicine, International Medical School, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Milan 20054, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mantovani</LastName><ForeName>Filippo</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biotechnology and Translational Medicine, International Medical School, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Milan 20054, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Antonino</LastName><ForeName>Jacopo Rosso</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Milan 20133, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tovani-Palone</LastName><ForeName>Marcos Roberto</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research Analytics, Saveetha Dental College and Hospitals, Saveetha Institute of Medical and Technical Sciences, Chennai 600077, India. marcos_palone@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Gastroenterol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1007-9327</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002177" MajorTopicYN="Y">Candidiasis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005767" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Candidiasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal microbiome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article. Tovani-Palone MR discontinued his affiliation with SRM College of Pharmacy, SRM Institute of Science and Technology, Kattankulathur, India.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39474404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11514539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v30.i37.4104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization.  A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. [cited 27 May 2024]. Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carod-Artal FJ. Post-COVID-19 syndrome: epidemiology, diagnostic criteria and pathogenic mechanisms involved. Rev Neurol. 2021;72:384&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34042167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Desai AD, Wan EY. Post-COVID-19 Condition. Annu Rev Med. 2023;74:55&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35914765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozlova O, Burygina E, Khostelidi S, Shadrivova O, Saturnov A, Gusev D, Rysev A, Zavrazhnov A, Vashukova M, Pichugina G, Mitichkin M, Kovyrshin S, Bogomolova T, Borzova Y, Oganesyan E, Vasilyeva N, Klimko N Working Group. Invasive Candidiasis in Adult Patients with COVID-19: Results of a Multicenter Study in St. Petersburg, Russia. J Fungi (Basel) 2023;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10532874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37755035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adzic-Vukicevic T, Velickovic J, Radovanovic-Spurnic A, Velickovic D, Milenkovic S, Petrovic F, Micic J, Dragutinovic N. Fatal invasive candidiasis in COVID-19 patient with severe bleeding and extensively drug-resistant Klebsiella enterobacter. J Infect Dev Ctries. 2022;16:1025&#x2013;1029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35797297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nambiar M, Varma SR, Jaber M, Sreelatha SV, Thomas B, Nair AS. Mycotic infections-mucormycosis and oral candidiasis associated with Covid-19: a significant and challenging association. J Oral Microbiol. 2021;13:1967699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8436966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34527182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kusakabe T, Lin WY, Cheong JG, Singh G, Ravishankar A, Yeung ST, Mesko M, DeCelie MB, Carriche G, Zhao Z, Rand S, Doron I, Putzel GG, Worgall S, Cushing M, Westblade L, Inghirami G, Parkhurst CN, Guo CJ, Schotsaert M, Garc&#xed;a-Sastre A, Josefowicz SZ, Salvatore M, Iliev ID. Fungal microbiota sustains lasting immune activation of neutrophils and their progenitors in severe COVID-19. Nat Immunol. 2023;24:1879&#x2013;1889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10805066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37872315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aishwarya S, Gunasekaran K. Meta-analysis of the microbial biomarkers in the gut-lung crosstalk in COVID-19, community-acquired pneumonia and Clostridium difficile infections. Lett Appl Microbiol. 2022;75:1293&#x2013;1306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9539240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35920823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization.  Post COVID-19 condition (Long COVID). [cited 27 May 2024]. Available from: https://www.who.int/europe/news-room/fact-sheets/item/post-COVID-19-condition .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV, Jayadevan R, Sashidharan S. Long COVID: An overview. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15:869&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2020-Dec-18 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi G, Sanchis-Gomar F, Henry BM. COVID-19 and its long-term sequelae: what do we know in 2023? Pol Arch Intern Med. 2023;133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36626183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global Prevalence of Post-Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Condition or Long COVID: A Meta-Analysis and Systematic Review. J Infect Dis. 2022;226:1593&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizvi A, Ziv Y, Crawford JM, Trindade AJ. Gastrointestinal and Hepatobiliary Symptoms and Disorders with Long (Chronic) COVID Infection. Gastroenterol Clin North Am. 2023;52:139&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9940919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36813422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan A, Shetty A, Delanerolle G, Zeng Y, Zhang Y, Raymont V, Rathod S, Halabi S, Elliot K, Shi JQ, Phiri P. A systematic review and meta-analysis of long COVID symptoms. Syst Rev. 2023;12:88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10220332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37245047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su S, Zhao Y, Zeng N, Liu X, Zheng Y, Sun J, Zhong Y, Wu S, Ni S, Gong Y, Zhang Z, Gao N, Yuan K, Yan W, Shi L, Ravindran AV, Kosten T, Shi J, Bao Y, Lu L. Epidemiology, clinical presentation, pathophysiology, and management of long COVID: an update. Mol Psychiatry. 2023;28:4056&#x2013;4069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37491461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond) 2021;53:737&#x2013;754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkodaymi MS, Omrani OA, Fawzy NA, Shaar BA, Almamlouk R, Riaz M, Obeidat M, Obeidat Y, Gerberi D, Taha RM, Kashour Z, Kashour T, Berbari EF, Alkattan K, Tleyjeh IM. Prevalence of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome symptoms at different follow-up periods: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28:657&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8812092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuin M, Rigatelli G, Battisti V, Costola G, Roncon L, Bilato C. Increased risk of acute myocardial infarction after COVID-19 recovery: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Cardiol. 2023;372:138&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9755219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36535564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai H, Yang M, Sun M, Pan B, Wang Q, Wang J, Tian J, Ding G, Yang K, Song X, Ge L. Risk of incident diabetes after COVID-19 infection: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Metabolism. 2022;137:155330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9546784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36220361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuin M, Rigatelli G, Bilato C, Pasquetto G, Mazza A. Risk of Incident New-Onset Arterial Hypertension After COVID-19 Recovery: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. High Blood Press Cardiovasc Prev. 2023;30:227&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10105348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37060396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chee YJ, Fan BE, Young BE, Dalan R, Lye DC. Clinical trials on the pharmacological treatment of long COVID: A systematic review. J Med Virol. 2023;95:e28289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9878018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36349400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fawzy NA, Abou Shaar B, Taha RM, Arabi TZ, Sabbah BN, Alkodaymi MS, Omrani OA, Makhzoum T, Almahfoudh NE, Al-Hammad QA, Hejazi W, Obeidat Y, Osman N, Al-Kattan KM, Berbari EF, Tleyjeh IM. A systematic review of trials currently investigating therapeutic modalities for post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and registered on WHO International Clinical Trials Platform. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2023;29:570&#x2013;577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9837206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36642173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi YJ, Seo YB, Seo JW, Lee J, Nham E, Seong H, Yoon JG, Noh JY, Cheong HJ, Kim WJ, Kim EJ, Song JY. Effectiveness of Antiviral Therapy on Long COVID: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Clin Med. 2023;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10707593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38068427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Kulzhabayeva D, Rodrigues NB, Di Vincenzo JD, Gill H, Subramaniapillai M, Lui LMW, Cao B, Mansur RB, Ho RC, Burke MJ, Rhee TG, Rosenblat JD, McIntyre RS. COVID-19 vaccination for the prevention and treatment of long COVID: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun. 2023;111:211&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10067136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36990297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao P, Liu J, Liu M. Effect of COVID-19 Vaccines on Reducing the Risk of Long COVID in the Real World: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9566528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36231717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haunhorst S, Bloch W, Wagner H, Ellert C, Kr&#xfc;ger K, Vilser DC, Finke K, Reuken P, Pletz MW, Stallmach A, Puta C. Long COVID: a narrative review of the clinical aftermaths of COVID-19 with a focus on the putative pathophysiology and aspects of physical activity. Oxf Open Immunol. 2022;3:iqac006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9494493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36846561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altmann DM, Whettlock EM, Liu S, Arachchillage DJ, Boyton RJ. The immunology of long COVID. Nat Rev Immunol. 2023;23:618&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37433988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin JX, Agbana YL, Sun ZS, Fei SW, Zhao HQ, Zhou XN, Chen JH, Kassegne K. Increased interleukin-6 is associated with long COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Infect Dis Poverty. 2023;12:43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10123579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37095536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas M, Rodr&#xed;guez Y, Acosta-Ampudia Y, Monsalve DM, Zhu C, Li QZ, Ram&#xed;rez-Santana C, Anaya JM. Autoimmunity is a hallmark of post-COVID syndrome. J Transl Med. 2022;20:129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8924736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35296346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son K, Jamil R, Chowdhury A, Mukherjee M, Venegas C, Miyasaki K, Zhang K, Patel Z, Salter B, Yuen ACY, Lau KS, Cowbrough B, Radford K, Huang C, Kjarsgaard M, Dvorkin-Gheva A, Smith J, Li QZ, Waserman S, Ryerson CJ, Nair P, Ho T, Balakrishnan N, Nazy I, Bowdish DME, Svenningsen S, Carlsten C, Mukherjee M. Circulating anti-nuclear autoantibodies in COVID-19 survivors predict long COVID symptoms. Eur Respir J. 2023;61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9515477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36137590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung CCL, Goh D, Lim X, Tien TZ, Lim JCT, Lee JN, Tan B, Tay ZEA, Wan WY, Chen EX, Nerurkar SN, Loong S, Cheow PC, Chan CY, Koh YX, Tan TT, Kalimuddin S, Tai WMD, Ng JL, Low JG, Yeong J, Lim KH. Residual SARS-CoV-2 viral antigens detected in GI and hepatic tissues from five recovered patients with COVID-19. Gut. 2022;71:226&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34083386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J, Wood J, Jaycox JR, Dhodapkar RM, Lu P, Gehlhausen JR, Tabachnikova A, Greene K, Tabacof L, Malik AA, Silva Monteiro V, Silva J, Kamath K, Zhang M, Dhal A, Ott IM, Valle G, Pe&#xf1;a-Hern&#xe1;ndez M, Mao T, Bhattacharjee B, Takahashi T, Lucas C, Song E, McCarthy D, Breyman E, Tosto-Mancuso J, Dai Y, Perotti E, Akduman K, Tzeng TJ, Xu L, Geraghty AC, Monje M, Yildirim I, Shon J, Medzhitov R, Lutchmansingh D, Possick JD, Kaminski N, Omer SB, Krumholz HM, Guan L, Dela Cruz CS, van Dijk D, Ring AM, Putrino D, Iwasaki A. Distinguishing features of long COVID identified through immune profiling. Nature. 2023;623:139&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10620090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37748514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Alberts J, Oben J, Cuthbertson DJ, Wootton D, Crooks M, Gabbay M, Brady M, Hishmeh L, Attree E, Heightman M, Banerjee R, Banerjee A COVERSCAN study investigators. Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e048391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vassiliou AG, Vrettou CS, Keskinidou C, Dimopoulou I, Kotanidou A, Orfanos SE. Endotheliopathy in Acute COVID-19 and Long COVID. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10179170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37175942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molnar T, Lehoczki A, Fekete M, Varnai R, Zavori L, Erdo-Bonyar S, Simon D, Berki T, Csecsei P, Ezer E. Mitochondrial dysfunction in long COVID: mechanisms, consequences, and potential therapeutic approaches. Geroscience. 2024;46:5267&#x2013;5286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11336094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38668888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Zhou Y, Ma Y, Chen P, Tang J, Yang B, Li H, Liang M, Xue Y, Liu Y, Zhang J, Wang X. Gut Microbiota Dysbiosis Correlates With Long COVID-19 at One-Year After Discharge. J Korean Med Sci. 2023;38:e120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10111044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37069814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berezhnoy G, Bissinger R, Liu A, Cannet C, Sch&#xe4;fer H, Kienzle K, Bitzer M, H&#xe4;berle H, G&#xf6;pel S, Trautwein C, Singh Y. Maintained imbalance of triglycerides, apolipoproteins, energy metabolites and cytokines in long-term COVID-19 syndrome patients. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1144224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10203989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37228606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giunta S, Giordani C, De Luca M, Olivieri F. Long-COVID-19 autonomic dysfunction: An integrated view in the framework of inflammaging. Mech Ageing Dev. 2024;218:111915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38354789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchegiani F, Recchioni R, Marcheselli F, Di Rosa M, Sabbatinelli J, Matacchione G, Giuliani A, Ramini D, Stripoli P, Biscetti L, Pelliccioni G, Sarzani R, Spannella F, Cherubini A, Corsonello A, Procopio AD, Bonfigli AR, Bonaf&#xe8; M, Lattanzio F, Olivieri F. Association of admission serum levels of neurofilament light chain and in-hospital mortality in geriatric patients with COVID-19. J Neurol. 2023;270:37&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9483416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36114298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diar Bakerly N, Smith N, Darbyshire JL, Kwon J, Bullock E, Baley S, Sivan M, Delaney B. Pathophysiological Mechanisms in Long COVID: A Mixed Method Systematic Review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2024;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11050596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38673384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong SH, Lui RN, Sung JJ. Covid-19 and the digestive system. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;35:744&#x2013;748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong ZY, Xiang BJ, Jiang M, Sun MJ, Dai C. The Prevalence of Gastrointestinal Symptoms, Abnormal Liver Function, Digestive System Disease and Liver Disease in COVID-19 Infection: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2021;55:67&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7713642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33116063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JG, Cui HR, Tang HB, Deng XL. Gastrointestinal symptoms and fecal nucleic acid testing of children with 2019 coronavirus disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2020;10:17846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7576139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33082472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobel YR, Phipps M, Zucker J, Lebwohl B, Wang TC, Sobieszczyk ME, Freedberg DE. Gastrointestinal Symptoms and Coronavirus Disease 2019: A Case-Control Study From the United States. Gastroenterology. 2020;159:373&#x2013;375.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7152871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32294477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cholankeril G, Podboy A, Aivaliotis VI, Pham EA, Spencer SP, Kim D, Ahmed A. Association of Digestive Symptoms and Hospitalization in Patients With SARS-CoV-2 Infection. Am J Gastroenterol. 2020;115:1129&#x2013;1132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7302101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32618665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Navarro-Pardo E, Torres-Macho J, Guijarro C, Pellicer-Valero OJ. Exploring the recovery curve for gastrointestinal symptoms from the acute COVID-19 phase to long-term post-COVID: The LONG-COVID-EXP-CM Multicenter Study. J Med Virol. 2022;94:2925&#x2013;2927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9088575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35315087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedberg DE, Chang L. Gastrointestinal symptoms in COVID-19: the long and the short of it. Curr Opin Gastroenterol. 2022;38:555&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36165028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghoshal UC, Ghoshal U. Gastrointestinal involvement in post-acute Coronavirus disease (COVID)-19 syndrome. Curr Opin Infect Dis. 2023;36:366&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37606895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siah KTH, Mahadeva S. Post-COVID-19 functional gastrointestinal disorders: Prepare for a GI aftershock. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;37:413&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35258135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbara G, Grover M, Bercik P, Corsetti M, Ghoshal UC, Ohman L, Rajili&#x107;-Stojanovi&#x107; M. Rome Foundation Working Team Report on Post-Infection Irritable Bowel Syndrome. Gastroenterology. 2019;156:46&#x2013;58.e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6309514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30009817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Q, Fan L, Liu W, Li J, Yue J, Wang M, Ke X, Yin Y, Chen Q, Jiang C. Direct Evidence of Active SARS-CoV-2 Replication in the Intestine. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:361&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32638022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamming I, Timens W, Bulthuis ML, Lely AT, Navis G, van Goor H. Tissue distribution of ACE2 protein, the functional receptor for SARS coronavirus. A first step in understanding SARS pathogenesis. J Pathol. 2004;203:631&#x2013;637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7167720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15141377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein SR, Ramelli SC, Grazioli A, Chung JY, Singh M, Yinda CK, Winkler CW, Sun J, Dickey JM, Ylaya K, Ko SH, Platt AP, Burbelo PD, Quezado M, Pittaluga S, Purcell M, Munster VJ, Belinky F, Ramos-Benitez MJ, Boritz EA, Lach IA, Herr DL, Rabin J, Saharia KK, Madathil RJ, Tabatabai A, Soherwardi S, McCurdy MT NIH COVID-19 Autopsy Consortium, Peterson KE, Cohen JI, de Wit E, Vannella KM, Hewitt SM, Kleiner DE, Chertow DS. SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence in the human body and brain at autopsy. Nature. 2022;612:758&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9749650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36517603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britton GJ, Chen-Liaw A, Cossarini F, Livanos AE, Spindler MP, Plitt T, Eggers J, Mogno I, Gonzalez-Reiche AS, Siu S, Tankelevich M, Grinspan LT, Dixon RE, Jha D, van de Guchte A, Khan Z, Martinez-Delgado G, Amanat F, Hoagland DA, tenOever BR, Dubinsky MC, Merad M, van Bakel H, Krammer F, Bongers G, Mehandru S, Faith JJ. Limited intestinal inflammation despite diarrhea, fecal viral RNA and SARS-CoV-2-specific IgA in patients with acute COVID-19. Sci Rep. 2021;11:13308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8233421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34172783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva Andrade B, Siqueira S, de Assis Soares WR, de Souza Rangel F, Santos NO, Dos Santos Freitas A, Ribeiro da Silveira P, Tiwari S, Alzahrani KJ, G&#xf3;es-Neto A, Azevedo V, Ghosh P, Barh D. Long-COVID and Post-COVID Health Complications: An Up-to-Date Review on Clinical Conditions and Their Possible Molecular Mechanisms. Viruses. 2021;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Q, Wang B, Zhang T, Xu J, Shang S. The mechanism and treatment of gastrointestinal symptoms in patients with COVID-19. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2020;319:G245&#x2013;G252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7414235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32639848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Zhang W, Guo M, Xiao C, Fu Z, Yu S, Jiang L, Wang S, Ling Y, Liu F, Tan Y, Chen S. Integrated analysis of gut microbiome and host immune responses in COVID-19. Front Med. 2022;16:263&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8902486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35258762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Mental Disorders Collaborators. Global prevalence and burden of depressive and anxiety disorders in 204 countries and territories in 2020 due to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet. 2021;398:1700&#x2013;1712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34634250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker CH, Naliboff BD, Shih W, Presson AP, Videlock EJ, Mayer EA, Chang L. Negative Events During Adulthood Are Associated With Symptom Severity and Altered Stress Response in Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;17:2245&#x2013;2252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6609507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30616026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luscombe FA. Health-related quality of life and associated psychosocial factors in irritable bowel syndrome: a review. Qual Life Res. 2000;9:161&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10983480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almario CV, Makaroff K, Alvarez G, Chey WD, Spiegel B. S496 Examining the Impact of the COVID-19 Pandemic on the Prevalence of Rome IV Functional Gastrointestinal Disorders. Am J Gastroenterol. 2021;116:S220&#x2013;S221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackett JW, Wainberg M, Elkind MSV, Freedberg DE. Potential Long Coronavirus Disease 2019 Gastrointestinal Symptoms 6 Months After Coronavirus Infection Are Associated With Mental Health Symptoms. Gastroenterology. 2022;162:648&#x2013;650.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8556689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34728186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulain D. Candida albicans, plasticity and pathogenesis. Crit Rev Microbiol. 2015;41:208&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23962107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basmaciyan L, Bon F, Paradis T, Lapaquette P, Dalle F. "Candida Albicans Interactions With The Host: Crossing The Intestinal Epithelial Barrier". Tissue Barriers. 2019;7:1612661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6619947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31189436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawhara S. How Gut Bacterial Dysbiosis Can Promote Candida albicans Overgrowth during Colonic Inflammation. Microorganisms. 2022;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9147621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35630457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voss A, Hollis RJ, Pfaller MA, Wenzel RP, Doebbeling BN. Investigation of the sequence of colonization and candidemia in nonneutropenic patients. J Clin Microbiol. 1994;32:975&#x2013;980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC267165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8027353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan L, Yang C, Tang J. Disruption of the intestinal mucosal barrier in Candida albicans infections. Microbiol Res. 2013;168:389&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23545353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy MJ. Regulation of Candida albicans populations in the gastrointestinal tract: mechanisms and significance in GI and systemic candidiasis. Curr Top Med Mycol. 1989;3:315&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2688919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corey L, Beyrer C, Cohen MS, Michael NL, Bedford T, Rolland M. SARS-CoV-2 Variants in Patients with Immunosuppression. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:562&#x2013;566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8494465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34347959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Lau RI, Liu Q, Su Q, Chan FKL, Ng SC. Gut microbiota in COVID-19: key microbial changes, potential mechanisms and clinical applications. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2023;20:323&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9589856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36271144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cater RE 2nd. Chronic intestinal candidiasis as a possible etiological factor in the chronic fatigue syndrome. Med Hypotheses. 1995;44:507&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7476598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segrelles-Calvo G, de S Ara&#xfa;jo GR, Llopis-Pastor E, Carrillo J, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Hern&#xe1;ndez M, Rey L, Melean NR, Escribano I, Ant&#xf3;n E, Zamarro C, Garc&#xed;a-Salmones M, Frases S. Candida spp. co-infection in COVID-19 patients with severe pneumonia: Prevalence study and associated risk factors. Respir Med. 2021;188:106619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8445759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34555702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altinkaya &#xc7;avu&#x15f; M, Sav H. Opportunistic Candida Infections in Critical COVID-19 Patients. Pol J Microbiol. 2022;71:411&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9608158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36185025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo T, Zhan H, Zhang F, Liu Q, Tso EYK, Lui GCY, Chen N, Li A, Lu W, Chan FKL, Chan PKS, Ng SC. Alterations in Fecal Fungal Microbiome of Patients With COVID-19 During Time of Hospitalization until Discharge. Gastroenterology. 2020;159:1302&#x2013;1310.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7318920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32598884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson AK, Omar R, Lehmann S, Sannevik J, Mastrovito B, Johansson A. General and orofacial symptoms associated with acute and long COVID in 80- and 90-year-old Swedish COVID-19 survivors. J Dent. 2024;141:104824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38145803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordalewska M, Perlin DS. Candida in COVID-19: Gut-Lung Axis, Dysbiosis, and Infections. Curr Fungal Infect Rep. 2023;17:263&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisano M, Romano A, Di Palo MP, Baroni A, Serpico R, Contaldo M. Oral Candidiasis in Adult and Pediatric Patients with COVID-19. Biomedicines. 2023;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10045279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36979825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niebauer JH, Binder-Rodriguez C, Iscel A, Schedl S, Capelle C, Kahr M, Cadjo S, Schamilow S, Badr-Eslam R, Lichtenauer M, Toma A, Zoufaly A, Valenta R, Hoffmann S, Charwat-Resl S, Krestan C, Hitzl W, Wenisch C, Bonderman D. Cardiopulmonary Long-Term Sequelae in Patients after Severe COVID-19 Disease. J Clin Med. 2023;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9959779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36836071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KG, Brokstad KA, Zhou F, Linchausen DW, Hansen BA, Lartey S, Onyango TB, Kuwelker K, S&#xe6;vik M, Bartsch H, T&#xf8;ndel C, Kittang BR Bergen COVID-19 Research Group, Cox RJ, Langeland N. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med. 2021;27:1607&#x2013;1613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Treatment Guidelines [Internet]. Bethesda (MD): National Institutes of Health (US); 2021 Apr 21&#x2013;2024 Feb 29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34003615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granata G, Schiavone F, Pipitone G, Taglietti F, Petrosillo N. Antibiotics Use in COVID-19 Patients: A Systematic Literature Review. J Clin Med. 2022;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9739751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36498781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelhafiz AS, Ali A, Maaly AM, Mahgoub MA, Ziady HH, Sultan EA. Predictors of post-COVID symptoms in Egyptian patients: Drugs used in COVID-19 treatment are incriminated. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0266175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8970499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35358268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chocarro Mart&#xed;nez A, Galindo Tobal F, Ruiz-Irastorza G, Gonz&#xe1;lez L&#xf3;pez A, Alvarez Navia F, Ochoa Sangrador C, Mart&#xed;n Arribas MI. Risk factors for esophageal candidiasis. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2000;19:96&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10746494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezeonu IM, Ntun NW, Ugwu KO. Intestinal candidiasis and antibiotic usage in children: case study of Nsukka, South Eastern Nigeria. Afr Health Sci. 2017;17:1178&#x2013;1184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5870271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29937890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliaga S, Clark RH, Laughon M, Walsh TJ, Hope WW, Benjamin DK, Kaufman D, Arrieta A, Benjamin DK Jr, Smith PB. Changes in the incidence of candidiasis in neonatal intensive care units. Pediatrics. 2014;133:236&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3904270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24446441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi-Sakamoto M, Tamai R, Isogai E, Kiyoura Y. Gastrointestinal colonisation and systemic spread of Candida albicans in mice treated with antibiotics and prednisolone. Microb Pathog. 2018;117:191&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29477742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel N, Goyal N, Nagaraja R, Kumar R. Systemic corticosteroids for management of 'long-COVID': an evaluation after 3 months of treatment. Monaldi Arch Chest Dis. 2021;92</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34730322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mainous AG 3rd, Rooks BJ, Orlando FA. The Impact of Initial COVID-19 Episode Inflammation Among Adults on Mortality Within 12 Months Post-hospital Discharge. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022;9:891375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9135460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35646997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lionakis MS, Kontoyiannis DP. Glucocorticoids and invasive fungal infections. Lancet. 2003;362:1828&#x2013;1838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14654323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myerowitz RL. Gastrointestinal and disseminated candidiasis. An experimental model in the immunosuppressed rat. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 1981;105:138&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6894077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda MA, Sousa SC, Montes VL. Post-COVID-19 neurocandidiasis. Neurol Sci. 2021;42:4419&#x2013;4420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8349610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34368903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhagali R, Prabhudesai NP, Prabhudesai MN. Post COVID-19 opportunistic candida retinitis: A case report. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2021;69:987&#x2013;989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8012955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33727474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawanda MK, Narula R, Gupta S, Sharma V, Sidhu SK, Kaur N. Mixed Infections (Mucormycosis, Actinomycosis and Candidiasis) Leading to Maxillary Osteomyelitis in a Diabetic Mellitus Patient in Post COVID Phase: First Case Report. Acta Medica (Hradec Kralove) 2021;64:218&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35285444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam S, Sharma G, Singla S, Garg S. Case Report: Secondary Hemophagocytic Lymphohistiocytosis (sHLH) and Candida auris Fungemia in Post-acute COVID-19 Syndrome: A Clinical Challenge. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022;9:835421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9247387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35783658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nucci M, Anaissie E. Revisiting the source of candidemia: skin or gut? Clin Infect Dis. 2001;33:1959&#x2013;1967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11702290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruellas M, Yubero A, Zapata M, Galvez EM, Gasc&#xf3;n M, Isla D, Lastra R, Mart&#xed;nez-Lostao L, Ocariz M, Pardo J, Ram&#xed;rez A, Sesma A, Torres-Ram&#xf3;n I, Pa&#xf1;o JR. How Could Antibiotics, Probiotics, and Corticoids Modify Microbiota and Its Influence in Cancer Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors: A Review. Infect Immun. 2021;89:e0066520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8370676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33526567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wise J. Covid-19: Long covid cases are underreported in GP records, research suggests. BMJ. 2021;374:n1685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34215626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman M, Ramsay DB, Borum ML. An unusual case report of small bowel Candida overgrowth as a cause of diarrhea and review of the literature. Dig Dis Sci. 2007;52:679&#x2013;680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>