<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39042286</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1211</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>76</Volume><Issue>5-6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Immunogenetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Immunogenetics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Bioinformatic analysis predicts the regulatory function of noncoding SNPs associated with Long COVID-19 syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>279</StartPage><EndPage>290</EndPage><MedlinePgn>279-290</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00251-024-01348-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long or Post COVID-19 is a condition of collected symptoms persisted after recovery from COVID-19. Host genetic factors play a crucial role in developing Long COVID-19, and GWAS studies identified several SNPs/genes in various ethnic populations. In African-American population two SNPS, rs10999901 (C&gt;T, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.6E-08, OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.39, MAF-0,27, GRCH38, chr10:71584799&#xa0;bp) and rs1868001 (G&gt;A, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;6.7E-09, OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.40, MAF-0.46, GRCH38, chr10:71587815&#xa0;bp) and in Hispanic population, rs3759084 (A&gt;C, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;9.7E-09, OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.56, MAF-0.17, chr12: 81,110,156&#xa0;bp) are strongly associated with Long COVID-19. All these three SNPs reside in noncoding regions implying their regulatory function in the genome. In silico dissection suggests that rs10999901 and rs1868001 physically interact with the CDH23 and C10orf105 genes. Both SNPs act as distant enhancers and bind with several transcription factors (TFs). Further, rs10999901 SNP is a CpG that is methylated in CD4++&#x2009;T cells and monocytes and loses its methylation due to transition from C&gt;T. rs3759084 is located in the promoter (-&#x2009;687&#xa0;bp) of MYF5, acts as a distant enhancer, and physically interacts with PTPRQ. These results offer plausible explanations for their association and provide the basis for experiments to dissect the development of symptoms of Long COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maiti</LastName><ForeName>Amit K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4918-3592</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genetics and Genomics, Mydnavar, 28475 Greenfield Rd, Southfield, USA. akmit123@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Immunogenetics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0420404</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0093-7711</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001741" MajorTopicYN="N">Black or African American</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019295" MajorTopicYN="Y">Computational Biology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020022" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Predisposition to Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055106" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome-Wide Association Study</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006630" MajorTopicYN="N">Hispanic or Latino</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="Y">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enhancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Expression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long Covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical interaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39042286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00251-024-01348-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00251-024-01348-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Angulo-Aguado M, Carrillo-Martinez JC, Contreras-Bravo NC, Morel A, Parra-Abaunza K, Usaqu&#xe9;n W, Fonseca-Mendoza DJ, Ortega-Recalde O (2024) Next-generation sequencing of host genetics risk factors associated with COVID-19 severity and long-COVID in Colombian population. Sci Rep 14(1):8497</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-57982-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38605121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11009356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansseau E, Laoudj-Chenivesse D, Marcowycz A, Tassin A, Vanderplanck C, Sauvage S, Barro M, Mahieu I, Leroy A, Leclercq I, Mainfroid V, Figlewicz D, Mouly V, Butler-Browne G, Belayew A, Copp&#xe9;e F (2009) DUX4c is up-regulated in FSHD. It induces the MYF5 protein and human myoblast proliferation. PLoS ONE 4(10):e7482</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0007482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19829708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2759506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appelman B, Charlton BT, Goulding RP, Kerkhoff TJ, Breedveld EA, Noort W, Offringa C, Bloemers FW, van Weeghel M, Schomakers BV, Coelho P, Posthuma JJ, Aronica E, Joost Wiersinga W, van Vugt M, W&#xfc;st RCI (2024) Muscle abnormalities worsen after post-exertional malaise in long COVID. Nat Commun 15(1):17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-44432-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38177128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10766651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolz H, von Brederlow B, Ram&#xed;rez A, Bryda EC, Kutsche K, Nothwang HG, Seeliger M, Cabrera MD, Vila MC, Molina OP, Gal A&#xa0;(2001) Mutation of CDH23, encoding a new member of the cadherin gene family, causes Usher syndrome type 1D. Nat Genet 27(1):108&#x2013;112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/83667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11138009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun T, Winter B, Bober E, Arnold HH (1990) Transcriptional activation domain of the muscle-specific gene-regulatory protein myf5. Nature 346(6285):663&#x2013;665</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/346663a0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2385294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera Martimbianco AL, Pacheco RL, Bagattini &#xc2;, Riera R (2021) Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID-19: a systematic review. Int J Clin Pract 75(10):e14357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijcp.14357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33977626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia-Hasler C, Br&#xfc;ningk SC, Hoch T, Fan B, Muzio G, Thompson RC, Ceglarek L, Meledin R, Westermann P, Emmenegger M, Taeschler P, Zurbuchen Y, Pons M, Menges D, Ballouz T, Cervia-Hasler S, Adamo S, Merad M, Charney AW, Puhan M, Brodin P, Nilsson J, Aguzzi A, Raeber ME, Messner CB, Beckmann ND, Borgwardt K, Boyman O (2024) Persistent complement dysregulation with signs of thromboinflammation in active Long Covid. Science 383(6680):eadg7942</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.adg7942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38236961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva R, de Sarges KML, Cantanhede MHD, da Costa FP, Dos Santos EF, Rodrigues FBB, de Nazar&#xe9; M, do Socorro de Almeida Viana M, de Meira Leite A, da Silva LS, de Brito MTM, da Silva Torres MK, Queiroz MAF, Vallinoto IVMC, Henriques DF, Dos Santos CP, Viana GMR, Quaresma JAS, Falc&#xe3;o LFM, Vallinoto ACR, Dos Santos EJM, (2023) Thrombophilia and immune-related genetic markers in long COVID. Viruses 15(4):885</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v15040885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37112866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10143911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deb P, Zannat KE, Talukder S, Bhuiyan AH, Jilani MSA, Saif-Ur-Rahman KM (2022) Association of HLA gene polymorphism with susceptibility, severity, and mortality of COVID-19: a systematic review. HLA 99(4):281&#x2013;312</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tan.14560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35067002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai AD, Lavelle M, Boursiquot BC, Wan EY (2022) Long-term complications of COVID-19. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol 322(1):C1&#x2013;C11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00375.2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34817268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farr&#xe9; D, Roset R, Huerta M, Adsuara JE, Rosell&#xf3; L, Alb&#xe0; MM, Messeguer X (2003) Identification of patterns in biological sequences at the ALGGEN server: PROMO and MALGEN. Nucleic Acids Res 31(13):3651&#x2013;3653</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkg605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12824386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">169011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Arendt-Nielsen L, D&#xed;az-Gil G, G&#xf3;mez-Esquer F, Gil-Crujera A, G&#xf3;mez-S&#xe1;nchez SM, Ambite-Quesada S, Palomar-Gallego MA, Pellicer-Valero OJ, Giordano R (2023) Apolipoprotein E (ApoE) &#x3b5;4 Genotype (ApoE rs429358-ApoE rs7412 Polymorphisms) is not associated with long COVID symptoms in previously hospitalized COVID-19 survivors. Genes (Basel) 14(7):1420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/genes14071420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37510324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, D&#xed;az-Gil G, Gil-Crujera A, G&#xf3;mez-S&#xe1;nchez SM, Ambite-Quesada S, Torres-Macho J, Ryan-Murua P, Franco-Moreno AI, Pellicer-Valero OJ, Arendt-Nielsen L, Giordano R (2024) Inflammatory polymorphisms (IL-6). Viruses 16(2):275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v16020275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38400050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10891518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullwood MJ, Han Y, Wei CL, Ruan X, Ruan Y (2010) Chromatin interaction analysis using paired-end tag sequencing. Curr Protoc Mol Biol chapter 21:Unit 21.15.21&#x2013;25</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullwood MJ, Liu MH, Pan YF, Liu J, Xu H, Mohamed YB, Orlov YL, Velkov S, Ho A, Mei PH, Chew EG, Huang PY, Welboren WJ, Han Y, Ooi HS, Ariyaratne PN, Vega VB, Luo Y, Tan PY, Choy PY, Wansa KD, Zhao B, Lim KS, Leow SC, Yow JS, Joseph R, Li H, Desai KV, Thomsen JS, Lee YK, Karuturi RK, Herve T, Bourque G, Stunnenberg HG, Ruan X, Cacheux-Rataboul V, Sung WK, Liu ET, Wei CL, Cheung E, Ruan Y (2009) An oestrogen-receptor-alpha-bound human chromatin interactome. Nature 462(7269):58&#x2013;64</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature08497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19890323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2774924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Initiative C-HG (2021) Mapping the human genetic architecture of COVID-19. Nature 600(7889):472&#x2013;477</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-021-03767-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin F, Li Y, Dixon JR, Selvaraj S, Ye Z, Lee AY, Yen CA, Schmitt AD, Espinoza CA, Ren B (2013) A high-resolution map of the three-dimensional chromatin interactome in human cells. Nature 503(7475):290&#x2013;294</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature12644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3838900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J, Wood J, Jaycox JR, Dhodapkar RM, Lu P, Gehlhausen JR, Tabachnikova A, Greene K, Tabacof L, Malik AA, Silva Monteiro V, Silva J, Kamath K, Zhang M, Dhal A, Ott IM, Valle G, Pe&#xf1;a-Hern&#xe1;ndez M, Mao T, Bhattacharjee B, Takahashi T, Lucas C, Song E, McCarthy D, Breyman E, Tosto-Mancuso J, Dai Y, Perotti E, Akduman K, Tzeng TJ, Xu L, Geraghty AC, Monje M, Yildirim I, Shon J, Medzhitov R, Lutchmansingh D, Possick JD, Kaminski N, Omer SB, Krumholz HM, Guan L, Dela Cruz CS, van Dijk D, Ring AM, Putrino D, Iwasaki A (2023) Distinguishing features of long COVID identified through immune profiling. Nature 623(7985):139&#x2013;148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-023-06651-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37748514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10620090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krietenstein N, Abraham S, Venev SV, Abdennur N, Gibcus J, Hsieh TS, Parsi KM, Yang L, Maehr R, Mirny LA, Dekker J, Rando OJ (2020) Ultrastructural details of mammalian chromosome architecture. Mol Cell 78(3):554-565.e557</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcel.2020.03.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32213324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7222625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lammi V, Nakanishi T, Jones SE, HGI LC, Zeberg H, Ollilia H (2023) Long COVID host genetics initiative identifies FOXP4 locus, lung fung functions and COVID-19 severity as associated to long COVID. European Societry of Human Genbetics Symposium (ESHG), Glascow, Scotland</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, Villapol S (2021) More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep 11(1):16144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8352980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiti AK (2020) The African-American population with a low allele frequency of SNP rs1990760 (T allele) in IFIH1 predicts less IFN-beta expression and potential vulnerability to COVID-19 infection. Immunogenetics 72:387&#x2013;391</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00251-020-01174-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32737579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7394703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messeguer X, Escudero R, Farr&#xe9; D, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez O, Mart&#xed;nez J, Alb&#xe0; MM (2002) PROMO: detection of known transcription regulatory elements using species-tailored searches. Bioinformatics 18(2):333&#x2013;334</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/18.2.333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11847087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molineros JE, Maiti AK, Sun C, Looger LL, Han S, Kim-Howard X, Glenn S, Adler A, Kelly JA, Niewold TB, Gilkeson GS, Brown EE, Alarc&#xf3;n GS, Edberg JC, Petri M, Ramsey-Goldman R, Reveille JD, Vil&#xe1; LM, Freedman BI, Tsao BP, Criswell LA, Jacob CO, Moore JH, Vyse TJ, Langefeld CL, Guthridge JM, Gaffney PM, Moser KL, Scofield RH, Alarc&#xf3;n-Riquelme ME, Williams SM, Merrill JT, James JA, Kaufman KM, Kimberly RP, Harley JB, Nath SK, Network B (2013) Admixture mapping in lupus identifies multiple functional variants within IFIH1 associated with apoptosis, inflammation, and autoantibody production. PLoS Genet 9(2):e1003222</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgen.1003222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23441136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3575474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;iz-Banciella MG, Albaiceta GM, Amado-Rodr&#xed;guez L, Del Riego ES, Alonso IL, L&#xf3;pez-Mart&#xed;nez C, Mart&#xed;n-Vicente P, Garc&#xed;a-Clemente M, Hermida-Valverde T, Enr&#xed;quez-Rodriguez AI, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Gonz&#xe1;lez C, Cuesta-Llavona E, Alvarez V, G&#xf3;mez J, Coto E (2022) Age-dependent effect of the IFIH1/MDA5 gene variants on the risk of critical COVID-19. Immunogenetics 75:91&#x2013;98</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00251-022-01281-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36434151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9702716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson JT, Turner D, Durand NC, Thorvaldsd&#xf3;ttir H, Mesirov JP, Aiden EL (2018) Juicebox.js provides a cloud-based visualization system for Hi-C data. Cell Syst 6(2):256-258.e251</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cels.2018.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29428417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6047755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez AD, PM Murray, J Minnier, F Xia, N Getty, T Cai, S Iyenger, S Luoh, K Cho, R Madduri (2023) Genome-wide association study of long COVID in the Million Veteran Program. American Journal of Human Genetics. ASHG at Washington DC</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy K, de la Serna IL, Imbalzano AN (2002) The myogenic basic helix-loop-helix family of transcription factors shows similar requirements for SWI/SNF chromatin remodeling enzymes during muscle differentiation in culture. J Biol Chem 277(37):33818&#x2013;33824</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M205159200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12105204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salameh TJ, Wang X, Song F, Zhang B, Wright SM, Khunsriraksakul C, Ruan Y, Yue F (2020) A supervised learning framework for chromatin loop detection in genome-wide contact maps. Nat Commun 11(1):3428</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-17239-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32647330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7347923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santopaolo M, Gregorova M, Hamilton F, Arnold D, Long A, Lacey A, Oliver E, Halliday A, Baum H, Hamilton K, Milligan R, Pearce O, Knezevic L, Morales Aza B, Milne A, Milodowski E, Jones E, Lazarus R, Goenka A, Finn A, Maskell N, Davidson AD, Gillespie K, Wooldridge L, Rivino L (2023) Prolonged T-cell activation and long COVID symptoms independently associate with severe COVID-19 at 3 months. Elife 12:e85009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.85009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37310006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10319436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz JM, Yang Y, Caride AJ, Filoteo AG, Penheiter AR, Lagziel A, Morell RJ, Mohiddin SA, Fananapazir L, Madeo AC, Penniston JT, Griffith AJ (2005) Modification of human hearing loss by plasma-membrane calcium pump PMCA2. N Engl J Med 352(15):1557&#x2013;1564</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa043899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15829536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seifert RA, Coats SA, Oganesian A, Wright MB, Dishmon M, Booth CJ, Johnson RJ, Alpers CE, Bowen-Pope DF (2003) PTPRQ is a novel phosphatidylinositol phosphatase that can be expressed as a cytoplasmic protein or as a subcellularly localized receptor-like protein. Exp Cell Res 287(2):374&#x2013;386</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0014-4827(03)00121-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12837292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Myers R, Mehl F, Murphy L, Brooks B, Wilson JM, Kadl A, Woodfolk J, Zeichner SL (2024) ACE-2-like enzymatic activity is associated with immunoglobulin in COVID-19 patients. mBio 15:e0054124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tak YG, Farnham PJ (2015) Making sense of GWAS: using epigenomics and genome engineering to understand the functional relevance of SNPs in non-coding regions of the human genome. Epigenetics Chromatin 8:57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13072-015-0050-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26719772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4696349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang B, Cheng X, Xi Y, Chen Z, Zhou Y, Jin VX (2017) Advances in genomic profiling and analysis of 3D chromatin structure and interaction. Genes (Basel) 8(9):223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/genes8090223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28885554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udomsinprasert W, Nontawong N, Saengsiwaritt W, Panthan B, Jiaranai P, Thongchompoo N, Santon S, Runcharoen C, Sensorn I, Jittikoon J, Chaikledkaew U, Chantratita W (2023) Host genetic polymorphisms involved in long-term symptoms of COVID-19. Emerg Microbes Infect 12(2):2239952</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/22221751.2023.2239952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37497655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10392286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varillas-Delgado D, Jimenez-Antona C, Lizcano-Alvarez A, Cano-de-la-Cuerda R, Molero-Sanchez A, Laguarta-Val S (2023) Predictive factors and. Int J Mol Sci 24(23)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xf5;sa U, Claringbould A, Westra HJ, Bonder MJ, Deelen P, Zeng B, Kirsten H, Saha A, Kreuzhuber R, Yazar S, Brugge H&#xa0;(2021) Large-scale cis- and trans-eQTL analyses identify thousands of genetic loci and polygenic scores that regulate blood gene expression. Nat Genet 53(9):1300&#x2013;1310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41588-021-00913-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Song C, Zhao J, Zhang Y, Zhao X, Feng C, Zhang G, Zhu J, Wang F, Qian F, Zhou L, Zhang J, Bai X, Ai B, Liu X, Wang Q, Li C (2023) SEdb 2.0: a comprehensive super-enhancer database of human and mouse. Nucleic Acids Res 51(D1):D280&#x2013;D290</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkac968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36318264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong AC, Devason AS, Umana IC, Cox TO, Dohnalov&#xe1; L, Litichevskiy L, Perla J, Lundgren P, Etwebi Z, Izzo LT, Kim J, Tetlak M, Descamps HC, Park SL, Wisser S, McKnight AD, Pardy RD, Blank N, Patel S, Thum K, Mason S, Beltra JC, Michieletto MF, Ngiow SF, Miller BM, Liou MJ, Madhu B, Dmitrieva-Posocco O, Huber AS, Hewins P, Petucci C, Chu CP, Baraniecki-Zwil G, Giron LB, Baxter AE, Greenplate AR, Kearns C, Montone K, Litzky LA, Feldman M, Henao-Mejia J, Striepen B, Ramage H, Jurado KA, Wellen KE, O&#x2019;Doherty U, Abdel-Mohsen M, Landay AL, Keshavarzian A, Henrich TJ, Deeks SG, Peluso MJ, Meyer NJ, Wherry EJ, Abramoff BA, Cherry S, Thaiss CA, Levy M (2023) Serotonin reduction in post-acute sequelae of viral infection. Cell 186(22):4851&#x2013;4867.e4820</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2023.09.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37848036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11227373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin K, Peluso MJ, Luo X, Thomas R, Shin MG, Neidleman J, Andrew A, Young KC, Ma T, Hoh R, Anglin K, Huang B, Argueta U, Lopez M, Valdivieso D, Asare K, Deveau TM, Munter SE, Ibrahim R, St&#xe4;ndker L, Lu S, Goldberg SA, Lee SA, Lynch KL, Kelly JD, Martin JN, M&#xfc;nch J, Deeks SG, Henrich TJ, Roan NR (2024) Long COVID manifests with T cell dysregulation, inflammation and an uncoordinated adaptive immune response to SARS-CoV-2. Nat Immunol 25(2):218&#x2013;225</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-023-01724-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38212464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10834368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Tang Z, Fan S, Yao D, Zhang Z, Guan C, Deng W, Ying Y (2022) Protein tyrosine phosphatase receptor-type Q: structure, activity, and implications in human disease. Protein Pept Lett 29(7):567&#x2013;573</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0929866529666220511141826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35546749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>