<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37797297</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Unraveling brain fog in post-COVID syndrome: Relationship between subjective cognitive complaints and cognitive function, fatigue, and neuropsychiatric symptoms.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.16084</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">"Brain fog" is a frequent and disabling symptom that can occur after SARS-CoV-2 infection. However, its clinical characteristics and the relationships among brain fog and objective cognitive function, fatigue, and neuropsychiatric symptoms (depression, anxiety) are still unclear. In this study, we aimed to examine the characteristics of brain fog and to understand how fatigue, cognitive performance, and neuropsychiatric symptoms and the mutual relationships among these variables influence subjective cognitive complaints.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 170 patients with cognitive complaints in the context of post-COVID syndrome were evaluated using a comprehensive neuropsychological protocol. The FLEI scale was used to characterize subjective cognitive complaints. Correlation analysis, regression machine-learning algorithms, and mediation analysis were calculated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Cognitive complaints were mainly attention and episodic memory symptoms, while executive functions (planning) issues were less often reported. The FLEI scale, a mental ability questionnaire, showed high correlations with a fatigue scale and moderate correlations with the Stroop test, and anxiety and depressive symptoms. Random forest algorithms showed an R<sup>2</sup> value of 0.409 for the prediction of FLEI score, with several cognitive tests, fatigue and depression being the best variables used in the prediction. Mediation analysis showed that fatigue was the main mediator between objective and subjective cognition, while the effect of depression was indirect and mediated through fatigue.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Brain fog associated with COVID-19 is mainly characterized by attention and episodic memory, and fatigue, which is the main mediator between objective and subjective cognition. Our findings contribute to understanding the pathophysiology of brain fog and emphasize the need to unravel the main mechanisms underlying brain fog, considering several aspects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delgado-Alonso</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hospital Cl&#xed;nico San Carlos, Health Research Institute "San Carlos" (IdISCC), Universidad Complutense de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D&#xed;ez-Cirarda</LastName><ForeName>Mar&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6768-189X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hospital Cl&#xed;nico San Carlos, Health Research Institute "San Carlos" (IdISCC), Universidad Complutense de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pag&#xe1;n</LastName><ForeName>Josu&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronic Engineering, Universidad Polit&#xe9;cnica de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Computational Simulation, Universidad Polit&#xe9;cnica de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>P&#xe9;rez-Izquierdo</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agricultural and Forestry Engineering, University Center of Plasencia, University of Extremadura, Plasencia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliver-Mas</LastName><ForeName>Silvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hospital Cl&#xed;nico San Carlos, Health Research Institute "San Carlos" (IdISCC), Universidad Complutense de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Romero</LastName><ForeName>Luc&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hospital Cl&#xed;nico San Carlos, Health Research Institute "San Carlos" (IdISCC), Universidad Complutense de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;nez-Petit</LastName><ForeName>&#xc1;lvaro</ForeName><Initials>&#xc1;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronic Engineering, Universidad Polit&#xe9;cnica de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Computational Simulation, Universidad Polit&#xe9;cnica de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valles-Salgado</LastName><ForeName>Mar&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hospital Cl&#xed;nico San Carlos, Health Research Institute "San Carlos" (IdISCC), Universidad Complutense de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gil-Moreno</LastName><ForeName>Mar&#xed;a Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hospital Cl&#xed;nico San Carlos, Health Research Institute "San Carlos" (IdISCC), Universidad Complutense de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yus</LastName><ForeName>Miguel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Hospital Clinico San Carlos, Health Research Institute "San Carlos" (IdISCC), Universidad Complutense de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mat&#xed;as-Guiu</LastName><ForeName>Jorge</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hospital Cl&#xed;nico San Carlos, Health Research Institute "San Carlos" (IdISCC), Universidad Complutense de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayala</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9; Luis</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Automatic Architecture and Automation, Universidad Complutense, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matias-Guiu</LastName><ForeName>Jordi A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5520-2708</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hospital Cl&#xed;nico San Carlos, Health Research Institute "San Carlos" (IdISCC), Universidad Complutense de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Comunidad de Madrid</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Instituto de Salud Carlos III</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37797297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.16084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ocon AJ. Caught in the thickness of brain fog: exploring the cognitive symptoms of chronic fatigue syndrome. Front Physiol. 2013;4:1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackay M. Lupus brain fog: a biologic perspective on cognitive impairment, depression, and fatigue in systemic lupus erithematosus. Immunol Res. 2015;63:26-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzo C, Martinez-Suarez E, Kechida M, Isetta M, Serra-Mestres J. Cognitive function in primary Sj&#xf6;gren's syndrome: a systematic review. Brain Sci. 2019;9:85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelland GW. Gluten-induced cognitive impairment (&#x201c;brain fog&#x201d;) in coeliac disease. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;32(Suppl 1):90-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ettleson MD, Raine A, Batistuzzo A, et al. Brain fog in hypothyroidism: understanding the patient's perspective. Endocr Pract. 2022;28:257-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McWhirter L, Smyth H, Hoeritzauer I, Couturier A, Stone J, Carson AJ. What is brain fog? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2022;94:321-325. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2022-329683</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV. WHO clinical case definition working Group in Post-COVID-19 condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:e102-e107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado-Alonso C, Valles-Salgado M, Delgado-&#xc1;lvarez A, et al. Cognitive dysfunction associated with COVID-19: a comprehensive neuropsychological study. J Psychiatr Res. 2022;150:40-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;nchez C, Calabria M, Grunden N, et al. Neuropsychological deficits in patients with cognitive complaints after COVID-19. Brain Behav. 2022;12(3):e2508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado-Alonso C, Cuevas C, Oliver-Mas S, et al. Fatigue and cognitive dysfunction are associated with occupational status in post-COVID syndrome. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:13368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunt J, Hemming S, Burton K, Elander J, Baraniak A. What workers can tell us about post-COVID workability. Occup Med (London). 2022. doi:10.1093/occmed/kqac086</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xed;ez-Cirarda M, Yus M, G&#xf3;mez-Ruiz N, et al. Multimodal neuroimaging in post-COVID syndrome and correlation with cognitive. Brain. 2022;146:2142-2152. doi:10.1093/brain/awac384</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matias-Guiu JA, Delgado-Alonso C, D&#xed;ez-Cirarda M, et al. Neuropsychological predictors of fatigue in post-COVID syndrome. J Clin Med. 2022;11:3886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabria M, Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;nchez C, Grunden N, et al. Post-COVID-19 fatigue: the contribution of cognitive and neuropsychiatric symptoms. J Neurol. 2022;269:3990-3999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattioli F, Stampatori C, Righetti F, Sala E, Tomasi C, De Palma G. Neurological and cognitive sequelae of Covid-19: a four month follow-up. J Neurol. 2021;268:4422-4428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schild AK, Goereci Y, Scharfenberg D, et al. Multidomain cognitive impairment in non-hospitalized patients with the post-COVID-19 syndrome: results from a prospective monocentric cohort. J Neurol. 2022;270:1215-1223. doi:10.1007/s00415-022-11444-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beblo T, Kunz M, Brokate B, et al. Entwicklung eines Fragebogens zur subjektiven Einsch&#xe4;tzung der geistigen Leistungsf&#xe4;higkeit (FLei) bei Patienten mit psychischen St&#xf6;rungen. Z Neuropsychol. 2010;21:143-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beblo T, Kunz M, Lautenbacher S, Albert S, Aschenbrenner S. Vienna test system (VTS): Mental ability questionnaire (FLEI). Schuhfried; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kos D, Kerckhofs E, Carrea I, Verza R, Ramos M, Jansa J. Evaluation of the modified fatigue impact scale in four different European countries. Mult Scler. 2005;11:76-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Hall ML, Strollo PJ, et al. Relationships between the Pittsburgh sleep quality index (PSQI), Epworth sleepiness scale (ESS), and clinical/polysomnographic measures in a community sample. J Clin Sleep Med. 2008;4:563-571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck AT, Steer RA, Brown GK. BDI-II. Beck Depression Inventory-Second Edition. Manual. The Psychological Corporation; 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spielberger CD, Gorsuch RL, Lushene R, Vagg PR, Jacobs GA. Manual for the State-Trait Anxiety Inventory. Consulting Psychologists Press; 1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graffigna G, Palamenghi L, Boccia S, Barello S. Relationship between citizens' health engagement and intention to take the covid-19 vaccine in Italy: a mediation analysis. Vaccine. 2020;8(4):1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosseel Y. Lavaan: an R package for structural equation modeling. J Stat Softw. 2012;48:1-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2022 https://www.R-project.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burmester B, Leathem J, Merrick P. Subjective cognitive complaints and objective cognitive function in aging: a systematic review and meta-analysis of recent cross-sectional findings. Neuropsychol Rev. 2016;26:376-393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groenman AP, van der Werf S, Geurts HM. Subjective cognition in adults with common psychiatric classifications; a systematic review. Psychiatry Res. 2022;308:114374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa AM, McCrae CS, Cowan N, Curtis AF. Paradoxical relationship between subjective and objective cognition: the role of sleep. J Clin Sleep Med. 2022;18:2009-2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matias-Guiu JA, Herrera E, Gonzalez-Nosti M, et al. Development of criteria for cognitive dysfunction in post-COVID syndrome: the IC-CoDi-COVID approach. Psychiatry Res. 2023;319:115006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephan KE, Magaly ZM, Mathys CD, et al. Allostatic self-efficacy: a metacognitive theory of dyshomeostasis-induced fatigue and depression. Front Hum Neurosci. 2016;10:550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchesi O, Vizzino C, Filippi M, Rocca MA. Current perspectives on the diagnosis and management of fatigue in multiple sclerosis. Expert Rev Neurother. 2022;22:681-693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T, Barwood M, Corbett J. Central fatigue theory and endurance exercise: toward an interoceptive model. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2018;93:93-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leavitt VM, DeLuca J. Central fatigue: issues related to cognition, mood, and behavior, and psychiatric diagnoses. PM R. 2010;2:332-337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matias-Guiu JA, Delgado-Alonso C, Yus M, et al. &#x201c;Brain fog&#x201d; by COVID-19 or Alzheimer's disease? A Case Report. Front Psychol. 2021;12:724022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Molina A, Garcia-Carmona S, Espi&#xf1;a-Bou M, Rodriguez-Rajo P, Sanchez-Carrion R, Ense&#xf1;at-Cantallops A. Neuropsychological rehabilitation for post-COVID-19 syndrome: results of a clinical programme and six-month follow up. Neurologia. 2022;S2173-5808(22):94-103. doi:10.1016/j.nrleng.2022.06.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linnhoff S, Koehler L, Haghikia A, Zaehle T. The therapeutic potential of non-invasive brain stimulation for the treatment of long-Covid related cognitive fatigue. Front Immunol. 2023;13:935614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klinkhammer S, Horn J, Duits AA, et al. Neurological and (neuro)psychological sequelae in intensive care and general ward COVID-19 survivors. Eur J Neurol. 2023;30:1880-1890. doi:10.1111/ene.15812</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>