<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37773796</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><Issue>39</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Global trends and future prospects of COVID-19 and physical activity: Bibliometric analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e35316</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e35316</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e35316</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000035316</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Containment measures implemented during the COVID-19 pandemic have led to drastic changes in daily life and effects on health behaviors such as decrease in physical activity (PA) levels. This study aims to present a general framework to researchers on COVID-19 and PA research in relation with changes in studies within years, current trend topics, gaps in the research field and possible future trends.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 1819 articles indexed in the WoS core collection database were analyzed according to publication year, citation, country and institution collaborations, coword, co-citation networks, concept-topic trends and topic clusters using bibliometric analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The most productive country was the USA(n&#x2005;=&#x2005;335), and the most productive institution was University of London in UK (n&#x2005;=&#x2005;38). The most cited publication was the study by Ammar et al, (2020) (n&#x2005;=&#x2005;188). In 2020, the most popular topics were PA and health meanwhile in 2021 behavior, lifestyle, social media and in 2022 habits, long COVID, sleep quality topics were in the foreground. Studies in 2023 focus on how COVID-19 affects PA habits and the associations between COVID-19-based anxiety and sleep patterns. These studies focused especially on effects of sport participation on life quality, diet, depression, mental health on young athletes, children, adolescent persons, older adult groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">An important gap in the study area is research on effect of changing lifestyle due to pandemic on individuals and the society during the Post COVID-19 period. If benefits of PA will not be limited to only physical benefits and psychological emotional, cognitive and social benefits are also taken into consideration, it is important that researchers conduct long-term and widescale observations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tokta&#x15f;</LastName><ForeName>Ne&#x15f;e</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Sciences, Akdeniz University, Antalya, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>K&#xf6;se</LastName><ForeName>Elif</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5490-3534</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Sciences, Akdeniz University, Antalya, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lapa</LastName><ForeName>Tennur-Yerlisu</ForeName><Initials>TY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Sciences, Akdeniz University, Antalya, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaas</LastName><ForeName>Evren-Tercan</ForeName><Initials>ET</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Sciences, Akdeniz University, Antalya, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Serdar Y&#xfc;cel</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Sciences, Firat University, Elazi&#x11f;, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Derman</LastName><ForeName>S&#xfc;leyman</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia and Reanimation, L&#xfc;tfi Kirdar City Hospital, &#x130;stanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015706" MajorTopicYN="N">Bibliometrics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37773796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10545167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000035316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202309290-00014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhai F, Zhai Y, Cong C, et al. . Research progress of coronavirus based on bibliometric analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:3766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7312058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32466477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wunsch K, Kienberger K, Niessner C. Changes in physical activity patterns due to the COVID-19 pandemic: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:2250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8871718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35206434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehmood K, Bao Y, Petropoulos GP, et al. . Investigating connections between COVID-19 pandemic, air pollution and community interventions for Pakistan employing geoinformation technologies. Chemosphere. 2021;272:129809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7846247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33582510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madjid M, Safavi-Naeini P, Solomon SD, et al. . Potential effects of coronaviruses on the cardiovascular system: a review. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:831&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32219363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vindegaard N, Benros ME. COVID-19 pandemic and mental health consequences: systematic review of the current evidence. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;89:531&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7260522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32485289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pokhrel S, Chhetri R. A literature review on impact of COVID-19 pandemic on teaching and learning. Higher Educ Future. 2021;8:133&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicola M, Alsafi Z, Sohrabi C, et al. . The socio-economic implications of the coronavirus pandemic (COVID-19): a review. Int J Surg. 2020;78:185&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7162753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32305533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehmood K, Bao Y, Mushtaq S, et al. . Perspectives from remote sensing to investigate the COVID-19 pandemic: a future-oriented approach. Front Public Health. 2022;10:938811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9360797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35958871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehmood K, Bao Y, Abrar MM, et al. . Spatiotemporal variability of COVID-19 pandemic in relation to air pollution, climate and socioeconomic factors in Pakistan. Chemosphere. 2021;271:129584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7797023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33482526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-de-Quel O, Su&#xe1;rez-Iglesias D, L&#xf3;pez-Flores M, et al. . Physical activity, dietary habits and sleep quality before and during COVID-19 lockdown: a longitudinal study. Appetite. 2021;158:105019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8580211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33161046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki S, Sato A, Tanabe Y, et al. . Associations between socioeconomic status, social participation, and physical activity in older people during the COVID-19 pandemic: a cross-sectional study in a northern Japanese city. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:1477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7915555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33557257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tulchin-Francis K, Stevens W, Jr, Gu X, et al. . The impact of the coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic on physical activity in US children. Sports Med Health Sci. 2021;10:323&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8167336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balci B, Aktar B, Buran S, et al. . Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on physical activity, anxiety, and depression in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Int J Rehabil Res. 2021;44:173&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8103842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33653991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertrand L, Shaw KA, Ko J, et al. . The impact of the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic on university students&#x2019; dietary intake, physical activity, and sedentary behaviour. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2021;46:265&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33449864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elnaggar RK, Alqahtani BA, Mahmoud WS, et al. . Physical activity in adolescents during the social distancing policies of the COVID-19 pandemic. Asia Pac J Public Health. 2020;32:491&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33016086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fettes L, Bayly J, de Bruin LM, et al. . Relationships between prolonged physical and social isolation during the COVID-19 pandemic, reduced physical activity and disability in activities of daily living among people with advanced respiratory disease. Chron Respir Dis. 2021;18:14799731211035822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8370888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34382888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore SA, Sharma R, Martin Ginis KA, et al. . Adverse effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on movement and play behaviours of children and youth living with disabilities: findings from the National Physical Activity Measurement (NPAM) study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:12950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8701838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34948560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz-Roso MB, Knott-Torcal C, Matilla-Escalante DC, et al. . COVID-19 lockdown and changes of the dietary pattern and physical activity habits in a cohort of patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Nutrients. 2020;12:2327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7468739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw KA, Bertrand L, Deprez D, et al. . The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on diet, fitness, and sedentary behaviour of elite para-athletes. Disabil Health J. 2021;14:101091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9760297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33715987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shima T, Nakao H, Tai K, et al. . The influences of changes in physical activity levels with easing restriction of access to the university campus on empathy and social supports in college students during the COVID-19 pandemic. Asia Pac J Public Health. 2022;34:406&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35249364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Mao L, Nassis GP, et al. . Coronavirus disease (COVID-19): the need to maintain regular physical activity while taking precautions. J Sport Health Sci. 2020;9:103&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7031771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32099716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzahrani H, Alshehri F, Alsufiany M, et al. . Impact of the 2019 Coronavirus disease pandemic on health-related quality of life and psychological status: the role of physical activity. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:3992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8069215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33920147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth FW, Roberts CK, Laye MJ. Lack of exercise is a major cause of chronic diseases. Compr Physiol. 2012;2:1143&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4241367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23798298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuezeki E, Engeroff T, Banzer W. Health benefits of light-intensity physical activity: a systematic review of accelerometer data of the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES). Sports Med. 2017;47:1769&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28393328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liska D, Andreansky M. Rehabilitation and physical activity for COVID-19 patients in the post infection period. Rehabilitation (Stuttg). 2021;122:310&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33848179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maugeri G, Castrogiovanni P, Battaglia G, et al. . The impact of physical activity on psychological health during COVID-19 pandemic in Italy. Heliyon. 2020;6:e04315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7311901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Posadzki P, Pieper D, Bajpai R, et al. . Exercise/physical activity and health outcomes: an overview of Cochrane systematic reviews. BMC Public Health. 2020;20:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7670795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33198717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravalli S, Musumeci G. Coronavirus outbreak in Italy: physiological benefits of home-based exercise during pandemic. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2020;5:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieman DC, Wentz LM. The compelling link between physical activity and the body&#x2019;s defense system. J Sport Health Sci. 2019;8:201&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6523821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31193280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Valenciano A, Su&#xe1;rez-Iglesias D, Sanchez-Lastra MA, et al. . Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on university students&#x2019; physical activity levels: an early systematic review. Front Psychol. 2021;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7845570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33519653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi L, Behme N, Breuer C. Physical activity of children and adolescents during the COVID-19 pandemic&#x2014;A scoping review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:11440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8583307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34769956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stockwell S, Trott M, Tully M, et al. . Changes in physical activity and sedentary behaviours from before to during the COVID-19 pandemic lockdown: a systematic review. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2021;7:e000960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7852071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34192010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopalakrishnan S, Ganeshkumar P. Systematic reviews and meta-analysis: understanding the best evidence in primary healthcare. J Family Med Prim Care. 2013;2:9&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3894019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24479036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris JD, Quatman CE, Manring M, et al. . How to write a systematic review. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42:2761&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23925575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciuldim M, Verlengia R, Crisp AH. A bibliographic analysis of primary studies on physical activity and COVID-19 during 2020&#x2013;2021. Epidemiologia. 2022;3:314&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9620884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36417240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sofyan D, Abdullah KH, Akinci AY, et al. . Sports activities during the Covid 19 pandemic: a bibliometric analysis. J Metrics Stud Soc Sci. 2022;1:50&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomanek M, Lis A. Physical activity in the context of the COVID-19 pandemic: Research profiling and mapping. Phys Educ Students. 2021;25:136&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wattanapisit A, Kotepui M, Wattanapisit S, et al. . Bibliometric analysis of literature on physical activity and COVID-19. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:7116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9223140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35742364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Zhang Y, Yu Y, et al. . Bibliometric analysis of the top-50 cited articles on COVID-19 and physical activity. Front Public Health. 2022;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9500202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36159319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Chen M, Liu C, et al. . A bibliometric analysis of COVID-19 and physical activity. Medicine (Baltimore). 2022;101:e30779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9524527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36181070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattioli AV, Ballerini Puviani M. Lifestyle at time of COVID-19: how could quarantine affect cardiovascular risk. Am J Lifestyle Med. 2020;14:240&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7232897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32477021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwivedi YK, Hughes DL, Coombs C, et al. . Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on information management research and practice: transforming education, work and life. Int J Inf Manage. 2020;55:102211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO (World Health Organization). Director-General&#x2019;s opening remarks at the media briefing &#x2013; 5 May 2023.
Available at: https://www.who.int/director-general/speeches/detail/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-the-media-briefing---5-may-2023. [access date Aug 3, 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Q, Mao G, Zhao L, et al. . Mapping the scientific research on life cycle assessment: a bibliometric analysis. Int J Life Cycle Assess. 2015;20:541&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao G, Liu X, Du H, et al. . Way forward for alternative energy research: a bibliometric analysis during 1994&#x2013;2013. Renew Sustain Energy Rev. 2015;48:276&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zupic I, &#x10c;ater T. Bibliometric methods in management and organization. Organ Res Methods. 2015;18:429&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Chen H, Wang W, et al. . What is the role of IT in innovation? A bibliometric analysis of research development in IT innovation. Behav Inf Technol. 2016;35:1130&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball R, Tunger D. Science indicators revisited&#x2013;Science Citation Index versus SCOPUS: a bibliometric comparison of both citation databases. Inf Serv Use. 2006;26:293&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Leeuwen T. The application of bibliometric analyses in the evaluation of social science research. Who benefits from it, and why it is still feasible. Scientometrics. 2006;66:133&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C. How to use CiteSpace. Victoria. British Columbia, Canada: Leanpub. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benckendorff P. Themes and trends in Australian and New Zealand tourism research: a social network analysis of citations in two leading journals (1994&#x2013;2007). J Hospitality Tourism Manage. 2009;16:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyack KW, Klavans R. Co-citation analysis, bibliographic coupling, and direct citation: which citation approach represents the research front most accurately? J Am Soc Inf Sci Technol. 2010;61:2389&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X, Li X, Kang Y. A bibliometric analysis of research on intangible cultural heritage using CiteSpace. Sage Open. 2019;9:215824401984011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghoson AM. editor Medical document classification based on MeSH. 2014 47th Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences; 2014: IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al. . Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses. PLoS Med. 2009;6:e1000097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y, Ritchie BW, Benckendorff P. Bibliometric visualisation: an application in tourism crisis and disaster management research. Curr Issues Tourism. 2019;22:1925&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Ibekwe-SanJuan F, Hou J. The structure and dynamics of cocitation clusters: a multiple-perspective cocitation analysis. J Am Soc Inf Sci Technol. 2010;61:1386&#x2013;409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Ma E, Qu H. Knowledge mapping of hospitality research&#x2212; A visual analysis using CiteSpace. Int J Hosp Manag. 2017;60:77&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simovici DA. Chapter 6: data mining algorithms I: clustering. In: Math ANB, Stojmenovi&#x107; I, ed. Handbook of Applied Algorithms: Solving Scientific, Engineering and Practical Problems. 1th ed. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc; 2007:177&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;se E, Seyman D, Yildirim FS, et al. . Bibliometric analysis of HIV and exercise literature based on scientific studies from 1990-2020. Iran J Public Health. 2021;50:2397&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9577152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36317018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO (World Health Organization). Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard: World Health Organization; 2022.
Available at: https://covid19.who.int/. [access date Jun 6, 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao KY, Wang YH, Li HC, et al. . COVID-19 publications in family medicine journals in 2020: a PubMed-based bibliometric analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:7748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8345810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34360040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammar A, Brach M, Trabelsi K, et al. . Effects of COVID-19 home confinement on physical activity and eating behaviour Preliminary results of the ECLB-COVID19 international online-survey. Nutrients. 2020;12:1583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7352706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32481594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks SK, Webster RK, Smith LE, et al. . The psychological impact of quarantine and how to reduce it: rapid review of the evidence. Lancet. 2020;395:912&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32112714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tylka TL, Homan KJ. Exercise motives and positive body image in physically active college women and men: exploring an expanded acceptance model of intuitive eating. Body Image. 2015;15:90&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26281958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abeza G, O&#x2019;Reilly N, S&#xe9;guin B, et al. . Social media scholarship in sport management research: a critical review. J Sport Manage. 2015;29:601&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes M. Social media and inspiring physical activity during COVID-19 and beyond. Manag Sport Leis. 2022;27:14&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Ma J. Post-COVID-19 distress and unhealthy behavior. J Mental Health. 2022:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35510749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szpunar M, Bourke M, Vanderloo LM, et al. . Parent-reported changes in Ontario children&#x2019;s physical activity levels during the COVID-19 pandemic. Children. 2023;10:221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9954678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36832350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katewongsa P, Widyastari DA, Haemathulin N, et al. . Recovery shape of physical activity after COVID-19 pandemic. J Sport Health Sci 2023;12:501&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9977470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36868376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acito M, Rondini T, Gargano G, et al. . How the COVID-19 pandemic has affected eating habits and physical activity in breast cancer survivors: the DianaWeb study. J Cancer Surviv. 2022;1:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9745269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36512160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng TK, Kwok CK, Ngan GY, et al. . Differential impacts of COVID-19 pandemic on physical activity involvements and exercise habits in people with and without chronic diseases: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;103:1448&#x2013;1465.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8994706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35417759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oudjedi A, Derouiche M, Allali A, et al. . Association between physical activity and sleep quality in Algerian adults during COVID-19 lockdown. Phys Educ Students. 2022;26:18&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanriverdi A, Savci S, Kahraman BO, et al. . Extrapulmonary features of post-COVID-19 patients: muscle function, physical activity, mood, and sleep quality. Ir J Med Sci. 2022;191:969&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8172250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34080125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calcaterra G, Fanos V, Cataldi L, et al. . Need for resuming sports and physical activity for children and adolescents following COVID-19 infection. Sport Sci Health. 2022;18:1179&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8966858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35378898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostermeier E, Tucker P, Tobin D, et al. . Parents&#x2019; perceptions of their children&#x2019;s physical activity during the COVID-19 pandemic. BMC Public Health. 2022;22:1459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9340749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35915418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui D, Zhang X, Guo J. The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on physical activity and sleep among healthy adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Psychol. 2023;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10344672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37457076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Blanco C, Bernal-Utrera C, Anarte-Lazo E, et al. . A 14-day therapeutic exercise telerehabilitation protocol of physiotherapy is effective in non-hospitalized post-COVID-19 conditions: a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Med. 2023;12:776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9918076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36769425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO (World Health Organization). Report of the WHO-China Joint Mission on Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) 2020.
Available at: https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/who-china-joint-mission-on-COVID-19-final-report.pdf. [access date Jun 6, 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sollini M, Ciccarelli M, Cecconi M, et al. . Vasculitis changes in COVID-19 survivors with persistent symptoms: an [18 F] FDG-PET/CT study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48:1460&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7595761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33123760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piva T, Masotti S, Raisi A, et al. . Exercise program for the management of anxiety and depression in adults and elderly subjects: Is it applicable to patients with post-covid-19 condition? A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Affect Disord. 2023;325:273&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9829440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36634854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa BOD, Andrade LS, Botton CE, et al. . Effects of a telehealth stretching exercise program on pain, sleep, depression, and functionality of women with fibromyalgia during the COVID-19 pandemic: a randomized clinical trial. Sustainability. 2023;15:2604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Wang W, Wang M, et al. . Personalized individual-based exercise prescriptions are effective in treating depressive symptoms of college students during the COVID-19: a randomized controlled trial in China. Front Psychiatry. 2023;13:1015725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9869038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36699477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanaway JD, Afshin A, Gakidou E, et al. . Global, regional, and national comparative risk assessment of 84 behavioural, environmental and occupational, and metabolic risks or clusters of risks for 195 countries and territories, 1990&#x2013;2017: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017. Lancet. 2018;392:1923&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6227755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30496105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawat D, Dixit V, Gulati S, et al. . Impact of COVID-19 outbreak on lifestyle behaviour: a review of studies published in India. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15:331&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33493852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cava MA, Fay KE, Beanlands HJ, et al. . The experience of quarantine for individuals affected by SARS in Toronto. Public Health Nurs. 2005;22:398&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16229732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan W-K, Lu K-J. Smartphone use at tourist destinations: Interaction with social loneliness, aesthetic scope, leisure boredom, and trip satisfaction. Telemat Inform. 2019;39:64&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kil N, Kim J, Park J, et al. . Leisure boredom, leisure challenge, smartphone use, and emotional distress among US college students: are they interrelated? Leisure Studies. 2021;40:779&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W-C. Exploring the relationship among free-time management, leisure boredom, and internet addiction in undergraduates in Taiwan. Psychol Rep. 2019;122:1651&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30071775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rad D, Balas VE, Demeter E, et al. . Chapter 9: The emerging association between boredom, COVID-19 anxiety, and aggressiveness in imposed prolonged social isolation. In: Balas VE, Geman O, eds. Biomedical Engineering Applications for People with Disabilities and the Elderly in the COVID-19 Pandemic and Beyond. 1th ed. Elsevier;2022:85&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehmood K, Mushtaq S, Bao Y, et al. . The impact of COVID-19 pandemic on air pollution: a global research framework, challenges, and future perspectives. Environ Sci Pollut Res. 2022;29:52618&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8906062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35262893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>