<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38850204</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1467-9566</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sociology of health &amp; illness</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sociol Health Illn</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>'You're just a Guinea pig': Exploring the barriers and impacts of living with long COVID-19: A view from the undiagnosed.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1467-9566.13795</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The COVID-19 pandemic had a disproportionate impact on ethnically minoritised and other marginalised communities, yet little is known about the impacts of long COVID-19 (LC) on this group. Living with LC takes its toll both physically, emotionally and financially and even more so when a diagnosis is hard to come by. By using qualitative interviews centring the view of undiagnosed and marginalised communities already classed as 'underserved' in the medical literature, we show the range of barriers and impacts faced by these groups in the UK, and the strategies of resilience they use. Whether trapped on a 'diagnostic odyssey' at the level of primary care, struggling to maintain employment and businesses, or managing family commitments, we argue many minoritised communities are caught in a liminal space of misrecognition, invalidation and ambiguity. We show how these impacts are generated by tensions and challenges in the process and categorisation of diagnosis, and how this effects the daily lives of many individuals already on the receiving end of health inequity. We also offer some examples and suggestions for best practices.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Sociology of Health &amp; Illness published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Foundation for the Sociology of Health &amp; Illness.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mullard</LastName><ForeName>Jordan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2712-6626</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Newcastle University &amp; Department of Sociology, Population Health Sciences Institute, Durham University, Durham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mir</LastName><ForeName>Ghazala</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5277-6885</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Leeds Institute for Health Sciences, University of Leeds, Leeds, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Herbert</LastName><ForeName>Chantal</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LOCOMOTION Study Participant and Contributor, Sister Shack CIC, Newcastle, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Evans</LastName><ForeName>Sophie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LOCOMOTION Patient Advisory Group, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>LOCOMOTION Consortium</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>COV-LT2-0016</GrantID><Agency>National Institute for Health and Care Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sociol Health Illn</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8205036</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0141-9889</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic odyssey</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emotional labour</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health inequalities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">invalidation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID&#x2010;19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">marginalised communities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recognition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38850204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1467-9566.13795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Armstrong, K., Micco, E., Carney, A., Stopfer, J., &amp; Putt, M. (2005). Racial differences in the use of BRCA1/2 testing among women with a family history of breast or ovarian cancer. JAMA, 293(14), 1729&#x2013;1736. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.293.14.1729</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker, K. K., Whooley, O., Madden, E. F., Ahrend, E. E., &amp; Greene, R. N. (2022). The long tail of COVID and the tale of LC: Diagnostic construction and the management of ignorance. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness, 1&#x2013;19. https://doi.org/10.1111/1467&#x2010;9566.13599</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayliss, K., Riste, L., Fisher, L., Wearden, A., Peters, S., Lovell, K., &amp; Chew&#x2010;Graham, C. (2014). Diagnosis and management of chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalitis in black and minority ethnic people: A qualitative study. Primary Health Care Research &amp; Development, 15(2), 143&#x2013;155. https://doi.org/10.1017/s1463423613000145</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baz, S. A., Fang, C., Carpentieri, J. D., &amp; Sheard, L. (2023). &#x2018;I don't know what to do or where to go&#x2019;. Experiences of accessing healthcare support from the perspectives of people living with long covid and healthcare professionals: A qualitative study in Bradford, UK. Health Expectations, 26(1), 542&#x2013;554. https://doi.org/10.1111/hex.13687</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhui, K. S., Dinos, S., Ashby, D., Nazroo, J., Wessely, S., &amp; White, P. D. (2011). Chronic fatigue syndrome in an ethnically diverse population: The influence of psychosocial adversity and physical inactivity. BMC Medicine, 9, 1&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.1186/1741&#x2010;7015&#x2010;9&#x2010;26</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaxter, M. (1978). Diagnosis as category and process: The case of alcoholism. Social Science &amp; Medicine &#x2010; Part A: Medical Psychology &amp; Medical Sociology, 12, 9&#x2013;17. https://doi.org/10.1016/0160&#x2010;7979(78)90150&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaxter, M. (1997). Whose fault is it? People's own conceptions of the reasons for health inequalities. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 44(6), 747&#x2013;756. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0277&#x2010;9536(96)00192&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bontempo, A. C. (2022). The need for a standardized conceptual term to describe invalidation of patient symptoms. Journal of Health Psychology, 27(9), 2104&#x2013;2114. https://doi.org/10.1177/13591053211024718</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brossard, B., &amp; Carpentier, N. (2017). To what extent does diagnosis matter? Dementia diagnosis, trouble interpretation and cbnaregiving network dynamics. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness, 39(4), 566&#x2013;580. https://doi.org/10.1111/1467&#x2010;9566.12501</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke, M. C. (2011). Resisting pathology: GID and the contested terrain of diagnosis in the transgender rights movement. In P. McGann &amp; D. J. Hutson (Eds.), Sociology of diagnosis advances in medical sociology (Vol. 12, pp. 183&#x2013;210). Emerald Group Publishing Limited. https://doi.org/10.1108/S1057&#x2010;6290(2011)0000012013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke, M. J. (2019). &#x201c;It&#x2019;s all in your head&#x201d;&#x2014;Medicine&#x2019;s silent epidemic. JAMA Neurology, 76(12), 1417&#x2013;1418. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2019.3043</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callard, F., &amp; Perego, E. (2021). How and why patients made LC. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 268, 113426. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113426</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell, C. K. (2021). Structural and intersectional biographical disruption: The case of HIV disclosure among a sample of black gay and bisexual men. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 280, 114046. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2021.114046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmichael, N., Tsipis, J., Windmueller, G., Mandel, L., &amp; Estrella, E. (2015). &#x201c;Is it going to hurt?&#x201d;: The impact of the diagnostic odyssey on children and their families. Journal of Genetic Counseling, 24(2), 325&#x2013;335. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10897&#x2010;014&#x2010;9773&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavez, L. R., Hubbell, F. A., McMullin, J. M., Martinez, R. G., &amp; MlSHRA, S. I. (1995). Structure and meaning in models of breast and cervical cancer risk factors: A comparison of perceptions among Latinas, Anglo women, and physicians. Medical Anthropology Quarterly, 9(1), 40&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1525/maq.1995.9.1.02a00030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Checkland, K. (2004). National service frameworks and UK general practitioners: Street&#x2010;level bureaucrats at work? Sociology of Health &amp; Illness, 26(7), 951&#x2013;975. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.0141&#x2010;9889.2004.00424.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clare, H. M., Waltz, M., Berg, J., Powell, B., Adams, M., Kahkoska, A., &amp; Lich, K. H. (2023). Characterizing research on the diagnostic odyssey in the United States: A systematic mapping review. Genetics in Medicine Open, 1(1), 379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohn, S. (1999). Taking time to smell the roses: Accounts of people with chronic fatigue syndrome and their struggle for legitimisation. Anthropology &amp; Medicine, 6(2), 195&#x2013;215. https://doi.org/10.1080/13648470.1999.9964583</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creighton, W. B. (1977). The equal opportunity act&#x2010;tokenism or prescription for change? Melb. UL Rev., 11, 503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Destoumieux&#x2010;Garz&#xf3;n, D., Mavingui, P., Boetsch, G., Boissier, J., Darriet, F., Duboz, P., Fritsch, C., Giraudoux, P., Le Roux, F., Morand, S., Paillard, C., Pontier, D., Sueur, C., &amp; Voituron, Y. (2018). The one health concept: 10 years old and a long road ahead. Frontiers in Veterinary Science, 5, 1&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2018.00014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenton, K., Pawson, E., &amp; de Souza&#x2010;Thomas, L. (2020). Beyond the data: Understanding the impact of COVID&#x2010;19 on BAME groups (pp. 1&#x2013;68). Public Health England.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford, J. A., Turley, R., Porter, T., Shakespeare, T., Wong, G., Jones, A. P., &amp; Steel, N. (2018). Access to primary care for socio&#x2010;economically disadvantaged older people in rural areas: A qualitative study. PLoS One, 13(3), e0193952. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0193952</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraiman, Y. S., &amp; Wojcik, M. H. (2021). The influence of social determinants of health on the genetic diagnostic odyssey: Who remains undiagnosed, why, and to what effect? Pediatric Research, 89(2), 295&#x2013;300. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41390&#x2010;020&#x2010;01151&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraser, N. (1998). Heterosexism, misrecognition and capitalism. New Left Review, 228, 140&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraser, N. (2005). Reframing global justice. New Left Review, 36, 69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, M. Z. (2023). (A) woke workplaces. Wisconsin Law Review, 2023(3). https://doi.org/10.59015/wlr.ksjv1288</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrmann, S. K. (2011). Social exclusion: Practices of misrecognition. Humiliation, Degradation, Dehumanization: Human Dignity Violated, 133&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honneth, A. (1996). The struggle for recognition: The moral grammar of social conflicts. MIT press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jauho, M. (2019). Patients&#x2010;in&#x2010;waiting or chronically healthy individuals? People with elevated cholesterol talk about risk. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness, 41(5), 867&#x2013;881. https://doi.org/10.1111/1467&#x2010;9566.12866</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeske, M., James, J., &amp; Joyce, K. (2023). Diagnosis and the practices of patienthood: How diagnostic journeys shape illness experiences. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness, 46(S1), 225&#x2013;241. https://doi.org/10.1111/1467&#x2010;9566.13614</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, C., Tomkow, L., &amp; Farrington, R. (2019). Access to primary health care for asylum seekers and refugees: A qualitative study of service user experiences in the UK. British Journal of General Practice, 69(685), e537&#x2013;e545. https://doi.org/10.3399/bjgp19x701309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karner, C., &amp; Parker, D. (2011). Conviviality and conflict: Pluralism, resilience and hope in inner&#x2010;city Birmingham. Journal of Ethnic and Migration Studies, 37(3), 355&#x2013;372. https://doi.org/10.1080/1369183x.2011.526776</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khullar, D., Zhang, Y., Zang, C., Xu, Z., Wang, F., Weiner, M. G., Carton, T. W., Rothman, R. L., Block, J. P., &amp; Kaushal, R. (2023). Racial/ethnic disparities in post&#x2010;acute sequelae of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection in New York: an EHR&#x2010;based cohort study from the RECOVER program. Journal of General Internal Medicine, 38(5), 1127&#x2013;1136. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11606&#x2010;022&#x2010;07997&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis, C., Skirton, H., &amp; Jones, R. (2010). Living without a diagnosis: The parental experience. Genetic Testing and Molecular Biomarkers, 14(6), 807&#x2013;815. https://doi.org/10.1089/gtmb.2010.0061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mir, G., Ghani, R., Meer, S., &amp; Hussain, G. (2019). Delivering a culturally adapted therapy for Muslim clients with depression. The Cognitive Behaviour Therapist, 12, e26. https://doi.org/10.1017/s1754470x19000059</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mir, G., Karlsen, S., Mitullah, W. V., Bhojani, U., Uzochukwu, B., Okeke, C., Mirzoev, T., Ebenso, B., Dracup, N., Dymski, G. A., &amp; Duong, D. T. T. (2020). Achieving SDG 10: A global review of public service inclusion strategies for ethnic and religious minorities. UNRISD Occasional Paper&#x2010;Overcoming Inequalities in a Fractured World: Between Elite Power and Social Mobilization.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mir, G., Meer, S., Cottrell, D., McMillan, D., House, A., &amp; Kanter, J. W. (2015). Adapted behavioural activation for the treatment of depression in Muslims. Journal of Affective Disorders, 180, 190&#x2013;199. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jad.2015.03.060</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullard, J. C. (2023). Authenticity and recognition: Theorising antiracist becomings and allyship in the time of COVID&#x2010;19 and Black Lives Matter. Anthropological Theory, 24(2), 111&#x2013;135. https://doi.org/10.1177/14634996231193608</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullard, J. C. R., Kawalek, J., Parkin, A., Rayner, C., Mir, G., Sivan, M., &amp; Greenhalgh, T. (2023). Towards evidence&#x2010;based and inclusive models of peer support for long covid: A hermeneutic systematic review. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 320, 115669. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2023.115669</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazroo, J. (2022). Race/ethnic inequalities in health: Moving beyond confusion to focus on fundamental causes (p. 1). Institute for Fiscal Studies.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norredam, M., Hayward, S., Deal, A., Agyemang, C., &amp; Hargreaves, S. (2022). Understanding and addressing long&#x2010;COVID among migrants and ethnic minorities in Europe. The Lancet Regional Health&#x2013;Europe, 19, 100427. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lanepe.2022.100427</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. (2023). Prevalence of ongoing symptom following coronavirus (COVID&#x2010;19) infection in the UK: 30 March 2023. ONS website, statistical bulletin. https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/30march2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okoro, O. N., Hillman, L. A., &amp; Cernasev, A. (2022). Intersectional invisibility experiences of low&#x2010;income African&#x2010;American women in healthcare encounters. Ethnicity and Health, 27(6), 1290&#x2013;1309. https://doi.org/10.1080/13557858.2021.1899138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul, E., Fancourt, D., &amp; Razai, M. (2022). Racial discrimination, low trust in the health system and COVID&#x2010;19 vaccine uptake: A longitudinal observational study of 633 UK adults from ethnic minority groups. Journal of the Royal Society of Medicine, 115(11), 439&#x2013;447. https://doi.org/10.1177/01410768221095241</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putnam, R. D. (2000). Bowling alone: America&#x2019;s declining social capital. In Culture and politics: A reader (pp. 223&#x2013;234). Palgrave Macmillan US.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaglio, G., Karapiperis, T., Van Woensel, L., Arnold, E., &amp; McDaid, D. (2013). Austerity and health in Europe. Health Policy, 113(1&#x2013;2), 13&#x2013;19. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.healthpol.2013.09.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie, J., Spencer, L., &amp; O&#x2019;Connor, W., (2003). Carrying out qualitative analysis. In: Qualitative research practice: A guide for social science students and researchers, pp.219&#x2013;262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodgers, D., &amp; O&#x2019;neill, B. (2012). Infrastructural violence: Introduction to the special issue. Ethnography, 13(4), 401&#x2013;412. https://doi.org/10.1177/1466138111435738</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roxo, L., Bambra, C., &amp; Perelman, J. (2021). Gender equality and gender inequalities in self&#x2010;reported health: A longitudinal study of 27 European countries 2004 to 2016. International Journal of Health Services, 51(2), 146&#x2013;154. https://doi.org/10.1177/0020731420960344</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rushforth, A., Ladds, E., Wieringa, S., Taylor, S., Husain, L., &amp; G, T. (2021). LC &#x2013; The illness narratives. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 286, 114326. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2021.114326</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim, J. K. (2010). Cultural health capital: A theoretical approach to understanding health care interactions and the dynamics of unequal treatment. Journal of Health and Social Behavior, 51(1), 1&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1177/0022146509361185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan, M., Greenhalgh, T., Darbyshire, J. L., Mir, G., O'Connor, R. J., Dawes, H., Greenwood, D., O&#x2019;Connor, D., Horton, M., Petrou, S., de Lusignan, S., Curcin, V., Mayer, E., Casson, A., Milne, R., Rayner, C., Smith, N., Parkin, A., Preston, N., &amp; Delaney, B. (2022). LOng COvid multidisciplinary consortium optimising treatments and servIces acrOss the NHS (LOCOMOTION): Protocol for a mixed&#x2010;methods study in the UK. BMJ Open, 12(5), e063505. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen&#x2010;2022&#x2010;063505</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, A. C., Woerner, J., Perera, R., Haeny, A. M., &amp; Cox, J. M. (2022). An investigation of associations between race, ethnicity, and past experiences of discrimination with medical mistrust and COVID&#x2010;19 protective strategies. Journal of racial and ethnic health disparities, 9(4), 1430&#x2013;1442. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40615&#x2010;021&#x2010;01080&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian, A., Nirantharakumar, K., Hughes, S., Myles, P., Williams, T., Gokhale, K. M., Taverner, T., Chandan, J. S., Brown, K., Simms&#x2010;Williams, N., Shah, A. D., Singh, M., Kidy, F., Okoth, K., Hotham, R., Bashir, N., Cockburn, N., Lee, S. I., Turner, G. M., &amp; Haroon, S. (2022). Symptoms and risk factors for LC in non&#x2010;hospitalized adults. Nature Medicine, 28(8), 1706&#x2013;1714. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591&#x2010;022&#x2010;01909&#x2010;w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatari, C. R., Andersen, B., Brogaard, T., Badre&#x2010;Esfahani, S. K., Jaafar, N., &amp; Kirkegaard, P. (2020). Perceptions about cancer and barriers towards cancer screening among ethnic minority women in a deprived area in Denmark&#x2013;a qualitative study. BMC Public Health, 20(1), 1&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889&#x2010;020&#x2010;09037&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodosius, C. (2008). Emotional Labour in Healthcare: The unmanaged heart of nursing. Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, M. D., Sohail, S., Mendez, R. M., M&#xe1;rquez&#x2010;Maga&#xf1;a, L., &amp; Allen, A. M. (2021). Racial discrimination and telomere length in midlife African American women: Interactions of educational attainment and employment status. Annals of Behavioral Medicine, 55(7), 601&#x2013;611. https://doi.org/10.1093/abm/kaaa104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmermans, S., &amp; Buchbinder, M. (2010). Patients&#x2010;in&#x2010;waiting: Living between sickness and health in the genomics era. Journal of Health and Social Behavior, 51(4), 408&#x2013;423. https://doi.org/10.1177/0022146510386794</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Ginneken, E., Siciliani, L., Reed, S., Eriksen, A., Tille, F., &amp; Zapata, T. (2022). Addressing backlogs and managing waiting lists during and beyond the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic. Eurohealth, 28(1), 35&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson, S., Fernandes&#x2010;Jesus, M., Young, J., Drury, J., Harris, C., Graber, R., Northorp, S., O&#x2019;Dwyer, E., &amp; Walker, C. (2023). A social capital approach to understanding community resilience during the covid&#x2010;19 pandemic. In Forum community psychology. Forum community psychology.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation. (2022). At least 17 million people in the WHO European Region experienced LC in the first two years of the pandemic; millions may have to live with it for years to come. https://www.who.int/europe/news/item/13&#x2010;09&#x2010;2022&#x2010;at&#x2010;least&#x2010;17&#x2010;million&#x2010;people&#x2010;in&#x2010;the&#x2010;who&#x2010;european&#x2010;region&#x2010;experienced&#x2010;long&#x2010;covid&#x2010;in&#x2010;the&#x2010;first&#x2010;two&#x2010;years&#x2010;of&#x2010;the&#x2010;pandemic&#x2010;&#x2010;millions&#x2010;may&#x2010;have&#x2010;to&#x2010;live&#x2010;with&#x2010;it&#x2010;for&#x2010;years&#x2010;to&#x2010;come</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>