<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36035093</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1876-3820</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>55</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of integrative medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Integr Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A service evaluation of a community project combining psychoeducation and mind-body complementary approaches to support those with long covid in the UK.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102182</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102182</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.eujim.2022.102182</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Post covid-19 syndrome or Long Covid has been estimated to impact 1.3 million individuals in the UK. This study evaluates the outcomes of delivering a complementary Long Covid support service using psycho-educational and mind-body approaches within a community setting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study utilised quantitative methods to evaluate the outcomes of implementing a complementary approach to providing Long Covid support. The service offered a package of care including group sessions combining psychoeducation and mind-body complementary approaches and optional 1:2:1 sessions (physiotherapy and craniosacral therapy (CST)). Screening for the service and health information was obtained using the Covid-19-Yorkshire Rehabilitation Screening tool (C-19 YRS). The impact of the service was assessed using the patient reported outcome measure: Warwick Holistic Health Questionnaire (WHHQ-18), and a survey was designed for general evaluation and feedback about the service from participants.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">25 participants engaged with the service. The C-19YRS proved to be a useful tool to screen service users. The WHHQ-18 highlighted a positive group change (<i>n</i>&#xa0;=&#xa0;16) in participants' mental, physical, emotional, and spiritual wellbeing: mean group score at the start&#xa0;=&#xa0;33.7 (SD=12.5), mean group score at the follow up&#xa0;=&#xa0;39.5 (SD=10.8). In the feedback from the service evaluation, participants reported that the service was useful in supporting them with their health challenges resulting from Long Covid and was delivered to the standard expected.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In conclusion the psycho-educational and mind-body complementary approaches used within this service were well received and the measures used to evaluate were suitable for a service delivered within a community setting.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Published by Elsevier GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brough</LastName><ForeName>Dr Nicola</ForeName><Initials>DN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Honorary Research Fellow, University of Warwick, Warwick Medical School, Department of Health Sciences, West Midlands, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abel</LastName><ForeName>Sally</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Torus Wellbeing CIC, Elgin Chambers, 24 Cemetery Road, Shelton, Stoke on Trent, ST4 2DL, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Priddle</LastName><ForeName>Lucy</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Skills Exchange Programme Keele University, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Integr Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518381</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1876-3820</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community setting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Complementary and integrative healthcare</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychoeducation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Service evaluation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>NB &amp; SA are practitioners of CST &amp; Physiotherapy and may gain an increase in clients because of publishing this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36035093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9392656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eujim.2022.102182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1876-3820(22)00083-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>(ONS), O.F.N.S., Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK 2022: London. p. 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W.H.O. World Health Organisation; 2021. A Clinical Case Definition of Post COVID-19 Condition By a Delphi consensus; p. 20. vi.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W.H.O. World Health Organisation: Europe; 2021. Support For rehabilitation: Self-Management After COVID-19-related Illness.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moynihan R., et al. Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on utilisation of healthcare services: a systematic review. British Med. J. Open. 2021;11 e0453435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7969768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33727273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brough N., et al. Perspectives on the effects and mechanisms of craniosacral therapy: a qualitative study of users' views. Eur. J. Integr. Med. 2015;7(2):172&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CSP. and C.S.o . The Chartered Society of Physiotherapists; London, UK: 2021. Physiotherapist, Safety First Approach to Long Covid Assessment, in Frontline.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green C., et al. A systematic review of craniosacral therapy: biological plausibility, assessment reliability and clinical effectiveness. Complement Ther. Med. 1999;7(4):201&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10709302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brough N., et al. Perspectives on the effect and mechanisms of craniosacral therapy: a qualitative study of users' views. Eur. J. Integr. Med. 2015;7:172&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro-Sanchez A.M., et al. Benefits of craniosacral therapy in patients with chronic low back pain: a randomized controlled trial. J. Altern. Compl. Med. 2016;22(8):650&#x2013;657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27347698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mataran-Penarrocha G.A., et al. Influence of craniosacral therapy on anxiety, depression and quality of life in patients with fibromyalgia. Evidence-based Compl. Altern. Med. 2011 2011 (no pagination)(178769)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3135864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19729492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro-Sanchez A.M., et al. A randomized controlled trial investigating the effects of craniosacral therapy on pain and heart rate variability in fibromyalgia patients. Clin. Rehabil. 2011;25(1):25&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20702514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fund, T.K. What is social prescribing? 2017 [cited 2022 12 August 2022]; Available from: https://www.kingsfund.org.uk/publications/social-prescribing?gclid=CjwKCAjw9NeXBhAMEiwAbaY4lp9S2_ZyFB5Mwmzs1MyenQM6DYgMunwU9QQJJYtb9L9YI12fxsnJghoCpXYQAvD_BwE#what-is-it.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biggs A., et al. A Survey of craniosacral therapy (CST) practitioners. Profiling practice and informing organisational strategy. Eur. J. Integr. Med. 2015:684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M., Halpin S., Gee J. Assessing long-term rehabilitation needs in COVID-19 survivors using a telephone screening tool (C19-YRS tool) Adv. Clin. Neurosci. Rehabil. 2020;19(4):14&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brough N., et al. Development and validation of a PROM to capture holistic outcomes in traditional, complementary and integrative medicine - the warwick holistic health questionnaire (WHHQ-18) Eur. J. Integr. Med. 2021;47</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>England P.H. Public Health England; London: 2015. Local Action on Health Inequalities: Improving Health Literacy to Improve Health Inequalities.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor R.J., et al. The COVID-19 Yorkshire Rehabilitation Scale (C19-YRS): application and psychometric analysis in a post-COVID-19 syndrome cohort. J. Med. Virol. 2022;94(3):1027&#x2013;1034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34676578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huppert F.A., So T.T. Flourishing across Europe: application of a new conceptual framework for defining well-being. Soc. Indic. Res. 2013;110(3):837&#x2013;861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3545194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23329863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>