<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37264687</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>New-onset type 1 diabetes in children and adolescents as postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: A systematic review and meta-analysis of cohort studies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e28833</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e28833</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.28833</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection in children and adolescents may increase risk for a variety of post-acute sequelae including new-onset type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM). Therefore, this meta-analysis aims to estimate the risk of developing new-onset type 1 diabetes in children and adolescents as post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection.&#xa0;PubMed/MEDLINE, CENTRAL, and EMBASE were systematically searched up to March 20, 2023. A systematic review and subsequent meta-analyses were performed to calculate the pooled effect size, expressed as risk ratio (RR) with corresponding 95% confidence interval (CI) of each outcome based on a one-stage approach and the random-effects estimate of the pooled effect sizes of each outcome were generated with the use of the DerSimonian-Laird method.&#xa0;Eight reports from seven studies involving 11&#x2009;220&#x2009;530 participants (2&#x2009;140&#x2009;897 patients with a history of diagnosed SARS-CoV-2 infection and 9&#x2009;079&#x2009;633 participants in the respective control groups) were included. The included studies reported data from four U.S. medical claims databases covering more than 503 million patients (IQVIA, HealthVerity, TriNetX, and Cerner Real-World Data), and three national health registries for all children and adolescents in Norway, Scotland, and Denmark. It was shown that the risk of new-onset T1DM following SARS-CoV-2 infection in children and adolescents was 42% (95% CI 13%-77%, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002) higher compared with non-COVID-19 control groups. The risk of developing new-onset T1DM following SARS-CoV-2 infection was significantly higher (67%, 95% CI 32 %-112%, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0001) in children and adolescents between 0 and 11 years, but not in those between 12 and 17 years (RR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.10, 95% CI 0.54-2.23, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.79). We also found that the higher risk for developing new-onset T1DM following SARS-CoV-2 infection only exists in studies from the United States (RR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.70, 95% CI 1.37-2.11, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.00001) but not Europe (RR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.02, 95% CI 0.67-1.55, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.93). Furthermore, we found that SARS-CoV-2 infection was associated with an elevation in the risk of diabetic ketoacidosis (DKA) in children and adolescents compared with non-COVID-19 control groups (RR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.56, 95% CI 1.07-6.11, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.03).&#xa0;Our findings mainly obtained from US&#xa0;medical claims databases, suggest that SARS-CoV-2 infection is associated with higher risk of developing new-onset T1DM and diabetic ketoacidosis in children and adolescents. These findings highlight the need for targeted measures to raise public health practitioners and physician awareness to provide intervention strategies to reduce the risk of developing T1DM in children and adolescents who have had COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rahmati</LastName><ForeName>Masoud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4792-027X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Faculty of Literature and Human Sciences, Lorestan University, Khoramabad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yon</LastName><ForeName>Dong Keon</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1628-9948</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Digital Health, Medical Science Research Institute, Kyung Hee University Medical Center, Kyung Hee University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Kyung Hee University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Seung Won</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5632-5208</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Precision Medicine, Sungkyunkwan University School of Medicine, Suwon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Udeh</LastName><ForeName>Raphael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Newcastle, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McEVoy</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Newcastle, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>La Trobe Rural Health School, College of Science, Health and Engineering, La Trobe University, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Min Seo</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Digital Health, Samsung Advanced Institute for Health Sciences &amp; Technology (SAIHST), Sungkyunkwan University, Samsung Medical Center, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gyasi</LastName><ForeName>Razak M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>African Population and Health Research Center, Nairobi, Kenya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Naturopathic Medicine, Faculty of Health, Southern Cross University, Lismore, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>Hans</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Suzanne Dworak Peck School of Social Work, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xf3;pez S&#xe1;nchez</LastName><ForeName>Guillermo F</ForeName><Initials>GF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9897-5273</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Preventive Medicine and Public Health, Department of Public Health Sciences, University of Murcia, Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacob</LastName><ForeName>Louis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development Unit, Parc Sanitari Sant Joan de D&#xe9;u, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n Biom&#xe9;dica en Red de Salud Mental (CIBERSAM), ISCIII, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Lariboisi&#xe8;re-Fernand Widal Hospital, AP-HP, Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yusheng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Deparment of Orthopedics, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koyanagi</LastName><ForeName>Ai</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development Unit, Parc Sanitari Sant Joan de D&#xe9;u, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n Biom&#xe9;dica en Red de Salud Mental (CIBERSAM), ISCIII, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituci&#xf3; Catalana de Recerca i Estudis Avan&#xe7;ats (ICREA), Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Jae Il</ForeName><Initials>JI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2326-1820</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Lee</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Health, Performance, and Wellbeing, Anglia Ruskin University, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003922" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016883" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetic Ketoacidosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">children and adolescents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">new-onset type 1 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37264687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Naeimi R, Sepidarkish M, Mollalo A, et al. SARS-CoV-2 seroprevalence in children worldwide: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eclinicalmedicine. 2023;56:101786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett CE, Koyama AK, Alvarez P, et al. Risk for newly diagnosed diabetes&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;30 days after SARS-CoV-2 infection among persons aged&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;18 years-United States, March 1, 2020-June 28, 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71(2):59-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulseth H. SARS-CoV-2 infection and subsequent risk of type 1 diabetes in 1.2 million children. In&#xa0;Diabetologia. Springer one New York Plaza; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurissi E, Alameer M, Ageeli F, et al. The association between SARS-CoV-2 infection and diabetic ketoacidosis in patients with New-Onset diabetes: a retrospective study from a diabetic center in Saudi Arabia. Pediatr Rep. 2022;14(4):519-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall EK, Olaker VR, Kaelber DC, Xu R, Davis PB. Association of SARS-CoV-2 infection with new-onset type 1 diabetes among pediatric patients from 2020 to 2021. JAMA Network Open. 2022;5(9):e2233014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKeigue PM. Relation of incident type 1 diabetes to recent COVID-19 infection: cohort study using e-health record linkage in scotland. Diabetes Care. 2022;46(5):921-928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noorzae R, Junker TG, Hviid AP, Wohlfahrt J, Olsen SF. Risk of type 1 diabetes in children is not increased after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a nationwide prospective study in Denmark. Diabetes Care. 2023;46(6):1261-1264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qeadan F, Tingey B, Egbert J, et al. The associations between COVID-19 diagnosis, type 1 diabetes, and the risk of diabetic ketoacidosis: a nationwide cohort from the US using the cerner real-world data. PLoS One. 2022;17(4):e0266809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group DP. Incidence and trends of childhood type 1 diabetes worldwide 1990-1999. Diabetic Med. 2006;23(8):857-866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubino F, Amiel SA, Zimmet P, et al. New-onset diabetes in Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(8):789-790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmati M, Keshvari M, Mirnasuri S, et al. The global impact of COVID-19 pandemic on the incidence of pediatric new-onset type 1 diabetes and ketoacidosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2022;94(11):5112-5127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ssentongo P, Zhang Y, Witmer L, Chinchilli VM, Ba DM. Association of COVID-19 with diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):20191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Mei Q, Zhang Z, et al. Risk for newly diagnosed diabetes after COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Med. 2022;20(1):444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SW, Koo MJ. PRISMA 2020 statement and guidelines for systematic review and meta-analysis articles, and their underlying mathematics: life cycle committee recommendations. Life Cycle. 2022;2:e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksen MB, Frandsen TF. The impact of patient, intervention, comparison, outcome (PICO) as a search strategy tool on literature search quality: a systematic review. J Med Libr Assoc. 2018;106(4):420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stang A. Critical evaluation of the Newcastle-Ottawa scale for the assessment of the quality of nonrandomized studies in meta-analyses. Eur J Epidemiol. 2010;25(9):603-605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catherine JP, Russell MV, Peter CH. The impact of race and socioeconomic factors on paediatric diabetes. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;42:101186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vries SAG, Verheugt CL, Mul D, Nieuwdorp M, Sas TCJ. Do sex differences in paediatric type 1 diabetes care exist? A systematic review. Diabetologia. 2023;66:618-630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Houwelingen HC, Zwinderman KH, Stijnen T. A bivariate approach to meta-analysis. Stat Med. 1993;12(24):2273-2284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stijnen T, Hamza TH, &#xd6;zdemir P. Random effects meta-analysis of event outcome in the framework of the generalized linear mixed model with applications in sparse data. Stat Med. 2010;29(29):3046-3067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SW. Methods for testing statistical differences between groups in medical research: statistical standard and guideline of life cycle committee. Life Cycle. 2022;2:e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. International Statistical Classification of Diseases and related health problems: Alphabetical index. Vol 3. World Health Organization; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu JY, Wilson J, Hou W, et al. Incidence of new-onset in-hospital and persistent diabetes in COVID-19 patients: comparison with influenza. EBioMedicine. 2023;90:104487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J-K, Lin SS, Ji XJ, Guo LM. Binding of SARS coronavirus to its receptor damages islets and causes acute diabetes. Acta Diabetol. 2010;47:193-199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bronson SC. Practical scenarios and day-to-day challenges in the management of diabetes in COVID-19-dealing with the &#x2018;double trouble. Primary Care Diabetes. 2021;15(4):737-739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suresh V, Parida D, Minz AP, Sethi M, Sahoo BS, Senapati S. Tissue distribution of ACE2 protein in Syrian golden hamster (Mesocricetus auratus) and its possible implications in SARS-CoV-2 related studies. Front Pharmacol. 2021;11:579330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coate KC, Cha J, Shrestha S, et al. SARS-CoV-2 cell entry factors ACE2 and TMPRSS2 are expressed in the microvasculature and ducts of human pancreas but are not enriched in &#x3b2; cells. Cell Metab. 2020;32(6):1028-1040.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C-T, Lidsky PV, Xiao Y, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infects human pancreatic &#x3b2; cells and elicits &#x3b2; cell impairment. Cell Metab. 2021;33(8):1565-1576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunti K, Del Prato S, Mathieu C, Kahn SE, Gabbay RA, Buse JB. COVID-19, hyperglycemia, and new-onset diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2021;44(12):2645-2655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamrath C, Rosenbauer J, Eckert AJ, et al. Incidence of type 1 diabetes in children and adolescents during the COVID-19 pandemic in Germany: results from the DPV registry. Diabetes Care. 2022;45(8):1762-1771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finlay BB, Amato KR, Azad M, et al. The hygiene hypothesis, the COVID pandemic, and consequences for the human microbiome. Proc&#xa0;Nat&#xa0;Acad&#xa0;Sci. 2021;118(6):e2010217118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traversi D, Rabbone I, Scaioli G, et al. Risk factors for type 1 diabetes, including environmental, behavioural and gut microbial factors: a case-control study. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):17566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourabbasi A, et al. Association of diabetes mellitus and structural changes in the central nervous system in children and adolescents: a systematic review. J Diabetes &amp; Metabo Dis. 2017;16:1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagnum V, Stene LC, Jenssen TG, et al. Causes of death in childhood-onset Type 1 diabetes: long-term follow-up. Diabetic Med. 2017;34(1):56-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasag DR, Gregory JW, Dayan C, Harvey JN. Excess all-cause mortality before age 30 in childhood onset type 1 diabetes: data from the Brecon Group Cohort in Wales. Arch Dis Child. 2018;103(1):44-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edge JA, Ford-Adams ME, Dunger DB. Causes of death in children with insulin dependent diabetes 1990-96. Arch Dis Child. 1999;81(4):318-323.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>