<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39424264</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-7544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroscience</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The tryptophan catabolite or kynurenine pathway in Long COVID disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0306-4522(24)00532-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.neuroscience.2024.10.021</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Recent studies confirm the involvement of activated immune-inflammatory responses and increased oxidative and nitrosative stress in Long COVID (LC) disease. However, the influence of these pathways on the metabolism of tryptophan (TRP) through the TRP catabolite (TRYCAT) pathway and their mediating effects on LC pathophysiology, has not been fully explored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This meta-analysis investigates peripheral TRP and TRYCAT levels and the TRYCAT pathway in patients with LC disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">This review utilized systematic searches of PubMed, Google Scholar, and SciFinder, including 14 full-text articles and 1,167 participants, consisting of 480 patients with LC and 687 normal controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The results indicated a significant increase in the kynurenine (KYN)/TRP ratio, with a large effect size (standardized mean difference, SMD = 0.755; confidence intervals, CI: 0.119;1.392), in LC patients compared to normal controls. Additionally, LC patients exhibited a significant decrease in TRP levels (SMD = -0.520, CI: -0.793; -0.246) and an increase in KYN levels after imputing missing studies (SMD = 1.176, CI: 0.474; 1.877), suggesting activation of the Indoleamine 2,3-dioxygenase (IDO) enzyme and upregulation of the TRYCAT pathway. No significant elevation in TRYCAT-related neurotoxicity, kynurenic acid (KA)/KYN and 3-hydroxykynurenine (3-HK)/KYN ratios were observed in LC patients compared to normal controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The current findings indicate that an activated TRYCAT pathway, characterized by decreased TRP levels and maybe elevated KYN levels, plays a significant role in the pathophysiology of LC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 International Brain Research Organization (IBRO). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almulla</LastName><ForeName>Abbas F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Laboratory Technology Department, College of Medical Technology, The Islamic University, Najaf, Iraq; Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thipakorn</LastName><ForeName>Yanin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Provincial Center for Mental Health, Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, School of Medicine, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu 610072, China; Key Laboratory of Psychosomatic Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Chengdu 610072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vojdani</LastName><ForeName>Aristo</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Immunosciences Lab, Inc., Los Angeles, CA 90035, USA; Cyrex Laboratories, LLC, Phoenix, AZ 85034, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paunova</LastName><ForeName>Rossitsa</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Medical University of Plovdiv, Plovdiv, Bulgaria; Research Institute, Medical University of Plovdiv, Plovdiv, Bulgaria; Strategic Research and Innovation Program for the Development of MU - PLOVDIV-(SRIPD-MUP), European Union - NextGenerationEU, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maes</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand; Sichuan Provincial Center for Mental Health, Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, School of Medicine, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu 610072, China; Key Laboratory of Psychosomatic Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Chengdu 610072, China; Department of Psychiatry, Medical University of Plovdiv, Plovdiv, Bulgaria; Research Institute, Medical University of Plovdiv, Plovdiv, Bulgaria; Strategic Research and Innovation Program for the Development of MU - PLOVDIV-(SRIPD-MUP), European Union - NextGenerationEU, Bulgaria; Cognitive Impairment and Dementia Research Unit, Faculty of Medicine, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand; Cognitive Fitness and Biopsychological Technology Research Unit, Faculty of Medicine, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok 10330, Thailand; Kyung Hee University, 26 Kyungheedae-ro, Dongdaemun-gu, Seoul 02447, Republic of Korea. Electronic address: dr.michaelmaes@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroscience</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605074</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0306-4522</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroimmune</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurotoxicity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative and nitrosative stress</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39424264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroscience.2024.10.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0306-4522(24)00532-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>