<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">34110078</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1462-2920</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19: long covid and its societal consequences.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4077</StartPage><EndPage>4091</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4077-4091</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1462-2920.15634</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>COVID-19 is an acute, highly transmissible respiratory infection that is potentially lethal, but often mild, sometimes asymptomatic, especially in the young. However, it has become clear that, in some patients, there may be sequelae involving tissues other than the lung, resulting in other types of morbidity, and sometimes longer term consequences that are often termed 'long covid'. In this Lilliput, we summarize recent findings about COVID-19 sequelae, with a particular focus on long covid. We also discuss some of the long scars that COVID-19 and long covid will collectively leave on society that we term Societal Long Covid.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Society for Applied Microbiology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Br&#xfc;ssow</LastName><ForeName>Harald</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4783-8583</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>KU Leuven, Department of Biosystems, Laboratory of Gene Technology, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Timmis</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0066-4670</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Microbiology, Technical University of Braunschweig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883692</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1462-2912</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012924" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Conditions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34110078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1462-2920.15634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Ackermann, M., Verleden, S.E., Kuehnel, M., Haverich, A., Welte, T., Laenger, F., et al. (2020) Pulmonary vascular Endothelialitis, thrombosis, and angiogenesis in Covid-19. N Engl J Med 383: 120-128. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2015432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, H., Patel, K., Greenwood, D.C., Halpin, S., Lewthwaite, P., Salawu, A., et al. (2020) Long-term clinical outcomes in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus outbreaks after hospitalisation or ICU admission: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Rehabil Med 52: jrm00063. https://doi.org/10.2340/16501977-2694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly, Z., Xie, Y., and Bowe, B. (2021) High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 594: 259-264. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-021-03553-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anonymous. (2020) Long COVID: let patients help define long-lasting COVID symptoms. Nature 586: 170. https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-020-02796-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe9;n&#xe9;zit, F., Le Turnier, P., Declerck, C., Paill&#xe9;, C., Revest, M., Dub&#xe9;e, V., et al. (2020) Utility of hyposmia and hypogeusia for the diagnosis of COVID-19. Lancet Infect Dis 20: 1014-1015. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30297-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlin, D.A., Gulick, R.M., and Martinez, F.J. (2020) Severe Covid-19. N Engl J Med 383: 2451-2460. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMcp2009575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boscolo-Rizzo, P., Borsetto, D., Fabbris, C., Spinato, G., Frezza, D., Menegaldo, A., et al. (2020) Evolution of altered sense of smell or taste in patients with mildly symptomatic COVID-19. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 146: 729-732. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaoto.2020.1379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley, B.T., Maioli, H., Johnston, R., Chaudhry, I., Fink, S.L., Xu, H., et al. (2020) Histopathology and ultrastructural findings of fatal COVID-19 infections in Washington State: a case series. Lancet 396: 320-332. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31305-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec;, A., Bernabei, R., Landi, F., and Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. (2020) Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA 324: 603-605. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.12603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Schneider, C., Laurent, E., Lemaignen, A., Beaufils, E., Bourbao-Tournois, C., Laribi, S., et al. (2021) Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Clin Microbiol Infect 27: 258-263. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2020.09.052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalli, G., De Luca, G., Campochiaro, C., Della-Torre, E., Ripa, M., Canetti, D., et al. (2020) Interleukin-1 blockade with high-dose anakinra in patients with COVID-19, acute respiratory distress syndrome, and hyperinflammation: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet Rheumatol 2: e325-e331. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2665-9913(20)30127-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra, V., Flanders, S.A., O'Malley, M., Malani, A.N., and Prescott, H.C. (2021) Sixty-day outcomes among patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Ann Intern Med 174: 576-578. https://doi.org/10.7326/M20-5661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, H.E., Assaf, G.S., McCorkell, L., Wei, H., Low, R.J., Re'em, Y., et al. (2020) Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. medRxiv. https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.12.24.20248802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis, A., Wamil, M., Kapur, S., Alberts, J., Badley, A., Decker, A.D., et al. (2020) Multi-organ impairment in low-risk individuals with long COVID. medRxiv. https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.10.14.20212555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durrant, D.M., Ghosh, S., and Klein, R.S. (2016) The olfactory bulb: an immunosensory effector organ during neurotropic viral infections. ACS Chem Nerosci 7: 464-469. https://doi.org/10.1021/acschemneuro.6b00043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox, S.E., Akmatbekov, A., Harbert, J.L., Li, G., Quincy Brown, J., and Vander Heide, R.S. (2020) Pulmonary and cardiac pathology in African American patients with COVID-19: an autopsy series from New Orleans. Lancet Respir Med 8: 681-686. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30243-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandhi, R.T., Lynch, J.B., and Del Rio, C. (2020) Mild or moderate Covid-19. N Engl J Med 383: 1757-1766. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMcp2009249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues, E., Janvier, P., Kherabi, Y., Le Bot, A., Hamon, A., Gouze, H., et al. (2020) Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. J Infect 81: e4-e6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2020.08.029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant, R.A., Morales-Nebreda, L., Markov, N.S., Swaminathan, S., Querrey, M., Guzman, E.R., et al. (2021) Circuits between infected macrophages and T cells in SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia. Nature 590: 635-641. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-03148-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin, S.J., McIvor, C., Whyatt, G., Adams, A., Harvey, O., McLean, L., et al. (2021) Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol 93: 1013-1022. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.26368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havervall, S., Rosell, A., Phillipson, M., Mangsbo, S.M., Nilsson, P., Hober, S., and Th&#xe5;lin, C. (2021) Symptoms and functional impairment assessed 8 months after mild COVID-19 among health care workers. JAMA 325: 2015-2016. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2021.5612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honigsbaum, M. (2010) The great dread: cultural and psychological impacts and responses to the &#x201c;Russian&#x201d; influenza in the United Kingdom, 1889-1893. Soc Hist Med 23: 299-319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C., Huang, L., Wang, Y., Li, X., Ren, L., Gu, X., et al. (2021) 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet 397: 220-232. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs, L.G., Paleoudis, E.G., Leski-Di Bari, D., Nyirenda, T., Friedman, T., and Gupta, A. (2020) Persistence of symptoms and quality of life at 35 days after hospitalization for COVID-19 infection. PLoS One 15: e0243882. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0243882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondratiuk, A.L., Pillay, T.D., Kon, O.M., and Lalvani, A. (2021) A conceptual framework to accelerate the clinical impact of evolving research into long COVID. Lancet Infect Dis 21: 756-757. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00136-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindner, D., Fitzek, A., Br&#xe4;uninger, H., Aleshcheva, G., Edler, C., Meissner, K., et al. (2020) Association of cardiac infection with SARS-CoV-2 in confirmed COVID-19 autopsy cases. JAMA Cardiol 5: 1281-1285. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2020.3551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathew, D., Giles, J.R., Baxter, A.E., Oldridge, D.A., Greenplate, A.R., Wu, J.E., et al. (2020) Deep immune profiling of COVID-19 patients reveals distinct immunotypes with therapeutic implications. Science 369: eabc8511. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.abc8511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke, J., L&#xfc;tgehetmann, M., Hagel, C., Sperhake, J.P., Schr&#xf6;der, A.S., Edler, C., et al. (2020) Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol 19: 919-929. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30308-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Melo, G.D., Lazarini, F., Levallois, S., Hautefort, C., Michel, V., Larrous, F., et al. (2021) COVID-19-related anosmia is associated with viral persistence and inflammation in human olfactory epithelium and brain infection in hamsters. Sci Transl Med 13: eabf8396. https://doi.org/10.1126/scitranslmed.abf8396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez, O., Merino, E., Leon-Ramirez, J.M., Andres, M., Ramos, J.M., Arenas-Jim&#xe9;nez, J., et al. (2021) Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: a Mediterranean cohort study. J Infect 82: 378-383. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2021.01.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie, X., Qian, L., Sun, R., Huang, B., Dong, X., Xiao, Q., et al. (2021) Multi-organ proteomic landscape of COVID-19 autopsies. Cell 184: 775-791.e14. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2021.01.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osikomaiya, B., Erinoso, O., Wright, K.O., Odusola, A.O., Thomas, B., Adeyemi, O., et al. (2021) &#x2018;Long COVID&#x2019;: persistent COVID-19 symptoms in survivors managed in Lagos state, Nigeria. BMC Infect Dis 21: 304. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12879-020-05716-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puelles, V.G., L&#xfc;tgehetmann, M., Lindenmeyer, M.T., Sperhake, J.P., Wong, M.N., Allweiss, L., et al. (2020) Multiorgan and renal tropism of SARS-CoV-2. N Engl J Med 383: 590-592. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMc2011400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntmann, V.O., Carerj, M.L., Wieters, I., Fahim, M., Arendt, C., Hoffmann, J., et al. (2020) Outcomes of cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in patients recently recovered from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiol 5: 1265-1273. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2020.3557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin, R. (2020) As their numbers grow, COVID-19 &#x201c;Long Haulers&#x201d; stump experts. JAMA 324: 1381-1383. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.17709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Say, D., Crawford, N., McNab, S., Wurzel, D., Steer, A., and Tosif, S. (2021) Post-acute COVID-19 outcomes in children with mild and asymptomatic disease. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 5: e22-e23. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2352-4642(21)00124-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre, C.H., Murray, B., Varsavsky, T., Graham, M.S., Penfold, R.S., Bowyer, R.C., et al. (2021) Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med 27: 626-631. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taboada, M., Cari&#xf1;ena, A., Moreno, E., Rodr&#xed;guez, N., Dom&#xed;nguez, M.J., Casal, A., et al. (2021). Post-COVID-19 functional status six-months after hospitalization. J Infect 82: e31-e33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde, M.W., Kim, S.S., Lindsell, C.J., Billig Rose, E., Shapiro, N.I., Files, D.C., et al. (2020) Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network - United States, march-June 2020. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 69: 993-998. https://doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm6930e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmis, K. (2020) COVID-19 transmission: economy-boosting investment should target innovation in pandemic containment strategies to minimize restrictions of civil liberties. Environ Microbiol 22: 4527-4531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmis, K., and Br&#xfc;ssow, H. (2020) The COVID-19 pandemic: some lessons learned about crisis preparedness and management, and the need for international benchmarking to reduce deficits. Environ Microbiol 22: 1986-1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmis, K., Huang, W.E., and Timmis, J. (2020) Strategies to minimize preventable morbidity and mortality resulting from pandemics like COVID-19. Environ Microbiol 22: 4085-4092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wichmann, D., Sperhake, J.P., L&#xfc;tgehetmann, M., Steurer, S., Edler, C., Heinemann, A., et al. (2020) Autopsy findings and venous thromboembolism in patients with COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Ann Intern Med 173: 268-277. https://doi.org/10.7326/M20-2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, Y., Bowe, B., Maddukuri, G., and Al-Aly, Z. (2020) Comparative evaluation of clinical manifestations and risk of death in patients admitted to hospital with covid-19 and seasonal influenza: cohort study. BMJ 371: m4677. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m4677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xydakis, M.S., Dehgani-Mobaraki, P., Holbrook, E.H., Geisthoff, U.W., Bauer, C., Hautefort, C., et al. (2020) Smell and taste dysfunction in patients with COVID-19. Lancet Infect Dis 20: 1015-1016. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30293-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L., Richards, A., Barrasa, M.I., Hughes, S.H., Young, R.A., and Jaenisch, R. (2021) Reverse-transcribed SARS-CoV-2 RNA can integrate into the genome of cultured human cells and can be expressed in patient-derived tissues. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 118: e2105968118. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2105968118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y.M., Shang, Y.M., Song, W.B., Li, Q.Q., Xie, H., Xu, Q.F., et al. (2020) Follow-up study of the pulmonary function and related physiological characteristics of COVID-19 survivors three months after recovery. EClinicalMedicine 25: 100463. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100463.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>