<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38206585</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-7385</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>103</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of physical medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Phys Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhanced External Counterpulsation Improves Cognitive Function of Persons With Long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>734</StartPage><EndPage>739</EndPage><MedlinePgn>734-739</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PHM.0000000000002433</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this study is to determine the effects of enhanced external counterpulsation (EECP) in patients with long COVID and objectively assessed cognitive impairment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN">A retrospective evaluation of long COVID patients referred for EECP, with cognitive sequela, and having completed an objective digital assessment before and after therapy. Patients had either cognitive impairment or no cognitive impairment at baseline. We assessed changes in composite score using multifactor analysis of variance. Multiple linear and logistic regression analyses were conducted to evaluate several independent variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Eighty long COVID patients (38 cognitive impairment vs. 42 no cognitive impairment) were included for analyses. All baseline characteristics were well matched. There was significant improvement in composite score post EECP in those with objective cognitive impairment at baseline. There were no notable documented safety concerns.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This is the first study showing that EECP led to significant improvement in cognitive functioning of long COVID patients with objectively defined cognitive impairment. Although a lack of a negative control group is a limitation of this study, EECP seems to be highly safe and effective with the potential for widespread application.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sathyamoorthy</LastName><ForeName>Mohanakrishnan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Internal Medicine, Burnett School of Medicine at Texas Christian University, Fort Worth, Texas (MS); Consultants in Cardiovascular Medicine and Science-Fort Worth, Fort Worth, Texas (MS); Department of Pharmacy Practice, Thomas J Long School of Pharmacy, University of the Pacific, Stockton, California (RJS, SAS); Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, UT Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas (JC, ML); Flow Therapy, Fort Worth, Texas (JF, SAS); and Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Joe R. and Teresa Lozano Long School of Medicine, San Antonio, Texas (MV-G).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sevak</LastName><ForeName>Rajkumar J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cabrera</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopez</LastName><ForeName>Marielisa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fox</LastName><ForeName>Jessie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Sachin A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verduzco-Gutierrez</LastName><ForeName>Monica</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Phys Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8803677</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0894-9115</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015908" MajorTopicYN="Y">Counterpulsation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Financial disclosure statements have been obtained, and no conflicts of interest have been reported by the authors or by any individuals in control of the content of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38206585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000002433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00002060-990000000-00397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Phillips S, Williams MA: Confronting our next national health disaster&#x2014;long-haul COVID. N Engl J Med 2021;385:577&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health + Long COVID Human-Centered Design Report . U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, 2022. Available at: https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/healthplus-long-covid-report.pdf . Accessed October 17, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach K: New data shows long COVID is keeping as many as 4 million people out of work. Available at: https://www.brookings.edu/research/new-data-shows-long-covid-is-keeping-as-many-as-4-million-people-out-of-work/ . Aug 24, 2022. Accessed October 10, 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj L, Kannapadi NV, Briggs J, et al.: Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: a meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci 2022;434:120162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneghan AM, Lewis KA, Gill E, et al.: Cognitive impairment in non-critical, mild-to-moderate COVID-19 survivors. Front Psychol 2022;13:770459</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boldrini M, Canoll PD, Klein RS: How COVID-19 affects the brain. JAMA Psychiatry 2021;78:682&#x2013;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dondaine T, Ruthmann F, Vuotto F, et al.: Long-term cognitive impairments following COVID-19: a possible impact of hypoxia. J Neurol 2022;269:3982&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrucci R, Dini M, Groppo E, et al.: Long-lasting cognitive abnormalities after COVID-19. Brain Sci 2021;11:235</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera E, P&#xe9;rez-S&#xe1;nchez MDC, San Miguel-Abella R, et al.: Cognitive impairment in young adults with post COVID-19 syndrome. Sci Rep 2023;13:6378</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams JA, Uryash A, Lopez JR, et al.: The endothelium as a therapeutic target in diabetes: a narrative review and perspective. Front Physiol 2021;12:638491</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin S, Xiao-Ming W, Gui-Fu W: Expert consensus on the clinical application of enhanced external counterpulsation in elderly people (2019). Aging Med (Milton) 2020;3:16&#x2013;24</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Zhao Y, Wang X, et al.: Low carotid artery wall shear stress is independently associated with brain white-matter hyperintensities and cognitive impairment in older patients. Atherosclerosis 2016;247:78&#x2013;86</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriarty PM, Badawi AH, Lepping RJ, et al.: External counterpulsation therapy for patients with mild cognitive impairment. Austin J Clin Med 2016;3:1029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BrainCheck Clinical User Guide. Available at: https://braincheck.com/resources/using-braincheck/ . 2014-2022. Accessed September 1, 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuyler R: Interpreting Cognitive Testing Results . Available at: https://braincheck.com/articles/interpreting-cognitive-testing-results/ . December 11, 2019. Accessed October 10, 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye S, Sun K, Huynh D, et al.: A computerized cognitive test battery for detection of dementia and mild cognitive impairment: instrument validation study. JMIR Aging 2022;5:e36825</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathyamoorthy M, Verduzco-Gutierrez M, Varanasi S, et al.: Enhanced external counterpulsation for management of symptoms associated with long COVID. Am Heart J Plus 2022;13:100105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanou MI, Palaiodimou L, Bakola E, et al.: Neurological manifestations of long-COVID syndrome: a narrative review. Ther Adv Chronic Dis 2022;13:20406223221076890</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callan C, Ladds E, Husain L, et al.: &#x2018;I can't cope with multiple inputs&#x2019;: a qualitative study of the lived experience of &#x2018;brain fog&#x2019; after COVID-19. BMJ Open 2022;12:e056366</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown K, Yahyouche A, Haroon S, et al.: Long COVID and self-management. Lancet 2022;399:P355</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melamed E, Rydberg L, Ambrose AF, et al.: Multi-disciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of neurologic sequelae in patients with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) [published online ahead of print, 2023 Mar 29]. PM R 2023. doi:10.1002/pmrj.12976</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmrj.12976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine JS, Ambrose AF, Didehbani N, et al.: Multi-disciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of cognitive symptoms in patients with post-acute sequelae of SARS-Cov-2 infection (PASC). PM R 2022;14:96&#x2013;111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolin S, Chakales A, Verduzco-Gutierrez M: Rehabilitation strategies for cognitive and neuropsychiatric manifestations of COVID-19. Curr Phys Med Rehabil Rep 2022;10:182&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ionescu M, Stoian AP, Rizzo M, et al.: The role of endothelium in COVID-19. Int J Mol Sci 2021;22:11920</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y, Ji W, Yang H, et al.: Endothelial activation and dysfunction in COVID-19: from basic mechanisms to potential therapeutic approaches. Signal Transduct Target Ther 2020;5:293</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moretta P, Maniscalco M, Papa A, et al.: Cognitive impairment and endothelial dysfunction in convalescent COVID-19 patients undergoing rehabilitation. Eur J Clin Invest 2022;52:e13726</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisicaro F, Di Napoli M, Liberto A, et al.: Neurological sequelae in patients with COVID-19: a histopathological perspective. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021;18:1415</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowenstein CJ, Solomon SD: Severe COVID-19 is a microvascular disease. Circulation 2020;142:1609&#x2013;11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fluge &#xd8;, Tronstad KJ, Mella O: Pathomechanisms and possible interventions in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). J Clin Invest 2021;131:e150377</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonetti PO, Barsness GW, Keelan PC, et al.: Enhanced external counterpulsation improves endothelial function in patients with symptomatic coronary artery disease. J Am Coll Cardiol 2003;41:1761&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan K, Lin Y, Prewitt KM, et al.: Multidisciplinary approach to brain fog and related persisting symptoms post COVID-19. J Health Serv Psychol 2022;48:31&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalechstein AD, De La Garza R 2nd, Newton TF: Modafinil administration improves working memory in methamphetamine-dependent individuals who demonstrate baseline impairment. Am J Addict 2010;19:340&#x2013;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barczyk ZA, Douglas KM, Porter RJ: Baseline predictors of cognitive change in the treatment of major depressive episode: systematic review. BJPsych Open 2020;6:e131</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>