<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37167361</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1524-4571</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>132</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Circulation research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Circ Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cell-Specific Mechanisms in the Heart of COVID-19 Patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1290</StartPage><EndPage>1301</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1290-1301</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.321876</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>From the onset of the pandemic, evidence of cardiac involvement in acute COVID-19 abounded. Cardiac presentations ranged from arrhythmias to ischemia, myopericarditis/myocarditis, ventricular dysfunction to acute heart failure, and even cardiogenic shock. Elevated serum cardiac troponin levels were prevalent among hospitalized patients with COVID-19; the higher the magnitude of troponin elevation, the greater the COVID-19 illness severity and in-hospital death risk. Whether these consequences were due to direct SARS-CoV-2 infection of cardiac cells or secondary to inflammatory responses steered early cardiac autopsy studies. SARS-CoV-2 was reportedly detected in endothelial cells, cardiac myocytes, and within the extracellular space. However, findings were inconsistent and different methodologies had their limitations. Initial autopsy reports suggested that SARS-CoV-2 myocarditis was common, setting off studies to find and phenotype inflammatory infiltrates in the heart. Nonetheless, subsequent studies rarely detected myocarditis. Microthrombi, cardiomyocyte necrosis, and inflammatory infiltrates without cardiomyocyte damage were much more common. In vitro and ex vivo experimental platforms have assessed the cellular tropism of SARS-CoV-2 and elucidated mechanisms of viral entry into and replication within cardiac cells. Data point to pericytes as the primary target of SARS-CoV-2 in the heart. Infection of pericytes can account for the observed pericyte and endothelial cell death, innate immune response, and immunothrombosis commonly observed in COVID-19 hearts. These processes are bidirectional and synergistic, rendering a definitive order of events elusive. Single-cell/nucleus analyses of COVID-19 myocardial tissue and isolated cardiac cells have provided granular data about the cellular composition and cell type-specific transcriptomic signatures of COVID-19 and microthrombi-positive COVID-19 hearts. Still, much remains unknown and more in vivo studies are needed. This review seeks to provide an overview of the current understanding of COVID-19 cardiac pathophysiology. Cell type-specific mechanisms and the studies that provided such insights will be highlighted. Given the unprecedented pace of COVID-19 research, more mechanistic details are sure to emerge since the writing of this review. Importantly, our current knowledge offers significant clues about the cardiac pathophysiology of long COVID-19, the increased postrecovery risk of cardiac events, and thus, the future landscape of cardiovascular disease.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsai</LastName><ForeName>Emily J</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5098-1463</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Columbia University Vagelos College of Physicians &amp; Surgeons, New York, NY (E.J.T.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>C&#x2c7;ih&#xe1;kov&#xe1;</LastName><ForeName>Daniela</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8713-2860</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD (D.C.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tucker</LastName><ForeName>Nathan R</ForeName><Initials>NR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5071-4218</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Masonic Medical Research Institute, Utica, NY (N.R.T.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 HL138528</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 HL118183</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 HL136586</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K01 HL140187</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Circ Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0047103</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0009-7330</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014336">Troponin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>Circ Res. 2023 Jun 23;133(1):e18. doi: 10.1161/RES.0000000000000615</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37347837</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009205" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myocarditis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042783" MajorTopicYN="N">Endothelial Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017052" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospital Mortality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006321" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006331" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014336" MajorTopicYN="N">Troponin</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D032383" MajorTopicYN="N">Myocytes, Cardiac</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endothelial cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myocardium</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pericytes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">single-cell analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thromboinflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viral tropism</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>Disclosures</b> None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37167361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10171292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.321876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Daugherty SE, Guo Y, Heath K, Dasmarinas MC, Jubilo KG, Samranvedhya J, Lipsitch M, Cohen K. Risk of clinical sequelae after the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;373:n1098. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n1098</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8132065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28:583&#x2013;590. doi: 10.1038/s41591-022-01689-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35132265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figliozzi S, Masci PG, Ahmadi N, Tondi L, Koutli E, Aimo A, Stamatelopoulos K, Dimopoulos MA, Caforio ALP, Georgiopoulos G. Predictors of adverse prognosis in COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Clin Invest. 2020;50:e13362. doi: 10.1111/eci.13362</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32726868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasoni D, Inciardi RM, Lombardi CM, Tedino C, Agostoni P, Ameri P, Barbieri L, Bellasi A, Camporotondo R, Canale C, et al. . Impact of heart failure on the clinical course and outcomes of patients hospitalized for COVID-19. Results of the Cardio-COVID-Italy multicentre study. Eur J Heart Fail. 2020;22:2238&#x2013;2247. doi: 10.1002/ejhf.2052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33179839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Yu T, Du R, Fan G, Liu Y, Liu Z, Xiang J, Wang Y, Song B, Gu X, et al. . Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet. 2020;395:1054&#x2013;1062. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30566-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32171076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arentz M, Yim E, Klaff L, Lokhandwala S, Riedo FX, Chong M, Lee M. Characteristics and outcomes of 21 critically ill patients with COVID-19 in Washington state. JAMA. 2020;323:1612&#x2013;1614. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.4326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7082763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32191259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Wu D, Chen H, Yan W, Yang D, Chen G, Ma K, Xu D, Yu H, Wang H, et al. . Clinical characteristics of 113 deceased patients with coronavirus disease 2019: retrospective study. BMJ. 2020;368:m1091. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m1091</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7190011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo T, Fan Y, Chen M, Wu X, Zhang L, He T, Wang H, Wan J, Wang X, Lu Z. Cardiovascular implications of fatal outcomes of patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:811&#x2013;818. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2020.1017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7101506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32219356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi S, Qin M, Shen B, Cai Y, Liu T, Yang F, Gong W, Liu X, Liang J, Zhao Q, et al. . Association of cardiac injury with mortality in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:802&#x2013;810. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2020.0950</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32211816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lala A, Johnson KW, Januzzi JL, Russak AJ, Paranjpe I, Richter F, Zhao S, Somani S, Van Vleck T, Vaid A, et al. ; Mount Sinai COVID Informatics Center. Prevalence and impact of myocardial injury in patients hospitalized with COVID-19 infection. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76:533&#x2013;546. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2020.06.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7279721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32517963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falasca L, Nardacci R, Colombo D, Lalle E, Di Caro A, Nicastri E, Antinori A, Petrosillo N, Marchioni L, Biava G, et al. . Post-mortem findings in Italian patients with COVID-19 - a descriptive full autopsy study of cases with and without co-morbidities. J Infect Dis. 2020;222:1807&#x2013;1815. doi: 10.1093/infdis/jiaa578</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32914853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schurink B, Roos E, Radonic T, Barbe E, Bouman CSC, de Boer HH, de Bree GJ, Bulle EB, Aronica EM, Florquin S, et al. . Viral presence and immunopathology in patients with lethal COVID-19: a prospective autopsy cohort study. Lancet Microbe. 2020;1:e290&#x2013;e299. doi: 10.1016/S2666-5247(20)30144-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7518879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33015653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halushka MK, Vander Heide RS. Myocarditis is rare in COVID-19 autopsies: cardiovascular findings across 277 postmortem examinations. Cardiovasc Pathol. 2021;50:107300. doi: 10.1016/j.carpath.2020.107300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7583586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33132119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aretz HT, Billingham ME, Edwards WD, Factor SM, Fallon JT, Fenoglio JJ, Jr, Olsen EG, Schoen FJ. Myocarditis. A histopathologic definition and classification. Am J Cardiovasc Pathol. 1987;1:3&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3455232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson P, McKenna W, Bristow M, Maisch B, Mautner B, O&#x2019;Connell J, Olsen E, Thiene G, Goodwin J, Gyarfas I, et al. . Report of the 1995 World Health Organization/International Society and Federation of Cardiology Task Force on the Definition and Classification of cardiomyopathies. Circulation. 1996;93:841&#x2013;842. doi: 10.1161/01.cir.93.5.841</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8598070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basso C, Leone O, Rizzo S, De Gaspari M, van der Wal AC, Aubry MC, Bois MC, Lin PT, Maleszewski JJ, Stone JR. Pathological features of COVID-19-associated myocardial injury: a multicentre cardiovascular pathology study. Eur Heart J. 2020;41:3827&#x2013;3835. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa664</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32968776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bois MC, Boire NA, Layman AJ, Aubry MC, Alexander MP, Roden AC, Hagen CE, Quinton RA, Larsen C, Erben Y, et al. . COVID-19-associated nonocclusive fibrin microthrombi in the heart. Circulation. 2021;143:230&#x2013;243. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.050754</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7805556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33197204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brener MI, Hulke ML, Fukuma N, Golob S, Zilinyi RS, Zhou Z, Tzimas C, Russo I, McGroder C, Pfeiffer RD, et al. . Clinico-histopathologic and single-nuclei RNA-sequencing insights into cardiac injury and microthrombi in critical COVID-19. JCI Insight. 2022;7:e154633. doi: 10.1172/jci.insight.154633</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8855793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34905515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jum&#x2019;ah H, Kundrapu S, Jabri A, Kondapaneni M, Tomashefski JF, Loeffler AG. Cardiac macrophage density in Covid-19 infection: relationship to myocyte necrosis and acute lung injury. Cardiovasc Pathol. 2022;60:107447. doi: 10.1016/j.carpath.2022.107447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35718082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrini D, Kawakami R, Guagliumi G, Sakamoto A, Kawai K, Gianatti A, Nasr A, Kutys R, Guo L, Cornelissen A, et al. . Microthrombi as a major cause of cardiac injury in COVID-19: a pathologic study. Circulation. 2021;143:1031&#x2013;1042. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.051828</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33480806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajendran P, Rengarajan T, Thangavel J, Nishigaki Y, Sakthisekaran D, Sethi G, Nishigaki I. The vascular endothelium and human diseases. Int J Biol Sci. 2013;9:1057&#x2013;1069. doi: 10.7150/ijbs.7502</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3831119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24250251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y, Zhang L, Fan G, Xu J, Gu X, et al. . Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020;395:497&#x2013;506. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Kruip M, van der Meer NJM, Arbous MS, Gommers D, Kant KM, Kaptein FHJ, van Paassen J, Stals MAM, Huisman MV, et al. . Confirmation of the high cumulative incidence of thrombotic complications in critically ill ICU patients with COVID-19: an updated analysis. Thromb Res. 2020;191:148&#x2013;150. doi: 10.1016/j.thromres.2020.04.041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7192101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32381264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodigiani C, Iapichino G, Carenzo L, Cecconi M, Ferrazzi P, Sebastian T, Kucher N, Studt JD, Sacco C, Bertuzzi A, et al. ; Humanitas COVID-19 Task Force. Venous and arterial thromboembolic complications in COVID-19 patients admitted to an academic hospital in Milan, Italy. Thromb Res. 2020;191:9&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1016/j.thromres.2020.04.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7177070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32353746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middeldorp S, Coppens M, van Haaps TF, Foppen M, Vlaar AP, Muller MCA, Bouman CCS, Beenen LFM, Kootte RS, Heijmans J, et al. . Incidence of venous thromboembolism in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. J Thromb Haemost. 2020;18:1995&#x2013;2002. doi: 10.1111/jth.14888</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7497052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32369666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wichmann D, Sperhake JP, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Steurer S, Edler C, Heinemann A, Heinrich F, Mushumba H, Kniep I, Schr&#xf6;der AS, et al. . Autopsy findings and venous thromboembolism in patients with COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Ann Intern Med. 2020;173:268&#x2013;277. doi: 10.7326/M20-2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7240772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32374815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Won T, Wood MK, Hughes DM, Talor MV, Ma Z, Schneider J, Skinner JT, Asady B, Goerlich E, Halushka MK, et al. . Endothelial thrombomodulin downregulation caused by hypoxia contributes to severe infiltration and coagulopathy in COVID-19 patient lungs. EBioMedicine. 2022;75:103812. doi: 10.1016/j.ebiom.2022.103812</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8756077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35033854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah S, Shah K, Patel SB, Patel FS, Osman M, Velagapudi P, Turagam MK, Lakkireddy D, Garg J. Elevated D-dimer levels are associated with increased risk of mortality in coronavirus disease 2019: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cardiol Rev. 2020;28:295&#x2013;302. doi: 10.1097/CRD.0000000000000330</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7437424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33017364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connors JM, Brooks MM, Sciurba FC, Krishnan JA, Bledsoe JR, Kindzelski A, Baucom AL, Kirwan BA, Eng H, Martin D, et al. ; ACTIV-4B Investigators. Effect of antithrombotic therapy on clinical outcomes in outpatients with clinically stable symptomatic COVID-19: the ACTIV-4B randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2021;326:1703&#x2013;1712. doi: 10.1001/jama.2021.17272</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8506296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34633405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moores LK, Tritschler T, Brosnahan S, Carrier M, Collen JF, Doerschug K, Holley AB, Jimenez D, Le Gal G, Rali P, et al. . Prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of VTE in patients with coronavirus disease 2019: CHEST guideline and expert panel report. Chest. 2020;158:1143&#x2013;1163. doi: 10.1016/j.chest.2020.05.559</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7265858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32502594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spyropoulos AC, Levy JH, Ageno W, Connors JM, Hunt BJ, Iba T, Levi M, Samama CM, Thachil J, Giannis D, et al. ; Subcommittee on Perioperative, Critical Care Thrombosis, Haemostasis of the Scientific, Standardization Committee of the International Society on Thrombosis and Haemostasis. Scientific and Standardization Committee communication: clinical guidance on the diagnosis, prevention, and treatment of venous thromboembolism in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. J Thromb Haemost. 2020;18:1859&#x2013;1865. doi: 10.1111/jth.14929</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7283841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32459046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouck EG, Denorme F, Holle LA, Middelton EA, Blair AM, de Laat B, Schiffman JD, Yost CC, Rondina MT, Wolberg AS, et al. . COVID-19 and sepsis are associated with different abnormalities in plasma procoagulant and fibrinolytic activity. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2021;41:401&#x2013;414. doi: 10.1161/ATVBAHA.120.315338</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7942774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33196292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goshua G, Pine AB, Meizlish ML, Chang CH, Zhang H, Bahel P, Baluha A, Bar N, Bona RD, Burns AJ, et al. . Endotheliopathy in COVID-19-associated coagulopathy: evidence from a single-centre, cross-sectional study. Lancet Haematol. 2020;7:e575&#x2013;e582. doi: 10.1016/S2352-3026(20)30216-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7326446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32619411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin X, Duan Y, Bao T, Gu J, Chen Y, Li Y, Mao S, Chen Y, Xie W. The values of coagulation function in COVID-19 patients. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0241329. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0241329</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7595402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33119703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowenstein CJ, Solomon SD. Severe COVID-19 is a microvascular disease. Circulation. 2020;142:1609&#x2013;1611. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.050354</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7580651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32877231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teuwen LA, Geldhof V, Pasut A, Carmeliet P. COVID-19: the vasculature unleashed. Nat Rev Immunol. 2020;20:389&#x2013;391. doi: 10.1038/s41577-020-0343-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7240244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32439870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong M, Jiang Y, Xia D, Xiong Y, Zheng Q, Chen F, Zou L, Xiao W, Zhu Y. Elevated expression of serum endothelial cell adhesion molecules in COVID-19 patients. J Infect Dis. 2020;222:894&#x2013;898. doi: 10.1093/infdis/jiaa349</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7337874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32582936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Li X, Chen M, Feng Y, Xiong C. The ACE2 expression in human heart indicates new potential mechanism of heart injury among patients infected with SARS-CoV-2. Cardiovasc Res. 2020;116:1097&#x2013;1100. doi: 10.1093/cvr/cvaa078</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32227090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deinhardt-Emmer S, Bottcher S, Haring C, Giebeler L, Henke A, Zell R, Jungwirth J, Jordan PM, Werz O, Hornung F, et al. . SARS-CoV-2 causes severe epithelial inflammation and barrier dysfunction. J Virol. 2021;95:e00110-21. doi: 10.1128/JVI.00110-21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8139673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33637603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldsmith CS, Miller SE, Martines RB, Bullock HA, Zaki SR. Electron microscopy of SARS-CoV-2: a challenging task. Lancet. 2020;395:e99. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31188-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7237172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamming I, Timens W, Bulthuis ML, Lely AT, Navis G, van Goor H. Tissue distribution of ACE2 protein, the functional receptor for SARS coronavirus. A first step in understanding SARS pathogenesis. J Pathol. 2004;203:631&#x2013;637. doi: 10.1002/path.1570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7167720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15141377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Garron TM, Chang Q, Su Z, Zhou C, Qiu Y, Gong EC, Zheng J, Yin YW, Ksiazek T, Brasel T, Jin Y, Boor P, Comer JE, Gong B. Cell-type apoptosis in lung during SARS-CoV-2 infection. Pathogens. 2021;10:509. doi: 10.3390/pathogens10050509</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8145065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33922476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCracken IR, Saginc G, He L, Huseynov A, Daniels A, Fletcher S, Peghaire C, Kalna V, Andaloussi-Mae M, Muhl L, et al. . Lack of evidence of angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 expression and replicative infection by SARS-CoV-2 in human endothelial cells. Circulation. 2021;143:865&#x2013;868. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.052824</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7899720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33405941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nascimento Conde J, Schutt WR, Gorbunova EE, Mackow ER. Recombinant ACE2 expression is required for SARS-CoV-2 to infect primary human endothelial cells and induce inflammatory and procoagulative responses. mBio. 2020;11:e03185-20. doi: 10.1128/mBio.03185-20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7751258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33310781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefer IM, Padera RF, Solomon IH, Kanjilal S, Hammer MM, Hornick JL, Sholl LM. In situ detection of SARS-CoV-2 in lungs and airways of patients with COVID-19. Mod Pathol. 2020;33:2104&#x2013;2114. doi: 10.1038/s41379-020-0595-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7304376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32561849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga Z, Flammer AJ, Steiger P, Haberecker M, Andermatt R, Zinkernagel AS, Mehra MR, Schuepbach RA, Ruschitzka F, Moch H. Endothelial cell infection and endotheliitis in COVID-19. Lancet. 2020;395:1417&#x2013;1418. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30937-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziegler CGK, Allon SJ, Nyquist SK, Mbano IM, Miao VN, Tzouanas CN, Cao Y, Yousif AS, Bals J, Hauser BM, et al. ; HCA Lung Biological Network. Electronic address: lung-network@humancellatlas.org. SARS-CoV-2 receptor ACE2 is an interferon-stimulated gene in human airway epithelial cells and is detected in specific cell subsets across tissues. Cell. 2020;181:1016&#x2013;1035.e19. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2020.04.035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7252096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32413319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y, Ji W, Yang H, Chen S, Zhang W, Duan G. Endothelial activation and dysfunction in COVID-19: from basic mechanisms to potential therapeutic approaches. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2020;5:293. doi: 10.1038/s41392-020-00454-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7758411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33361764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu KK, Thiagarajan P. Role of endothelium in thrombosis and hemostasis. Annu Rev Med. 1996;47:315&#x2013;331. doi: 10.1146/annurev.med.47.1.315</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8712785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conway EM. Thrombomodulin and its role in inflammation. Semin Immunopathol. 2012;34:107&#x2013;125. doi: 10.1007/s00281-011-0282-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21805323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe-Kusunoki K, Nakazawa D, Ishizu A, Atsumi T. Thrombomodulin as a physiological modulator of intravascular injury. Front Immunol. 2020;11:575890. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2020.575890</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7525002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33042158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanne TM, Pedersen A, Gisslen M, Jern C. Low admission protein C levels are a risk factor for disease worsening and mortality in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Thromb Res. 2021;204:13&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1016/j.thromres.2021.05.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8163729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34102452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura Y, Nakano T, Irie K, Sano K, Tanaka J, Yamashita Y, Satho T, Matsuo K, Fujioka M, Ishikura H, et al. . Recombinant human soluble thrombomodulin ameliorates cerebral ischemic injury through a high-mobility group box 1 inhibitory mechanism without hemorrhagic complications in mice. J Neurol Sci. 2016;362:278&#x2013;282. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2016.01.047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26944163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su EJ, Geyer M, Wahl M, Mann K, Ginsburg D, Brohmann H, Petersen KU, Lawrence DA. The thrombomodulin analog Solulin promotes reperfusion and reduces infarct volume in a thrombotic stroke model. J Thromb Haemost. 2011;9:1174&#x2013;1182. doi: 10.1111/j.1538-7836.2011.04269.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3111949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21645225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito T, Thachil J, Asakura H, Levy JH, Iba T. Thrombomodulin in disseminated intravascular coagulation and other critical conditions-a multi-faceted anticoagulant protein with therapeutic potential. Crit Care. 2019;23:280. doi: 10.1186/s13054-019-2552-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6694689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31416465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamakawa K, Aihara M, Ogura H, Yuhara H, Hamasaki T, Shimazu T. Recombinant human soluble thrombomodulin in severe sepsis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Thromb Haemost. 2015;13:508&#x2013;519. doi: 10.1111/jth.12841</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25581687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brumback BD, Dmytrenko O, Robinson AN, Bailey AL, Ma P, Liu J, Hicks SC, Ng S, Li G, Zhang DM, et al. . Human cardiac pericytes are susceptible to SARS-CoV-2 infection. JACC Basic Transl Sci. 2023;8:109&#x2013;120. doi: 10.1016/j.jacbts.2022.09.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9473702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36124009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan AO, Reyat JS, Hill H, Bourne JH, Colicchia M, Newby ML, Allen JD, Crispin M, Youd E, Murray PG, et al. . Preferential uptake of SARS-CoV-2 by pericytes potentiates vascular damage and permeability in an organoid model of the microvasculature. Cardiovasc Res. 2022;118:3085&#x2013;3096. doi: 10.1093/cvr/cvac097</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35709328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonaventura A, Vecchie A, Dagna L, Martinod K, Dixon DL, Van Tassell BW, Dentali F, Montecucco F, Massberg S, Levi M, et al. . Endothelial dysfunction and immunothrombosis as key pathogenic mechanisms in COVID-19. Nat Rev Immunol. 2021;21:319&#x2013;329. doi: 10.1038/s41577-021-00536-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33824483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holter JC, Pischke SE, de Boer E, Lind A, Jenum S, Holten AR, Tonby K, Barratt-Due A, Sokolova M, Schjalm C, et al. . Systemic complement activation is associated with respiratory failure in COVID-19 hospitalized patients. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2020;117:25018&#x2013;25025. doi: 10.1073/pnas.2010540117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7547220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32943538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessenbrock K, Krumbholz M, Schonermarck U, Back W, Gross WL, Werb Z, Grone HJ, Brinkmann V, Jenne DE. Netting neutrophils in autoimmune small-vessel vasculitis. Nat Med. 2009;15:623&#x2013;625. doi: 10.1038/nm.1959</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2760083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19448636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middleton EA, He XY, Denorme F, Campbell RA, Ng D, Salvatore SP, Mostyka M, Baxter-Stoltzfus A, Borczuk AC, Loda M, et al. . Neutrophil extracellular traps contribute to immunothrombosis in COVID-19 acute respiratory distress syndrome. Blood. 2020;136:1169&#x2013;1179. doi: 10.1182/blood.2020007008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7472714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32597954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skendros P, Mitsios A, Chrysanthopoulou A, Mastellos DC, Metallidis S, Rafailidis P, Ntinopoulou M, Sertaridou E, Tsironidou V, Tsigalou C, et al. . Complement and tissue factor-enriched neutrophil extracellular traps are key drivers in COVID-19 immunothrombosis. J Clin Invest. 2020;130:6151&#x2013;6157. doi: 10.1172/JCI141374</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7598040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson PJ, Liu-Fei F, Ng C, Minato TA, Lai C, Hossain AR, Chan R, Grewal B, Singhera G, Rai H, et al. . Characterization of COVID-19-associated cardiac injury: evidence for a multifactorial disease in an autopsy cohort. Lab Invest. 2022;102:814&#x2013;825. doi: 10.1038/s41374-022-00783-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9015288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35437316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolai L, Leunig A, Brambs S, Kaiser R, Weinberger T, Weigand M, Muenchhoff M, Hellmuth JC, Ledderose S, Schulz H, et al. . Immunothrombotic dysregulation in COVID-19 pneumonia is associated with respiratory failure and coagulopathy. Circulation. 2020;142:1176&#x2013;1189. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.048488</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7497892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32755393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta AK, Joshi MB, Philippova M, Erne P, Hasler P, Hahn S, Resink TJ. Activated endothelial cells induce neutrophil extracellular traps and are susceptible to NETosis-mediated cell death. FEBS Lett. 2010;584:3193&#x2013;3197. doi: 10.1016/j.febslet.2010.06.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20541553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y, Yang X, Chatterjee V, Meegan JE, Beard RS, Jr, Yuan SY. Role of neutrophil extracellular traps and vesicles in regulating vascular endothelial permeability. Front Immunol. 2019;10:1037. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2019.01037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6520655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31143182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi H, Yang S, Zhang L. Neutrophil extracellular traps and endothelial dysfunction in atherosclerosis and thrombosis. Front Immunol. 2017;8:928. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2017.00928</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5545592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28824648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coenen DM, Mastenbroek TG, Cosemans J. Platelet interaction with activated endothelium: mechanistic insights from microfluidics. Blood. 2017;130:2819&#x2013;2828. doi: 10.1182/blood-2017-04-780825</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29018081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etulain J, Schattner M. Glycobiology of platelet-endothelial cell interactions. Glycobiology. 2014;24:1252&#x2013;1259. doi: 10.1093/glycob/cwu056</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24928621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meini S, Zanichelli A, Sbrojavacca R, Iuri F, Roberts AT, Suffritti C, Tascini C. Understanding the pathophysiology of COVID-19: could the contact system be the key?. Front Immunol. 2020;11:2014. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2020.02014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7432138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32849666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekassy Z, Lopatko Fagerstrom I, Bader M, Karpman D. Crosstalk between the renin-angiotensin, complement and kallikrein-kinin systems in inflammation. Nat Rev Immunol. 2022;22:411&#x2013;428. doi: 10.1038/s41577-021-00634-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8579187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34759348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glowacka I, Bertram S, Herzog P, Pfefferle S, Steffen I, Muench MO, Simmons G, Hofmann H, Kuri T, Weber F, et al. . Differential downregulation of ACE2 by the spike proteins of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus and human coronavirus NL63. J Virol. 2010;84:1198&#x2013;1205. doi: 10.1128/JVI.01248-09</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2798380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19864379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conway EM, Mackman N, Warren RQ, Wolberg AS, Mosnier LO, Campbell RA, Gralinski LE, Rondina MT, van de Veerdonk FL, Hoffmeister KM, et al. . Understanding COVID-19-associated coagulopathy. Nat Rev Immunol. 2022;22:639&#x2013;649. doi: 10.1038/s41577-022-00762-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9362465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35931818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastard P, Rosen LB, Zhang Q, Michailidis E, Hoffmann HH, Zhang Y, Dorgham K, Philippot Q, Rosain J, Beziat V, et al. ; HGID Lab. Autoantibodies against type I IFNs in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science. 2020;370:eabd4585. doi: 10.1126/science.abd4585</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Bastard P, Bolze A, Jouanguy E, Zhang SY, Effort CHG, Cobat A, Notarangelo LD, Su HC, Abel L, et al. . Life-threatening COVID-19: defective interferons unleash excessive inflammation. Med. 2020;1:14&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1016/j.medj.2020.12.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7748410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33363283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damoiseaux J, Dotan A, Fritzler MJ, Bogdanos DP, Meroni PL, Roggenbuck D, Goldman M, Landegren N, Bastard P, Shoenfeld Y, et al. . Autoantibodies and SARS-CoV2 infection: the spectrum from association to clinical implication: report of the 15th Dresden Symposium on Autoantibodies. Autoimmun Rev. 2022;21:103012. doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2021.103012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8656211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34896650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Y, Estes SK, Ali RA, Gandhi AA, Yalavarthi S, Shi H, Sule G, Gockman K, Madison JA, Zuo M, et al. . Prothrombotic autoantibodies in serum from patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Sci Transl Med. 2020;12:eabd3876. doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.abd3876</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7724273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33139519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durigutto P, Grossi C, Borghi MO, Macor P, Pregnolato F, Raschi E, Myers MP, de Groot PG, Meroni PL, Tedesco F. New insight into antiphospholipid syndrome: antibodies to beta2glycoprotein I-domain 5 fail to induce thrombi in rats. Haematologica. 2019;104:819&#x2013;826. doi: 10.3324/haematol.2018.198119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6442945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30442725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favaloro EJ, Henry BM, Lippi G. COVID-19 and antiphospholipid antibodies: time for a reality check?. Semin Thromb Hemost. 2022;48:72&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1055/s-0041-1728832</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34130340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmann O, Zdunek S, Felker A, Salehpour M, Alkass K, Bernard S, Sjostrom SL, Szewczykowska M, Jackowska T, Dos Remedios C, et al. . Dynamics of cell generation and turnover in the human heart. Cell. 2015;161:1566&#x2013;1575. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2015.05.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26073943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto AR, Ilinykh A, Ivey MJ, Kuwabara JT, D&#x2019;Antoni ML, Debuque R, Chandran A, Wang L, Arora K, Rosenthal NA, et al. . Revisiting cardiac cellular composition. Circ Res. 2016;118:400&#x2013;409. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.115.307778</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4744092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26635390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Nyengaard JR, Andersen JB, Baandrup U, Gundersen HJ. The application of stereological methods for estimating structural parameters in the human heart. Anat Rec (Hoboken). 2009;292:1630&#x2013;1647. doi: 10.1002/ar.20952</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19714657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins-Marques T, Hausenloy DJ, Sluijter JPG, Leybaert L, Girao H. Intercellular communication in the heart: therapeutic opportunities for cardiac ischemia. Trends Mol Med. 2021;27:248&#x2013;262. doi: 10.1016/j.molmed.2020.10.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33139169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tirziu D, Giordano FJ, Simons M. Cell communications in the heart. Circulation. 2010;122:928&#x2013;937. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.108.847731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2941440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20805439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M, Kleine-Weber H, Schroeder S, Kruger N, Herrler T, Erichsen S, Schiergens TS, Herrler G, Wu NH, Nitsche A, et al. . SARS-CoV-2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and is blocked by a clinically proven protease inhibitor. Cell. 2020;181:271&#x2013;280.e8. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muus C, Luecken MD, Eraslan G, Sikkema L, Waghray A, Heimberg G, Kobayashi Y, Vaishnav ED, Subramanian A, Smillie C, et al. ; NHLBI LungMap Consortium. Single-cell meta-analysis of SARS-CoV-2 entry genes across tissues and demographics. Nat Med. 2021;27:546&#x2013;559. doi: 10.1038/s41591-020-01227-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9469728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33654293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang A, Chiou J, Poirion OB, Buchanan J, Valdez MJ, Verheyden JM, Hou X, Kudtarkar P, Narendra S, Newsome JM, et al. ; NHLBI LungMap Consortium. Single-cell multiomic profiling of human lungs reveals cell-type-specific and age-dynamic control of SARS-CoV2 host genes. Elife. 2020;9:e62522. doi: 10.7554/eLife.62522</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7688309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33164753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brauninger H, Stoffers B, Fitzek ADE, Meissner K, Aleshcheva G, Schweizer M, Weimann J, Rotter B, Warnke S, Edler C, et al. . Cardiac SARS-CoV-2 infection is associated with pro-inflammatory transcriptomic alterations within the heart. Cardiovasc Res. 2022;118:542&#x2013;555. doi: 10.1093/cvr/cvab322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8803085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34647998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulfamante GP, Perrucci GL, Falleni M, Sommariva E, Tosi D, Martinelli C, Songia P, Poggio P, Carugo S, Pompilio G. Evidence of SARS-CoV-2 transcriptional activity in cardiomyocytes of COVID-19 patients without clinical signs of cardiac involvement. Biomedicines. 2020;8:626. doi: 10.3390/biomedicines8120626</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7767122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33352880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox SE, Akmatbekov A, Harbert JL, Li G, Quincy Brown J, Vander Heide RS. Pulmonary and cardiac pathology in African American patients with COVID-19: an autopsy series from New Orleans. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8:681&#x2013;686. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30243-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32473124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macosko EZ, Basu A, Satija R, Nemesh J, Shekhar K, Goldman M, Tirosh I, Bialas AR, Kamitaki N, Martersteck EM, et al. . Highly parallel genome-wide expression profiling of individual cells using nanoliter droplets. Cell. 2015;161:1202&#x2013;1214. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2015.05.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4481139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26000488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litvin&#x2c7;ukov&#xe1; M, Talavera-L&#xf3;pez C, Maatz H, Reichart D, Worth CL, Lindberg EL, Kanda M, Polanski K, Heinig M, Lee M, et al. . Cells of the adult human heart. Nature. 2020;588:466&#x2013;472. doi: 10.1038/s41586-020-2797-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7681775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32971526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao X, Zhang X, Zhang R, Zhu R, Hou X, Yi W, Wu F, Hao L, Feng R. The atlas of ACE2 expression in fetal and adult human hearts reveals the potential mechanism of heart-injured patients infected with SARS-CoV-2. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2022;322:C723&#x2013;C738. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.00169.2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8977135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35138176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker NR, Chaffin M, Bedi KC, Jr, Papangeli I, Akkad AD, Arduini A, Hayat S, Eraslan G, Muus C, Bhattacharyya RP, et al. ; Human Cell Atlas Lung Biological Network. Myocyte-specific upregulation of ACE2 in cardiovascular disease: implications for SARS-CoV-2-mediated myocarditis. Circulation. 2020;142:708&#x2013;710. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.047911</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7424896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32795091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey AL, Dmytrenko O, Greenberg L, Bredemeyer AL, Ma P, Liu J, Penna V, Winkler ES, Sviben S, Brooks E, et al. . SARS-CoV-2 infects human engineered heart tissues and models COVID-19 myocarditis. JACC Basic Transl Sci. 2021;6:331&#x2013;345. doi: 10.1016/j.jacbts.2021.01.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7909907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33681537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bojkova D, Wagner JUG, Shumliakivska M, Aslan GS, Saleem U, Hansen A, Luxan G, Gunther S, Pham MD, Krishnan J, et al. . SARS-CoV-2 infects and induces cytotoxic effects in human cardiomyocytes. Cardiovasc Res. 2020;116:2207&#x2013;2215. doi: 10.1093/cvr/cvaa267</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32966582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchiano S, Hsiang TY, Khanna A, Higashi T, Whitmore LS, Bargehr J, Davaapil H, Chang J, Smith E, Ong LP, et al. . SARS-CoV-2 infects human pluripotent stem cell-derived cardiomyocytes, impairing electrical and mechanical function. Stem Cell Rep. 2021;16:478&#x2013;492. doi: 10.1016/j.stemcr.2021.02.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7881699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navaratnarajah CK, Pease DR, Halfmann PJ, Taye B, Barkhymer A, Howell KG, Charlesworth JE, Christensen TA, Kawaoka Y, Cattaneo R, et al. ; Wanek Family Program for HLHS-Stem Cell Pipeline. Highly efficient SARS-CoV-2 infection of human cardiomyocytes: spike protein-mediated cell fusion and its inhibition. J Virol. 2021;95:e0136821. doi: 10.1128/JVI.01368-21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8610601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34613786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Bermejo JA, Kang S, Rockwood SJ, Simoneau CR, Joy DA, Silva AC, Ramadoss GN, Flanigan WR, Fozouni P, Li H, et al. . SARS-CoV-2 infection of human iPSC-derived cardiac cells reflects cytopathic features in hearts of patients with COVID-19. Sci Transl Med. 2021;13:eabf7872. doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.abf7872</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8128284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33723017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Han Y, Nilsson-Payant BE, Gupta V, Wang P, Duan X, Tang X, Zhu J, Zhao Z, Jaffre F, et al. . A human pluripotent stem cell-based platform to study SARS-CoV-2 tropism and model virus infection in human cells and organoids. Cell Stem Cell. 2020;27:125&#x2013;136.e7. doi: 10.1016/j.stem.2020.06.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7303620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32579880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren X, Wen W, Fan X, Hou W, Su B, Cai P, Li J, Liu Y, Tang F, Zhang F, et al. . COVID-19 immune features revealed by a large-scale single-cell transcriptome atlas. Cell. 2021;184:1895&#x2013;1913.e19. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2021.01.053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoeckius M, Hafemeister C, Stephenson W, Houck-Loomis B, Chattopadhyay PK, Swerdlow H, Satija R, Smibert P. Simultaneous epitope and transcriptome measurement in single cells. Nat Methods. 2017;14:865&#x2013;868. doi: 10.1038/nmeth.4380</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5669064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28759029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson E, Reynolds G, Botting RA, Calero-Nieto FJ, Morgan MD, Tuong ZK, Bach K, Sungnak W, Worlock KB, Yoshida M, et al. ; Cambridge Institute of Therapeutic Immunology and Infectious Disease-National Institute of Health Research (CITIID-NIHR) COVID-19 BioResource Collaboration. Single-cell multi-omics analysis of the immune response in COVID-19. Nat Med. 2021;27:904&#x2013;916. doi: 10.1038/s41591-021-01329-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8121667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33879890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delorey TM, Ziegler CGK, Heimberg G, Normand R, Yang Y, Segerstolpe A, Abbondanza D, Fleming SJ, Subramanian A, Montoro DT, et al. . COVID-19 tissue atlases reveal SARS-CoV-2 pathology and cellular targets. Nature. 2021;595:107&#x2013;113. doi: 10.1038/s41586-021-03570-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8919505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33915569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stahl PL, Salmen F, Vickovic S, Lundmark A, Navarro JF, Magnusson J, Giacomello S, Asp M, Westholm JO, Huss M, et al. . Visualization and analysis of gene expression in tissue sections by spatial transcriptomics. Science. 2016;353:78&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1126/science.aaf2403</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27365449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia C, Fan J, Emanuel G, Hao J, Zhuang X. Spatial transcriptome profiling by MERFISH reveals subcellular RNA compartmentalization and cell cycle-dependent gene expression. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2019;116:19490&#x2013;19499. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1912459116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6765259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31501331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulasinghe A, Liu N, Tan CW, Monkman J, Sinclair JE, Bhuva DD, Godbolt D, Pan L, Nam A, Sadeghirad H, et al. . Transcriptomic profiling of cardiac tissues from SARS-CoV-2 patients identifies DNA damage. Immunology. 2023;168:403&#x2013;419. doi: 10.1111/imm.13577</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9537957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36107637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adjei S, Hong K, Molinari NM, Bull-Otterson L, Ajani UA, Gundlapalli AV, Harris AM, Hsu J, Kadri SS, Starnes J, et al. . Mortality risk among patients hospitalized primarily for COVID-19 during the Omicron and Delta variant pandemic periods - United States, April 2020-June 2022. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71:1182&#x2013;1189. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm7137a4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9484808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36107788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chudzik M, Babicki M, Kapusta J, Kaluzinska-Kolat Z, Kolat D, Jankowski P, Mastalerz-Migas A. Long-COVID clinical features and risk factors: a retrospective analysis of patients from the STOP-COVID registry of the PoLoCOV study. Viruses. 2022;14:1755. doi: 10.3390/v14081755</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9415629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36016376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estiri H, Strasser ZH, Brat GA, Semenov YR, Patel CJ, Murphy SN; Consortium for Characterization of COVID-19 by EHR (4CE). Evolving phenotypes of non-hospitalized patients that indicate long COVID. BMC Med. 2021;19:249. doi: 10.1186/s12916-021-02115-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34565368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal SM, Landers DB, Hollenberg SM, Turi ZG, Glotzer TV, Tancredi J, Parrillo JE. Prospective evaluation of autonomic dysfunction in post-acute sequela of COVID-19. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79:2325&#x2013;2330. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2022.03.357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8976261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35381331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mabila S, Patel D, Fan M, Stahlman S, Seliga N, Nowak G, Wells N. Post -acute sequalae of COVID-19 and cardiac outcomes in U. S. military members. Int J Cardiol Cardiovasc Risk Prev. 2023;17:200183. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcrp.2023.200183</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10014478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36936859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh J, Bhagaloo L, Sy E, Lavoie AJ, Dehghani P, Bardutz HA, Mang CS, Buttigieg J, Neary JP. Cardiac impairments in postacute COVID-19 with sustained symptoms: a review of the literature and proof of concept. Physiol Rep. 2022;10:e15430. doi: 10.14814/phy2.15430</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9393908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35993433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SY, Adejumo P, See C, Onuma OK, Miller EJ, Spatz ES. Characteristics of patients referred to a cardiovascular disease clinic for post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Am Heart J Plus. 2022;18:100176. doi: 10.1016/j.ahjo.2022.100176</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9277988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35856065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiemken TL, McGrath LJ, Andersen KM, Khan F, Malhotra D, Alfred T, Nguyen JL, Puzniak L, Thoburn E, Jodar L, et al. . Coronavirus disease 2019 severity and risk of subsequent cardiovascular events. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76:e42&#x2013;e50. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciac661</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9907540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35984816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Zang C, Xu Z, Zhang Y, Xu J, Bian J, Morozyuk D, Khullar D, Zhang Y, Nordvig AS, et al. . Data-driven identification of post-acute SARS-CoV-2 infection subphenotypes. Nat Med. 2023;29:226&#x2013;235. doi: 10.1038/s41591-022-02116-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9873564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36456834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisaccia G, Ricci F, Recce V, Serio A, Iannetti G, Chahal AA, Stahlberg M, Khanji MY, Fedorowski A, Gallina S. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 and cardiovascular autonomic dysfunction: what do we know?. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis. 2021;8:156. doi: 10.3390/jcdd8110156</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8621226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34821709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Bluemke DA, Luscher TF, Neubauer S. Long COVID: post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 with a cardiovascular focus. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:1157&#x2013;1172. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehac031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8903393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35176758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud Z, East L, Gleva M, Woodard PK, Lavine K, Verma AK. Cardiovascular symptom phenotypes of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2. Int J Cardiol. 2022;366:35&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2022.07.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9278009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35842003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull-Otterson L, Baca S, Saydah S, Boehmer TK, Adjei S, Gray S, Harris AM. Post&#x2013;COVID conditions among adult COVID-19 survivors aged 18&#x2013;64 and &#x2265;65 years &#x2014; United States, March 2020&#x2013;November 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71:7135&#x2013;7717. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm7121e1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Italia L, Ingallina G, Napolano A, Boccellino A, Belli M, Cannata F, Rolando M, Ancona F, Melillo F, Stella S, et al. . Subclinical myocardial dysfunction in patients recovered from COVID-19. Echocardiogr. 2021;38:1778&#x2013;1786. doi: 10.1111/echo.15215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8652678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>