<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36074666</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2066-8279</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>63</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Season>Jan-Mar</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Romanian journal of morphology and embryology = Revue roumaine de morphologie et embryologie</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rom J Morphol Embryol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19 infection: from stress-related cortisol levels to adrenal glands infarction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>39</StartPage><EndPage>48</EndPage><MedlinePgn>39-48</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.47162/RJME.63.1.03</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cortisol is a key element in acute stress including a severe infection. However, in coronavirus-associated disease, 20% of subjects experience hypocortisolemia due to direct or immune damage of pituitary and adrenal glands. One extreme form of adrenal insufficiency is found in 2&#x2215;3 of cases with viral and post-viral adrenal infarction (AI) (with&#x2215;without adrenal hemorrhage) that is mostly associated with a severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) infection; it requires prompt glucocorticoid intervention. Some reports are incidental findings at computed tomography (CT)&#x2215;magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scans for non-adrenal complications like pulmonary spreading and others are seen on post-mortem analysis. This is a review of PubMed-accessible, English papers focusing on AI in addition to the infection, between March 1, 2020 and November 1, 2021. Exclusion criteria were acute adrenal insufficiency without the histopathological (HP) and&#x2215;or imaging report of adrenal enlargement, necrosis, etc., respective adrenal failure due to pituitary causes, or non-COVID-19-related adrenal events. We identified a total of 84 patients (different levels of statistical evidence), as follows: a retrospective study on 51 individuals, two post-mortem studies comprising nine, respectively 12 patients, a case series of five subjects, seven single-case reports. HP aspects include necrosis associated with ischemia, cortical lipid degeneration (+/- focal adrenalitis), and infarcts at the level of adrenal cortex, blood clot into vessels, acute fibrinoid necrosis in arterioles and capsules, as well as subendothelial vacuolization. Collateral potential contributors to adrenal damage are thrombotic events, coagulation anomalies, antiphospholipid syndrome, endothelial dysfunction, severe COVID-19 infection with multiorgan failure, etc. Clinical picture is variable from acute primary adrenal insufficiency to asymptomatic or mild evolution, even a retrospective diagnostic; it may be a part of long COVID-19 syndrome; glucocorticoid therapy for non-adrenal considerations might mask cortisol deficient status due to AI&#x2215;hemorrhage. Despite its rarity, the COVID-19-associated AI/hemorrhage represents a challenging new chapter, a condition that is essential to be recognized due to its gravity since prompt intervention with glucocorticoid replacement is lifesaving.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Popescu</LastName><ForeName>Mihaela</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, Carol Davila University of Medicine and Pharmacy, C.I. Parhon National Institute of Endocrinology, Bucharest, Romania; carsote_m@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Terzea</LastName><ForeName>Dana Cristina</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carsote</LastName><ForeName>Mara</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghenea</LastName><ForeName>Alice Elena</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costache</LastName><ForeName>Andrei</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Popescu</LastName><ForeName>Iulian Alin Silviu</ForeName><Initials>IAS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biciu&#x15f;c&#x103;</LastName><ForeName>Viorel</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Busuioc</LastName><ForeName>Cristina Jana</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghemigian</LastName><ForeName>Adina Mariana</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Romania</Country><MedlineTA>Rom J Morphol Embryol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112454</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1220-0522</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005938">Glucocorticoids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>WI4X0X7BPJ</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006854">Hydrocortisone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000311" MajorTopicYN="N">Adrenal Glands</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000309" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adrenal Insufficiency</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005938" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucocorticoids</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006470" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemorrhage</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006854" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrocortisone</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007238" MajorTopicYN="N">Infarction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009336" MajorTopicYN="N">Necrosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013927" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thrombosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36074666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9593124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47162/RJME.63.1.03</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">630122039048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Karwacka IM, Obo&#x142;o&#x144;czyk &#x141;, Sworczak K. Adrenal hemorrhage: a single center experience and literature review. Adv Clin Exp Med. 2018;27(5):681&#x2013;687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29616752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An P, Chen K, Yang GQ, Dou JT, Chen YL, Jin XY, Wang XL, Mu YM, Wang QS. Diffuse large B cell lymphoma with bilateral adrenal and hypothalamic involvement: a case report and literature review. World J Clin Cases. 2019;7(23):4075&#x2013;4083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6906562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31832411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toti MS, Ghirri P, Bartoli A, Caputo C, Laudani E, Masoni F, Mele L, Bernardini R. Adrenal hemorrhage in newborn: how, when and why - from case report to literature review. Ital J Pediatr. 2019;45(1):58&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6507044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31068206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimidar N, Ysebaert D, Twickler M, Spinhoven M, Dams K, Jorens PG. Bilateral adrenal haemorrhage after a high energetic trauma: a case report and review of current literature. Acta Chir Belg. 2020;120(2):131&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30270759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumitrascu MC, Sandru F, Carsote M. From oral anticoagulants to Prednisone. Medical Image Database. 2021;4(1):31&#x2013;32. https://www.medicalimage.ro/index.php/MID/article/view/104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valea A, Carsote M, Petrova E, Dumitrascu MC, Sandru F. Pale skin: an adrenal cancer. Rom J Med Pract. 2019;14(4):460&#x2013;463. https://rjmp.com.ro/rpm-vol-xiv-nr-4-an-2019/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumitrascu MC, Trandafir AI, Petrova E, Ghemigian A, Carsote M, Sandru F, Mehedintu C. Bilateral adrenal hemorrhage. Rom J Med Pract. 2021;16(4):413&#x2013;421. https://rjmp.com.ro/rpm-vol-xvi-nr-4-an-2021/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valea A, Botezan O, Turturea R, Carsote M, Rusu C. Surgery for primary hyperparathyroidism diagnosed as acute renal failure. J Surg Sci. 2018;5(2):108&#x2013;112. https://journalofsurgicalsciences.com/index.php/jss/article/view/161</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumitrascu MC, Rentea DE, Zugravu S, Mehedintu C, Carsote M, Sandru F. Follow-up of second adrenal tumor after remission of Cushing syndrome. Rom J Med Pract. 2021;16(4):509&#x2013;515. https://rjmp.com.ro/rpm-vol-xvi-nr-4-an-2021/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandru F, Dumitrascu MC, Petca RC, Mehedintu C, Carsote M. Adrenal surgery amid COVID-19 pandemic. Rom Med J. 2021;68(4):429&#x2013;432. https://rmj.com.ro/rmj-vol-lxviii-nr-4-an-2021/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yonezaki S, Nagasaki K, Yamaguchi H, Kobayashi H. Bilateral adrenal infarctions as an initial manifestation of TAFRO syndrome: a case report and review of the literature. Intern Med. 2022;61(5):743&#x2013;747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8943364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34393171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soltanmohammadi S, Vakhshoori M, Sajadi G, Heidarpour M. Bilateral adrenal hemorrhage and adrenal insufficiency in the context of polycythemia vera: a case report and review of the literature. Case Rep Med. 2022;2022:5335543&#x2013;5335543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9242798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35783462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carsote M, Ghemigian A, Terzea D, Gheorghisan-Galateanu AA, Valea A. Cystic adrenal lesions: focus on pediatric population (a review) Clujul Med. 2017;90(1):5&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5305088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28246490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terzea D, Carsote M. Inside of an adrenal cyst. Medical Image Database. 2019;2(2) http://www.medicalimage.ro/index.php/MID/article/view/35</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moroti R, Badiu C. Endocrine effects of COVID 19: difficulties in the management of endocrine disorders from individual to societies. Acta Endocrinol (Bucharest) 2020;16(1):74&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7364014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32685042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazakou P, Paschou SA, Psaltopoulou T, Gavriatopoulou M, Korompoki E, Stefanaki K, Kanouta F, Kassi GN, Dimopoulos MA, Mitrakou A. Early and late endocrine complications of COVID-19. Endocr Connect. 2021;10(9):R229&#x2013;R239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8494407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34424853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi C, Wang L, Ye J, Gu Z, Wang S, Xia J, Xie Y, Li Q, Xu R, Lin N. Predictors of mortality in patients with coronavirus disease 2019: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):663&#x2013;663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8264491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34238232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Y, Xu B, Guan W, Xu D, Li F, Ren R, Zhu X, Gao Y, Jiang L. The adrenal cortex, an underestimated site of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2021;11:593179&#x2013;593179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33488517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li MY, Li L, Zhang Y, Wang XS. Expression of the SARS-CoV-2 cell receptor gene ACE2 in a wide variety of human tissues. Infect Dis Poverty. 2020;9(1):45&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7186534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32345362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashim M, Athar S, Gaba WH. New onset adrenal insufficiency in a patient with COVID-19. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14(1):e237690&#x2013;e237690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7813399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33462013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbas EM, Akbas N. COVID-19, adrenal gland, glucocorticoids, and adrenal insufficiency. Biomed Pap Med Fac Univ Palacky Olomouc Czech Repub. 2021;165(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33542545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lite C, Ahmed SSSJ, Juliet M, Freddy AJ. SARS-CoV-2/human interactome reveals ACE2 locus crosstalk with the immune regulatory network in the host. Pathog Dis. 2021;79(2):ftab005&#x2013;ftab005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7928900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33469663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasile CM, Udri&#x15f;toiu AL, Ghenea AE, Popescu M, Gheonea C, Niculescu CE, Ungureanu AM, Udri&#x15f;toiu &#x15e;, Droca&#x15f; AI, Gruionu LG, Gruionu G, Iacob AV, Alexandru DO. Intelligent diagnosis of thyroid ultrasound imaging using an ensemble of deep learning methods. Medicina (Kaunas) 2021;57(4):395&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33921597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel E, Zill-E-Huma R, Demertzidou E. Spontaneous adrenal haemorrhage in pregnancy and review of the literature. BMJ Case Rep. 2022;15(5):e246240&#x2013;e246240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9083427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35523516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Wang Z. Identification of risk factors for in-hospital death of COVID-19 pneumonia &#x2013; lessons from the early outbreak. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):113&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7829622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33494706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Stasi V, Rastrelli G, Inglese F, Beccaria M, Garuti M, Di Costanzo D, Spreafico F, Cervi G, Greco GF, Pecoriello A, Todisco T, Cipriani S, Maseroli E, Scavello I, Glingani C, Franchini M, Maggi M, De Donno G, Vignozzi L. Higher testosterone is associated with increased inflammatory markers in women with SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia: preliminary results from an observational study. J Endocrinol Invest. 2021;45(3):639&#x2013;648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8564592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34731444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calderon-Lopez MT, Garcia-Leon N, Gomez-Arevalillo S, Martin-Serrano P, Matilla-Garcia A. Coronavirus disease 2019 and coagulopathy: other prothrombotic coagulation factors. Blood Coagul Fibrinolysis. 2021;32(1):44&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33417336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raishan S, Alsabri M, Hanna AM, Brett M. Resolution of pituitary microadenoma after coronavirus disease 2019: a case report. J Med Case Rep. 2021;15(1):544&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8559425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34724974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valea A, Ghervan C, Carsote M, Morar A, Iacob I, Tomesc F, Pop DD, Georgescu C. Effects of combination therapy: somatostatin analogues and dopamine agonists on GH and IGF1 levels in acromegaly. Clujul Med. 2015;88(3):310&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4632888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26609262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valea A, Carsote M, Ghervan C, Georgescu C. Glycemic profile in patients with acromegaly treated with somatostatin analogue. J Med Life. 2015;8(Spec Issue):82&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4564028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26361517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leow MKS, Kwek DSK, Ng AWK, Ong KC, Kaw GJL, Lee LSU. Hypocortisolism in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 2005;63(2):197&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7188349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16060914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piticchio T, Le Moli R, Tumino D, Frasca F. Relationship between betacoronaviruses and the endocrine system: a new key to understand the COVID-19 pandemic &#x2013; a comprehensive review. J Endocrinol Invest. 2021;44(8):1553&#x2013;1570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7882054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33583003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das L, Dutta P, Walia R, Mukherjee S, Suri V, Puri GD, Mahajan V, Malhotra P, Chaudhary S, Gupta R, Jayant SS, Agrawal K, Kumar V, Sachdeva N, Rastogi A, Bhadada SK, Ram S, Bhansali A. Spectrum of endocrine dysfunction and association with disease severity in patients with COVID-19: insights from a cross-sectional, observational study. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2021;12:645787&#x2013;645787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8283965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34276556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua MWJ, Chua MPW. Delayed onset of central hypocortisolism in a patient recovering from COVID-19. AACE Clin Case Rep. 2021;7(1):2&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33521254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De La Flor Merino JC, Mola Reyes L, Linares Gravalos T, Roel Conde A, Rodeles Del Pozo M. An unusual case of severe acute hyponatremia in patient with COVID-19 infection. Nefrologia (Engl Ed) 2020;40(3):356&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7205617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32439187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke SA, Phylactou M, Patel B, Mills EG, Muzi B, Izzi-Engbeaya C, Choudhury S, Khoo B, Meeran K, Comninos AN, Abbara A, Tan T, Dhillo WS. Normal adrenal and thyroid function in patients who survive COVID-19 Infection. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2021;106(8):2208&#x2013;2220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8194556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34008009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salzano C, Saracino G, Cardillo G. Possible adrenal involvement in long COVID syndrome. Medicina (Kaunas) 2021;57(10):1087&#x2013;1087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8537520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34684123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera Martimbianco AL, Pacheco RL, Bagattini &#xc2;M, Riera R. Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID-19: a systematic review. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75(10):e14357&#x2013;e14357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8236920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33977626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churilov LP, Kanduc D, Ryabkova VA. COVID-19: adrenal response and molecular mimicry. Isr Med Assoc J. 2021;23(10):618&#x2013;619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Z, Lv Y, Xu C, Sun W, Chen W, Peng Z, Chen C, Cui X, Jiao D, Cheng C, Chi Y, Wei H, Hu C, Zeng Y, Zhang X, Yi Y. Clinical use of short-course and low-dose corticosteroids in patients with non-severe COVID-19 during pneumonia progression. Front Public Health. 2020;8:355&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32719766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim MX, Fong KK, Yeap TB. Use of extracorporeal blood purification therapy (ECBPT) as an adjuvant to high-dose corticosteroids in a severely ill COVID-19 patient with concomitant bacterial infection. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14(10):e245639&#x2013;e245639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34645636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smail SW, Saeed M, Twana A, Khudhur ZO, Younus DA, Rajab MF, Abdulahad WH, Hussain HI, Niaz K, Safdar M. Inflammation, immunity and potential target therapy of SARS-CoV-2: a total scale analysis review. Food Chem Toxicol. 2021;150:112087&#x2013;112087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7905385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33640537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan J, Yuan Y, Xu C, Song C, Liu D, Ma D, Gao Q. A retrospective comparison of drugs against COVID-19. Virus Res. 2021;294:198262&#x2013;198262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33333102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansems K, Grundeis F, Dahms K, Mikolajewska A, Thieme V, Piechotta V, Metzendorf MI, Stegemann M, Benstoem C, Fichtner F. Remdesivir for the treatment of COVID-19. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;8(8):CD014962&#x2013;CD014962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8406992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34350582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke E, Haber E, Pike CW, Sonti R. Outcomes of renal replacement therapy in the critically ill with COVID-19. Med Intensiva. 2021;45(6):325&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7891048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34629584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner C, Griesel M, Mikolajewska A, Mueller A, Nothacker M, Kley K, Metzendorf MI, Fischer AL, Kopp M, Stegemann M, Skoetz N, Fichtner F. Systemic corticosteroids for the treatment of COVID-19. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;8(8):CD014963&#x2013;CD014963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8406706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34396514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao C, He L, Ma J, Chen M, Li Y, Jiang Q, Wu S, Yu L, Huang W, Qian G, Zhu C, Chu J, Chen X. Clinical features and predictors for patients with severe SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia at the start of the pandemic: a retrospective multicenter cohort study. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):666&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8266160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34238240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esslami GG, Moienafshar A. Neonatal bilateral adrenal hemorrhage and adrenal insufficiency accompanied by subgaleal hematoma: a case report with brief review of literature. BMC Pediatr. 2022;22(1):248&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9069721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35513814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoza-Jim&#xe9;nez KJ, Carranza-Zavala B, Manrique-Franco K, Espinoza-Morales F, Mejia CR. Daily glucose variation influenced by the use of corticosteroids in COVID-19 patients treated in Lima &#x2013; Peru. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15(4):102188&#x2013;102188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34217143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarfraz A, Sarfraz Z, Razzack AA, Patel G, Sarfraz M. Venous thromboembolism, corticosteroids and COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Appl Thromb Hemost. 2021;27:1076029621993573&#x2013;1076029621993573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7883150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33571009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez Z&#xfa;&#xf1;iga M&#xc1;, Moreno-Moral A, Oca&#xf1;a-Granados A, Padilla-Moreno FA, Castillo-Fern&#xe1;ndez AM, Guillam&#xf3;n-Fern&#xe1;ndez D, Ram&#xed;rez-S&#xe1;nchez C, Sanchez-Palop M, Mart&#xed;nez-Colmenero J, Pimentel-Villar MA, Bl&#xe1;zquez-Rosell&#xf3; S, Moreno-S&#xe1;nchez JJ, L&#xf3;pez-V&#xed;lchez M, Prior-S&#xe1;nchez I, J&#xf3;dar-Moreno R, L&#xf3;pez Ruz M&#xc1;. High-dose corticosteroid pulse therapy increases the survival rate in COVID-19 patients at risk of hyper-inflammatory response. PLoS One. 2021;16(1):e0243964&#x2013;e0243964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7842890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33507958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Ko JH, Baek JY, Hong J, Ha S, Lee B, Huh K, Cho SY, Kang CI, Chung DR, Kim YJ, Kang ES, Peck KR. Effects of short-term corticosteroid use on reactogenicity and immuno-genicity of the first dose of ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccine. Front Immunol. 2021;12:744206&#x2013;744206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8493039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34630425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal R. COVID-19, hypothalamo&#x2013;pituitary&#x2013;adrenal axis and clinical implications. Endocrine. 2020;68(2):251&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7186765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32346813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheatland R. Molecular mimicry of ACTH in SARS &#x2013; implications for corticosteroid treatment and prophylaxis. Med Hypotheses. 2004;63(5):855&#x2013;862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7126000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15488660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancio M, Ciccocioppo R, Rocco PRM, Levine BL, Bronte V, Bollard CM, Weiss D, Boelens JJ, Hanley PJ. Emerging trends in COVID-19 treatment: learning from inflammatory conditions associated with cellular therapies. Cytotherapy. 2020;22(9):474&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7252029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32565132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellastella G, Maiorino MI, Esposito K. Endocrine complications of COVID-19: what happens to the thyroid and adrenal glands. J Endocrinol Invest. 2020;43(8):1169&#x2013;1170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7265876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32488724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clotman K, Twickler MB. Diabetes or endocrinopathy admitted in the COVID-19 ward. Eur J Clin Invest. 2020;50(7):e13262&#x2013;e13262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32383239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freire Santana M, Borba MGS, Ba&#xed;a-da-Silva DC, Val F, Alexandre MAA, Brito-Sousa JD, Melo GC, Queiroga MVO, Le&#xe3;o Farias ME, Camilo CC, Naveca FG, Xavier MS, Monteiro WM, Augusto Pivoto Jo&#xe3;o G, Hajjar LA, Ordi J, Lacerda MVG, Ferreira LCL. Case Report: Adrenal pathology findings in severe COVID-19: an autopsy study. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2020;103(4):1604&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32876012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iuga AC, Marboe CC, Yilmaz MM, Lefkowitch JH, Gauran C, Lagana SM. Adrenal vascular changes in COVID-19 autopsies. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 2020;144(10):1159&#x2013;1160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32579380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado IFR, Menezes IQ, Figueiredo SR, Coelho FMA, Terrabuio DRB, Ramos DV, Fagundes GFC, Maciel AAW, Claudia Latronico A, Fragoso MCBV, Cancado ELR, Mendonca BB, Almeida MQ. Primary adrenal insufficiency due to bilateral adrenal infarction in COVID-19. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2022;107(1):e394&#x2013;e400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34324679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgel D, Chocron R, Grimaud M, Philippe A, Chareyre J, Brakta C, Lasne D, Bonnet D, Toubiana J, Angoulvant F, Desvages M, Renolleau S, Smadja DM, Oualha M. Endothelial dysfunction as a component of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2-related multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children with shock. Crit Care Med. 2021;49(11):e1151&#x2013;e1156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8507588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34049308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darvishi M, Shahali H. Acute cardiac tamponade: a case of life-threatening coronavirus disease 2019 complication during air medical transportation. Air Med J. 2021;40(3):179&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7843023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33933222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirza SA, Sheikh AAE, Barbera M, Ijaz Z, Javaid MA, Shekhar R, Pal S, Sheikh AB. COVID-19 and the endocrine system: a review of the current information and misinformation. Infect Dis Rep. 2022;14(2):184&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35314653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R, Guruparan T, Siddiqi S, Sheth R, Jacyna M, Naghibi M, Vrentzou E. A case of adrenal infarction in a patient with COVID 19 infection. BJR Case Rep. 2020;6(3):20200075&#x2013;20200075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7465735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32922854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warriach SA, Mustafa M, O&#x2019;Keeffe D, Watts M. Unusual case of antiphospholipid syndrome presenting as adrenal insufficiency. BMJ Case Rep. 2020;13(3):e233631&#x2013;e233631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7078771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32188612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaskar S, Sinha A, Banach M, Mittoo S, Weissert R, Kass JS, Rajagopal S, Pai AR, Kutty S. Cytokine storm in COVID-19-immunopathological mechanisms, clinical considerations, and therapeutic approaches: the REPROGRAM Consortium Position Paper. Front Immunol. 2020;11:1648&#x2013;1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7365905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32754159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkhouly MMN, Elazzab AA, Moghul SS. Bilateral adrenal hemorrhage in a man with severe COVID-19 pneumonia. Radiol Case Rep. 2021;16(6):1438&#x2013;1442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7998055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33815638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maria ATJ, Diaz-Cau I, Benejean JM, Nutz A, Schiffmann A, Biron-Andreani C, Guilpain P. Flare of antiphospholipid syndrome in the course of COVID-19. TH Open. 2020;4(3):e207&#x2013;e210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32935073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankel M, Feldman I, Levine M, Frank Y, Bogot NR, Benjaminov O, Kurd R, Breuer GS, Munter G. Bilateral adrenal hemorrhage in coronavirus disease 2019 patient: a case report. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2020;105(12):dgaa487&#x2013;dgaa487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong SH, Lui RN, Sung JJ. Covid-19 and the digestive system. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;35(5):744&#x2013;748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel KP, Patel PA, Vunnam RR, Hewlett AT, Jain R, Jing R, Vunnam SR. Gastrointestinal, hepatobiliary, and pancreatic manifestations of COVID-19. J Clin Virol. 2020;128:104386&#x2013;104386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7189193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32388469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed U, Sellevoll HB, Young VS, Sandbaek G, Glomsaker T, Mala T. Covid-19 may present with acute abdominal pain. Br J Surg. 2020;107(7):e186&#x2013;e187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32343396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murali N, El Hayek SM. Abdominal pain mimics. Emerg Med Clin North Am. 2021;39(4):839&#x2013;850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8430370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34600641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung H, Seo H, Park S, Kim H, Jung J, Chong YP, Kim SH, Lee SO, Choi SH, Kim YS, Kim MJ. The first case of multi-system inflammatory syndrome in adult after COVID-19 in Korea. J Korean Med Sci. 2021;36(25):e181&#x2013;e181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34184438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira MFB, Litvinov N, Farhat SCL, Eisencraft AP, Gibelli MABC, Carvalho WB, Fernandes VR, Fink TT, Framil JVS, Galleti KV, Fante AL, Fonseca MFM, Watanabe A, Paula CSY, Palandri GG, Leal GN, Diniz MFR, Pinho JRR, Silva CA, Marques HHS, Pediatric COVID HC-FMUSP Study Group. Rossi Junior A, Delgado AF, Andrade APM, Schvartsman C, Sabino EC, Rocha MC, Kanunfre KA, Okay TS, Carneiro-Sampaio MMS, Jorge PPD. Severe clinical spectrum with high mortality in pediatric patients with COVID-19 and multisystem inflammatory syndrome. Clinics (Sao Paulo) 2020;75:e2209&#x2013;e2209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7426591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32844958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cattalini M, Della Paolera S, Zunica F, Bracaglia C, Giangreco M, Verdoni L, Meini A, Sottile R, Caorsi R, Zuccotti G, Fabi M, Montin D, Meneghel A, Consolaro A, Dellepiane RM, Maggio MC, La Torre F, Marchesi A, Simonini G, Villani A, Cimaz R, Ravelli A, Taddio A, Rheumatology Study Group of the Italian Pediatric Society Defining Kawasaki disease and pediatric inflammatory multisystem syndrome-temporally associated to SARS-CoV-2 infection during SARS-CoV-2 epidemic in Italy: results from a national, multicenter survey. Pediatr Rheumatol Online J. 2021;19(1):29&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7962084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33726806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsaied T, Tremoulet AH, Burns JC, Saidi A, Dionne A, Lang SM, Newburger JW, de Ferranti S, Friedman KG. Review of cardiac involvement in multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children. Circulation. 2021;143(1):78&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittaker E, Bamford A, Kenny J, Kaforou M, Jones CE, Shah P, Ramnarayan P, Fraisse A, Miller O, Davies P, Kucera F, Brierley J, McDougall M, Carter M, Tremoulet A, Shimizu C, Herberg J, Burns JC, Lyall H, Levin M, PIMS-TS Study Group and EUCLIDS and PERFORM Consortia Clinical characteristics of 58 children with a pediatric inflammatory multisystem syndrome temporally associated with SARS-CoV-2. JAMA. 2020;324(3):259&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7281356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32511692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperotto F, Friedman KG, Son MBF, VanderPluym CJ, Newburger JW, Dionne A. Cardiac manifestations in SARS-CoV-2-associated multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children: a comprehensive review and proposed clinical approach. Eur J Pediatr. 2021;180(2):307&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32803422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leyendecker P, Ritter S, Riou M, Wackenthaler A, Meziani F, Roy C, Ohana M. Acute adrenal infarction as an incidental CT finding and a potential prognosis factor in severe SARS-CoV-2 infection: a retrospective cohort analysis on 219 patients. Eur Radiol. 2021;31(2):895&#x2013;900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7450155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32852586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanley B, Naresh KN, Roufosse C, Nicholson AG, Weir J, Cooke GS, Thursz M, Manousou P, Corbett R, Goldin R, Al-Sarraj S, Abdolrasouli A, Swann OC, Baillon L, Penn R, Barclay WS, Viola P, Osborn M. Histopathological findings and viral tropism in UK patients with severe fatal COVID-19: a post-mortem study. Lancet Microbe. 2020;1(6):e245&#x2013;e253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7440861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32844161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiperi LE, Ionescu AD, Marcu CT, Itu-Mure&#x15f;an C, Pantelemon C. Hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis in a child with human immunodeficiency virus infection &#x2013; a case report. Rom J Morphol Embryol. 2021;62(1):279&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8597364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34609432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paladugu S, Donato AA. Recommendations for caring for patients with severe and nonsevere COVID-19. Ann Intern Med. 2020;173(2):JC3&#x2013;JC3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32687760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattos-Silva P, Felix NS, Silva PL, Robba C, Battaglini D, Pelosi P, Rocco PRM, Cruz FF. Pros and cons of corticosteroid therapy for COVID-19 patients. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2020;280:103492&#x2013;103492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7351052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32659271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>lvarez-Troncoso J, Zapatero Larrauri M, Montero Vega MD, Gil Vallano R, Palmier Pel&#xe1;ez E, Mart&#xed;n Rojas-Marcos P, Mart&#xed;n-Luengo F, L&#xe1;zaro Del Campo P, Herrero Gil CR, Trigo Esteban E. Case Report: COVID-19 with bilateral adrenal hemorrhage. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2020;103(3):1156&#x2013;1157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7470557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32682452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharrack N, Baxter CT, Paddock M, Uchegbu E. Adrenal haemorrhage as a complication of COVID-19 infection. BMJ Case Rep. 2020;13(11):e239643&#x2013;e239643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7705581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebollo-Rom&#xe1;n A, Alhambra-Exp&#xf3;sito MR, Herrera-Mart&#xed;nez Y, Leiva-Cepas F, Alzas C, Mu&#xf1;oz-Jim&#xe9;nez C, Ortega-Salas R, Molina-Puertas MJ, G&#xe1;lvez-Moreno MA, Herrera-Mart&#xed;nez AD. Catecholaminergic crisis after a bleeding complication of COVID-19 infection: a case report. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2021;12:693004&#x2013;693004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8456100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34566886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CY, Huang LY, Wu KA, Chan JS, Wu KL, Shyu HY, Hsiao PJ. Response to bilateral adrenal haemorrhage in the differential diagnosis of abdominal pain in vaccine-induced thrombosis with thrombocytopenia. QJM. 2022;114(12):910&#x2013;911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34546343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Rawahi B, BaTaher H, Jaffer Z, Al-Balushi A, Al-Mazrouqi A, Al-Balushi N. Vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia following AstraZeneca (ChAdOx1 nCOV19) vaccine &#x2013; a case report. Res Pract Thromb Haemost. 2021;5(6):e12578&#x2013;e12578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8385181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34466769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuter DJ. Exacerbation of immune thrombocytopenia following COVID-19 vaccination. Br J Haematol. 2021;195(3):365&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34075578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YH, Huang LY, Chen YL, Chan JS, Chiang WF, Lin CY, Chen MH, Shyu HY, Hsiao PJ. ChAdOx1 COVID-19 vaccine-induced thrombocytopenia syndrome. QJM. 2021;114(10):733&#x2013;734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8499769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34432063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varona JF, Garc&#xed;a-Isidro M, Moeinvaziri M, Ramos-L&#xf3;pez M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Dom&#xed;nguez M. Primary adrenal insufficiency associated with Oxford&#x2013;AstraZeneca ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia (VITT) Eur J Intern Med. 2021;91:90&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8271354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34256983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor P, Allen L, Shrikrishnapalasuriyar N, Stechman M, Rees A. Vaccine-induced thrombosis and thrombocytopenia with bilateral adrenal haemorrhage. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 2022;97(1):26&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34235757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blauenfeldt RA, Kristensen SR, Ernstsen SL, Kristensen CCH, Simonsen CZ, Hvas AM. Thrombocytopenia with acute ischemic stroke and bleeding in a patient newly vaccinated with an adenoviral vector-based COVID-19 vaccine. J Thromb Haemost. 2021;19(7):1771&#x2013;1775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33877737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Agostino V, Caranci F, Negro A, Piscitelli V, Tuccillo B, Fasano F, Sirabella G, Marano I, Granata V, Grassi R, Pupo D, Grassi R. A rare case of cerebral venous thrombosis and disseminated intravascular coagulation temporally associated to the COVID-19 vaccine administration. J Pers Med. 2021;11(4):285&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8068274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haji N, Ali S, Wahashi EA, Khalid M, Ramamurthi K. Johnson and Johnson COVID-19 vaccination triggering pheochromocytoma multisystem crisis. Cureus. 2021;13(9):e18196&#x2013;e18196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8536310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34707965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>