<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35662932</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-861X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Curcumin - The Nutraceutical With Pleiotropic Effects? Which Cardiometabolic Subjects Might Benefit the Most?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>865497</StartPage><MedlinePgn>865497</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">865497</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fnut.2022.865497</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Despite continuous advances in pharmacotherapy, atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease remains the world's leading killer. Atherosclerosis relates not only to an increased level of cholesterol, but involves the development of atherosclerotic plaques, which are formed as a result of processes including inflammation and oxidative stress. Therefore, in addition to the classical risk factors for ASCVD (such as type 2 diabetes, overweight, obesity, hypertension and metabolic syndrome), residual risk factors such as inflammation and oxidative stress should also be reduced. The most important intervention in ASCVD is prevention, which includes promoting a healthy diet based on products of natural origin. Curcumin, which is often present in the diet, has been demonstrate to confer several benefits to health. It has been shown in numerous clinical trials that curcumin exhibited anti-diabetic, lipid-lowering, antihypertensive, antioxidant and anti-inflammatory effects, as well as promoting weight loss. All this means that curcumin has a comprehensive impact on the most important risk factors of ASCVD and may be a beneficial support in the treatment of these diseases. Recently, it has also been shown that curcumin may have a beneficial effect on the course of SARS-CoV-2 infection and might be helpful in the prevention of long-COVID complications. The aim of this review is to summarize the current knowledge regarding the safety and efficacy of curcumin in the prevention and treatment of cardiometabolic diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Surma, Sahebkar, Urba&#x144;ski, Penson and Banach.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Surma</LastName><ForeName>Stanis&#x142;aw</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medical Sciences in Katowice, Medical University of Silesia, Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Club of Young Hypertensiologists, Polish Society of Hypertension, Gda&#x144;sk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sahebkar</LastName><ForeName>Amirhossein</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biotechnology Research Center, Pharmaceutical Technology Institute, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurogenic Inflammation Research Center, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Urba&#x144;ski</LastName><ForeName>Jakub</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NomiBiotech Corporation, Z&#x142;otniki, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Penson</LastName><ForeName>Peter E</ForeName><Initials>PE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacy and Therapeutics Research Group, School of Pharmacy and Biomolecular Sciences, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liverpool Centre for Cardiovascular Science, Liverpool, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banach</LastName><ForeName>Maciej</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Preventive Cardiology and Lipidology, Medical University of Lodz, &#x141;&#xf3;d&#x17a;, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Centre, University of Zielona Gora, Zielona G&#xf3;ra, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Adult Congenital Heart Diseases, Polish Mother's Memorial Hospital Research Institute (PMMHRI), &#x141;&#xf3;d&#x17a;, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101642264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-861X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">curcumin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>JU is CSO at Nomi Biotech Corporation. PP owns four shares in AstraZeneca PLC and has received honoraria and/or travel reimbursement for events sponsored by AKCEA, Amgen, AMRYT, Link Medical, Mylan, Napp, Sanofi. MB: speakers bureau: Amgen, Herbapol, Kogen, KRKA, Polpharma, Mylan/Viatris, Novartis, Novo-Nordisk, Sanofi-Aventis, Teva, Zentiva; consultant to Amgen, Daichii Sankyo, Esperion, Freia Pharmaceuticals, Novartis, Novo-Nordisk, Polfarmex, Sanofi-Aventis; Grants from Amgen, Mylan/Viatris, Sanofi and Valeant; CMO at Nomi Biotech Corporation. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35662932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9159377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2022.865497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Roth GA, Mensah GA, Johnson CO, Addolorato G, Ammirati E, Baddour LM, et al. . Global burden of cardiovascular diseases and risk factors, 1990-2019: update from the GBD 2019 study. J Am Coll Cardiol. (2020) 76:2982&#x2013;3021. 10.1016/j.jacc.2020.11.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2020.11.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33309175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Lin L, Wu H, Yan L, Wang H, Yang H, et al. . Global, regional, and national death, and disability-adjusted life-years (DALYs) for cardiovascular disease in 2017 and trends and risk analysis from 1990 to 2017 using the global burden of disease study and implications for prevention. Front Public Health. (2021) 9:559751. 10.3389/fpubh.2021.559751</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2021.559751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8589040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34778156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams R, Karuranga S, Malanda B, Saeedi P, Basit A, Besan&#xe7;on Besan&#xe7;on S et al. . Global and regional estimates and projections of diabetes-related health expenditure: results from the International Diabetes Federation Diabetes Atlas, 9th edition. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. (2020) 162:108072. 10.1016/j.diabres.2020.108072</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2020.108072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32061820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin X, Xu Y, Pan X, Xu J, Ding Y, Sun X, et al. . Global, regional, and national burden and trend of diabetes in 195 countries and territories: an analysis from 1990 to 2025. Sci Rep. (2020) 10:14790. 10.1038/s41598-020-71908-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-71908-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7478957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32901098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Lancet Gastroenterology Hepatology . Obesity: another ongoing pandemic. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. (2021) 6:411. 10.1016/S2468-1253(21)00143-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-1253(21)00143-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9259282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34015350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly T, Yang W, Chen CS, Reynolds K, He J. Global burden of obesity in 2005 and projections to 2030. Int J Obes. (2008) 32:1431&#x2013;37. 10.1038/ijo.2008.102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ijo.2008.102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18607383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirode G, Wong RJ. Trends in the prevalence of metabolic syndrome in the United States, 2011-2016. JAMA. (2020) 323:2526&#x2013;8. 10.1001/jama.2020.4501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.4501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7312413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32573660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou B, Carrillo-Larco RM, Danaei G, Riley LM, Paciorek CJ, Stevens GA, et al. . Worldwide trends in hypertension prevalence and progress in treatment and control from 1990 to 2019: a pooled analysis of 1201 population-representative studies with 104 million participants. Lancet. (2021) 398:957&#x2013;80. 10.1016/S0140-6736(21)01330-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)01330-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8446938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34450083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirillo A, Casula M, Olmastroni E, Norata GD, Catapano AL. Global epidemiology of dyslipidaemias. Nat Rev Cardiol. (2021) 18:689&#x2013;700. 10.1038/s41569-021-00541-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41569-021-00541-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33833450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathiyakumar V, Kapoor K, Jones SR, Banach M, Martin SS. Novel therapeutic targets for managing dyslipidemia. Trends Pharmacol Sci. (2018) 39:733&#x2013;47. 10.1016/j.tips.2018.06.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tips.2018.06.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29970260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komiyama M, Hasegawa K. Coronavirus disease 2019: psychological stress and cardiovascular diseases. Eur Cardiol. (2021) 16:e33. 10.15420/ecr.2021.10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15420/ecr.2021.10</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8477172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34603513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Z, Peng F, Xu B, Zhao J, Liu H, Peng J, et al. . Risk factors of critical and mortal COVID-19 cases: a systematic literature review and meta-analysis. J Infect. (2020) 81:16&#x2013;25. 10.1016/j.jinf.2020.04.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2020.04.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7177098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32335169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosengren A, Smyth A, Rangarajan S, Ramasundarahettige C, Bangdiwala SI, AlHabib KF, et al. . Socioeconomic status and risk of cardiovascular disease in 20 low-income, middle-income, and high-income countries: the prospective urban rural epidemiologic (PURE) study. Lancet Glob Health. (2019) 7:748&#x2013;60. 10.1016/S2214-109X(19)30045-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(19)30045-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31028013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalla SM, Yu S, Galea S. Trends in cardiovascular disease prevalence by income level in the United States. JAMA Netw Open. (2020) 3:e2018150. 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.18150</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.18150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7519418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32975572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cicero AFG, Colletti A, Bajraktari G, Descamps O, Djuric DM, Ezhov M, et al. . Lipid lowering nutraceuticals in clinical practice: position paper from an international lipid expert panel. Arch Med Sci. (2017) 13:965&#x2013;1005. 10.5114/aoms.2017.69326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/aoms.2017.69326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5575230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28883839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banach M, Burchardt P, Chlebus K, Dobrowolski P, Dudek D, Dyrbu&#x15b; K, et al. . PoLA/CFPiP/PCS/PSLD/PSD/PSH guidelines on diagnosis and therapy of lipid disorders in Poland 2021. Arch Med Sci. (2021) 17:1447&#x2013;547. 10.5114/aoms/141941</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/aoms/141941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8641518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34900032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruscica M, Penson PE, Ferri N, Sirtori CR, Pirro M, Mancini GBJ, et al. . Impact of nutraceuticals on markers of systemic inflammation: potential relevance to cardiovascular diseases - a position paper from the International Lipid Expert Panel (ILEP). Prog Cardiovasc Dis. (2021) 67:40&#x2013;52. 10.1016/j.pcad.2021.06.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcad.2021.06.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34186099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banach M, Bruckert E, Descamps OS, Elleg&#xe5;rd L, Ezhov M, F&#xf6;ger B, et al. . The role of red yeast rice (RYR) supplementation in plasma cholesterol control: a review and expert opinion. Atheroscler Suppl. (2019) 39:1&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.atherosclerosissup.2019.08.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atherosclerosissup.2019.08.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31451336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Averna M, Banach M, Bruckert E, Drexel H, Farnier M, Gaita D, et al. . Practical guidance for combination lipid-modifying therapy in high- and very-high-risk patients: a statement from a European atherosclerosis society task force. Atherosclerosis. (2021) 325:99&#x2013;109. 10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2021.03.039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2021.03.039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahedipour F, Hosseini SA, Sathyapalan T, Majeed M, Jamialahmadi T, Al-Rasadi K, et al. . Potential effects of curcumin in the treatment of COVID-19 infection. Phytother Res. (2020) 34:2911&#x2013;20. 10.1002/ptr.6738</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7276879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32430996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahedian-Azimi A, Abbasifard M, Rahimi-Bashar F, Guest PC, Majeed M, Mohammadi A, et al. . Effectiveness of curcumin on outcomes of hospitalized COVID-19 patients: a systematic review of clinical trials. Nutrients. (2022) 14:256. 10.3390/nu14020256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14020256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8779570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35057437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewek J, Jatczak-Pawlik I, Maciejewski M, Jankowski P, Banach M. COVID-19 and cardiovascular complications - preliminary results of the LATE-COVID study. Arch Med Sci. (2021) 17:818&#x2013;22. 10.5114/aoms/134211</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/aoms/134211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8130484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34025853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotha RR, Luthria DL. Curcumin: biological, pharmaceutical, nutraceutical, and analytical aspects. Molecules. (2019) 24:2930. 10.3390/molecules24162930</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules24162930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6720683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31412624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anand P, Kunnumakkara AB, Newman RA, Aggarwal BB. Bioavailability of curcumin: problems and promises. Mol Pharm. (2007) 4:807&#x2013;18. 10.1021/mp700113r</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/mp700113r</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17999464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khajuria A, Zutshi U, Bedi K. Permeability characteristics of piperine on oral absorption: an active alkaloid from peppers and a bioavailability enhancer. Ind J Exp Biol. (1998) 36:46&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9536651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Sureda A, Devkota HP, Pittal&#xe0; V, Barreca D, Silva AS, et al. . Curcumin, the golden spice in treating cardiovascular diseases. Biotechnol Adv. (2020) 38:107343. 10.1016/j.biotechadv.2019.01.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biotechadv.2019.01.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30716389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganjani S, Blesso CN, Banach M, Pirro M, Majeed M, Sahebkar A. Effects of curcumin on HDL functionality. Pharmacol Res. (2017) 119:208&#x2013;18. 10.1016/j.phrs.2017.02.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2017.02.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28192240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mi&#x142;obedzka J, Kostanecki S, Lampe V. Zur kenntnis des curcumins. Berichte der deutschen chemischen Gesellschaft. (1910) 43:2163&#x2013;70. 10.1002/cber.191004302168</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cber.191004302168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulido-Moran M, Moreno-Fernandez J, Ramirez-Tortosa C, Ramirez-Tortosa M. Curcumin and health. Molecules. (2016) 21:264. 10.3390/molecules21030264</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules21030264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6273481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26927041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Zhai Y, Heng X, Che FY, Chen W, Sun D, et al. . Oral bioavailability of curcumin: problems and advancements. J Drug Target. (2016) 24:694&#x2013;702. 10.3109/1061186X.2016.1157883</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/1061186X.2016.1157883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26942997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dei Cas M, Ghidoni R. Dietary curcumin: correlation between bioavailability and health potential. Nutrients. (2019) 11:2147. 10.3390/nu11092147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11092147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6770259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31500361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorgani L, Mohammadi M, Najafpour GD, Nikzad M. Piperine-the bioactive compound of black pepper: from isolation to medicinal formulations. Compr Rev Food Sci Food Saf. (2016) 16:124&#x2013;40. 10.1111/1541-4337.12246</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1541-4337.12246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33371546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stojanovi&#x107;-Radi&#x107; Z, Pej&#x10d;i&#x107; M, Dimitrijevi&#x107; M, Aleksi&#x107; A, Kumar KVA, Salehi B, et al. . Piperine-a major principle of black pepper: a review of its bioactivity and studies. Appl Sci. (2019) 9:4270. 10.3390/app9204270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app9204270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baell J, Walters M. Chemistry: chemical con artists foil drug discovery. Nature. (2014) 513:481&#x2013;3. 10.1038/513481a</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/513481a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25254460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furia TE. CRC Handbook of Food Additives. 2nd ed. Volume 2. Boca Raton, Florida: CRC Press, Inc., (1980).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Z, Wang N, He H, Tang X. Pharmaceutical strategies of improving oral systemic bioavailability of curcumin for clinical application. J Control Release. (2019) 316:359&#x2013;80. 10.1016/j.jconrel.2019.10.053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2019.10.053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31682912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleimani V, Sahebkar A, Hosseinzadeh H. Turmeric (Curcuma longa) and its major constituent (curcumin) as nontoxic and safe substances: review. Phytother Res. (2018) 32:985&#x2013;95. 10.1002/ptr.6054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29480523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan JL, Heckler CE, Ling M, Katz A, Williams JP, Pentland AP, et al. . Curcumin for radiation dermatitis: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial of thirty breast cancer patients. Radiat Res. (2013) 180:34&#x2013;43. 10.1667/RR3255.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1667/RR3255.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3998827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23745991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmani S, Asgary S, Askari G, Keshvari M, Hatamipour M, Feizi A, et al. . Treatment of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease with curcumin: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Phytother Res. (2016) 30:1540&#x2013;8. 10.1002/ptr.5659</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.5659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27270872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ger R, Lowery RP, Calvanese AV, Joy JM, Purpura M, Wilson JM. Comparative absorption of curcumin formulations. Nutr J. (2014) 13:11. 10.1186/1475-2891-13-11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1475-2891-13-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3918227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24461029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangolim CS, Moriwaki C, Nogueira AC, Sato F, Baesso LM, Neto AM, et al. . Curcumin&#x2013;&#x3b2;-cyclodextrin inclusion complex: stability, solubility, characterisation by FT-IR, FT- Raman, X-ray diffraction and photoacoustic spectroscopy, and food application. Food Chem. (2014) 153:361&#x2013;70. 10.1016/j.foodchem.2013.12.067</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2013.12.067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24491741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcolino VA, Zanin GM, Durrant LR, Benassi MT, Matioli G. Interaction of curcumin and bixin with &#x3b2;-cyclodextrin: complexation methods, stability, and applications in food. J Agric Food Chem. (2011) 59:3348&#x2013;57 10.1021/jf104223k</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jf104223k</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21381747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YJ, Pan MH, Cheng AL, Lin LI, Ho YS, Hsieh CY, et al. . Stability of curcumin in buffer solutions and characterization of its degradation products. J Pharm Biomed Anal. (1997) 15:1867&#x2013;76. 10.1016/S0731-7085(96)02024-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0731-7085(96)02024-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9278892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins RM, Pereira SV, Siqueira S, Salom&#xe3;o WF, Freitas LAP. Curcuminoid content and antioxidant activity in spray dried microparticles containing turmeric extract. Food Res Int. (2013) 50:657&#x2013;63. 10.1016/j.foodres.2011.06.030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodres.2011.06.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuomo J, Appendino G, Dern AS, Schneider E, McKinnon TP, Brown MJ. Comparative absorption of a standardized curcuminoid mixture and its lecithin formulation. J Nat Prod. (2011) 74:664&#x2013;9. 10.1021/np1007262</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/np1007262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21413691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gota VS, Maru GB, Soni TG, Gandhi TR, Kochar N, Agarwal MG. Safety and pharmacokinetics of a solid lipid curcumin particle formulation in osteosarcoma patients and healthy volunteers. J Agric Food Chem. (2010) 58:2095&#x2013;9. 10.1021/jf9024807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jf9024807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20092313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madhavi D, Kagan D. Bioavailability of a sustained release formulation of curcumin. Integr Med. (2014) 13:24&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4684130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26770097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiborr C, Kocher A, Behnam D, Jandasek J, Toelstede S, Frank J. The oral bioavailability of curcumin from micronized powder and liquid micelles is significantly increased in healthy humans and differs between sexes. Mol Nutr Food Res. (2014) 58:516&#x2013;27. 10.1002/mnfr.201300724</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mnfr.201300724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24402825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antony B, Merina B, Iyer VS, Judy N, Lennertz K, Joyal S, et al. . pilot cross-over study to evaluate human oral bioavailability of BCM-95CG (Biocurcumax), a novel bioenhanced preparation of curcumin. Indian J Pharm Sci. (2008) 70:445&#x2013;9. 10.4103/0250-474X.44591</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0250-474X.44591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2792534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20046768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purpura M, Lowery RP, Wilson JM, Mannan H, M&#xfc;nch G, Razmovski-Naumovski V. Analysis of different innovative formulations of curcumin for improved relative oral bioavailability in human subjects. Eur J Nutr. (2018) 57:929&#x2013;38. 10.1007/s00394-016-1376-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00394-016-1376-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5861163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28204880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki H, Sunagawa Y, Takahashi K, Imaizumi A, Fakuda H, Hashimoto T, et al. . Innovative preparation of curcumin for improved oral bioavailability. Biol Pharm Bull. (2011) 34:660&#x2013;5. 10.1248/bpb.34.660</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/bpb.34.660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21532153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen AL, Hsu CH, Lin JK, Hsu MM, Ho YF, Sheh TS, et al. . Phase I clinical trial of curcumin, a chemopreventive agent, in patients with high-risk or pre-malignant lesions. Anticancer Res. (2001) 21:e2900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11712783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lao CD, Ruffin MT IV, Normolle D, Heath DD, Murray SI, Bailey JM, et al. . Dose escalation of a curcuminoid formulation. BMC Complement Altern Med. (2006) 6:4&#x2013;7. 10.1186/1472-6882-6-10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6882-6-10</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1434783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16545122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vareed SK, Kakarala M, Ruffin MT, Crowell JA, Normolle DP, Djuric Z, et al. . Pharmacokinetics of curcumin conjugate metabolites in healthy human subjects. Cancer Epidemiol Biomark Prev. (2008) 17:1411&#x2013;7. 10.1158/1055-9965.EPI-07-2693</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1055-9965.EPI-07-2693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4138955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18559556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karandish M, Mozaffari-Khosravi H, Mohammadi SM, Cheraghian B, Azhdari M. The effect of curcumin and zinc co-supplementation on glycemic parameters in overweight or obese prediabetic subjects: a phase 2 randomized, placebo-controlled trial with a multi-arm, parallel-group design. Phytother Res. (2021) 35:4377&#x2013;87. 10.1002/ptr.7136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.7136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33893671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokhtari M, Razzaghi R, Momen-Heravi M. The effects of curcumin intake on wound healing and metabolic status in patients with diabetic foot ulcer: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Phytother Res. (2021) 35:2099&#x2013;107. 10.1002/ptr.6957</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33200488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thota RN, Rosato JI, Dias CB, Burrows TL, Martins RN, Garg ML. Dietary supplementation with curcumin reduce circulating levels of glycogen synthase kinase-3&#x3b2; and islet amyloid polypeptide in adults with high risk of type 2 diabetes and Alzheimer's disease. Nutrients. (2020) 12:1032. 10.3390/nu12041032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12041032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7230780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32283762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafabakhsh R, Mobini M, Raygan F, Aghadavod E, Ostadmohammadi V, Amirani E, et al. . Curcumin administration and the effects on psychological status and markers of inflammation and oxidative damage in patients with type 2 diabetes and coronary heart disease. Clin Nutr ESPEN. (2020) 40:77&#x2013;82. 10.1016/j.clnesp.2020.09.029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnesp.2020.09.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33183576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi S, Gholami MS, Siassi F, Qorbani M, Sotoudeh G. Beneficial effects of nano-curcumin supplement on depression and anxiety in diabetic patients with peripheral neuropathy: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Phytother Res. (2020) 34:896&#x2013;903. 10.1002/ptr.6571</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31788880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafabakhsh R, Asemi Z, Reiner Z, Soleimani A, Aghadavod E, Bahmani F. The effects of nano-curcumin on metabolic status in patients with diabetes on hemodialysis, a randomized, double blind, placebo-controlled trial. Iran J Kidney Dis. (2020) 14:290&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32655024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funamoto M, Shimizu K, Sunagawa Y, Katanasaka Y, Miyazaki Y, Kakeya H, et al. . Effects of highly absorbable curcumin in patients with impaired glucose tolerance and non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus. J Diabetes Res. (2019) 2019:8208237. 10.1155/2019/8208237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/8208237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6906884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31871950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanaie A, Shahidi S, Iraj B, Siadat ZD, Kabirzade M, Shakiba F, et al. . Curcumin as a major active component of turmeric attenuates proteinuria in patients with overt diabetic nephropathy. J Res Med Sci. (2019) 24:77. 10.4103/jrms.JRMS_1055_18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jrms.JRMS_1055_18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6734668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31523263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adibian M, Hodaei H, Nikpayam O, Sohrab G, Hekmatdoost A, Hedayati M. The effects of curcumin supplementation on high-sensitivity C-reactive protein, serum adiponectin, and lipid profile in patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Phytother Res. (2019) 33:1374&#x2013;83. 10.1002/ptr.6328</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30864188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi S, Gholami MS, Siassi F, Qorbani M, Khamoshian K, Sotoudeh G. Nano curcumin supplementation reduced the severity of diabetic sensorimotor polyneuropathy in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized double-blind placebo- controlled clinical trial. Complement Ther Med. (2019) 43:253&#x2013;60. 10.1016/j.ctim.2019.02.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctim.2019.02.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30935539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan A, Selvarajan S, Kamalanathan S, Kadhiravan T, Lakshmi NCP, Adithan S. Effect of Curcuma longa on vascular function in native Tamilians with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized, double-blind, parallel arm, placebo-controlled trial. Phytother Res. (2019) 33:1898&#x2013;911. 10.1002/ptr.6381</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31155769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tohta RN, Acharya SA, Garg ML. Curcumin and/or omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids supplementation reduces insulin resistance and blood lipids in individuals with high risk of type 2 diabetes: a randomised controlled trial. Lipids Health Dis. (2019) 18:31. 10.1186/s12944-019-0967-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12944-019-0967-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6347796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30684965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodaei H, Adibian M, Nikpayam O, Hedayati M, Sohrab G. The effect of curcumin supplementation on anthropometric indices, insulin resistance and oxidative stress in patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomized, double-blind clinical trial. Diabetol Metab Syndr. (2019) 11:41. 10.1186/s13098-019-0437-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13098-019-0437-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6537430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31149032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thota RN, Dias CB, Abbott KA, Acharya SH, Garg ML. Curcumin alleviates postprandial glycaemic response in healthy subjects: a cross-over, randomized controlled study. Sci Rep. (2018) 8:13679. 10.1038/s41598-018-32032-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-32032-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6135827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30209353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panahi Y, Khalili N, Sahebi E, Namazi S, Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, Majeed M, et al. . Effects of curcuminoids plus piperine on glycemic, hepatic and inflammatory biomarkers in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial. Drug Res. (2018) 68:403&#x2013;9. 10.1055/s-0044-101752</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0044-101752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29458218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panahi Y, Khalili N, Sahebi E, Namazi S, Karimian MS, Majeed M, et al. . Antioxidant effects of curcuminoids in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized controlled trial. Inflammopharmacology. (2017) 25:25&#x2013;31. 10.1007/s10787-016-0301-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10787-016-0301-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27928704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panahi Y, Khalili N, Sahebi E, Namazi S, Reiner Z, Majeed M, et al. . Curcuminoids modify lipid profile in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized controlled trial. Complement Ther Med. (2017) 33:1&#x2013;5. 10.1016/j.ctim.2017.05.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctim.2017.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28735818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panahi Y, Khalili N, Sahebi E, Namazi S, Atkin SL, Majeed M, et al. . Curcuminoids plus piperine modulate adipokines in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Curr Clin Pharmacol. (2017) 12:253&#x2013;8. 10.2174/1574884713666180104095641</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1574884713666180104095641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29299989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Osorio AS, Garc&#xed;a-Ni&#xf1;o WR, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Reyes S, &#xc1;lvarez-Mej&#xed;a AE, Guerra-Le&#xf3;n S, Salazar-Segovia J, et al. . The effect of dietary supplementation with curcumin on redox status and Nrf2 activation in patients with nondiabetic or diabetic proteinuric chronic kidney disease: a pilot study. J Ren Nutr. (2016) 26:237&#x2013;44. 10.1053/j.jrn.2016.01.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jrn.2016.01.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26915483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi HR, Mohammadpour AH, Dastani M, Jaafari MR, Abnous K, Mobarhan MG, et al. . The effect of nano-curcumin on HbA1c, fasting blood glucose, and lipid profile in diabetic subjects: a randomized clinical trial. Avicenna J Phytomed. (2016) 6:567&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5052420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27761427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Xu W, Zhou Z, Liu J, Li X, Chen L, et al. . Curcumin attenuates urinary excretion of albumin in type II diabetic patients with enhancing nuclear factor erythroid-derived 2-like 2 (Nrf2) system and repressing inflammatory signaling efficacies. Exp Clin Endocrinol Diabetes. (2015) 123:360&#x2013;7. 10.1055/s-0035-1545345</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0035-1545345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25875220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Na LX, Yan BL, Jiang S, Cui HL Li Y, Sun CH. Curcuminoids target decreasing serum adipocyte-fatty acid binding protein levels in their glucose-lowering effect in patients with type 2 diabetes. Biomed Environ Sci. (2014) 27:902&#x2013;6. 10.3967/bes2014.127</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3967/bes2014.127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25374024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuengsamarn S, Rattanamongkolgul S, Phonrat B, Tungtrongchitr R, Jirawatnotai S. Reduction of atherogenic risk in patients with type 2 diabetes by curcuminoid extract: a randomized controlled trial. J Nutr Biochem. (2014) 25:144&#x2013;50. 10.1016/j.jnutbio.2013.09.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnutbio.2013.09.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24445038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Na LX, Li Y, Pan HZ, Zhou XL, Sun DJ, Meng M, et al. . Curcuminoids exert glucose-lowering effect in type 2 diabetes by decreasing serum free fatty acids: a double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Mol Nutr Food Res. (2013) 57:1569&#x2013;77. 10.1002/mnfr.201200131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mnfr.201200131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22930403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuengsamarn S, Rattanamongkolgul S, Luechapudiporn R, Phisalaphong C, Jirawatnotai S. Curcumin extract for prevention of type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. (2012) 35:2121&#x2013;7. 10.2337/dc12-0116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc12-0116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3476912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22773702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, He Q, Liu Y, Chen Z, Hu H. Efficacy and safety of curcumin supplement on improvement of insulin resistance in people with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. (2021) 2021:4471944. 10.1155/2021/4471944</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/4471944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8410384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34484389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Qin S, Huang L, Tang Y, Ren H, Hu H. Efficacy and safety of Rhizoma curcumea longae with respect to improving the glucose metabolism of patients at risk for cardiovascular disease: a meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. J Hum Nutr Diet. (2019) 32:591&#x2013;606. 10.1111/jhn.12648</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jhn.12648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30983042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Melo ISV, Dos Santos AF, Bueno NB. Curcumin or combined curcuminoids are effective in lowering the fasting blood glucose concentrations of individuals with dysglycemia: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Pharmacol Res. (2018) 128:137&#x2013;44. 10.1016/j.phrs.2017.09.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2017.09.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28928074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altobelli E, Angeletti PM, Marziliano C, Mastrodomenico M, Giuliani AR, Petrocelli R. Potential therapeutic effects of curcumin on glycemic and lipid profile in uncomplicated type 2 diabetes - a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trial. Nutrients. (2021) 13:404. 10.3390/nu13020404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13020404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7912109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33514002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton LT, Pescinini-E-Salzedas LM, Camargo MEC, Barbalho SM, Dos Santos Haber JF, et al. . The effects of curcumin on diabetes mellitus: a systematic review. Front Endocrinol. (2021) 12:669448. 10.3389/fendo.2021.669448</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2021.669448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8126655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34012421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdavi A, Moradi S, Askari G, Iraj B, Sathyapalan T, Guest PC, et al. . Effect of curcumin on glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review of randomized clinical trials. Adv Exp Med Biol. (2021) 1291:139&#x2013;49. 10.1007/978-3-030-56153-6_8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-56153-6_8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34331688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pivari F, Mingione A, Brasacchio C, Soldati L. Curcumin and type 2 diabetes mellitus: prevention and treatment. Nutrients. (2019) 11:1837. 10.3390/nu11081837</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11081837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6723242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31398884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi E, Behnam B, Mohammadinejad R, Guest PC, Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, Sahebkar A. Antidiabetic properties of curcumin: insights on new mechanisms. Adv Exp Med Biol. (2021) 1291:151&#x2013;64. 10.1007/978-3-030-56153-6_9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-56153-6_9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34331689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelmoaty AAA, Zhang P, Lin W, Fan Y, Ye S, Xu J. C0818, a novel curcumin derivative, induces ROS-dependent cytotoxicity in human hepatocellular carcinoma cells in vitro via disruption of Hsp90 function. Acta Pharmacol Sin. (2022) 43:446&#x2013;56. 10.1038/s41401-021-00642-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41401-021-00642-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8792041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33824458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalidowska I, Gazi O, Sulejczak D, Przybylski M, Bieganowski P. Heat shock protein 90 chaperones E1A early protein of adenovirus 5 and is essential for replication of the virus. Int J Mol Sci. (2021) 22:2020. 10.3390/ijms22042020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22042020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7921956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33670684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings MR, Parks RJ. Antiviral effects of curcumin on adenovirus replication. Microorganisms. (2020) 8:1524. 10.3390/microorganisms8101524</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms8101524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7599685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33020422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Zanni E, Bachetti T, Parodi S, Bocca P, Prigione I, Di Lascio S, et al. . In vitro drug treatments reduce the deleterious effects of aggregates containing polyAla expanded PHOX2B proteins. Neurobiol Dis. (2012) 45:508&#x2013;18. 10.1016/j.nbd.2011.09.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2011.09.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21964250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alidadi M, Sahebkar A, Eslami S, Vakilian F, Jarahi L, Alinezhad-Namaghi M, et al. . The effect of curcumin supplementation on pulse wave velocity in patients with metabolic syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Adv Exp Med Biol. (2021) 1308:1&#x2013;11. 10.1007/978-3-030-64872-5_1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-64872-5_1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33861432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateni Z, Rahimi HR, Hedayati M, Afsharian S, Goudarzi R, Sohrab G. The effects of nano-curcumin supplementation on glycemic control, blood pressure, lipid profile, and insulin resistance in patients with the metabolic syndrome: a randomized, double-blind clinical trial. Phytother Res. (2021) 35:3945&#x2013;53. 10.1002/ptr.7109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.7109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33851448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirhafez SR, Azimi-Nezhad M, Dehabeh M, Hriri M, Naderan RD, Movahedi A, et al. . The effect of curcumin phytosome on the treatment of patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Adv Exp Med Biol. (2021) 1308:25&#x2013;35. 10.1007/978-3-030-64872-5_3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-64872-5_3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33861434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamilian M, Foroozanfard F, Kavossian E, Aghadavod E, Shafabakhsh R, Hoseini A, et al. . Effects of curcumin on body weight, glycemic control and serum lipids in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Clin Nutr ESPEN. (2020) 36:128&#x2013;33. 10.1016/j.clnesp.2020.01.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnesp.2020.01.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32220355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohaei S, Amani R, Tarrahi MJ, Ghasemi-Tehrani H. The effects of curcumin supplementation on glycemic status, lipid profile and hs-CRP levels in overweight/obese women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Complement Ther Med. (2019) 47:102201. 10.1016/j.ctim.2019.102201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctim.2019.102201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31780025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jazayeri-Tehrani SA, Rezayat SM, Mansouri S, Qorbani M, Alavian SM, Daneshi-Maskooni M, et al. . Nano-curcumin improves glucose indices, lipids, inflammation, and Nesfatin in overweight and obese patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD): a double-blind randomized placebo-controlled clinical trial. Nutr Metab. (2019) 16:8. 10.1186/s12986-019-0331-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12986-019-0331-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6348610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30705687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraf-Bank S, Ahmadi A, Paknahad Z, Maracy M, Nourian M. Effects of curcumin on cardiovascular risk factors in obese and overweight adolescent girls: a randomized clinical trial. S&#xe3;o Paulo Med J. (2019) 137:414&#x2013;22. 10.1590/1516-3180.2018.0454120419</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1516-3180.2018.0454120419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9745817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31691723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraf-Bank S, Ahmadi A, Paknahad Z, Maracy M, Nourian M. Effects of curcumin supplementation on markers of inflammation and oxidative stress among healthy overweight and obese girl adolescents: a randomized placebo-controlled clinical trial. Phytother Res. (2019) 33:2015&#x2013;22. 10.1002/ptr.6370</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31206225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell MS, Ouyang A, Krishnakumar IM, Charnigo RJ, Westgate PM, Fleenor BS. Influence of enhanced bioavailable curcumin on obesity-associated cardiovascular disease risk factors and arterial function: a double-blinded, randomized, controlled trial. Nutrition. (2019) 62:135&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.nut.2019.01.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2019.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30889454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saadati S, Hatami B, Yari Z, Shahrbaf MA, Eghtesad S, Mansour A, et al. . The effects of curcumin supplementation on liver enzymes, lipid profile, glucose homeostasis, and hepatic steatosis and fibrosis in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Eur J Clin Nutr. (2019) 73:441&#x2013;9. 10.1038/s41430-018-0382-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41430-018-0382-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30610213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirhafez SR, Farimani AR, Dehhabe M, Bidkhori M, Hariri M, Ghouchani BF, et al. . Effect of Phytosomal curcumin on circulating levels of adiponectin and leptin in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial. J Gastrointestin Liver Dis. (2019) 28:183&#x2013;9. 10.15403/jgld-179</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15403/jgld-179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31204416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panahi Y, Kianpour P, Mohtashami R, Jafari R, Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, Sahebkar A. Efficacy and safety of phytosomal curcumin in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a randomized controlled trial. Drug Res. (2017) 67:244&#x2013;51. 10.1055/s-0043-100019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0043-100019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28158893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell MS, Berrones AJ, Krishnakumar IM, Charnigo RJ, Westgate PM, Fleenor BS. Responsiveness to curcumin intervention is associated with reduced aortic stiffness in young, obese men with higher initial stiffness. J Funct Foods. (2017) 29:154&#x2013;60. 10.1016/j.jff.2016.12.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jff.2016.12.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panahi Y, Hosseini MS, Khalili N, Naimi E, Soflaei SS, Majeed M, et al. . Effects of supplementation with curcumin on serum adipokine concentrations: a randomized controlled trial. Nutrition. (2016) 32:1116&#x2013;22. 10.1016/j.nut.2016.03.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2016.03.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27297718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panahi Y, Hosseini MS, Khalili N, Naimi E, Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, Majeed M, et al. . Effects of curcumin on serum cytokine concentrations in subjects with metabolic syndrome: a post-hoc analysis of a randomized controlled trial. Biomed Pharmacother. (2016) 82:578&#x2013;82. 10.1016/j.biopha.2016.05.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2016.05.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27470399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaily H, Sahebkar A, Iranshahi M, Ganjali S, Mohammadi A, Ferns G, et al. . An investigation of the effects of curcumin on anxiety and depression in obese individuals: a randomized controlled trial. Chin J Integr Med. (2015) 21:332&#x2013;8. 10.1007/s11655-015-2160-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11655-015-2160-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25776839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Pierro F, Bressan A, Ranaldi D, Rapacioli G, Giacomelli L, Bertuccioli A. Potential role of bioavailable curcumin in weight loss and omental adipose tissue decrease: preliminary data of a randomized, controlled trial in overweight people with metabolic syndrome. Preliminary study. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. (2015) 19:4195&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26592847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganjali S, Sahebkar A, Mahdipour E, Jamialahmadi K, Torabi S, Akhlaghi S, et al. . Investigation of the effects of curcumin on serum cytokines in obese individuals: a randomized controlled trial. Sci World J. (2014) 2014:898361. 10.1155/2014/898361</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/898361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3942342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24678280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkin SL, Kastsiki N, Derosa G, Maffioli P, Sahebkar A. Curcuminoids lower plasma leptin concentrations: a meta-analysis. Phytother Res. (2017) 31:1836&#x2013;41. 10.1002/ptr.5905</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.5905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28880413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark CCT, Ghaedi E, Arab A, Pourmasoumi M, Hadi A. The effect of curcumin supplementation on circulating adiponectin: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Diabetes Metab Syndr. (2019) 13:2819&#x2013;25. 10.1016/j.dsx.2019.07.045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsx.2019.07.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31425942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azhdari M, Karandish M, Mansoori A. Metabolic benefits of curcumin supplementation in patients with metabolic syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Phytother Res. (2019) 33:1289&#x2013;301. 10.1002/ptr.6323</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30941814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panahi Y, Hosseini MS, Khalili N, Naimi E, Majeed M, Sahebkar A. Antioxidant and anti-inflammatory effects of curcuminoid-piperine combination in subjects with metabolic syndrome: a randomized controlled trial and an updated meta-analysis. Clin Nutr. (2015) 34:1101&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.clnu.2014.12.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2014.12.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25618800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baziar N, Parohan M. The effects of curcumin supplementation on body mass index, body weight, and waist circumference in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Phytother Res. (2020) 34:464&#x2013;74. 10.1002/ptr.6542</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31799714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousavi SM, Milajerdi A, Varkaneh HK, Gorjipour MM, Esmaillzadeh A. The effects of curcumin supplementation on body weight, body mass index and waist circumference: a systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. (2020) 60:171&#x2013;80. 10.1080/10408398.2018.1517724</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2018.1517724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30373373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabrizi R, Vakili S, Lankarani KB, Akbari M, Mirhosseini N, Ghayour-Mobarhan M, et al. . The effects of curcumin on glycemic control and lipid profiles among patients with metabolic syndrome and related disorders: a systematic review and metaanalysis of randomized controlled trials. Curr Pharm Des. (2018) 24:3184&#x2013;99. 10.2174/1381612824666180828162053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1381612824666180828162053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30156145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safari Z, Bagherniya M, Askari G, Sathyapalan T, Sahebkar A. The effect of curcumin supplemsentation on anthropometric indices in overweight and obese individuals: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Adv Exp Med Biol. (2021) 1291:121&#x2013;37. 10.1007/978-3-030-56153-6_7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-56153-6_7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34331687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, Cicero AFG, Atkin SL, Majeed M, Sahebkar A. A systematic review and meta-analysis of the effect of curcuminoids on adiponectin levels. Obes Res Clin Pract. (2019) 13:340&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.orcp.2019.04.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.orcp.2019.04.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31064708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadi A, Pourmasoumi M, Ghaedi E, Sahebkar A. The effect of curcumin/turmeric on blood pressure modulation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pharmacol Res. (2019) 150:104505. 10.1016/j.phrs.2019.104505</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2019.104505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31647981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Jo C, Choi HY, Lee K. Effect of co-administration of curcumin with amlodipine in hypertension. Nutrients. (2021) 13:2797. 10.3390/nu13082797</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13082797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8399053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, Pirro M, Gotto AM Jr, Banach M, Atkin SL, Majeed M, et al. . Lipid-modifying activity of curcuminoids: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. (2019) 59:1178&#x2013;87. 10.1080/10408398.2017.1396201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2017.1396201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29185808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan F, Dong H, Gong J, Wang D, Hu M, Huang W, et al. . A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials on the effects of turmeric and curcuminoids on blood lipids in adults with metabolic diseases. Adv Nutr. (2019) 10:791&#x2013;802. 10.1093/advances/nmz021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/advances/nmz021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6743846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31212316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin S, Huang L, Gong J, Shen S, Huang J, Ren H, et al. . Efficacy and safety of turmeric and curcumin in lowering blood lipid levels in patients with cardiovascular risk factors: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Nutr J. (2017) 16:68. 10.1186/s12937-017-0293-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12937-017-0293-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5637251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29020971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson JJA, Stojanovski E, MacDonald-Wicks L, Garg ML. Curcumin potentiates cholesterol-lowering effects of phytosterols in hypercholesterolaemic individuals. A randomised controlled trial. Metabolism. (2018) 82:22&#x2013;35. 10.1016/j.metabol.2017.12.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2017.12.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29291429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derosa G, Maffioli P, Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, Bo S, Sahebkar A. Effect of curcumin on circulating interleukin-6 concentrations: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Pharmacol Res. (2016) 111:394&#x2013;404. 10.1016/j.phrs.2016.07.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2016.07.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27392742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorabi AM, Razi B, Aslani S, Abbasifard M, Imani D, Sathyapalan T, et al. . Effect of curcumin on proinflammatory cytokines: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Cytokine. (2021) 143:155541. 10.1016/j.cyto.2021.155541</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cyto.2021.155541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33934954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson JJA, Abbott KA, Garg ML. Anti-inflammatory effects of oral supplementation with curcumin: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Nutr Rev. (2021) 79:1043&#x2013;66. 10.1093/nutrit/nuaa114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nutrit/nuaa114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34378053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorabi AM, Abbasifard M, Imani D, Aslani S, Razi B, Alizadeh S, et al. . Effect of curcumin on C-reactive protein as a biomarker of systemic inflammation: an updated meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Phytother Res. (2022) 36:85&#x2013;97. 10.1002/ptr.7284</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.7284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34586711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabrizi R, Vakili S, Akbari M, Mirhosseini N, Lankarani KB, Rahimi M, et al. . The effects of curcumin-containing supplements on biomarkers of inflammation and oxidative stress: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Phytother Res. (2019) 33:253&#x2013;62. 10.1002/ptr.6226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30402990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin S, Huang L, Gong J, Shen S, Huang J, Tang Y, et al. . Meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials of 4 weeks or longer suggest that curcumin may afford some protection against oxidative stress. Nutr Res. (2018) 60:1&#x2013;12. 10.1016/j.nutres.2018.08.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2018.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30527253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panahi Y, Kianpour P, Mohtashami R, Jafari R, Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, Sahebkar A. Curcumin lowers serum lipids and uric acid in subjects with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a randomized controlled trial. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol. (2016) 68:223&#x2013;9. 10.1097/FJC.0000000000000406</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/FJC.0000000000000406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27124606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh L, Sharma S, Xu S, Tewari D, Fang J. Curcumin as a natural remedy for atherosclerosis: a pharmacological review. Molecules. (2021) 26:4036. 10.3390/molecules26134036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules26134036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8272048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34279384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzabeigi P, Mohammadpour AH, Salarifar M, Gholami K, Mojtahedzadeh M, Javadi MR. The effect of curcumin on some of traditional and non-traditional cardiovascular risk factors: a pilot randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Iran J Pharm Res. (2015) 14:479&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4403064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25901155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwi I, Santoso T, Suyono S, Sutrisna B, Suyatna FD, Kresno SB, et al. . The effect of curcumin on lipid level in patients with acute coronary syndrome. Acta Med Indones. (2008) 40:201&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19151449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wongcharoen W, Jai-Aue S, Phrommintikul A, Nawarawong W, Woragidpoonpol S, Tepsuwan T, et al. . Effects of curcuminoids on frequency of acute myocardial infarction after coronary artery bypass grafting. Am J Cardiol. (2012) 110:40&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.amjcard.2012.02.043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2012.02.043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22481014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabaee S, Sahebkar A, Aghamohammadi T, Pakdel M, Dehabeh M, Sobhani R, et al. . The effects of curcumin plus piperine supplementation in patients with acute myocardial infarction: a randomized, double-blind, and placebo-controlled trial. Adv Exp Med Biol. (2021) 1328:199&#x2013;211. 10.1007/978-3-030-73234-9_13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-73234-9_13</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34981479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahebkar A, Saboni N, Pirro M, Banach M. Curcumin: an effective adjunct in patients with statin-associated muscle symptoms? J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. (2017) 8:19&#x2013;24. 10.1002/jcsm.12140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.12140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5326825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27897416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vafadar Afshar G, Rasmi Y, Yaghmaei P, Khadem-Ansari MH, Makhdomii K, Rasooli J. The effects of nano-curcumin supplementation on serum level of hs-CRP, adhesion molecules, and lipid profiles in hemodialysis patients, a randomized controlled clinical trial. Iran J Kidney Dis. (2020) 14:52&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32156842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silalahi T, Alwi I, Suyatna F, Sartika KD. Curcumin's effect on inflammatory response following percutaneous coronary intervention in adult patients with stable coronary heart disease. Int J Angiol. (2021) 30:132&#x2013;8. 10.1055/s-0040-1720969</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0040-1720969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8159605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34054271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashtary-Larky D, Kelishadi MR, Bagheri R, Moosavian SP, Wong A, Davoodi SH, et al. . The Effects of nano-curcumin supplementation on risk factors for cardiovascular disease: a GRADE-assessed systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical trials. Antioxidants. (2021) 10:1015. 10.3390/antiox10071015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox10071015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8300831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34202657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed ES, El-Beih NM, El-Hussieny EA, El-Ahwany E, Hassan M, Zoheiry M. Effects of free and nanoparticulate curcumin on chemically induced liver carcinoma in an animal model. Arch Med Sci. (2021) 17:218&#x2013;27. 10.5114/aoms.2020.93739</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/aoms.2020.93739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7811328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33488874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>