<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36065103</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1539-6304</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Allergy and asthma proceedings</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Allergy Asthma Proc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The long COVID syndrome: A conundrum for the allergist/immunologist.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>368</StartPage><EndPage>374</EndPage><MedlinePgn>368-374</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2500/aap.2022.43.220059</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Background:</b> The long coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) syndrome includes a group of patients who, after infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) exhibit lingering mild-to-moderate symptoms and develop medical complications that can have lasting health problems. <b>Objective:</b> The purpose of this report was to examine the current body of evidence that deals with the relationship of COVID-19 infection with the long COVID syndrome to define the possible immunologic mechanisms involved in the pathogenesis of long COVID and to describe potential strategies for the diagnosis and clinical management of the condition. <b>Methods:</b> Extensive research was conducted in medical literature data bases by applying terms such as long COVID, post-COVID-19 condition, pathogenesis of long COVID, management of the long COVID syndrome. <b>Results:</b> The post-COVID conditions, a more recent and less anxiety-inducing term for the patient than long COVID or "long haul," is an umbrella term for a wide range of physical and mental health symptoms similar to those seen in patients with the myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS), experienced by some patients and are present &#x2265; 4 weeks after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Although the precise reason why long COVID develops is unknown, one of the major causes is thought to be related to chronic inflammation with overproduction of inflammatory cytokines responsible for the symptoms of the disorder. <b>Conclusion:</b> Long COVID is a growing burden for millions of patients, health-care providers, and global health-care systems, and is a particular challenge for the allergist/immunologist. Many survivors of COVID-19 struggle with multiple symptoms, increased disability, reduced function, and poor quality of life. The allergist/immunologist can assist the total health-care team's efforts in providing a comprehensive and coordinated approach to the management of these patients by promoting comprehensive vaccination and rehabilitation and social services that focus on improving physical, mental, and social well-being, and by establishing partnerships with specialists and other health-care professionals who can provide behavioral, lifestyle, and integrative approaches that may have much to offer in helping patients cope with their symptoms.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bellanti</LastName><ForeName>Joseph A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Departments of Pediatrics and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Allergy Asthma Proc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9603640</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1088-5412</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072223" MajorTopicYN="N">Allergists</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The author has no conflicts of interest to declare pertaining to this article</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36065103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9465643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2500/aap.2022.43.220059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Piazza M, Boner AL, et al. . Long COVID: a proposed hypothesis-driven model of viral persistence for the pathophysiology of the syndrome. Allergy Asthma Proc. 2022; 43:187-193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9106095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35524358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, et al. . WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on post-COVID-19 condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022; 22:e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Emergency Use ICD Codes for COVID-19 Disease Outbreak. Available online at https://www.who.int/standards/classifications/classification-of-diseases/emergency-use-icd-codes-for-covid-19-disease-outbreak; accessed April 24, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
ICD-10-CM Codes. Available online at https://www.icd10data.com/ICD10CM/Codes/U00-U85/U00-U49/U09-/U09.9; accessed April 24, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altmann DM, Boyton RJ. Decoding the unknowns in long covid. BMJ. 2021; 372:n132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33541867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bektas A, Schurman SH, Franceschi C, et al. . A public health perspective of aging: do hyper-inflammatory syndromes such as COVID-19, SARS, ARDS, cytokine storm syndrome, and post-ICU syndrome accelerate short- and long-term inflammaging? Immun Ageing. 2020; 17:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7443812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32849908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datta SD, Talwar A, Lee JT. A proposed framework and timeline of the spectrum of disease due to SARS-CoV-2 infection: illness beyond acute infection and public health implications. JAMA. 2020; 324:2251&#x2013;2252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33206133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dotan A, David P, Arnheim D, et al. . The autonomic aspects of the post-COVID19 syndrome. Autoimmun Rev. 2022; 21:103071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8848724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35182777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BK, Francisco EB, Yogendra R, et al. . Persistence of SARS CoV-2 S1 protein in CD16+ monocytes in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) up to 15 months post-infection. Front Immunol. 2022; 12:746021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8784688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoharides TC. Could SARS-CoV-2 spike protein be responsible for long-COVID syndrome? Mol Neurobiol. 2022; 59:1850&#x2013;1861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8757925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35028901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trougakos IP, Terpos E, Alexopoulos H, et al. . Adverse effects of COVID-19 mRNA vaccines: the spike hypothesis. Trends Mol Med. 2022; 28:542-554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9021367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35537987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt J, Blease C, Geraghty KJ. Long Covid at the crossroads: comparisons and lessons from the treatment of patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). J Health Psychol. 2022; 13591053221084494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35341334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong TL, Weitzer DJ. Long COVID and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS)&#x2013;a systemic review and comparison of clinical presentation and symptomatology. Medicina (Kaunas). 2021; 57:418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8145228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33925784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Calderone R, Nsouli TM, et al. . Salivary and serum IgA and IgG responses to SARS-CoV-2-spike protein following SARS-CoV-2 infection and after immunization with COVID-19 vaccines. Allergy Asthma Proc. 2022; 43:419&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9465644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36065108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liston A, Humblet-Baron S, Duffy D, et al. . Human immune diversity: from evolution to modernity. Nat Immunol. 2021; 22:1479&#x2013;1489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34795445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei J, Pouwels KB, Stoesser N, et al. . Antibody responses and correlates of protection in the general population after two doses of the ChAdOx1 or BNT162b2 vaccines. Nat Med. 2022; 28:1072&#x2013;1082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9117148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35165453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steensels D, Pierlet N, Penders J, et al. . Comparison of SARS-CoV-2 antibody response following vaccination with BNT162b2 and mRNA-1273. JAMA. 2021; 326:1533&#x2013;1535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8406205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34459863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meissner HC. A viral pandemic, vaccine safety, and compensation for adverse events. JAMA. 2021; 325:721&#x2013;722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33544127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg M, Maralakunte M, Garg S, et al. . The conundrum of 'long-COVID-19': a narrative review. Int J Gen Med. 2021; 14:2491&#x2013;2506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8214209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
The vaccine injury compensation program: addressing needs and improving practices. House Report 106&#x2013;977. Available at https://www.congress.gov/106/crpt/hrpt977/CRPT-106hrpt977.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Fourth Amendment to the Declaration Under the Public Readiness and Emergency Preparedness Act for Medical Countermeasures Against COVID-19 and Republication of the Declaration. 2020; 79190&#x2013;79198. Available at https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2020/12/09/2020-26977/fourth-amendment-to-the-declaration-under-the-public-readiness-and-emergency-preparedness-act-for.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security (CARES) Act of 2020. Available at https://www.congress.gov/116/bills/s3548/BILLS-116s3548is.pdf.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34549589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
FDA News Release. Available at https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/coronavirus-covid-19-update-fda-limits-use-janssen-covid-19-vaccine-certain-individuals.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>