<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38827662</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2249-4863</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of family medicine and primary care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Family Med Prim Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long-COVID-19 Impact in non-hospitalized patients: Sleep and quality of life 24 months after SARS-CoV-2 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1384</StartPage><EndPage>1392</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1384-1392</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_1610_23</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIMS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Sleep disruption and reduced quality of life are common long coronavirus disease (COVID) manifestations, affecting survivors irrespective of initial COVID-19 severity. Limited research investigates symptoms beyond 24 months post-infection. We aimed to address this gap by longitudinally studying sleep patterns and overall quality of life in non-hospitalized adults, 24 months after severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This prospective observational study involved the enrolment of 337 adult non-hospitalized patients in a consecutive fashion. Individuals with past COVID-19 (from 15 April 2020 to 30 June 2021) were examined at two Government hospitals and completed a telephone interview between 1 May 2023 and 30 June 2023, located in Jharkhand, India. Participants were queried about their sleep patterns and quality of life, utilizing the DSM5 LEVEL 2 and EQ-ED-5L tool, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Among 337 non-hospitalized participants, 212 completed the survey. Within this group (59.4% men, mean age 38), 36 (17.0%) experienced sleep impairment. All five dimensions of quality of life (QoL) were adversely affected in long COVID patients. Advanced age, high income, residing in rural or semi-urban areas, and having comorbidities were associated with a higher likelihood of decreased quality of life across various domains. Conversely, participants who were married, employed in healthcare or government positions, and vaccinated exhibited a reduced likelihood of experiencing lower quality of life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Long COVID-19 affects sleep and quality of life, with various demographic and clinical factors influencing outcomes. This study provides insights into the extended consequences of long COVID-19 and aids healthcare systems in addressing the challenges posed by this condition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2024 Journal of Family Medicine and Primary Care.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mudgal</LastName><ForeName>Shiv K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patidar</LastName><ForeName>Vipin</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Suman</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaur</LastName><ForeName>Rakhi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agarwal</LastName><ForeName>Rajat</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of CTVS, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varikasuvu</LastName><ForeName>Seshadri Reddy</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Pratima</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varshney</LastName><ForeName>Saurabh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Executive Director &amp; CEO, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Family Med Prim Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610082</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2249-4863</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2 infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-hospitalized patients</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38827662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11141957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_1610_23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JFMPC-13-1384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV. A clinical case defnition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:e102&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, Myles P, Williams T, Gokhale KM, et al. Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat Med. 2022;28:1706&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Patidar V, Mudgal SK, Kumar S, Agarwal R, Gupta P, et al. Self-reported persistent symptoms at 18 months and above among COVID-19 nonhospitalized patients: A Prospective cohort study. Cureus. 2023;15:e43239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10491500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37692652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Coronavirus disease (COVID-19): Post COVID-19 condition. www.who.int. 2023.  Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/questions-and-answers/item/coronavirus-disease-(covid-19)-post-covid-19-condition .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudgal SK, Gaur R, Rulaniya S, Latha T, Agarwal R, Kumar S, et al. Pooled prevalence of long COVID-19 symptoms at 12 months and above follow-up period: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Cureus. 2023;15:e36325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10108372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37077615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or long COVID: A meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis. 2022;226:1593&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen KY, Li T, Gong FH, Zhang JS, Li XK. Predictors of health-related quality of life and influencing factors for COVID-19 patients, a follow-up at one month. Front Psychiatry. 2020;11:668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7360857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32733299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>der Sar-van V, der Brugge S, Talman S, Boonman-de Winter L, de Mol M, Hoefman E, et al. Pulmonary function and health-related quality of life after COVID-19 pneumonia. Respir Med. 2021;176:106272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7701891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33302142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B, Peters JB, Brink M, Schoon Y, Bleeker-Rovers CP, Schers H, et al. Comprehensive health assessment 3 months after recovery from acute coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:E1089&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs LG, Paleoudis EG, Lesky-Di Bari D, Nyirenda T, Friedman T, Gupta A, et al. Persistence of symptoms and quality of life at 35 days after hospitalization for COVID-19 infection. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0243882. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0243882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7732078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betschart M, Rezek S, Unger I, Ott N, Beyer S, Boni A, et al. One year follow-up of physical performance and quality of life in patients surviving COVID-19: A prospective cohort study. Swiss Med Wkly. 2021;151:w30072. doi: 10.4414/smw. 2021.w30072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34751538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erber J, Wiessner JR, Zimmermann GS, Barthel P, Burian E, Lohofer F, et al. Longitudinal assessment of health and quality of life of COVID-19 patients requiring intensive care-an observational study. J Clin Med. 2021;10:101&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8658191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34884172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamberini L, Mazzoli CA, Prediletto I, Sintonen H, Scaramuzzo G, Allegri D, et al. Health-related quality of life profiles, trajectories, persistent symptoms and pulmonary function one year after ICU discharge in invasively ventilated COVID-19 patients, a prospective follow-up study. Respir Med. 2021;189:106665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8531241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34717097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>See&#x3b2;le J, Waterboer T, Hippchen T, Simon J, Kirchner M, Lim A, et al. Persistent symptoms in adult patients one year after COVID-19: A prospective cohort study. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;74:1191&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34223884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tessitore E, Handgraaf S, Poncet A, Achard M, Hofer S, Carballo S, et al. Symptoms and quality of life at 1-year follow up of patients discharged after an acute COVID-19 episode. Swiss Med Wkly. 2021;151:w30093. doi:10.4414/smw.2021.w30093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34909433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang LX, Yao Q, Gu XY, Wang QY, Ren LL, Wang YM, et al. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: A longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398:747&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xf6;rster C, Colombo MG, Wetzel AJ, Martus P, Joos S. Persisting symptoms after COVID-19. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2022;119:167&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9215272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35236547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanares D, Kohn L, Dauvrin M, Detollenaere J, Maertens de Noordhout C, Jongh P-D, et al.  Long COVID: Pathophysiology&#x2013;epidemiology and patient needs. Health Serv Res (HSR) Brussels: Belgian Health Care Knowledge Center (KCE). 2021. KCE Reports 344. D/2021/10.273/31.  [[Last accessed on 2023 Aug 15]].  Available from: https://www.kce.fgov.be/sites/default/files/2021-11/KCE_344C_Long_Covid_Short_report.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam MK, Molla MMA, Hasan P, Sharif MM, Hossain FS, Amin MR, et al. Persistence of sleep disturbance among post-COVID patients: Findings from a 2-month follow-up study in a Bangladeshi cohort. J Med Virol. 2022;94:971&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34647638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin M, Schommers P, Stecher M, Dewald F, Gieselmann L, Gruell H, et al. Post-COVID syndrome in non-hospitalised patients with COVID-19: A longitudinal prospective cohort study. Lancet Reg Health Eur. 2021;6:100122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8129613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34027514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lackermair K, Wilhelm K, William F, Grzanna N, Lehmann E, Sams L, et al. The Prevalence of persistent symptoms after COVID-19 disease. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2022;119:175&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9215271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35583039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Li X, Gu X, Zhang H, Ren L, Guo L, et al. Health outcomes in people 2 years after surviving hospitalisation with COVID-19: A longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10:863&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9094732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35568052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Cancela-Cilleruelo I, Guerrero-Peral A, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, et al. Post-COVID-19 symptoms 2 years after SARS-CoV-2 infection among hospitalized vs nonhospitalized patients. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:e2242106. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.42106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9667330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36378309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Psychiatric Association. Online Assessment Measures.  Available from: https://www.psychiatry.org/psychiatrists/practice/dsm/educational-resources/assessment-measures .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herdman M, Gudex C, Lloyd A, Janssen M, Kind P, Parkin D, et al. Development and preliminary testing of the new five-level version of EQ-5D (EQ-5D-5L) Qual Life Res. 2011;20:1727&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3220807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21479777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Bae S, Chang HH, Kim SW. Long COVID prevalence and impact on quality of life 2 years after acute COVID-19. Sci Rep. 2023;13:11207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10336045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37433819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirchberger I, Meisinger C, Warm TD, Hyhlik-D&#xfc;rr A, Linseisen J, Go&#xdf;lau Y. Post-COVID-19 syndrome in non-hospitalized individuals: Healthcare situation 2 years after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Viruses. 2023;15:1326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10303962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37376625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny G, Townsend L, Savinelli S, Mallon P. Long COVID: Clinical characteristics, proposed pathogenesis and potential therapeutic targets. Front Mol Biosci. 2023;10:1157651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10171433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37179568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son KY. Depression of Korean, and long COVID syndrome. Korean J Fam Pract. 2022;12:211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudgal SK. Assess learning needs of nursing students and effectiveness of workshop on knowledge regarding extended and expanded role of nurses. Intl J Nurs Educ. 2018;10:109&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma SK, Mudgal SK, Thakur K, Gaur R, Aggarwal P. Lifestyle behavior of budding health care professionals: A cross-sectional descriptive study. J Family Med Prim Care. 2020;9:3525&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7567278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33102325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudgal SK, Agarwal R, Chaturvedi J, Gaur R, Ranjan N. Real-world application, challenges and implication of artificial intelligence in healthcare: An essay. Pan Afr Med J. 2022;43:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9557803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36284890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>