<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37991394</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID in Icelandic Children: A Matched Cohort Study of Nonspecific Symptoms Following SARS-CoV-2 Infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>226</StartPage><EndPage>233</EndPage><MedlinePgn>226-233</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000004187</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Pediatric severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) infections are usually mild and the mortality rates are low, but concerns have been raised about long-term symptoms that may resemble other postinfectious syndromes. Studies with robust control groups and high response rates have been few.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We obtained identifiers for all 837 Icelandic children diagnosed with SARS-CoV-2 by PCR between March 2020 and June 2021 and contacted them by telephone. We asked about 10 physical and mental symptoms being present at least twice weekly for at least 2 months. Participants who reported symptoms were contacted again a year later. For each subject who completed the questionnaire, an age- and sex-matched comparator without SARS-CoV-2 infection was asked to complete the same questionnaire, and the risk difference was calculated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Responses from 643 cases and 602 comparators were analyzed. Children who had been infected with SARS-CoV-2 were more likely to report one or more symptoms, except for anxiety/depression and sleep disturbances. Fatigue and loss of concentration were evidently more common in cases among teenagers (risk difference: 15%; 95% CI: 7-22% and 15%; 95% CI: 7-23%, respectively). At the second follow-up, close to a third of Long COVID cases had resolved but some participants had developed new persistent symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Symptoms of Long COVID in children are common and impact their quality of life. The importance of further unraveling the pathophysiology of acute and long-term symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection in children is vital as well as potential preventive measures.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thors</LastName><ForeName>Valtyr</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0976-9604</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Children's Hospital Iceland, Landspitali, University Hospital Reykjavik, Iceland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Iceland, Faculty of Medicine, Reykjavik, Iceland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bjornsdottir</LastName><ForeName>Kristin Lilja</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Children's Hospital Iceland, Landspitali, University Hospital Reykjavik, Iceland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Love</LastName><ForeName>Thorvardur Jon</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Iceland, Faculty of Medicine, Reykjavik, Iceland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Landspitali, University Hospital, Reykjavik, Iceland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haraldsson</LastName><ForeName>Asgeir</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Children's Hospital Iceland, Landspitali, University Hospital Reykjavik, Iceland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Iceland, Faculty of Medicine, Reykjavik, Iceland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007055" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Iceland</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>VT has undertaken consultancy work for Pfizer and Sanofi. All funding related to these activities is paid to his employers, Landspitali University Hospitals Reykjavik, Iceland. He receives no personal remuneration related to these activities and has no other financial interest in these or other companies or any related intellectual property. None of the funding was received in relation to the work reported here. The other authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37991394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000004187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-990000000-00651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Castagnoli R, Votto M, Licari A, et al. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection in children and adolescents: a systematic review. JAMA Pediatr. 2020;174:882&#x2013;889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thors V, Bjornsdottir KL, Love T, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infections in Icelandic children: close follow-up of all confirmed cases in a nationwide study. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2022;41:835&#x2013;840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Curtis N. Why is COVID-19 less severe in children? A review of the proposed mechanisms underlying the age-related difference in severity of SARS-CoV-2 infections. Arch Dis Child. 2020;106:429&#x2013;439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uka A, Buettcher M, Bernhard-Stirnemann S, et al.; Swiss Paediatric Surveillance Unit (SPSU). Factors associated with hospital and intensive care admission in paediatric SARS-CoV-2 infection: a prospective nationwide observational cohort study. Eur J Pediatr. 2021;181:1245&#x2013;1255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertran M, Amin-Chowdhury Z, Davies HG, et al. COVID-19 deaths in children and young people in England, March 2020 to December 2021: an active prospective national surveillance study. PLoS Med. 2022;19:e1004118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graff K, Smith C, Silveira L, et al. Risk factors for severe COVID-19 in children. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:e137&#x2013;e145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman C, Anderson R. The role of co-infections and secondary infections in patients with COVID-19. Pneumonia (Nathan). 2021;13:5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Pittet LF, Curtis N. How Common is Long COVID in Children and Adolescents? Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:e482&#x2013;e487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaRovere KL, Riggs BJ, Poussaint TY, et al.; Overcoming COVID-19 Investigators. Neurologic involvement in children and adolescents hospitalized in the United States for COVID-19 or multisystem inflammatory syndrome. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78:536&#x2013;547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vos-Kerkhof E, Geurts DH, Wiggers M, et al. Tools for &#x201c;safety netting&#x201d; in common paediatric illnesses: a systematic review in emergency care. Arch Dis Child. 2016;101:131&#x2013;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molteni E, Sudre CH, Canas LS, et al. Illness duration and symptom profile in symptomatic UK school-aged children tested for SARS-CoV-2. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2021;5:708&#x2013;718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakken IJ, Tveito K, Aaberg KM, et al. Comorbidities treated in primary care in children with chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis: a nationwide registry linkage study from Norway. BMC Fam Pract. 2016;17:128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Shafran R, De Stavola B, et al.; CLoCk Consortium members. Long COVID and the mental and physical health of children and young people: national matched cohort study protocol (the CLoCk study). BMJ Open. 2021;11:e052838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carfi A, Bernabei R, Landi F, et al. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borch L, Holm M, Knudsen M, et al. Long COVID symptoms and duration in SARS-CoV-2 positive children - a nationwide cohort study. Eur J Pediatr. 2022;181:1597&#x2013;1607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, et al. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudbjartsson DF, Norddahl GL, Melsted P, et al. Humoral immune response to SARS-CoV-2 in Iceland. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:1724&#x2013;1734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, et al. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)--a metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform. 2009;42:377&#x2013;381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Munblit D, De Rose C, et al. Preliminary evidence on long COVID in children. Acta Paediatr. 2021;110:2208&#x2013;2211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, et al.; WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Clinical management of COVID-19: interim guidance. 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers JP, Chesney E, Oliver D, et al. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: a systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;7:611&#x2013;627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27:626&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giron Perez DA, Fonseca-Aguero A, Toledo-Ibarra GA, et al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome in outpatients and its association with viral load. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:15145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Roy D, Sinha K, et al. Impact of COVID-19 and lockdown on mental health of children and adolescents: a narrative review with recommendations. Psychiatry Res. 2020;293:113429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du M, Ma Y, Deng J, et al. Comparison of Long COVID-19 caused by different SARS-CoV-2 strains: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:16010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, et al. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet. 2022;399:2263&#x2013;2264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Pinto Pereira SM, Nugawela MD, et al.; CLoCk Consortium. Long COVID-six months of prospective follow-up of changes in symptom profiles of non-hospitalised children and young people after SARS-CoV-2 testing: a national matched cohort study (The CLoCk) study. PLoS One. 2023;18:e0277704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haraldsson A, Love TJ, Thors VS. No one will be safe until our children are safe: parent&#x2019;s attitude towards COVID-19 childhood immunization. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:e388.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>