<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33889231</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1937-8688</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Pan African medical journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pan Afr Med J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The occurrence of long COVID: a rapid review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>65</StartPage><MedlinePgn>65</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">65</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.11604/pamj.2021.38.65.27366</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The long-term effects of the severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) are not well understood. This rapid review was aimed at synthesizing evidence on the long-term effects of the SARS-CoV-2 infection among survivors. We considered both randomised controlled trials and non-randomised studies eligible for inclusion in this review. The following databases were searched: PubMed, Scopus, Cochrane library, Google Scholar, and the World Health Organization (WHO) COVID-19 database. The reference lists of all the included studies were also searched. Two authors independently screened the search outputs and reviewed full texts of potentially eligible articles. Data extraction was done by one author and checked by a second author. A meta-analysis was not conducted due to heterogeneity among the included studies. Results are presented narratively. Eleven studies met our inclusion criteria. All these studies were conducted in high-income countries. Study findings demonstrate that COVID-19 survivors can experience persistent symptoms after recovering from their initial illness, especially among previously hospitalized persons. The majority of symptoms reported were fatigue, shortness of breath, cough, and sleep disorders. Mental conditions, such as depression and anxiety disorders, were also reported. In conclusion, this study showed that COVID-19 survivors can experience persistent symptoms after recovering from their initial illness. Therefore, there is a need for a long-term follow-up of COVID-19 patients and rehabilitation services for survivors. More research is needed in this area, especially in Africa.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: Chinwe Juliana Iwu et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iwu</LastName><ForeName>Chinwe Juliana</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing and Midwifery, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Stellenbosch University, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iwu</LastName><ForeName>Chidozie Declan</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Systems and Public Health, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Pretoria, Pretoria 0001, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiysonge</LastName><ForeName>Charles Shey</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cochrane South Africa, South African Medical Research Council, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Global Health, Stellenbosch University, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health and Family Medicine, University of Cape Town, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Uganda</Country><MedlineTA>Pan Afr Med J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101517926</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006760" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitalization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017741" MajorTopicYN="Y">Survivors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long haulers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long term effects of COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33889231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8028365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11604/pamj.2021.38.65.27366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PAMJ-38-65</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Buheji M, da Costa Cunha K, Beka G, Mavri&#x107; B, Leandro do Carmo de Souza Y, Souza da Costa Silva S, et al. The extent of COVID-19 pandemic socio-economic impact on global poverty: a global integrative multidisciplinary review. Am J Econ. 2020;2020(4):213&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sollini M, Ciccarelli M, Cecconi M, Aghemo A, Morelli P, Gelardi F, et al. Vasculitis changes in COVID-19 survivors with persistent symptoms: an [18F]FDG-PET/CT study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2020 Oct 30;:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7595761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33123760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandhi RT, Lynch JB, del Rio C. Mild or Moderate COVID-19. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(18)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32329974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S. Understanding the long-term health effects of COVID-19. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;26:100586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7527190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33020749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahase E. COVID-19: what do we know about &#x201c;Long COVID&#x201d;. BMJ. 2020;370:m2815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32665317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG, PRISMA Group. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Med. 2009;6(7):e1000097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, Rose EB, Shapiro NI, Clark D, et al. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a Multistate Health Care Systems Network-United States, March-June 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020 Jul 31;69(30):993&#x2013;998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Schneider C, Laurent E, Lemaignen A, Beaufils E, Bourbao-Tournois C, Laribi S, et al. Follow-up of adults with non-critical COVID-19 two months after symptoms&#xb4; onset. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2020 Oct 5;S1198-743X(20):30606&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Docherty AB, Harrison EM, Green CA, Hardwick Karl HE, Frank Dondelinger A Holden, Laura Merson, et al. Features of 20 133 UK patients in hospital with COVID-19 using the ISARIC WHO clinical characterisation protocol: prospective observational cohort study. BMJ. 2020;369</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32444460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, et al. Post-discharge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021 Feb;93(2):1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues E, Janvier P, Kherabi Y, Le Bot A, Hamon A, Gouze H, et al. Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. J Infect. 2020 Dec;81(6):e4&#x2013;e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swapna Mandal, Joseph Barnett, Simon E Brill, Jeremy S Brown, Emma K Denneny, Samanjit S Hare, et al. Thorax. 2020. Nov 10, Long-COVID: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. thoraxjnl-2020;215818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak P. Post COVID-19 syndrome associated with orthostatic cerebral hypoperfusion syndrome, small fiber neuropathy and benefit of immunotherapy: a case report. eNeurologicalSci. 2020 Sep 21;:100276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7502253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32984564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Respiratory Society. COVID-19 patients suffer long-term lung and heart damage but it can improve with time. European Respiratory Society. 2020;19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM. Chronic COVID syndrome: seed for an appropriate medical terminology for Long-COVID and COVID Long-Haulers. J Med Virol. 2020 Oct 23;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33095459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callard F, Perego DE. How and why patients made long COVID. Soc Sci Med. 2021 Jan;268:113426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7539940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33199035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahase E. COVID-19: Nearly 20% of patients receive psychiatric diagnosis within three months of COVID, study finds. BMJ. 2020;4386</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honigsbaum M, Krishnan L. Taking pandemic sequelae seriously: from the Russian influenza to COVID-19 long-haulers. Lancet. 2020;396(10260):1389&#x2013;1391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7550169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33058777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin R. As their numbers grow. COVID-19 &#x201c;Long Haulers&#x201d; Stump Experts. JAMA. 2020. Sep 23,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32965460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Harrison PJ. Bi-directional associations between COVID-19 and psychiatric disorder: retrospective cohort studies of 62 354 COVID-19 cases in the USA. The lancet Psychiatry. 2020 Nov 9;S2215- 0366;(20):30462&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weerahandi H, Hochman KA, Simon E, Blaum C, Chodosh J, Duan E, et al. Post-discharge health status and symptoms in patients with severe COVID-19. medRxiv Prepr 2020. 2020 Aug 14;08(11):20172742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33443703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludvigsson J. Case report and systematic review suggest that children may experience similar long-term effects to adults after clinical COVID-19. Acta Paediatr. 2020. Nov 17,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apa.15673.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33205450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moldofsky H, Patcai J. Chronic widespread musculoskeletal pain, fatigue, depression and disordered sleep in chronic post-SARS syndrome; a case-controlled study. BMC Neurol. 2011 Mar 24;11:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3071317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21435231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam MH-B, Wing Y-K, Yu MW-M, Leung C-M, Ma RCW, Kong APS, et al. Mental morbidities and chronic fatigue in severe acute respiratory syndrome survivors. Arch Intern Med. 2009;169(22):2142&#x2013;2147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20008700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngai JC, Ko FW, Ng SS, To KW, Tong M, Hui DS. The long-term impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome on pulmonary function, exercise capacity and health status. Respirology. 2010;15(3):543&#x2013;550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7192220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20337995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall M. The lasting misery of coronavirus long-haulers. Nature. 2020;585(7825):339&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32929257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>