<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38711990</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1663-9812</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Management of cognitive impairment associated with post-COVID-19 syndrome: recommendations for primary care.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1338235</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1338235</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1338235</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphar.2024.1338235</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Introduction:</b> Although post-COVID-19 syndrome (PCS) with cognitive impairment is increasingly encountered in primary care, evidence-based recommendations for its appropriate management are lacking. <b>Methods:</b> A systematic literature search evaluating the diagnosis and treatment of cognitive impairment associated with PCS was conducted. Practical recommendations for the management of PCS-associated cognitive impairment in primary care are summarized, based on an evaluation of pharmacological plausibility and clinical applications. <b>Results:</b> Currently, the pathology of cognitive impairment associated with PCS remains unclear with no high-quality data to support targeted interventions. Existing treatment approaches are directed towards symptom relief where counseling on the chronicity of the disease and regular reassessments at 4- to 8-week intervals is considered reasonable. Patients should be informed and encouraged to adopt a healthy lifestyle that centers around balanced nutrition and appropriate physical activities. They may also benefit from the intake of vitamins, micronutrients, and probiotics. The administration of <i>Ginkgo biloba</i> extract could offer a safe and potentially beneficial treatment option. Other non-pharmacological measures include physiotherapy, digitally supported cognitive training, and, if indicated, ergotherapy or speech therapy. In most patients, symptoms improve within 8 weeks. If serious, ambiguous, or when new symptoms occur, specialized diagnostic measures such as comprehensive neurocognitive testing or neuroimaging should be initiated. Very few patients would require inpatient rehabilitation. <b>Conclusion:</b> PCS with cognitive impairment is a debilitating condition that could affect daily functioning and reduce work productivity. Management in primary care should adopt a multidisciplinary approach, centering around physical, cognitive, and pharmacological therapies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Zifko, Guendling, Seet and Kasper.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zifko</LastName><ForeName>Udo</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rudolfinerhaus private clinic GmbH, Rudolfinerhaus, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guendling</LastName><ForeName>Katja</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine Family Practice, Bad Camberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seet</LastName><ForeName>Raymond</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine, National University of Singapore, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kasper</LastName><ForeName>Siegfried</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Brain Research, Department of Molecular Neuroscience, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101548923</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1663-9812</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EGb 761&#xae;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ginkgo biloba extract</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive impairment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute covid</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>This research received funding from Dr. Willmar Schwabe GmbH &amp; Co. KG. The funder was involved in the study design and data collection. The final decision to submit the article for publication remained with the authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38711990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11072190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2024.1338235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1338235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aiello E. N., Fiabane E., Manera M. R., Radici A., Grossi F., Ottonello M., et al. (2022). Screening for cognitive sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a comparison between the mini-mental state examination (MMSE) and the Montreal cognitive assessment (MoCA). Neurol. Sci. 43 (1), 81&#x2013;84. 10.1007/s10072-021-05630-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-021-05630-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8526352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34668124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi O. L., Hughes S. E., Turner G., Rivera S. C., McMullan C., Chandan J. S., et al. (2021). Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J. R. Soc. Med. 114 (9), 428&#x2013;442. 10.1177/01410768211032850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/01410768211032850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astin R., Banerjee A., Baker M. R., Dani M., Ford E., Hull J. H., et al. (2023). Long COVID: mechanisms, risk factors and recovery. Exp. Physiol. 108 (1), 12&#x2013;27. 10.1113/EP090802</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP090802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10103775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36412084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachmeier B. E., Holzle S., Gasser M., van den Akker M. (2023). How do German general practitioners manage long-/post-COVID? A qualitative study in primary care. Viruses 15 (4), 1016. 10.3390/v15041016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v15041016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10146752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37112996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrea L., Vetrani C., Caprio M., Cataldi M., Ghoch M. E., Elce A., et al. (2022). From the ketogenic diet to the mediterranean diet: the potential dietary therapy in patients with obesity after CoVID-19 infection (post CoVID syndrome). Curr. Obes. Rep. 11 (3), 144&#x2013;165. 10.1007/s13679-022-00475-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13679-022-00475-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9075143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35524067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonilla H., Peluso M. J., Rodgers K., Aberg J. A., Patterson T. F., Tamburro R., et al. (2023). Therapeutic trials for long COVID-19: a call to action from the interventions taskforce of the RECOVER initiative. Front. Immunol. 14, 1129459. 10.3389/fimmu.2023.1129459</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1129459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10034329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36969241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabria M., Garcia-Sanchez C., Grunden N., Pons C., Arroyo J. A., Gomez-Anson B., et al. (2022). Post-COVID-19 fatigue: the contribution of cognitive and neuropsychiatric symptoms. J. Neurol. 269 (8), 3990&#x2013;3999. 10.1007/s00415-022-11141-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-022-11141-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9055007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35488918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carfi A., Bernabei R., Landi F., Gemelli Against C.-P.-A. C. S. G. (2020). Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA 324 (6), 603&#x2013;605. 10.1001/jama.2020.12603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.12603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanares-Zapatero D., Chalon P., Kohn L., Dauvrin M., Detollenaere J., Maertens de Noordhout C., et al. (2022). Pathophysiology and mechanism of long COVID: a comprehensive review. Ann. Med. 54 (1), 1473&#x2013;1487. 10.1080/07853890.2022.2076901</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2022.2076901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35594336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catalano A., Iacopetta D., Ceramella J., Maio A. C., Basile G., Giuzio F., et al. (2022). Are nutraceuticals effective in COVID-19 and post-COVID prevention and treatment? Foods 11 (18), 2884. 10.3390/foods11182884</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/foods11182884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9498392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36141012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F., Ling S., Lui L. M. W., Lee Y., Gill H., Teopiz K. M., et al. (2022). Fatigue and cognitive impairment in Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav. Immun. 101, 93&#x2013;135. 10.1016/j.bbi.2021.12.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2021.12.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crivelli L., Calandri I., Corvalan N., Carello M. A., Keller G., Martinez C., et al. (2022). Cognitive consequences of COVID-19: results of a cohort study from South America. Arq. Neuropsiquiatr. 80 (3), 240&#x2013;247. 10.1590/0004-282X-ANP-2021-0320</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/0004-282X-ANP-2021-0320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9648931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34816972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H. E., McCorkell L., Vogel J. M., Topol E. J. (2023). Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 21 (3), 133&#x2013;146. 10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diez-Cirarda M., Yus M., Gomez-Ruiz N., Polidura C., Gil-Martinez L., Delgado-Alonso C., et al. (2023). Multimodal neuroimaging in post-COVID syndrome and correlation with cognition. Brain 146 (5), 2142&#x2013;2152. 10.1093/brain/awac384</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awac384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9620345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36288544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnachie E., Hapfelmeier A., Linde K., Tauscher M., Gerlach R., Greissel A., et al. (2022). Incidence of post-COVID syndrome and associated symptoms in outpatient care in Bavaria, Germany: a retrospective cohort study using routinely collected claims data. BMJ Open 12 (9), e064979. 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-064979</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-064979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9511014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36137635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunabeitia J. A., Mera F., Baro O., Jadad-Garcia T., Jadad A. R. (2023). Personalized computerized training for cognitive dysfunction after COVID-19: a before-and-after feasibility pilot study. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 20 (4), 3100. 10.3390/ijerph20043100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20043100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9966004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36833793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elizalde-Diaz J. P., Miranda-Narvaez C. L., Martinez-Lazcano J. C., Martinez-Martinez E. (2022). The relationship between chronic immune response and neurodegenerative damage in long COVID-19. Front. Immunol. 13, 1039427. 10.3389/fimmu.2022.1039427</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.1039427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9800881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36591299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdin&#x4ab;ler D. S., Karako&#x4ab; Y., Toplan S., &#xd6;nen S., Sukyasyan A., Be&#x11f;er T., et al. (1996). The effect of ginkgo biloba glycoside on the blood viscosity and erythrocyte deformability. Clin. Hemorheol. 16 (3), 271&#x2013;276. 10.3233/ch-1996-16306</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/ch-1996-16306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Castaneda A., Lu P., Geraghty A. C., Song E., Lee M. H., Wood J., et al. (2022). Mild respiratory COVID can cause multi-lineage neural cell and myelin dysregulation. Cell 185 (14), 2452&#x2013;2468.e16. 10.1016/j.cell.2022.06.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2022.06.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9189143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35768006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrucci R., Cuffaro L., Capozza A., Rosci C., Maiorana N., Groppo E., et al. (2023). Brain positron emission tomography (PET) and cognitive abnormalities one year after COVID-19. J. Neurol. 270 (4), 1823&#x2013;1834. 10.1007/s00415-022-11543-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-022-11543-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9873215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36692636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franke C., Boesl F., Goereci Y., Gerhard A., Schweitzer F., Schroeder M., et al. (2023). Association of cerebrospinal fluid brain-binding autoantibodies with cognitive impairment in post-COVID-19 syndrome. Brain Behav. Immun. 109, 139&#x2013;143. 10.1016/j.bbi.2023.01.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2023.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9841734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36657623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera J. A., Guekht A., Allegri R. F., Ashraf M., Baykan B., Crivelli L., et al. (2023). Evaluation and treatment approaches for neurological post-acute sequelae of COVID-19: a consensus statement and scoping review from the global COVID-19 neuro research coalition. J. Neurol. Sci. 454, 120827. 10.1016/j.jns.2023.120827</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2023.120827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37856998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gang J., Wang H., Xue X., Zhang S. (2022). Microbiota and COVID-19: long-term and complex influencing factors. Front. Microbiol. 13, 963488. 10.3389/fmicb.2022.963488</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2022.963488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9417543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36033885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Sanchez C., Calabria M., Grunden N., Pons C., Arroyo J. A., Gomez-Anson B., et al. (2022). Neuropsychological deficits in patients with cognitive complaints after COVID-19. Brain Behav. 12 (3), e2508. 10.1002/brb3.2508</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/brb3.2508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8933779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35137561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gargouri B., Carstensen J., Bhatia H. S., Huell M., Dietz G. P. H., Fiebich B. L. (2018). Anti-neuroinflammatory effects of Ginkgo biloba extract EGb761 in LPS-activated primary microglial cells. Phytomedicine 44, 45&#x2013;55. 10.1016/j.phymed.2018.04.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phymed.2018.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29895492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier S., Schlaefke S. (2014). Efficacy and tolerability of Ginkgo biloba extract EGb 761&#xae; in dementia: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized placebo-controlled trials. Clin. Interv. Aging 9, 2065&#x2013;2077. 10.2147/CIA.S72728</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CIA.S72728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4259871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25506211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavrilova S. I., Preuss U. W., Wong J. W., Hoerr R., Kaschel R., Bachinskaya N., et al. (2014). Efficacy and safety of Ginkgo biloba extract EGb 761 in mild cognitive impairment with neuropsychiatric symptoms: a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, multi-center trial. Int. J. Geriatr. Psychiatry 29 (10), 1087&#x2013;1095. 10.1002/gps.4103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/gps.4103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24633934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grass-Kapanke B., Busmane A., Lasmanis A., Hoerr R., Kaschel R. (2011). Effects of ginkgo biloba special extract EGb 761&amp;amp;#174; in very mild cognitive impairment (vMCI). Neurosci. Med. 2 (01), 48&#x2013;56. 10.4236/nm.2011.21007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/nm.2011.21007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E., Campion J. Y., Dudouet P., Kaphan E., Bregeon F., Tissot-Dupont H., et al. (2021). (18)F-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in patients with long COVID. Eur. J. Nucl. Med. Mol. Imaging 48 (9), 2823&#x2013;2833. 10.1007/s00259-021-05215-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-021-05215-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33501506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadad R., Khoury J., Stanger C., Fisher T., Schneer S., Ben-Hayun R., et al. (2022). Cognitive dysfunction following COVID-19 infection. J. Neurovirol 28 (3), 430&#x2013;437. 10.1007/s13365-022-01079-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13365-022-01079-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9134977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35618983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausswirth C., Schmit C., Rougier Y., Coste A. (2023). Positive impacts of a four-week neuro-meditation program on cognitive function in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 patients: a randomized controlled trial. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 20 (2), 1361. 10.3390/ijerph20021361</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20021361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9858974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36674117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegna E., Racki V., Hero M., Papic E., Rozmaric G., Radovic K., et al. (2023). Post-COVID-19 syndrome in neurology patients: a single center experience. Pathogens 12 (6), 796. 10.3390/pathogens12060796</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pathogens12060796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10302491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37375486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almazan A., Buendia-Romero A., Martinez-Cava A., Franco-Lopez F., Sanchez-Alcaraz B. J., Courel-Ibanez J., et al. (2023). Effects of a concurrent training, respiratory muscle exercise, and self-management recommendations on recovery from post-COVID-19 conditions: the RECOVE trial. J. Appl. Physiol. 134 (1), 95&#x2013;104. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00489.2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00489.2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9829459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36476156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Koczulla A. R., Ankermann T., Behrends U., Berlit P., Berner R., B&#xf6;ing S., et al.  (2022). AWMF S1-leitlinie long/post-COVID (S1 guideline long/post-COVID). Available at: https://register.awmf.org/de/leitlinien/detail/020-027 (Accessed August, 2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36479679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuchler T., Gunthner R., Ribeiro A., Hausinger R., Streese L., Wohnl A., et al. (2023). Persistent endothelial dysfunction in post-COVID-19 syndrome and its associations with symptom severity and chronic inflammation. Angiogenesis 26, 547&#x2013;563. 10.1007/s10456-023-09885-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10456-023-09885-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10542303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37507580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kupferschmitt A., Etzrodt F., Kleinschmidt J., Kollner V. (2023). Not only multimodal, but also interdisciplinary: a concept for interdisciplinary cooperation in the rehabilitation of post-COVID syndrome. Psychother. Psychosom. Med. Psychol. 73 (1), 34&#x2013;41. 10.1055/a-1838-3055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1838-3055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35605967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauria A., Carfi A., Benvenuto F., Bramato G., Ciciarello F., Rocchi S., et al. (2022). Neuropsychological measures of long COVID-19 fog in older subjects. Clin. Geriatr. Med. 38 (3), 593&#x2013;603. 10.1016/j.cger.2022.05.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cger.2022.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9080120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35868675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leng A., Shah M., Ahmad S. A., Premraj L., Wildi K., Li Bassi G., et al. (2023). Pathogenesis underlying neurological manifestations of long COVID syndrome and potential therapeutics. Cells 12 (5), 816. 10.3390/cells12050816</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells12050816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10001044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36899952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludwig B., Deckert M., Krajnc N., Keritam O., Macher S., Bsteh G., et al. (2023). Reported neurological symptoms after severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus type 2 infection: a systematic diagnostic approach. Eur. J. Neurol. 30 (9), 2713&#x2013;2725. 10.1111/ene.15923</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37306533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch S., Ferrando S. J., Dornbush R., Shahar S., Smiley A., Klepacz L. (2022). Screening for brain fog: is the montreal cognitive assessment an effective screening tool for neurocognitive complaints post-COVID-19? Gen. Hosp. Psychiatry 78, 80&#x2013;86. 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2022.07.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2022.07.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9359801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35930974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnavita N., Arnesano G., Di Prinzio R. R., Gasbarri M., Meraglia I., Merella M., et al. (2023). Post-COVID symptoms in occupational cohorts: effects on health and work ability. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 20 (9), 5638. 10.3390/ijerph20095638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20095638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10178744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37174158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majidi N., Bahadori E., Shekari S., Gholamalizadeh M., Tajadod S., Ajami M., et al. (2022). Effects of supplementation with low-dose group B vitamins on clinical and biochemical parameters in critically ill patients with COVID-19: a randomized clinical trial. Expert Rev. Anti Infect. Ther., 1&#x2013;7. 10.1080/14787210.2022.2125867</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14787210.2022.2125867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36108676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manganotti P., Michelutti M., Furlanis G., Deodato M., Buoite Stella A. (2023). Deficient GABABergic and glutamatergic excitability in the motor cortex of patients with long-COVID and cognitive impairment. Clin. Neurophysiol. 151, 83&#x2013;91. 10.1016/j.clinph.2023.04.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2023.04.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10170904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37210757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matias-Guiu J. A., Herrera E., Gonzalez-Nosti M., Krishnan K., Delgado-Alonso C., Diez-Cirarda M., et al. (2023). Development of criteria for cognitive dysfunction in post-COVID syndrome: the IC-CoDi-COVID approach. Psychiatry Res. 319, 115006. 10.1016/j.psychres.2022.115006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2022.115006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36521337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mina Y., Enose-Akahata Y., Hammoud D. A., Videckis A. J., Narpala S. R., O'Connell S. E., et al. (2023). Deep phenotyping of neurologic postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Neurol. Neuroimmunol. Neuroinflamm 10 (4), e200097. 10.1212/NXI.0000000000200097</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXI.0000000000200097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10162706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37147136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed Hussein A. A. R., Galal I., Amin M. T., Moshnib A. A., Makhlouf N. A., Makhlouf H. A., et al. (2022). Prevalence of vitamin D deficiency among patients attending Post COVID-19 follow-up clinic: a cross-sectional study. Eur. Rev. Med. Pharmacol. Sci. 26 (8), 3038&#x2013;3045. 10.26355/eurrev_202204_28635</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26355/eurrev_202204_28635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35503606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momtazmanesh S., Ansari S., Izadi Z., Shobeiri P., Vatankhah V., Seifi A., et al. (2023). Effect of famotidine on cognitive and behavioral dysfunctions induced in post-COVID-19 infection: a randomized, double-blind, and placebo-controlled study. J. Psychosom. Res. 172, 111389. 10.1016/j.jpsychores.2023.111389</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2023.111389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10229204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37327698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monje M., Iwasaki A. (2022). The neurobiology of long COVID. Neuron 110 (21), 3484&#x2013;3496. 10.1016/j.neuron.2022.10.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2022.10.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9537254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36288726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller J. K., Muller W. E. (2024). Multi-target drugs for the treatment of cognitive impairment and fatigue in post-COVID syndrome: focus on Ginkgo biloba and Rhodiola rosea. J. Neural Transm. (Vienna) 131 (3), 203&#x2013;212. 10.1007/s00702-024-02749-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-024-02749-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10874325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38347175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller L., Di Benedetto S. (2023). Aged brain and neuroimmune responses to COVID-19: post-acute sequelae and modulatory effects of behavioral and nutritional interventions. Immun. Ageing 20 (1), 17. 10.1186/s12979-023-00341-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12979-023-00341-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10090758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37046272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine Z. S., Phillips N. A., Bedirian V., Charbonneau S., Whitehead V., Collin I., et al. (2005). The Montreal Cognitive Assessment, MoCA: a brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. J. Am. Geriatr. Soc. 53 (4), 695&#x2013;699. 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2005.53221.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2005.53221.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navis A. (2023). A review of neurological symptoms in long COVID and clinical management. Semin. Neurol. 43 (2), 286&#x2013;296. 10.1055/s-0043-1767781</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0043-1767781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37068519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicotra A., Masserini F., Calcaterra F., Di Vito C., Doneddu P. E., Pomati S., et al. (2023). What do we mean by long-COVID? A scoping review of the cognitive sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Eur. J. Neurol. 30, 3968&#x2013;3978. 10.1111/ene.16027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.16027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37540896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noda Y., Sato A., Shichi M., Sato A., Fujii K., Iwasa M., et al. (2023). Real world research on transcranial magnetic stimulation treatment strategies for neuropsychiatric symptoms with long-COVID in Japan. Asian J. Psychiatr. 81, 103438. 10.1016/j.ajp.2022.103438</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajp.2022.103438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9795803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36610206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostergaard L. (2021). SARS CoV-2 related microvascular damage and symptoms during and after COVID-19: consequences of capillary transit-time changes, tissue hypoxia and inflammation. Physiol. Rep. 9 (3), e14726. 10.14814/phy2.14726</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.14726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7849453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33523608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palladini M., Bravi B., Colombo F., Caselani E., Di Pasquasio C., D'Orsi G., et al. (2023). Cognitive remediation therapy for post-acute persistent cognitive deficits in COVID-19 survivors: a proof-of-concept study. Neuropsychol. Rehabil. 33 (7), 1207&#x2013;1224. 10.1080/09602011.2022.2075016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09602011.2022.2075016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35583357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlidou E., Poulios E., Papadopoulou S. K., Fasoulas A., Dakanalis A., Giaginis C. (2024). Clinical evidence on the potential beneficial effects of diet and dietary supplements against COVID-19 infection risk and symptoms' severity. Med. Sci. (Basel) 12 (1), 11. 10.3390/medsci12010011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medsci12010011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10885051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38390861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierre S. V., Lesnik P., Moreau M., Bonello L., Droy-Lefaix M. T., Sennoune S., et al. (2008). The standardized Ginkgo biloba extract Egb-761 protects vascular endothelium exposed to oxidized low density lipoproteins. Cell Mol. Biol. (Noisy-le-grand) 54, OL1032&#x2013;1042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18954552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pooladgar P., Sakhabakhsh M., Soleiman-Meigooni S., Taghva A., Nasiri M., Darazam I. A. (2023). The effect of donepezil hydrochloride on post-COVID memory impairment: a randomized controlled trial. J. Clin. Neurosci. 118, 168&#x2013;174. 10.1016/j.jocn.2023.09.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocn.2023.09.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37952347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal A. D., VanElzakker M. B. (2021). Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): an overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front. Microbiol. 12, 698169. 10.3389/fmicb.2021.698169</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2021.698169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabady S., Hoffmann K., Aigner M., Altenberger J., Brose M., Costa U., et al. (2023). S1 guidelines for the management of postviral conditions using the example of post-COVID-19. Wien Klin. Wochenschr 135 (4), 525&#x2013;598. 10.1007/s00508-023-02242-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00508-023-02242-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10504206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37555900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabaiotti P., Ciraci C., Donelli D., Oggioni C., Rizzi B., Savi F., et al. (2023). Effects of multidisciplinary rehabilitation enhanced with neuropsychological treatment on post-acute SARS-CoV-2 cognitive impairment (brain fog): an observational study. Brain Sci. 13 (5), 791. 10.3390/brainsci13050791</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci13050791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10216015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37239263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schild A. K., Goereci Y., Scharfenberg D., Klein K., Lulling J., Meiberth D., et al. (2023). Multidomain cognitive impairment in non-hospitalized patients with the post-COVID-19 syndrome: results from a prospective monocentric cohort. J. Neurol. 270 (3), 1215&#x2013;1223. 10.1007/s00415-022-11444-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-022-11444-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9686246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36422669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmachtenberg T., Muller F., Kranz J., Dragaqina A., Wegener G., Konigs G., et al. (2023). How do long COVID patients perceive their current life situation and occupational perspective? Results of a qualitative interview study in Germany. Front. Public Health 11, 1155193. 10.3389/fpubh.2023.1155193</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1155193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10034079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36969629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrimpf A., Braesigk A., Lippmann S., Bleckwenn M. (2022). Management and treatment of long COVID symptoms in general practices: an online-based survey. Front. Public Health 10, 937100. 10.3389/fpubh.2022.937100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2022.937100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9513068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36176520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz M., Hoerr R., Mueller H. (2018). 46th ESCP symposium on clinical pharmacy "Science meets practice: towards evidence-based clinical pharmacy services", Heidelberg, Germany, October 9th-11th, 2017. Int. J. Clin. Pharm. 40 (1), 203&#x2013;317. 10.1007/s11096-017-0565-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11096-017-0565-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29222732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano-Castro P. J., Garzon-Maldonado F. J., Casado-Naranjo I., Ollero-Ortiz A., Minguez-Castellanos A., Iglesias-Espinosa M., et al. (2022). The cognitive and psychiatric subacute impairment in severe Covid-19. Sci. Rep. 12 (1), 3563. 10.1038/s41598-022-07559-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-07559-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8894467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35241761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanley J. E., Valenciano A. F., Timmons G., Miner A. E., Kakarla V., Rempe T., et al. (2022). Longitudinal evaluation of neurologic-post acute sequelae SARS-CoV-2 infection symptoms. Ann. Clin. Transl. Neurol. 9 (7), 995&#x2013;1010. 10.1002/acn3.51578</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.51578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9268882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35702954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherif Z. A., Gomez C. R., Connors T. J., Henrich T. J., Reeves W. B., Force R. M. P. T. (2023). Pathogenic mechanisms of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC). Elife 12, e86002. 10.7554/eLife.86002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.86002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10032659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36947108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siso-Almirall A., Brito-Zeron P., Conangla Ferrin L., Kostov B., Moragas Moreno A., Mestres J., et al. (2021). Long covid-19: proposed primary care clinical guidelines for diagnosis and disease management. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 18 (8), 4350. 10.3390/ijerph18084350</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18084350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33923972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E., Zhang C., Israelow B., Lu-Culligan A., Prado A. V., Skriabine S., et al. (2021). Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 in human and mouse brain. J. Exp. Med. 218 (3), e20202135. 10.1084/jem.20202135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1084/jem.20202135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y., Yuan D., Chen D. G., Ng R. H., Wang K., Choi J., et al. (2022). Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell 185 (5), 881&#x2013;895.e20. 10.1016/j.cell.2022.01.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2022.01.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes D. L., Holdsworth L., Jawad N., Gunasekera P., Morice A. H., Crooks M. G. (2021). Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung 199 (2), 113&#x2013;119. 10.1007/s00408-021-00423-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00408-021-00423-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taruffi L., Muccioli L., Mitolo M., Ferri L., Descovich C., Mazzoni S., et al. (2023). Neurological manifestations of long COVID: a single-center one-year experience. Neuropsychiatr. Dis. Treat. 19, 311&#x2013;319. 10.2147/NDT.S387501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S387501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9904212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36761395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixido L., Andreeva E., Gartmann J., Lemhofer C., Sturm C., Gutenbrunner C. (2023). Outpatient rehabilitative care for patients with Long-COVID - a guideline-based clinical practice guideline. Laryngorhinootologie 102 (7), 521&#x2013;532. 10.1055/a-1985-0450</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1985-0450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37130538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosato M., Ciciarello F., Zazzara M. B., Pais C., Savera G., Picca A., et al. (2022). Nutraceuticals and dietary supplements for older adults with long COVID-19. Clin. Geriatr. Med. 38 (3), 565&#x2013;591. 10.1016/j.cger.2022.04.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cger.2022.04.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35868674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieth R. (2022). Critique of public health guidance for vitamin D and sun exposure in the context of cancer and COVID-19. Anticancer Res. 42 (10), 5027&#x2013;5034. 10.21873/anticanres.16011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21873/anticanres.16011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36191997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollbracht C., Kraft K. (2021). Feasibility of vitamin C in the treatment of post viral fatigue with focus on long COVID, based on a systematic review of IV vitamin C on fatigue. Nutrients 13 (4), 1154. 10.3390/nu13041154</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13041154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8066596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker S., Goodfellow H., Pookarnjanamorakot P., Murray E., Bindman J., Blandford A., et al. (2023). Impact of fatigue as the primary determinant of functional limitations among patients with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a cross-sectional observational study. BMJ Open 13 (6), e069217. 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-069217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-069217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10335413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37286327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2021). A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021. Geneva: World Health Organization.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F., Zhao H., Liu H., Wu X., Li Y. (2021). Manifestations and mechanisms of central nervous system damage caused by SARS-CoV-2. Brain Res. Bull. 177, 155&#x2013;163. 10.1016/j.brainresbull.2021.09.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainresbull.2021.09.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8462004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34571039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaa C. A., Espitia C., Reyes-Barrera K. L., An Z., Velasco-Velazquez M. A. (2023). Neuroprotective agents with therapeutic potential for COVID-19. Biomolecules 13 (11), 1585. 10.3390/biom13111585</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom13111585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10669388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38002267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Wang D. F., Zhang Z., Han D., Yang K. (2017). EGb 761 protects cardiac microvascular endothelial cells against hypoxia/reoxygenation injury and exerts inhibitory effect on the ATM pathway. J. Microbiol. Biotechnol. 27 (3), 584&#x2013;590. 10.4014/jmb.1611.11024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4014/jmb.1611.11024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27974731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zifko U. A., Yacob M., Braun B. J., Dietz G. P. H. (2022). Alleviation of post-COVID-19 cognitive deficits by treatment with EGb 761&#xae;: a case series. Am. J. Case Rep. 23, e937094. 10.12659/AJCR.937094</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/AJCR.937094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9523733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36156538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>