<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39479090</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Complications of Long COVID: Unraveling a Case of Very-Late-Onset Myasthenia Gravis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70552</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70552</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e70552</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.70552</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Myasthenia gravis (MG) is defined as an autoimmune neuromuscular disorder where autoantibodies disrupt synaptic transmission at the neuromuscular junction by targeting the acetylcholine receptor (AChR), muscle-specific kinase (MuSK), or other proteins related to the AChR complex. This disruption leads to characteristic muscle weakness and rapid fatigability. Clinically, MG is classified based on the age of onset into three distinct categories: early-onset MG (younger than 50 years), late-onset MG (between 50 and 64 years), and very-late-onset MG (65 years and older). We present a rare case of an 81-year-old man who presented with dysarthria, shortness of breath, diplopia, and oropharyngeal dysphagia to both solids and liquids for approximately seven days and was noted to be more progressive in the last 48 hours prior to his presentation to the emergency room. Upon arrival at the emergency room, he complained of shortness of breath and diplopia. Of note, approximately four months prior to this admission, he was diagnosed with COVID-19 pneumonia and was treated appropriately with remdesivir and corticosteroids. He had an uneventful COVID-19 pneumonia hospitalization and was discharged home. Given the progressive nature of his symptomatology, particularly dyspnea, he was transferred to the ICU for further evaluation and treatment. Laboratory results were positive for AChR binding, blocking, and modulating antibodies, confirming the diagnosis of MG. The patient received treatment consisting of pyridostigmine, a pulse dose of methylprednisolone, and intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG) therapy. This case is unique and highlights a case of a very late onset of MG and the manifestation of new-onset MG four months following COVID-19. Additionally, this patient had a very delayed onset of MG symptoms, as he presented four months after his infection with COVID-19, compared to the average onset of reported cases of post-COVID MG being four to eight weeks post-infection with COVID-19. This uniquely delayed onset, occurring beyond a three-month window post-COVID-19 infection, aligns with the criteria established by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) and the World Health Organization (WHO) for a diagnosis of "Post-COVID Condition," also known as "Long COVID." This case illustrates the intricate link between post-viral states and autoimmune responses, particularly in geriatric patients. The pathophysiology linking COVID-19 to MG primarily involves immune dysregulation triggered by the viral infection, which may disrupt immune tolerance and lead to clinical autoimmunity. This case stresses the need for vigilance in diagnosis and managing neurological complications in the context of viral respiratory illnesses, particularly in vulnerable populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Feiz et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feiz</LastName><ForeName>Hamid</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Nova Southeastern University Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Allopathic Medicine, Fort Lauderdale, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castellano</LastName><ForeName>Courteney</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Osteopathic Medicine, Nova Southeastern University Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Osteopathic Medicine, Fort Lauderdale, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feiz</LastName><ForeName>Leyla</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Osteopathic Medicine, Nova Southeastern University Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Osteopathic Medicine, Fort Lauderdale, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">late-onset myasthenia gravis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-covid complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-infectious myasthenia gravis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sars-cov-2 (severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus -2)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Consent was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39479090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11524643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.70552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Myasthenia gravis. Gilhus NE, Tzartos S, Evoli A, Palace J, Burns TM, Verschuuren JJ. https://www.nature.com/articles/s41572-019-0079-y#citeas. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2019;5:30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31048702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of tacrolimus therapy for a single Chinese cohort with very-late-onset myasthenia gravis. Zheng Y, Yuan X, Zhang C, et al.  https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/neurology/articles/10.3389/fneur.2022.843523/full Front Neurol. 2022;13:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9007732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35432159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The relationship between myasthenia gravis and COVID-19: a systematic review. Tugasworo D, Kurnianto A, Retnaningsih Retnaningsih, Andhitara Y, Ardhini R, Budiman J. https://ejnpn.springeropen.com/articles/10.1186/s41983-022-00516-3#citeas. Egypt J Neurol Psychiatr Neurosurg. 2022;58:83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9261189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35818475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A case report and literature review of new-onset myasthenia gravis after COVID-19 infection. Chatterjee T, Senthil Kumaran S, Roy M. https://www.cureus.com/articles/129412-a-case-report-and-literature-review-of-new-onset-myasthenia-gravis-after-covid-19-infection#!/ Cureus. 2022;14:48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9881688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36721575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>New onset of ocular myasthenia gravis in a patient with COVID-19: a novel case report and literature review. Sriwastava S, Tandon M, Kataria S, Daimee M, Sultan S. https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00415-020-10263-1. J Neurol. 2021;268:2690&#x2013;2696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7549728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33047223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myasthenia gravis. Gilhus NE. https://www.nejm.org/doi/10.1056/NEJMra1602678. N Engl J Med. 2016;375:2570&#x2013;2581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28029925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical profile and impact of comorbidities in patients with very-late-onset myasthenia gravis. Vijayan J, Menon D, Barnett C, Katzberg H, Lovblom LE, Bril V. https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/mus.27369. Muscle Nerve. 2021;64:462&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34235762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID Basics.  [
Apr;
2024 
]. 2024. https://www.cdc.gov/covid/long-term-effects/index.html https://www.cdc.gov/covid/long-term-effects/index.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ERS/ATS technical standard on interpretive strategies for routine lung function tests. Stanojevic S, Kaminsky DA, Miller MR, et al.  https://erj.ersjournals.com/content/60/1/2101499 Eur Respir J. 2022;60:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34949706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myasthenia gravis associated with anti-MuSK antibodies developed after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Assini A, Gandoglia I, Damato V, Rikani K, Evoli A, Del Sette M. https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/ene.14721. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28:3537&#x2013;3539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33421278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of thymomatous myasthenia gravis - case report of a rare COVID19 infection sequelae. Bhandarwar A, Jadhav S, Tandur A, Dhimole N, Wagh A, Bhondve S. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2210261221002728?via%3Dihub Int J Surg Case Rep. 2021;81:71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7954768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33744800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Transient acetylcholine receptor-related myasthenia gravis, post multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) temporally associated with COVID-19 infection. Essajee F, Lishman J, Solomons R, Abraham DR, Goussard P, Van Toorn R. https://casereports.bmj.com/content/14/8/e244102 BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8359482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34380685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postinfectious onset of myasthenia gravis in a COVID-19 patient. Huber M, Rogozinski S, Puppe W, Framme C, H&#xf6;glinger G, Hufendiek K, Wegner F. https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/neurology/articles/10.3389/fneur.2020.576153/full. Front Neurol. 2020;11:53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33123081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>New onset generalized myasthenia gravis evolving following SARS-CoV-2 infection. J&#xf5;gi K, Sabre L, Rosental M, Leheste AR, Vilisaar J. COVID. 2022;2:464&#x2013;471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myasthenia gravis associated with novel coronavirus 2019 infection: a report of three cases. Karimi N, Okhovat AA, Ziaadini B, Haghi Ashtiani B, Nafissi S, Fatehi F. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0303846721003632?via%3Dihub Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2021;208:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8299214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34329810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MuSK antibody-associated myasthenia gravis With SARS-CoV-2 infection: a case report. Muhammed L, Baheerathan A, Cao M, Leite MI, Viegas S. https://www.acpjournals.org/doi/10.7326/L20-1298. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174:872&#x2013;873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temporal association between SARS-CoV-2 and new-onset myasthenia gravis: is it causal or coincidental? Muralidhar Reddy Y, B SK, Osman S, Murthy JM. https://casereports.bmj.com/content/14/7/e244146 BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14:46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8296802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34290032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 infection associated with diplopia and anti-acetylcholine receptor antibodies. P&#xe9;rez &#xc1;lvarez &#xc1;I, Su&#xe1;rez Cuervo C, Fern&#xe1;ndez Men&#xe9;ndez S. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2173580820300584?via%3Dihub. Neurolog&#xed;a. 2020;35:264&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7165292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32364121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myasthenia gravis associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Restivo DA, Centonze D, Alesina A, Marchese-Ragona R. https://www.acpjournals.org/doi/10.7326/L20-0845. Ann Intern Med. 2020;173:1027&#x2013;1028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32776781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>New-onset myasthenia gravis after novel coronavirus 2019 infection. Taheri A, Davoodi L, Soleymani E, Ahmadi N. https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/rcr2.978 Respirol Case Rep. 2022;10:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9125167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35620352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A brief review of influenza virus infection. Javanian M, Barary M, Ghebrehewet S, Koppolu V, Vasigala V, Ebrahimpour S. https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jmv.26990. J Med Virol. 2021;93:4638&#x2013;4646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33792930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myasthenia gravis and infectious disease. Gilhus NE, Romi F, Hong Y, Skeie GO. https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00415-018-8751-9. J Neurol. 2018;265:1251&#x2013;1258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29372387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lack of evidence for Epstein-Barr virus infection in myasthenia gravis thymus. Meyer M, H&#xf6;ls AK, Liersch B, et al.  https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/ana.22522. Ann Neurol. 2011;70:515&#x2013;518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21905083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myasthenia gravis exacerbation and myasthenic crisis associated with COVID-19: case series and literature review. Rodrigues CL, de Freitas HC, Lima PR, de Oliveira Junior PH, Fernandes JM, D'Almeida JA, N&#xf3;brega PR. https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10072-021-05823-w. Neurol Sci. 2022;43:2271&#x2013;2276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8763445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35039987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein-Barr virus persistence and reactivation in myasthenia gravis thymus. Cavalcante P, Serafini B, Rosicarelli B, et al.  https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/ana.21902. Ann Neurol. 2010;67:726&#x2013;738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20517934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 vaccination and late-onset myasthenia gravis: A new case report and review of the literature. Virgilio E, Tondo G, Montabone C, Comi C. https://www.mdpi.com/1660-4601/20/1/467. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;20:67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9819717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36612789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of intravenous immunoglobulin treatment in selected neurological diseases&#x2014;one centre&#x2019;s experience based on the therapy of 141 patients. Lasek-Bal A, Wagner-Kusz A, Rogo&#x17c; B, Cisowska-Babraj M, Gajewska G. https://www.mdpi.com/2077-0383/12/18/5983 J Clin Med. 2023;12:83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10531894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37762922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>