<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35325624</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-8595</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The lancet. Diabetes &amp; endocrinology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Risks and burdens of incident diabetes in long COVID: a cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>311</StartPage><EndPage>321</EndPage><MedlinePgn>311-321</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00044-4</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-8587(22)00044-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">There is growing evidence suggesting that beyond the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection, people with COVID-19 could experience a wide range of post-acute sequelae, including diabetes. However, the risks and burdens of diabetes in the post-acute phase of the disease have not yet been comprehensively characterised. To address this knowledge gap, we aimed to examine the post-acute risk and burden of incident diabetes in people who survived the first 30 days of SARS-CoV-2 infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this cohort study, we used the national databases of the US Department of Veterans Affairs to build a cohort of 181&#x2009;280 participants who had a positive COVID-19 test between March 1, 2020, and Sept 30, 2021, and survived the first 30 days of COVID-19; a contemporary control (n=4&#x2009;118&#x2009;441) that enrolled participants between March 1, 2020, and Sept 30, 2021; and a historical control (n=4&#x2009;286&#x2009;911) that enrolled participants between March 1, 2018, and Sept 30, 2019. Both control groups had no evidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Participants in all three comparison groups were free of diabetes before cohort entry and were followed up for a median of 352 days (IQR 245-406). We used inverse probability weighted survival analyses, including predefined and algorithmically selected high dimensional variables, to estimate post-acute COVID-19 risks of incident diabetes, antihyperglycaemic use, and a composite of the two outcomes. We reported two measures of risk: hazard ratio (HR) and burden per 1000 people at 12 months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS">In the post-acute phase of the disease, compared with the contemporary control group, people with COVID-19 exhibited an increased risk (HR 1&#xb7;40, 95% CI 1&#xb7;36-1&#xb7;44) and excess burden (13&#xb7;46, 95% CI 12&#xb7;11-14&#xb7;84, per 1000 people at 12 months) of incident diabetes; and an increased risk (1&#xb7;85, 1&#xb7;78-1&#xb7;92) and excess burden (12&#xb7;35, 11&#xb7;36-13&#xb7;38) of incident antihyperglycaemic use. Additionally, analyses to estimate the risk of a composite endpoint of incident diabetes or antihyperglycaemic use yielded a HR of 1&#xb7;46 (95% CI 1&#xb7;43-1&#xb7;50) and an excess burden of 18&#xb7;03 (95% CI 16&#xb7;59-19&#xb7;51) per 1000 people at 12 months. Risks and burdens of post-acute outcomes increased in a graded fashion according to the severity of the acute phase of COVID-19 (whether patients were non-hospitalised, hospitalised, or admitted to intensive care). All the results were consistent in analyses using the historical control as the reference category.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION">In the post-acute phase, we report increased risks and 12-month burdens of incident diabetes and antihyperglycaemic use in people with COVID-19 compared with a contemporary control group of people who were enrolled during the same period and had not contracted SARS-CoV-2, and a historical control group from a pre-pandemic era. Post-acute COVID-19 care should involve identification and management of diabetes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING">US Department of Veterans Affairs and the American Society of Nephrology.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Epidemiology Center, Research and Development Service, VA Saint Louis Health Care System, Saint Louis, MO, USA; Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, College for Public Health and Social Justice, Saint Louis University, Saint Louis, MO, USA; Veterans Research and Education Foundation of Saint Louis, Saint Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Aly</LastName><ForeName>Ziyad</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Epidemiology Center, Research and Development Service, VA Saint Louis Health Care System, Saint Louis, MO, USA; Nephrology Section, Medicine Service, VA Saint Louis Health Care System, Saint Louis, MO, USA; Veterans Research and Education Foundation of Saint Louis, Saint Louis, MO, USA; Department of Medicine, Washington University School of Medicine, Saint Louis, MO, USA; Institute for Public Health, Washington University in Saint Louis, Saint Louis, MO, USA. Electronic address: ziyad.alaly@va.gov.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101618821</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-8587</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007004">Hypoglycemic Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2022 May;10(5):298-299. doi: 10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00078-X</RefSource><PMID Version="1">35325625</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>MMW Fortschr Med. 2022 Apr;164(8):16-17. doi: 10.1007/s15006-022-1105-7</RefSource><PMID Version="1">35449257</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2022 Sep 28;107(10):e4248-e4249. doi: 10.1210/clinem/dgac384</RefSource><PMID Version="1">35749295</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Ann Intern Med. 2022 Aug;175(8):JC93. doi: 10.7326/J22-0052</RefSource><PMID Version="1">35914265</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>MMW Fortschr Med. 2022 Aug;164(14):28-29. doi: 10.1007/s15006-022-1301-5</RefSource><PMID Version="1">35941441</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003920" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007004" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypoglycemic Agents</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests YX and ZA-A declare support from the US Department of Veterans Affairs for the submitted work. YX declares support for the American Society of Nephrology for the submitted work. ZA-A reports receiving consultation fees from Gilead Sciences and receipt of funding (unrelated to this work) from Tonix Pharmaceuticals. ZA-A is a Member Board of Directors for Veterans Research and Education Foundation of Saint Louis, associate editor for the Journal of the American Society of Nephrology, and is a member of multiple editorial boards.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35325624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8937253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00044-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-8587(22)00044-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594:259&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montefusco L, Ben Nasr M, D'Addio F, et al. Acute and long-term disruption of glycometabolic control after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Metab. 2021;3:774&#x2013;785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9931026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34035524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Maddukuri G, Al-Aly Z. Comparative evaluation of clinical manifestations and risk of death in patients admitted to hospital with COVID-19 and seasonal influenza: cohort study. BMJ. 2020;371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7735416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33323357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accili D. Can COVID-19 cause diabetes? Nat Metab. 2021;3:123&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8892570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33432203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathish T, Kapoor N, Cao Y, Tapp RJ, Zimmet P. Proportion of newly diagnosed diabetes in COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2021;23:870&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33245182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubino F, Amiel SA, Zimmet P, et al. New-onset diabetes in COVID-19. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:789&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7304415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Khunti K, Nafilyan V, et al. Post-COVID syndrome in individuals admitted to hospital with COVID-19: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;372:n693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8010267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steenblock C, Schwarz PEH, Ludwig B, et al. COVID-19 and metabolic disease: mechanisms and clinical management. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2021;9:786&#x2013;798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8489878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34619105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunti K, Del Prato S, Mathieu C, Kahn SE, Gabbay RA, Buse JB. COVID-19, hyperglycemia, and new-onset diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2021;44:2645&#x2013;2655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8669536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34625431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Xian H, Lian M, Al-Aly Z. Geographic variation and US County characteristics associated with rapid kidney function decline. Kidney Int Rep. 2016;2:5&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5678675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29142937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Li T, Xian H, Yan Y, Al-Aly Z. Higher blood urea nitrogen is associated with increased risk of incident diabetes mellitus. Kidney Int. 2018;93:741&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29241622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Yan Y, Al-Aly Z. Burden of cause-specific mortality associated with PM2.5 air pollution in the United States. JAMA Netw Open. 2019;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6902821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31747037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Yan Y, Xian H, Li T, Al-Aly Z. Estimates of all cause mortality and cause specific mortality associated with proton pump inhibitors among US veterans: cohort study. BMJ. 2019;365</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6538974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31147311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Xian H, Li T, Al-Aly Z. Association between monocyte count and risk of incident CKD and progression to ESRD. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2017;12:603&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5383390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28348030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Gibson A, et al. Comparative effectiveness of the sodium-glucose co-transporter-2 inhibitor empagliflozin vs. other antihyperglycemics on risk of major adverse kidney events. Diabetes Care. 2020;43:2785&#x2013;2795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7576413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32912850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Gibson AK, McGill JB, Maddukuri G, Al-Aly Z. Comparative effectiveness of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors vs sulfonylureas in patients with type 2 diabetes. JAMA Intern Med. 2021;181:1043&#x2013;1053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8240007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34180939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Cai M, Xie Y, Gibson AK, Maddukuri G, Al-Aly Z. Acute kidney injury in a national cohort of hospitalized US veterans with COVID-19. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020;16:14&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7792643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33199414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Gibson AK, et al. Comparative effectiveness of SGLT2 Inhibitors, GLP-1 receptor agonists, DPP-4 inhibitors, and sulfonylureas on risk of kidney outcomes: emulation of a target trial using health care databases. Diabetes Care. 2020;43:2859&#x2013;2869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32938746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Gibson AK, McGill JB, Maddukuri G, Al-Aly Z. Clinical implications of estimated glomerular filtration rate dip following sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitor initiation on cardiovascular and kidney outcomes. J Am Heart Assoc. 2021;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8483543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34013739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Veterans Affairs  COVID-19: shared data resource. 2020. https://vhacdwdwhweb100.vha.med.va.gov/phenotype/index.php/COVID-19:Shared_Data_Resource#Acknowledgements_COVID-19_Shared_Data_Resource</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kind AJH, Buckingham WR. Making neighborhood-disadvantage metrics accessible&#x2014;the Neighborhood Atlas. N Engl J Med. 2018;378:2456&#x2013;2458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6051533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29949490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Burdens of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 by severity of acute infection, demographics and health status. Nat Commun. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8589966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34772922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Xu E, Al-Aly Z. Kidney outcomes in long COVID. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;32:2851&#x2013;2862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8806085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34470828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022 doi: 10.1038/s41591-022-01689-3. published online Feb 7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01689-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35132265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Al-Aly Z. Risks of mental health outcomes in people with COVID-19: cohort study. BMJ. 2022;377</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8847881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35172971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneeweiss S, Rassen JA, Glynn RJ, Avorn J, Mogun H, Brookhart MA. High-dimensional propensity score adjustment in studies of treatment effects using health care claims data. Epidemiology. 2009;20:512&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3077219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19487948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Y, Wang Y, Di Q, et al. Short term exposure to fine particulate matter and hospital admission risks and costs in the Medicare population: time stratified, case crossover study. BMJ. 2019;367</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6880251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31776122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubert CE, Schnipper JL, Roumet M, et al. Best definitions of multimorbidity to identify patients with high health care resource utilization. Mayo Clin Proc Innov Qual Outcomes. 2020;4:40&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7011007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32055770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality  Clinical Classifications Software Refined (CCSR) https://www.hcup-us.ahrq.gov/toolssoftware/ccsr/ccs_refined.jsp</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olvey EL, Clauschee S, Malone DC. Comparison of critical drug-drug interaction listings: the Department of Veterans Affairs medical system and standard reference compendia. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2010;87:48&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19890252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene M, Steinman MA, McNicholl IR, Valcour V. Polypharmacy, drug-drug interactions, and potentially inappropriate medications in older adults with human immunodeficiency virus infection. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2014;62:447&#x2013;453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4043391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24576251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin PC. An introduction to propensity score methods for reducing the effects of confounding in observational studies. Multivariate Behav Res. 2011;46:399&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3144483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21818162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas LE, Li F, Pencina MJ. Overlap weighting: a propensity score method that mimics attributes of a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2020;323:2417&#x2013;2418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32369102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Thomas LE, Li F. Addressing extreme propensity scores via the overlap weights. Am J Epidemiol. 2019;188:250&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30189042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Buuren S. Multiple imputation of discrete and continuous data by fully conditional specification. Stat Methods Med Res. 2007;16:219&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17621469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipsitch M, Tchetgen Tchetgen E, Cohen T. Negative controls: a tool for detecting confounding and bias in observational studies. Epidemiology. 2010;21:383&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3053408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20335814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi X, Miao W, Tchetgen ET. A selective review of negative control methods in epidemiology. Curr Epidemiol Rep. 2020;7:190&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8118596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33996381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO  WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard. https://covid19.who.int/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett CE, K. A., Alvarez P, et al. Risk for newly diagnosed diabetes &gt;30 days after SARS-CoV-2 infection among persons aged &lt;18 years&#x2014;United States, March 1, 2020&#x2013;June 28, 2021. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71:59&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8757617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35025851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKeigue PM, et al. Relation of incident type 1 diabetes to recent COVID-19 infection: cohort study using e-health record linkage in Scotland. medRxiv. 2022 doi: 10.1101/2022.02.11.22270785. published online Feb 11. (preprint).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2022.02.11.22270785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35880797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathish T, Kapoor N, Cao Y, Tapp RJ, Zimmet P. Proportion of newly diagnosed diabetes in COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2021;23:870&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33245182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Khunti K, Nafilyan V, et al. Post-COVID syndrome in individuals admitted to hospital with COVID-19: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;372:n693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8010267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collaborative O, et al. Rates of serious clinical outcomes in survivors of hospitalisation with COVID-19: a descriptive cohort study within the OpenSAFELY platform. medRxiv. 2021 doi: 10.1101/2021.01.22.21250304. published online Jan 25. (preprint).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.01.22.21250304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10285340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37362009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziegler CGK, Allon SJ, Nyquist SK, et al. SARS-CoV-2 receptor ACE2 is an interferon &#x2013; stimulated gene in human airway epithelial cells and is detected in specific cell subsets across tissues. Cell. 2020;181:1016&#x2013;1035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7252096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32413319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller JA, Gro&#xdf; R, Conzelmann C, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infects and replicates in cells of the human endocrine and exocrine pancreas. Nat Metab. 2021;3:149&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33536639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Han Y, Nilsson-Payant BE, et al. A human pluripotent stem cell-based platform to study SARS-CoV-2 tropism and model virus infection in human cells and organoids. Cell Stem Cell. 2020;27:125&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7303620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32579880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CT, Lidsky PV, Xiao Y, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infects human pancreatic &#x3b2; cells and elicits &#x3b2; cell impairment. Cell Metab. 2021;33:1565&#x2013;1576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8130512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34081912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang X, Uhl S, Zhang T, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection induces beta cell transdifferentiation. Cell Metab. 2021;33:1577&#x2013;1591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8133495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34081913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Heide V, Jangra S, Cohen P, et al. Limited extent and consequences of pancreatic SARS-CoV-2 infection. Cell Rep. 2022;38</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8858708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35247306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Gibson AK, et al. Ambient fine particulate matter air pollution and the risk of hospitalization among COVID-19 positive individuals: cohort study. Environ Int. 2021;154</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8040542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33964723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Yan Y, Cai M, Al-Aly Z. County-level contextual characteristics and disparities in life expectancy. Mayo Clin Proc. 2021;96:92&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai M, Bowe B, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Temporal trends of COVID-19 mortality and hospitalisation rates: an observational cohort study from the US Department of Veterans Affairs. BMJ Open. 2021;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8370839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34400452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>