<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35873350</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-3546</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Brain, behavior, &amp; immunity - health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Brain Behav Immun Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neuropsychiatric sequelae of long COVID-19: Pilot results from the COVID-19 neurological and molecular prospective cohort study in Georgia, USA.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100491</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100491</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100491</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bbih.2022.100491</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">As the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic continues, there has been a growing interest in the chronic sequelae of COVID-19. Neuropsychiatric symptoms are observed in the acute phase of infection, but there is a need for accurate characterization of how these symptoms evolve over time. Additionally, African American populations have been disproportionately affected by the COVID-19 pandemic. The COVID-19 Neurological and Molecular Prospective Cohort Study in Georgia (CONGA) was established to investigate the severity and chronicity of these neurologic findings over the five-year period following infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The CONGA study aims to recruit COVID-19 positive adult patients in Georgia, United States from both the inpatient and outpatient setting, with 50% being African American. This paper reports our preliminary results from the baseline visits of the first 200 patients recruited who were on average 125 days since having a positive COVID-19 test. The demographics, self-reported symptoms, comorbidities, and quantitative measures of depression, anxiety, smell, taste, and cognition were analyzed. Cognitive measures were compared to demographically matched controls. Blood and mononuclear cells were drawn and stored for future analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Fatigue was the most reported symptom in the study cohort (68.5%). Thirty percent of participants demonstrated hyposmia and 30% of participants demonstrated hypogeusia. Self-reported neurologic dysfunction did not correlate with dysfunction on quantitative neurologic testing. Additionally, self-reported symptoms and comorbidities were associated with depression and anxiety. The study cohort performed worse on cognitive measures compared to demographically matched controls, and African American patients scored lower compared to non-Hispanic White patients on all quantitative cognitive testing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Our results support the growing evidence that there are chronic neuropsychiatric symptoms following COVID-19 infection. Our results suggest that self-reported neurologic symptoms do not appear to correlate with associated quantitative dysfunction, emphasizing the importance of quantitative measurements in the complete assessment of deficits. Self-reported symptoms are associated with depression and anxiety. COVID-19 infection appears to be associated with worse performance on cognitive measures, though the disparity in score between African American patients and non-Hispanic White patients is likely largely due to psychosocial, physical health, and socioeconomic factors.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Alex K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical College of Georgia at Augusta University, 1120 15th St, Augusta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoling</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Georgia Prevention Institute, Medical College of Georgia at Augusta University, 1457 Walton Way, Augusta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCluskey</LastName><ForeName>Lynnette P</ForeName><Initials>LP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Regenerative Medicine, Medical College of Georgia at Augusta University, 1120 15th St, Augusta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morgan</LastName><ForeName>John C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Movement and Memory Disorder Programs, Department of Neurology, Medical College of Georgia at Augusta University, 1120 15th St, Augusta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Switzer</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Medical College of Georgia at Augusta University, 1120 15th St, Augusta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehta</LastName><ForeName>Rohini</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Medical College of Georgia at Augusta University, 997 St. Sebastian Way, Augusta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tingen</LastName><ForeName>Martha</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Georgia Prevention Institute, Medical College of Georgia at Augusta University, 1457 Walton Way, Augusta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Shaoyong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Georgia Prevention Institute, Medical College of Georgia at Augusta University, 1457 Walton Way, Augusta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harris</LastName><ForeName>Ryan Alan</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Georgia Prevention Institute, Medical College of Georgia at Augusta University, 1457 Walton Way, Augusta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hess</LastName><ForeName>David C</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Medical College of Georgia at Augusta University, 1120 15th St, Augusta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rutkowski</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth K</ForeName><Initials>EK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Medical College of Georgia at Augusta University, 1120 15th St, Augusta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS112511</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Brain Behav Immun Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101759062</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-3546</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hyposmia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>D.C.H. receives funding from the National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NIH/NINDS R01NS112511-01A1S1 (Hess, D)). The remaining authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could appear to influence the work in this paper. David Hess reports financial support was provided by 10.13039/100000065National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke. David Hess reports financial support was provided by TR Reddy Family Fund.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35873350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9290328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbih.2022.100491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-3546(22)00081-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Almeria M., Cejudo J.C., Sotoca J., Deus J., Krupinski J. Cognitive profile following COVID-19 infection: clinical predictors leading to neuropsychological impairment. Brain, behavior, &amp; immunity-health. 2020;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7581383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33111132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almutairi M.M., Sivandzade F., Albekairi T.H., Alqahtani F., Cucullo L. Neuroinflammation and its impact on the pathogenesis of COVID-19. Front. Med. 2021;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8652056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34901061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arias-de la Torre J., Vilagut G., Serrano-Blanco A., Martin V., Molina A.J., Valderas J.M., Alonso J. Accuracy of self-reported items for the screening of depression in the general population. Int. J. Environ. Res. Publ. Health. 2020;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7662518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33138196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya A.A., Simani L. Central nervous system manifestations of COVID-19: a systematic review. J. Neurol. Sci. 2020;413</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7151535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32299017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F., Ling S., Lui L.M.W., Lee Y., Gill H., Teopiz K.M., Rodrigues N.B., Subramaniapillai M., Di Vincenzo J.D., Cao B., Lin K., Mansur R.B., Ho R.C., Rosenblat J.D., Miskowiak K.W., Vinberg M., Maletic V., McIntyre R.S. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav. Immun. 2022;101:93&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F., Nogo D., Carvalho I.P., Lee Y., Nasri F., Xiong J., Lui L.M.W., Subramaniapillai M., Gill H., Liu R.N., Joseph P., Teopiz K.M., Cao B., Mansur R.B., Lin K., Rosenblat J.D., Ho R.C., McIntyre R.S. Association between mood disorders and risk of COVID-19 infection, hospitalization, and death: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatr. 2021;78:1079&#x2013;1091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8319830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34319365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin A.L., Negash S., Xie S., Arnold S.E., Hamilton R. Quality, and not just quantity, of education accounts for differences in psychometric performance between african americans and white non-hispanics with Alzheimer's disease. J. Int. Neuropsychol. Soc. 2012;18:277&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3685288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22300593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou S.H., Beghi E., Helbok R., Moro E., Sampson J., Altamirano V., Mainali S., Bassetti C., Suarez J.I., McNett M., Consortium G.C.-N., Consortium E. Global incidence of neurological manifestations among patients hospitalized with COVID-19-A report for the GCS-NeuroCOVID consortium and the ENERGY consortium. JAMA Netw. Open. 2021;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8114143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33974053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coogan P., Schon K., Li S., Cozier Y., Bethea T., Rosenberg L. Experiences of racism and subjective cognitive function in African American women. Alzheimer's &amp; Dementia: Diagnosis. Assessment &amp; Disease Monitoring. 2020;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7409101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32782921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Erausquin G.A., Snyder H., Carrillo M., Hosseini A.A., Brugha T.S., Seshadri S., Consortium C.S.-C.-. The chronic neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19: the need for a prospective study of viral impact on brain functioning. Alzheimers Dement. 2021;17:1056&#x2013;1065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10431934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33399270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doty R. 2020. Self-administered Waterless Empirical Taste Test (SA-WETT) Administration Manual.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doty R.L. Sensonics; Incorporated: 1995. The Smell Identification Test: Administration Manual.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doty R.L., Frye R.E., Agrawal U. Internal consistency reliability of the fractionated and whole university of Pennsylvania smell identification test. Percept. Psychophys. 1989;45:381&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2726398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doty R.L., Wylie C., Potter M. Validation of the waterless empirical taste test (WETT((R))) Behav. Res. Methods. 2021;53:864&#x2013;873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32885386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G., Lee S., Alfaro-Almagro F., Arthofer C., Wang C., McCarthy P., Lange F., Andersson J.L.R., Griffanti L., Duff E., Jbabdi S., Taschler B., Keating P., Winkler A.M., Collins R., Matthews P.M., Allen N., Miller K.L., Nichols T.E., Smith S.M. SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature. 2022;604:697&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9046077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge D., Dong Y., Wang X., Treiber F.A., Snieder H. The Georgia Cardiovascular Twin Study: influence of genetic predisposition and chronic stress on risk for cardiovascular disease and type 2 diabetes. Twin Res. Hum. Genet. 2006;9:965&#x2013;970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17254438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerkin R.C., Ohla K., Veldhuizen M.G., Joseph P.V., Kelly C.E., Bakke A.J., Steele K.E., Farruggia M.C., Pellegrino R., Pepino M.Y., Bouysset C., Soler G.M., Pereda-Loth V., Dibattista M., Cooper K.W., Croijmans I., Di Pizio A., Ozdener M.H., Fjaeldstad A.W., Lin C., Sandell M.A., Singh P.B., Brindha V.E., Olsson S.B., Saraiva L.R., Ahuja G., Alwashahi M.K., Bhutani S., D'Errico A., Fornazieri M.A., Golebiowski J., Hwang L.D., Ozturk L., Roura E., Spinelli S., Whitcroft K.L., Faraji F., Fischmeister F.P.S., Heinbockel T., Hsieh J.W., Huart C., Konstantinidis I., Menini A., Morini G., Olofsson J.K., Philpott C.M., Pierron D., Shields V.D.C., Voznessenskaya V.V., Albayay J., Altundag A., Bensafi M., Bock M.A., Calcinoni O., Fredborg W., Laudamiel C., Lim J., Lundstrom J.N., Macchi A., Meyer P., Moein S.T., Santamaria E., Sengupta D., Dominguez P.P., Yanik H., Boesveldt S., de Groot J.H.B., Dinnella C., Freiherr J., Laktionova T., Marino S., Monteleone E., Nunez-Parra A., Abdulrahman O., Ritchie M., Thomas-Danguin T., Walsh-Messinger J., Al Abri R., Alizadeh R., Bignon E., Cantone E., Cecchini M.P., Chen J., Guardia M.D., Hoover K.C., Karni N., Navarro M., Nolden A.A., Mazal P.P., Rowan N.R., Sarabi-Jamab A., Archer N.S., Chen B., Di Valerio E.A., Feeney E.L., Frasnelli J., Hannum M., Hopkins C., Klein H., Mignot C., Mucignat C., Ning Y., Ozturk E.E., Peng M., Saatci O., Sell E.A., Yan C.H., Alfaro R., Cecchetto C., Coureaud G., Herriman R.D., Justice J.M., Kaushik P.K., Koyama S., Overdevest J.B., Pirastu N., Ramirez V.A., Roberts S.C., Smith B.C., Cao H., Wang H., Balungwe P., Baguma M., Hummel T., Hayes J.E., Reed D.R., Niv M.Y., Munger S.D., Parma V. medRxiv; 2020. The Best COVID-19 Predictor Is Recent Smell Loss: a Cross-Sectional Study.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham E.L., Clark J.R., Orban Z.S., Lim P.H., Szymanski A.L., Taylor C., DiBiase R.M., Jia D.T., Balabanov R., Ho S.U., Batra A., Liotta E.M., Koralnik I.J. Persistent neurologic symptoms and cognitive dysfunction in non-hospitalized Covid-19 "long haulers. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2021;8:1073&#x2013;1085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33755344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampshire A., Trender W., Chamberlain S., Jolly A., Grant J., Patrick F., Mehta M.A. Cognitive deficits in people who have recovered from COVID-19. EClinicalMedicine. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8298139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34316551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao F., Tam W., Hu X., Tan W., Jiang L., Jiang X., Zhang L., Zhao X., Zou Y., Hu Y., Luo X., McIntyre R.S., Quek T., Tran B.X., Zhang Z., Pham H.Q., Ho C.S.H., Ho R.C.M. A quantitative and qualitative study on the neuropsychiatric sequelae of acutely ill COVID-19 inpatients in isolation facilities. Transl. Psychiatry. 2020;10:355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7570419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33077738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho C.S., Chee C.Y., Ho R.C. Mental health strategies to combat the psychological impact of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) beyond paranoia and panic. Ann. Acad. Med. Singapore. 2020;49:155&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32200399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho R.C., Sharma V.K., Tan B.Y.Q., Ng A.Y.Y., Lui Y.S., Husain S.F., Ho C.S., Tran B.X., Pham Q.H., McIntyre R.S., Chan A.C.Y. Comparison of brain activation patterns during olfactory stimuli between recovered COVID-19 patients and healthy controls: a functional near-infrared spectroscopy (fNIRS) study. Brain Sci. 2021;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8391911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34439587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y.H., Jiang D., Huang J.T. SARS-CoV-2 detected in cerebrospinal fluid by PCR in a case of COVID-19 encephalitis. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;87:149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7202824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hummel T., Landis B.N., H&#xfc;ttenbrink K.-B. Smell and taste disorders. GMS Curr. Top. Otorhinolaryngol., Head Neck Surg. 2011;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3341581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22558054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeste D.V., Palmer B.W., Appelbaum P.S., Golshan S., Glorioso D., Dunn L.B., Kim K., Meeks T., Kraemer H.C. A new brief instrument for assessing decisional capacity for clinical research. Arch. Gen. Psychiatr. 2007;64:966&#x2013;974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17679641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K., Spitzer R.L., Williams J.B. The PHQ-9: validity of a brief depression severity measure. J. Gen. Intern. Med. 2001;16:606&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1495268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11556941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kullar R., Marcelin J.R., Swartz T.H., Piggott D.A., Macias Gil R., Mathew T.A., Tan T. Racial disparity of coronavirus disease 2019 in african American communities. J. Infect. Dis. 2020;222:890&#x2013;893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7337812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32599614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G., Zong G., Doty R.L., Sun Q. Prevalence and risk factors of taste and smell impairment in a nationwide representative sample of the US population: a cross-sectional study. BMJ Open. 2016;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5129069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28157672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loomba R.S., Villarreal E.G., Farias J.S., Aggarwal G., Aggarwal S., Flores S. Serum biomarkers for prediction of mortality in patients with COVID-19. Ann. Clin. Biochem. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33874737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey K., Ayers C.K., Kondo K.K., Saha S., Advani S.M., Young S., Spencer H., Rusek M., Anderson J., Veazie S., Smith M., Kansagara D. Racial and ethnic disparities in COVID-19-related infections, hospitalizations, and deaths : a systematic review. Ann. Intern. Med. 2021;174:362&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7772883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33253040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manunta M.D.I., Lamorte G., Ferrari F., Trombetta E., Tirone M., Bianco C., Cattaneo A., Santoro L., Baselli G., Brasca M., Ostadreza M., Erba E., Gori A., Bandera A., Porretti L., Valenti L.V.C., Prati D. Impact of SARS-CoV-2 infection on the recovery of peripheral blood mononuclear cells by density gradient. Sci. Rep. 2021;11:4904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7921094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33649400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke J., Lutgehetmann M., Hagel C., Sperhake J.P., Schroder A.S., Edler C., Mushumba H., Fitzek A., Allweiss L., Dandri M., Dottermusch M., Heinemann A., Pfefferle S., Schwabenland M., Sumner Magruder D., Bonn S., Prinz M., Gerloff C., Puschel K., Krasemann S., Aepfelbacher M., Glatzel M. Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19:919&#x2013;929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7535629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukaka M. Statistics corner: a guide to appropriate use of correlation in medical research. Malawi Med. J. 2012;24:69&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3576830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23638278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A., Sehgal K., Gupta A., Madhavan M.V., McGroder C., Stevens J.S., Cook J.R., Nordvig A.S., Shalev D., Sehrawat T.S., Ahluwalia N., Bikdeli B., Dietz D., Der-Nigoghossian C., Liyanage-Don N., Rosner G.F., Bernstein E.J., Mohan S., Beckley A.A., Seres D.S., Choueiri T.K., Uriel N., Ausiello J.C., Accili D., Freedberg D.E., Baldwin M., Schwartz A., Brodie D., Garcia C.K., Elkind M.S.V., Connors J.M., Bilezikian J.P., Landry D.W., Wan E.Y. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine Z.S., Phillips N.A., Bedirian V., Charbonneau S., Whitehead V., Collin I., Cummings J.L., Chertkow H. The Montreal Cognitive Assessment, MoCA: a brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. J. Am. Geriatr. Soc. 2005;53:695&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niesen M., Trotta N., Noel A., Coolen T., Fayad G., Leurkin-Sterk G., Delpierre I., Henrard S., Sadeghi N., Goffard J.C., Goldman S., De Tiege X. Structural and metabolic brain abnormalities in COVID-19 patients with sudden loss of smell. Eur. J. Nucl. Med. Mol. Imag. 2021;48:1890&#x2013;1901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7781559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33398411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization W.H. 2021. COVID-19 Weekly Epidemiological Update, 9 March 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavli A., Theodoridou M., Maltezou H.C. Post-COVID syndrome: incidence, clinical spectrum, and challenges for primary healthcare professionals. Arch. Med. Res. 2021;52:575&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8093949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33962805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennington A.F., Kompaniyets L., Summers A.D., Danielson M.L., Goodman A.B., Chevinsky J.R., Preston L.E., Schieber L.Z., Namulanda G., Courtney J. Oxford University Press US; 2021. Risk of Clinical Severity by Age and Race/ethnicity Among Adults Hospitalized for COVID-19&#x2014;United States, March&#x2013;September 2020. Open Forum Infectious Diseases; p. ofaa638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7798738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33553477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S., Williams M.A. Confronting our next national health disaster - long-haul covid. N. Engl. J. Med. 2021;385:577&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34192429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plummer F., Manea L., Trepel D., McMillan D. Screening for anxiety disorders with the GAD-7 and GAD-2: a systematic review and diagnostic metaanalysis. Gen. Hosp. Psychiatr. 2016;39:24&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26719105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quarmley M., Moberg P.J., Mechanic-Hamilton D., Kabadi S., Arnold S.E., Wolk D.A., Roalf D.R. Odor identification screening improves diagnostic classification in incipient Alzheimer's disease. J. Alzheim. Dis. 2017;55:1497&#x2013;1507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5350629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27886011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renaud-Charest O., Lui L.M.W., Eskander S., Ceban F., Ho R., Di Vincenzo J.D., Rosenblat J.D., Lee Y., Subramaniapillai M., McIntyre R.S. Onset and frequency of depression in post-COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review. J. Psychiatr. Res. 2021;144:129&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34619491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renaud M., Thibault C., Le Normand F., McDonald E.G., Gallix B., Debry C., Venkatasamy A. Clinical outcomes for patients with anosmia 1 Year after COVID-19 diagnosis. JAMA Netw. Open. 2021;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8226421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34165581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossetti H.C., Lacritz L.H., Hynan L.S., Cullum C.M., Van Wright A., Weiner M.F. Montreal cognitive assessment performance among community-dwelling african Americans. Arch. Clin. Neuropsychol. 2017;32:238&#x2013;244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5860177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28365749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosso A.L., Flatt J.D., Carlson M.C., Lovasi G.S., Rosano C., Brown A.F., Matthews K.A., Gianaros P.J. Neighborhood socioeconomic status and cognitive function in late life. Am. J. Epidemiol. 2016;183:1088&#x2013;1097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4908209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27257114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy D., Ghosh R., Dubey S., Dubey M.J., Benito-Leon J., Kanti Ray B. Neurological and neuropsychiatric impacts of COVID-19 pandemic. Can. J. Neurol. Sci. 2021;48:9&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7533477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santomauro D.F., Herrera A.M.M., Shadid J., Zheng P., Ashbaugh C., Pigott D.M., Abbafati C., Adolph C., Amlag J.O., Aravkin A.Y. Global prevalence and burden of depressive and anxiety disorders in 204 countries and territories in 2020 due to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet. 2021;398:1700&#x2013;1712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34634250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrag A., Siddiqui U.F., Anastasiou Z., Weintraub D., Schott J.M. Clinical variables and biomarkers in prediction of cognitive impairment in patients with newly diagnosed Parkinson's disease: a cohort study. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16:66&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5377592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27866858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soh H.L., Ho R.C., Ho C.S., Tam W.W. Efficacy of digital cognitive behavioural therapy for insomnia: a meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Sleep Med. 2020;75:315&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32950013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su S., Wang X., Pollock J.S., Treiber F.A., Xu X., Snieder H., McCall W.V., Stefanek M., Harshfield G.A. Adverse childhood experiences and blood pressure trajectories from childhood to young adulthood: the Georgia stress and Heart study. Circulation. 2015;131:1674&#x2013;1681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4430378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25858196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xydakis M.S., Albers M.W., Holbrook E.H., Lyon D.M., Shih R.Y., Frasnelli J.A., Pagenstecher A., Kupke A., Enquist L.W., Perlman S. Post-viral effects of COVID-19 in the olfactory system and their implications. Lancet Neurol. 2021;20:753&#x2013;761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8324113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yancy C.W. COVID-19 and african Americans. JAMA. 2020;323:1891&#x2013;1892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32293639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Pinto J.M. The Epidemiology of olfactory disorders. Curr Otorhinolaryngol Rep. 2016;4:130&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6317880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30613439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#xfc;ce M., Filiztekin E., &#xd6;zkaya K.G. COVID-19 diagnosis &#x2014;a review of current methods. Biosens. Bioelectron. 2021;172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7584564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33126180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahodne L.B., Manly J.J., Smith J., Seeman T., Lachman M.E. Socioeconomic, health, and psychosocial mediators of racial disparities in cognition in early, middle, and late adulthood. Psychol. Aging. 2017;32:118&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5369602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28287782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M.W., Ho R.C. Moodle: the cost effective solution for internet cognitive behavioral therapy (I-CBT) interventions. Technol. Health Care. 2017;25:163&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27689560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z., Kang H., Li S., Zhao X. Understanding the neurotropic characteristics of SARS-CoV-2: from neurological manifestations of COVID-19 to potential neurotropic mechanisms. J. Neurol. 2020;267:2179&#x2013;2184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7249973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32458193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>