<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37163472</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A meta-ethnography investigating relational influences on mental health and cancer-related health care interventions for racially minoritised people in the UK.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0284878</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0284878</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0284878</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0284878</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Despite calls to increase the 'cultural competence' of health care providers, racially minoritised people continue to experience a range of problems when it comes to health care, including discrimination. While relevant qualitative meta-syntheses have suggested better ways forward for health care for racialised minorities, many have lacked conceptual depth, and none have specifically investigated the relational dimensions involved in care. We set out to investigate the social and cultural influences on health care interventions, focusing on psychological approaches and/or cancer care to inform the trial of a new psychological therapy for those living with or beyond cancer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">A meta-ethnography approach was used to examine the relevant qualitative studies, following Noblit and Hare, and guided by patient involvement throughout. Papers were analysed between September 2018 and February 2023, with some interruptions caused by the Covid pandemic. The following databases were searched: Ovid MEDLINE, EBSCO CINAHL, Ovid Embase, EBSCO PsycINFO, Proquest Sociology Collection (including Applied Social Sciences Index &amp; Abstracts (ASSIA), Sociological Abstracts and Sociology Database), EBSCO SocINDEX, Ovid AMED, and Web of Science. The systematic review protocol was registered with the International Prospective Register of Systematic Reviews (PROSPERO) (ID: CRD42018107695), and reporting follows the eMERGe Reporting Guidance for meta-ethnographies (France et al. 2019).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Twenty-nine journal papers were included in the final review. Themes (third-order constructs) developed in the paper include the centrality of the patient-practitioner relationship; how participants give meaning to their illness in connection to others; how families (rather than individuals) may make health decisions; how links with a higher power and spiritual/religious others can play a role in coping; and the ways in which a hierarchy of help-seeking develops, frequently with the first port of call being the resources of oneself. Participants in studies had a need to avoid being 'othered' in their care, valuing practitioners that connected with them, and who were able to recognise them as whole and complex (sometimes described in relational languages like 'love'). Complex family-based health decision-making and/or the importance of relations with non-human interactants (e.g. God, spiritual beings) were frequently uncovered, not to mention the profoundly emergent nature of stigma, whereby families could be relatively safe havens for containing and dealing with health challenges. A conceptual framework of 'animated via (frequently hidden) affective relationality' emerged in the final synthesis, bringing all themes together, and drawing attention to the emergent nature of the salient issues facing minoritised patients in health care interactions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Our analysis is important because it sheds light on the hitherto buried relational forces animating and producing the specific issues facing racially minoritised patients, which study participants thought were largely overlooked, but to which professionals can readily relate (given the universal nature of human relations). Thus, training around the affective relationality of consultations could be a fruitful avenue to explore to improve care of diverse patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2023 Ridge et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ridge</LastName><ForeName>Damien</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9245-5958</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Social Sciences, University of Westminster, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pilkington</LastName><ForeName>Karen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Care Professions, University of Portsmouth, Portsmouth, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donovan</LastName><ForeName>Sheila</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moschopoulou</LastName><ForeName>Elisavet</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gopal</LastName><ForeName>Dipesh</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhui</LastName><ForeName>Kamaldeep</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Nuffield Department of Primary Care Health Sciences, University of Oxford, Oxford, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wadham College, University of Oxford, Oxford, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>World Psychiatric Association Collaborating Centre, Oxford, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chalder</LastName><ForeName>Trudie</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychological Medicine, Kings College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Imran</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2069-7410</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korszun</LastName><ForeName>Ania</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>SURECAN Investigators</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RP-PG-0616-20002</GrantID><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008603" MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078202" MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic Reviews as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000884" MajorTopicYN="N">Anthropology, Cultural</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003695" MajorTopicYN="N">Delivery of Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006113" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United Kingdom</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>DR has received funding from Roche for a project &#x2018;Investigating how carers cope, access and use support services &#x2013; Lessons from Covid-19&#x2019;. He is also funded by the NIHR for (NIHR203106) "Hearing from the unheard: impact of long-COVID in minority ethnic groups in the UK (Hi-COVE)&#x201d;. DG has received honoraria for speaking at meetings: Plenary "Unravelling the threads of race, racism and medicine" at Association for Medical Education in Europe (AMEE), August 2021. He has a NIHR In-Practice Fellowship (NIHR301018), and (NIHR203106) "Hearing from the unheard: impact of long-COVID in minority ethnic groups in the UK (Hi-COVE)&#x201d;. No other competing interests exist. This does not alter our adherence to PLOS ONE policies on sharing data and materials."</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37163472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10171693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0284878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-22-27964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Milner A, Jumbe S. Using the right words to address racial disparities in COVID-19. The Lancet Public Health. 2020;5(8):e419. doi: 10.1016/S2468-2667(20)30162-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-2667(20)30162-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7373398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32707127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhui K, Dein S, Pope C. Clinical ethnography in severe mental illness: a clinical method to tackle social determinants and structural racism in personalised care. BJPsych Open. 2021;7(3):e78. doi: 10.1192/bjo.2021.38</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjo.2021.38</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8086386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33840400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamidele O, McGarvey H, Lagan BM, Ali N, Chinegwundoh Mbe F, Parahoo K, et al.. Life after prostate cancer: A systematic literature review and thematic synthesis of the post&#x2010;treatment experiences of Black African and Black Caribbean men. European Journal of Cancer Care. 2018;27(1):e12784. doi: 10.1111/ecc.12784</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ecc.12784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29034575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher JR. Black knowledges matter: How the suppression of non&#x2010;white understandings of dementia harms us all and how we can combat it. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness. 2021; 43(8):1818&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34002398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prajapati R, Liebling H. Accessing Mental Health Services: a Systematic Review and Meta-ethnography of the Experiences of South Asian Service Users in the UK. Journal of Racial and Ethnic Health Disparities. 2021:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8897382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33686621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moschopoulou E, Brewin D, Ridge D, Donovan S, Taylor SJ, Bourke L, et al.. Evaluating an interactive acceptance and commitment therapy (ACT) workshop delivered to trained therapists working with cancer patients in the United Kingdom: a mixed methods approach. BMC cancer. 2022;22(1):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9195438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35698089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roseneil S, Ketokivi K. Relational Persons and Relational Processes: Developing the Notion of Relationality for the Sociology of Personal Life. Sociology. 2015;50(1):143&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xe9;pelteau F. Relational sociology, pragmatism, transactions and social fields. International Review of Sociology. 2015;25(1):45&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buys R, Marotta V. Relational Theories of Encounters and the Relational Subject. Journal of Intercultural Studies. 2021;42(1):99&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tynan L. What is relationality? Indigenous knowledges, practices and responsibilities with kin. Cultural Geographies. 2021;28(4):597&#x2013;610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemmings C. Invoking affect: Cultural theory and the ontological turn. Cultural Studies. 2005;19(5):548&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishida A. Relating through differences: Disability, affective relationality, and the U.S. public healthcare assemblage. Subjectivity. 2017;10(1):89&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herring J. Health as Vulnerability; Interdependence and Relationality. The New Bioethics. 2016;22(1):18&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1080/20502877.2016.1151255</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/20502877.2016.1151255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28219282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkitt I. Relational agency: Relational sociology, agency and interaction. European Journal of Social Theory. 2015;19(3):322&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Togni G, Erikainen S, Chan S, Cunningham-Burley S. What makes AI &#x2018;intelligent&#x2019; and &#x2018;caring&#x2019;? Exploring affect and relationality across three sites of intelligence and care. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2021;277:113874. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2021.113874</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2021.113874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8135128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33901725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffman MJ. Cultural caring in nursing practice: A meta-synthesis of qualitative research. Journal of Cultural Diversity. 2004;11(3):100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15689144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maleku A, Aguirre RTP. Culturally Competent Health Care from the Immigrant Lens: A Qualitative Interpretive Meta-Synthesis (QIMS). Social Work in Public Health. 2014;29(6):561&#x2013;80. doi: 10.1080/19371918.2014.893417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19371918.2014.893417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25144698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Licqurish S, Phillipson L, Chiang P, Walker J, Walter F, Emery J. Cancer beliefs in ethnic minority populations: a review and meta&#x2010;synthesis of qualitative studies. European Journal of Cancer Care. 2017;26(1):e12556. doi: 10.1111/ecc.12556</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ecc.12556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27515153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivas C, Matheson L, Nayoan J, Glaser A, Gavin A, Wright P, et al.. Ethnicity and the prostate cancer experience: a qualitative metasynthesis. Psycho-Oncology. 2016;25(10):1147&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1002/pon.4222</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.4222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5096040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27416079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrett CR, Gask LL, Hays R, Cherrington A, Bundy C, Dickens C, et al.. Accessing primary health care: a meta-ethnography of the experiences of British South Asian patients with diabetes, coronary heart disease or a mental health problem. Chronic Illness. 2012;8(2):135&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1177/1742395312441631</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1742395312441631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22414446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb J, Bower P, Rogers A, Dowrick C, Gask L. Access to mental health in primary care: A qualitative meta-synthesis of evidence from the experience of people from &#x2018;hard to reach&#x2019; groups. Health. 2012;16(1):76&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1177/1363459311403945</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1363459311403945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21486918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keesing S, McNamara B, Rosenwax L. Cancer survivors&#x2019; experiences of using survivorship care plans: a systematic review of qualitative studies. Journal of Cancer Survivorship. 2015;9:260&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1007/s11764-014-0407-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-014-0407-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25343971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stergiou-Kita M, Grigorovich A, Tseung V, Milosevic E, Hebert D, Phan S, et al.. Qualitative meta-synthesis of survivors&#x2019; work experiences and the development of strategies to facilitate return to work. Journal of Cancer Survivorship. 2014;8:657&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1007/s11764-014-0377-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-014-0377-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24993807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midtgaard J, Hammer NM, Andersen C, Larsen A, Bruun D-M, Jarden M. Cancer survivors&#x2019; experience of exercise-based cancer rehabilitation&#x2013;a meta-synthesis of qualitative research. Acta Oncologica. 2015;54(5):609&#x2013;17. doi: 10.3109/0284186X.2014.995777</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/0284186X.2014.995777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25751760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon-Woods M, Cavers D, Agarwal S, Annandale E, Arthur A, Harvey J, et al.. Conducting a critical interpretive synthesis of the literature on access to healthcare by vulnerable groups. BMC Medical Research Methodology. 2006;6(1):35. doi: 10.1186/1471-2288-6-35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-6-35</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1559637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16872487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall GCN. Psychotherapy research with ethnic minorities: empirical, ethical, and conceptual issues. Journal of consulting and clinical psychology. 2001;69(3):502&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1037//0022-006x.69.3.502</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037//0022-006x.69.3.502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11495179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkan R, Avis M, Cox K, Wilson E, Patel S, Miller S, et al.. The reported views and experiences of cancer service users from minority ethnic groups: a critical review of the literature. European Journal of Cancer Care. 2007;16(2):109&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2354.2006.00726.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2354.2006.00726.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17371419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal N, Karlsen S, Sashidharan SP, Cohen R, Chew-Graham CA, Malpass A. Understanding ethnic inequalities in mental healthcare in the UK: A meta-ethnography. PLoS Medicine. 2022;19(12):e1004139. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1004139</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1004139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9746991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36512523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noblit GW, Hare RD. Meta-ethnography: synthesizing qualitative studies. Newbury Park, California: Sage Publications, Inc.; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhui K, Chalder T, Donovan S, Gopal D, Khan I, Korszun A, et al.. A meta-ethnography of cultural influences on cancer-related psychological interventions. PROSPERO. 2018; CRD42018107695: https://www.crd.york.ac.uk/prospero/display_record.php?RecordID=107695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>France EF, Cunningham M, Ring N, Uny I, Duncan EA, Jepson RG, et al.. Improving reporting of meta-ethnography: the eMERGe reporting guidance. BMC Medical Research Methodology. 2019;19:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6359764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30709371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>France EF, Wells M, Lang H, Williams B. Why, when and how to update a meta-ethnography qualitative synthesis. Systematic Reviews. 2016;5(1):44. doi: 10.1186/s13643-016-0218-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13643-016-0218-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4791806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26979748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanton V, Dale J. &#x2019;It don&#x2019;t make sense to worry too much&#x2019;: the experience of prostate cancer in African-Caribbean men in the UK. European Journal of Cancer Care. 2011;20 1:62&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2354.2009.01155.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2354.2009.01155.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20148937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patsiurko N, Campbell JL, Hall JA. Measuring cultural diversity: ethnic, linguistic and religious fractionalization in the OECD. Ethnic and Racial Studies. 2012;35(2):195&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tompkins C, Scanlon K, Scott E, Ream E, Harding S, Armes J. Survivorship care and support following treatment for breast cancer: a multi-ethnic comparative qualitative study of women&#x2019;s experiences. BMC health services research. 2016;16(1):401. doi: 10.1186/s12913-016-1625-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-016-1625-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4989374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27535665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loewenthal D, Mohamed A, Mukhopadhyay S, Ganesh K, Thomas R. Reducing the barriers to accessing psychological therapies for Bengali, Urdu, Tamil and Somali communities in the UK: some implications for training, policy and practice. British Journal of Guidance &amp; Counselling. 2012;40(1):43&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCutchan G, Wood F, Smits S, Edwards A, Brain K. Barriers to cancer symptom presentation among people from low socioeconomic groups: a qualitative study. BMC Public Health. 2016;16(1):1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1186/s12889-016-3733-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-016-3733-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5057256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27729048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selkirk M, Quayle E, Rothwell N. Influences on Polish migrants&#x2019; responses to distress and decisions about whether to seek psychological help. Counselling Psychology Review. 2012;27(3):40&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sisley EJ, Hutton JM, Louise Goodbody C, Brown JS. An interpretative phenomenological analysis of African Caribbean women&#x2019;s experiences and management of emotional distress. Health &amp; Social Care in the Community. 2011;19(4):392&#x2013;402. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2524.2010.00986.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2524.2010.00986.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21314849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilkington K, Ridge DT, Igwesi-Chidobe CN, Chew-Graham CA, Little P, Babatunde O, et al.. A relational analysis of an invisible illness: A meta-ethnography of people with chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME) and their support needs. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2020;265:113369. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113369</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33039734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>JBI critical appraisal checklist for qualitative research [Internet]. 2017 [cited 8th October 2021].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>France EF, Ring N, Noyes J, Maxwell M, Jepson R, Duncan E, et al.. Protocol-developing meta-ethnography reporting guidelines (eMERGe). BMC Medical Research Methodology. 2015;15(1):1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4660777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26606922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malpass A, Shaw A, Sharp D, Walter F, Feder G, Ridd M, et al.. &#x201c;Medication career&#x201d; or &#x201c;moral career&#x201d;? The two sides of managing antidepressants: a meta-ethnography of patients&#x2019; experience of antidepressants. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2009;68(1):154&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2008.09.068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2008.09.068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19013702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britten N, Campbell R, Pope C, Donovan J, Morgan M, Pill R. Using meta ethnography to synthesise qualitative research: a worked example. Journal of Health Services Research &amp; Policy. 2002;7(4):209&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1258/135581902320432732</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1258/135581902320432732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12425780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkins S, Lewin S, Smith H, Engel M, Fretheim A, Volmink J. Conducting a meta-ethnography of qualitative literature: lessons learnt. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2008;8. doi: 10.1186/1471-2288-8-21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-8-21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2374791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18416812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unruh DR. The nature of social worlds. Pacific Sociological Review. 1980;23(3):271&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLean S, Dwyer R, Pennay A, Savic M, Wilkinson C, Roberts S, et al.. The &#x2018;social worlds&#x2019; concept: a useful tool for public health-oriented studies of drinking cultures. Addiction Research &amp; Theory. 2021;29(3):231&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock A, Campbell P, Struthers C, Synnot A, Nunn J, Hill S, et al.. Stakeholder involvement in systematic reviews: a scoping review. Systematic Reviews. 2018;7(1):1&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6260873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30474560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyde C, Dunn KM, Higginbottom A, Chew&#x2010;Graham CA. Process and impact of patient involvement in a systematic review of shared decision making in primary care consultations. Health Expectations. 2017;20(2):298&#x2013;308. doi: 10.1111/hex.12458</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hex.12458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5354055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27170213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics (ONS). Religion, England and Wales: Census 2021. 2022. p. https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/culturalidentity/religion/bulletins/religionenglandandwales/census2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaspal R, da Silva Lopes BC, Breakwell GM. British national identity and life satisfaction in ethnic minorities in the United Kingdom. National Identities. 2021;23(5):455&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabiee F, Smith P. Being understood, being respected: an evaluation of mental health service provision from service providers and users&#x2019; perspectives in Birmingham, UK. International Journal of Mental Health Promotion. 2013;15(3):162&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabiee F, Smith P. Understanding mental health and experience of accessing services among African and African Caribbean Service users and carers in Birmingham, UK. Diversity &amp; Equality in Health &amp; Care. 2014;11(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannes K, Lockwood C, Pearson A. A comparative analysis of three online appraisal instruments&#x2019; ability to assess validity in qualitative research. Qualitative Health Research. 2010;20(12):1736&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1177/1049732310378656</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732310378656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20671302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barlow F, Lloyd-Knight P. The impact of the detection and diagnosis of breast cancer in black and Asian women. Ethnicity and Inequalities in Health and Social Care. 2012;5(4):133&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fazil Q, Aujla N, Hale C, Kai J. Unequal treatment: health care experiences and needs of patients with cancer from minority ethnic communities. Divers Equal Health Care. 2015;12:95&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel G, Harcourt D, Naqvi H, Rumsey N. Black and South Asian women&#x2019;s experiences of breast cancer: a qualitative study. Diversity &amp; Equality in Health &amp; Care. 2014;11(2):135&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtereva E, Ward T, Ramsey-Wade C. Becoming" another brick in the wall": A thematic analysis of Central and Eastern European immigrants&#x2019; experience of psychological distress and help-seeking. Counselling Psychology Review. 2017;32(3).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edge D, MacKian SC. Ethnicity and mental health encounters in primary care: help-seeking and help-giving for perinatal depression among Black Caribbean women in the UK. Ethnicity &amp; Health. 2010;15(1):93&#x2013;111. doi: 10.1080/13557850903418836</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13557850903418836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20077242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam Z, Rabiee F, Singh SP. Black and minority ethnic groups&#x2019; perception and experience of early intervention in psychosis services in the United Kingdom. Journal of Cross-Cultural Psychology. 2015;46(5):737&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent F, Jenkins H, Larkin M, Clohessy S. Asylum-seekers&#x2019; experiences of trauma-focused cognitive behaviour therapy for post-traumatic stress disorder: a qualitative study. Behavioural and Cognitive Psychotherapy. 2013;41(5):579&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1017/S1352465812000550</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1352465812000550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22794141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittkowski A, Zumla A, Glendenning S, Fox JRE. The experience of postnatal depression in South Asian mothers living in Great Britain: a qualitative study. Journal of Reproductive and Infant Psychology. 2011;29(5):480&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memon A, Taylor K, Mohebati LM, Sundin J, Cooper M, Scanlon T, et al.. Perceived barriers to accessing mental health services among black and minority ethnic (BME) communities: a qualitative study in Southeast England. BMJ open. 2016;6(11):e012337. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2016-012337</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2016-012337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5128839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27852712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S. Cognitive behaviour therapy in a second language. Mental Health Practice. 2016;20(3).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarabi SA, Loulopoulou AI, Henton I. &#x201c;Guide or conversation?&#x201d; The experience of Second-Generation Pakistani Muslim men receiving CBT in the UK. Counselling Psychology Quarterly. 2020;33(1):46&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathod S, Kingdon D, Phiri P, Gobbi M. Developing culturally sensitive cognitive behaviour therapy for psychosis for ethnic minority patients by exploration and incorporation of service users&#x2019; and health professionals&#x2019; views and opinions. Behavioural and Cognitive Psychotherapy. 2010;38(5):511. doi: 10.1017/S1352465810000378</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1352465810000378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20630118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovell K, Lamb J, Gask L, Bower P, Waheed W, Chew-Graham C, et al.. Development and evaluation of culturally sensitive psychosocial interventions for under-served people in primary care. BMC Psychiatry. 2014;14(1):217. doi: 10.1186/s12888-014-0217-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-014-0217-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4149271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25085447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lwembe S, Green SA, Chigwende J, Ojwang T, Dennis R. Co-production as an approach to developing stakeholder partnerships to reduce mental health inequalities: an evaluation of a pilot service. Primary Health Care Research &amp; Development. 2017;18(1):14&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1017/S1463423616000141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1463423616000141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27132634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weatherhead S, Daiches A. Muslim views on mental health and psychotherapy. Psychology and Psychotherapy: Theory, Research and Practice. 2010;83(1):75&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1348/147608309X467807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1348/147608309X467807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19735608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edge D. &#x2018;It&#x2019;s leaflet, leaflet, leaflet then,&#x201c;see you later&#x201d;&#x2018;: Black Caribbean women&#x2019;s perceptions of perinatal mental health care. British Journal of General Practice. 2011;61(585):256&#x2013;62. doi: 10.3399/bjgp11X567063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3399/bjgp11X567063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3063015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21439184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masood Y, Lovell K, Lunat F, Atif N, Waheed W, Rahman A, et al.. Group psychological intervention for postnatal depression: a nested qualitative study with British South Asian women. BMC Women&#x2019;s Health. 2015;15(1):1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1186/s12905-015-0263-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-015-0263-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4659205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26603604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weich S, Griffith L, Commander M, Bradby H, Sashidharan S, Pemberton S, et al.. Experiences of acute mental health care in an ethnically diverse inner city: qualitative interview study. Social Psychiatry and Psychiatric Epidemiology. 2012;47(1):119&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1007/s00127-010-0314-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00127-010-0314-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21046068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yon K, Malik R, Mandin P, Midgley N. Challenging core cultural beliefs and maintaining the therapeutic alliance: A qualitative study. Journal of Family Therapy. 2018;40(2):180&#x2013;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel-Kerai G, Harcourt D, Rumsey N, Naqvi H. Exploring the lived experience of breast cancer diagnosis and treatment amongst Gujarati speaking Indian women. Diversity and Equality in Health and Care. 2015;12(1):9&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bache RA, Bhui KS, Dein S, Korszun A. African and Black Caribbean origin cancer survivors: a qualitative study of the narratives of causes, coping and care experiences. Ethnicity &amp; Health. 2012;17(1&#x2013;2):187&#x2013;201. doi: 10.1080/13557858.2011.635785</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13557858.2011.635785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22107269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos O, Dallos R. The Process of Cross-Cultural Therapy between White Therapists and Clients of African-Caribbean Descent. Qualitative Research in Psychology. 2012;9(1):62&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagstaff C, Graham H, Farrell D, Larkin M, Nettle M. Experiences of mental health services for &#x2018;black&#x2019;men with schizophrenia and a history of disengagement: A qualitative study. International Journal of Mental Health Nursing. 2018;27(1):158&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1111/inm.12305</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/inm.12305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28019715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Littlewood R, Dein S. &#x2018;Islamic fatalism&#x2019;: life and suffering among Bangladeshi psychiatric patients and their families in London&#x2014;an interview study 2. Anthropology &amp; Medicine. 2013;20(3):264&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1080/13648470.2013.853598</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13648470.2013.853598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4095941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24670160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson-Blott KA, O&#x2019;Ceallaigh B, Wiltshire K, Hunt S. Evaluating a &#x201c;healthy minds&#x201d; course for asylum seekers. Mental Health and Social Inclusion. 2015;19(3):133&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabanas E. Rekindling individualism, consuming emotions: Constructing &#x201c;psytizens&#x201d; in the age of happiness. Culture &amp; Psychology. 2016;22(3):467&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridge D, Smith H, Fixsen A, Broom A, Oliffe J. How men step back&#x2014;and recover&#x2014;from suicide attempts: A relational and gendered account. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness. 2021;43(1):238&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33151571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermans H. The dialogical self in education: Introduction. Journal of Constructivist Psychology. 2013;26(2):81&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkind A. Using metaphor to read the organisation of the NHS. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 1998;47(11):1715&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9877342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattison S. Religion, Spirituality and Health Care: Confusions, Tensions, Opportunities. Health Care Analysis. 2013;21(3):193&#x2013;207. doi: 10.1007/s10728-013-0245-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10728-013-0245-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23568086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poole R, Cook CCH, Higgo R. Psychiatrists, spirituality and religion. The British Journal of Psychiatry. 2019;214(4):181&#x2013;2. doi: 10.1192/bjp.2018.241</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.2018.241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30442213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper A. Institutional racism: Can psychotherapy change? British Journal of Psychotherapy. 2010;26(4):486&#x2013;501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feagin J, Bennefield Z. Systemic racism and U.S. health care. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2014;103:7&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2013.09.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2013.09.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24507906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie K, Bhui K. Institutional racism in mental health care. BMJ. 2007;334(7595):649&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1136/bmj.39163.395972.80</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.39163.395972.80</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1839175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17395908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazroo JY, Bhui KS, Rhodes J. Where next for understanding race/ethnic inequalities in severe mental illness? Structural, interpersonal and institutional racism. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness. 2020;42(2):262&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1111/1467-9566.13001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1467-9566.13001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7028120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31562655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel T. Race and Society. London: Sage; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donati P. Discovering the relational goods: their nature, genesis and effects. International Review of Sociology. 2019;29(2):238&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seet AZ. Serving the White nation: Bringing internalised racism within a sociological understanding. Journal of Sociology. 2021;57(2):213&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapadia D. Stigma, mental illness &amp; ethnicity: Time to centre racism and structural stigma. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness. 2023(1&#x2013;17)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10946858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36738120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lokugamage AU, Ahillan T, Pathberiya S. Decolonising ideas of healing in medical education. Journal of Medical Ethics. 2020;46(4):265&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1136/medethics-2019-105866</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/medethics-2019-105866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32029542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xe9;pelteau F. What Is the Direction of the &#x201c;Relational Turn&#x201d;? In: Powell C, D&#xe9;pelteau F, editors. Conceptualizing Relational Sociology: Ontological and Theoretical Issues. New York: Palgrave Macmillan US; 2013:163&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culver JR. 84 &#x201c;Racial Weathering&#x201d; and Other Flaws in the Utilitarian Approach to Economic Lockdown. Aegis: The Otterbein Humanities Journal. 2021; 18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Why, when and how to update a meta-ethnography qualitative synthesis. Systematic Reviews. 2016;5(1):1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1186/s13643-016-0218-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13643-016-0218-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4791806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26979748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenisin K, Trumm A, Akinwande E, Breen K. The experience of inequality and its impact on mental illness&#x2014;thematic analysis of patients&#x2019; lived experiences admitted to secure mental health hospital. The Journal of Forensic Practice. 2022;24(3):270&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamidele OO, McCaughan E. A constructivist grounded theory study on decision-making for treatment choice among Black African and Black Caribbean prostate cancer survivors. European Journal of Cancer Care. 2022;31(1):e13516. doi: 10.1111/ecc.13516</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ecc.13516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34632651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang L. The double hazard in recovery journey: The experiences of UK Chinese users of mental health services. International Journal of Social Psychiatry. 2019;65(4):271&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1177/0020764019840059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0020764019840059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30973295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Condon L, Curejova J, Leeanne Morgan D, Fenlon D. Cancer diagnosis, treatment and care: A qualitative study of the experiences and health service use of Roma, Gypsies and Travellers. European Journal of Cancer Care. 2021;30(5):e13439. doi: 10.1111/ecc.13439</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ecc.13439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33955101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuffour I. &#x201c;There is anointing everywhere&#x201d;: An interpretative phenomenological analysis of the role of religion in the recovery of Black African service users in England. Journal of Psychiatric and Mental Health Nursing. 2020;27(4):352&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1111/jpm.12589</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jpm.12589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31913535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamidele O, McGarvey H, Lagan BM, Parahoo K, Chinegwundoh MBE F, McCaughan E. &#x201c;Man in the driving seat&#x201d;: A grounded theory study of the psychosocial experiences of Black African and Black Caribbean men treated for prostate cancer and their partners. Psycho&#x2010;Oncology. 2019;28(8):1712&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1002/pon.5150</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.5150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31216078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagland R, Nayoan J, Matheson L, Rivas C, Brett J, Collaco N, et al.. Adjustment strategies amongst black African and black Caribbean men following treatment for prostate cancer: findings from the Life After Prostate Cancer Diagnosis (LAPCD) study. European Journal of Cancer Care. 2020;29(1):e13183. doi: 10.1111/ecc.13183</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ecc.13183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31642565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margariti C, Gannon K, Thompson R, Walsh J, Green J. Experiences of UK African-Caribbean prostate cancer survivors of discharge to primary care. Ethnicity &amp; Health. 2021;26(8):1115&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1080/13557858.2019.1606162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13557858.2019.1606162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30987446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toye F, Seers K, Allcock N, Briggs M, Carr E, Andrews J, et al.. &#x2018;Trying to pin down jelly&#x2019;&#x2014;exploring intuitive processes in quality assessment for meta-ethnography. BMC Medical Research Methodology. 2013;13(1):46. doi: 10.1186/1471-2288-13-46</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-13-46</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3639821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23517438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold M, Rutherford MJ, Bardot A, Ferlay J, Andersson TM, Myklebust T&#xc5;, et al.. Progress in cancer survival, mortality, and incidence in seven high-income countries 1995&#x2013;2014 (ICBP SURVMARK-2): a population-based study. The Lancet Oncology. 2019;20(11):1493&#x2013;505. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(19)30456-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(19)30456-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6838671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31521509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson M. Delivering race equality in mental health care: a review. Department of Health, London. 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willan J, King AJ, Jeffery K, Bienz N. Challenges for NHS hospitals during covid-19 epidemic. BMJ. 2020;20:368. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m1117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m1117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32198166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ham C. The challenges facing the NHS in England in 2021. BMJ. 2020;371:m4973. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m4973</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m4973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33384281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice T, Rosenau P, Unruh LY, Barnes AJ, Saltman RB, Van Ginneken E, et al.. United States of America: Health system review. Health Systems in Transition. 2013;15(3):1&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24025796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broom A. Conceptualizing Qualitative Data. Qualitative Health Research. 2021;31(10):1767&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1177/10497323211024951</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10497323211024951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34166154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>