<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36326730</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1751-4266</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in supportive and palliative care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Support Palliat Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-COVID-19 respiratory problems: burden and management.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>203</StartPage><EndPage>209</EndPage><MedlinePgn>203-209</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/SPC.0000000000000619</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">To describe the burden of post-COVID respiratory sequelae in posthospital and nonhospitalized COVID-19 survivors and to describe the priorities of clinical management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Due to varying definitions of 'Long COVID' or 'Post-COVID', the prevalence of post-COVID sequelae or persisting symptoms is challenging to estimate but ranges from 2.3 to 51%. Risk factors for persistent post-COVID symptoms include age, female sex, deprivation, presence of comorbidities; and in posthospital COVID-19 survivors, the severity of acute infection. Common post-COVID respiratory symptoms include breathlessness, cough and chest pain and many individuals also experience exercise intolerance. The most common pulmonary function test abnormality is impaired diffusing capacity for carbon monoxide. In posthospital COVID-19 survivors, the prevalence of interstitial lung damage is 5-11%. Disordered breathing is common in all post-COVID patients and respiratory physiotherapy is helpful.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">The vast numbers of COVID-19 infections globally implies that a large number of people will be affected by post-COVID sequelae even with conservative estimates. A significant number of people are affected for several months and up to years following acute infection. Post-COVID sequelae have a detrimental impact on quality of life and ability to work.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kessler</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Respiratory division, University College London Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heightman</LastName><ForeName>Melissa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brennan</LastName><ForeName>Ewen</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Support Palliat Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101297402</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1751-4258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012129" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Function Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017563" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Diseases, Interstitial</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36326730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SPC.0000000000000619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01263393-202212000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation. WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard. 2022; Geneva: World Health Organisation, Retrieved from: https://covid19.who.int/ . [Last accessed 13 July 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan Q, Yang K, Wang W, et al. Clinical predictors of mortality due to COVID-19 based on an analysis of data of 150 patients from Wuhan, China. Intensive Care Med 2020; 46:846&#x2013;848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, McAuley DF, Brown M, et al. HLH Across Speciality Collaboration, UK. COVID-19: consider cytokine storm syndromes and immunosuppression. Lancet 2020; 395:1033&#x2013;1034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Yu T, Du R, et al. Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet 2020; 395:1054&#x2013;1062. Published correction appears in Lancet 2020 Mar 28;395 (10229):1038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou-Ismail MY, Diamond A, Kapoor S, et al. The hypercoagulable state in COVID-19: incidence, pathophysiology, and management. Thromb Res 2020; 194:101&#x2013;115. Published correction appears in Thromb Res. 2020 Nov 26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horby P, Lim WS, et al. RECOVERY Collaborative Group. Dexamethasone in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. N Engl J Med 2021; 384:693&#x2013;704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RECOVERY Collaborative Group. Tocilizumab in patients admitted to hospital with COVID-19 (RECOVERY): a randomised, controlled, open-label, platform trial. Lancet 2021; 397:1637&#x2013;1645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beigel JH, Tomashek KM, Dodd LE, et al. Remdesivir for the treatment of COVID-19 &#x2013; final report. N Engl J Med 2020; 383:1813&#x2013;1826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vegivinti CTR, Evanson KW, Lyons H, et al. Efficacy of antiviral therapies for COVID-19: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. BMC Infect Dis 2022; 22:107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021. 2022; Geneva: WHO, Retrieved from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1 . [Last accessed 13 July 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg P, Arora U, Kumar A, Wig N. The &#x201c;post-COVID&#x201d; syndrome: how deep is the damage? J Med Virol 2021; 93:673&#x2013;674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med 2021; 27:626&#x2013;631. Published correction appears in Nat Med. 2021 Jun;27(6):1116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirulli ET, Schiabor Barrett KM, Riffle S, et al. Long-term COVID-19 symptoms in a large unselected population. medRxiv 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladds E, Rushforth A, Wieringa S, et al. Persistent symptoms after COVID-19: qualitative study of 114 &#x201c;long Covid&#x201d; patients and draft quality principles for services. BMC Health Serv Res 2020; 20:1144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull-Otterson L, Baca S, Saydah S, et al. Post-COVID conditions among adult COVID-19 survivors aged 18-64 and &#x2265;65 years &#x2013; United States, March 2020&#x2013;November 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2022; 71:713&#x2013;717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office For National Statistics, Office for National Statistics. Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK. 2022; Retrieved from: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/7july2022 . [Last accessed 13 July 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson EJ, Williams DM, Walker AJ, et al. Long COVID burden and risk factors in 10 UK longitudinal studies and electronic health records. Nat Commun 2022; 13:3528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker AJ, MacKenna B, Inglesby P, et al. Clinical coding of long COVID in English primary care: a federated analysis of 58 million patient records in situ using OpenSAFELY. Br J Gen Pract 2021; 71:e806&#x2013;e814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heightman M, Prashar J, Hillman TE, et al. Post-COVID-19 assessment in a specialist clinical service: a 12-month, single-centre, prospective study in 1325 individuals. BMJ Open Respir Res 2021; 8:e001041Erratum in: BMJ Open Respir Res. 2022 Jan; 9(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitaker M, Elliott J, Chadeau-Hyam M, et al. Persistent COVID-19 symptoms in a community study of 606,434 people in England. Nat Commun 2022; 13:1957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grist JT, Collier GJ, Walters H, et al. The investigation of pulmonary abnormalities using hyperpolarised xenon magnetic resonance imaging in patients with long-COVID. medRxiv 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh I, Joseph P, Heerdt PM, et al. Persistent exertional intolerance after COVID-19: insights from invasive cardiopulmonary exercise testing. Chest 2022; 161:54&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samaranayake C, Warren C, Rhamie S, et al. P142 chaotic breathing in post COVID-19 breathlessness: a key feature characterised by approximate entropy. Thorax 2021; 76:A144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xe9;sard I, Genecand L, Altarelli M, et al. Dysfunctional breathing diagnosed by cardiopulmonary exercise testing in &#x2018;long COVID&#x2019; patients with persistent dyspnoea. BMJ Open Respir Res 2022; 9:e001126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courtney R, van Dixhoorn J, Greenwood KM, Anthonissen EL. Medically unexplained dyspnea: partly moderated by dysfunctional (thoracic dominant) breathing pattern. J Asthma 2011; 48:259&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motiejunaite J, Balagny P, Arnoult F, et al. Hyperventilation as one of the mechanisms of persistent dyspnoea in SARS-CoV-2 survivors. Eur Respir J 2021; 58:2101578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson L, Ramdharry G, Chapman O, et al. Does virtual breathing pattern retraining improve breathlessness in patients with post COVID syndrome? European Respiratory Journal 2021; 58: (suppl 65): PA2265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PHOSP-COVID Collaborative Group. Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet Respir Med 2022; 10:761&#x2013;775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, et al. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet 2021; 398:747&#x2013;758. Published correction appears in Lancet. 2022 May 7;399(10337):1778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Li X, Gu X, et al. Health outcomes in people 2 years after surviving hospitalisation with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Respir Med 2022; 10:863&#x2013;876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comelli A, Viero G, Bettini G, et al. Patient-reported symptoms and sequelae 12 months after COVID-19 in hospitalized adults: a multicenter long-term follow-up study. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022; 9:834354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellan M, Baricich A, Patrucco F, et al. Long-term sequelae are highly prevalent one year after hospitalization for severe COVID-19. Sci Rep 2021; 11:22666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faverio P, Luppi F, Rebora P, et al. One-year pulmonary impairment after severe COVID-19: a prospective, multicenter follow-up study. Respir Res 2022; 23:65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, et al. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and nonhospitalized COVID-19 survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Intern Med 2021; 92:55&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang X, Ming C, Cen Y, et al. Postsequelae one year after hospital discharge among older COVID-19 patients: a multicenter prospective cohort study. J Infect 2022; 84:179&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart I, Jacob J, George PM, et al. Interstitial lung damage following COVID-19 hospitalisation: an interim analysis of the UKILD Post-COVID study. medRxiv 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huntley CC, Patel K, Bil Bushra SE, et al. Pulmonary function test and computed tomography features during follow-up after SARS, MERS and COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. ERJ Open Res 2022; 8:00056&#x2013;2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Li J, Liu H, et al. Long-term bone and lung consequences associated with hospital-acquired severe acute respiratory syndrome: a 15-year follow-up from a prospective cohort study. Bone Res 2020; 8:8Erratum in: Bone Res. 2020 Sep 21;8:34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayakumar B, Tonkin J, Devaraj A, et al. CT lung abnormalities after COVID-19 at 3 months and 1 year after hospital discharge. Radiology 2022; 303:444&#x2013;454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X, Huang H, Wang C, et al. Follow-up study of pulmonary function among COVID-19 survivors 1 year after recovery. J Infect 2021; 83:381&#x2013;412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Liu X, Zhou Y, et al. 3-month, 6-month, 9-month, and 12-month respiratory outcomes in patients following COVID-19-related hospitalisation: a prospective study. Lancet Respir Med 2021; 9:747&#x2013;754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Tao M, Shang L, et al. Assessment of sequelae of COVID-19 nearly 1 year after diagnosis. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021; 8:717194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Zhao X, Wang Y, et al. Damaged lung gas exchange function of discharged COVID-19 patients detected by hyperpolarized 129Xe MRI. Sci Adv 2021; 7:eabc8180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barisione G, Brusasco V. Lung diffusing capacity for nitric oxide and carbon monoxide following mild-to-severe COVID-19. Physiol Rep 2021; 9:e14748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsoularis I, Fonseca-Rodri-guez O, Farrington P, et al. Risks of deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, and bleeding after covid-19: nationwide self-controlled cases series and matched cohort study. BMJ 2022; 377:e069590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carubbi F, Alunno A, Leone S, et al. Pericarditis after SARS-CoV-2 infection: another pebble in the mosaic of long COVID? Viruses 2021; 13:1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaminski A, Albus M, Mohseni M, et al. A delayed case of pericarditis following recovery from COVID-19 infection. Cureus 2021; 13:e14397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arany&#xf3; J, Bazan V, Llad&#xf3;s G, et al. Inappropriate sinus tachycardia in post-COVID-19 syndrome. Sci Rep 2022; 12:298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker WH, Moudgil R, Wilson RG, et al. COVID-19 and postural tachycardia syndrome: a case series. Eur Heart J Case Rep 2021; 5:ytab325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas P, Baldwin C, Bissett B, et al. Physiotherapy management for COVID-19 in the acute hospital setting: clinical practice recommendations. J Physiother 2020; 66:73&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puchner B, Sahanic S, Kirchmair R, et al. Beneficial effects of multidisciplinary rehabilitation in postacute COVID-19 &#x2013; an observational cohort study. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 2021; 57:189&#x2013;198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore J, Hillard N, Plumbe K, et al. A review of an innovative digital group therapy breathing &amp; energy management programme designed to reduce symptoms of long COVID. 2021; London, UK: The Chartered Society Of Physiotherapy, Retrieved from: https://www.csp.org.uk/innovations/review-innovative-digital-group-therapy-breathing-energy-management-programme-designed . [Last accessed 13 July 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Watt A, Houchen-Wolloff L, et al. P70 The impact of post COVID-19 rehabilitation on hospital and nonhospitalised participant &#x2013; is there a difference? Thorax 2021; 76:A104&#x2013;A105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myall KJ, Mukherjee B, Castanheira AM, et al. Persistent post-COVID-19 interstitial lung disease. An observational study of corticosteroid treatment. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2021; 18:799&#x2013;806.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>