<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38833210</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1828-695X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Multidisciplinary respiratory medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Multidiscip Respir Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>mRNA vaccines protect from the lung microvasculature injury and the capillary blood volume loss occurring in SARS-CoV-2 paucisymptomatic infections.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">973</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5826/mrm.2024.973</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The reduction of lung capillary blood volume (Vc) had been identified as the microvascular injury mostly underlying the respiratory Long-COVID syndrome following post-COVID-19 pneumonia. The same kind of injury have been recently also found in several individuals after milder paucisymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infections. Though current guidelines strongly recommend vac-cination, studies aimed to investigate the in vivo protection of anti-SARS-CoV-2 vaccines on lung microvascular targets still are missing to our best knowledge.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">to assess the protection of mRNA vaccines from the reduction of lung capillary blood volume (Vc) caused by pauci-symptomatic SARS.CoV-2 infections in vaccinated compared to unvaccinated individuals.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Non-smoking individuals with recent paucisymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection were divided into vaccinated and unvaccinated groups. Lung function parameters, including single-breath diffusing capacity and microvascular blood volume, were compared between groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">fifty vaccinated and twenty-five unvaccinated well-matched individuals were studied. Differently than usual lung function parameters, only the single-breath simultaneous assessment of sDLCO, sDLNO/sDLCO ratio and Vc allowed to identify the occurrence of the lung microvascular injury with high sensitivity and specificity (p&lt;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">mRNA vaccines proved to exert a high protection from the loss of lung capillary blood volume (Vc) induced by SARS.CoV-2 paucisymptomatic infections (p&lt;0.001). The availability of this non-invasive investigational model should be regarded as a very helpful tool for assessing and comparing in vivo the protective effect of mRNA vaccines on the human microvascular structures of the deep lung.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dal Negro</LastName><ForeName>Roberto W</ForeName><Initials>RW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Respiratory Pharmacoeconomics &amp; Pharmacoepidemiology - CESFAR, Verona.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turco</LastName><ForeName>Paola</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Respiratory Pharmacoeconomics and Pharmacoepidemiology - CESFAR, 37124 Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Povero</LastName><ForeName>Massimiliano</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AdRes Health Economics and Outcomes Research, 10121 Torino, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Multidiscip Respir Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101477642</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1828-695X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of interest:</b> The authors declare no conflict of interest. RWDN is Associate Editor of <i>Multidisciplinary Respiratory Medicine</i>.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38833210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11186436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5826/mrm.2024.973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ashhurst AS, Johansen MD, Maxwell JWC, Stockdale S, Ashley CL, Aggarwa A, et al. Mucosal TLR2-activating protein-based vaccination induces potent pulmonary immunity and protection against SARS-CoV-2 in mice. Nature Commun. 2022;13:6972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9665025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36379950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu N, Zhang D, Wang W, Li X, Yang B, Song J, et al. China Novel Coronavirus Investigating and Research Team. A novel coronavirus from patients with pneumonia in China, 2019. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:27&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31978945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matricardi PM, Dal Negro RW, Nisini R. The first, comprehensive immunological model of COVID-19: implications for prevention, diagnosis, and public health measures. Pediatr Allergy Immunol. 2020;31(5):454&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1111/pai.13271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pai.13271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32359201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan W, Ni Z, Hu Y, Liang WH, Ou CQ, He JX, et al. Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:1708&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2002032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2002032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32109013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020;395:497&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbarialiabad H, Taghrir MH, Abdollahi A, Ghahramani N, Kumar M, Paydar S, et al. Long COVID, a comprehensive systematic scoping review. Infection. 2021;49:1163&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8317481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34319569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-de-las-Penas C. Long-COVID: current definition. Infection. 2022;50:285&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8438555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34519974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshee S, Vatti N, Chang C. Long-Term effects of COVID-19. Mayo Clin Proc. 2022;97:579&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8752286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35246288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis. 2021;53(10):737&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanares-Zapatero P, Chalon L, Kohn M, Dauvrin M, Detollenaere J, Maertens de Noordhout C, et al. Pathophysiology and mechanism of long COVID: a comprehensive review. Ann Med. 2022;54:1473&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35594336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Hu B, Hu C, Zhu F, Liu X, Zhang J, et al. Clinical characteristics of 138 hospitalized patients with 2019 novel coronavirus-infected pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA. 2020;323:1061&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iba T, Connors JM, Levy JH. The coagulopathy, endotheliopathy, and vasculitis of COVID-19. Inflamm Res. 2020;69:1181&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32918567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo X, Jian W, Su Z, Chen M, Peng H, Peng P, et al. Abnormal pulmonary function in COVID-19 patients at time of hospital discharge. Eur Respir J. 2020;55:2001217. doi: 10.1183/13993003.01217-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.01217-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32381497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence, Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network, Royal College of General practitioners. COVID-19 rapid guideline managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. Dec 18, 2020.  [accessed April 30, 2022].  
 https//www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Negro RW, Turco P, Povero M. Long-lasting dyspnea in patients otherwise clinically and radiologically recovered from COVID pneumonia: a probe for checking persisting disorders in capillary lung volume as a cause. Multidiscip Respir Med. 2022;17(1):875. doi: 10.4081/mrm.2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/mrm.2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9577559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36268261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque AH, Pant AB. Long COVID: untangling the complex syndrome and the search for therapeutics. Viruses. 2023;15:42. doi: 10.3390/v15010042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v15010042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9864843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36680082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, et al. Post-discharge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a crosssectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93(2):1013&#x2013;1022. doi: 10.1002/jmv.26368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH, Crooks MG. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is Long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;199:113&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Negro RW, Turco P, Povero M. Phenotyping lung function disorders in respiratory Long-COVID. Brit J Multidisc Adv Studies. 2023;4:71&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Negro RW, Turco P, Povero M. Persistent Reduction of Lung Capillary Blood Volume as the Major &#x201c;Deep Lung&#x201d; Disorder Underlying Respiratory Long-COVID Syndrome. Am J Med and Public Health. 2024;5(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Drug Administration. Learn more about COVID-19 vaccines from the FDA. Silver Spring, MD: US Department of Health and Human Services, Food and Drug Administration; 2021.  [Accessed August 23, 2021].  
 https://www.fda.gov/consumers/consumer-updates/learn-more-about-covid-19-vaccines-fda
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC. COVID-19: different COVID-19 vaccines. Atlanta, GA: US Department of Health and Human Services, CDC; 2021.  [Accessed August 25, 2021].  
 https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/different-vaccines.html
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krammer F. SARS-CoV-2 vaccines in development. Nature. 2020;586:516&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32967006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavelle EC, Ward RW. Mucosal vaccines &#x2014; fortifying the frontiers. Nat Rev Immunol. 2022;22:236&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8312369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas EJ, Angulo FJ, McLaughlin JM, Anis E, Singer SR, Khan F, Brooks, et al. Impact and effectiveness of mRNA BNT162b2 vaccine against SARS-CoV-2 infections and COVID-19 cases, hospitalisations, and deaths following a nationwide vaccination campaign in Israel: An observational study using national surveillance data. Lancet. 2021;397:1819&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8099315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33964222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagan N, Barda N, Kepten E, Miron O, Perchik S, Katz MA, et al. BNT162b2 mRNA COVID-19 Vaccine in a Nationwide Mass Vaccination Setting. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:1412&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7944975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33626250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung H, He S, Nasreen S, Sundaram ME, Buchan SA, Wilson SE, et al. Canadian Immunization Research Network (CIRN) Provincial Collaborative Network (PCN) Investigators. Effectiveness of BNT162b2 and mRNA-1273 COVID-19 vaccines against symptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection and severe COVID-19 outcomes in Ontario, Canada: Test negative design study. BMJ. 2021;374:n1943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8377789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34417165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauring AS, Tenforde MW, Chappell JD, Gaglani M, Ginde AA, Tresa McNeal T, et al. Clinical severity of, and effectiveness of mRNA vaccines against Covid-19 from omicron, delta, and alpha SARS-CoV-2 variants in the United States: prospective observational study. BMJ. 2022;376:e069761. doi: 10.1136/bmj-2021-069761).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2021-069761)</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8905308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35264324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angel Y, Spitzer A, Henig O, Saiag E, Sprecher E, Padova H, et al. Association Between Vaccination With BNT162b2 and Incidence of Symptomatic and Asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 Infections Among Health Care Workers. JAMA. 2021;325:2457&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8220476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33956048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilishvili T, Gierke R, Fleming-Dutra KE, Farrar JL, Mohr NM, Talan DA, et al. Vaccine Effectiveness among Healthcare Personnel Study Team Effectiveness of mRNA COVID-19 Vaccine among, U.S. Health Care Personnel. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:e90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34551224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahler DA, Wells CK. Evaluation of clinical methods for rating dyspnoea. Chest. 1988;93:580&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3342669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roughton FJ, Forster RE. Relative importance of diffusion and chemical reaction in determining rate of exchange of gases in the human lung. J Appl Physiol. 1957;11:290&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13475180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham BL, Brusasco V, Burgos F, Cooper BG, Jensen R, Kendrick A, et al. ERS/ATS standards for single-breath carbon monoxide uptake in the lung. Eur Respir J. 2017;49(1):1600016. doi: 10.1183/13993003.00016-2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00016-2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28049168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Kessel SAM, Olde Hartman TC, Lucassen PLBJ, van Jaarsveld CHM. Postacute and long-COVID-19 symptoms in patients with mild diseases: a systematic review. Fam Pract. 2022;39:159&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8414057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34268556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian S, Xiong Y, Liu H, Niu L, Guo J, Liao M, et al. Pathological study of the 2019 novel coronavirus disease (COVID-19) through postmortem core biopsies. Mod Pathol. 2020;33(6):1007&#x2013;1014. doi: 10.1038/s41379-020-0536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41379-020-0536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32291399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhawan RT, Gopalan D, Howard L, Vicente A, Park M, Manalan K, et al. Beyond the clot: perfusion imaging of the pulmonary vasculature after COVID-19. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:107&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33217366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickman D, Sperhake JP, Lutgehetmann M, Steurer S, Edler C, Heinemann A, et al. Autopsy findings and venous thromboembolism in patients with COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Ann Intern Med. 2020;173:268&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7240772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32374815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libby P, Luscher T. COVID-19 is in the end, an endothelial disease. Eur Heart J. 2020;41:3038&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7470753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32882706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iba T, Connors JM, Levy JH. The coagulopathy, endotheliopathy, and vasculitis of COVID-19. Inflamm Res. 2020;69:1181&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32918567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frija-Masson J, Debray MP, Gilbert M, Lescure FX, Travert F, Borie R, et al. Functional characteristics of patients with SARS-CoV- 2 pneumonia at 30 days post-infection. Eur Respir J. 2020;56:2001754. doi: 10.1183/13993003.01754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.01754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32554533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo X, Jian W, Su Z, Chen M, Peng H, Peng P, et al. Abnormal pulmonary function in COVID-19 patients at time of hospital discharge. Eur Respir J. 2020;55:2001217. doi: 10.1183/13993003.01217-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.01217-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32381497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson QH, Roughton FJW. The kinetics and equilibria of the reactions of nitric oxide with sheep haemoglobin. J Phys. 1957;136:507&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1358871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13429517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zavorsky GS, van der Lee I. Can the measurement of pulmonary diffusing capacity for nitric oxide replace the measurement of pulmonary diffusing capacity for carbon monoxide? Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2017;241:9&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27884796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zavorsky GS, Hsia CCW, Hughes MB, Borland CD, Gu&#xe9;nard H, van der Lee I, et al. Standardization and application of the single-breath determination of nitric oxide uptake in the lung. Eur Respir J. 2017;49:1600962. doi: 10.1183/13993003.00962-2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00962-2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28179436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borland CDR, Hughes JMB. Lung diffusing capacities (DL) for nitric oxide (NO) and carbon monoxide (CO): The evolving story. Compr Physiol. 2020;10:73&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31853952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George PM, Barratt SL, Condliffe R, Desai SR, Devaraj A, Forrest I, et al. Respiratory follow-up of patients with COVID-19 pneumonia. Thorax. 2020;75:1009&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32839287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osiaevi I, Schulze A, Evers G, Harmening K, Vink H, Kumpers P, et al. Persistent capillary rarefication in long COVID syndrome. Angiogenesis. 2023 Feb;26(1):53&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1007/s10456-022-09850-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10456-022-09850-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9366128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35951203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Self WH, Tenforde MW, Rhoads JP, Gaglani M, Adit A, Ginde AA, et al. Comparative Effectiveness of Moderna, Pfizer-BioNTech, and Janssen ( Johnson &amp; Johnson) Vaccines in Preventing COVID-19 Hospitalizations Among Adults Without Immunocompromising Conditions &#x2014; United States, March&#x2013;August 2021. MMWR. 2021;70(38):1337&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34555004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham BS. Advances in antiviral vaccine development. Immunol Rev. 2013;255(1):230&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1111/imr.1209890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/imr.1209890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3821995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23947359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarte KI, Catahay JA, Velasco JV, Pastrana A, Ver AT, Pangilinan FC, et al. Impact of Covid-19 vaccination on the risk of developing long-COVID and on existing long-COVID symptoms. A systematic review. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;53:101624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9417563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36051247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque AH, Pant AB. Long COVID: untangling the complex syndrome and the search for therapeutics. Viruses. 2023;15:42. doi: 10.3390/v15010042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v15010042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9864843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36680082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo D, Del Nonno F, Marchioni L, Lalle E, Gall&#xec; P, Vaia F, et al. Autopsies Revealed Pathological Features of COVID-19 in Unvaccinated vs. Vaccinated Patients. Biomedicines. 2023;11:551. doi: 10.3390/biomedicines11020551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines11020551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9953314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36831087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang M-Y, Grebenkov D, Gu&#xe9;nard H, Katz I. B Sapoval B - The Roughton-Forster equation for DLCO and DLNO reexamined. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2017;241:62&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28049017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>