<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37122115</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1681</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>50</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical and experimental pharmacology &amp; physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pre-pandemic autonomic function as a predictor of the COVID clinical course in young adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>594</StartPage><EndPage>603</EndPage><MedlinePgn>594-603</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1440-1681.13776</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long coronavirus disease (COVID) is emerging as a common clinical entity in the current era. Autonomic dysfunction is one of the frequently reported post-COVID complications. We hypothesize a bi-directional relationship between the autonomic function and the COVID course. This postulation has been inadequately addressed in the literature. A retrospective cohort (pre and post-comparison) study was conducted on 30 young adults whose pre-COVID autonomic function test results were available. They were divided into case and control groups based on whether they tested reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction positive for COVID-19. Autonomic function tests were performed in both the case and control groups. COVID infection in healthy young adults shifts the sympatho-vagal balance from the pre-disease state. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome was present in 35% of the COVID-affected group. COVID course parameters were found to be associated with parasympathetic reactivity and the baroreflex function. Baseline autonomic function (parasympathetic reactivity represented by &#x394; heart rate changes during deep breathing and 30:15 ratio during lying-to-standing test) was also associated with the COVID course, the post-COVID symptoms and the post-COVID autonomic function profile. Additionally, multiple regression analysis found that the baseline parasympathetic reactivity was a very important determinant of the clinical course of COVID, the post-COVID symptoms and the post-COVID autonomic profile. Sympatho-vagal balance shifts to parasympathetic withdrawal with sympathetic predominance due to COVID infection in healthy young adults. There is a bi-directional relationship between the autonomic function and the COVID course.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Vagisha</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Vardhman Mahavir Medical College and Safdarjung Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pattnaik</LastName><ForeName>Sanghamitra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Vardhman Mahavir Medical College and Safdarjung Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahluwalia</LastName><ForeName>Himani</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Vardhman Mahavir Medical College and Safdarjung Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaur</LastName><ForeName>Manpreet</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3650-3825</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Vardhman Mahavir Medical College and Safdarjung Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0425076</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0305-1870</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001341" MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic Nervous System</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autonomic function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">baroreflex function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bi-directional relationship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">para</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sympathetic function</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37122115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1440-1681.13776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P, et al. Autonomic dysfunction in &#x201c;long COVID&#x201d;: rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin Med (Lond). 2021;21(1):e63-e67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva Andrade B, Siqueira S, de Assis Soares WR, et al. Long-COVID and post-COVID health complications: an up-to-date review on clinical conditions and their possible molecular mechanisms. Viruses. 2021;13(4):700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaliyaperumal D, Rk K, Alagesan M, Ramalingam S. Characterization of cardiac autonomic function in COVID-19 using heart rate variability: a hospital based preliminary observational study. J Basic Clin Physiol Pharmacol. 2021;32(3):247-253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Junarta J, Riley JM, Pavri BB. Describing heart rate variability in patients with chronic atrial fibrillation during hospitalization for COVID-19. J Arrhythmia. 2021 Aug;37(4):893-898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamaleswaran R, Sadan O, Kandiah P, Li Q, Coopersmith CM, Buchman TG. Altered heart rate variability early in ICU admission differentiates critically ill coronavirus disease 2019 and all-cause sepsis patients. Crit Care Explor. 2021 Dec;3(12):e0570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milovanovic B, Djajic V, Bajic D, et al. Assessment of autonomic nervous system dysfunction in the early phase of infection with SARS-CoV-2 virus. Front Neurosci. 2021;15:640835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen NW, Stiles LE, Miglis MG. Preparing for the long-haul: autonomic complications of COVID-19. Auton Neurosci. 2021;235:102841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Rio R, Marcus NJ, Inestrosa NC. Potential role of autonomic dysfunction in Covid-19 morbidity and mortality. Front Physiol. 2020;11:561749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porzionato A, Emmi A, Barbon S, et al. Sympathetic activation: a potential link between comorbidities and COVID-19. FEBS J. 2020;287(17):3681-3688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leitzke M, Stefanovic D, Meyer JJ, Schimpf S, Sch&#xf6;nknecht P. Autonomic balance determines the severity of COVID-19 courses. Bioelectron Med. 2020;6(1):22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scala I, Rizzo PA, Bellavia S, et al. Autonomic dysfunction during acute SARS-CoV-2 infection: a systematic review. J Clin Med. 2022;11(13):3883.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scala I, Bellavia S, Luigetti M, et al. Autonomic dysfunction in non-critically ill COVID-19 patients during the acute phase of disease: an observational, cross-sectional study. Neurol Sci. 2022;43(8):4635-4643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellavia S, Scala I, Luigetti M, et al. Instrumental evaluation of COVID-19 related dysautonomia in non-critically-ill patients: an observational, cross-sectional study. J Clin Med. 2021;10(24):5861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Moloney D, Finucane C, et al. Fatigue following COVID-19 infection is not associated with autonomic dysfunction. PloS One. 2021;16(2):e0247280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asarcikli LD, Hayiroglu M&#x130;, Osken A, Keskin K, Kolak Z, Aksu T. Heart rate variability and cardiac autonomic functions in post-COVID period. J Interv Card Electrophysiol. 2022;63:715-721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S, Whitelaw S. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) and other autonomic disorders after COVID-19 infection: a case series of 20 patients. Immunol Res. 2021;69(2):205-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurto&#x11f;lu E, Afsin A, Akta&#x15f; &#x130;, Akt&#xfc;rk E, Kutlusoy E, &#xc7;a&#x11f;a&#x15f;ar &#xd6;. Altered cardiac autonomic function after recovery from COVID-19. Ann Noninvasive Electrocardiol. 2022;27(1):e12916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barizien N, Le Guen M, Russel S, Touche P, Huang F, Vall&#xe9;e A. Clinical characterization of dysautonomia in long COVID-19 patients. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):14042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y, Yu Z, Yuan Y, et al. Alteration of autonomic nervous system is associated with severity and outcomes in patients with COVID-19. Front Physiol. 2021;12:630038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheldon RS, Grubb BP, Olshansky B, et al. 2015 heart rhythm society expert consensus statement on the diagnosis and treatment of postural tachycardia syndrome, inappropriate sinus tachycardia, and vasovagal syncope. Heart Rhythm. 2015;12(6):e41-e63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarte KI, Catahay JA, Velasco JV, et al. Impact of COVID-19 vaccination on the risk of developing long-COVID and on existing long-COVID symptoms: a systematic review. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;53:101624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buoite Stella A, Furlanis G, Frezza NA, Valentinotti R, Ajcevic M, Manganotti P. Autonomic dysfunction in post-COVID patients with and witfhout neurological symptoms: a prospective multidomain observational study. J Neurol. 2022;269(2):587-596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shouman K, Vanichkachorn G, Cheshire WP, et al. Autonomic dysfunction following COVID-19 infection: an early experience. Clin Auton Res. 2021 Jun;31(3):385-394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadian M, Golchoobian R. Potential autonomic nervous system dysfunction in COVID-19 patients detected by heart rate variability is a sign of SARS-CoV-2 neurotropic features. Mol Biol Rep. 2022 Aug;49(8):8131-8137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skazkina V, Borovkova E, Krasikova N, et al. Analysis of coupling between autonomic control loops of blood circulation in patients with Covid-19. 2021 5th Scientific School Dynamics of Complex Networks and their Applications (DCNA). IEEE; 2021:187-189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skazkina V, Krasikova N, Borovkova E, et al. Synchronization of autonomic control loops of blood circulation In patients with COVID-19. Russ Open Med J. 2021;30:10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baji&#x107; D, &#x110;aji&#x107; V, Milovanovi&#x107; B. Entropy analysis of COVID-19 cardiovascular signals. Entropy (Basel). 2021;23(1):87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon I, Horesh D, Milstein N, Tomashin A, Mayo O, Korisky A. Pre-pandemic autonomic nervous system activity predicts mood regulation expectancies during COVID-19 in Israel. Psychophysiology. 2021;58(11):e13910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Electrophysiology TF. Heart rate variability: standards of measurement, physiological interpretation and clinical use. Task force of the European Society of Cardiology and the north American Society of Pacing and Electrophysiology. Circulation. 1996;93(5):1043-1065.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>