<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39324381</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1934-1563</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PM &amp; R : the journal of injury, function, and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PM R</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Use of cardiopulmonary exercise testing to identify mechanisms of exertional symptoms in children with long COVID.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/pmrj.13263</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Little is known about the mechanisms of exercise intolerance and exertional symptoms in children with long COVID. Through utilization of cardiopulmonary exercise testing (CPET), this study is the first of its kind to evaluate exertional symptoms and attempt to identify potential mechanism of long COVID-19 in children.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine if CPET will uncover potential reasons for persistent symptoms of long COVID when there is no indication of cardiopulmonary or upper airway disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We performed a retrospective chart review study involving children 6-17&#x2009;years of age with symptoms of long COVID at Phoenix Children''s Hospital from January 1, 2021, to June 1, 2022. Symptoms included but were not limited to exercise intolerance, fatigue, shortness of breath, dyspnea on exertion, and chest pain. We recorded any measurable abnormalities present on CPET after comparing it to established normal reference ranges. Range, median, and SD of data points were calculated and p values were determined using the Mann-Whitney U and Fisher's exact test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-three children with exertional symptoms consistent with long COVID were identified. The most frequent symptoms reported during exercise include dyspnea on exertion (35%), followed by chest pain (30%) and dizziness (13%). Nearly half of the children (47%) demonstrated decreased exercise capacity with 30% displaying limitations due to deconditioning, 22% limited by body habitus, and 13% due to bronchospasm. Other contributing factors include ventilation to perfusion mismatch and volitional hyperventilation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Decreased aerobic activity due to multiple factors was found in 47% of children with a history of COVID-19. This study illustrates the importance of ongoing research into this phenomenon to elucidate its mechanism and assist physicians in making decisions regarding referral to specialists for further testing.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 American Academy of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lowe</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-7794-4071</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Phoenix Children's Hospital, Phoenix, Arizona, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Graduate Medical Education, University of Arizona College of Medicine-Phoenix, Phoenix, Arizona, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sabati</LastName><ForeName>Arash</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Phoenix Children's Hospital, Phoenix, Arizona, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, Phoenix Children's Hospital, Phoenix, Arizona, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhatia</LastName><ForeName>Rajeev</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Phoenix Children's Hospital, Phoenix, Arizona, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division Chief, Pulmonary, Department of Pediatrics, Phoenix Children's Hospital, Phoenix, Arizona, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PM R</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101491319</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1934-1482</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39324381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmrj.13263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO Coronavirus Disease (COVID&#x2010;19) Dashboard. Accessed February 14, 2024. https://covid19.who.int/region/amro/country/us</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Children and COVID&#x2010;19: State&#x2010;Level Data Report. Accessed January 26, 2024. www.aap.org. https://www.aap.org/en/pages/2019-novel-coronavirus-covid-19-infections/children-and-covid-19-state-level-data-report/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Disease Control and Prevention. Demographic Trends of COVID&#x2010;19 cases and deaths in the US reported to CDC. Accessed February 14, 2024. https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#demographics</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancini D, Brunjes D, Lala A, et al. Use of cardiopulmonary stress testing for patients with unexplained dyspnea post&#x2010;coronavirus disease. JACC Heart Fail. 2021;9(12):927&#x2010;937. doi:10.1016/j.jchf.2021.10.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H, Assaf G, McCorkell L, et al. Characterizing long covid in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clavario P, De Marzo V, Lotti R, et al. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing in covid&#x2010;19 patients at 3 months follow up. Int J Cardiol. 2021;340:113&#x2010;118. doi:10.1016/j.ijcard.2021.07.033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr A, Dannerbeck L, Lange T, et al. Cardiopulmonary exercise pattern in patients with persistent dyspnea after recovering from covid&#x2010;19. Multidiscip Respir Med. 2021;16(1):732. doi:10.4081/mrm.2021.732</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varughese R, Lam G, Brotto A, et al. Reduced exercise tolerance in long covid patients. Am J Resp Crit. 2021;203(9):A4116. doi:10.1164/AJRCCM&#x2010;CONFERENCE.2021.203.1_MEETINGABSTRACTS.A4116</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vonbank K, Lehmann A, Bernitzky D, et al. Predictors of prolonged cardiopulmonary exercise impairment after covid&#x2010;19 infection: a prospective observational study. Front Med. 2021;8:773778. doi:10.3389/fmed.2021.773788</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh I, Joseph P, Heerdt P, et al. Persistent exertional intolerance after covid&#x2010;19: insights from invasive cardiopulmonary exercise testing. Chest. 2022;161(1):54&#x2010;63. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2021.08.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motiejunaite J, Balagny P, Arnoult F, et al. Hyperventilation: a possible explanation for long lasting exercise intolerance in mild covid&#x2010;19 survivors? Front Physiol. 2021;11:614590. doi:10.3389/fphys.2020.614590</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melamed K, Santos M, Oliveira R, et al. Unexplained exertional intolerance associated with impaired systemic oxygen extraction. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019;119(10):2375&#x2010;2389. doi:10.1007/s00421&#x2010;019&#x2010;04222&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fresard I, Genecand L, Altarelli M, et al. Dysfunctional breathing diagnosed by cardiopulmonary exercise testing in long covid patient with persistent dyspnea. BMJ Open Respir Res. 2022;9(1):e001126. doi:10.1136/bmjresp&#x2010;2021&#x2010;001126</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naeije R, Caravita S. CPET for long covid&#x2010;19. JACC Heart Fail. 2022;10(3):214&#x2010;215. doi:10.1016/j.jchf.2022.01.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito S, Principi N, Azzari C, et al. Italian intersociety consensus on management of long covid in children. Ital J Pediatr. 2022;48(1):42. doi:10.1186/s13052&#x2010;022&#x2010;01233&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burstein D, Edelson J, O'Malley S, et al. Cardiopulmonary exercise performance in the pediatric and young adult population before and during the covid&#x2010;19 pandemic. Pediatr Cardiol. 2022;43(8):1832&#x2010;1837. doi:10.1007/s00246&#x2010;022&#x2010;02920&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funk A, Kuppermann N, Florin T, et al. Post&#x2010;covid 19 conditions among children 90&#x2009;days after SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(7):e2223253. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.23253</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behnood S, Shafran R, Bennett S, et al. Persistent symptoms following SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection amongst children and young people: a meta&#x2010;analysis of controlled and uncontrolled studies. J Infect. 2022;84(2):158&#x2010;170. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2021.11.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatia J, Abu&#x2010;Hasan M, Weinberger M. Exercise&#x2010;induced dyspnea in children and adolescents: differential diagnosis. Pediatr Ann. 2019;48(3):e121&#x2010;e127. doi:10.3928/19382359&#x2010;20190219&#x2010;02</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Di Giuda D, Sigfrid L, et al. Evidence of lung perfusion defects and ongoing inflammation in an adolescent with post&#x2010;acute sequelae of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2021;5(9):677&#x2010;680. doi:10.1016/S2352&#x2010;4642(21)00196&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morand A, Campion J, Lepine A, et al. Similar patterns of [18F]&#x2010;FDG brain PET hypometabolism in pediatric and adult patients with long covid: a pediatric case series. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;49(3):913&#x2010;920. doi:10.1007/s00259&#x2010;021&#x2010;05528&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post&#x2010;acute COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):601&#x2010;615. doi:10.1038/s41591&#x2010;021&#x2010;01283&#x2010;z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan P. NICE guideline on long COVID. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9(2):129. doi:10.1016/S2213&#x2010;2600(21)00031&#x2010;X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano J, Murthy S, Marshall J, Relan P, Diaz JV, WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(4):e102&#x2010;e107. doi:10.1016/S1473&#x2010;3099(21)00703&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez&#x2010;Leon S, Wegman&#x2010;Ostrosky T, Perelman C, et al. More than 50 long&#x2010;term effects of COVID&#x2010;19: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analyses. Sci Rep. 2021;11:16144. doi:10.1101/2021.01.27.21250617</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan A, Shetty A, Delanerolle G, et al. A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of long COVID symptoms. Syst Rev. 2023;12:88. doi:10.1186/s13643&#x2010;023&#x2010;02250&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez&#x2010;Leon S, Wigman&#x2010;Ostrosky T, Ayuzo N, et al. Long&#x2010;COVID in children and adolescents: as systematic review and meta&#x2010;analyses. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):9950. doi:10.1038/s41598&#x2010;022&#x2010;13495&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robles N, Nowlen T, Sabati A. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing in children after recovery from multisystem inflammatory syndrome. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023;81(3):318&#x2010;319. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2022.10.031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock M, Bohannon R, Cooper K, et al. A comparative analysis of four protocol for maximal treadmill stress testing. Am Heart J. 1976;92(1):39&#x2010;46. doi:10.1016/s0002&#x2010;8703(76)80401&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons J, Hallstrand T, Mastronarde J, et al. An official American Thoracic Society clinical practice guideline: exercise induced bronchoconstriction. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2013;187(9):1016&#x2010;1027. doi:10.1164/rccm.201303&#x2010;0437ST</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhammar D, Adams&#x2010;Huet B, Babb T. Quantification of cardiorespiratory fitness in children with obesity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(11):2243&#x2010;2250. doi:10.1249/MSS.0000000000002061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu&#x2010;Hasan M, Tannous B, Weinberger M. Exercise&#x2010;induced dyspnea in children and adolescents: if not asthma then what? Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2005;94(3):366&#x2010;371. doi:10.1016/S1081&#x2010;1206(10)60989&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denina M, Lorenzo A, Ronco L, Funiciello E, et al. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing in children six months after COVID&#x2010;19. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2023;58(7):2154&#x2010;2157. doi:10.1002/ppul.26406</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares M, Eggelbusch M, Naddaf E, et al. Skeletal muscle alterations in patients with acute covid&#x2010;19 and post&#x2010;acute sequelae of covid&#x2010;19. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022;12(1):11&#x2010;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Z, De Vries H, Vlarr A, et al. Diaphragm pathology in critically ill patients with covid&#x2010;19 and postmortem findings from 3 medical centers. JAMA Intern Med. 2021;181:122&#x2010;124. doi:10.1002/jcsm.12896</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stierman B, Afful J, Carroll M, et al. National Health, and Nutrition Examination Survey 2017&#x2010;March 2020 Prepandemic Data Files Development of Files and Prevalence Estimates for Selected Outcomes. National Center for Health Statistics; 2021. Accessed February 14, 2024. https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/nhanes/about_nhanes.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatia R. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing for pediatric exercise&#x2010;induced dyspnea especially in patients whose asthma treatment failed. Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2020;124(1):101&#x2010;102. doi:10.1016/j.anai.2019.09.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacavalerie M, Pierre&#x2010;Francois S, Agossou M, et al. Obese patients with long COVID&#x2010;19 display abnormal hyperventilatory response and impaired gas exchange at peak exercise. Future Cardiol. 2022;18:577&#x2010;584. doi:10.2217/fca&#x2010;2022&#x2010;0017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzi A. COVID&#x2010;19 and mitochondrial non&#x2010;coding RNA: new insights from published data. Front Physiol. 2022;4:805005. doi:10.3389/fphys.2021.805005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barash M, Ramalingam V. Post&#x2010;COVID interstitial lung disease and other lung sequelae. Clin Chest Med. 2023;44(2):263&#x2010;277. doi:10.1016/j.ccm.2022.11.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H, Kim B, Chung S, et al. New onset asthma following COVID&#x2010;19 in adults. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2023;11(7):2228&#x2010;2231. doi:10.1016/j.jaip.2023.03.050</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaeilzadeh H, Dashti A, Mortazavi N, et al. Persistent cough, and asthma like symptoms post COVID&#x2010;19 hospitalization in children. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22(1):244. doi:10.1186/s12879&#x2010;022&#x2010;07252&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk G, Beken B, Do&#x11f;an S, et al. Pulmonary function tests in the follow up of children with COVID&#x2010;19. Eur J Pedatr. 2022;181(7):2839&#x2010;2847. doi:10.1007/s00431&#x2010;022&#x2010;04493&#x2010;w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pizzuto D, Buonsenso D, Morello R, et al. Lung perfusion assessment in children with long&#x2010;COVID: a pilot study. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2023;58(7):2059&#x2010;2067. doi:10.1002/ppul.26432</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buosenso D, Morello R, De Rose C, et al. Long term outcome of a child with postcovid condition: role of cardiopulmonary exercise testing and 24&#x2010;h Holter ECG to monitor treatment and response and recovery. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2023;58(10):2944&#x2010;2946. doi:10.1002/ppul.26578</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley S, Karlson E, et al. Development of a definition of postacute sequelae of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection. JAMA. 2023;329(22):1934&#x2010;1946. doi:10.1001/jama.2023.8823</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>