<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38112241</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2689-8381</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JBI evidence synthesis</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JBI Evid Synth</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Definitions and measures of long COVID fatigue in adults: a scoping review protocol.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>481</StartPage><EndPage>488</EndPage><MedlinePgn>481-488</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.11124/JBIES-23-00277</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this scoping review is to investigate how fatigue is defined and measured in adults with long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Following COVID-19 infection, 10% to 20% of individuals experience persisting symptoms for a minimum of 3 months; this is commonly known as long COVID. Fatigue is one of the most prevalent symptoms of long COVID, but there is currently no consistently applied definition of long COVID fatigue. To advance our understanding of long COVID fatigue, we must first identify the current definitions and measures being used to describe and mesure this condition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INCLUSION CRITERIA" NlmCategory="METHODS">This review will consider published and unpublished studies involving adults (&#x2265;18 years) that define and/or measure long COVID fatigue. Papers using quantitative or qualitative designs will be included. Conference abstracts, editorials, and opinion papers will be excluded.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Published studies from January 2020 onwards will be searched for across MEDLINE (Ovid), CINAHL (EBSCOhost), Embase (Ovid), Scopus, PsycINFO (Ovid), Web of Science Core Collection, Epistemonikos, and Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (CENTRAL). Dimensions, Overton, and ProQuest Dissertations and Theses will be searched for unpublished literature. Eligible records will be de-duplicated, and 2 independent reviewers will carry out title, abstract, and full-text screening. A data extraction tool will be pilot tested on a small number of papers, then modified as necessary, with any modifications detailed in the scoping review. Findings will be presented in tables and charts, supported by a narrative summary.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="REVIEW REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Open Science Framework https://osf.io/hnf8z.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 JBI.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>Bethan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Healthcare Sciences, Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pattinson</LastName><ForeName>Rachael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Healthcare Sciences, Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Edwards</LastName><ForeName>Deborah</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wales Centre For Evidence Based Care: A JBI Centre of Excellence, Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dale</LastName><ForeName>Carys</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Healthcare Sciences, Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jenkins</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Healthcare Sciences, Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lande</LastName><ForeName>Helena</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bundy</LastName><ForeName>Christine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Healthcare Sciences, Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davies</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Healthcare Sciences, Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JBI Evid Synth</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101764819</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2689-8381</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012196" MajorTopicYN="N">Review Literature as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>DE is an associate editor of JBI Evidence Synthesis but was not involved in the editorial processing of this manuscript. The other authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38112241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11124/JBIES-23-00277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">02174543-202403000-00015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid - mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ 2021;374:n1648&#x2013;n.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joli J, Buck P, Zipfel S, Stengel A. Post-COVID-19 fatigue: a systematic review. Front Psychiatr 2022;13:947973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Post COVID-19 condition (long COVID) [internet]. WHO; 2022 [cited 2022 Dec 7]. Available from: https://www.who.int/europe/news-room/fact-sheets/item/post-covid-19-condition .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19 [internet]. NICE; 2021 [cited 2020 Dec 18]. Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings G, Monaghan A, Xue F, Duggan E, Romero-Ortu&#xf1;o R. Comprehensive clinical characterisation of brain fog in adults reporting long COVID symptoms. J Clin Med 2022;11(12):3440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK [Statistical bulletin; internet]. ONS; 2023 [cited 2023 Mar 30]. Available from: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/30march2023#cite-this-statistical-bulletin .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey R, DeMars J, Franklin K, Culos-Reed SN, Weatherald J, Wrightson JG. Chronic fatigue and postexertional malaise in people living with long COVID: an observational study. Phys Ther 2022;102(4):pzac005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaime-Lara RB, Koons BC, Matura LA, Hodgson NA, Riegel B. A qualitative metasynthesis of the experience of fatigue across five chronic conditions. J Pain Symptom Manage 2020;59(6):1320&#x2013;1343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hersche R, Roser K, Weise A, Michel G, Barbero M. Fatigue self-management education in persons with disease-related fatigue: a comprehensive review of the effectiveness on fatigue and quality of life. Patient Educ Couns 2022;105(6):1362&#x2013;1378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alotibi WM, Alzeer Z, Alfarhan IF, Alharbi AD, Alhaqbani FA, Almutairi AS, et al. The Incidence of long-term fatigue in patients who achieved remission from COVID-19 at King Abdulaziz Medical City. Cureus 2023;15(1):e33869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanous J, Zero AM, Rice CL. Muscle fatigability and post-acute COVID-19 syndrome: a case study. Physiolog Rep 2022;10(16):e15391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freidin MB, Cheetham N, Duncan EL, Steves CJ, Doores KJ, Malim MH, et al. Long-COVID fatigue is not predicted by pre-pandemic plasma IL-6 levels in mild COVID-19. Inflamm Res 2023;72(5):947&#x2013;953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agergaard J, Leth S, Pedersen TH, Harbo T, Blicher JU, Karlsson P, et al. Myopathic changes in patients with long-term fatigue after COVID-19. Clin Neurophysiol 2021;132(8):1974&#x2013;1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coscia F, Mancinelli R, Gigliotti PV, Checcaglini F, Fano-Illic G. Physical activity effects on muscle fatigue in sport in active adults with long COVID-19: an observational study. Diagnostics (Basel) 2023;13(7).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matias-Guiu JA, Delgado-Alonso C, Diez-Cirarda M, Martinez-Petit A, Oliver-Mas S, Delgado-Alvarez A, et al. Neuropsychological predictors of fatigue in post-COVID syndrome. J Clin Med 2022;11(13).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baum P, Do L, Deterding L, Lier J, Kunis I, Saur D, et al. Cardiac function in relation to functional status and fatigue in patients with post-COVID syndrome. Scientif Rep 2022;12(1):19575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekhael M, Lim CH, El Hajjar AH, Noujaim C, Pottle C, Makan N, et al. Studying the effect of long COVID-19 infection on sleep quality using wearable health devices: observational study. J Med Internet Res 2022;24(7):e38000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkins J, Hires C, Keenan L, Dunne E. Aromatherapy blend of thyme, orange, clove bud, and frankincense boosts energy levels in post-COVID-19 female patients: a randomized, double-blinded, placebo controlled clinical trial. Complement Ther Med 2022;67:102823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM, Almuklass AM, Alenazy M, Alvarez E, Duchateau J. Distinguishing between fatigue and fatigability in multiple sclerosis. Neurorehabil Neural Repair 2021;35(11):960&#x2013;973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens M, Gube M, Chaabene H, Prieske O, Zenon A, Broscheid KC, et al. Fatigue and human performance: an updated framework. Sports Med 2023;53(1):7&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penner I-K. Clinical assessment tools for fatigue. Fatigue in multiple sclerosis: background, clinic, diagnostic, therapy. 1st ed. Springer International Publishing; 2023. p.109&#x2013;121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matias-Guiu JA, Delgado-Alonso C, Diez-Cirarda M, Martinez-Petit A, Oliver-Mas S, Delgado-Alvarez A, et al. Neuropsychological predictors of fatigue in post-COVID syndrome. J Clin Med 2022;11(13).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik H, Shao S, Tran KC, Wong AW, Russell JA, Khor E, et al. Evaluating fatigue in patients recovering from COVID-19: validation of the fatigue severity scale and single item screening questions. Health Qual Life Outcomes 2022;20(1):170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Sayed S, Shokry D, Gomaa SM. Post-COVID-19 fatigue and anhedonia: a cross-sectional study and their correlation to post-recovery period. Neuropsychopharmacol Rep 2021;41(1):50&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabria M, Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;nchez C, Grunden N, Pons C, Arroyo JA, G&#xf3;mez-Anson B, et al. Post-COVID-19 fatigue: the contribution of cognitive and neuropsychiatric symptoms. J Neurol 2022;269(8):3990&#x2013;3999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Sousa KCA, Gardel DG, Lopes AJ. Postural balance and its association with functionality and quality of life in non&#x2010;hospitalized patients with post&#x2010;acute COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome. Physiother Res Int 2022;27(4):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cash A, Kaufman DL. Oxaloacetate treatment for mental and physical fatigue in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) and long-COVID fatigue patients: a non-randomized controlled clinical trial. J Translation Med 2022;20(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vet HCW, Terwee CB, Mokkink LB, Knol DL. Measurement in medicine: a practical guide. Cambridge University Press; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters MDJ, Godfrey C, McInerney P, Munn Z, Tricco AC, Khalil H. Chapter 11: Scoping reviews. In: Aromataris E, Munn Z, editors. JBI Manual for Evidence Synthesis [internet] JBI; 2020 [cited 2023 Aug 1]. Available from: https://synthesismanual.jbi.global .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt P, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 2021;372:n71.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>