<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36609778</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The pattern of cytokines expression and dynamic changes of renal function at 6 months in patients with Omicron&#xa0;COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e28477</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e28477</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.28477</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To analyze the dynamic changes of renal function longitudinally and investigate the cytokine profiles at 6 months in patients with Omicron COVID-19.&#xa0;Forty-seven patients with a proven diagnosis of Omicron COVID-19 from January to February 2022 attended a 6-month follow-up after discharge at Tianjin First Central Hospital. The demographic parameters, clinical features, and laboratory indexes were collected during hospitalization and 6 months after discharge. The serum cytokine levels at 6 months were also assessed. Patients were grouped according to with or without kidney involvement at admission.&#xa0;The levels of serum creatinine and estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) were all normal both in the hospital and at follow-up. Whereas, compared with renal function in the hospital, serum creatinine levels at 6 months increased remarkably; meanwhile, eGFR decreased significantly in all patients. The serum levels of&#xa0;interleukin&#xa0;(IL)-2, IL-4, IL-5, IL-6, IL-10, and&#xa0;TNF-&#x3b1; and IFN-&#x3b3; significantly decreased and TGF-&#x3b2; remarkably increased in the kidney involvement group. The serum levels of IL-2 and IL-5 were positively correlated with age; contrarily, TGF-&#x3b2; showed a negative correlation with aging. The younger was an independent risk factor of the higher TGF-&#x3b2; levels. Omicron patients showed a decline in renal function at follow-up, reflecting the trend of CKD. Serum cytokine profiles were characterized with the majority of cytokines decreased and TGF-&#x3b2; increased in the kidney involvement group; the latter may be used as a sign of CKD. The tendency of CKD is one of the manifestations of long COVID and deserves attention.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teng</LastName><ForeName>Lanbo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8958-6324</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Tianjin First Center Hospital, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission (NHC) Key Laboratory for Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Center Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Xinyuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Tianjin First Center Hospital, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission (NHC) Key Laboratory for Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Center Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Miaomiao</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Tianjin First Center Hospital, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission (NHC) Key Laboratory for Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Center Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Yingying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Tianjin First Center Hospital, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission (NHC) Key Laboratory for Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Center Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Ge</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Tianjin Medical University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Wenxiu</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Tianjin First Center Hospital, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission (NHC) Key Laboratory for Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Center Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Zhongyang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission (NHC) Key Laboratory for Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Center Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Organ Transplant Center, Tianjin First Center Hospital, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016207">Cytokines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>AYI8EX34EU</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003404">Creatinine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015848">Interleukin-5</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016212">Transforming Growth Factor beta</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016207" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003404" MajorTopicYN="N">Creatinine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015848" MajorTopicYN="N">Interleukin-5</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016212" MajorTopicYN="N">Transforming Growth Factor beta</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005919" MajorTopicYN="N">Glomerular Filtration Rate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051436" MajorTopicYN="Y">Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CKD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Omicron</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cytokines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">renal function</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36609778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Hu B, Guo H, Zhou P, Shi ZL. Characteristics of SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2021;19(3):141-154. doi:10.1038/s41579-020-00459-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen PA, Olsen RJ, Long SW, et al. Signals of significantly increased vaccine breakthrough, decreased hospitalization rates, and less severe disease in patients with Coronavirus disease 2019 caused by the Omicron variant of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 in Houston, Texas. Am J Pathol. 2022;192(4):642-652. doi:10.1016/j.ajpath.2022.01.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah F, Myers J, Basu D, et al. Decreased severity of disease during the first global omicron variant covid-19 outbreak in a large hospital in Tshwane, South Africa. Int J Infect Dis. 2022;116:38-42. doi:10.1016/j.ijid.2021.12.357</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyberg T, Ferguson NM, Nash SG, et al. Comparative analysis of the risks of hospitalisation and death associated with SARS-CoV-2 omicron (B.1.1.529) and delta (B.1.617.2) variants in England: a&#xa0;cohort study. Lancet. 2022;399(10332):1303-1312. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(22)00462-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan L, Chaudhary K, Saha A, et al. AKI in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;32(1):151-160. doi:10.1681/ASN.2020050615</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta S, Coca SG, Chan L, et al. AKI treated with renal replacement therapy in critically ill patients with COVID-19. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;32(1):161-176. doi:10.1681/ASN.2020060897</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nogueira S&#xc1;R, Oliveira SCS, Carvalho AFM, et al. Renal changes and acute kidney injury in covid-19:a systematic review. Rev Assoc Med Bras. 2020;66(suppl 2):112-117. doi:10.1590/1806-9282.66.S2.112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inciardi RM, Chandra A. Editorial commentary: long COVID-19: a tangled web of lungs, heart, mind, and gender. Trends Cardiovasc Med. 2022;32(1):18-19. doi:10.1016/j.tcm.2021.10.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai AD, Lavelle M, Boursiquot BC, Wan EY. Long-term complications of COVID-19. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2022;322(1):C1-C11. doi:10.1152/ajpcell.00375.2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nature Med. 2021;27(4):601-615. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbarialiabad H, Taghrir MH, Abdollahi A, et al. Long COVID, a comprehensive systematic scoping review. Infection. 2021;49(6):1163-1186. doi:10.1007/s15010-021-01666-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francisco &#xc1;M, Fresnedo GF. Long COVID-19 renal disease: a present medical need for nephrology. Nefrologia. 2022;851931. doi:10.1016/j.nefro.2022.04.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Cai M, Xie Y, Gibson AK, Maddukuri G, Al-Aly Z. Acute kidney injury in a national cohort of hospitalized US veterans with COVID-19. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020;16(1):14-25. doi:10.2215/CJN.09610620</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594(7862):259-264. doi:10.1038/s41586-021-03553-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funke-Chambour M, Feldmeyer L, Hoepner R, et al. The long-COVID syndrome-a new clinical picture after COVID-19 infection. Praxis (Bern 1994). 2021;110(7):377-382. doi:10.1024/1661-8157/a003678</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaundal RK, Kalvala AK, Kumar A. Neurological implications of COVID-19: role of redox imbalance and mitochondrial dysfunction. Mol Neurobiol. 2021;58(9):4575-4587. doi:10.1007/s12035-021-02412-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization.&#xa0;Laboratory Testing Strategy Recommendations for COVID-19: Interim Guidance, 21 March&#xa0;2020. World Health Organization; 2020. https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/331509</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Health Commission of China.&#xa0;Guideline of Management of COVID-19. 8th trial ed. National Health Commission of China. http://www.nhc.gov.cn/yzygj/s7653p/202002/3b09b894ac9b4204a79db5b8912d4440.shtml</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng L, Sun N, Chang W. Analysis of age-based stratified renal involvement in Tianjin first batch of 430 patients with Omicron variant of novel coronavirus infection. Zhonghua wei zhong bing ji jiu yi xue. 2022;34(5):465-470. doi:10.3760/cma.j.cn121430-20220328-00303</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Long J, Jiang W, et al. Trends in chronic kidney disease in China. N Engl J Med. 2016;375(9):905-906. doi:10.1056/NEJMc1602469</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins-Juarez SY, Qian L, King KL, et al. Outcomes for patients with COVID-19 and acute kidney injury: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Kidney Int Rep. 2020;5:1149-1160. doi:10.1016/j.ekir.2020.06.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver SA, Beaubien-Souligny W, Shah PS, et al. The prevalence of acute kidney injury in patients hospitalized with COVID-19 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Kidney Med. 2021;3(1):83-98. doi:10.1016/j.xkme.2020.11.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220-232. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shivani F, Kumari N, Bai P, et al. Long-term symptoms of COVID-19: one-year follow-up study. Cureus. 2022;14(6):25937. doi:10.7759/cureus.25937</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omer D, Pleniceanu O, Gnatek Y, et al. Human kidney spheroids and monolayers provide insights into SARS-CoV-2 renal interactions. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;32(9):2242-2254. doi:10.1681/ASN.2020111546</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen J, Reimer KC, Nagai JS, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infects the human kidney and drives fibrosis in kidney organoids. Cell Stem Cell. 2022;29(2):217-231. doi:10.1016/j.stem.2021.12.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang KC, Imig JD, Kalantar-Zadeh K, Gupta A. Kidney in the net of acute and long-haul coronavirus disease 2019: a potential role for lipid mediators in causing renal injury and fibrosis. Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens. 2022;31(1):36-46. doi:10.1097/MNH.0000000000000750</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen SF, Ho YC. SARS-CoV-2: a storm is raging. J Clin Invest. 2020;130(5):2202-2205. doi:10.1172/JCI137647</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, et al. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020;395(10223):497-506. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michot JM, Albiges L, Chaput N, et al. Tocilizumab, an anti-IL-6 receptor antibody, to treat COVID-19-related respiratory failure: a case report. Ann Oncol. 2020;31(7):961-964. doi:10.1016/j.annonc.2020.03.300</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Mauro G, Scavone C, Rafaniello C, Rossi F, Capuano A. SARS-Cov-2 infection: response of human immune system and possible implications for the rapid test and treatment. Int Immunopharmacol. 2020;84:106519. doi:10.1016/j.intimp.2020.106519</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Xu Y, Zhang X, et al. Leptin correlates with monocytes activation and severe condition in COVID-19 patients. J Leukoc Biol. 2021;110(1):9-20. doi:10.1002/JLB.5HI1020-704R</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafer MM, El-Mahallawy HA, Ashour HM. Severe COVID-19 and sepsis: immune pathogenesis and laboratory markers. Microorganisms. 2021;9(1):159. doi:10.3390/microorganisms9010159</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Li S, Liu J, et al. Longitudinal characteristics of lymphocyte responses and cytokine profiles in the peripheral blood of SARS-CoV-2 infected patients. EBioMedicine. 2020;55:102763. doi:10.1016/j.ebiom.2020.102763</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Wu D, Guo W, et al. Clinical and immunological features of severe and moderate coronavirus disease 2019. J Clin Invest. 2020;130:2620-2629. doi:10.1172/JCI137244</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polidoro RB, Hagan RS, de Santis Santiago R, Schmidt NW. Overview: systemic inflammatory response derived from lung injury caused by SARS-CoV-2 infection explains severe outcomes in COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2020;11:1626. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2020.01626</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Zhang R, He G. Hematological findings in coronavirus disease 2019: indications of progression of disease. Ann Hematol. 2020;99(7):1421-1428. doi:10.1007/s00277-020-04103-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechner-Scott J, Levy M, Hawkes C, Yeh A, Giovannoni G. Long COVID or post COVID-19 syndrome. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2021;55:103268. doi:10.1016/j.msard.2021.103268</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Queiroz MAF, Neves PFM, Lima SS, et al. Cytokine profiles associated with acute COVID-19 and long COVID-19 syndrome. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2022;12:922422. doi:10.3389/fcimb.2022.922422</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colarusso C, Maglio A, Terlizzi M, et al. Post-COVID-19 patients who develop lung fibrotic-like changes have lower circulating levels of IFN-&#x3b2; but higher levels of IL-1&#x3b1; and TGF-&#x3b2;. Biomedicines. 2021;9(12):1931. doi:10.3390/biomedicines9121931</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu ZJ, Xu J, Yin JM, et al. Lower circulating interferon-gamma is a risk factor for lung fibrosis in COVID-19 patients. Front Immunol. 2020;11:585647. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2020.585647</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dan JM, Mateus J, Kato Y, et al. Immunological memory to SARS-CoV-2 assessed for up to 8 months after infection. Science. 2021;371(6529):eabf4063. doi:10.1126/science.abf4063</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BK, Guevara-Coto J, Yogendra R, et al. Immune-based prediction of COVID-19 severity and chronicity decoded using machine learning. Front Immunol. 2021;12:700782. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.700782</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramakrishnan RK, Kashour T, Hamid Q, Halwani R, Tleyjeh IM. Unraveling the mystery surrounding post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2021;12:686029. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.686029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malmstr&#xf6;m J, Lindberg H, Lindberg C, et al. Transforming growth factor-&#x3b2;1 specifically induce proteins involved in the myofibroblast contractile apparatus. Mol Cell Proteomics. 2004;3(5):466-477. doi:10.1074/mcp.M300108-MCP200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maranatha D, Hasan H, Bakhtiar A, Widyoningroem A, Aryati. Association of TNF-&#x3b1;, TGF-&#x3b2;1, amphiregulin, IL-2, and EGFR with pulmonary fibrosis in COVID-19. J Infect Public Health. 2022;15(10):1072-1075. doi:10.1016/j.jiph.2022.08.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Klein SL, Garibaldi BT, et al. Aging in COVID-19: vulnerability, immunity and intervention. Ageing Res Rev. 2021;65:101205. doi:10.1016/j.arr.2020.101205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Q, Zhu Z, Tan C, et al. Changes of serum IL-10, IL-1&#x3b2;, IL-6, MCP-1, TNF-&#x3b1;, IP-10 and IL-4 in COVID-19 patients. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75(9):e14462. doi:10.1111/ijcp.14462</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franceschi C, Campisi J. Chronic inflammation (inflammaging) and its potential contribution to age-associated diseases. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2014;69(suppl 1):S4-S9. doi:10.1093/gerona/glu057</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Iturbe B, Pons H, Quiroz Y, Johnson RJ. The immunological basis of hypertension. Am J Hypertens. 2014;27(11):1327-1337. doi:10.1093/ajh/hpu142</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>