<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34653099</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-9847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2022 Mar-Apr 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nursing research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nurs Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-COVID-19 Syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>164</StartPage><EndPage>174</EndPage><MedlinePgn>164-174</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/NNR.0000000000000565</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Since the beginning of the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic, many individuals have reported persistent symptoms and/or complications lasting beyond 4 weeks, which is now called post-COVID-19 syndrome. SARS-CoV-2 is a respiratory coronavirus that causes COVID-19, and injury to the lungs is expected; however, there is often damage to numerous other cells and organs, leading to an array of symptoms. These long-term symptoms occur in patients with mild to severe COVID-19; currently, there is limited literature on the potential pathophysiological mechanisms of this syndrome.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">The purpose of this integrative review is to summarize and evaluate post-COVID-19 syndrome from a biological perspective.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">An integrative review was conducted using Whittemore and Knafl's methodology for literature published through August 30, 2021. The PubMed, CINAHL, and Web of Science databases were searched for articles published as of August 30, 2021, using combinations of the following key words: post-COVID-19 syndrome, post-SARS-CoV-2, long COVID-19, long COVID-19 syndrome, and pathophysiology of post-COVID-19. Data were analyzed using the constant comparison method.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The search generated 27,929 articles. After removing duplicates and screening abstracts and full-text reviews, we retained 68 articles and examined 54 specific articles related to the pathophysiology of post-COVID-19 syndrome. The findings from our review indicated that there were four pathophysiological categories involved: virus-specific pathophysiological variations, oxidative stress, immunologic abnormalities, and inflammatory damage.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Although studies examining the pathophysiology of post-COVID-19 syndrome are still relatively few, there is growing evidence that this is a complex and multifactorial syndrome involving virus-specific pathophysiological variations that affect many mechanisms but specifically oxidative stress, immune function, and inflammation. Further research is needed to elucidate the pathophysiology, pathogenesis, and longer term consequences involved in post-COVID-19 syndrome.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pierce</LastName><ForeName>Janet D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7100-7865</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Qiuhua</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1236-0244</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cintron</LastName><ForeName>Samantha A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8120-9687</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hiebert</LastName><ForeName>John B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8841-0378</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Nurs Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0376404</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0029-6562</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008403" MajorTopicYN="N">Mass Screening</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34653099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NNR.0000000000000565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006199-900000000-99627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amenta E. M., Spallone A., Rodriguez-Barradas M. C., El Sahly H. M., Atmar R. L., Kulkarni P. A. (2020). Postacute COVID-19: An overview and approach to classification. Open Forum Infectious Diseases, 7, ofaa509. 10.1093/ofid/ofaa509</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ofid/ofaa509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astuti I., Ysrafil (2020). Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2): An overview of viral structure and host response. Diabetes and Metabolic Syndrome: Clinical Research and Reviews, 14, 407&#x2013;412. 10.1016/j.dsx.2020.04.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsx.2020.04.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolourani S., Brenner M., Wang P. (2021). The interplay of DAMPs, TLR4, and proinflammatory cytokines in pulmonary fibrosis. Journal of Molecular Medicine, 99, 1373&#x2013;1384. 10.1007/s00109-021-02113-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00109-021-02113-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carfi A., Bernabei R., Landi F. (2020). Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA, 324, 603&#x2013;605. 10.1001/jama.2020.12603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.12603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. (2021). Post-COVID conditions: Information for healthcare providers. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-conditions.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandrashekara S., Jaladhar P., Paramshetti S., Ramachandran V., Nizar S. F., Kori D. (2020). Post COVID inflammation syndrome: Different manifestations caused by the virus. Journal of the Association of Physicians of India, 68, 33&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Liu Q., Guo D. (2020). Emerging coronaviruses: Genome structure, replication, and pathogenesis. Journal of Medical Virology, 92, 418&#x2013;423. 10.1002/jmv.25681</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.25681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra V., Flanders S. A., O&#x2019;Malley M., Malani A. N., Prescott H. C. (2021). Sixty-day outcomes among patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Annals of Internal Medicine, 174, 576&#x2013;578. 10.7326/M20-5661</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M20-5661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Codo A. C., Davanzo G. G., Monteiro L. B., de Souza G. F., Muraro S. P., Virgilio-da-Silva J. V., Prodonoff J. S., Carregari V. C., de Biagi Junior C. A. O., Crunfli F., Jimenez Restrepo J. L., Vendramini P. H., Reis-de-Oliveira G., Bispo Dos Santos K., Toledo-Teixeira D. A., Parise P. L., Martini M. C., Marques R. E., Carmo H. R., Moraes-Vieira P. M. (2020). Elevated glucose levels favor SARS-CoV-2 infection and monocyte response through a HIF-1alpha/glycolysis-dependent axis. Cell Metabolism, 32, 437&#x2013;446.e5. 10.1016/j.cmet.2020.07.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2020.07.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dan J. M., Mateus J., Kato Y., Hastie K. M., Yu E. D., Faliti C. E., Grifoni A., Ramirez S. I., Haupt S., Frazier A., Nakao C., Rayaprolu V., Rawlings S. A., Peters B., Krammer F., Simon V., Saphire E. O., Smith D. M., Weiskopf D., Crotty S. (2021). Immunological memory to SARS-CoV-2 assessed for up to 8 months after infection. Science, 371, eabf4063. 10.1126/science.abf4063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abf4063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derouiche S. (2020). Oxidative stress associated with SARS-Cov-2 (COVID-19) increases the severity of the lung disease&#x2014;A systematic review. Journal of Infectious Diseases and Epidemiology, 6. 10.23937/2474-3658/1510121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23937/2474-3658/1510121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eze B., Starkweather A. (2021). COVID-19 pain and comorbid symptoms. Topics in Pain Management, 36, 1&#x2013;7. 10.1097/01.TPM.0000753136.60432.2f</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.TPM.0000753136.60432.2f</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gedefaw L., Ullah S., Leung P. H. M., Cai Y., Yip S.-P., Huang C.-L. (2021). Inflammasome activation-induced hypercoagulopathy: Impact on cardiovascular dysfunction triggered in COVID-19 patients. Cell, 10, 916. 10.3390/cells10040916</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells10040916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T., Knight M., A&#x2019;Court C., Buxton M., Husain L. (2020). Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ, 370, m3026. 10.1136/bmj.m3026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m3026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H., Callaway J. B., Ting J. P.-Y. (2015). Inflammasomes: Mechanism of action, role in disease, and therapeutics. Nature Medicine, 21, 677&#x2013;687. 10.1038/nm.3893</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.3893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawker S., Payne S., Kerr C., Hardey M., Powell J. (2002). Appraising the evidence: Reviewing disparate data systematically. Qualitative Health Research, 12, 1284&#x2013;1299. 10.1177/1049732302238251</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732302238251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaundal R. K., Kalvala A. K., Kumar A. (2021). Neurological implications of COVID-19: Role of redox imbalance and mitochondrial dysfunction. Molecular Neurobiology, 58, 4575&#x2013;4587. 10.1007/s12035-021-02412-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-021-02412-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levison M. E. (2020). Commentary: What we know so far about post-COVID syndrome. Merck Manual Consumer Version. https://www.merckmanuals.com/home/news/editorial/2020/09/24/19/01/post-covid-syndrome</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Zhang R., He G. (2020). Hematological findings in coronavirus disease 2019: Indications of progression of disease. Annals of Hematology, 99, 1421&#x2013;1428. 10.1007/s00277-020-04103-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00277-020-04103-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallakpour S., Azadi E., Hussain C. M. (2021). Protection, disinfection, and immunization for healthcare during the COVID-19 pandemic: Role of natural and synthetic macromolecules. Science of the Total Environment, 776, 145989. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.145989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.145989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuishi Y., Mathis B. J., Shimojo N., Subrina J., Okubo N., Inoue Y. (2021). Severe COVID-19 infection associated with endothelial dysfunction induces multiple organ dysfunction: A review of therapeutic interventions. Biomedicine, 9, 279. 10.3390/biomedicines9030279</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines9030279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misra D. P., Agarwal V., Gasparyan A. Y., Zimba O. (2020). Rheumatologists&#x2019; perspective on coronavirus disease 19 (COVID-19) and potential therapeutic targets. Clinical Rheumatology, 39, 2055&#x2013;2062. 10.1007/s10067-020-05073-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10067-020-05073-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miwa M., Nakajima M., Kaszynski R. H., Hamada S., Ando H., Nakano T., Shirokawa M., Goto H. (2021). Abnormal pulmonary function and imaging studies in critical COVID-19 survivors at 100 days after the onset of symptoms. Respiratory Investigation, 59, 614&#x2013;621. 10.1016/j.resinv.2021.05.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resinv.2021.05.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D., Liberati A., Tetzlaff J., Altman D. G.; Prisma Group (2009). Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses: The PRISMA statement. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology, 62, 1006&#x2013;1012. 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2009.06.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2009.06.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murgolo N., Therien A. G., Howell B., Klein D., Koeplinger K., Lieberman L. A., Adam G. C., Flynn J., McKenna P., Swaminathan G., Hazuda D. J., Olsen D. B. (2021). SARS-CoV-2 tropism, entry, replication, and propagation: Considerations for drug discovery and development. PLoS Pathogens, 17, e1009225. 10.1371/journal.ppat.1009225</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1009225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A., Sehgal K., Gupta A., Madhavan M. V., McGroder C., Stevens J. S., Cook J. R., Nordvig A. S., Shalev D., Sehrawat T. S., Ahluwalia N., Bikdeli B., Dietz D., Der-Nigoghossian C., Liyanage-Don N., Rosner G. F., Bernstein E. J., Mohan S., Beckley A. A., Wan E. Y. (2021). Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nature Medicine, 27, 601&#x2013;615. 10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onishi M., Yamano K., Sato M., Matsuda N., Okamoto K. (2021). Molecular mechanisms and physiological functions of mitophagy. EMBO Journal, 40, e104705. 10.15252/embj.2020104705</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15252/embj.2020104705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oronsky B., Larson C., Hammond T. C., Oronsky A., Kesari S., Lybeck M., Reid T. R. (2021). A review of persistent post-COVID syndrome (PPCS). Clinical Reviews in Allergy &amp; Immunology, 1&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s12016-021-08848-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12016-021-08848-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson B. K., Guevara-Coto J., Yogendra R., Francisco E. B., Long E., Pise A., Rodrigues H., Parikh P., Mora J., Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez R. A. (2021). Immune-based prediction of COVID-19 severity and chronicity decoded using machine learning. Frontiers in Immunology, 12, 700782. 10.3389/fimmu.2021.700782</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.700782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavli A., Theodoridou M., Maltezou H. C. (2021). Post-COVID syndrome: Incidence, clinical spectrum, and challenges for primary healthcare professionals. Archives of Medical Research, 52, 575&#x2013;581. 10.1016/j.arcmed.2021.03.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arcmed.2021.03.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramakrishnan R. K., Kashour T., Hamid Q., Halwani R., Tleyjeh I. M. (2021). Unraveling the mystery surrounding post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Frontiers in Immunology, 12, 686029. 10.3389/fimmu.2021.686029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.686029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano J. B., Waterer G., Pe&#xf1;alvo J. L., Rello J. (2021). Nefer, Sinuhe and clinical research assessing post COVID-19 condition. European Respiratory Journal, 57, 2004423. 10.1183/13993003.04423-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.04423-2020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugimoto M. A., Sousa L. P., Pinho V., Perretti M., Teixeira M. M. (2016). Resolution of inflammation: What controls its onset?Frontiers in Immunology, 7, 160. 10.3389/fimmu.2016.00160</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2016.00160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walls A. C., Park Y. J., Tortorici M. A., Wall A., McGuire A. T., Veesler D. (2020). Structure, function, and antigenicity of the SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein. Cell, 181, 281&#x2013;292.e6. 10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.058</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West A. P., Shadel G. S., Ghosh S. (2011). Mitochondria in innate immune responses. Nature Reviews Immunology, 11, 389&#x2013;402. 10.1038/nri2975</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nri2975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteside T. L. (2021). Procoagulant activity of extracellular vesicles in plasma of patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection. eBioMedicine, 68, 103411. 10.1016/j.ebiom.2021.103411</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2021.103411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittemore R. (2005). Combining evidence in nursing research: Methods and implications. Nursing Research, 54, 56&#x2013;62. 10.1097/00006199-200501000-00008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00006199-200501000-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittemore R., Knafl K. (2005). The integrative review: Updated methodology. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 52, 546&#x2013;553. 10.1111/j.1365-2648.2005.03621.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2648.2005.03621.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J., Liang B., Chen C., Wang H., Fang Y., Shen S., Yang X., Wang B., Chen L., Chen Q., Wu Y., Liu J., Yang X., Li W., Zhu B., Zhou W., Wang H., Li S., Lu S., Zheng X. (2021). SARS-CoV-2 infection induces sustained humoral immune responses in convalescent patients following symptomatic COVID-19. Nature Communications, 12, 1813. 10.1038/s41467-021-22034-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-22034-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q., Zhou L., Sun X., Yan Z., Hu C., Wu J., Xu L., Li X., Liu H., Yin P., Li K., Zhao J., Li Y., Wang X., Li Y., Zhang Q., Xu G., Chen H. (2017). Altered lipid metabolism in recovered SARS patients twelve years after infection. Scientific Reports, 7, 9110. 10.1038/s41598-017-09536-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-09536-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>