<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38588073</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5948</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of occupational and environmental medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Occup Environ Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID-ACOEM Guidance Statement.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>349</StartPage><EndPage>357</EndPage><MedlinePgn>349-357</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JOM.0000000000003059</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Persistent symptoms are common after acute COVID-19, often referred to as long COVID. Long COVID may affect the ability to perform activities of daily living, including work. Long COVID occurs more frequently in those with severe acute COVID-19. This guidance statement reviews the pathophysiology of severe acute COVID-19 and long COVID and provides pragmatic approaches to long COVID symptoms, syndromes, and conditions in the occupational setting. Disability laws and workers' compensation are also addressed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 American College of Occupational and Environmental Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stave</LastName><ForeName>Gregg M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7528-9556</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Division of Occupational and Environmental Medicine, Duke University, Durham, NC (G.M.S.); Department of Environmental Medicine and Public Health, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, NY (I.N.); and Division of Preventive Medicine, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada (Q.D.-M.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nabeel</LastName><ForeName>Ismail</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6909-1970</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Durand-Moreau</LastName><ForeName>Quentin</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1168-4201</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Occup Environ Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9504688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1076-2752</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000203" MajorTopicYN="N">Activities of Daily Living</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014942" MajorTopicYN="N">Workers' Compensation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38588073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JOM.0000000000003059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00043764-202404000-00013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jones JM, Manrique IM, Stone MS, et al. Estimates of SARS-CoV-2 seroprevalence and incidence of primary SARS-CoV-2 infections among blood donors, by COVID-19 vaccination status&#x2014;United States, April 2021-September 2022. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2023;72:601&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liew F, Efstathiou C, Fontanella S, et al. Large scale phenotyping of long COVID inflammation reveals mechanistic subtypes of disease. medRxiv. June 12, 2023. doi:10.1101/2023.06.07.23291077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.06.07.23291077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Hou C, Shen Y, et al. Two-year health outcomes in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors in China. JAMA Netw Open 2022;5:e2231790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi B, Sudry T, Flaks-Manov N, et al. Long covid outcomes at one year after mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: nationwide cohort study. BMJ 2023;380:e072529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosworth ML, Shenhuy B, Walker AS, et al. Risk of new-onset long COVID following reinfection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2: a community-based cohort study. Open Forum Infect Dis 2023;10:ofad493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Acute and postacute sequelae associated with SARS-CoV-2 reinfection. Nat Med 2022;28:2398&#x2013;2405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: let patients help define long-lasting COVID symptoms. Nature 2020;586:170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera JE, Niehaus WN, Whiteson J, et al. Multidisciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of fatigue in postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) patients. PM R 2021;13:1027&#x2013;1043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Post-COVID conditions: information for healthcare providers. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-conditions.html. Accessed October 16, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV; WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis 2022;22:e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawal G, Yadav S, Kumar R. Post-intensive care syndrome: an overview. J Transl Int Med 2017;5:90&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Center for Health Statistics. U.S. Census Bureau, Household Pulse Survey, 2022&#x2013;2023. Long COVID. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/covid19/pulse/long-covid.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford ND, Slaughter D, Edwards D, et al. Long COVID and significant activity limitation among adults, by age&#x2014;United States, June 1&#x2013;13, 2022, to June 7&#x2013;19, 2023. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2023;72:866&#x2013;870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach K. New data shows long COVID is keeping as many as 4 million people out of work. Brookings August 24, 2022. Available at: https://www.brookings.edu/articles/new-data-shows-long-covid-is-keeping-as-many-as-4-million-people-out-of-work/. Accessed August 14, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosn J, Piroth L, Epaulard O, et al. Persistent COVID-19 symptoms are highly prevalent 6 months after hospitalization: results from a large prospective cohort. Clin Microbiol Infect 2021;27:1041.e1&#x2013;1041.e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Descatha A, Evanoff BA, Fadel M. Post-COVID condition or &#x201c;long COVID,&#x201d; return-to work, and occupational health research. Scand J Work Environ Health 2023;49:165&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nittas V, Gao M, West EA, et al. Long COVID through a public health lens: an umbrella review. Public Health Rev 2022;43:1604501. doi:10.3389/phrs.2022.1604501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/phrs.2022.1604501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trades Union Congress. Workers&#x2019; experience of Long COVID. Joint report by the TUC and Long COVID support. March 27, 2023. Available at: https://www.tuc.org.uk/research-analysis/reports/workers-experience-long-covid. Accessed July 12, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohn L, Dauvrin M, Detollenaere J, et al. Long COVID and return to work: a qualitative study. Occup Med (Lond) 2024;74:29&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlis RH, Lunz Trujillo K, Safarpour A, et al. Association of post-COVID-19 condition symptoms and employment status. JAMA Netw Open 2023;6:e2256152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaber TAK, Ashish A, Unsworth A. Persistent post-COVID symptoms in healthcare workers. Occup Med (Lond) 2021;71:144&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodore DA, Branche AR, Zhang L, et al. Clinical and demographic factors associated with COVID-19, severe COVID-19, and SARS-CoV-2 infection in adults: a secondary cross-protocol analysis of 4 randomized clinical trials. JAMA Netw Open 2023;6:e2323349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett TD, Moffitt RA, Hajagos JG, et al. Clinical characterization and prediction of clinical severity of SARS-CoV-2 infection among US adults using data from the US National COVID Cohort Collaborative. JAMA Netw Open 2021;4:e2116901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao M, Piernas C, Astbury NM, et al. Associations between body-mass index and COVID-19 severity in 6.9 million people in England: a prospective, community-based, cohort study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2021;9:350&#x2013;359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popkin BM, Du S, Green WD, et al. Individuals with obesity and COVID-19: a global perspective on the epidemiology and biological relationships. Obes Rev 2020;21:e13128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman JD, Robinson PC, Uldrick TS, Ljungman P. COVID-19 in immunocompromised populations: implications for prognosis and repurposing of immunotherapies. J Immunother Cancer 2021;9:e002630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Berger NA, Xu R. Risks of SARS-CoV-2 breakthrough infection and hospitalization in fully vaccinated patients with multiple myeloma. JAMA Netw Open 2021;4:e2137575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Berger NA, Xu R. When hematologic malignancies meet COVID-19 in the United States: infections, death and disparities. Blood Rev 2021;47:100775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pairo-Castineira E, Rawlik K, Bretherick AD, et al. GWAS and meta-analysis identifies 49 genetic variants underlying critical COVID-19. Nature 2023;617:764&#x2013;768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Bastard P, Liu Z, et al. Inborn errors of type I IFN immunity in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science 2020;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastard P, Rosen LB, Zhang Q, et al. Autoantibodies against type I IFNs in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science 2020;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi H, Zuo Y, Navaz S, et al. Endothelial cell-activating antibodies in COVID-19. Arthritis Rheumatol 2022;74:1132&#x2013;1138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Y, Estes SK, Ali RA, et al. Prothrombotic autoantibodies in serum from patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Sci Transl Med 2020;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guarnieri JW, Dybas JM, Fazelinia H, et al. Core mitochondrial genes are down-regulated during SARS-CoV-2 infection of rodent and human hosts. Sci Transl Med 2023;15:eabq1533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J, Lin WW, Zucker JE, et al. Inflammation and mortality in COVID-19 hospitalized patients with and without type 2 diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2022;107:e1961&#x2013;e1968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grobbelaar LM, Venter C, Vlok M, et al. SARS-CoV-2 spike protein S1 induces fibrin(ogen) resistant to fibrinolysis: implications for microclot formation in COVID-19. Biosci Rep 2021;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biering SB, Gomes de Sousa FT, Tjang LV, et al. SARS-CoV-2 Spike triggers barrier dysfunction and vascular leak via integrins and TGF-&#x3b2; signaling. Nat Commun 2022;13:7630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackermann M, Verleden SE, Kuehnel M, et al. Pulmonary vascular endothelialitis, thrombosis, and angiogenesis in COVID-19. N Engl J Med 2020;383:120&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei Y, Zhang J, Schiavon CR, et al. SARS-CoV-2 spike protein impairs endothelial function via downregulation of ACE 2. Circ Res 2021;128:1323&#x2013;1326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vassiliou AG, Vrettou CS, Keskinidou C, Dimopoulou I, Kotanidou A, Orfanos SE. Endotheliopathy in acute COVID-19 and long COVID. Int J Mol Sci 2023;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis PB, Xu R. COVID-19 and incident diabetes-recovery is not so sweet after all. JAMA Netw Open 2023;6:e238872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheong JG, Ravishankar A, Sharma S, et al. Epigenetic memory of coronavirus infection in innate immune cells and their progenitors. Cell 2023;186:3882&#x2013;3902.e24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son K, Jamil R, Chowdhury A, et al. Circulating anti-nuclear autoantibodies in COVID-19 survivors predict long COVID symptoms. Eur Respir J 2023;61:2200970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong AC, Devason AS, Umana IC, et al. Serotonin reduction in post-acute sequelae of viral infection. Cell 2023;186:4851&#x2013;4867.e20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB, Aleman S, et al. SARS-CoV-2 reservoir in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC). Nat Immunol 2023;24:1616&#x2013;1627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing H, Wu X, Xiang M, Liu L, Novakovic VA, Shi J. Pathophysiological mechanisms of thrombosis in acute and long COVID-19. Front Immunol 2022;13:992384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB, et al. Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Immunol 2022;23:210&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E, Vlok M, Venter C, et al. Persistent clotting protein pathology in long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) is accompanied by increased levels of antiplasmin. Cardiovasc Diabetol 2021;20:172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tannous J, Pan AP, Potter T, et al. Real-world effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccines and anti-SARS-CoV-2 monoclonal antibodies against postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2: analysis of a COVID-19 observational registry for a diverse US metropolitan population. BMJ Open 2023;13:e067611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg-Morris L, Leach S, Xu Y, et al. Covid-19 vaccine effectiveness against post-covid-19 condition among 589 722 individuals in Sweden: population based cohort study. BMJ 2023;383:e076990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Choi T, Al-Aly Z. Association of treatment with nirmatrelvir and the risk of post-COVID-19 condition. JAMA Intern Med 2023;183:554&#x2013;564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramante CT, Buse JB, Liebovitz DM, et al. Outpatient treatment of COVID-19 and incidence of post-COVID-19 condition over 10 months (COVID-OUT): a multicentre, randomised, quadruple-blind, parallel-group, phase 3 trial. Lancet Infect Dis 2023;23:1119&#x2013;1129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickie I, Davenport T, Wakefield D, et al. Post-infective and chronic fatigue syndromes precipitated by viral and non-viral pathogens: prospective cohort study. BMJ 2006;333:575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moldofsky H, Patcai J. Chronic widespread musculoskeletal pain, fatigue, depression and disordered sleep in chronic post-SARS syndrome; a case-controlled study. BMC Neurol 2011;11:37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Sullivan O. Long-term sequelae following previous coronavirus epidemics. Clin Med (Lond) 2021;21:e68&#x2013;e70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Shin HS, Park HY, et al. Depression as a mediator of chronic fatigue and post-traumatic stress symptoms in Middle East respiratory syndrome survivors. Psychiatry Investig 2019;16:59&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard TD, Self WH, Edwards KM, et al. Long-term cognitive impairment after hospitalization for community-acquired pneumonia: a prospective cohort study. J Gen Intern Med 2018;33:929&#x2013;935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah FA, Pike F, Alvarez K, et al. Bidirectional relationship between cognitive function and pneumonia. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2013;188:586&#x2013;592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dicpinigaitis PV. Post-viral anosmia (loss of sensation of smell) did not begin with COVID-19! Lung 2021;199:237&#x2013;238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohoon KP, Ashrani AA, Crusan DJ, Petterson TM, Bailey KR, Heit JA. Is infection an independent risk factor for venous thromboembolism? A population-based, case-control study. Am J Med 2018;131:307&#x2013;316.e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turk Wensveen T, Gasparini D, Rahelic D, Wensveen FM. Type 2 diabetes and viral infection; cause and effect of disease. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2021;172:108637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Husain M, Harrison PJ. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med 2021;18:e1003773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders C, Sperling S, Bendstrup E. A new paradigm is needed to explain long COVID. Lancet Respir Med 2023;11:e12&#x2013;e13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwendinger F, Knaier R, Schmidt-Trucksass A. Concerns regarding a suggested long COVID paradigm. Lancet Respir Med 2023;11:e33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clayton EW. Beyond myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: an IOM report on redefining an illness. JAMA 2015;313:1101&#x2013;1102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Job Accommodation Network. Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Available at: https://askjan.org/disabilities/Myalgic-Encephalomyelitis-Chronic-Fatigue-Syndrome.cfm. Accessed September 15, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinosa-Gonzalez AB, Master H, Gall N, Halpin S, Rogers N, Greenhalgh T. Orthostatic tachycardia after COVID-19. BMJ 2023;380:e073488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL. Advances in understanding the pathophysiology of chronic fatigue syndrome. JAMA 2019;322:499&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menzler K, Mayr P, Knake S, et al. Undiagnosed obstructive sleep apnea syndrome as a treatable cause of new-onset sleepiness in some post-COVID patients. Eur J Neurol 2023. doi:10.1111/ene.16159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.16159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason LA, Dorri JA. ME/CFS and post-exertional malaise among patients with long COVID. Neurol Int 2022;15:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuut TA, Muller F, Csorba I, et al. Efficacy of cognitive-behavioral therapy targeting severe fatigue following coronavirus disease 2019: results of a randomized controlled trial. Clin Infect Dis 2023;77:687&#x2013;695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedorowski A. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome: clinical presentation, aetiology and management. J Intern Med 2019;285:352&#x2013;366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healthline. What is brain fog? March 27, 2020. Available at: https://www.healthline.com/health/brain-fog. Accessed August 31, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA, Akbari A, Emami A, et al. Long COVID syndrome-associated brain fog. J Med Virol 2022;94:979&#x2013;984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheetham NJ, Penfold R, Giunchiglia V, et al. The effects of COVID-19 on cognitive performance in a community-based cohort: a COVID symptom study biobank prospective cohort study. EClinicalMedicine 2023;62:102086.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampshire A, Chatfield DA, MPhil AM, et al. Multivariate profile and acute-phase correlates of cognitive deficits in a COVID-19 hospitalised cohort. EClinicalMedicine 2022;47:101417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PHOSP-Covid Collaborative Group. Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet Respir Med 2022;10:761&#x2013;775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Zhang Z, Zhang Z, Wang Z, Li H. Cognitive impairment after long COVID-19: current evidence and perspectives. Front Neurol 2023;14:1239182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li X, Geng D, et al. Cerebral micro-structural changes in COVID-19 patients&#x2014;an MRI-based 3-month follow-up study. EClinicalMedicine 2020;25:100484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein TL. Cortical grey matter volume depletion links to neurological sequelae in post COVID-19 &#x201c;long haulers.&#x201d; BMC Neurol 2023;23:22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etter MM, Martins TA, Kulsvehagen L, et al. Severe neuro-COVID is associated with peripheral immune signatures, autoimmunity and neurodegeneration: a prospective cross-sectional study. Nat Commun 2022;13:6777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eden A, Grahn A, Bremell D, et al. Viral antigen and inflammatory biomarkers in cerebrospinal fluid in patients with COVID-19 infection and neurologic symptoms compared with control participants without infection or neurologic symptoms. JAMA Netw Open 2022;5:e2213253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang L, Ryan MC, Liang H, et al. Changes in brain activation patterns during working memory tasks in people with post-COVID condition and persistent neuropsychiatric symptoms. Neurology 2023;100:e2409&#x2013;e2423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen AK, Wang X, McCluskey LP, et al. Neuropsychiatric sequelae of long COVID-19: pilot results from the COVID-19 neurological and molecular prospective cohort study in Georgia, USA. Brain Behav Immun Health 2022;24:100491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman S. Managing cognitive decline concerns in the workplace. February 3, 2022. Available at: https://blog.petrieflom.law.harvard.edu/2022/02/03/managing-cognitive-decline-concerns-in-the-workplace/. Accessed September 1, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVries A, Shambhu S, Sloop S, Overhage JM. One-year adverse outcomes among US adults with post-COVID-19 condition vs those without COVID-19 in a large commercial insurance database. JAMA Health Forum 2023;4:e230010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gyongyosi M, Alcaide P, Asselbergs FW, et al. Long COVID and the cardiovascular system-elucidating causes and cellular mechanisms in order to develop targeted diagnostic and therapeutic strategies: a joint scientific statement of the ESC Working Groups on Cellular Biology of the Heart and Myocardial and Pericardial Diseases. Cardiovasc Res 2023;119:336&#x2013;356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Zhao P, Tang D, et al. Cardiac involvement in patients recovered from COVID-2019 identified using magnetic resonance imaging. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging 2020;13:2330&#x2013;2339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajpal S, Tong MS, Borchers J, et al. Cardiovascular magnetic resonance findings in competitive athletes recovering from COVID-19 infection. JAMA Cardiol 2021;6:116&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Bluemke DA, Luscher TF, Neubauer S. Long COVID: post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 with a cardiovascular focus. Eur Heart J 2022;43:1157&#x2013;1172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yugar-Toledo JC, Yugar LBT, Sedenho-Prado LG, Schreiber R, Moreno H. Pathophysiological effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on the cardiovascular system and its clinical manifestations-a mini review. Front Cardiovasc Med 2023;10:1162837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akpek M. Does COVID-19 cause hypertension? Angiology 2022;73:682&#x2013;687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Society of Cardiology. Severe COVID-19 linked with 16-fold risk of life-threatening heart rhythm within 6 months. Available at: https://www.escardio.org/The-ESC/Press-Office/Press-releases/severe-covid-19-linked-with-16-fold-risk-of-life-threatening-heart-rhythm-within. Accessed August 31, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker RC. Evaluating chest pain in patients with post COVID conditions permission to think outside of the box. J Thromb Thrombolysis 2023;55:592&#x2013;603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Chen L, Fan Y, et al. Longitudinal assessment of chest CT findings and pulmonary function after COVID-19 infection. Radiology 2023;307:e222888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellan M, Soddu D, Balbo PE, et al. Respiratory and psychophysical sequelae among patients with COVID-19 four months after hospital discharge. JAMA Netw Open 2021;4:e2036142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regmi B, Friedrich J, J&#xf6;rn B, et al. Diaphragm muscle weakness might explain exertional dyspnea 15 months after hospitalization for COVID-19. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2023;207:1012&#x2013;1021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Occupational and Environmental Medicine. ACOEM Practice Guidelines: COVID-19 (Coronavirus). MDGuidelines. Available at: http://www.mdguidelines.com/acoem/disorders/Low-Back-Disorders. June 28, 2023. Accessed August 31, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker-Davies RM, O'Sullivan O, Senaratne KPP, et al. The Stanford Hall consensus statement for post-COVID-19 rehabilitation. Br J Sports Med 2020;54:949&#x2013;959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouliopoulou DV, Macdermid JC, Saunders E, et al. Rehabilitation interventions for physical capacity and quality of life in adults with post-COVID-19 condition: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open 2023;6:e2333838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan RK, Schuyler KM. Guide to the Medical Evaluation for Respirator Use. OEM Health Information: Beverly, MA; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zazhytska M, Kodra A, Hoagland DA, et al. Non-cell-autonomous disruption of nuclear architecture as a potential cause of COVID-19-induced anosmia. Cell 2022;185:1052&#x2013;1064.e12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho CY, Salimian M, Hegert J, et al. Postmortem assessment of olfactory tissue degeneration and microvasculopathy in patients with COVID-19. JAMA Neurol 2022;79:544&#x2013;553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell MB, Workman AD, Rathi VK, Bhattacharyya N. Smell and taste loss associated with COVID-19 infection. Laryngoscope 2023;133:2357&#x2013;2361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boscolo-Rizzo P, Fabbris C, Polesel J, et al. Two-year prevalence and recovery rate of altered sense of smell or taste in patients with mildly symptomatic COVID-19. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2022;148:889&#x2013;891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boscolo-Rizzo P, Hummel T, Spinato G, et al. Olfactory and gustatory function 3 years after mild COVID-19-a cohort psychophysical study. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2024;150:79&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho DH, Reiter ER, French E, Costanzo RM. Decreasing incidence of chemosensory changes by COVID-19 variant. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2023;168:704&#x2013;706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos DV, Reiter ER, DiNardo LJ, Costanzo RM. Hazardous events associated with impaired olfactory function. Arch Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2004;130:317&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hummel T, Rissom K, Reden J, Hahner A, Weidenbecher M, Huttenbrink KB. Effects of olfactory training in patients with olfactory loss. Laryngoscope 2009;119:496&#x2013;499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelalim AA, Mohamady AA, Elsayed RA, Elawady MA, Ghallab AF. Corticosteroid nasal spray for recovery of smell sensation in COVID-19 patients: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Otolaryngol 2021;42:102884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahadev A, Hentati F, Miller B, et al. Efficacy of gabapentin for post-COVID-19 olfactory dysfunction: the GRACE randomized clinical trial. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2023;149:1111&#x2013;1119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Romieu AC, Carton TW, Saydah S, et al. Prevalence of select new symptoms and conditions among persons aged younger than 20 years and 20 years or older at 31 to 150 days after testing positive or negative for SARS-CoV-2. JAMA Netw Open 2022;5:e2147053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naveed Z, Velasquez Garcia HA, Wong S, et al. Association of COVID-19 infection with incident diabetes. JAMA Netw Open 2023;6:e238866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathmann W, Kuss O, Kostev K. Incidence of newly diagnosed diabetes after COVID-19. Diabetologia 2022;65:949&#x2013;954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong R, Lam E, Bramante CT, et al. Does COVID-19 infection increase the risk of diabetes? Current evidence. Curr Diab Rep 2023;23:207&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung KS, Hung IFN, Chan PPY, et al. Gastrointestinal manifestations of SARS-CoV-2 infection and virus load in fecal samples from a Hong Kong cohort: systematic review and meta-analysis. Gastroenterology 2020;159:81&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan A, Zlitni S, Brooks EF, et al. Gastrointestinal symptoms and fecal shedding of SARS-CoV-2 RNA suggest prolonged gastrointestinal infection. Med 2022;3:371&#x2013;387.e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Doorn AS, Meijer B, Frampton CMA, Barclay ML, de Boer NNK. Systematic review with meta-analysis: SARS-CoV-2 stool testing and the potential for faecal-oral transmission. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2020;52:1276&#x2013;1288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks EF, Bhatt AS. The gut microbiome: a missing link in understanding the gastrointestinal manifestations of COVID-19? Cold Spring Harb Mol Case Stud 2021;7:a006031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu E, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Long-term gastrointestinal outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Commun 2023;14:983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marasco G, Cremon C, Barbaro MR, et al. Post COVID-19 irritable bowel syndrome. Gut 2022;gutjnl-2022-328483. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2022-328483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2022-328483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight R, Walker V, Ip S, et al. Association of COVID-19 with major arterial and venous thrombotic diseases: a population-wide cohort study of 48 million adults in England and Wales. Circulation 2022;146:892&#x2013;906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang MC, Reynolds K, Tabada GH, et al. Assessment of the risk of venous thromboembolism in nonhospitalized patients with COVID-19. JAMA Netw Open 2023;6:e232338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng NM, Chan YC, Cheng SW. COVID-19 related thrombosis: a mini-review. Phlebology 2022;37:326&#x2013;337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Yu C, Jing H, et al. Long COVID: the nature of thrombotic sequelae determines the necessity of early anticoagulation. Front Cell Infect Microbiol 2022;12:861703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NIH COVID-19 Treatment Guidelines. Antithrombotic therapy in patients with COVID-19. Available at: https://www.covid19treatmentguidelines.nih.gov/therapies/antithrombotic-therapy/#:~:text=Although%20there%20is%20no%20clear,had%20risk%20factors%20for%20VTE. Accessed September 12, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P, Zhao W, Kaatz S, Latack K, Schultz L, Poisson L. Factors associated with risk of postdischarge thrombosis in patients with COVID-19. JAMA Netw Open 2021;4:e2135397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang EY, Mao T, Klein J, et al. Diverse functional autoantibodies in patients with COVID-19. Nature 2021;595:283&#x2013;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Sawalha AH, Lu Q. COVID-19 and autoimmune diseases. Curr Opin Rheumatol 2021;33:155&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascolini S, Vannini A, Deleonardi G, et al. COVID-19 and immunological dysregulation: can autoantibodies be useful? Clin Transl Sci 2021;14:502&#x2013;508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang R, Yen-Ting Chen T, Wang SI, Hung YM, Chen HY, Wei CJ. Risk of autoimmune diseases in patients with COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study. EClinicalMedicine 2023;56:101783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch F, Ehm F, Vivirito A, et al. Incident autoimmune diseases in association with SARS-CoV-2 infection: a matched cohort study. Clin Rheumatol 2023;42:2905&#x2013;2914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim SH, Ju HJ, Han JH, et al. Autoimmune and autoinflammatory connective tissue disorders following COVID-19. JAMA Netw Open 2023;6:e2336120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Equal Employment Opportunity Commission. What you should know about COVID-19 and the ADA, the Rehabilitation Act, and Other EEO Laws. Available at: https://www.eeoc.gov/wysk/what-you-should-know-about-covid-19-and-ada-rehabilitation-act-and-other-eeo-laws. Accessed September 12, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 PLN-, 104 Stat. 328 (1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Americans with Disabilities Amendments Act of 2008 PLN-, 122 Stat. 3553 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (29 U.S.C. 794).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services. Guidance on &#x201c;Long COVID&#x201d; as a Disability Under the ADA, Section 504, and Section 1557. Available at: https://www.hhs.gov/civil-rights/for-providers/civil-rights-covid19/guidance-long-covid-disability/index.html. Accessed September 12, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Job Accommodation Network. Long COVID. Available at: https://askjan.org/disabilities/Long-Covid.cfm. Accessed September 10, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kersey L. COVID-19 workers compensation presumptions update&#x2014;five things you need to know. June 20, 2022 Available at: https://www.ncci.com/Articles/Pages/Insights-COVID-19-WorkersComp-Presumptions-Update-5-Things-to-Know.aspx. Accessed September 10, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dworsky M, Saunders-Medina B. COVID-19 and workers' compensation: considerations for policymakers. January 2022. Available at: https://www.rand.org/pubs/perspectives/PEA1346-1.html. Accessed October 29, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Conference of State Legislatures. COVID-19: Workers&#x2019; Compensation. January 24, 2022. Available at: https://www.ncsl.org/labor-and-employment/covid-19-workers-compensation. Accessed October 29, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton SV. Updated findings: long COVID in the workers&#x2019; compensation system. Lexis Nexis. October 4, 2023. Available at: https://www.lexisnexis.com/community/insights/legal/workers-compensation/b/recent-cases-news-trends-developments/posts/updated-findings-long-covid-in-the-workers-compensation-system. Accessed September 15, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>New York State Insurance Fund. Shining a light on Long COVID: an analysis of workers&#x2019; compensation data. January 2023. Available at: https://ww3.nysif.com/-/media/Files/NYSIF_Publications/PDF/NYSIFLongCOVIDStudy2023.ashx. Accessed July 2, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH), Bernard BP, Putz-Anderson V, eds. In: Musculoskeletal Disorders and Workplace Factors: A Critical Review of Epidemiological Evidence for Work-related Musculoskeletal Disorders of the Neck, Upper Extremity, and Low Back. Atlanta, GA: US Department of Health and Human Services; 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegmann KT, Thiese MS, Oostema SJ, et al. Chapter 3: Causal associations and determination of work-relatedness. In: Melhorn JM, Ackermann WE III, eds. AMA Guides to the Evaluation of Disease and Injury Causation. 2nd ed. Chicago, IL: American Medical Association Press; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Occupational and Environmental Medicine (ACOEM). ACOEM Practice Guidelines: Work-relatedness. MDGuidelines. Available at: https://app.mdguidelines.com/acoem-section/acoem%2Ffoundations%2Fwork-relatedness. January 12, 2018. Accessed January 12, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greaves WW, Das R, McKenzie JG, Sinclair DC 2nd, Hegmann KT. Work-relatedness. J Occup Environ Med 2018;60:e640&#x2013;e646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navaratnam AMD, Shrotri M, Nguyen V, et al. Nucleocapsid and spike antibody responses following virologically confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection: an observational analysis in the Virus Watch community cohort. Int J Infect Dis 2022;123:104&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallais F, Gantner P, Bruel T, et al. Evolution of antibody responses up to 13 months after SARS-CoV-2 infection and risk of reinfection. EBioMedicine 2021;71:103561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickman HM, Rampling T, Shaw K, et al. Nosocomial transmission of coronavirus disease 2019: a retrospective study of 66 hospital-acquired cases in a London teaching hospital. Clin Infect Dis 2021;72:690&#x2013;693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabii KB, Javaid W, Nabeel I. Development and implementation of centralised, cloud-based, employee health contact tracing database and predictive modelling framework in the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet Digit Health 2022;4:e770&#x2013;e772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alteri C, Cento V, Piralla A, et al. Genomic epidemiology of SARS-CoV-2 reveals multiple lineages and early spread of SARS-CoV-2 infections in Lombardy, Italy. Nat Commun 2021;12:434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh D. Occupational risks for COVID-19 infection. Occup Med (Lond) 2020;70:3&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pray IW, Grajewski B, Morris C, et al. Measuring work-related risk of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): comparison of COVID-19 incidence by occupation and industry-Wisconsin, September 2020 to May 2021. Clin Infect Dis 2023;76:e163&#x2013;e171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Occupational Safety and Health Administration. Revised Enforcement Guidance for Recording Cases of Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19). May 19, 2020. Available at: https://www.osha.gov/laws-regs/standardinterpretations/2020-05-19. Accessed August 10, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman JJ, Manavi K, Marson EJ, Botkai AH, Sapey E. COVID-19: to be or not to be; that is the diagnostic question. Postgrad Med J 2020;96:392&#x2013;398.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>