<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38349116</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4644</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>125</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cellular biochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cell Biochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intrinsic factors behind long COVID: IV. Hypothetical roles of the SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein and its liquid-liquid phase separation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e30530</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e30530</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcb.30530</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>When the SARS-CoV-2&#xa0;virus infects humans, it leads to a condition called COVID-19&#xa0;that has a wide spectrum of clinical manifestations, from no symptoms to acute respiratory distress syndrome. The virus initiates damage by attaching to the ACE-2&#xa0;protein on the surface of endothelial cells that line the blood vessels and using these cells as hosts for replication. Reactive oxygen species levels are increased during viral replication, which leads to oxidative stress. About three-fifths&#xa0;(~60%) of the people who get infected with the virus eradicate it from their body after 28 days and recover their normal activity. However, a large fraction (~40%) of the people who are infected with the virus suffer from various symptoms (anosmia and/or ageusia, fatigue, cough, myalgia, cognitive impairment, insomnia, dyspnea, and tachycardia) beyond 12 weeks and are diagnosed with a syndrome called long COVID. Long-term clinical studies in a group of people who contracted SARS-CoV-2&#xa0;have been contrasted with a noninfected matched group of people. A subset of infected people can be distinguished by a set of cytokine markers to have persistent, low-grade inflammation and often self-report two or more bothersome symptoms. No medication can alleviate their symptoms efficiently. Coronavirus nucleocapsid proteins have been investigated extensively as potential drug targets due to their key roles in virus replication, among which is their ability to bind their respective genomic RNAs for incorporation into emerging virions. This review highlights basic studies of the nucleocapsid protein and its ability to undergo liquid-liquid phase separation. We hypothesize that this ability of the nucleocapsid protein for phase separation may contribute to long COVID. This hypothesis unlocks new investigation angles and could potentially open novel avenues for a better understanding of long COVID and treating this condition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eltayeb</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-7107-5768</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Science, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Sarraj</LastName><ForeName>Faisal</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5017-3570</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Science, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alharbi</LastName><ForeName>Mona</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Science, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Albiheyri</LastName><ForeName>Raed</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9739-5496</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Science, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Excellence in Bionanoscience Research, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Immunology Unit, King Fahad Medical Research Centre, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mattar</LastName><ForeName>Ehab H</ForeName><Initials>EH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Science, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abu Zeid</LastName><ForeName>Isam M</ForeName><Initials>IM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Science, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bouback</LastName><ForeName>Thamer A</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Science, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bamagoos</LastName><ForeName>Atif</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Science, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uversky</LastName><ForeName>Vladimir N</ForeName><Initials>VN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4037-5857</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine and USF Health Byrd Alzheimer's Research Institute, Morsani College of Medicine, University of South Florida, Tampa, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pushchino Scientific Center for Biological Research of the Russian Academy of Sciences, Moscow Region, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rubio-Casillas</LastName><ForeName>Alberto</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Autlan Regional Hospital, Health Secretariat, Autlan, Jalisco, Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biology Laboratory, Autlan Regional Preparatory School, University of Guadalajara, Autlan, Jalisco, Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Redwan</LastName><ForeName>Elrashdy M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8246-0075</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Science, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Excellence in Bionanoscience Research, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cell Biochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8205768</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0730-2312</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000086462">Coronavirus Nucleocapsid Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019590">Nucleocapsid Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086462" MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus Nucleocapsid Proteins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042783" MajorTopicYN="N">Endothelial Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000095496" MajorTopicYN="N">Phase Separation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019590" MajorTopicYN="N">Nucleocapsid Proteins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liquid-liquid phase separation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nucleocapsid protein</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38349116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcb.30530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Servidio C, Stellacci F. Therapeutic approaches against coronaviruses acute respiratory syndrome. Pharmacol Res Perspect. 2021;9(1):e00691. doi:10.1002/prp2.691</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;scher TF. Understanding COVID-19: in the end it is the endothelium-what else? Eur Heart J. 2020;41(32):3023-3027. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa706</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalish H, Klumpp-Thomas C, Hunsberger S, et al. Undiagnosed SARS-CoV-2 seropositivity during the first 6 months of the COVID-19 pandemic in the United States. Sci Transl Med. 2021;13(601):eabh3826. doi:10.1126/scitranslmed.abh3826</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi N. Long covid: how to define it and how to manage it. BMJ. 2020;370:m3489. doi:10.1136/bmj.m3489</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodin P. Immune determinants of COVID-19 disease presentation and severity. Nature Med. 2021;27(1):28-33. doi:10.1038/s41591-020-01202-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menni C, Valdes AM, Freidin MB, et al. Real-time tracking of self-reported symptoms to predict potential COVID-19. Nature Med. 2020;26(7):1037-1040. doi:10.1038/s41591-020-0916-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin-Chowdhury Z, Ladhani SN. Causation or confounding: why controls are critical for characterizing long COVID. Nature Med. 2021;27(7):1129-1130. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01402-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darley DR, Dore GJ, Byrne AL, et al. Limited recovery from post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 at 8 months in a prospective cohort. ERJ Open Res. 2021;7(4):00384-2021. doi:10.1183/23120541.00384-2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB, et al. Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nature Immunol. 2022;23(2):210-216. doi:10.1038/s41590-021-01113-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH, Crooks MG. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;199(2):113-119. doi:10.1007/s00408-021-00423-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KGI, Brokstad KA, et al. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nature Med. 2021;27(9):1607-1613. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01433-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radin JM, Quer G, Ramos E, et al. Assessment of prolonged physiological and behavioral changes associated with COVID-19 infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(7):e2115959. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.15959</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nature Med. 2021;27(4):601-615. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libby P, L&#xfc;scher T. COVID-19 is, in the end, an endothelial disease. Eur Heart J. 2020;41(32):3038-3044. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa623</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackermann M, Verleden SE, Kuehnel M, et al. Pulmonary vascular endothelialitis, thrombosis, and angiogenesis in Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(2):120-128. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2015432</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armulik A, Genov&#xe9; G, Betsholtz C. Pericytes: developmental, physiological, and pathological perspectives, problems, and promises. Dev Cell. 2011;21(2):193-215. doi:10.1016/j.devcel.2011.07.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Yang Y, Fan X. Microvascular pericytes in brain-associated vascular disease. Biomed Pharmacother. 2020;121:109633. doi:10.1016/j.biopha.2019.109633</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd8;stergaard L. SARS CoV-2 related microvascular damage and symptoms during and after COVID-19: consequences of capillary transit-time changes, tissue hypoxia and inflammation. Physiol Rep. 2021;9(3):e14726. doi:10.14814/phy2.14726</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall M. COVID and the brain: researchers zero in on how damage occurs. Nature. 2021;595(7868):484-485. doi:10.1038/d41586-021-01693-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brann DH, Tsukahara T, Weinreb C, et al. Non-neuronal expression of SARS-CoV-2 entry genes in the olfactory system suggests mechanisms underlying COVID-19-associated anosmia. Sci Adv. 2020;6(31):eabc5801. doi:10.1126/sciadv.abc5801</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro DE, Oliveira-Giacomelli &#xc1;, Glaser T, et al. Hyperactivation of P2X7 receptors as a culprit of COVID-19 neuropathology. Mol Psychiatry. 2021;26(4):1044-1059. doi:10.1038/s41380-020-00965-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Xu J, Hou Y, et al. Network medicine links SARS-CoV-2/COVID-19 infection to brain microvascular injury and neuroinflammation in dementia-like cognitive impairment. Alzheimer's Res Ther. 2021;13(1):110. doi:10.1186/s13195-021-00850-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antifeeva IA, Fonin AV, Fefilova AS, et al. Liquid-liquid phase separation as an organizing principle of intracellular space: overview of the evolution of the cell compartmentalization concept. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2022;79(5):251. doi:10.1007/s00018-022-04276-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nesterov SV, Ilyinsky NS, Uversky VN. Liquid-liquid phase separation as a common organizing principle of intracellular space and biomembranes providing dynamic adaptive responses. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Cell Res. 2021;1868(11):119102. doi:10.1016/j.bbamcr.2021.119102</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banani SF, Lee HO, Hyman AA, Rosen MK. Biomolecular condensates: organizers of cellular biochemistry. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2017;18(5):285-298. doi:10.1038/nrm.2017.7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turoverov KK, Kuznetsova IM, Fonin AV, Darling AL, Zaslavsky BY, Uversky VN. Stochasticity of biological soft matter: emerging concepts in intrinsically disordered proteins and biological phase separation. Trends Biochem Sci. 2019;44(8):716-728. doi:10.1016/j.tibs.2019.03.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson P, Kedersha N. RNA granules: post-transcriptional and epigenetic modulators of gene expression. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2009;10(6):430-436. doi:10.1038/nrm2694</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawyer IA, Bartek J, Dundr M. Phase separated microenvironments inside the cell nucleus are linked to disease and regulate epigenetic state, transcription and RNA processing. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2019;90:94-103. doi:10.1016/j.semcdb.2018.07.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gall JG. The centennial of the Cajal body. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2003;4(12):975-980. doi:10.1038/nrm1262</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teilum K, Olsen JG, Kragelund BB. On the specificity of protein-protein interactions in the context of disorder. Biochem J. 2021;478(11):2035-2050. doi:10.1042/BCJ20200828</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uversky VN. Unusual biophysics of intrinsically disordered proteins. Biochim Biophys Acta Proteins Proteom. 2013;1834(5):932-951. doi:10.1016/j.bbapap.2012.12.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uversky VN. Intrinsically disordered proteins and their &#x201c;mysterious&#x201d; (meta)physics. Front Phys. 2019;7:10. doi:10.3389/fphy.2019.00010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darling AL, Liu Y, Oldfield CJ, Uversky VN. Intrinsically disordered proteome of human membrane-less organelles. Proteomics. 2018;18(5-6):e1700193. doi:10.1002/pmic.201700193</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darling AL, Zaslavsky BY, Uversky VN. Intrinsic disorder-based emergence in cellular biology: physiological and pathological liquid-liquid phase transitions in cells. Polymers. 2019;11(6):990. doi:10.3390/polym11060990</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uversky VN. Recent developments in the field of intrinsically disordered proteins: intrinsic disorder-based emergence in cellular biology in light of the physiological and pathological liquid-liquid phase transitions. Annu Rev Biophys. 2021;50:135-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uversky V, Finkelstein A. Life in phases: intra-and inter-molecular phase transitions in protein solutions. Biomolecules. 2019;9(12):842. doi:10.3390/biom9120842</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo Y, Feng Y, Huang W, et al. Liquid-liquid phase separation in cardiovascular diseases. Cells. 2022;11(19):3040. doi:10.3390/cells11193040</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Z, Mei S, Zhou L, et al. Liquid-liquid phase separation sheds new light upon cardiovascular diseases. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(20):15418. doi:10.3390/ijms242015418</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Gu Y. The emerging role of biomolecular condensates in plant immunity. Plant Cell. 2022;34(5):1568-1572. doi:10.1093/plcell/koab240</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonin AV, Silonov SA, Shpironok OG, et al. The role of non-specific interactions in canonical and ALT-associated PML-bodies formation and dynamics. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(11):5821. doi:10.3390/ijms22115821</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberti S, Gladfelter A, Mittag T. Considerations and challenges in studying liquid-liquid phase separation and biomolecular condensates. Cell. 2019;176(3):419-434. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2018.12.035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathieu C, Pappu RV, Taylor JP. Beyond aggregation: pathological phase transitions in neurodegenerative disease. Science. 2020;370(6512):56-60. doi:10.1126/science.abb8032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong X, Tang R, Xu J, et al. Liquid-liquid phase separation in tumor biology. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2022;7(1):221. doi:10.1038/s41392-022-01076-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty P, Zweckstetter M. Role of aberrant phase separation in pathological protein aggregation. Curr Opin Struct Biol. 2023;82:102678. doi:10.1016/j.sbi.2023.102678</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad A, Uversky VN, Khan RH. Aberrant liquid-liquid phase separation and amyloid aggregation of proteins related to neurodegenerative diseases. Int J Biiol Macromol. 2022;220:703-720. doi:10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2022.08.132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darling AL, Shorter J. Combating deleterious phase transitions in neurodegenerative disease. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Cell Res. 2021;1868(5):118984. doi:10.1016/j.bbamcr.2021.118984</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huai Y, Mao W, Wang X, et al. How do RNA binding proteins trigger liquid-liquid phase separation in human health and diseases? BioSci Trends. 2022;16(6):389-404. doi:10.5582/bst.2022.01449</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Cui Y, Han X, et al. Liquid-liquid phase separation by SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein and RNA. Cell Res. 2020;30(12):1143-1145. doi:10.1038/s41422-020-00408-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stortz M, Pecci A, Presman DM, Levi V. Unraveling the molecular interactions involved in phase separation of glucocorticoid receptor. BMC Biol. 2020;18(1):59. doi:10.1186/s12915-020-00788-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong JY, Torres JZ. Phase separation in cell division. Mol Cell. 2020;80(1):9-20. doi:10.1016/j.molcel.2020.08.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei MT, Chang YC, Shimobayashi SF, Shin Y, Strom AR, Brangwynne CP. Nucleated transcriptional condensates amplify gene expression. Nature Cell Biol. 2020;22(10):1187-1196. doi:10.1038/s41556-020-00578-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roden C, Gladfelter AS. RNA contributions to the form and function of biomolecular condensates. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2021;22(3):183-195. doi:10.1038/s41580-020-0264-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spegg V, Altmeyer M. Biomolecular condensates at sites of DNA damage: more than just a phase. DNA Repair. 2021;106:103179. doi:10.1016/j.dnarep.2021.103179</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noda NN, Wang Z, Zhang H. Liquid-liquid phase separation in autophagy. J Cell Biol. 2020;219(8):e202004062. doi:10.1083/jcb.202004062</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du M, Chen ZJ. DNA-induced liquid phase condensation of cGAS activates innate immune signaling. Science. 2018;361(6403):704-709. doi:10.1126/science.aat1022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibble RW, Depaix A, Kowalska J, Jemielity J, Gross JD. Biomolecular condensates amplify mRNA decapping by biasing enzyme conformation. Nat Chem Biol. 2021;17(5):615-623. doi:10.1038/s41589-021-00774-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel A, Lee HO, Jawerth L, et al. A liquid-to-solid phase transition of the ALS protein FUS accelerated by disease mutation. Cell. 2015;162(5):1066-1077. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2015.07.047</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song MS, Grabocka E. Stress granules in cancer. Rev Physiol Biochem Pharmacol. 2023;185:25-52. doi:10.1007/112_2020_37</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein IA, Boija A, Afeyan LK, et al. Partitioning of cancer therapeutics in nuclear condensates. Science. 2020;368(6497):1386-1392. doi:10.1126/science.aaz4427</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianchi G, Brocca S, Longhi S, Uversky VN. Liaisons dangereuses: intrinsic disorder in cellular proteins recruited to viral infection-related biocondensates. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(3):2151. doi:10.3390/ijms24032151</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Nunzio F, Uversky VN, Mouland AJ. Biomolecular condensates: insights into early and late steps of the HIV-1 replication cycle. Retrovirology. 2023;20(1):4. doi:10.1186/s12977-023-00619-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etibor T, Yamauchi Y, Amorim M. Liquid biomolecular condensates and viral lifecycles: review and perspectives. Viruses. 2021;13(3):366. doi:10.3390/v13030366</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Shi C, Xu Q, Yin H. SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein undergoes liquid-liquid phase separation into stress granules through its N-terminal intrinsically disordered region. Cell Discov. 2021;7(1):5. doi:10.1038/s41421-020-00240-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iserman C, Roden C, Boerneke M, et al. Specific viral RNA drives the SARS CoV-2 nucleocapsid to phase separate. bioRxiv. 2020. doi:10.1101/2020.06.11.147199</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iserman C, Roden CA, Boerneke MA, et al. Genomic RNA elements drive phase separation of the SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid. Mol Cell. 2020;80(6):1078-1091. doi:10.1016/j.molcel.2020.11.041</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S, Ye Q, Singh D, et al. The SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid phosphoprotein forms mutually exclusive condensates with RNA and the membrane-associated M protein. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):502. doi:10.1038/s41467-020-20768-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perdikari TM, Murthy AC, Ryan VH, Watters S, Naik MT, Fawzi NL. SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein phase-separates with RNA and with human hnRNPs. EMBO J. 2020;39(24):e106478. doi:10.15252/embj.2020106478</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cubuk J, Alston JJ, Incicco JJ, et al. The SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein is dynamic, disordered, and phase separates with RNA. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):1936. doi:10.1038/s41467-021-21953-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang M, Li Y, Song J. ATP biphasically modulates LLPS of SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein and specifically binds its RNA-binding domain. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2021;541:50-55. doi:10.1016/j.bbrc.2021.01.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savastano A, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez de Opakua A, Rankovic M, Zweckstetter M. Nucleocapsid protein of SARS-CoV-2 phase separates into RNA-rich polymerase-containing condensates. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):6041. doi:10.1038/s41467-020-19843-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molliex A, Temirov J, Lee J, et al. Phase separation by low complexity domains promotes stress granule assembly and drives pathological fibrillization. Cell. 2015;163(1):123-133. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2015.09.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeynaems S, Alberti S, Fawzi NL, et al. Protein phase separation: a new phase in cell biology. Trends Cell Biol. 2018;28(6):420-435. doi:10.1016/j.tcb.2018.02.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruff KM, Dar F, Pappu RV. Polyphasic linkage and the impact of ligand binding on the regulation of biomolecular condensates. Biophysics Rev. 2021;2(2):021302. doi:10.1063/5.0050059</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dignon GL, Best RB, Mittal J. Biomolecular phase separation: from molecular driving forces to macroscopic properties. Annu Rev Phys Chem. 2020;71:53-75. doi:10.1146/annurev-physchem-071819-113553</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darling AL, Uversky VN. Known types of membrane-less organelles and biomolecular condensates. In: Uversky VN, ed. Droplets of Life: Membrane-Less Organelles, Biomolecular Condensates, and Biological Liquid-Liquid Phase Separation. 1st ed. Elsevier; 2023:271-335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaete-Argel A, M&#xe1;rquez CL, Barriga GP, Soto-Rifo R, Valiente-Echeverr&#xed;a F. Strategies for success. Viral infections and membraneless organelles. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2019;9:336. doi:10.3389/fcimb.2019.00336</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cascarina SM, Ross ED. A proposed role for the SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein in the formation and regulation of biomolecular condensates. FASEB J. 2020;34(8):9832-9842. doi:10.1096/fj.202001351</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson CR, Asfaha JB, Ghent CM, et al. Phosphoregulation of phase separation by the SARS-CoV-2 N protein suggests a biophysical basis for its dual functions. Mol Cell. 2020;80(6):1092-1103. doi:10.1016/j.molcel.2020.11.025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali N, Prasad K, AlAsmari AF, Alharbi M, Rashid S, Kumar V. Genomics-guided targeting of stress granule proteins G3BP1/2 to inhibit SARS-CoV-2 propagation. Int J Biiol Macromol. 2021;190:636-648. doi:10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2021.09.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W, Ju X, Tian M, et al. Molecular determinants for regulation of G3BP1/2 phase separation by the SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein. Cell Discov. 2021;7(1):69. doi:10.1038/s41421-021-00306-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo L, Li Z, Zhao T, et al. SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein phase separates with G3BPs to disassemble stress granules and facilitate viral production. Sci Bull. 2021;66(12):1194-1204. doi:10.1016/j.scib.2021.01.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somasekharan SP, Gleave M. SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein interacts with immunoregulators and stress granules and phase separates to form liquid droplets. FEBS Lett. 2021;595(23):2872-2896. doi:10.1002/1873-3468.14229</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Ma L, Cai S, et al. RNA-induced liquid phase separation of SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein facilitates NF-kappaB hyper-activation and inflammation. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6(1):167. doi:10.1038/s41392-021-00575-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Wu D, Nguyen A, et al. Energetic and structural features of SARS-CoV-2 N-protein co-assemblies with nucleic acids. iScience. 2021;24(6):102523. doi:10.1016/j.isci.2021.102523</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, Leavy OC, Richardson M, et al. Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10(8):761-775. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(22)00127-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Dai T, Qin Z, et al. Targeting liquid-liquid phase separation of SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein promotes innate antiviral immunity by elevating MAVS activity. Nature Cell Biol. 2021;23(7):718-732. doi:10.1038/s41556-021-00710-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao D, Xu W, Zhang X, et al. Understanding the phase separation characteristics of nucleocapsid protein provides a new therapeutic opportunity against SARS-CoV-2. Protein Cell. 2021;12(9):734-740. doi:10.1007/s13238-021-00832-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao M, Yu Y, Sun LM, et al. GCG inhibits SARS-CoV-2 replication by disrupting the liquid phase condensation of its nucleocapsid protein. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):2114. doi:10.1038/s41467-021-22297-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broz P, Dixit VM. Inflammasomes: mechanism of assembly, regulation and signalling. Nat Rev Immunol. 2016;16(7):407-420. doi:10.1038/nri.2016.58</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agostini L, Martinon F, Burns K, McDermott MF, Hawkins PN, Tschopp J. NALP3 forms an IL-1&#x3b2;-processing inflammasome with increased activity in Muckle-Wells autoinflammatory disorder. Immunity. 2004;20(3):319-325. doi:10.1016/s1074-7613(04)00046-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He W, Wan H, Hu L, et al. Gasdermin D is an executor of pyroptosis and required for interleukin-1&#x3b2; secretion. Cell Res. 2015;25(12):1285-1298. doi:10.1038/cr.2015.139</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anand PK, Malireddi RKS, Lukens JR, et al. NLRP6 negatively regulates innate immunity and host defence against bacterial pathogens. Nature. 2012;488(7411):389-393. doi:10.1038/nature11250</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy M, Shapiro H, Thaiss CA, Elinav E. NLRP6: a multifaceted innate immune sensor. Trends Immunol. 2017;38(4):248-260. doi:10.1016/j.it.2017.01.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grenier JM, Wang L, Manji GA, et al. Functional screening of five PYPAF family members identifies PYPAF5 as a novel regulator of NF-&#x3ba;B and caspase-1. FEBS Lett. 2002;530(1-3):73-78. doi:10.1016/s0014-5793(02)03416-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen C, Li R, Negro R, et al. Phase separation drives RNA virus-induced activation of the NLRP6 inflammasome. Cell. 2021;184(23):5759-5774. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2021.09.032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst KR, Ye R, Goebel SJ, Jayaraman P, Masters PS. An interaction between the nucleocapsid protein and a component of the replicase-transcriptase complex is crucial for the infectivity of coronavirus genomic RNA. J Virol. 2010;84(19):10276-10288. doi:10.1128/JVI.01287-10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seth RB, Sun L, Ea CK, Chen ZJ. Identification and characterization of MAVS, a mitochondrial antiviral signaling protein that activates NF-&#x3ba;B and IRF3. Cell. 2005;122(5):669-682. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2005.08.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Kontodimas K, Bosmann M. The MAVS immune recognition pathway in viral infection and sepsis. Antioxid Redox Signaling. 2021;35(16):1376-1392. doi:10.1089/ars.2021.0167</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien TR, Thomas DL, Jackson SS, Prokunina-Olsson L, Donnelly RP, Hartmann R. Weak induction of interferon expression by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 supports clinical trials of interferon-&#x3bb; to treat early coronavirus disease 2019. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71(6):1410-1412. doi:10.1093/cid/ciaa453</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadjadj J, Yatim N, Barnabei L, et al. Impaired type I interferon activity and inflammatory responses in severe COVID-19 patients. Science. 2020;369(6504):718-724. doi:10.1126/science.abc6027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez L, Sang PC, Tian Y, Sang Y. Dysregulated interferon response underlying severe COVID-19. Viruses. 2020;12(12):1433. doi:10.3390/v12121433</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun SC. The non-canonical NF-&#x3ba;B pathway in immunity and inflammation. Nat Rev Immunol. 2017;17(9):545-558. doi:10.1038/nri.2017.52</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Lenardo MJ, Baltimore D. 30 years of NF-&#x3ba;B: a blossoming of relevance to human pathobiology. Cell. 2017;168(1-2):37-57. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2016.12.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayden MS, Ghosh S. Shared principles in NF-&#x3ba;B signaling. Cell. 2008;132(3):344-362. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2008.01.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayden MS, Ghosh S. NF-&#x3ba;B, the first quarter-century: remarkable progress and outstanding questions. Genes Dev. 2012;26(3):203-234. doi:10.1101/gad.183434.111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jobe F, Simpson J, Hawes P, Guzman E, Bailey D. Respiratory syncytial virus sequesters NF-&#x3ba;B subunit p65 to cytoplasmic inclusion bodies to inhibit innate immune signaling. J Virol. 2020;94(22):10-1128. doi:10.1128/JVI.01380-20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maubach G, Schm&#xe4;dicke AC, Naumann M. NEMO links nuclear factor-&#x3ba;B to human diseases. Trends Mol Med. 2017;23(12):1138-1155. doi:10.1016/j.molmed.2017.10.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenson PD, Mort M, Ball EV, Shaw K, Phillips AD, Cooper DN. The Human Gene Mutation Database: building a comprehensive mutation repository for clinical and molecular genetics, diagnostic testing and personalized genomic medicine. Hum Genet. 2014;133(1):1-9. doi:10.1007/s00439-013-1358-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du M, Ea CK, Fang Y, Chen ZJ. Liquid phase separation of NEMO induced by polyubiquitin chains activates NF-&#x3ba;B. Mol Cell. 2022;82(13):2415-2426.doi:10.1016/j.molcel.2022.03.037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia S, Chen Z, Shen C, Fu TM. Higher-order assemblies in immune signaling: supramolecular complexes and phase separation. Protein Cell. 2021;12(9):680-694. doi:10.1007/s13238-021-00839-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou W, Mohr L, Maciejowski J, Kranzusch PJ. cGAS phase separation inhibits TREX1-mediated DNA degradation and enhances cytosolic DNA sensing. Mol Cell. 2021;81(4):739-755. doi:10.1016/j.molcel.2021.01.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X, Zhang L, Shen J, et al. The STING phase-separator suppresses innate immune signalling. Nature Cell Biol. 2021;23(4):330-340. doi:10.1038/s41556-021-00659-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Zhang M, Yuan C, et al. Progress of cGAS-STING signaling in response to SARS-CoV-2 infection. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1010911. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2022.1010911</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Wei L, Xu F, et al. SARS-CoV-2 spike protein-induced cell fusion activates the cGAS-STING pathway and the interferon response. Sci Signaling. 2022;15(729):eabg8744. doi:10.1126/scisignal.abg8744</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Zhao J, Xu S, et al. Species-specific deamidation of cGAS by herpes simplex virus UL37 protein facilitates viral replication. Cell Host Microbe. 2018;24(2):234-248. doi:10.1016/j.chom.2018.07.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, You H, Su C, Li Y, Chen S, Zheng C. Herpes simplex virus 1 tegument protein VP22 abrogates cGAS/STING-mediated antiviral innate immunity. J Virol. 2018;92(15):10-1128. doi:10.1128/JVI.00841-18</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhowmik D, Du M, Tian Y, et al. Cooperative DNA binding mediated by KicGAS/ORF52 oligomerization allows inhibition of DNA-induced phase separation and activation of cGAS. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021;49(16):9389-9403. doi:10.1093/nar/gkab689</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu G, Liu C, Zhou S, et al. Viral tegument proteins restrict cGAS-DNA phase separation to mediate immune evasion. Mol Cell. 2021;81(13):2823-2837. doi:10.1016/j.molcel.2021.05.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertzog J, Zhou W, Fowler G, et al. Varicella-Zoster virus ORF9 is an antagonist of the DNA sensor cGAS. EMBO J. 2022;41(14):e109217. doi:10.15252/embj.2021109217</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin Z, Fang X, Sun W, et al. Deactylation by SIRT1 enables liquid-liquid phase separation of IRF3/IRF7 in innate antiviral immunity. Nature Immunol. 2022;23(8):1193-1207. doi:10.1038/s41590-022-01269-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta M, Mahanty S, Greer P, et al. Persistent infection with ebola virus under conditions of partial immunity. J Virol. 2004;78(2):958-967. doi:10.1128/jvi.78.2.958-967.2004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riddell MA, Moss WJ, Hauer D, Monze M, Griffin DE. Slow clearance of measles virus RNA after acute infection. J Clin Virol. 2007;39(4):312-317. doi:10.1016/j.jcv.2007.05.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viola MV, Scott C, Duffy PD. Persistent measles virus infection in vitro and in man. Arthritis Rheum. 1978;21(5 suppl):S46-S51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ireland DDC, Manangeeswaran M, Lewkowicz AP, et al. Long-term persistence of infectious Zika virus: inflammation and behavioral sequela in mice. PLoS Pathog. 2020;16(12):e1008689. doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1008689</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caniego-Casas T, Mart&#xed;nez-Garc&#xed;a L, Alonso-Ria&#xf1;o M, et al. RNA SARS-CoV-2 persistence in the lung of severe COVID-19 patients: a case series of autopsies. Front Microbiol. 2022;13:824967. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2022.824967</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desimmie BA, Raru YY, Awadh HM, He P, Teka S, Willenburg KS. Insights into SARS-CoV-2 persistence and its relevance. Viruses. 2021;13(6):1025. doi:10.3390/v13061025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randall RE, Griffin DE. Within host RNA virus persistence: mechanisms and consequences. Curr Opin Virol. 2017;23:35-42. doi:10.1016/j.coviro.2017.03.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung WC, Ahn JH, Song MJ. Liquid-liquid phase separation drives herpesvirus assembly in the cytoplasm. J Cell Biol. 2023;222(1):e202211015. doi:10.1083/jcb.202211015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagan MF, Mohajerani F. Self-assembly coupled to liquid-liquid phase separation. PLoS Comput Biol. 2023;19(5):e1010652. doi:10.1371/journal.pcbi.1010652</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei W, Bai L, Yan B, et al. When liquid-liquid phase separation meets viral infections. Front Immunol. 2022;13:985622. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2022.985622</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Shen W, Hu J, et al. Molecular mechanisms and cellular functions of liquid-liquid phase separation during antiviral immune responses. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1162211. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2023.1162211</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez N, Camporeale G, Salgueiro M, et al. Deconstructing virus condensation. PLoS Pathog. 2021;17(10):e1009926. doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1009926</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akiba K, Katoh-Fukui Y, Yoshida K, et al. Role of liquid-liquid separation in endocrine and living cells. J Endocr Soc. 2021;5(10):bvab126. doi:10.1210/jendso/bvab126</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Ji X, Li P, et al. Liquid-liquid phase separation in biology: mechanisms, physiological functions and human diseases. Science China Life Sciences. 2020;63(7):953-985. doi:10.1007/s11427-020-1702-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strzyz P. Targeting viruses in their phase. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2021a;20(9):667. doi:10.1038/d41573-021-00129-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strzyz P. Targeting viruses in their phase. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2021b;22(9):585. doi:10.1038/s41580-021-00400-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocca S, Grandori R, Longhi S, Uversky V. Liquid-liquid phase separation by intrinsically disordered protein regions of viruses: roles in viral life cycle and control of virus-host interactions. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(23):9045. doi:10.3390/ijms21239045</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorson AE, Deen GF, Bernstein KT, et al. Persistence of Ebola virus in semen among Ebola virus disease survivors in Sierra Leone: a cohort study of frequency, duration, and risk factors. PLoS Med. 2021;18(2):e1003273. doi:10.1371/journal.pmed.1003273</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keita AK, Koundouno FR, Faye M, et al. Resurgence of Ebola virus in 2021 in Guinea suggests a new paradigm for outbreaks. Nature. 2021;597(7877):539-543. doi:10.1038/s41586-021-03901-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira Souto I, Alejo-Cancho I, Gasc&#xf3;n Brustenga J, Peir&#xf3; Mestres A, Mu&#xf1;oz Guti&#xe9;rrez J, Mart&#xed;nez Yoldi MJ. Persistence of Zika virus in semen 93 days after the onset of symptoms. Enferm Infecc Microbiol Clin. 2018;36(1):21-23. doi:10.1016/j.eimc.2016.10.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensson K, Norrby E. Persistence of RNA viruses in the central nervous system. Annu Rev Microbiol. 1986;40:159-184. doi:10.1146/annurev.mi.40.100186.001111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo L, Wang G, Wang Y, et al. SARS-CoV-2-specific antibody and T-cell responses 1 year after infection in people recovered from COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Microbe. 2022;3(5):e348-e356. doi:10.1016/S2666-5247(22)00036-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaebler C, Wang Z, Lorenzi JCC, et al. Evolution of antibody immunity to SARS-CoV-2. Nature. 2021;591(7851):639-644. doi:10.1038/s41586-021-03207-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu F, Chen F, Ou Z, et al. A compromised specific humoral immune response against the SARS-CoV-2 receptor-binding domain is related to viral persistence and periodic shedding in the gastrointestinal tract. Cell Mol Immunol. 2020;17(11):1119-1125. doi:10.1038/s41423-020-00550-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamitani W, Narayanan K, Huang C, et al. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus nsp1 protein suppresses host gene expression by promoting host mRNA degradation. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2006;103(34):12885-12890. doi:10.1073/pnas.0603144103</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min YQ, Huang M, Sun X, Deng F, Wang H, Ning YJ. Immune evasion of SARS-CoV-2 from interferon antiviral system. Comput Struct Biotechnol J. 2021;19:4217-4225. doi:10.1016/j.csbj.2021.07.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee AK, Blanco MR, Bruce EA, et al. SARS-CoV-2 disrupts splicing, translation, and protein trafficking to suppress host defenses. Cell. 2020;183(5):1325-1339. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2020.10.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Q, Cheng J, Mei W, Yang D, Zhang P, Zeng C. Phase separation in cancer at a glance. J Transl Med. 2023;21(1):237. doi:10.1186/s12967-023-04082-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning W, Guo Y, Lin S, et al. DrLLPS: a data resource of liquid-liquid phase separation in eukaryotes. Nucleic Acids Res. 2020;48(D1):D288-D295. doi:10.1093/nar/gkz1027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azaldegui CA, Vecchiarelli AG, Biteen JS. The emergence of phase separation as an organizing principle in bacteria. Biophys J. 2021;120(7):1123-1138. doi:10.1016/j.bpj.2020.09.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvador-Castell M, Dem&#xe9; B, Oger P, Peters J. Lipid phase separation induced by the apolar polyisoprenoid squalane demonstrates its role in membrane domain formation in archaeal membranes. Langmuir. 2020;36(26):7375-7382. doi:10.1021/acs.langmuir.0c00901</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansma HG. Better than membranes at the origin of life? Life. 2017;7(2):28. doi:10.3390/life7020028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyman AA, Weber CA, J&#xfc;licher F. Liquid-liquid phase separation in biology. Annu Rev Cell Dev Biol. 2014;30:39-58. doi:10.1146/annurev-cellbio-100913-013325</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Z, Chen X, Wu X, Zhang M. Formation of biological condensates via phase separation: characteristics, analytical methods, and physiological implications. J Biol Chem. 2019;294(40):14823-14835. doi:10.1074/jbc.REV119.007895</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes E, Shorter J. The molecular language of membraneless organelles. J Biol Chem. 2019;294(18):7115-7127. doi:10.1074/jbc.TM118.001192</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White JP, Lloyd RE. Regulation of stress granules in virus systems. TIM. 2012;20(4):175-183. doi:10.1016/j.tim.2012.02.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCormick C, Khaperskyy DA. Translation inhibition and stress granules in the antiviral immune response. Nat Rev Immunol. 2017;17(10):647-660. doi:10.1038/nri.2017.63</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchan JR, Parker R. Eukaryotic stress granules: the ins and outs of translation. Mol Cell. 2009;36(6):932-941. doi:10.1016/j.molcel.2009.11.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedersha N, Ivanov P, Anderson P. Stress granules and cell signaling: more than just a passing phase. Trends Biochem Sci. 2013;38(10):494-506. doi:10.1016/j.tibs.2013.07.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahboubi H, Stochaj U. Cytoplasmic stress granules: dynamic modulators of cell signaling and disease. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Basis Dis. 2017;1863(4):884-895. doi:10.1016/j.bbadis.2016.12.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon SL, Morisaki T, Stasevich TJ, Parker R. Coupling of translation quality control and mRNA targeting to stress granules. J Cell Biol. 2020;219(8):e202004120. doi:10.1083/jcb.202004120</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riback JA, Katanski CD, Kear-Scott JL, et al. Stress-triggered phase separation is an adaptive, evolutionarily tuned response. Cell. 2017;168(6):1028-1040. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2017.02.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumann K. mRNA translation in stress granules is not uncommon. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2021;22(3):164. doi:10.1038/s41580-021-00331-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Q, McAtee CK, Su X. Phase separation in immune signalling. Nat Rev Immunol. 2022;22(3):188-199. doi:10.1038/s41577-021-00572-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng ZQ, Wang SY, Xu ZS, Fu YZ, Wang YY. SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein impairs stress granule formation to promote viral replication. Cell Discov. 2021;7(1):38. doi:10.1038/s41421-021-00275-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahlquist P. Parallels among positive-strand RNA viruses, reverse-transcribing viruses and double-stranded RNA viruses. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2006;4(5):371-382. doi:10.1038/nrmicro1389</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y, Hinchman MM, Lewandrowski M, et al. The multi-functional reovirus &#x3c3;3 protein is a virulence factor that suppresses stress granule formation and is associated with myocardial injury. PLoS Pathog. 2021;17(7):e1009494. doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1009494</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson P, Kedersha N. RNA granules. J Cell Biol. 2006;172(6):803-808. doi:10.1083/jcb.200512082</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Leeuwen W, Rabouille C. Cellular stress leads to the formation of membraneless stress assemblies in eukaryotic cells. Traffic. 2019;20(9):623-638. doi:10.1111/tra.12669</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian XJ, Gallouzi IE. Oxidative stress increases the number of stress granules in senescent cells and triggers a rapid decrease in p21waf1/cip1 translation. J Biol Chem. 2009;284(13):8877-8887. doi:10.1074/jbc.M806372200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emara MM, Fujimura K, Sciaranghella D, Ivanova V, Ivanov P, Anderson P. Hydrogen peroxide induces stress granule formation independent of eIF2&#x3b1; phosphorylation. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2012;423(4):763-769. doi:10.1016/j.bbrc.2012.06.033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaete-Argel A, Vel&#xe1;squez F, M&#xe1;rquez CL, et al. Tellurite promotes stress granules and nuclear SG-like assembly in response to oxidative stress and DNA damage. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2021;9:622057. doi:10.3389/fcell.2021.622057</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reineke LC, Cheema SA, Dubrulle J, Neilson JR. Chronic starvation induces noncanonical pro-death stress granules. J Cell Sci. 2018;131(19):jcs220244. doi:10.1242/jcs.220244</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathyanarayanan U, Musa M, Bou Dib P, Raimundo N, Milosevic I, Krisko A. ATP hydrolysis by yeast Hsp104 determines protein aggregate dissolution and size in vivo. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):5226. doi:10.1038/s41467-020-19104-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moutaoufik MT, El Fatimy R, Nassour H, et al. UVC-induced stress granules in mammalian cells. PLoS One. 2014;9(11):e112742. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0112742</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying S, Khaperskyy DA. UV damage induces G3BP1-dependent stress granule formation that is not driven by mTOR inhibition-mediated translation arrest. J Cell Sci. 2020;133(20):jcs248310. doi:10.1242/jcs.248310</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timalsina S, Arimoto-Matsuzaki K, Kitamura M, et al. Chemical compounds that suppress hypoxia-induced stress granule formation enhance cancer drug sensitivity of human cervical cancer HeLa cells. J Biochem. 2018;164(5):381-391. doi:10.1093/jb/mvy062</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Laan AMA, van Gemert AMC, Dirks RW, et al. mRNA cycles through hypoxia-induced stress granules in live Drosophila embryonic muscles. Int J Dev Biol. 2012;56(9):701-709. doi:10.1387/ijdb.103172al</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namkoong S, Ho A, Woo YM, Kwak H, Lee JH. Systematic characterization of stress-induced RNA granulation. Mol Cell. 2018;70(1):175-187. doi:10.1016/j.molcel.2018.02.025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tweedie A, Nissan T. Hiding in plain sight: formation and function of stress granules during microbial infection of mammalian cells. Front Mol Biosci. 2021;8:647884. doi:10.3389/fmolb.2021.647884</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Child JR, Chen Q, Reid DW, Jagannathan S, Nicchitta CV. Recruitment of endoplasmic reticulum-targeted and cytosolic mRNAs into membrane-associated stress granules. RNA. 2021;27(10):1241-1256. doi:10.1261/rna.078858.121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Sridharan S, Zagoriy I, et al. Molecular mechanisms of stress-induced reactivation in mumps virus condensates. Cell. 2023;186(9):1877-1894. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2023.03.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emara MM, Brinton MA. Interaction of TIA-1/TIAR with West Nile and dengue virus products in infected cells interferes with stress granule formation and processing body assembly. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2007;104(21):9041-9046. doi:10.1073/pnas.0703348104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katoh H, Okamoto T, Fukuhara T, et al. Japanese encephalitis virus core protein inhibits stress granule formation through an interaction with Caprin-1 and facilitates viral propagation. J Virol. 2013;87(1):489-502. doi:10.1128/JVI.02186-12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>John L, Samuel CE. Induction of stress granules by interferon and down-regulation by the cellular RNA adenosine deaminase ADAR1. Virology. 2014;454-455:299-310. doi:10.1016/j.virol.2014.02.025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courtney SC, Scherbik SV, Stockman BM, Brinton MA. West Nile virus infections suppress early viral RNA synthesis and avoid inducing the cell stress granule response. J Virol. 2012;86(7):3647-3657. doi:10.1128/JVI.06549-11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bl&#xe1;zquez AB, Mart&#xed;n-Acebes MA, Poderoso T, Saiz JC. Relevance of oxidative stress in inhibition of eIF2 alpha phosphorylation and stress granules formation during Usutu virus infection. PLoS Neglected Trop Dis. 2021;15(1):e0009072. doi:10.1371/journal.pntd.0009072</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou S, Kumar A, Xu Z, et al. Zika virus hijacks stress granule proteins and modulates the host stress response. J Virol. 2017;91(16):10-1128. doi:10.1128/JVI.00474-17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Ramasamy A, Verduzco-Gutierrez M, Brode WM, Melamed E. Acute and post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a review of risk factors and social determinants. Virol J. 2023;20(1):124. doi:10.1186/s12985-023-02061-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan P, Shen M, Yu Z, et al. SARS-CoV-2 N protein promotes NLRP3 inflammasome activation to induce hyperinflammation. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):4664. doi:10.1038/s41467-021-25015-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghimire L, Paudel S, Jin L, Jeyaseelan S. The NLRP6 inflammasome in health and disease. Mucosal Immunol. 2020;13(3):388-398. doi:10.1038/s41385-020-0256-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lage SL, Amaral EP, Hilligan KL, et al. Persistent oxidative stress and inflammasome activation in CD14highCD16&#x2212; monocytes from COVID-19 patients. Front Immunol. 2021;12:799558. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.799558</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nallur G. Interaction of the SARS-COV2 Envelope Protein (E) with Lysophosphatidic Acid Receptor 1 (LPAR1) and additional human proteins involved in inflammation, immunity, ADP ribosylation and vesicular transport. Immunity, ADP Ribosylation and Vesicular Transport (September 24, 2020). iSCIENCE-September. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angosto-Bazarra D, Molina-L&#xf3;pez C, Pelegr&#xed;n P. Physiological and pathophysiological functions of NLRP6: pro- and anti-inflammatory roles. Commun Biol. 2022;5(1):524. doi:10.1038/s42003-022-03491-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao N, Di B, Xu L. The NLRP3 inflammasome and COVID-19: activation, pathogenesis and therapeutic strategies. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2021;61:2-15. doi:10.1016/j.cytogfr.2021.06.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chau BA, Chen V, Cochrane AW, Parent LJ, Mouland AJ. Liquid-liquid phase separation of nucleocapsid proteins during SARS-CoV-2 and HIV-1 replication. Cell Rep. 2023;42(1):111968. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2022.111968</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schonthal AH. Endoplasmic reticulum stress: its role in disease and novel prospects for therapy. Scientifica. 2012;2012:857516. doi:10.6064/2012/857516</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li A, Song NJ, Riesenberg BP, Li Z. The emerging roles of endoplasmic reticulum stress in balancing immunity and tolerance in health and diseases: mechanisms and opportunities. Front Immunol. 2020;10:3154. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2019.03154</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yiang GT, Wu CC, Lu CL, et al. Endoplasmic reticulum stress in elderly patients with COVID-19: potential of melatonin treatment. Viruses. 2023;15(1):156. doi:10.3390/v15010156</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicchitta CV. An emerging role for the endoplasmic reticulum in stress granule biogenesis. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2024;156:160-166. doi:10.1016/j.semcdb.2022.09.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo YY, Wu JJ, Li YM. Regulation of liquid-liquid phase separation with focus on post-translational modifications. Chem Commun. 2021;57(98):13275-13287. doi:10.1039/d1cc05266g</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Gan Y, Cao J, Dong X, Ouyang W. Pathophysiology of stress granules: an emerging link to diseases. Int J Mol Med. 2022;49(4):44. doi:10.3892/ijmm.2022.5099</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Yang W, Li B, Yuan S, Wang F. Response to stress in biological disorders: implications of stress granule assembly and function. Cell Prolif. 2021;54(8):e13086. doi:10.1111/cpr.13086</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsivgoulis G, Palaiodimou L, Katsanos AH, et al. Neurological manifestations and implications of COVID-19 pandemic. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2020;13:1756286420932036. doi:10.1177/1756286420932036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein RS, Garber C, Funk KE, et al. Neuroinflammation during RNA viral infections. Annu Rev Immunol. 2019;37:73-95. doi:10.1146/annurev-immunol-042718-041417</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collantes MEV, Espiritu AI, Sy MCC, Anlacan VMM, Jamora RDG. Neurological manifestations in COVID-19 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Can J Neurol Sci. 2021;48(1):66-76. doi:10.1017/cjn.2020.146</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paniz-Mondolfi A, Bryce C, Grimes Z, et al. Central nervous system involvement by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2). J Med Virol. 2020;92(7):699-702. doi:10.1002/jmv.25915</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Xu X, Chen Z, et al. Nervous system involvement after infection with COVID-19 and other coronaviruses. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:18-22. doi:10.1016/j.bbi.2020.03.031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varatharaj A, Galea I. The blood-brain barrier in systemic inflammation. Brain Behav Immun. 2017;60:1-12. doi:10.1016/j.bbi.2016.03.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galea I. The blood-brain barrier in systemic infection and inflammation. Cell Mol Immunol. 2021;18(11):2489-2501. doi:10.1038/s41423-021-00757-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels BP, Holman DW, Cruz-Orengo L, Jujjavarapu H, Durrant DM, Klein RS. Viral pathogen-associated molecular patterns regulate blood-brain barrier integrity via competing innate cytokine signals. mBio. 2014;5(5):e01476-01414. doi:10.1128/mBio.01476-14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels BP, Jujjavarapu H, Durrant DM, et al. Regional astrocyte IFN signaling restricts pathogenesis during neurotropic viral infection. J Clin Invest. 2017;127(3):843-856. doi:10.1172/JCI88720</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skelly DT, Hennessy E, Dansereau MA, Cunningham C. A systematic analysis of the peripheral and CNS effects of systemic LPS, IL-1beta, [corrected] TNF-alpha and IL-6 challenges in C57BL/6 mice. PLoS One. 2013;8(7):e69123. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0069123</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong R, L&#xe9;n&#xe1;rt N, Hill L, et al. Interleukin-1 mediates ischaemic brain injury via distinct actions on endothelial cells and cholinergic neurons. Brain Behav Immun. 2019;76:126-138. doi:10.1016/j.bbi.2018.11.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pajo AT, Espiritu AI, Apor ADAO, Jamora RDG. Neuropathologic findings of patients with COVID-19: a systematic review. Neurol Sci. 2021;42(4):1255-1266. doi:10.1007/s10072-021-05068-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caramaschi S, Kapp ME, Miller SE, et al. Histopathological findings and clinicopathologic correlation in COVID-19: a systematic review. Mod Pathol. 2021;34(9):1614-1633. doi:10.1038/s41379-021-00814-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Casta&#xf1;eda A, Lu P, Geraghty AC, et al. Mild respiratory COVID can cause multi-lineage neural cell and myelin dysregulation. Cell. 2022;185(14):2452-2468. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2022.06.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taeschler P, Adamo S, Deng Y, et al. T-cell recovery and evidence of persistent immune activation 12 months after severe COVID-19. Allergy. 2022;77(8):2468-2481. doi:10.1111/all.15372</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergamaschi L, Mescia F, Turner L, et al. Longitudinal analysis reveals that delayed bystander CD8+ T cell activation and early immune pathology distinguish severe COVID-19 from mild disease. Immunity. 2021;54(6):1257-1275. doi:10.1016/j.immuni.2021.05.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballering AV, van Zon SKR, Olde Hartman TC, Rosmalen JGM. Persistence of somatic symptoms after COVID-19 in the Netherlands: an observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022;400(10350):452-461. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(22)01214-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan NA. The road to addressing Long Covid. Science. 2021;373(6554):491-493. doi:10.1126/science.abg7113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pluss M, Mese K, Kowallick JT, Schuster A, Tampe D, Tampe B. Case report: cytomegalovirus reactivation and pericarditis following ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccination against SARS-CoV-2. Front Immunol. 2021;12:784145. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.784145</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): an overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front Microbiol. 2021;12:698169. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2021.698169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zollner A, Koch R, Jukic A, et al. Postacute COVID-19 is characterized by gut viral antigen persistence in inflammatory bowel diseases. Gastroenterology. 2022;163(2):495-506. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2022.04.037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatto I, Biagioni E, Coloretti I, et al. Cytomegalovirus blood reactivation in COVID-19 critically ill patients: risk factors and impact on mortality. Intensive Care Med. 2022;48(6):706-713. doi:10.1007/s00134-022-06716-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filbin MR, Mehta A, Schneider AM, et al. Longitudinal proteomic analysis of severe COVID-19 reveals survival-associated signatures, tissue-specific cell death, and cell-cell interactions. Cell Reports Medicine. 2021;2(5):100287. doi:10.1016/j.xcrm.2021.100287</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahase E. Covid-19: what do we know about &#x201c;long covid&#x201d;? BMJ. 2020;370:m2815. doi:10.1136/bmj.m2815</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tejerina F, Catalan P, Rodriguez-Grande C, et al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome. SARS-CoV-2 RNA detection in plasma, stool, and urine in patients with persistent symptoms after COVID-19. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22(1):211. doi:10.1186/s12879-022-07153-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Hang X, Wei B, et al. Persistent SARS-COV-2 RNA positivity in a patient for 92 days after disease onset: a case report. Medicine. 2020;99(34):e21865. doi:10.1097/MD.0000000000021865</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truong TT, Ryutov A, Pandey U, et al. Increased viral variants in children and young adults with impaired humoral immunity and persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection: a consecutive case series. EBioMedicine. 2021;67:103355. doi:10.1016/j.ebiom.2021.103355</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma MJ, Qiu SF, Cui XM, et al. Persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection in asymptomatic young adults. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2022;7(1):77. doi:10.1038/s41392-022-00931-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caba&#xf1;ero-Navalon MD, Garcia-Bustos V, Ruiz-Rodriguez P, et al. Persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection with repeated clinical recurrence in a patient with common variable immunodeficiency. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28(2):308-310. doi:10.1016/j.cmi.2021.10.021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B, Fan J, Huang J, et al. Clinical and molecular characteristics of COVID-19 patients with persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):3501. doi:10.1038/s41467-021-23621-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irrera N, Russo M, Pallio G, et al. The role of NLRP3 inflammasome in the pathogenesis of traumatic brain injury. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(17):6204. doi:10.3390/ijms21176204</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangan MSJ, Olhava EJ, Roush WR, Seidel HM, Glick GD, Latz E. Targeting the NLRP3 inflammasome in inflammatory diseases. Nat Rev Drug Discovery. 2018;17(8):588-606. doi:10.1038/nrd.2018.97</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrero-Andres A, Panisello-Rosello A, Rosello-Catafau J, Folch-Puy E. NLRP3 inflammasome-mediated inflammation in acute pancreatitis. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(15):5386. doi:10.3390/ijms21155386</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fusco R, Siracusa R, Genovese T, Cuzzocrea S, Di Paola R. Focus on the role of NLRP3 inflammasome in diseases. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(12):4223. doi:10.3390/ijms21124223</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dostert C, P&#xe9;trilli V, Van Bruggen R, Steele C, Mossman BT, Tschopp J. Innate immune activation through Nalp3 inflammasome sensing of asbestos and silica. Science. 2008;320(5876):674-677. doi:10.1126/science.1156995</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toldo S, Abbate A. The NLRP3 inflammasome in acute myocardial infarction. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2018;15(4):203-214. doi:10.1038/nrcardio.2017.161</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HM, Kim JJ, Kim HJ, Shong M, Ku BJ, Jo EK. Upregulated NLRP3 inflammasome activation in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes. 2013;62(1):194-204. doi:10.2337/db12-0420</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baragetti A, Catapano AL, Magni P. Multifactorial activation of NLRP3 inflammasome: relevance for a precision approach to atherosclerotic cardiovascular risk and disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(12):4459. doi:10.3390/ijms21124459</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinon F, P&#xe9;trilli V, Mayor A, Tardivel A, Tschopp J. Gout-associated uric acid crystals activate the NALP3 inflammasome. Nature. 2006;440(7081):237-241. doi:10.1038/nature04516</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathews RJ, Robinson JI, Battellino M, et al. Evidence of NLRP3-inflammasome activation in rheumatoid arthritis (RA); genetic variants within the NLRP3-inflammasome complex in relation to susceptibility to RA and response to anti-TNF treatment. Ann Rheum Dis. 2014;73(6):1202-1210. doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2013-203276</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heneka MT, Kummer MP, Stutz A, et al. NLRP3 is activated in Alzheimer's disease and contributes to pathology in APP/PS1 mice. Nature. 2013;493(7434):674-678. doi:10.1038/nature11729</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito M, Shichita T, Okada M, et al. Bruton's tyrosine kinase is essential for NLRP3 inflammasome activation and contributes to ischaemic brain injury. Nat Commun. 2015;6:7360. doi:10.1038/ncomms8360</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terpos E, Ntanasis-Stathopoulos I, Elalamy I, et al. Hematological findings and complications of COVID-19. Am J Hematol. 2020;95(7):834-847. doi:10.1002/ajh.25829</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahamed J, Laurence J. Long COVID endotheliopathy: hypothesized mechanisms and potential therapeutic approaches. J Clin Invest. 2022;132(15):e161167. doi:10.1172/JCI161167</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Wu D, Guo W, et al. Clinical and immunological features of severe and moderate coronavirus disease 2019. J Clin Invest. 2020;130(5):2620-2629. doi:10.1172/JCI137244</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J, Tacquard C, Severac F, et al. High risk of thrombosis in patients with severe SARS-CoV-2 infection: a multicenter prospective cohort study. Intensive Care Med. 2020;46(6):1089-1098. doi:10.1007/s00134-020-06062-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karampela I, Christodoulatos GS, Vallianou N, et al. Circulating chemerin and its kinetics may be a useful diagnostic and prognostic biomarker in critically ill patients with sepsis: a prospective study. Biomolecules. 2022;12(2):301. doi:10.3390/biom12020301</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karampela I, Kandri E, Antonakos G, et al. Kinetics of circulating fetuin-A may predict mortality independently from adiponectin, high molecular weight adiponectin and prognostic factors in critically ill patients with sepsis: a prospective study. J Crit Care. 2017;41:78-85. doi:10.1016/j.jcrc.2017.05.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133-146. doi:10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roca-Fernandez A, Wamil M, Telford A, et al. Cardiac abnormalities in Long COVID 1-year post-SARS-CoV-2 infection. Open Heart. 2023;10(1):e002241. doi:10.1136/openhrt-2022-002241</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes SE, Haroon S, Subramanian A, et al. Development and validation of the symptom burden questionnaire for long covid (SBQ-LC): Rasch analysis. BMJ. 2022;377:e070230. doi:10.1136/bmj-2022-070230</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal SM, Landers DB, Hollenberg SM, et al. Prospective evaluation of autonomic dysfunction in post-acute sequela of COVID-19. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79(23):2325-2330. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2022.03.357</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavileci B, &#xd6;zdemir E, &#xd6;zdemir B, Ereren E, Cengiz M. De-novo development of fragmented QRS during a six-month follow-up period in patients with COVID-19 disease and its cardiac effects. J Electrocardiol. 2022;72:44-48. doi:10.1016/j.jelectrocard.2022.02.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grist JT, Collier GJ, Walters H, et al. Lung abnormalities detected with hyperpolarized 129Xe MRI in patients with long COVID. Radiology. 2022;305(3):709-717. doi:10.1148/radiol.220069</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman L, Bested AC, Bonilla HF, et al. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: essentials of diagnosis and management. Mayo Clin Proc. 2021;96(11):2861-2878. doi:10.1016/j.mayocp.2021.07.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler RJ. Therapeutics-how to treat phase separation-associated diseases. Emerg Top Life Sci. 2020;4(3):307-318. doi:10.1042/ETLS20190176</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malinovska L, Kroschwald S, Alberti S. Protein disorder, prion propensities, and self-organizing macromolecular collectives. Biochim Biophys Acta Proteins Proteom. 2013;1834(5):918-931. doi:10.1016/j.bbapap.2013.01.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen I, Shewmaker F. The role of post-translational modifications in the phase transitions of intrinsically disordered proteins. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20(21):5501. doi:10.3390/ijms20215501</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradhan A, Mishra S, Surolia A, Panda D. C1 inhibits liquid-liquid phase separation and oligomerization of tau and protects neuroblastoma cells against toxic tau oligomers. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2021;12(11):1989-2002. doi:10.1021/acschemneuro.1c00098</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zbinden A, P&#xe9;rez-Berlanga M, De Rossi P, Polymenidou M. Phase separation and neurodegenerative diseases: a disturbance in the force. Dev Cell. 2020;55(1):45-68. doi:10.1016/j.devcel.2020.09.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan H, Sun Q, Zhang W, Liu Y, Lai L. Targeting intrinsically disordered proteins at the edge of chaos. Drug Discovery Today. 2019;24(1):217-227. doi:10.1016/j.drudis.2018.09.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macedo B, Cordeiro Y. Unraveling prion protein interactions with aptamers and other PrP-binding nucleic acids. Int J Mol Sci. 2017;18(5):1023. doi:10.3390/ijms18051023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matos CO, Passos YM, Amaral MJ, et al. Liquid-liquid phase separation and fibrillation of the prion protein modulated by a high-affinity DNA aptamer. FASEB J. 2020;34(1):365-385. doi:10.1096/fj.201901897R</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni S, Zhuo Z, Pan Y, et al. Recent progress in aptamer discoveries and modifications for therapeutic applications. ACS Appl Mater Interfaces. 2021;13(8):9500-9519. doi:10.1021/acsami.0c05750</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shola David M, Kanayeva D. Enzyme linked oligonucleotide assay for the sensitive detection of SARS-CoV-2 variants. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2022;12:1017542. doi:10.3389/fcimb.2022.1017542</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Juhas M, Kwok CK. Aptamers targeting SARS-COV-2: a promising tool to fight against COVID-19. Trends Biotechnol. 2023;41(4):528-544. doi:10.1016/j.tibtech.2022.07.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fare CM, Shorter J. (Dis)Solving the problem of aberrant protein states. Dis Models &amp; Mech. 2021;14(5):dmm048983. doi:10.1242/dmm.048983</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jack A, Ferro LS, Trnka MJ, et al. SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein forms condensates with viral genomic RNA. PLoS Biol. 2021;19(10):e3001425. doi:10.1371/journal.pbio.3001425</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>