<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39429336</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19 Infection and Vaccination Effects on Breast Implant Illness: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e69772</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e69772</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e69772</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.69772</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Breast implant illness (BII) is a term used to describe a range of symptoms associated with silicone breast implants. This condition suggests that silicone may trigger symptoms in individuals who are immunologically predisposed, and the spectrum of symptoms may be linked to autonomic dysregulation in these patients. We present the case of a female patient in her mid-40s with a history of autoimmune thyroiditis who had not required prior therapy. She underwent breast augmentation and subsequently developed gradual difficulties. After recovering from a COVID-19 infection, her nonspecific symptoms, consistent with BII, worsened. These symptoms included chronic fatigue, hair loss, dry skin, petechiae, low-grade fever, and frequent urination. Additionally, she developed symptoms associated with long COVID. A subsequent Pfizer-BioNTech COVID-19 vaccination further exacerbated her symptoms and overall condition. Due to the broad spectrum of nonspecific symptoms, the patient underwent numerous screenings over an 18-month period, which were inconclusive. We hypothesize that the vaccination and previous infection had a synergistic effect on her ongoing BII symptoms, contributing to the worsening of her condition. An isolated right-sided seroma with left-sided lymphadenopathy appeared to be a side effect of the vaccine. Additionally, the patient developed a newly diagnosed allergy to polyethylene glycol and other allergic manifestations, such as chronic urticaria, which are consistent with autonomic nervous system dysregulation and long COVID. These symptoms resolved within three weeks of explantation with en bloc capsulectomy. It is noteworthy that the patient was unaware of BII until an MRI revealed a suspected intracapsular implant rupture on the right side, which led to the decision to remove the implants.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Bohac et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bohac</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Plastic Surgery, Faculty of Medicine, Institute of Medical Biology, Genetics and Clinical Genetics, Comenius University Bratislava, Bratislava, SVK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chot&#xe1;rov&#xe1;</LastName><ForeName>Martina</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Plastic Surgery, University Hospital Bratislava, Bratislava, SVK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mitevov&#xe1;</LastName><ForeName>Dominika</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Plastic Surgery, University Hospital Bratislava, Bratislava, SVK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mayer</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgery, IV. Department of Surgery, Comenius University in Bratislava, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Bratislava, Bratislava, SVK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autonomic dysregulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breast augmentation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breast implant illness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">capsulectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid 19</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Consent was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: This paper was created thanks to support of the Scientific Grant Agency (VEGA) under contracts No. 2/0067/22 There is no conflict of interest for all authors regarding the research presented in this article. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39429336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11491132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.69772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Assessing long-term outcomes in breast implant illness: the missing link? A systematic review. Rohrich RJ, Bellamy JL, Alleyne B. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2022;149:638&#x2013;645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35103633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of explantation on systemic disease symptoms and quality of life in patients with breast implant illness: a prospective cohort study. Bird GR, Niessen FB. Sci Rep. 2022;12:21073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9726875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36473891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Understanding breast implant illness, before and after explantation: a patient-reported outcomes study. Wee CE, Younis J, Isbester K, et al. Ann Plast Surg. 2020;85:0&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7294749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Understanding breast implant illness: etiology is the key. Yang S, Klietz ML, Harren AK, Wei Q, Hirsch T, Aitzetm&#xfc;ller MM. Aesthet Surg J. 2022;42:370&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33871569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>QS9: host biofilm interaction in breast implant illness. Khan I, Minto RE, Kelley-Patteson C, et al. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2021;9:48&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autoantibody production in rabbits. II. Organ-specific autontibody in rabbits injected with rat tissues. Asherson GL, Dumonde DC. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/13965166/ Immunology. 1963;6:19&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1423192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13965166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hypergammaglobulinemia by prolonged adjuvancity in man. Disorders developed after augmentation mammaplasty. Miyoshi K, Miyamura T, Kobayashi Y, et al. Japan Med J. 1964;2122:9&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breast implant illness: a way forward. Magnusson MR, Cooter RD, Rakhorst H, McGuire PA, Adams WP Jr, Deva AK. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2019;143:74&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30817559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silicone breast implants and the risk of autoimmune/rheumatic disorders: a real-world analysis. Watad A, Rosenberg V, Tiosano S, et al. Int J Epidemiol. 2018;47:1846&#x2013;1854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30329056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuroimaging in breast implant illness: an fMRI pilot study. Miser&#xe9; RM, Rutten S, van den Hurk J, Colaris MJ, van der Hulst RR. Aesthet Surg J. 2023;43:51&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9830978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35926836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Distant migration of multiple siliconomas in lower extremities following breast implant rupture: case report. Oh JH, Song SY, Lew DH, Lee DW. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2016;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5096512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27826457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breast implant-associated immunological disorders. Suh LJ, Khan I, Kelley-Patteson C, Mohan G, Hassanein AH, Sinha M. J Immunol Res. 2022;2022:8536149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9095406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35571560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Case report: evidence of migratory silicone particles arising from cohesive silicone breast implants. Mustaf&#xe1; JC, Fleury EF, Dijkman HB. Front Glob Womens Health. 2022;3:730276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9085291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35547828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-COVID dysautonomias: what we know and (mainly) what we don't know. Goldstein DS. Nat Rev Neurol. 2024;20:99&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38212633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adverse reactions to cosmetic implants after COVID-19 vaccination: a literature review. Cheng WJ, Cai ZX, Tang XJ. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2023;22:3199&#x2013;3212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37592436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autoimmune diseases induced or exacerbated by COVID-19: a single center experience. Ishay Y, Kenig A, Rubin L, Shamriz O, Kharouf F. Autoimmune Dis. 2022;2022:9171284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9470368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36111059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autoimmune complications of COVID-19 and potential consequences for long-lasting disease syndromes. Amiral J, Seghatchian J. Transfus Apher Sci. 2023;62:103625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9757887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36585276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autoimmune dysautonomia in women with silicone breast implants. Halpert G, Watad A, Tsur AM, et al. J Autoimmun. 2021;120:102631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33799099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autoimmune autonomic dysfunction syndromes: potential involvement and pathophysiology related to complex regional pain syndrome, fibromyalgia, chronic fatigue syndrome, silicone breast implant-related symptoms and post-COVID syndrome. Mahroum N, Shoenfeld Y. Pathophysiology. 2022;29:414&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9396987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35997389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breast implant illness: scientific evidence of its existence. Cohen Tervaert JW, Mohazab N, Redmond D, van Eeden C, Osman M. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2022;18:15&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34882509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allergic manifestations in women with silicone breast implants. Tanay G, Halpert G, Dotan A, et al. Hum Immunol. 2024;85:110747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38155072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breast prosthesis syndrome: pathophysiology and management algorithm. Caravantes-Cortes MI, Roldan-Valadez E, Zwojewski-Martinez RD, Salazar-Ruiz SY, Carballo-Zarate AA. Aesthetic Plast Surg. 2020;44:1423&#x2013;1437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32152711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 vaccines. Hahn WO, Wiley Z. Infect Dis Clin North Am. 2022;36:481&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8802612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35636910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Axillary lymphadenopathy associated with COVID-19 vaccination: updates and recommendations. Schwaner SL. J Radiol Nurs. 2022;41:309&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35999889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitigating the impact of coronavirus disease (COVID-19) vaccinations on patients undergoing breast imaging examinations: a pragmatic approach. Lehman CD, Lamb LR, D'Alessandro HA. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2021;217:584&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33617288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A rare case of BIA-ALCL mass associated with mastectomy skin flap erythema after immunization with COVID-19. Garusi C, De Antoni E, Fiori S, Vanazzi A, Pileri SA. Aesthetic Plast Surg. 2023;47:116&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9666973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36380099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overview of reported breast implant-related reactions after COVID-19 infection or vaccination. Mahrhofer M, Weitgasser L, Schoeller T. Aesthet Surg J. 2022;42:0&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9383747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35435942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breast implant seroma: a SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccine side effect. Kayser F, Fourneau H, Mazy OC, Mazy S. J Clin Ultrasound. 2021;49:984&#x2013;986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8426943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34405902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Development of acute seroma around breast implants following administration of COVID-19 vaccination. Mak C, Graham S, Deva A. Aesthet Surg J. 2022;42:0&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9383379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35134133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regional lymphadenopathy following COVID-19 vaccination: literature review and considerations for patient management in breast cancer care. Garreffa E, Hamad A, O'Sullivan CC, et al. Eur J Cancer. 2021;159:38&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8502686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34731748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delayed prosthetic seroma: a localized inflammatory response to COVID vaccination and infection? Chan SL, Hsieh MK, Mok JW, Kong TY. Eur J Plast Surg. 2023;46:125&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9813890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36624820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19/SARS-CoV-2 virus spike protein-related delayed inflammatory reaction to hyaluronic acid dermal fillers: a challenging clinical conundrum in diagnosis and treatment. Munavalli GG, Guthridge R, Knutsen-Larson S, Brodsky A, Matthew E, Landau M. Arch Dermatol Res. 2022;314:1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7871141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33559733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A case report of capsular contracture immediately following COVID-19 vaccination. Restifo RJ. Aesthet Surg J Open Forum. 2021;3:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8241424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breast implant illness: a cohort study. Serena TJ, Habib P, Derosa A. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10208020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37228535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cognitive impairment, sleep disturbance, and depression in women with silicone breast implants: association with autoantibodies against autonomic nervous system receptors. Tocut M, Halpert G, Tsur AM, et al. Biomolecules. 2022;12:776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9221347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35740901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palpitation in women with silicone breast implants: association with autoantibodies against autonomic nervous system. Elroy T, Halpert G, Tsur AM, Heidecke H, Amital H, Shoenfeld Y. Immunol Res. 2024;72:155&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37845561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ISAPS International Survey on Aesthetic/Cosmetic Procedures Performed in 2023. https://www.isaps.org/media/rxnfqibn/isaps-global-survey_2023.pdf https://www.isaps.org/media/rxnfqibn/isaps-global-survey_2023.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revision breast augmentation. Denney BD, Cohn AB, Bosworth JW, Kumbla PA. Semin Plast Surg. 2021;35:98&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8186996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34121945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Self-reported health complaints in women undergoing explantation of breast implants. Miser&#xe9; RM, van der Hulst RR. Aesthet Surg J. 2022;42:171&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8756082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33252630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of common and uncommon problems after primary breast augmentation. Nahabedian MY, Patel K. Clin Plast Surg. 2009;36:127-38, vii.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19055968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The history and safety of breast implants. Molitor M, M&#x11b;&#x161;&#x165;&#xe1;k O, Kalinov&#xe1; L, Krajcov&#xe1; A, M&#x11b;&#x161;&#x165;&#xe1;k J. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25484272/ Acta Chir Plast. 2014;56:15&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25484272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breast implant illness: treatment using total capsulectomy and implant removal. Metzinger SE, Homsy C, Chun MJ, Metzinger RC. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35602522/ Eplasty. 2022;22:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9097901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35602522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>En bloc capsulectomy for breast implant illness: a social media phenomenon? Keane G, Chi D, Ha AY, Myckatyn TM. Aesthet Surg J. 2021;41:448&#x2013;459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32940709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breast implant illness: surgical, autoimmune, and breast reconstruction associations. Varela-Chinchilla C, Salinas-McQuary G, Segura-Azuara N, et al.  https://doi-1org-1s3x6wrwi0926.erproxy.cvtisr.sk/10.3390/surgeries3020013 Surgeries. 2022;3:111&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Commentary on: En bloc capsulectomy for breast implant illness: a social media phenomenon? McGuire PA. Aesthet Surg J. 2021;41:460&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32940664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical recommendations for diagnosis and treatment according to current updated knowledge on BIA-ALCL. Longo B, Di Napoli A, Curigliano G, et al. Breast. 2022;66:332&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9763507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36502569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>