<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38204779</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0973-6131</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Season>May-Aug</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of yoga</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Yoga</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of Meditation-based Interventions on Health Problems Caused by COVID-19 Pandemic: Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>72</StartPage><EndPage>78</EndPage><MedlinePgn>72-78</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/ijoy.ijoy_112_23</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This article provides a quantitative review of the potential applications of meditation-based interventions (MBIs) in addressing the major health issues arising from the COVID-19 pandemic. The review assesses the effectiveness of MBIs on five prevalent disorders during the pandemic, namely depression, anxiety, stress, insomnia, and long COVID. This is achieved by selecting and scrutinizing seven studies that involve various types of online randomized controlled trials and utilize control group outcomes for effectiveness evaluation. The findings reveal a significant impact of MBIs on overall distress disorder, encompassing symptoms of depression, anxiety, and stress, with effectiveness ranging from 20.5% to 68.8%. The interventions also show moderate effectiveness on insomnia disorder with improvements between 5.2% and 38.5%. However, the effectiveness on long COVID disorder presents a mixed picture, with improvements varying from 0.0% to 71.2% across 13 related symptoms or qualities examined. This review offers compelling evidence supporting the effectiveness of MBIs in alleviating these five prevalent disorders resulting from the COVID-19 pandemic.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2023 International Journal of Yoga.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tseng</LastName><ForeName>Ampere A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Manufacturing Institute, Arizona State University, Tempe, Arizona, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Yoga</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101313247</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0973-6131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 pandemic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intervention effectiveness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meditation-based interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental and physical symptoms</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38204779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10775841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijoy.ijoy_112_23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJY-16-72</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Walsh R, Shapiro SL. The meeting of meditative disciplines and Western psychology: A mutually enriching dialogue. Am Psychol. 2006;61:227&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16594839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampaio CV, Lima MG, Ladeia AM. Meditation, health and scientific investigations: Review of the literature. J Relig Health. 2017;56:411&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26915053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng AA. Buddhist meditation and generosity to Chinese Buddhists during the COVID-19 pandemic. Rev Relig Chin Soc. 2022;9:198&#x2013;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng AA. Scientific evidence of health benefits by practicing mantra meditation: Narrative review. Int J Yoga. 2022;15:89&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9623891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36329765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ospina MB, Bond K, Karkhaneh M, Tjosvold L, Vandermeer B, Liang Y, et al. Meditation practices for health: State of the research. Evid Rep Technol Assess (Full Rep) 2007;155:1&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4780968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17764203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Health Interview Survey (NHIS)   Hyattsville (MD): The National Center for Health Statistics; 2013.  [Last accessed on 2023 May 30]. Public Use Data Release. Available from: https://www.ftp.cdc.gov/pub/health_statistics/nchs/dataset_documentation/NHIS/2012/srvydesc.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke A, Lam CN, Stussman B, Yang H. Prevalence and patterns of use of mantra, mindfulness and spiritual meditation among adults in the United States. BMC Complement Altern Med. 2017;17:316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5472955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28619092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutz A, Slagter HA, Dunne JD, Davidson RJ. Attention regulation and monitoring in meditation. Trends Cogn Sci. 2008;12:163&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2693206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18329323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bethesda (MD): National Center for Complementary and Alternative Medicine (NCCAM); 2023.  [Last accessed on 2023 Jan 25]. Meditation and Mindfulness: What You Need to Know. Available from: https://www.nccih.nih.gov/health/meditation-and-mindfulness-what-you-need-to-know .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>New York: UN News; 2023.  [Last accessed on 2023 May 25]. WHO Chief Declares End to COVID-19 as a Global Health Emergency. Available from: https://www.news.un.org/en/story/2023/05/1136367 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey RA. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2008. Design of Comparative Experiments.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godwin M, Ruhland L, Casson I, MacDonald S, Delva D, Birtwhistle R, et al. Pragmatic controlled clinical trials in primary care: The struggle between external and internal validity. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2003;3:28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC317298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14690550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson VE. Revised standards for statistical evidence. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2013;110:19313&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3845140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24218581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psychological Distress.  [Last accessed on 2023 Mar 25];American Psychological Association.  Available from: https://www.dictionary.apa.org/psychological-distress .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vierti&#xf6; S, Kiviruusu O, Piirtola M, Kaprio J, Korhonen T, Marttunen M, et al. Factors contributing to psychological distress in the working population, with a special reference to gender difference. BMC Public Health. 2021;21:611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akin A, &#xc7;etin B. The Depression Anxiety and Stress Scale (DASS): The study of validity and reliability. Educational Sciences: Theory and Practice. 2007;7:260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  . Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization; 2022.  [Last accessed on 2023 Jul 25]. COVID-19 Pandemic Triggers 25% Increase in Prevalence of Anxiety and Depression Worldwide. Available from: https://www.who.int/news/item/02-03-2022-covid-19-pandemic-triggers-25-increase-in-prevalence-of-anxiety-and-depression-worldwide .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>APA: U.S. Adults Report Highest Stress Level Since Early Days of the COVID-19 Pandemic.  [Last accessed on 2023 Jul 25];American Psychological Association. 2021  Available from: https://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/2021/02/adults-stress-pandemic .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komariah M, Ibrahim K, Pahria T, Rahayuwati L, Somantri I. Effect of mindfulness breathing meditation on depression, anxiety, and stress: A randomized controlled trial among university students. Healthcare (Basel) 2022;11:26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9819153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36611488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Zhang A, Liu C, Xiao J, Wang K. A brief online mindfulness-based group intervention for psychological distress among Chinese residents during COVID-19: A pilot randomized controlled trial. Mindfulness. 2021;12:1502&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7972025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33758629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabat-Zinn J. Some reflections on the origins of MBSR, skillful means, and the trouble with maps. Contemp Buddhism. 2011;12:281&#x2013;306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Kelly BC, Liu T, Zhang G, Hao W. Factorial structure of the Brief Symptom Inventory (BSI)-18 among Chinese drug users. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2013;133:368&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3818478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23906998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barczak-Scarboro NE, Van Cappellen P, Fredrickson BL. For whom do meditation interventions improve mental health symptoms? Looking at the roles of psychological and biological resources over time. Mindfulness. 2021;12:2781&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;ney E, Cengizhan S&#xd6;, Karata&#x15f; Okyay E, Bal Z, U&#xe7;ar T. Effect of the mindfulness-based stress reduction program on stress, anxiety, and childbirth fear in pregnant women diagnosed with COVID-19. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2022;47:101566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8863420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35219222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bethesda, Maryland: The National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, US National Institutes of Health; 2022.  [Last accessed on 2023 Aug 03]. What Is Insomnia? Available from: https://www.nhlbi.nih.gov/health/insomnia#:~:text=Insomnia%20is%20a%20common%20sleep, feel%20sleepy%20during%20the%20day .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusch HL, Rosario M, Levison LM, Olivera A, Livingston WS, Wu T, et al. The effect of mindfulness meditation on sleep quality: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2019;1445:5&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6557693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30575050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JM, Wu R, Zhang T, Zhong SY, Hu T, Wang D, et al. Psychological responses of medical staff during COVID-19 and the adjustment effect of brief mindfulness meditation. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2022;48:101600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9074297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35580535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soldatos CR, Dikeos DG, Paparrigopoulos TJ. Athens insomnia scale: Validation of an instrument based on ICD-10 criteria. J Psychosom Res. 2000;48:555&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11033374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausswirth C, Nesi X, Dubois A, Duforez F, Rougier Y, Slattery K. Four weeks of a neuro-meditation program improves sleep quality and reduces hypertension in nursing staff during the COVID-19 pandemic: A parallel randomized controlled trial. Front Psychol. 2022;13:854474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9130829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35645851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klimm HD, Dreyfus JF, Delmotte M. Zopiclone versus nitrazepam: A double-blind comparative study of efficacy and tolerance in elderly patients with chronic insomnia. Sleep. 1987;10(Suppl 1):73&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3326118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake CL, Jefferson C, Roehrs T, Roth T. Stress-related sleep disturbance and polysomnographic response to caffeine. Sleep Med. 2006;7:567&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2535762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16996309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or long COVID: A meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis. 2022;226:1593&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seang S, Itani O, Monsel G, Abdi B, Marcelin AG, Valantin MA, et al. Long COVID-19 symptoms: Clinical characteristics and recovery rate among non-severe outpatients over a six-month follow-up. Infect Dis Now. 2022;52:165&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8832844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35158095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID or Post-COVID Conditions  Atlanta [GA]: US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.  [Last accessed on 2023 Jan 25];2022  Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cahalan RM, Meade C, Mockler S. SingStrong-A singing and breathing retraining intervention for respiratory and other common symptoms of long COVID: A pilot study. Can J Respir Ther. 2022;58:20&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8906430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35359819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Halpin S, Gee J. Assessing long-term rehabilitation needs in COVID-19 survivors using a telephone screening tool (C19-YRS tool) Adv Clin Neurosci Rehabil. 2020;19:14&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poenaru S, Abdallah SJ, Corrales-Medina V, Cowan J. COVID-19 and post-infectious myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: A narrative review. Ther Adv Infect Dis. 2021;8:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8060761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33959278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausswirth C, Schmit C, Rougier Y, Coste A. Positive impacts of a four-week neuro-meditation program on cognitive function in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 patients: A randomized controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20:1361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9858974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36674117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can YS, Chalabianloo N, Ekiz D, Fernandez-Alvarez J, Riva G, Ersoy C. Personal stresslevel clustering and decision-level smoothing to enhance the performance of ambulatory stress detection with smartwatches. IEEE Access. 2020;8:38146&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>