<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37549214</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-8918</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current sports medicine reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Sports Med Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise is the Most Important Medicine for COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>284</StartPage><EndPage>289</EndPage><MedlinePgn>284-289</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/JSR.0000000000001092</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>COVID-19 infection and long COVID affect multiple organ systems, including the respiratory, cardiovascular, renal, digestive, neuroendocrine, musculoskeletal systems, and sensory organs. Exerkines, released during exercise, have a potent crosstalk effect between multiple body systems. This review describes the evidence of how exerkines can mitigate the effects of COVID-19 in each organ system that the virus affects. The evidence presented in the review suggests that exercise should be considered a first-line strategy in the prevention and treatment of COVID-19 infection and long COVID disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torres</LastName><ForeName>Georgia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Sports Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Constantinou</LastName><ForeName>Demitri</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Sports Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gradidge</LastName><ForeName>Philippe</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Sports Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Deepak</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Sports &amp; Exercise Medicine, Department of Family Medicine &amp; Primary Care, School of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patricios</LastName><ForeName>Jon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wits Sport and Health (WiSH), School of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Sports Med Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101134380</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1537-890X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37549214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0000000000001092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00149619-202308000-00007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization Web site [Internet]. Geneva (Switzerland): World Health Organization; [cited 2023 March 9]. Available from: https://covid19.who.int/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Narayan RK, Prasoon P, et al. COVID-19 mechanisms in the human body&#x2014;what we know so far. Front. Immunol. 2021; 12:693938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. [Internet]. 2023; [cited 2023 Feb 11]; Available from: https://www.nature.com/articles/s41579-022-00846-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallis R, Young DR, Tartof SY, et al. Physical inactivity is associated with a higher risk for severe COVID-19 outcomes: a study in 48 440 adult patients. Br. J. Sports Med. 2021; 55:1099&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmati M, Shamsi MM, Khoramipour K, et al. Baseline physical activity is associated with reduced mortality and disease outcomes in COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Rev. Medical Virol [Internet]. 2022 [cited 2023 Feb 11];32(5). Available from: https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/rmv.2349; 32:e2349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rmv.2349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzatvar Y, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, Izquierdo M, Garcia-Hermoso A. Physical activity and risk of infection, severity and mortality of COVID-19: a systematic review and non-linear dose&#x2013;response meta-analysis of data from 1 853 610 adults. Br. J. Sports Med. 2022; 56:1188&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steenkamp L, Saggers RT, Bandini R, et al. Small steps, strong shield: directly measured, moderate physical activity in 65 361 adults is associated with significant protective effects from severe COVID-19 outcomes. Br. J. Sports Med. 2022; 56:568&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young DR, Sallis JF, Baecker A, et al. Associations of physical inactivity and COVID-19 outcomes among subgroups. Am. J. Prev. Med. 2022; 64:492&#x2013;502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SW, Lee J, Moon SY, et al. Physical activity and the risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection, severe COVID-19 illness and COVID-19 related mortality in South Korea: a nationwide cohort study. Br. J. Sports Med. 2022; 56:901&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S, Ma C, Yang Z, et al. Hygiene behaviors associated with influenza-like illness among adults in Beijing, China: a large, population-based survey. PLoS One. 2016; 11:e0148448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong CM, Lai HK, Ou CQ, et al. Is exercise protective against influenza-associated mortality? PLoS One. 2008; 3:e2108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zbinden-Foncea H, Francaux M, Deldicque L, Hawley JA. Does high cardiorespiratory fitness confer some protection against proinflammatory responses after infection by SARS-CoV-2? Obesity. 2020; 28:1378&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen RAG, Arneja J, St Cyr K, et al. The association of estimated cardiorespiratory fitness with COVID-19 incidence and mortality: a cohort study. PLoS One. 2021; 16:e0250508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow LS, Gerszten RE, Taylor JM, et al. Exerkines in health, resilience and disease. Nat. Rev. Endocrinol. 2022; 18:273&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung MK, Karnik S, Saef J, et al. SARS-CoV-2 and ACE2: the biology and clinical data settling the ARB and ACEI controversy. EBioMedicine. 2020; 58:102907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishiga M, Wang DW, Han Y, et al. COVID-19 and cardiovascular disease: from basic mechanisms to clinical perspectives. Nat. Rev. Cardiol. 2020; 17:543&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingraham NE, Barakat AG, Reilkoff R, et al. Understanding the renin&#x2013;angiotensin&#x2013;aldosterone&#x2013;SARS-CoV axis: a comprehensive review. Eur. Respir. J. 2020; 56:2000912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaha KB, Manandhar DN, Cho JR, Adhikari A. COVID-19 and the heart: what we have learnt so far. Postgrad. Med. J. 2021; 97:655&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsoularis I, Fonseca-Rodr&#xed;guez O, Farrington P, et al. Risks of deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, and bleeding after COVID-19: nationwide self-controlled cases series and matched cohort study. BMJ. 2022; 377:e069590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osiaevi I, Schulze A, Evers G, et al. Persistent capillary rarefication in long COVID syndrome. Angiogenesis. 2023; 26:53&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godlee F. The miracle cure. BMJ. 2019; l5605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK, Saltin B. Exercise as medicine - evidence for prescribing exercise as therapy in 26 different chronic diseases. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports. 2015; 25:1&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiuza-Luces C, Garatachea N, Berger NA, Lucia A. Exercise is the real polypill. Physiology (Bethesda). 2013; 28:330&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, McAuley H, Harrison EM, et al. Physical, cognitive, and mental health impacts of COVID-19 after hospitalisation (PHOSP-COVID): a UK multicentre, prospective cohort study. Lancet. Respir. Med. 2021; 9:1275&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PHOSP-COVID Collaborative Group. Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet. Respir. Med. 2022; 10:761&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas M, Price OJ, Hull JH. Pulmonary function and COVID-19. Curr. Opin. Physiol. 2021; 21:29&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixit S, Borghi-Silva A, Bairapareddy KC. Revisiting pulmonary rehabilitation during COVID-19 pandemic: a narrative review. Rev. Cardiovasc. Med. 2021; 22:315&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed AA, Alawna M. Role of increasing the aerobic capacity on improving the function of immune and respiratory systems in patients with coronavirus (COVID-19): a review. Diabetes Metab. Syndr. 2020; 14:489&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lira FS, dos Santos T, Caldeira RS, et al. Short-term high- and moderate-intensity training modifies inflammatory and metabolic factors in response to acute exercise. Front. Physiol. 2017; 8:856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves CAM, Dantas PMS, dos Santos IK, et al. Effect of acute and chronic aerobic exercise on immunological markers: a systematic review. Front. Physiol. 2020; 10:1602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Az&#xf3;car-Gallardo J, Ojeda-Aravena A, Carrizo Largo J, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Mosqueira C. Can the immunological system of the upper respiratory tract, improved by physical exercise, act as a first immunological barrier against SARS-CoV-2? Expert Rev. Anti-Infect. Ther. 2022; 20:981&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkhatib SK, Alley J, Jepsen M, et al. Exercise duration modulates upper and lower respiratory fluid cellularity, antiviral activity, and lung gene expression. Physiol. Rep. [Internet]. 2021; [cited 2023 Mar 13];9(20). Available from: https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.14814/phy2.15075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.15075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhardwaj V, Dela Cruz M, et al. Exercise-induced myokines downregulates the ACE2 level in bronchial epithelial cells: implications for SARS-CoV-2 prevention. PLoS One. 2022; 17:e0271303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Z, Spaulding HR. Extracellular superoxide dismutase, a molecular transducer of health benefits of exercise. Redox Biol. 2020; 32:101508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebello CJ, Axelrod CL, Reynolds CF, et al. Exercise as a moderator of persistent neuroendocrine symptoms of COVID-19. Exerc. Sport Sci. Rev. 2022; 50:65&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDowell CP, Dishman RK, Gordon BR, Herring MP. Physical activity and anxiety: a systematic review and meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies. Am. J. Prev. Med. 2019; 57:545&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dishman RK, McDowell CP, Herring MP. Customary physical activity and odds of depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis of 111 prospective cohort studies. Br. J. Sports Med. 2021; 55:926&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vujic A, Lerchenm&#xfc;ller C, Wu TD, et al. Exercise induces new cardiomyocyte generation in the adult mammalian heart. Nat. Commun. 2018; 9:1659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Wang J, Cretoiu D, et al. Exercise-mediated regulation of autophagy in the cardiovascular system. J. Sport Health Sci. 2020; 9:203&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleh J, Peyssonnaux C, Singh KK, Edeas M. Mitochondria and microbiota dysfunction in COVID-19 pathogenesis. Mitochondrion. 2020; 54:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laker RC, Drake JC, Wilson RJ, et al. Ampk phosphorylation of Ulk1 is required for targeting of mitochondria to lysosomes in exercise-induced mitophagy. Nat. Commun. 2017; 8:548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slaets H, Fonteyn L, Eijnde BO, Hellings N. Train your T cells: how skeletal muscles and T cells keep each other fit during aging. Brain Behav. Immun. 2023; 110:237&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P, Tahmasebi N, Gant V, Gupta R. Long COVID following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: characteristic T cell alterations and response to antihistamines. J. Investig. Med. 2022; 70:61&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB, et al. Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat. Immunol. 2022; 23:210&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talla A, Vasaikar SV, Lemos MP, et al. Longitudinal immune dynamics of mild COVID-19 define signatures of recovery and persistence [Internet]. Immunology. 2021; [cited 2023 Feb 15]. Available from: http://biorxiv.org/lookup/doi/10.1101/2021.05.26.442666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.05.26.442666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duggal NA, Niemiro G, Harridge SDR, et al. Can physical activity ameliorate immunosenescence and thereby reduce age-related multi-morbidity? Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2019; 19:563&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furtado GE, Letieri RV, Caldo-Silva A, et al. Sustaining efficient immune functions with regular physical exercise in the COVID-19 era and beyond. Eur. J. Clin. Investigation [Internet]. 2021 [cited 2023 Mar 10];51(5). Available from: https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/eci.13485; 51:e13485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/eci.13485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idorn M, Hojman P. Exercise-dependent regulation of NK cells in cancer protection. Trends Mol. Med. 2016; 22:565&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunz HE, Spielmann G, Agha NH, et al. A single exercise bout augments adenovirus-specific T-cell mobilization and function. Physiol. Behav. 2018; 194:56&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graff RM, Kunz HE, Agha NH, et al. &#x3b2;2-adrenergic receptor signaling mediates the preferential mobilization of differentiated subsets of CD8+ T-cells, NK-cells and non-classical monocytes in response to acute exercise in humans. Brain Behav. Immun. 2018; 74:143&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulthei&#xdf; C, Willscher E, Paschold L, et al. From online data collection to identification of disease mechanisms: the IL-1&#xdf;, IL-6 and TNF-&#x3b1; cytokine triad is associated with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 in a digital research cohort. SSRN J. [Internet]. 2021; [cited 2023 Feb 15]; Available from: https://www.ssrn.com/abstract=3963839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severinsen MCK, Pedersen BK. Muscle&#x2013;organ crosstalk: the emerging roles of myokines. Endocr. Rev. 2020; 41:594&#x2013;609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flikweert AW, Kobold ACM, Van Der Sar-van Der Brugge S, et al. Circulating adipokine levels and COVID-19 severity in hospitalized patients. Int. J. Obes. 2023; 47:126&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordain L, Gotshall RW, Eaton SB, Eaton SB 3rd. Physical activity, energy expenditure and fitness: an evolutionary perspective. Int. J. Sports Med. 1998; 19:328&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Keefe JH, Vogel R, Lavie CJ, Cordain L. Exercise like a hunter-gatherer: a prescription for organic physical fitness. Prog. Cardiovasc. Dis. 2011; 53:471&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paffenbarger RS Jr., Hyde RT, Wing AL, Hsieh CC. Physical activity, all-cause mortality, and longevity of college alumni. N. Engl. J. Med. 1986; 314:605&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nystoriak MA, Bhatnagar A. Cardiovascular effects and benefits of exercise. Front Cardiovasc. Med. 2018; 5:135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieman DC, Wentz LM. The compelling link between physical activity and the body&#x2019;s defense system. J. Sport Health Sci. 2019; 8:201&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collie S, Saggers RT, Bandini R, et al. Association between regular physical activity and the protective effect of vaccination against SARS-CoV-2 in a south African case&#x2013;control study. Br. J. Sports Med. 2023; 57:205&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chastin SFM, Abaraogu U, Bourgois JG, et al. Effects of regular physical activity on the immune system, vaccination and risk of community-acquired infectious disease in the general population: systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2021; 51:1673&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suthar AB, Wang J, Seffren V, et al. Public health impact of COVID-19 vaccines in the US: observational study. BMJ. 2022; e069317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuler PB, Lloyd LK, Leblanc PA, et al. The effect of physical activity and fitness on specific antibody production in college students. J. Sports Med. Phys. Fitness. 1999; 39:233&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keylock KT, Lowder T, Leifheit KA, et al. Higher antibody, but not cell-mediated, responses to vaccination in high physically fit elderly. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985). 2007; 102:1090&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohut ML, Cooper MM, Nickolaus MS, et al. Exercise and psychosocial factors modulate immunity to influenza vaccine in elderly individuals. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 2002; 57:M557&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieman DC, Sakaguchi CA. Physical activity lowers the risk for acute respiratory infections: time for recognition. J. Sport Health Sci. 2022; 11:648&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>