<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38504586</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>96</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A retrospective cohort study on early antibiotic use in vaccinated and unvaccinated COVID-19 patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e29507</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e29507</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.29507</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The bacteriophage behavior of SARS-CoV-2 during the acute and post-COVID-19 phases appears to be an important factor in the development of the disease. The early use of antibiotics seems to be crucial to inhibit disease progression-to prevent viral replication in the gut microbiome, and control toxicological production from the human microbiome. To study the impact of specific antibiotics on recovery from COVID-19 and long COVID (LC) taking into account: vaccination status, comorbidities, SARS-CoV-2 wave, time of initiation of antibiotic therapy and concomitant use of corticosteroids and nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs). A total of 211 COVID-19 patients were included in the study: of which 59 were vaccinated with mRNA vaccines against SARS-CoV-2 while 152 were unvaccinated. Patients were enrolled in three waves: from September 2020 to October 2022, corresponding to the emergence of the pre-Delta, Delta, and Omicron variants of the SARS-CoV-2 virus. The three criteria for enrolling patients were: oropharyngeal swab positivity or fecal findings; moderate symptoms with antibiotic intake; and measurement of blood oxygen saturation during the period of illness. The use of antibiotic combinations, such as amoxicillin with clavulanic acid (875&#x2009;+&#x2009;125&#x2009;mg tablets, every 12&#x2009;h) plus rifaximin (400 mg tablets every 12&#x2009;h), as first choice, as suggested from the previous data, or azithromycin (500&#x2009;mg tablets every 24&#x2009;h), plus rifaximin as above, allows healthcare professionals to focus on the gut microbiome and its implications in COVID-19 disease during patient care. The primary outcome measured in this study was the estimated average treatment effect, which quantified the difference in mean recovery between patients receiving antibiotics and those not receiving antibiotics at 3 and 9 days after the start of treatment. In the analysis, both vaccinated and unvaccinated groups had a median illness duration of 7 days (interquartile range [IQR] 6-9 days for each; recovery crude hazard ratio [HR]&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.94, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.700). The median illness duration for the pre-Delta and Delta waves was 8 days (IQR 7-10 days), while it was shorter, 6.5 days, for Omicron (IQR 6-8 days; recovery crude HR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.71, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). These results were confirmed by multivariate analysis. Patients with comorbidities had a significantly longer disease duration: median 8 days (IQR 7-10 days) compared to 7 days (IQR 6-8 days) for those without comorbidities (crude HR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.75, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.038), but this result was not confirmed in multivariate analysis as statistical significance was lost. Early initiation of antibiotic therapy resulted in a significantly shorter recovery time (crude HR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.74, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Concomitant use of NSAIDs did not reduce disease duration and in multivariate analysis prolonged the disease (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.041). A subgroup of 42 patients receiving corticosteroids for a median of 3 days (IQR 3-6 days) had a longer recovery time (median 9 days, IQR 8-10 days) compared to others (median 7 days, IQR 6-8 days; crude HR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.542, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), as confirmed also by the adjusted HR. In this study, a statistically significant reduction in recovery time was observed among patients who received early antibiotic treatment. Early initiation of antibiotics played a crucial role in maintaining higher levels of blood oxygen saturation. In addition, it is worth noting that a significant number of patients who received antibiotics in the first 3 days and for a duration of 7 days, during the acute phase did not develop LC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brogna</LastName><ForeName>Carlo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Craniomed Group Srl. Research Facility, Bresso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Montano</LastName><ForeName>Luigi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Andrology Unit and Service of Lifestyle Medicine in Uro-Andrology, Local Health Authority (ASL), Salerno, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zanolin</LastName><ForeName>Maria Elisabetta</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostics and Public Health, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bisaccia</LastName><ForeName>Domenico Rocco</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Craniomed Group Srl. Research Facility, Bresso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ciammetti</LastName><ForeName>Gianluca</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Otorhinolaryngology Unit, Hospital Ferdinando Veneziale Isernia, Regional Health Authority of Molise, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Viduto</LastName><ForeName>Valentina</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Long Covid-19 Foundation, Leeds, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fabrowski</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Royal Sussex County Hospital, University Hospitals Sussex, Brighton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baig</LastName><ForeName>Abdul M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological and Biomedical Sciences, Aga Khan University, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gerlach</LastName><ForeName>Joachim</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health-Shield, Vedicinals,9, Langenfeld, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gennaro</LastName><ForeName>Iapicca</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pineta Grande Hospital Group, Department of Urology, Santa Rita Clinic, Atripalda, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bignardi</LastName><ForeName>Elio</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiology Uniy, ASL Lecce, Casarano, Lecce, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brogna</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Moscati Hospital, Avellino, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frongillo</LastName><ForeName>Aquilino</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Craniomed Group Srl. Research Facility, Bresso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cristoni</LastName><ForeName>Simone</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ISB-Ion Source &amp; Biotechnologies Srl., Bresso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piscopo</LastName><ForeName>Marina</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, University of Naples Federico II, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>L36O5T016N</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000078262">Rifaximin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000086663">COVID-19 Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000894">Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000305">Adrenal Cortex Hormones</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000711908">SARS-CoV-2 variants</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078262" MajorTopicYN="N">Rifaximin</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086663" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000894" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000305" MajorTopicYN="N">Adrenal Cortex Hormones</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS coronavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antiviral agents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">toxic products</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccines/vaccine strains</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38504586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.29507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M, et al. Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(6):683-690. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.1127</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rom&#xe1;n GC, Spencer PS, Reis J, et al. The neurology of COVID-19 revisited: a proposal from the environmental neurology specialty group of the world federation of neurology to implement international neurological registries. J Neurol Sci. 2020;414:116884. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2020.116884</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fotuhi M, Mian A, Meysami S, Meysami S, Raji CA. Neurobiology of COVID-19. J Alzheimers Dis. 2020;76(1):3-19. doi:10.3233/JAD-200581</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Living Guidance for CLINICAL Management of COVID-19. World Health Organization. 2021. https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/338882</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, et al. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020;395(10223):497-506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z, McGoogan JM. Characteristics of and important lessons from the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) outbreak in China: summary of a report of 72314 cases from the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention. JAMA. 2020;323:1239-1242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Yu Y, Xu J, et al. Clinical course and outcomes of critically ill patients with SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a single-centered, retrospective, observational study. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8(5):475-481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moons KGM, Wolff RF, Riley RD, et al. PROBAST: a tool to assess risk of bias and applicability of prediction model studies: explanation and elaboration. Ann Intern Med. 2019;170(1):W1-W33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N, Zhou M, Dong X, et al. Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of 99 cases of 2019 novel coronavirus pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a descriptive study. Lancet. 2020;395(10223):507-513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Hu B, Hu C, et al. Clinical characteristics of 138 hospitalized patients with 2019 novel coronavirus-infected pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA. 2020;323:1061-1069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan W, Ni Z, Hu Y, et al. Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(18):1708-1720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favas TT, Dev P, Chaurasia RN, et al. Neurological manifestations of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of proportions. Neurol Sci. 2020;41:3437-3470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullahi A, Candan SA, Abba MA, et al. Neurological and musculoskeletal features of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta- analysis. Front Neurol. 2020;11:687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arons MM, Hatfield KM, Reddy SC, et al. Presymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infections and transmission in a skilled nursing facility. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:2081-2090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMichael TM, Currie DW, Clark S, et al. Epidemiology of Covid-19 in a long-term care facility in King County, Washington. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:2005-2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tay HS, Harwood R. Atypical presentation of COVID-19 in a frail older person. Age Ageing. 2020;49(4):523-524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elshafeey F, Magdi R, Hindi N, et al. A systematic scoping review of COVID-19 during pregnancy and childbirth. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2020;150(1):47-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC COVID-19 Response Team. Coronavirus disease 2019 in children-United States, February 12-April 2, 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69(14):422-426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://www.covid19treatmentguidelines.nih.gov/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vegivinti C, Thej R, et al. Efficacy of antiviral therapies for COVID-19: a systematic review of randomised controlled trials. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22(1):107. doi:10.1186/s12879-022-07068-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal V, et al. Mortality benefit of remdesivir in COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Med, 2021; 7:606429. doi:10.3389/fmed.2020.606429</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayk Bernal A, Gomes da Silva MM, Musungaie DB, et al. Molnupiravir for oral treatment of Covid-19 in nonhospitalized patients. N Engl J Med. 2022;386(6):509-520. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2116044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah MM, Joyce B, Plumb ID, et al. Paxlovid associated with decreased hospitalization rate among adults with COVID-19-United States, April-September 2022. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71:1531-1537. doi:10.15585/mmwr.mm7148e2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Huang S, Huang S, et al. Prevalence of NSAID use among people with COVID-19 and the association with COVID-19-related outcomes: systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2022;88(12):5113-5127. doi:10.1111/bcp.15512</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donzelli A. Full-dose NSAIDs at the first sign of respiratory infection? Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(11):1533-1534. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(22)00649-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perico N, Cortinovis M, Suter F, Remuzzi G. Home as the new frontier for the treatment of COVID-19: the case for anti-inflammatory agents. Lancet Infect Dis. 2023;23(1):e22-e33. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(22)00433-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J-W, Yang L, Luo RG, Xu JF. Corticosteroid administration for viral pneumonia: COVID-19 and beyond. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2020;26(9):1171-1177. doi:10.1016/j.cmi.2020.06.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebrahimi CF, et al Effects of corticosteroids on Covid-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis on clinical outcomes. Pulm Pharmacol Ther. 2022;72:102107. doi:10.1016/j.pupt.2021.102107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrillo M, Brogna C, Cristoni S, Querci M, Piazza O, Van den Eede G. Increase of SARS-CoV-2 RNA load in faecal samples prompts for rethinking of SARS-CoV-2 biology and COVID-19 epidemiology. F1000Res. 2021;10:370. doi:10.12688/f1000research.52540.3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna C, Brogna B, Bisaccia DR, et al. Could SARS-CoV-2 have bacteriophage behavior or induce the activity of other bacteriophages? Vaccines. 2022;10(5):708. doi:10.3390/vaccines10050708</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alharbi KS, et al. Gut microbiota disruption in COVID-19 or post-COVID illness association with severity biomarkers: a possible role of Pre/Pro-biotics in manipulating microflora. Chem Biol Interact. 2022;358:109898. doi:10.1016/j.cbi.2022.109898</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty C, Sharma AR, Bhattacharya M, Dhama K, Lee SS. Altered gut microbiota patterns in COVID-19: markers for inflammation and disease severity. World J Gastroenterol. 2022;28(25):2802-2822. doi:10.3748/wjg.v28.i25.2802</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gharajeh NH, Pourjafar H, Derakhshanian H, Mohammadi H, Barzegari A, Eslami S. Gut microbiota might act as a potential therapeutic pathway in COVID-19. Curr Pharm Biotechnol. 2022;23(15):1837-1850. doi:10.2174/1389201023666220404183859</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao F, Guo R, Ma Q, et al. Stressful events induce long-term gut microbiota dysbiosis and associated post-traumatic stress symptoms in healthcare workers fighting against COVID-19. J Affect Disord. 2022;303:187-195. doi:10.1016/j.jad.2022.02.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu J, Han B, Wang J. COVID-19: gastrointestinal manifestations and potential fecal-oral transmission. Gastroenterology. 2020;158(6):1518-1519. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2020.02.054</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel KP, Patel PA, Vunnam RR, et al. Gastrointestinal, hepatobiliary, and pancreatic manifestations of COVID-19. J Clin Virol. 2020;128:104386. doi:10.1016/j.jcv.2020.104386</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo M, Tao W, Flavell RA, Zhu S. Potential intestinal infection and faecal-oral transmission of SARS-CoV-2. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;18:269-283. doi:10.1038/s41575-021-00416-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Garrett S, Sun J. Gastrointestinal symptoms, pathophysiology, and treatment in COVID-19. Genes Dis. 2021;8(4):385-400. doi:10.1016/j.gendis.2020.08.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velikova T, Snegarova V, Kukov A, Batselova H, Mihova A, Nakov R. Gastrointestinal mucosal immunity and COVID-19. World J Gastroenterol. 2021;27(30):5047-5059. doi:10.3748/wjg.v27.i30.5047</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan A, Zlitni S, Brooks EF, et al. Gastrointestinal symptoms and fecal shedding of SARS-CoV-2 RNA suggest prolonged gastrointestinal infection. Med. 2022;3(6):371-387. doi:10.1016/j.medj.2022.04.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haramoto E, Malla B, Thakali O, Kitajima M. First environmental surveillance for the presence of SARS-CoV-2 RNA in wastewater and river water in Japan. Sci Total Environ. 2020;737:140405. doi:10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.140405</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed W, Bertsch PM, Bibby K, et al. Decay of SARS-CoV-2 and surrogate murine hepatitis virus RNA in untreated wastewater to inform application in wastewater-based epidemiology. Environ Res. 2020;191:110092. doi:10.1016/j.envres.2020.110092</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed W, Bertsch PM, Angel N, et al. Detection of SARS-CoV-2 RNA in commercial passenger aircraft and cruise ship wastewater: a surveillance tool for assessing the presence of COVID-19 infected travellers. J Travel Med. 2020;27(5):taaa116. doi:10.1093/jtm/taaa116</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Rosa G, Iaconelli M, Mancini P, et al. First detection of SARS-CoV-2 in untreated wastewaters in Italy. Sci Total Environ. 2020;736:139652. doi:10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.139652</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echeverr&#xed;a-Esnal D, Martin-Ontiyuelo C, Navarrete-Rouco ME, et al. Azithromycin in the treatment of COVID-19: a review. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2021;19(2):147-163. doi:10.1080/14787210.2020.1813024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautret P, Lagier J-C, Parola P, et al. Hydroxychloroquine and azithromycin as a treatment of COVID-19: results of an open-label non-randomized clinical trial. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2020;56(1):105949. doi:10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2020.105949</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalcanti AB, Zampieri FG, Rosa RG, et al. Hydroxychloroquine with or without azithromycin in mild-to-moderate Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(21):2041-2052. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2019014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel AM, Monem MSA, Sharaf NA, Magdy N, Farid SF. Efficacy and safety of azithromycin in Covid-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Rev Med Virol. 2022;32(1):e2258. doi:10.1002/rmv.2258</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javelle E, Raoult D. Antibiotics against poliovirus carriage: an additional tool in the polio endgame? Clin Microbiol Infect. 2020;26(5):542-544. doi:10.1016/j.cmi.2020.01.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods Acevedo MA, Pfeiffer JK. Microbiota-independent antiviral effects of antibiotics on poliovirus and coxsackievirus. Virology. 2020;546:20-24. doi:10.1016/j.virol.2020.04.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis EA, Cao J, Hsu YH, Magrioti V, Kokotos G. Phospholipase A2 enzymes: physical structure, biological function, disease implication, chemical inhibition, and therapeutic intervention. Chem Rev. 2011;111(10):6130-6185. doi:10.1021/cr200085w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams BB, Green SJ, Bosch RJ, et al. Four weeks of treatment with rifaximin fails to significantly alter microbial diversity in rectal samples of HIV-infected immune non-responders (ACTG A5286) which may be attributed to rectal swab use. Pathog Immun. 2019;4(2):235-250. doi:10.20411/pai.v4i2.290</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenorio AR, Chan ES, Bosch RJ, et al. Rifaximin has a marginal impact on microbial translocation, T-cell activation and inflammation in HIV-positive immune non-responders to antiretroviral therapy-ACTG A5286. J Infect Dis. 2015;211(5):780-790. doi:10.1093/infdis/jiu515</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zajac V, Matelova L, Liskova A, et al. Confirmation of HIV-like sequences in respiratory tract bacteria of Cambodian and Kenyan HIV-positive pediatric patients. Med Sci Monit. 2011;17(3):CR154-CR158. doi:10.12659/msm.881449</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard A, Montagnier L. AIDS-associated mycoplasmas. Annu Rev Microbiol. 1994;48:687-712. doi:10.1146/annurev.mi.48.100194.003351</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Heping, et al Altered gut microbiota is associated with different immunologic responses to antiretroviral therapy in HIV-infected men who have sex with men. J Med Virol. 2023;95(3):e28674. doi:10.1002/jmv.28674</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moyes D, Saxena D, John M, Malamud D. The gut and oral microbiome in HIV disease: a workshop report. Oral Dis. 2016;22(suppl 1):166-170. doi:10.1111/odi.12415</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgognone A, Noguera-Julian M, Oriol B, et al. Gut microbiome signatures linked to HIV-1 reservoir size and viremia control. Microbiome. 2022;10(1):59. doi:10.1186/s40168-022-01247-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu HY, Chang PH, Chen KY, et al. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) associated bacterial coinfection: incidence, diagnosis and treatment. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2022;55(6):985-992. doi:10.1016/j.jmii.2022.09.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzaei R, Goodarzi P, Asadi M, et al. Bacterial co-infections with SARS-CoV-2. IUBMB Life. 2020;72(10):2097-2111. doi:10.1002/iub.2356</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna C, Cristoni S, Brogna B, et al. Toxin-like peptides from the bacterial cultures derived from gut microbiome infected by SARS-CoV-2-new data for a possible role in the long COVID pattern. Biomedicines. 2023;11(1):87. doi:10.3390/biomedicines11010087</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pistollato F, Petrillo M, Clerbaux LA, et al. Effects of spike protein and toxin-like peptides found in COVID-19 patients on human 3D neuronal/glial model undergoing differentiation: possible implications for SARS-CoV-2 impact on brain development. Reprod Toxicol. 2022;111:34-48. doi:10.1016/j.reprotox.2022.04.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna C, Cristoni S, Petrillo M, Querci M, Piazza O, Van den Eede G. Toxin-like peptides in plasma, urine and faecal samples from COVID-19 patients. F1000Res. 2021;10:550. doi:10.12688/f1000research.54306.2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wais T, Hasan M, Rai V, Agrawal DK. Gut-brain communication in COVID-19: molecular mechanisms, mediators, biomarkers, and therapeutics. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2022;18(9):947-960. doi:10.1080/1744666X.2022.2105697</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna C, Costanzo V, Brogna B, et al. Analysis of bacteriophage behavior of a human RNA virus, SARS-CoV-2, through the integrated approach of immunofluorescence microscopy, proteomics and D-amino acid quantification. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(4):3929. doi:10.3390/ijms24043929)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna C, Viduto V, Fabrowski M, et al. The importance of the gut microbiome in the pathogenesis and transmission of SARS-CoV-2. Gut Microbes. 2023;15(1):2244718. doi:10.1080/19490976.2023.2244718</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association. World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA. 2013;310(20):2191-2194. doi:10.1001/jama.2013.281053</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna B, Brogna C, Petrillo M, et al. SARS-CoV-2 detection in fecal sample from a patient with typical findings of COVID-19 pneumonia on CT but negative to multiple SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR tests on oropharyngeal and nasopharyngeal swab samples. Medicina. 2021;57(3):290. doi:10.3390/medicina57030290</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna C, Brogna B, Bisaccia DR, et al. SARS-CoV-2: reinfection after 18 months of a previous case with multiple negative nasopharyngeal swab tests and positive fecal molecular test. Medicina. 2022;58(5):642. doi:10.3390/medicina58050642</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seasely AR, Blanchard CT, Arora N, et al. Maternal and perinatal outcomes associated with the omicron variant of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection. Obstet Gynecol. 2022;140(2):262-265. doi:10.1097/aog.0000000000004849</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez-Castrell&#xf3;n P, Gandara-Mart&#xed; T, Abreu Y Abreu AT, et al. Probiotic improves symptomatic and viral clearance in Covid19 outpatients: a randomized, quadruple-blinded, placebo-controlled trial. Gut Microbes. 2022;14(1):2018899. doi:10.1080/19490976.2021.2018899</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawry&#x142;kowicz V, Lietz-Kijak D, Ka&#x17a;mierczak-Siedlecka K, et al. Patient nutrition and probiotic therapy in COVID-19: what do we know in 2021? Nutrients. 2021;13:3385. doi:10.3390/nu13103385</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing YH, Ni W, Wu Q, et al. Pro-longed viral shedding in feces of pediatric patients with coronavirus disease 2019. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2020;53(3):473-480. doi:10.1016/j.jmii.2020.03.021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo M, Tao W, Flavell RA, Zhu S. Reply to: rectally shed SARS-CoV-2 lacks infectivity: time to re-think faecal-oral transmission? Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;18(9):669-670. doi:10.1038/s41575-021-00503-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuicchi D, Lazzarotto T, Poggioli G. Fecal-oral transmission of SARS-CoV-2: review of laboratoryconfirmed virus in gastrointestinal system. Int J Colorectal Dis. 2021;36(3):437-444. doi:10.1007/s00384-020-03785-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna C, Cristoni S, Petrillo M, et al. The first report on detecting SARS-CoV-2 inside bacteria of the human gut microbiome: a case series on asymptomatic family members and a child with COVID-19 [version 2; peer review: 1 approved with reservations, 1 not approved]. F1000Res. 2022;11:135. doi:10.12688/f1000research.77421.2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson KE, Caliendo AM, Arias CA, et al. Infectious diseases society of america guidelines on the diagnosis of COVID-19: molecular diagnostic testing. Clin Infect Dis. 2021:ciab048.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong CKH, Au ICH, Lau KTK, Lau EHY, Cowling BJ, Leung GM. Real-world effectiveness of early molnupiravir or nirmatrelvir-ritonavir in hospitalised patients with COVID-19 without supplemental oxygen requirement on admission during Hong Kong's omicron BA.2 wave: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(12):1681-1693. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(22)00507-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian L, Pang Z, Li M, et al. Molnupiravir and its antiviral activity against COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2022;13:855496. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2022.855496</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmah L, Abarikwu SO, Arero AG, et al. Oral antiviral treatments for COVID-19: opportunities and challenges. Pharmacol Rep. 2022;74(6):1255-1278. doi:10.1007/s43440-022-00388-7)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinosoglou K, Schinas G, Gogos C. Oral antiviral treatment for COVID-19: a comprehensive review on nirmatrelvir/ritonavir. Viruses. 2022;14(11):2540. doi:10.3390/v14112540</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravolatz LD, Depcinski S, Sharma M. Molnupiravir and nirmatrelvir-ritonavir: oral coronavirus disease 2019 antiviral drugs. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76(1):165-171. doi:10.1093/cid/ciac180</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultana J, Cutroneo PM, Crisafulli S, Puglisi G, Caramori G, Trifir&#xf2; G. Azithromycin in COVID-19 patients: pharmacological mechanism, clinical evidence and prescribing guidelines. Drug Saf. 2020;43(8):691-698. doi:10.1007/s40264-020-00976-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakajima K, Abe T, Saji R, et al. Serum cholinesterase associated with COVID-19 penumonia severety and moratality. J Infect 2021; 82(2):282-327. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2020.08.021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z, Gao W, Bao H, et al. VV116 versus nirmatrelvir-ritonavir for oral treatment of Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2023;388:406-417. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2208822</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinreich DM, Sivapalasingam S, Norton T, et al. REGEN-COV antibody combination and outcomes in outpatients with Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2021;385(23):e81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottlieb RL, Nirula A, Chen P, et al. Effect of bamlanivimab as monotherapy or in combination with etesevimab on viral load in patients with mild to moderate COVID-19: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2021;325:632-644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganatra S, Dani SS, Ahmad J, et al. Oral nirmatrelvir and ritonavir in non-hospitalized vaccinated patients with Covid-19. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;74(6):563-572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dryden-Peterson S, Kim A, Kim AY, et al. Nirmatrelvir plus ritonavir for early COVID-19 and hospitalization in a large US health system. Ann Intern Med. 2023;176(1):77-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najjar-Debbiny R, Gronich N, Weber G, et al. Effectiveness of Paxlovid in reducing severe COVID-19 and mortality in high risk patients. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76(3):e342-e349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna B, Bignardi E, Brogna C, et al. COVID-19 pneumonia in vaccinated population: a six clinical and radiological case series. Medicina. 2021;57(9):891. doi:10.3390/medicina57090891</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuss SK, Best GT, Etheredge CA, et al. Intestinal microbiota promote enteric virus replication and systemic pathogenesis. Science. 2011;334(6053):249-252. doi:10.1126/science.1211057</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kane M, Case LK, Kopaskie K, et al. Successful transmission of a retrovirus depends on the commensal microbiota. Science. 2011;334(6053):245-249. doi:10.1126/science.1210718</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente JC, Pehrsson EC, Blaser MJ, et al. The microbiome of uncontacted amerindians. Sci Adv. 2015;1(3):e1500183. doi:10.1126/sciadv.1500183</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browne AJ, Chipeta MG, Haines-Woodhouse G, et al. Global antibiotic consumption and usage in humans, 2000-18: a spatial modelling study. Lancet Planet Health. 2021;5(12):e893-e904. doi:10.1016/S2542-5196(21)00280-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finley RL, Collignon P, Joakim Larsson DGJ, et al. The scourge of antibiotic resistance: the important role of the environment. Clin Infect Dis. 2013;57:704-710. doi:10.1093/cid/cit355</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manyi-Loh C, Mamphweli S, Meyer E, Okoh A. Antibiotic use in agriculture and its consequential resistance in environmental sources: potential public health implications. Molecules. 2018;23(4):795. doi:10.3390/molecules23040795</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CC, Chen SY, Ko WC, Hsueh PR. Increased antimicrobial resistance during the COVID-19 pandemic. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2021;57(4):106324. doi:10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2021.106324</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman-Esquivel J, Mendoza-Hernandez MA, Guzman-Solorzano HP, et al. Clinical characteristics in the acute phase of COVID-19 that predict long COVID: tachycardia, myalgias, severity, and use of antibiotics as main risk factors, while education and blood group B are protective. Healthcare. 2023;11(2):197. doi:10.3390/healthcare11020197</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman-Esquivel J, Galvan-Salazar H, Guzman-Solorzano H, et al. Efficacy of the use of mefenamic acid combined with standard medical care vs. standard medical care alone for the treatment of COVID-19: a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial. Int J Mol Med. 2022;49(3):29. doi:10.3892/ijmm.2022.5084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fazio S, Bellavite P, Zanolin E, McCullough PA, Pandolfi S, Affuso F. Retrospective study of outcomes and hospitalization rates of patients in Italy with a confirmed diagnosis of early COVID-19 and treated at home within 3 days or after 3 days of symptom onset with prescribed and non-prescribed treatments between November 2020 and August 2021. Med Sci Monit. 2021;27:e935379. doi:10.12659/MSM.935379</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maseda D, Ricciotti E. NSAID-gut microbiota interactions. Front Pharmacol. 2020;11:1153. doi:10.3389/fphar.2020.01153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers MAM, Aronoff DM. The influence of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs on the gut microbiome. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2016;22(2):178.e1-178.e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabin AB. Pathogenesis of poliomyelitis; reappraisal in the light of new data. Science. 1956;123:1151-1157. doi:10.1126/science.123.3209.1151</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabin AB. Behaviour of chimpanzee-avirulent poliomyelitis viruses in experimentally infected human volunteers. BMJ. 1955;2:160-162. doi:10.1136/bmj.2.4932.160</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabin AB. Present status of attenuated live virus poliomyelitis vaccine. Bull N Y Acad Med. 1957;33:17-39. doi:10.1001/jama.1956.02970350005002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabin AB. Oral poliovirus vaccine: recent results and recommendations for optimum use. R Soc Health J. 1962;82:51-59. doi:10.1177/146642406208200205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna C, Cristoni S. A new absolute quantitative method for peptide and metabolite detection. J Mass Spectrom. 2024;59(1):e4991. doi:10.1002/jms.4991</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>