<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35283306</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-0691</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical microbiology and infection : the official publication of the European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Microbiol Infect</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caring for older adults during the COVID-19 pandemic.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>785</StartPage><EndPage>791</EndPage><MedlinePgn>785-791</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.cmi.2022.02.040</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1198-743X(22)00117-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Elderly patients represent a high-risk group with increased risk of death from COVID-19. Despite the number of published studies, several unmet needs in care for older adults exist.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To discuss unmet needs of COVID-19 in this special population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SOURCES" NlmCategory="METHODS">A literature review for studies on COVID-19 in elderly patients published between December 2019 and November 2021 was performed. Clinical questions were formulated to guide the literature search. The search was conducted in the MEDLINE database, combining specific search terms. Two reviewers independently conducted the search and selected the studies according to the prespecified clinical questions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONTENT" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Elderly patients with COVID-19 have peculiar characteristics. They may have atypical clinical presentation, with no fever and with delirium or neurological manifestations as the most common signs, with potential delayed diagnosis and increased risk of death. The reported fatality rates among elderly patients with COVID-19 are extremely high. Several factors, including comorbidities, atypical presentation, and exclusion from intensive care unit care, contribute to this excess of mortality. Age alone is frequently used as a key factor to exclude the elderly from intensive care, but there is evidence that frailty rather than age better predicts the risk of poor outcome in this category. Durability of vaccine efficacy in the elderly remains debated, and the need for a third booster dose is becoming increasingly evident. Finally, efforts to care for elderly patients who have survived after acute COVID-19 should be implemented, considering the high rates of long COVID sequelae and the risk of longitudinal functional and cognitive decline.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We highlight peculiar aspects of COVID-19 in elderly patients and factors contributing to high risk of poor outcome in this category. We also illuminated gaps in current evidence, suggesting future research directions and underlining the need for further studies on the optimal management of elderly patients with COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prendki</LastName><ForeName>Virginie</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Geneva University Hospitals and Faculty of Medicine, Geneva, Switzerland; Faculty of Medicine, University of Geneva, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tiseo</LastName><ForeName>Giusy</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Unit, Department of Clinical and Experimental Medicine, Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Pisana, University of Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Falcone</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Unit, Department of Clinical and Experimental Medicine, Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Pisana, University of Pisa, Italy. Electronic address: marco.falcone@unipi.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>ESCMID Study Group for Infections in the Elderly (ESGIE)</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Microbiol Infect</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9516420</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1198-743X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073496" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frailty</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elderly</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Frailty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Geriatric</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Older</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccines</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35283306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8912971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmi.2022.02.040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1198-743X(22)00117-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bonanad C., Garc&#xed;a-Blas S., Tarazona-Santabalbina F., Sanchis J., Bertomeu-Gonz&#xe1;lez V., F&#xe1;cila L., et al. The effect of age on mortality in patients with Covid-19: a meta-analysis with 611,583 subjects. J&#xa0;Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;21:915&#x2013;918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7247470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32674819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy M., Helfand B.K.I., Gou R.Y., Gartaganis S.L., Webb M., Moccia J.M., et al. Delirium in older patients with COVID-19 presenting to the Emergency Department. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7677760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33211114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO Weekly epidemiological update on COVID-19. 2021. https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/weekly-epidemiological-update-on-covid-19---22-march-2022 Available at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olabi B., Bagaria J., Bhopal S.S., Curry G.D., Villarroel N., Bhopal R. Population perspective comparing COVID-19 to all and common causes of death during the first wave of the pandemic in seven European countries. Public Health Pract (Oxf) 2021;2:100077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33521739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knock E.S., Whittles L.K., Lees J.A., Perez-Guzman P.N., Verity R., FitzJohn R.G., et al. Key epidemiological drivers and impact of interventions in the 2020 SARS-CoV-2 epidemic in England. Sci Transl Med. 2021;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8432953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34158411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resciniti N.V., Fuller M., Sellner J., Lohman M.C. COVID-19 incidence and mortality among long-term care facility residents and staff in South Carolina. J&#xa0;Am Med Dir Assoc. 2021;22:2026&#x2013;2031.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8364806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34481792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian J., Jin X., Hao S., Cai H., Zhang S., Zheng L., et al. Analysis of epidemiological and clinical features in older patients with Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) outside Wuhan. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71:740&#x2013;747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32211844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pepe M., Maroun-Eid C., Romero R., Arroyo-Espliguero R., Arroyo-Espliguero R., Fern&#xe0;ndez-Rozas I., et al. Clinical presentation, therapeutic approach, and outcome of young patients admitted for COVID-19, with respect to the elderly counterpart. Clin Exp Med. 2021;21:249&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7868661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zazzara M.B., Penfold R.S., Roberts A.L., Lee K.A., Dooley H., Sudre C.H., et al. Probable delirium is a presenting symptom of COVID-19 in frail, older adults: a cohort study of 322 hospitalised and 535 community-based older adults. Age Ageing. 2021;50:40&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32986799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez-Belda A.B., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Garc&#xe9;s M., Mateo-Sanchis E., Madrazo M., Carmona M., Piles-Roger L., et al. COVID-19 in older adults: what are the differences with younger patients? Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2021;21:60&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33264816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao S.C., Lai C.C., Chen Y.H., Chen Y.C., Hung M.J., Liao S.C. Prevalence, incidence and mortality of delirium in patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Age Ageing. 2021;50:1445&#x2013;1453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8247209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33984129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohuabunwa U., Turner J., Johnson T. Atypical presentations among older adults with COVID-19 disease: a need for broadening the differential diagnosis. Gerontol Geriatr Med. 2021;7 2333721421999313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7961707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33786339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Besselaar J.H., Sikkema R.S., Koene F.M.H.P.A., van Buul L.W., Oude Munnink B.B., Fr&#xe9;nay I., et al. Are presymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infections in nursing home residents unrecognised symptomatic infections? Sequence and metadata from weekly testing in an extensive nursing home outbreak. Age Ageing. 2021;50:1454&#x2013;1463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8136016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33963830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung C., Fj&#xf8;lner J., Bruno R.R., Wernly B., Artigas A., Bollen Pinto B., et al. Differences in mortality in critically ill elderly patients during the second COVID-19 surge in Europe. Crit Care. 2021;25:344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34556171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillon A., Laurent E., Godillon L., Kimmoun A., Grammatico-Guillon L. Long-term mortality of elderly patients after intensive care unit admission for COVID-19. Intensive Care Med. 2021;47:710&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8040757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33844045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aw D., Woodrow L., Ogliari G., Harwood R. Association of frailty with mortality in older inpatients with Covid-19: a cohort study. Age Ageing. 2020;49:915&#x2013;922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32778870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomaard L.C., van der Linden C.M.J., van der Bol J.M., Jansen S.W.M., Polinder-Bos H.A., Willems H.C., et al. Frailty is associated with in-hospital mortality in older hospitalised COVID-19 patients in The Netherlands: the COVID-OLD study. Age Ageing. 2021;50:631&#x2013;640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33951156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal S., Kumar P., Singh S., Saha S., Dey A.B. Clinical features and outcomes of COVID-19 in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Geriatr. 2021;21:321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8133052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covino M., Russo A., Salini S., De Matteis G., Simeoni B., Della Polla D., et al. Frailty assessment in the emergency department for risk stratification of COVID-19 patients aged &#x2265;80 years. J&#xa0;Am Med Dir Assoc. 2021;22:1845&#x2013;18452.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8289672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34364846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y., Liu X., Deng M., Liu P., Li F., Xie N., et al. Epidemiology of COVID-19 in older persons, Wuhan, China. Age Ageing. 2020;49:706&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7337701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32584953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meis-Pinheiro U., Lopez-Segui F., Walsh S., Ussi A., Santaeugenia S., Garcia-Navarro J.A., et al. Clinical characteristics of COVID-19 in older adults. A retrospective study in long-term nursing homes in Catalonia. PLoS One. 2021;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8301631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34297774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brill S.E., Jarvis H.C., Ozcan E., Burns T.L.P., Warraich R.A., Amani L.J., et al. COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study with focus on the over-80s and hospital-onset disease. BMC Med. 2020;18:194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7315690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32586323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinnadurai R., Ogedengbe O., Agarwal P., Money-Coomes S., Abdurrahman A.Z., Mohammed S., et al. Older age and frailty are the chief predictors of mortality in COVID-19 patients admitted to an acute medical unit in a secondary care setting- a cohort study. BMC Geriatr. 2020;20:409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7563906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33066750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles A., Webb T.E., Mcloughlin B.C., Mannan I., Rather A., Knopp P., et al. Outcomes from COVID-19 across the range of frailty: excess mortality in fitter older people. Eur Geriatr Med. 2020;11:851&#x2013;855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7368630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32683576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kundi H., &#xc7;etin E.H.&#xd6;., Canpolat U., Aras S., Celik O., Ata N., et al. The role of frailty on adverse outcomes among older patients with COVID-19. J&#xa0;Infect. 2020;81:944&#x2013;951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7521439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33002560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendes A., Serratrice C., Herrmann F.R., Genton L., P&#xe9;rivier S., Scheffler M., et al. Predictors of in-hospital mortality in older patients with COVID-19: the COVID age study. J&#xa0;Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;21:1546&#x2013;1554.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33138936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen R.K., Conroy S.P., Taub N., Jones W., Bryden D., Pareek M., et al. Comparing associations between frailty and mortality in hospitalised older adults with or without COVID-19 infection: a retrospective observational study using electronic health records. Age Ageing. 2021;50:307&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32678866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinmeyer Z., Vienne-Noyes S., Bernard M., Steinmeyer A., Balardy L., Piau A., et al. Acute care of older patients with COVID-19: clinical characteristics and outcomes. Geriatrics (Basel) 2020;5:65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7709587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32992602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanc F., Waechter C., Vogel T., Schorr B., Demuynck C., Hunyadi C.M., et al. Therapeutic prevention of COVID-19 in elderly: a case-control study. Geroscience. 2021;43:2333&#x2013;2343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8285285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva N.J., Ribeiro-Silva R.C., Ferreira A.J.F., Teixeira C.S.S., Rocha A.S., Alves F.J.O., et al. Combined association of obesity and other cardiometabolic diseases with severe COVID-19 outcomes: a nationwide cross-sectional study of 21 773 Brazilian adult and elderly inpatients. BMJ Open. 2021;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8354760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dres M., Hajage D., Lebbah S., Kimmoun A., Pham T., B&#xe9;duneau G., et al. Characteristics, management, and prognosis of elderly patients with COVID-19 admitted in the ICU during the first wave: insights from the COVID-ICU study: prognosis of COVID-19 elderly critically ill patients in the ICU. Ann Intensive Care. 2021;11:77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8120254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33988767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ticinesi A., Nouvenne A., Prati B., Guida L., Parise A., Cerundolo N., et al. The clinical significance of procalcitonin elevation in patients over 75 years old admitted for COVID-19 pneumonia. Mediators Inflamm. 2021;2021:5593806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8245241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34326704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas L.E.M., de Lange D.W., van Dijk D., van Delden J.J.M. Should we deny ICU admission to the elderly? Ethical considerations in times of COVID-19. Crit Care. 2020;24:321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7282209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32517776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewitt J., Carter B., Vilches-Moraga A., Quinn T.J., Braude P., Verduri A., et al. The effect of frailty on survival in patients with COVID-19 (COPE): a multicentre, European, observational cohort study. Lancet Public Health. 2020;5:e444&#x2013;e451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7326416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32619408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sprung C.L., Joynt G.M., Christian M.D., Truog R.D., Rello J., Nates J.L. Adult ICU triage during the coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic: who will live and who will die? Recommendations to improve survival. Crit Care Med. 2020;48:1196&#x2013;1202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7217126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32697491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung C., Flaatten H., Fj&#xf8;lner J., Bruno R.R., Wernly B., Artigas A., et al. The impact of frailty on survival in elderly intensive care patients with COVID-19: the COVIP study. Crit Care. 2021;25:149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8054503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33874987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence  COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing COVID-19. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng191</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34181371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kastora S., Kounidas G., Perrott S., Carter B., Hewitt J., Myint P.K. Clinical frailty scale as a point of care prognostic indicator of mortality in COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;36:100896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8141355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34036252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pranata R., Henrina J., Lim M.A., Lawrensia S., Yonas E., Vania R., et al. Clinical frailty scale and mortality in COVID-19: a systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2021;93:104324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33352430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiseo G., Yahav D., Paul M., Tinelli M., Gavazzi G., Mussini C., et al. What have we learned from the first to the second wave of COVID-19 pandemic? An international survey from the ESCMID Study Group for Infection in the Elderly (ESGIE) group. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2022;41:281&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8590524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34775534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falcone M., Suardi L.R., Tiseo G., Barbieri C., Giusti L., Galfo V., et al. Early use of remdesivir and risk of disease progression in hospitalized patients with mild to moderate COVID-19. Clin Ther. 2022 S0149-2918(22)00012-1. Epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8761549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35120742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanai O., Fujita K., Nanba K., Esaka N., Hata H., Seta K., et al. Safety of remdesivir for patients 80 years of age or older with Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Drugs Aging. 2021;38:1067&#x2013;1074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8638643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34859387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remdesivir (Veklury&#xae;) prescribing information. Gilead Sciences, Inc.; Foster City, CA: 2022. https://www.gilead.com/-/media/files/pdfs/medicines/covid-19/veklury/veklury_pi.pdf Updated January.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menichetti F., Popoli P., Puopolo M., Spila Alegiani S., Tiseo G., Bartoloni A., et al. Effect of high-titer convalescent plasma on progression to severe respiratory failure or death in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 pneumonia: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4 Erratum in: JAMA Netw Open 2021;4:e2144236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8630572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34842924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libster R., P&#xe9;rez Marc G., Wappner D., Coviello S., Bianchi A., Braem V., et al. Early high-titer plasma therapy to prevent severe Covid-19 in older adults. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2021;384:610&#x2013;618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7793608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33406353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falcone M., Tiseo G., Valoriani B., Barbieri C., Occhineri S., Mazzetti P., et al. Efficacy of bamlanivimab/etesevimab and casirivimab/imdevimab in preventing progression to severe COVID-19 and role of variants of concern. Infect Dis Ther. 2021;10:2479&#x2013;2488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8386337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34435337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M., Kr&#xfc;ger N., Schulz S., Cossmann A., Rocha C., Kempf A., et al. The Omicron variant is highly resistant against antibody-mediated neutralization: implications for control of the COVID-19 pandemic. Cell. 2022;185:447&#x2013;456. e11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8702401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35026151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RECOVERY Collaborative Group. Horby P., Lim W.S., Emberson J.R., Mafham M., Bell J.L., Linsell L., et al. Dexamethasone in hospitalized patients with Covid-19. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2021;384:693&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32678530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung C., Wernly B., Fj&#xf8;lner J., Bruno R.R., Dudzinski D., Artigas A., et al. Steroid use in elderly critically ill COVID-19 patients. Eur Respir J. 2021;58:2100979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8246007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34172464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallay L., Tran V.T., Perrodeau E., Vignier N., Mahevas M., Bisio F., et al. Fourteen-day survival among older adults with severe infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome Coronavirus 2 treated with corticosteroid: a cohort study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:1145&#x2013;1150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8016731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33819571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coppelli A., Giannarelli R., Aragona M., Penno G., Falcone M., Tiseo G., et al. Hyperglycemia at hospital admission is associated with severity of the prognosis in patients hospitalized for COVID-19: the Pisa COVID-19 study. Diabetes Care. 2020;43:2345&#x2013;2348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte-Mill&#xe1;n M.A., Mesa-Plaza N., Guerrero-Santill&#xe1;n M., Morales-Ortega A., Bernal-Bello D., Farf&#xe1;n-Sedano A.I., et al. Prognostic factors and combined use of tocilizumab and corticosteroids in a Spanish cohort of elderly COVID-19 patients. J&#xa0;Med Virol. 2022;94:1540&#x2013;1549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9015514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34845754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falcone M., Tiseo G., Giordano C., Leonildi A., Menichini M., Vecchione A., et al. Predictors of hospital-acquired bacterial and fungal superinfections in COVID-19: a prospective observational study. J&#xa0;Antimicrob Chemother. 2021;76:1078&#x2013;1084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7799007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33374002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falcone M., Tiseo G., Barbieri G., Galfo V., Russo A., Virdis A., et al. Role of low-molecular-weight heparin in hospitalized patients with Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 pneumonia: a prospective observational study. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2020;7:ofaa563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33365358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putot A., Bouiller K., Laborde C., Gilis M., F&#xe9;vre A., Hacquin A., et al. Association between early antibiotic therapy and in-hospital mortality among older patients with SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia. J&#xa0;Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2021:glab209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8406862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34272847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prendki V., Tau N., Avni T., Falcone M., Huttner A., Kaiser L., et al. A&#xa0;systematic review assessing the under-representation of elderly adults in COVID-19 trials. BMC Geriatr. 2020;20:538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7749979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33342426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collier D.A., Ferreira I.A.T.M., Kotagiri P., Datir R.P., Lim E.Y., Touizer E., et al. Age-related immune response heterogeneity to SARS-CoV-2 vaccine BNT162b2. Nature. 2021;596:417&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8373615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34192737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polack F.P., Thomas S.J., Kitchin N., Absalon J., Gurtman A., Lockhart S., et al. Safety and efficacy of the BNT162b2 mRNA Covid-19 vaccine. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2020;383:2603&#x2013;2615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7745181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33301246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falsey A.R., Sobieszczyk M.E., Hirsch I., Sproule S., Robb M.L., Corey L., et al. Phase 3 safety and efficacy of AZD1222 (ChAdOx1 nCoV-19) covid-19 vaccine. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2021;385:2348&#x2013;2360. NEJMoa2105290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8522798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34587382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baden L.R., El Sahly H.M., Essink B., Kotloff K., Frey S., Novak R., et al. Efficacy and safety of the mRNA-1273 SARS-CoV-2 vaccine. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2021;384:403&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7787219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33378609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh E.E., Frenck R.W., Jr., Falsey A.R., Kitchin N., Absalon J., Gurtman A., et al. Safety and immunogenicity of two RNA-based Covid-19 vaccine candidates. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2020;383:2439&#x2013;2450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7583697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33053279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson E.J., Rouphael N.G., Widge A.T., Jackson L.A., Roberts P.C., Makhene M., et al. Safety and immunogenicity of SARS-CoV-2 mRNA-1273 vaccine in older adults. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2020;383:2427&#x2013;2438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7556339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramasamy M.N., Minassian A.M., Ewer K.J., Flaxman A.L., Folegatti P.M., Owens D.R., et al. Safety and immunogenicity of ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccine administered in a prime-boost regimen in young and old adults (COV002): a single-blind, randomised, controlled, phase 2/3 trial. Lancet. 2021;396:1979&#x2013;1993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7674972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazagatos C., Monge S., Olmedo C., Vega L., Gallego P., Mart&#xed;n-Merino E., et al. Effectiveness of mRNA COVID-19 vaccines in preventing SARS-CoV-2 infections and COVID-19 hospitalisations and deaths in elderly long-term care facility residents, Spain, weeks 53 2020 to 13 2021. Euro Surveill. 2021;26:2100452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8212595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34142647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-On Y.M., Goldberg Y., Mandel M., Bodenheimer O., Freedman L., Kalkstein N., et al. Protection of BNT162b2 vaccine booster against Covid-19 in Israel. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2021;385:1393&#x2013;1400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8461568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34525275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Beltran W.F., St Denis K.J., Hoelzemer A., Lam E.C., Nitido A.D., Sheehan M.L., et al. mRNA-based COVID-19 vaccine boosters induce neutralizing immunity against SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variant. Cell. 2022;185:457&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8733787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34995482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C., Huang L., Wang Y., Li X., Ren L., Gu X., et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Wang F., Shen Y., Zhang X., Cen Y., Wang B., et al. Symptoms and health outcomes among survivors of COVID-19 infection 1 year after discharge from hospitals in Wuhan, China. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34586367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosato M., Carf&#xec; A., Martis I., Pais C., Ciciarello F., Rota E., et al. Prevalence and predictors of persistence of COVID-19 symptoms in older adults: a single-center study. J&#xa0;Am Med Dir Assoc. 2021;22:1840&#x2013;1844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8286874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34352201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y.H., Wang Y.R., Wang Q.H., Chen Y., Chen X., Li Y., et al. Post-infection cognitive impairments in a cohort of elderly patients with COVID-19. Mol Neurodegener. 2021;16:48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8287105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34281568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>