<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38455611</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2807-2618</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Narra J</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Narra J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Factors associated with small airway obstruction in COVID-19 survivors: A cross-sectional study among health-care providers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e437</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e437</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e437</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.52225/narra.v3i3.437</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) has been identified for more than two years, yet studies assessing post-infection lung function are limited. Reports on lung function in COVID-19 patients indicate that patients have restrictive defects and small airway dysfunction that can persist and are not necessarily related to the severity of the disease. The aim of this study was to assess the incidence of small airway obstruction and its incidence-associated factors among COVID-19 survivors to better describe the long-term effects of COVID-19. A cross-sectional study was conducted among COVID-19 survivors who less than 50 years at Medan Adventist Hospital between 2020-2022. The data were collected through interview, direct assessment and respiratory examination. A total of 89 COVID-19 survivors were recruited of which the majority of them were female with a mean age of 32.6-year-old with the largest group was 19-30 years. The comorbidities found among the survivors were heart and thyroid disorders, with the most common symptom of post-COVID-19 was fatigue. Most of them had mild COVID-19. The mean forced mid-expiratory flow (FEF<sub>25-75%</sub>) was 96.3&#xb1;20.22, with an incidence rate of small airway obstruction was 19.1%. Univariate and multivariate analyses indicated no significant association between age, gender, comorbidities, history of oxygenation during COVID-19 treatment, COVID-19 severity and the type of post COVID-19 syndrome symptoms with the incidence of small airway obstruction. In conclusion, among COVID-19 survivors who were less than 50 years old, those studied variables seems have less association with the incidence of small airway obstruction. Nevertheless, a further study with a bigger sample size is important to be conducted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aritonang</LastName><ForeName>Minarni Es</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonology and Respiratory Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Sumatera Utara, Medan, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandia</LastName><ForeName>Pandiaman</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Asthma and COPD, Department of Pulmonology and Respiratory Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Sumatera Utara, Medan, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pradana</LastName><ForeName>Andika</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Asthma and COPD, Department of Pulmonology and Respiratory Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Sumatera Utara, Medan, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashar</LastName><ForeName>Taufik</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Health, Universitas Sumatera Utara, Medan, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Indonesia</Country><MedlineTA>Narra J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918625888906676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2807-2618</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 survivor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary function test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk factor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">small airway obstruction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38455611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10919440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52225/narra.v3i3.437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">NarraJ-3-e437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Salahshoori I, Mobaraki-Asl N, Seyfaee A, et al. . Overview of COVID-19 disease: Virology, epidemiology, prevention diagnosis, treatment, and vaccines. Biologics 2021;1(1):2&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toufen C, P&#xea;go-Fernandes PM. COVID-19: Long-term respiratory consequences. Sao Paulo Med J 2021;139:421&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9632533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34287513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surendra H, Paramita D, Arista NN, et al. . Geographical variations and district-level factors associated with COVID-19 mortality in Indonesia: A nationwide ecological study. BMC Public Health 2023;23:103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9840537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36641453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. . Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med 2021;27(4):601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stockley JA, Alhuthail EA, Coney AM, et al. . Lung function and breathing patterns in hospitalised COVID-19 survivors: A review of post-COVID-19 Clinics. Respir Res 2021;22:255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34579722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogami R, Ara&#xfa;jo Filho RC, Cobo Chantong CG, et al. . The importance of radiological patterns and small airway disease in long-term follow-up of postacute COVID-19: A preliminary study. Radiol Res Pract 2022;2022:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9098330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35572465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherrez-Ojeda I, Osorio MF, Robles-Velasco K, et al. . Small airway disease in post-acute COVID-19 syndrome, a non-conventional approach in three years follow-up of a patient with long COVID: A case report. J Med Case Rep 2023;17(1):386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10494419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37691104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-p&#xe9;rez O, Merino E, Leon-ramirez J manuel, et al. . Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: A mediterranean cohort study. J Infect 2021;82:373&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7802523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, et al. . Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol 2021;93(2):1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo X, Jian W, Su Z, et al. . Abnormal pulmonary function in COVID-19 patients at time of hospital discharge. Eur Respir J 2020;55(6):2&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32381497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho JL, Villacreses R, Nagpal P, et al. . Quantitative chest ct assessment of small airways disease in post-acute SARS-CoV-2 infection. Radiology 2022;304(1):185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9270680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35289657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindahl A, Reijula J, Malmberg LP, et al. . Small airway function in Finnish COVID-19 survivors. Respir Res 2021;22(1):1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8390085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34446020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinai B, Khan K, Hong S, et al. . Post-COVID Dyspnea Related to Small Airway Disease. American Thoracic Society 2022 International Conference, May 13-18, 2022 - San Francisco, CA. American Thoracic Society; 2022. p. A2692&#x2013;A2692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao X, Wang Y, He Z, et al. . Three-month pulmonary function and radiological outcomes in COVID-19 survivors: A longitudinal patient cohort study. Open Forum Infect Dis 2021;8(9):ofaa540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34667824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas M, Price OJ, Hull JH. Pulmonary function and COVID-19. Curr Opin Physiol 2021;21:29&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7997144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33817453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Castro R, Vasconcello-Castillo L, Alsina-Restoy X, et al. . Respiratory function in patients post-infection by COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Pulmonology 2021;27(4):328&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7687368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33262076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doerre A, Doblhammer G.. The influence of gender on COVID-19 infections and mortality in Germany: Insights from age- and gender-specific modeling of contact rates, infections, and deaths in the early phase of the pandemic. PLoS One 2022;17:1&#x2013;0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9075634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35522614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGonagle D, O&#x2019;Donnell JS, Sharif K, et al. . Immune mechanisms of pulmonary intravascular coagulopathy in COVID-19 pneumonia. Lancet Rheumatol 2020;2(7):e437&#x2013;e445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7252093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32835247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasio F, Barbuto S, Scarnecchia E, et al. . Medium-term impact of COVID-19 on pulmonary function, functional capacity and quality of life. Eur Respir J 2021;58(3):2004015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7877327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33574080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touman A, Kahyat M, Bulkhi A, et al. . Post COVID-19 chronic parenchymal lung changes. Cureus 2022;14(5):e25197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9209776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35747023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myall KJ, Mukherjee B, Castanheira AM, et al. . Persistent post&#x2013;COVID-19 interstitial lung disease. An observational study of corticosteroid treatment. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2021;18(5):799&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8086530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawadogo W, Tsegaye M, Gizaw A, et al. . Overweight and obesity as risk factors for COVID-19-associated hospitalisations and death: Systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Nutr Prev Heal 2022:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8783972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35814718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sattar N, Valabhji J.. Obesity as a risk factor for severe COVID-19: Summary of the best evidence and implications for health care. Curr Obes Rep 2021;10(3):282&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8353061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34374955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mafort TT, Rufino R, Costa CH, et al. . Obesity: Systemic and pulmonary complications, biochemical abnormalities, and impairment of lung function. Multidiscip Respir Med 2016;11(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4940831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27408717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuperberg SJ, Navetta-Modrov B.. The role of obesity in the immunopathogenesis of COVID-19 respiratory disease and critical illness. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol 2021;65(1):113&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8320126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33797351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R, Rathore SS, Khan H, et al. . Association of obesity with COVID-19 severity and mortality: An updated systemic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression. Front Endocrinol 2022;13:780872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9205425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35721716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Lu Y, Huang YM, et al. . Obesity in patients with COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Metabolism 2020;113:154378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7521361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33002478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arulanandam B, Beladi H, Chakrabarti A.. Obesity and COVID-19 mortality are correlated. Sci Rep 2023;13(1):5895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10088638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37041203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis KL, Helgeson SA, Tatari MM, et al. . COVID-19 and the effects on pulmonary function following infection: A retrospective analysis. EClinicalMedicine 2021;39:101079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8360709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34405138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Clinical management living guidance COVID-19. WHO; 2021:16&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surendra H, Elyazar IR, Djaafara BA, et al. . Clinical characteristics and mortality associated with COVID-19 in Jakarta, Indonesia: A hospital-based retrospective cohort study. Lancet Reg Heal - West Pacific 2021;9:100108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7924904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33681830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>miao Zhao Y, min Shang Y, bin Song W, et al. . Follow-up study of the pulmonary function and related physiological characteristics of COVID-19 survivors three months after recovery. EClinicalMedicine 2020;25:100463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar SS, Binu A, Devan AR, et al. . Mucus targeting as a plausible approach to improve lung function in COVID-19 patients. Med Hypotheses 2021;156:110680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34592563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>