<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39404791</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1619-7089</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of nuclear medicine and molecular imaging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Persistent dysfunctions of brain metabolic connectivity in long-covid with cognitive symptoms.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00259-024-06937-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Our study examines brain metabolic connectivity in SARS-CoV-2 survivors during the acute-subacute and chronic phases, aiming to elucidate the mechanisms underlying the persistence of neurological symptoms in long-COVID patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We perfomed a cross-sectional study including 44 patients (pts) with neurological symptoms who underwent FDG-PET scans, and classified to timing infection as follows: acute (7 pts), subacute (17 pts), long-term (20 pts) phases. Interregional correlation analysis (IRCA) and ROI-based IRCA were applied on FDG-PET data to extract metabolic connectivity in resting state networks (ADMN, PDMN, EXN, ATTN, LIN, ASN) of neuro-COVID pts in acute/subacute and long-term groups compared with healthy controls (HCs). Univariate approach was used to investigate metabolic alterations from the acute to sub-acute and long-term phase.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The acute/subacute phase was characterized by hyperconnectivity in EXN and ATTN networks; the same networks showed hypoconnectivity in the chronic phase. EXN and ATTN hypoconnectivity was consistent with clinical findings in long-COVID patients, e.g. altered performances in neuropsychological tests of executive and attention domains. The ASN and LIN presented hyperconnectivity in acute/subacute phase and normalized in long-term phase. The ADMN and PDMN presented a preseverved connectivity. Univariate analysis showed hypometabolism in fronto-insular cortex in acute phase, which reduced in sub-acute phase and disappeared in long-term phase.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A compensatory EXN and ATTN hyperconnectivity was found in the acute/subacute phase and hypoconnectivity in long-term. Hypoconnectivity and absence of hypometabolism suggest that connectivity derangement in frontal networks could be related to protraction of neurological symptoms in long-term COVID patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Martini</LastName><ForeName>Anna Lisa</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuclear Medicine Unit, Department of Diagnostic Imaging, N.O.P. - S. Stefano, U.S.L. Toscana Centro, Prato, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Carli</LastName><ForeName>Giulia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department Neurology, University Michigan, Ann Arbor, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caminiti</LastName><ForeName>Silvia Paola</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department Brain Behavioral Sciences, University Pavia, Pavia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiferle</LastName><ForeName>Lorenzo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Unit, N.O.P. - S. Stefano, U.S.L. Toscana Centro, Prato, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leo</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuclear Medicine Unit, Department of Diagnostic Imaging, N.O.P. - S. Stefano, U.S.L. Toscana Centro, Prato, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perani</LastName><ForeName>Daniela</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuclear Medicine Unit, San Raffaele Hospital, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sestini</LastName><ForeName>Stelvio</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4886-2756</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuclear Medicine Unit, Department of Diagnostic Imaging, N.O.P. - S. Stefano, U.S.L. Toscana Centro, Prato, Italy. stelvio.sestini@uslcentro.toscana.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101140988</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1619-7070</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain metabolic connectivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FDG-PET</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuro-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resting state network</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39404791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-024-06937-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00259-024-06937-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rothstein TL. Cortical Grey matter volume depletion links to neurological sequelae in post COVID-19 &#x201c;long haulers.&#x201d; BMC Neurol. 2023;23(1):22&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12883-023-03049-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36647063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9843113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera JE, Niehaus WN, Whiteson J, Azola A, Baratta JM, Fleming TK, et al. Multidisciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of fatigue in postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) patients. PM R. 2021;13(9):1027&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmrj.12684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34346558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8441628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV, W.H.O.C.C.D.W.G. on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022; 22(4):e102-e107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Bae S, Chang HH, Kim SW. Long COVID prevalence and impact on quality of life 2 years after acute COVID-19. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):11960&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-39132-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37488240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10366175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghimi N, Di Napoli M, Biller J, Siegler JE, Shekhar R, McCullough LD, et al. The neurological manifestations of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Current Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2021;21(9):1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11910-021-01130-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ariza M, Cano N, Segura B, Adan A, Bargall&#xf3; N, Cald&#xfa; X, et al. Neuropsychological impairment in post-COVID condition individuals with and without cognitive complaints. Front Aging Neurosci. 2022;14:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2022.1029842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leng A, Shah M, Ahmad SA, Premraj L, Wildi K, Li Bassi G, et al. Pathogenesis underlying neurological manifestations of long COVID syndrome and potential therapeutics. Cells. 2023;12(5):816&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells12050816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36899952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10001044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toniolo S, Di Lorenzo F, Scarioni M, Frederiksen KS, Nobili F. Is the Frontal lobe the primary target of SARS-CoV-2? J Alzheimers Dis. 2021;81(1):75&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-210008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33720900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martini AL, Carli G, Kiferle L, Piersanti P, Palumbo P, Morbelli S, et al. Time-dependent recovery of brain hypometabolism in neuro-COVID-19 patients. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2022;50(1):90&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-022-05942-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35984451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9388976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiss AB, Greene C, Dayaramani C, Rauchman SH, Stecker MM, De Leon J, et al. Long COVID, the brain, nerves, and cognitive function. Neurol Int. 2023;15(3):821&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/neurolint15030052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37489358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10366776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM, Sanders EC. Potential neuroinvasive pathways of SARS-CoV-2: deciphering the spectrum of neurological deficit seen in coronavirus disease. J Med Virol. 2020;92(10):1845&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32492193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7300748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wischmann J, Bartos LM, Brendel M, Albert NL, Forbrig R, Straube A, Masouris I. Translocator protein (TSPO)-PET as diagnostic and monitoring tool in COVID-19 related MRI-negative brainstem encephalitis: a case report. J Neurol. 2023;270(6):2853&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-023-11691-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37012466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10069725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser D, Golla SSV, Verfaillie SCJ, Coomans EM, Rikken RM, van de Giessen EM, den Hollander ME, Verveen A, Yaqub M, Barkhof F, Horn J, Koopman B, Schober P, Koch DW, Schuit RC, Windhorst AD, Kassiou M, Boellaard R, van Vugt M, Knoop H, Tolboom N, van Berckel BNM.&#xa0;Long COVID is associated with extensive in-vivo neuroinflammation on [18F]DPA-714 PET. medRxiv. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1101/2022.06.02.22275916 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein JA, Kaes M, Smola S, Schulz-Schaeffer WJ. Neuropathology in COVID-19 autopsies is defined by microglial activation and lesions of the white matter with emphasis in cerebellar and brain stem areas. Front Neurol. 2023;14:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2023.1229641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verger A, Kas A, Dudouet P, Goehringer F, Salmon-Ceron D, Guedj E. Visual interpretation of brain hypometabolism related to neurological long COVID: a French multicentric experience Multicenter Study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;49(9):3197&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-022-05753-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hameed R, Bahadur AR, Singh SB, Sher J, Todua M, Moradi LM, Bastakoti S, Arslan M, Ajmal H, Lee GY, Ayubcha C, Werner TJ, Alavi A, Revheim ME. Neurological and psychiatric manifestations of long COVID-19 and their [<sup>18</sup>F]FDG PET findings: a review. Diagnostics (Basel). 2023;13(14):2353&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics13142353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37510097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horowitz T, Dudouet P, Campion JY, Kaphan E, Radulesco T, Gonzalez S, Camilleri S, M&#xe9;nard A, Guedj E. Perrsistent brain metabolic impairment in long COVID patients with persistent clinical symptoms: a nine-month follow-up [18F]FDG-PET study. EJNMMI. 2024;51:3215&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varrone A, Asenbaum S, Vander Borght T, Booij J, Nobili F, N&#xe5;gren K, et al. EANM procedure guidelines for PET brain imaging using [18F]FDG, version 2. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2009;36(12):2103&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-009-1264-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19838705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paez D, Gnanasegaran G, Fanti S, Bomanji J, Hacker M, Sathekge M, et al. COVID-19 pandemic: guidance for nuclear medicine departments. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2020;47(7):1615&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-020-04825-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32296886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7159284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caminiti SP, Sala A, Presotto L, Chincarini A, Sestini S, Perani D, et al. Validation of FDG-PET datasets of normal controls for the extraction of SPM-based brain metabolism maps. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48(8):1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-020-05175-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Della Rosa PA, Cerami C, Gallivanone F, Prestia A, Caroli A, Castiglioni I, et al. A standardized [18F]-FDG-PET template for spatial normalization in statistical parametric mapping of dementia. Neuroinformatics. 2014;12(4):575&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12021-014-9235-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24952892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perani D, Della Rosa PA, Cerami C, Gallivanone F, Fallanca F, Vanoli EG, et al. Validation of an optimized SPM procedure for FDG-PET in dementia diagnosis in a clinical setting. NeuroImage Clin. 2014;6:445&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2014.10.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25389519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4225527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schindlbeck KA, Eidelberg D. Network imaging biomarkers: Insights and clinical applications in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17:629&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30169-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29914708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ripp I, Stadhouders T, Savio A, Goldhardt O, Cabello J, Calhoun V, et al. Integrity of neurocognitive networks in dementing disorders as measured with simultaneous PET/functional MRI. J Nucl Med. 2020;61:1341&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2967/jnumed.119.234930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32358091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voruz P, Cionca A, Jacot de Alc&#xe2;ntara I, Nuber-Champier A, Allali G, Benzakour L, et al. Brain functional connectivity alterations associated with neuropsychological performance 6&#x2013;9 months following SARS-CoV-2 infection. Human Brain Mapp. 2023;44(4):1629&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.26163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horwitz B, Duara R, Rapoport SI. Intercorrelations of glucose metabolic rates between brain regions: application to healthy males in a state of reduced sensory input. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 1984;4(4):484&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/jcbfm.1984.73</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6501442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boccalini C, Bortolin E, Carli G, Pilotto A, Galbiati A, Padovani A, et al. Metabolic connectivity of resting-state networks in alpha synucleinopathies, from prodromal to dementia phase. Front Neurosci. 2022;16:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2022.930735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savio A, F&#x215;nger S, Tahmasian M, Rachakonda S, Manoliu A, Sorg C. Resting-state networks as simultaneously measured with functional MRI and PET. J Nucl Med. 2017;58(8):1314&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2967/jnumed.116.185835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28254868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6944183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzourio-Mazoyer N, Landeau B, Papathanassiou D, Crivello F, Etard O, Delcroix N, Mazoyer B, Joliot M. Automated anatomical labeling of activations in SPM using a macroscopic anatomical parcellation of the MNI MRI single-subject brain. Neuroimage. 2002;15(1):273&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/nimg.2001.0978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11771995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duff EP, Cunnington R, Egan GF. REX: response exploration for neuroimaging datasets. Neuroinformatics. 2007; Winter 5(4):223&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kas A, Soret M, Pyatigoskaya N, Habert M-O, Hesters A, Le Guennec L, et al. The cerebral network of COVID-19-related encephalopathy: a longitudinal voxel-based 18F-FDG-PET study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48(8):2543&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-020-05178-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33452633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7810428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voigt K, Liang EX, Misic B, Ward PGD, Egan GF, Jamadar SD. Metabolic and functional connectivity provide unique and complementary insights into cognition-connectome relationships. Cereb Cortex. 2023;33(4):1476&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bhac150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35441214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miskowiak KW, Bech JL, Henriksen AC, Johnsen S, Podlekareva D, Marner L. Cerebral metabolic rate of glucose and cognitive tests in long COVID patients. Brain Sci. 2022;22:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sala A, Lizarraga A, Caminiti SP, Calhoun VD, Eickhoff SB, Habeck C, Jamadar SD, Perani D, Pereira JB, Veronese M, Yakushev I. Brain connectomics: time for a molecular imaging perspective? Trends Cogn Sci. 2023;27(4):353&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tics.2022.11.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36621368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10432882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DS, Kang H, Kim H, Park H, Oh JS, Lee JS, et al. Metabolic connectivity by interregional correlation analysis using statistical parametric mapping (SPM) and FDG brain PET; methodological development and patterns of metabolic connectivity in adults. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2008;35(9):1681&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-008-0808-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18491089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito F, Cirillo M, De Micco R, Caiazzo G, Siciliano M, Russo AG, et al. Olfactory loss and brain connectivity after 25 COVID-19. Hum Brain Mapp. 2022;43(5):1548&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.25741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35083823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8886650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillary FG, Grafman JH. Injured Brains and Adaptive Networks: The Benefits and Costs of Hyperconnectivity. Trends Cogn Sci. 2017;21(5):385&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tics.2017.03.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28372878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6664441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sala A, Perani D. Brain molecular connectivity in neurodegenerative diseases: recent advances and new perspectives using positron emission tomography. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:617&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2019.00617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31258466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6587303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer D, Snider SB, Barra ME, Sanders WR, Rapalino O, Schaefer P, et al. Disorders of consciousness associated with COVID-19: Aprospective multimodal study of recovery and brain connectivity. Neurology. 2022;98(3):e315&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000013067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34862317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8792809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedetti F, Palladini M, Paolini M, Melloni E, Vai B, De Lorenzo R, et al. Brain correlates of depression, post-traumatic distress, and inflammatory biomarkers in COVID-19 survivors: A multimodal magnetic resonance imaging study. Brain, Behav Immun Health. 2021;18:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildirim D, Kandemirli SG, Sanli DET, Akinci O, Altundag A. A comparative olfactory MRI, DTI and fMRI study of COVID-19 related anosmia and post viral olfactory dysfunction. Acad Radiol. 2022;29(1):31&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.acra.2021.10.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34810059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Chung T, Wong F, Hung I, Mak H. Changes in the Intranetwork and Internetwork connectivity of Default Mode Network and Olfactory Network in Patients with COVID-19 and Olfactory Dysfuction. Brain Sci. 2022;12:511&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci12040511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35448042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9029634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>