<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38576710</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-858X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Med (Lausanne)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acupressure: a possible therapeutic strategy for anxiety related to COVID-19: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1341072</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1341072</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1341072</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fmed.2024.1341072</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">From the end of 2019 to December 2023, the world grappled with the COVID-19 pandemic. The scope and ultimate repercussions of the pandemic on global health and well-being remained uncertain, ushering in a wave of fear, anxiety, and worry. This resulted in many individuals succumbing to fear and despair. Acupoint massage emerged as a safe and effective alternative therapy for anxiety relief. However, its efficacy was yet to be extensively backed by evidence-based medicine. This study aimed to enhance the clinical effectiveness of acupoint massage and extend its benefits to a wider population. It undertakes a systematic review of the existing randomized controlled trials (RCTs) assessing the impact of acupoint massage on anxiety treatment, discussing its potential benefits and implications. This research aims to furnish robust evidence supporting anxiety treatment strategies for patients afflicted with COVID-19 disease and spark new approaches to anxiety management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study evaluates the evidence derived from randomised controlled trials (RCTs), quantifies the impact of acupressure on anxiety manifestations within the general population, and proposes viable supplementary intervention strategies for managing COVID-19 related anxiety.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This review included RCTs published between February 2014 and July 2023, that compared the effects of acupressure with sham control in alleviating anxiety symptomatology as the outcome measure. The studies were sourced from the multiple databases, including CINAHL, EBM Reviews, Embase, Medline, PsycINFO, Scopus and Web of Science. A meta-analysis was performed on the eligible studies, and an overall effect size was computed specifically for the anxiety outcome. The Cochrane Collaboration Bias Risk Assessment Tool (RevMan V5.4) was employed to assess bias risk, data integration, meta-analysis, and subgroup analysis. The mean difference, standard mean deviation, and binary data were used to represent continuous outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Of 1,110 studies of potential relevance, 39 met the criteria for inclusion in the meta-analysis. The majority of the studies reported a positive effect of acupressure in assuaging anticipatory anxiety about treatment. Eighteen studies were evaluated using the STAI scale. The acupressure procedures were thoroughly documented, and studies exhibited a low risk of bias. The cumulative results of the 18 trials showcased a more substantial reduction in anxiety in the acupressure group compared to controls (SMD =&#x2009;-5.39, 95% CI -5.61 to -5.17, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01). A subsequent subgroup analysis, based on different interventions in the control group, demonstrated improvement in anxiety levels with sham acupressure in improving changes in anxiety levels (SMD -1.61, 95% CI: -2.34 to -0.87, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.0001), and blank controls (SMD -0.92, 95% CI: -2.37 to 0.53, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.22).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In the clinical research of traditional Chinese medicine treatment of anxiety, acupressure demonstrated effectiveness in providing instant relief from anxiety related to multiple diseases with a medium effect size. Considering the increasing incidence of anxiety caused by long COVID, the widespread application of acupressure appears feasible. However, the results were inconsistent regarding improvements on physiological indicators, calling for more stringent reporting procedures, including allocation concealment, to solidify the findings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Peng, Zheng, Yang, Zhang, Li, Xu, Cui and Lin.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Zhihua</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Hospital of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine (Futian), Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Yulin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Hospital of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine (Futian), Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Zeyu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Hospital of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine (Futian), Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hongxiao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Hospital of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine (Futian), Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhennan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Polytechnic University, Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Mingzhu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Shenzhen Hospital, Southern Medical University, Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Shaoyang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Hospital of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine (Futian), Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Run</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Hospital of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine (Futian), Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Med (Lausanne)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101648047</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-858X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acupressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acupuncture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the conduct of this study does not involve any commercial or financial relationships that could be interpreted as potential conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38576710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10993250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2024.1341072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pandey K, Thurman M, Johnson SD, Acharya A, Johnston M, Klug EA, et al. . Mental health issues during and after COVID-19 vaccine era. Brain Res Bull. (2021) 176:161&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1016/j.brainresbull.2021.08.012, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainresbull.2021.08.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8414813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34487856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czeisler M, Lane RI, Petrosky E, Wiley JF, Christensen A, Njai R, et al. . Mental health, substance use, and suicidal ideation during the COVID-19 pandemic&#x2014;United States, June 24&#x2013;30, 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. (2020) 69:1049&#x2013;57. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm6932a1, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm6932a1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7440121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishikawa-Pacher A. Research questions with PICO: a universal mnemonic. Publications. (2022) 10:21. doi: 10.3390/publications10030021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/publications10030021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankot M, Mueller PM, Young ME, Vonder HC. Statistical power and false positive rates for interdependent outcomes are strongly influenced by test type: implications for behavioral neuroscience. Neuropsychopharmacology. (2023) 48:1612&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1038/s41386-023-01592-6, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-023-01592-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10516944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37142665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son S, Yoo BR, Lee SG, Kim WK, Jung JM. Full-endoscopic versus minimally invasive lumbar interbody fusion for lumbar degenerative diseases: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Korean Neurosurg Soc. (2022) 65:539&#x2013;48. doi: 10.3340/jkns.2021.0168, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3340/jkns.2021.0168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9271818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35765801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hmwe NT, Subramanian P, Tan LP, Chong WK. The effects of acupressure on depression, anxiety and stress in patients with hemodialysis: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Nurs Stud. (2015) 52:509&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2014.11.002, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2014.11.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25468282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bikmoradi A, Najafi F, Roshanaei G, Esmaeil ZP, Khatibian M, Ahmadi A. Acupressure and anxiety in cancer patients. Iran Red Crescent Med J. (2015) 17:e25919. doi: 10.5812/ircmj.25919</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/ircmj.25919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26019908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aygin D, &#x15e;en S. Acupressure on anxiety and sleep quality after cardiac surgery: a randomized controlled trial. J Perianesth Nurs. (2019) 34:1222&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1016/j.jopan.2019.03.014, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jopan.2019.03.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31303389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani M, Sharma L, Advani U, Kumar S. Acupressure as an adjunct to pharmacological treatment for depression, anxiety, and stress in patients with knee osteoarthritis. J Acupunct Meridian Stud. (2020) 13:129&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1016/j.jams.2020.07.001, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jams.2020.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastani F. Effect of acupressure on maternal anxiety in women with gestational diabetes mellitus: a randomized clinical trial. Clin Nurs Res. (2016) 25:325&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1177/1054773815579344, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1054773815579344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25848127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abadi F, Abadi F, Fereidouni Z, Amirkhani M, Karimi S, Najafi KM. Effect of acupressure on preoperative cesarean section anxiety. J Acupunct Meridian Stud. (2018) 11:361&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.jams.2018.07.001, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jams.2018.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29990586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zick S, Schrepf A, Hasset A, Sen A, Harris R. Depression, anxiety, and pain as potential mediators and moderators of self administered acupressure&#x2019;s effect on fatigue and sleep quality in breast cancer survivors. Psycho-oncology. (2018) 27:74. doi: 10.1002/pon.4623</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.4623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohaddes Ardabili F, Purhajari S, Najafi Ghzeljeh T, Haghani H. The effect of shiatsu massage on underlying anxiety in burn patients. World J Plast Surg. (2015) 4:36&#x2013;9. PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4298863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25606475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehghanmehr S, Sargazi GH, Biabani A, Nooraein S, Allahyari J. Comparing the effect of acupressure and foot reflexology on anxiety and depression in hemodialysis patients: a clinical trial. Med Surg Nurs J. (2019) 8:e100386. doi: 10.5812/msnj.100386</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/msnj.100386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouy S, Etebarian A, Saeidi S, Majidi S. Evaluating the effectiveness of acupressure on anxiety of mothers in a pediatric surgical waiting area: a randomized clinical trial. Anaesth Crit Care Pain Med. (2019) 23:23&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadi P, Alipour Z, Lamyian M. The effect of acupressure at spleen 6 acupuncture point on the anxiety level and sedative and analgesics consumption of women during labor: a randomized, single-blind clinical trial. Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res. (2018) 23:87&#x2013;92. doi: 10.4103/ijnmr.IJNMR_199_16, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijnmr.IJNMR_199_16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5881236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29628954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horiuchi S, Tsuda A, Honda Y, Kobayashi H, Naruse M, Tsuchiyagaito A. Mood changes by self-administered acupressure in Japanese college students: a randomized controlled trial. Global J Health Sci. (2015) 7:40&#x2013;4. doi: 10.5539/gjhs.v7n4p40</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5539/gjhs.v7n4p40</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4802122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25946916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanza Gul D, Solt KA. Effects of acupressure on preoperative acute anxiety in cesarean section under spinal anesthesia: a double-blind randomized controlled study. Holist Nurs Pract. (2020) 34:356&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1097/HNP.0000000000000413, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HNP.0000000000000413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33060498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasokolaei ZR, Rejeh N, Heravi-Karimooi M, Tadrisi SD, Saatchi K, Poshtchaman Z, et al. . Comparison of the effects of hand reflexology versus acupressure on anxiety and vital signs in female patients with coronary artery diseases. Healthcare. (2019) 7:26. doi: 10.3390/healthcare7010026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare7010026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6473738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30754687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansoorzadeh KH, Afazel MR, Taghadosi M, Gilasi HR. The effect of acupressure on anxiety and dysrhythmia in patients undergoing cardiac catheterization. Life Sci J. (2014) 11:153&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genc F, Tan M. The effect of acupressure application on chemotherapy-induced nausea, vomiting, and anxiety in patients with breast cancer. Palliat Support Care. (2015) 13:275&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1017/S1478951514000248, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1478951514000248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24787745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifi Rizi M, Shamsalinia A, Ghaffari F, Keyhanian S, Naderi NB. The effect of acupressure on pain, anxiety, and the physiological indexes of patients with cancer undergoing bone marrow biopsy. Complement Ther Clin Pract. (2017) 29:136&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1016/j.ctcp.2017.09.002, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2017.09.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29122251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rarani SA, Rajai N, Sharififar S. Effects of acupressure at the P6 and LI4 points on the anxiety level of soldiers in the Iranian military. BMJ Mil Health. (2021) 167:177&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1136/jramc-2019-001332, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jramc-2019-001332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avisa P, Kamatham R, Vanjari K, Nuvvula S. Effectiveness of acupressure on dental anxiety in children. Pediatr Dent. (2018) 40:177&#x2013;83. PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29793563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borji M, Pouy S, Yaghobi Y, Nabi BN. Effectiveness of acupressure on anxiety of children undergoing anesthesia. Int J Adolesc Med Health. (2019) 33. doi: 10.1515/ijamh-2018-0177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/ijamh-2018-0177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31050652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo SY, Tsai SH, Chen SL, Tzeng YL. Auricular acupressure relieves anxiety and fatigue, and reduces cortisol levels in post-caesarean section women: a single-blind, randomised controlled study. Int J Nurs Stud. (2016) 53:17&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2015.10.006, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2015.10.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26525188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kafaei-Atrian M, Mirbagher-Ajorpaz N, Sarvieh M, Sadat Z, Asghari-Jafarabadi M, Solhi M. The effect of acupressure at third liver point on the anxiety level in patients with primary dysmenorrhea. Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res. (2016) 21:142&#x2013;6. doi: 10.4103/1735-9066.178233, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1735-9066.178233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4815368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27095986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi Z, Akbarzadeh M, Moradi P, Toosi M, Hadianfard MJ. The effect of acupressure at GB-21 and SP-6 acupoints on anxiety level and maternal-fetal attachment in primiparous women: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Nurs Midwifery Stud. (2014) 3:e19948. doi: 10.17795/nmsjournal19948</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17795/nmsjournal19948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4332991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25699279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng YT, Chen IH, Lee PH, Lin PC. Effects of auricular acupressure on depression and anxiety in older adult residents of long-term care institutions: a randomized clinical trial. Geriatr Nurs. (2021) 42:205&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1016/j.gerinurse.2020.08.003, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gerinurse.2020.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32921508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L, Zhang Y, Qian HY, Xu JL, Xie CY, Dong B, et al. . Auricular acupressure for cancer-related fatigue during lung cancer chemotherapy: a randomised trial. BMJ Support Palliat Care. (2021) 11:32&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1136/bmjspcare-2019-001937, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjspcare-2019-001937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31836594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo L, Dai Q, Mo Y, Yan Y, Qian M, Zhuang X, et al. . The effect of auricular acupressure on preoperative anxiety in patients undergoing gynecological surgery. Int J Clin Exp Med. (2016) 9:4065&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bang YY, Park H. Effects of auricular acupressure on the quality of sleep and anxiety in patients undergoing cardiac surgery: a single-blind, randomized controlled trial. Appl Nurs Res. (2020) 53:151269. doi: 10.1016/j.apnr.2020.151269, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apnr.2020.151269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32451010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangani NJ, Rahimi H, Mirzaei SMM, BahramiTaghanaki H, Vagharseyyedin SA. Effect of acupressure on anxiety, stress, and depression among the primary family caregivers of the patients with stroke. J Holist Nurs Midwifery. (2023) 33:113&#x2013;21. doi: 10.32598/jhnm.33.2.2303</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32598/jhnm.33.2.2303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd Elgwad Ali IS, Ali ZH, Hasan SN. The effect of acupressure on severity of pain and level of anxiety for patients post coronary artery bypass graft. Afr J Nurs Midwifery. (2022) 5:91&#x2013;110. doi: 10.52589/AJHNM-FQOINTFB</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52589/AJHNM-FQOINTFB</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bal SK, Gun M. The effects of acupressure on pain, anxiety and vital signs in patients undergoing coronary angiography: a randomized and sham-controlled trial. Explore. (2023). doi: 10.1016/j.explore.2023.07.001, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.explore.2023.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37429762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derya Ister E, Altinbas Y. The effect of acupressure on anxiety and pain among patients undergoing coronary angiography: a randomized controlled trial. Holist Nurs Pract. (2022) 36:E57&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1097/HNP.0000000000000553, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HNP.0000000000000553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36255344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai W, Zhang K, Wang GT, Li J, Wei XY, Ma W, et al. . Effects and safety of auricular acupressure on depression and anxiety in isolated COVID-19 patients: a single-blind randomized controlled trial. Front Psychiatry. (2022) 13:1041829. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2022.1041829</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2022.1041829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9760812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36545041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masoudi Z, Kasraeian M, Akbarzadeh M. Assessment of educational intervention and acupressure during labor on the mother&#x2019;s anxiety level and arterial oxygen pressure of the umbilical cord of infants (PO2). A randomized controlled clinical trial. J Educ Health Promot. (2022) 11:86. doi: 10.4103/jehp.jehp_685_20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jehp.jehp_685_20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9093657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35573609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho Y, Joo JM, Kim S, Sok S. Effects of meridian acupressure on stress, fatigue, anxiety, and self-efficacy of shiftwork nurses in South Korea. Int J Environ Res Public Health. (2021) 18:4199. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18084199, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18084199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8071356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33921026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#x105;cznik AK, Schneiders AG, Athens J, Sullivan SJ. Does acupressure hit the mark? A three-arm randomized placebo-controlled trial of acupressure for pain and anxiety relief in athletes with acute musculoskeletal sports injuries. Clin J Sport Med. (2017) 27:338&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1097/JSM.0000000000000378, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28653963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharwal J, Srinivasan P, Kanika SJ. Effect of acupressure on anxiety among patients undergoing hemodialysis in selected hospitals of Ambala, Haryana: a randomized controlled trial. Appl Nurs Res. (2020) 11:345&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee E, Park JH. Effect of acupressure on pre-exam anxiety in nursing students. Altern Ther Health Med. (2023) 29:158&#x2013;63. PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34331752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consola&#xe7;&#xe3;o Soares ME, de Souza AA, Lagares Pinto IC, Ara&#xfa;jo Barbosa LS, Borsatto MC, Galo R. Effect of acupressure on dental anxiety in children: a pilot study for a randomized clinical trial. J Acupunct Meridian Stud. (2022) 15:307&#x2013;13. doi: 10.51507/j.jams.2022.15.5.307, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51507/j.jams.2022.15.5.307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36521828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanik TC, Kanat C, Karaman A, Yilmaz SG, Ugras GA. Effect of acupressure on senior nursing students&#x2019; anxiety during the COVID-19 pandemic: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Int J Caring Sci. (2023) 16:218&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balon R, Starcevic V. Role of benzodiazepines in anxiety disorders. Adv Exp Med Biol. (2020) 1191:367&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1007/978-981-32-9705-0_20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-32-9705-0_20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32002938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shyken JM, Babbar S, Babbar S, Forinash A. Benzodiazepines in Pregnancy. Clin Obstet Gynecol. (2019) 62:156&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1097/GRF.0000000000000417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/GRF.0000000000000417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30628916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubovsky SL, Marshall D. Benzodiazepines remain important therapeutic options in psychiatric practice. Psychother Psychosom. (2022) 91:307&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1159/000524400, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000524400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35504267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickson SJ, Kuhnert RL, Lavell CH, Rapee RM. Impact of psychotherapy for children and adolescents with anxiety disorders on global and domain-specific functioning: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Child Fam Psychol Rev. (2022) 25:720&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1007/s10567-022-00402-7, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10567-022-00402-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9622529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35794304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amorim D, Brito I, Caseiro A, Figueiredo JP, Pinto A, Macedo I, et al. . Electroacupuncture and acupuncture in the treatment of anxiety&#x2014;a double blinded randomized parallel clinical trial. Complement Ther Clin Pract. (2022) 46:101541. doi: 10.1016/j.ctcp.2022.101541, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2022.101541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9760487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong QY, Liu R, Zhang K, Gao Y, Cui GW, Shen WD. Can acupuncture therapy reduce preoperative anxiety? A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Integr Med. (2021) 19:20&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.joim.2020.10.007, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joim.2020.10.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33288487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues PA, Zaninotto AL, Neville IS, Hayashi CY, Brunoni AR, Teixeira MJ, et al. . Transcranial magnetic stimulation for the treatment of anxiety disorder. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. (2019) 15:2743&#x2013;61. doi: 10.2147/NDT.S201407, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S201407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6765211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31576130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed SA, Cunningham K, Bloch RM. Depression and anxiety disorders: benefits of exercise, yoga, and meditation. Am Fam Physician. (2019) 99:620&#x2013;7. PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31083878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou PW, Hsu HC, Lin YW, Tang NY, Cheng CY, Hsieh CL. The history, mechanism, and clinical application of auricular therapy in traditional Chinese medicine. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. (2015) 2015:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1155/2015/495684, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/495684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4707384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26823672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SR, Hou WH, Lai JN, Kwong JSW, Lin PC. Effects of acupressure on anxiety: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Integr Complement Med. (2022) 28:25&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1089/jicm.2020.0256, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jicm.2020.0256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35085025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chellappa SL, Aeschbach D. Sleep and anxiety: from mechanisms to interventions. Sleep Med Rev. (2022) 61:101583. doi: 10.1016/j.smrv.2021.101583</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2021.101583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34979437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Iorio CR, Carey CE, Michalski LJ, Corral-Frias NS, Conley ED, Hariri AR, et al. . Hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis genetic variation and early stress moderates amygdala function. Psychoneuroendocrinology. (2017) 80:170&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.psyneuen.2017.03.016, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psyneuen.2017.03.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5685810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28364727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Au DW, Tsang HW, Ling PP, Leung CH, Ip PK, Cheung WM. Effects of acupressure on anxiety: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Acupunct Med. (2015) 33:353&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1136/acupmed-2014-010720, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/acupmed-2014-010720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26002571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juruena MF, Eror F, Cleare AJ, Young AH. The role of early life stress in HPA axis and anxiety. Adv Exp Med Biol. (2020) 1191:141&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1007/978-981-32-9705-0_9, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-32-9705-0_9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32002927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawluski JL, Swain JE, Lonstein JS. Neurobiology of peripartum mental illness. Handb Clin Neurol. (2021) 182:63&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1016/B978-0-12-819973-2.00005-8, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-12-819973-2.00005-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34266612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai YH, Wu SY, Hu WL, Lai YR, Tsao Y, Yen KT, et al. . Immediate effect of non-invasive auricular acupoint stimulation on the performance and meridian activities of archery athletes: a protocol for randomized controlled trial. Medicine. (2021) 100:e24753. doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000024753, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000024753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7909231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33663090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao H, Wei D, Cai D, Yu S, Zhang C, Wei J, et al. . Effects of acupuncture on ANP and CNP in adrenal gland and CORT in plasma in rats with chronic emotional stress anxiety. Zhongguo Zhen Jiu. (2016) 36:169&#x2013;74. PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27348920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z, Kim SC, Liu H, Zhang J, Wang Y, Cho IJ, et al. . Manual acupuncture at PC6 ameliorates acute restraint stress-induced anxiety in rats by normalizing amygdaloid noradrenergic response. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. (2017) 2017:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1155/2017/4351723</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2017/4351723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5576413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28900460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue N, Li B, Yang L, Han QQ, Huang HJ, Wang YL, et al. . Electro-acupuncture alleviates chronic unpredictable stress-induced depressive- and anxiety-like behavior and hippocampal neuroinflammation in rat model of depression. Front Mol Neurosci. (2018) 11:149. doi: 10.3389/fnmol.2018.00149, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnmol.2018.00149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6007169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Cao L, Liu J, Zhang Z, Fan P, Zhu Y, et al. . Increased hippocampal glucocorticoid receptor expression and reduced anxiety-like behavior following Tuina in a rat model with allergic airway inflammation. J Manip Physiol Ther. (2022) 45:586&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1016/j.jmpt.2023.04.008, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmpt.2023.04.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37294215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>