<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37695426</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0070-217X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>441</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current topics in microbiology and immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Top Microbiol Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Biological Sex and Pregnancy on SARS-CoV-2 Pathogenesis and Vaccine Outcomes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>75</StartPage><EndPage>110</EndPage><MedlinePgn>75-110</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/978-3-031-35139-6_4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>SARS-CoV-2 is the causative agent of COVID-19 in humans and has&#xa0;resulted in the death of millions of people worldwide. Similar numbers of infections have been documented in males and females; males, however, are more likely than females to be hospitalized, require intensive care unit, or die from COVID-19. The mechanisms that account for this are multi-factorial and are likely to include differential expression of ACE2 and TMPRSS2 molecules that are required for viral entry into hosts cells and&#xa0;sex differences in the immune response, which are&#xa0;due to modulation of cellular functions by sex hormones&#xa0;and differences in&#xa0;chromosomal gene expression. Furthermore, as comorbidities are also associated with poorer outcomes to SARS-CoV-2 infection and several comorbidities are overrepresented in males, these are also likely to contribute to the observed sex differences. Despite their relative better prognosis following infection with SARS-CoV-2, females do have poorer outcomes during pregnancy. This is likely to be due to pregnancy-induced changes in the immune system that adversely affect viral immunity and disruption of the renin-angiotensin system. Importantly, vaccination reduces the severity of disease in males and females, including pregnant females, and there is no evidence that vaccination has any adverse effects on the outcomes of pregnancy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s), under exclusive license to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shapiro</LastName><ForeName>Janna R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of International Health, Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Craig W</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Pharmacy and Biomedical Sciences, University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arcovio</LastName><ForeName>Kasandra</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Pharmacy and Biomedical Sciences, University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reade</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Pharmacy and Biomedical Sciences, University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klein</LastName><ForeName>Sabra L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of International Health, Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>W. Harry Feinstone Department of Molecular Microbiology and Immunology, Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dhakal</LastName><ForeName>Santosh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>W. Harry Feinstone Department of Molecular Microbiology and Immunology, Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, Baltimore, MD, USA. sdhakal3@vet.k-state.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic Medicine/Pathobiology, College of Veterinary Medicine, Kansas State University, Manhattan, KS, USA. sdhakal3@vet.k-state.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Top Microbiol Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0110513</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0070-217X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014612">Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014612" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014611" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccination</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053586" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Internalization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 vaccine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sex difference</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37695426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-031-35139-6_4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdullahi H, Elnahas A, Konje JC (2021) Seasonal influenza during pregnancy. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol 258:235&#x2013;239</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33476926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejogrb.2021.01.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal U, Katikireddi SV, McCowan C, Mulholland RH, Azcoaga-Lorenzo A, Amele S et al (2021) COVID-19 hospital admissions and deaths after BNT162b2 and ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccinations in 2&#xb7; 57 million people in Scotland (EAVE II): a prospective cohort study. Lancet Respir Med 9(12):1439&#x2013;1449</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34599903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8480963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00380-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, Rivera SC, McMullan C, Chandan JS et al (2021) Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med 114(9):428&#x2013;442</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8450986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/01410768211032850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbar MIA, Gumilar KE, Andriya R, Wardhana MP, Mulawardhana P, Anas JY et al (2022) Clinical manifestations and pregnancy outcomes of COVID-19 in indonesian referral hospital in central pandemic area. Obstet Gynecol Sci 65(1):29&#x2013;36</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34736316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8784935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5468/ogs.21135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfredo CA, Noemi CR, Samuel RL, Daniel OC, Rodrigo RB, Paul MT, et al (2022) Effect of norelgestromin and ethinylestradiol in transdermal patches on the clinical outcomes and biochemical parameters of COVID-19 patients: a clinical trial pilot study. Pharmaceuticals (Basel) 15(6)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghamdi IG, Hussain II, Almalki SS, Alghamdi MS, Alghamdi MM, El-Sheemy MA (2014) The pattern of Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus in Saudi Arabia: a descriptive epidemiological analysis of data from the Saudi Ministry of Health. Int J Gen Med 7:417&#x2013;423</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25187734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4149400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJGM.S67061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhumaid S, Al Mutair A, Al Alawi Z, Rabaan AA, Tirupathi R, Alomari MA et al (2021) Anaphylactic and nonanaphylactic reactions to SARS-CoV-2 vaccines: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Allergy Asthma Clin Immunol 17(1):1&#x2013;24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13223-021-00613-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anis E, Preis SA, Cedar N, Tal Y, Hershkowitz I, Hershko AY (2022) Reporting of allergic reactions during Pfizer-BioNTech BNTT162B2 vaccination in Israel. J Allergy Clin Immunol: In Pract 10(11):2969&#x2013;2976</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asano T, Boisson B, Onodi F, Matuozzo D, Moncada-Velez M, Maglorius Renkilaraj MRL et al (2021) X-linked recessive TLR7 deficiency in ~1% of men under 60 years old with life-threatening COVID-19. Sci Immunol 6(62)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baden LR, El Sahly HM, Essink B, Kotloff K, Frey S, Novak R et al (2020) Efficacy and safety of the mRNA-1273 SARS-CoV-2 vaccine. New Engl J Med</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baristaite G, Gurwitz D (2022) Estradiol reduces ACE2 and TMPRSS2 mRNA levels in A549 human lung epithelial cells. Drug Dev Res 83(4):961&#x2013;966</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35103351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9015589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ddr.21923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastard P, Rosen LB, Zhang Q, Michailidis E, Hoffmann HH, Zhang Y et al (2020) Autoantibodies against type I IFNs in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science 370(6515)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blakeway H, Prasad S, Kalafat E, Heath PT, Ladhani SN, Le Doare K et al (2022) COVID-19 vaccination during pregnancy: coverage and safety. Am J Obstet Gynecol 226(2):236e1&#x2013;236e14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bookstein Peretz S, Regev N, Novick L, Nachshol M, Goffer E, Ben-David A et al (2021) Short-term outcome of pregnant women vaccinated with BNT162b2 mRNA COVID-19 vaccine. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol 58(3):450&#x2013;456</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34198360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8441755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/uog.23729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozkurt B, Kamat I, Hotez PJ (2021) Myocarditis with COVID-19 mRNA vaccines. Circulation 144(6):471&#x2013;484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34281357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8340726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.121.056135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brainard J, Jones NR, Harrison FCD, Hammer CC, Lake IR (2023) Super-spreaders of novel coronaviruses that cause SARS, MERS and COVID-19: a systematic review. Ann Epidemiol 82:66&#x2013;76.e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunyavanich S, Do A, Vicencio A (2020) Nasal gene expression of angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 in children and adults. JAMA 323(23):2427&#x2013;2429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32432657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7240631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.8707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadegiani FA, McCoy J, Gustavo Wambier C, Goren A (2021) Early antiandrogen therapy with Dutasteride reduces viral shedding, inflammatory responses, and time-to-remission in males with COVID-19: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled interventional trial (EAT-DUTA AndroCoV Trial&#x2014;Biochemical). Cureus 13(2):e13047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33643746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7885746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrouel F, Gadea E, Esparcieux A, Dimet J, Langlois ME, Perrier H et al (2021) Saliva quantification of SARS-CoV-2 in real-time PCR from asymptomatic or mild COVID-19 adults. Front Microbiol 12:786042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35046915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2021.786042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castano-Jaramillo LM, Yamazaki-Nakashimada MA, O&#x2019;Farrill-Romanillos PM, Muzquiz Zerme&#xf1;o D, Scheffler Mendoza SC, Venegas Montoya E et al (2021) COVID-19 in the context of inborn errors of immunity: a case series of 31 patients from Mexico. J Clin Immunol 41(7):1463&#x2013;1478</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34114122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8191444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10875-021-01077-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakravarty D, Nair SS, Hammouda N, Ratnani P, Gharib Y, Wagaskar V et al (2020) Sex differences in SARS-CoV-2 infection rates and the potential link to prostate cancer. Commun Biol 3(1):374</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32641750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7343823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42003-020-1088-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang JJ, Woods M, Lindsay RJ, Doyle EH, Griesbeck M, Chan ES et al (2013) Higher expression of several interferon-stimulated genes in HIV-1-infected females after adjusting for the level of viral replication. J Infect Dis 208(5):830&#x2013;838</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23757341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3733517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jit262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N, Zhou M, Dong X, Qu J, Gong F, Han Y et al (2020a) Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of 99 cases of 2019 novel coronavirus pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a descriptive study. Lancet 395(10223):507&#x2013;513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32007143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7135076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30211-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Guo J, Wang C, Luo F, Yu X, Zhang W et al (2020b) Clinical characteristics and intrauterine vertical transmission potential of COVID-19 infection in nine pregnant women: a retrospective review of medical records. Lancet 395(10226):809&#x2013;815</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32151335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7159281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30360-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen PZ, Bobrovitz N, Premji ZA, Koopmans M, Fisman DN, Gu FX (2021) SARS-CoV-2 shedding dynamics across the respiratory tract, sex, and disease severity for adult and pediatric COVID-19. Elife 10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B (2022) Global prevalence of post COVID-19 condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis 6: 100122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong WP, Ip WK, Tso GH, Ng MW, Wong WH, Law HK et al (2006) The interferon gamma gene polymorphism +874 A/T is associated with severe acute respiratory syndrome. BMC Infect Dis 6:82</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16672072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1468415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2334-6-82</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu H, Chan JF, Wang Y, Yuen TT, Chai Y, Hou Y et al (2020) Comparative replication and immune activation profiles of SARS-CoV-2 and SARS-CoV in human lungs: an ex vivo study with implications for the pathogenesis of COVID-19. Clin Infect Dis 71(6):1400&#x2013;1409</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32270184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciaa410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collier AY, McMahan K, Yu J, Tostanoski LH, Aguayo R, Ansel J et al (2021) Immunogenicity of COVID-19 mRNA vaccines in pregnant and lactating women. JAMA 325(23):2370&#x2013;2380</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33983379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.7563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook IF (2009) Sex differences in injection site reactions with human vaccines. Hum Vaccin 5(7):441&#x2013;449</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19377279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4161/hv.8476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutinho JM, Ferro JM, Canhao P, Barinagarrementeria F, Cant&#xfa; C, Bousser M-G et al (2009) Cerebral venous and sinus thrombosis in women. Stroke 40(7):2356&#x2013;2361</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19478226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.108.543884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dambha-Miller H, Hinton W, Wilcox CR, Joy M, Feher M de Lusignan S (2022) Mortality in COVID-19 among women on hormone replacement therapy: a retrospective cohort study. Family Pract</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demonbreun AR, Sancilio A, Velez ME, Ryan DT, Pesce L, Saber R et al (2021) COVID-19 mRNA vaccination generates greater IgG levels in women compared to men. J Infect Dis jiab314</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Q, Rasool RU, Russell RM, Natesan R, Asangani IA (2021) Targeting androgen regulation of TMPRSS2 and ACE2 as a therapeutic strategy to combat COVID-19. iScience 24(3):102254</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhakal S, Ruiz-Bedoya CA, Zhou R, Creisher PS, Villano JS, Littlefield K et al (2021) Sex differences in lung imaging and SARS-CoV-2 antibody responses in a COVID-19 golden Syrian Hamster model. mBio 12(4):e0097421</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhindsa S, Zhang N, McPhaul MJ, Wu Z, Ghoshal AK, Erlich EC et al (2021) Association of circulating sex hormones with inflammation and disease severity in patients with COVID-19. JAMA Netw Open 4(5):e2111398</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34032853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8150664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.11398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Resta C, Ferrari D, Vigan&#xf2; M, Moro M, Sabetta E, Minerva M et al (2021) The gender impact assessment among healthcare workers in the SARS-CoV-2 vaccination&#x2014;an analysis of serological response and side effects. Vaccines 9(5):522</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34070196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8158485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vaccines9050522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding T, Zhang J, Wang T, Cui P, Chen Z, Jiang J et al (2021) Potential influence of menstrual status and sex hormones on female severe acute respiratory syndrome Coronavirus 2 infection: a cross-sectional multicenter study in Wuhan, China. Clin Infect Dis 72(9):e240&#x2013;e248</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32697835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciaa1022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Englund JA, Chu HY (2018) Respiratory virus infection during pregnancy: does it matter? J Infect Dis 218(4):512&#x2013;515</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29741694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiy169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pai M (ed) (2022) Epidemiology of VITT. In: Seminars in hematology. Elsevier</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairweather D, Cooper LT Jr, Blauwet LA (2013) Sex and gender differences in myocarditis and dilated cardiomyopathy. Curr Probl Cardiol 38(1):7&#x2013;46</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23158412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4136454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpcardiol.2012.07.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falsey AR, Sobieszczyk ME, Hirsch I, Sproule S, Robb ML, Corey L et al (2021) Phase 3 safety and efficacy of AZD1222 (ChAdOx1 nCoV-19) COVID-19 vaccine. N Engl J Med 385(25):2348&#x2013;2360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34587382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2105290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanagan KL, Fink AL, Plebanski M, Klein SL (2017) Sex and gender differences in the outcomes of vaccination over the life course. Annu Rev Cell Dev Biol 33:577&#x2013;599</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28992436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-cellbio-100616-060718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foldi M, Farkas N, Kiss S, Dembrovszky F, Szakacs Z, Balasko M et al (2021) Visceral adiposity elevates the risk of critical condition in COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obesity (silver Spring) 29(3):521&#x2013;528</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33263191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.23096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo SS, Cambou MC, Mok T, Fajardo VM, Jung KL, Fuller T et al (2021) The systemic inflammatory landscape of COVID-19 in pregnancy: extensive serum proteomic profiling of mother-infant dyads with in utero SARS-CoV-2. Cell Rep Med 2(11):100453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34723226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8549189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xcrm.2021.100453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fung G, Luo H, Qiu Y, Yang D, McManus B (2016) Myocarditis. Circ Res 118(3):496&#x2013;514</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26846643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.115.306573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galasso V, Pons V, Profeta P, Becher M, Brouard S, Foucault M (2020) Gender differences in COVID-19 attitudes and behavior: Panel evidence from eight countries. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 117(44):27285&#x2013;27291</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33060298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7959517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2012520117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesh R, Grach SL, Ghosh AK, Bierle DM, Salonen BR, Collins NM et al (2022) The female-predominant persistent immune dysregulation of the post-COVID syndrome. Mayo Clin Proc 97(3):454&#x2013;464</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35135695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mayocp.2021.11.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Z, Chen Z, Sun A, Deng X (2019) Gender differences in cardiovascular disease. Med Novel Technol Dev 4:100025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.medntd.2019.100025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gargano JW, Wallace M, Hadler SC, Langley G, Su JR, Oster ME et al (2021) Use of mRNA COVID-19 vaccine after reports of myocarditis among vaccine recipients: update from the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices&#x2014;United States, June 2021. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 70(27):977</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm7027e2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebhard C, Regitz-Zagrosek V, Neuhauser HK, Morgan R, Klein SL (2020) Impact of sex and gender on COVID-19 outcomes in Europe. Biol Sex Differ 11(1):29</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32450906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7247289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13293-020-00304-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gedeborg R, Styrke J, Loeb S, Garmo H, Stattin P (2021) Androgen deprivation therapy and excess mortality in men with prostate cancer during the initial phase of the COVID-19 pandemic. PLoS ONE 16(10):e0255966</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34618806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8496782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0255966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Good N, Fedak KM, Goble D, Keisling A, L&#x2019;Orange C, Morton E et al (2021) Respiratory aerosol emissions from vocalization: age and sex differences are explained by volume and exhaled CO<sub>2</sub>. Environ Sci Technol Lett 8(12):1071&#x2013;1076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.estlett.1c00760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray KJ, Bordt EA, Atyeo C, Deriso E, Akinwunmi B, Young N et al (2021) Coronavirus disease 2019 vaccine response in pregnant and lactating women: a cohort study. Am J Obstet Gynecol 225(3):303.e1&#x2013;303.e17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green MS, Peer V, Magid A, Hagani N, Anis E, Nitzan D (2022) Gender differences in adverse events following the Pfizer-BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine. Vaccines 10(2):233</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35214694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8875740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vaccines10020233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greinacher A, Thiele T, Warkentin TE, Weisser K, Kyrle PA, Eichinger S (2021a) Thrombotic thrombocytopenia after ChAdOx1 nCov-19 vaccination. N Engl J Med 384(22):2092&#x2013;2101</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33835769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2104840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greinacher A, Selleng K, Palankar R, Wesche J, Handtke S, Wolff M et al (2021b) Insights in ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia. Blood J Am Soc Hematol 138(22):2256&#x2013;2268</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grzelak L, Velay A, Madec Y, Gallais F, Staropoli I, Schmidt-Mutter C et al (2021) Sex differences in the evolution of neutralizing antibodies to severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2. J Infect Dis 224(6):983&#x2013;988</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33693749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiab127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan WJ, Ni ZY, Hu Y, Liang WH, Ou CQ, He JX et al (2020) Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N Engl J Med 382(18):1708&#x2013;1720</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32109013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2002032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan WJ, Liang WH, Zhao Y, Liang HR, Chen ZS, Li YM et al (2020) Comorbidity and its impact on 1590 patients with COVID-19 in China: a nationwide analysis. Eur Respir J 55(5)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadjadj J, Yatim N, Barnabei L, Corneau A, Boussier J, Smith N et al (2020) Impaired type I interferon activity and inflammatory responses in severe COVID-19 patients. Science 369(6504):718&#x2013;724</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7402632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abc6027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajeer AH, Balkhy H, Johani S, Yousef MZ, Arabi Y (2016) Association of human leukocyte antigen class II alleles with severe Middle East respiratory syndrome-coronavirus infection. Ann Thorac Med. 11(3):211&#x2013;213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27512511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4966224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1817-1737.185756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hause AM, Avadhanula V, Maccato ML, Pinell PM, Bond N, Santarcangelo P et al (2018) A cross-sectional surveillance study of the frequency and etiology of acute respiratory illness among pregnant women. J Infect Dis 218(4):528&#x2013;535</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29741642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiy167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidari S, Palmer-Ross A, Goodman T (2021) A systematic review of the sex and gender reporting in COVID-19 clinical trials. Vaccines 9(11):1322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34835253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8622702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vaccines9111322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez AF, Calina D, Poulas K, Docea AO, Tsatsakis AM (2021) Safety of COVID-19 vaccines administered in the EU: should we be concerned? Toxicol Rep 8:871&#x2013;879</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33898273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8055532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.toxrep.2021.04.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillson K, Clemens SC, Madhi SA, Voysey M, Pollard AJ, Minassian AM (2021) Fertility rates and birth outcomes after ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 (AZD1222) vaccination. Lancet 398(10312):1683&#x2013;1684</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34688353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8530465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02282-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M, Kleine-Weber H, Schroeder S, Kruger N, Herrler T, Erichsen S et al (2020) SARS-CoV-2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and Is blocked by a clinically proven protease inhibitor. Cell 181(2):271&#x2013;80.e8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann MA, Wieler HJ, Enders P, Buchholz H-G, Plachter B (2021) Age- and sex-graded data evaluation of vaccination reactions after initial injection of the BNT162b2 mRNA vaccine in a local vaccination center in Germany. Vaccines 9(8):911</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34452036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8402474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vaccines9080911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hox V, Desai A, Bandara G, Gilfillan AM, Metcalfe DD, Olivera A (2015) Estrogen increases the severity of anaphylaxis in female mice through enhanced endothelial nitric oxide synthase expression and nitric oxide production. J Allergy Clin Immunol 135(3):729&#x2013;36.e5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25553642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2014.11.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang N, P&#xe9;rez P, Kato T, Mikami Y, Okuda K, Gilmore RC et al (2021) SARS-CoV-2 infection of the oral cavity and saliva. Nat Med 27(5):892&#x2013;903</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33767405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8240394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01296-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huber SA, Pfaeffle B (1994) Differential Th1 and Th2 cell responses in male and female BALB/c mice infected with coxsackievirus group B type 3. J Virol 68(8):5126&#x2013;5132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8035512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">236456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jvi.68.8.5126-5132.1994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iguacel I, Maldonado AL, Ruiz-Cabello AL, Casaus M, Moreno LA, Mart&#xed;nez-Jarreta B (2021) Association between COVID-19 vaccine side effects and body mass index in Spain. Vaccines 9(11):1321</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34835252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8623604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vaccines9111321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izumo T, Kuse N, Awano N, Tone M, Sakamoto K, Takada K et al (2021) Side effects and antibody titer transition of the BNT162b2 messenger ribonucleic acid coronavirus disease 2019 vaccine in Japan. Respir Investig 59(5):635&#x2013;642</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34210623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8214200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resinv.2021.06.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaiswal V, Nepal G, Dijamco P, Ishak A, Dagar M, Sarfraz Z et al (2022) Cerebral venous sinus thrombosis following COVID-19 vaccination: a systematic review. J Prim Care Community Health 13:21501319221074450</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8841914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21501319221074450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen A, Stromme M, Moyassari S, Chadha AS, Tartaglia MC, Szoeke C et al (2022) COVID-19 vaccines: considering sex differences in efficacy and safety. Contemp Clin Trials 115:106700</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jering KS, Claggett BL, Cunningham JW, Rosenthal N, Vardeny O, Greene MF et al (2021) Clinical characteristics and outcomes of hospitalized women giving birth with and without COVID-19. JAMA Intern Med 181(5):714&#x2013;717</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33449067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7811188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2020.9241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kageyama T, Ikeda K, Tanaka S, Taniguchi T, Igari H, Onouchi Y et al (2021) Antibody responses to BNT162b2 mRNA COVID-19 vaccine and their predictors among healthcare workers in a tertiary referral hospital in Japan. Clin Microbiol Infect 27(12):1861.e1&#x2013;e5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahn F, Bonander C, Moghaddassi M, Rasmussen M, Malmqvist U, Inghammar M et al (2022) Risk of severe COVID-19 from the Delta and Omicron variants in relation to vaccination status, sex, age and comorbidities&#x2013;surveillance results from southern Sweden, July 2021 to January 2022. Eurosurveillance 27(9):2200121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35241215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8895467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2022.27.9.2200121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlberg J, Chong DS, Lai WY (2004) Do men have a higher case fatality rate of severe acute respiratory syndrome than women do? Am J Epidemiol 159(3):229&#x2013;231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14742282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aje/kwh056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S, Peng L, Siddique R, Nabi G, Nawsherwan, Xue M et al (2020) Impact of COVID-19 infection on pregnancy outcomes and the risk of maternal-to-neonatal intrapartum transmission of COVID-19 during natural birth. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol 41(6):748&#x2013;50</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kini A, Morgan R, Kuo H, Shea P, Shapiro J, Leng SX et al (2022) Differences and disparities in seasonal influenza vaccine, acceptance, adverse reactions, and coverage by age, sex, gender, and race. Vaccine 40(11):1643&#x2013;1654</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33933316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2021.04.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein SL, Flanagan KL (2016) Sex differences in immune responses. Nat Rev Immunol 16(10):626&#x2013;638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27546235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nri.2016.90</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein SL, Dhakal S, Ursin RL, Deshpande S, Sandberg K, Mauvais-Jarvis F (2020a) Biological sex impacts COVID-19 outcomes. PLoS Pathog 16(6):e1008570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32569293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7307725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1008570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein SL, Pekosz A, Park HS, Ursin RL, Shapiro JR, Benner SE et al (2020b) Sex, age, and hospitalization drive antibody responses in a COVID-19 convalescent plasma donor population. J Clin Invest 130(11):6141&#x2013;6150</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32764200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7598041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI142004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein SL, Creisher PS, Burd I (2021) COVID-19 vaccine testing in pregnant females is necessary. J Clin Invest 131(5)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi GS, Brito LA, Moreira DP, Suzuki AM, Hsia GSP, Pimentel LF et al (2021) A novel saliva RT-LAMP workflow for rapid identification of COVID-19 cases and restraining viral spread. Diagnostics (Basel) 11(8)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kompaniyets L, Pennington AF, Goodman AB, Rosenblum HG, Belay B, Ko JY et al (2021) Underlying medical conditions and severe illness among 540,667 adults hospitalized with COVID-19, March 2020&#x2013;March 2021. Prev Chronic Dis 18:E66</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34197283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8269743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5888/pcd18.210123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo H, Kageyama T, Tanaka S, Otsuka K, Tsukumo S-i, Mashimo Y et al (2022) Markers of memory CD8 T cells depicting the effect of the BNT162b2 mRNA COVID-19 vaccine in Japan. Front Immunol 13:836923</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosmicki JA, Horowitz JE, Banerjee N, Lanche R, Marcketta A, Maxwell E et al (2021) Pan-ancestry exome-wide association analyses of COVID-19 outcomes in 586,157 individuals. Am J Hum Genet 108(7):1350&#x2013;1355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34115965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajhg.2021.05.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzywicka K, Heldner MR, S&#xe1;nchez van Kammen M, van Haaps T, Hiltunen S, Silvis SM et al (2021) Post&#x2010;SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2&#x2010;vaccination cerebral venous sinus thrombosis: an analysis of cases notified to the European Medicines Agency. Eur J Neurol 28(11):3656&#x2013;3662</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laisuan W (2021) COVID-19 vaccine anaphylaxis: current evidence and future approaches. Front Allerg 2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau ES, McNeill JN, Paniagua SM, Liu EE, Wang JK, Bassett IV et al (2021) Sex differences in inflammatory markers in patients hospitalized with COVID-19 infection: Insights from the MGH COVID-19 patient registry. PLoS ONE 16(4):e0250774</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33909684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8081177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0250774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leach DA, Mohr A, Giotis ES, Cil E, Isac AM, Yates LL et al (2021) The antiandrogen enzalutamide downregulates TMPRSS2 and reduces cellular entry of SARS-CoV-2 in human lung cells. Nat Commun 12(1):4068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34210968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8249423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-24342-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YW, Lim SY, Lee J-H, Lim JS, Kim M, Kwon S et al (2021) Adverse reactions of the second dose of the BNT162b2 mRNA COVID-19 vaccine in healthcare workers in Korea. J Korean Med Sci 36(21)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KS, Russ BP, Wong TY, Horspool AM, Winters MT, Barbier M et al (2022) Obesity and metabolic dysfunction drive sex-associated differential disease profiles in hACE2-mice challenged with SARS-CoV-2. iScience 25(10):105038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levin EG, Lustig Y, Cohen C, Fluss R, Indenbaum V, Amit S et al (2021) Waning immune humoral response to BNT162b2 Covid-19 vaccine over 6 months. N Engl J Med 385(24):e84</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34614326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2114583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Yang J, Zhao F, Zhi L, Wang X, Liu L et al (2020a) Prevalence and impact of cardiovascular metabolic diseases on COVID-19 in China. Clin Res Cardiol 109(5):531&#x2013;538</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32161990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7087935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00392-020-01626-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li N, Han L, Peng M, Lv Y, Ouyang Y, Liu K et al (2020b) Maternal and Neonatal outcomes of pregnant women with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pneumonia: a case-control study. Clin Infect Dis 71(16):2035&#x2013;2041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32249918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciaa352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Ji H, Zheng W, Wu X, Zhu JJ, Arnold AP et al (2010) Sex differences in renal angiotensin converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) activity are 17beta-oestradiol-dependent and sex chromosome-independent. Biol Sex Differ 1(1):6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21208466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3010099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2042-6410-1-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucas C, Wong P, Klein J, Castro TBR, Silva J, Sundaram M et al (2020) Longitudinal analyses reveal immunological misfiring in severe COVID-19. Nature 584(7821):463&#x2013;469</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32717743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7477538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-020-2588-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu-Culligan A, Chavan AR, Vijayakumar P, Irshaid L, Courchaine EM, Milano KM et al (2021) Maternal respiratory SARS-CoV-2 infection in pregnancy is associated with a robust inflammatory response at the maternal-fetal interface. Med (NY) 2(5):591-610.e10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lustig Y, Sapir E, Regev-Yochay G, Cohen C, Fluss R, Olmer L et al (2021) BNT162b2 COVID-19 vaccine and correlates of humoral immune responses and dynamics: a prospective, single-centre, longitudinal cohort study in health-care workers. Lancet Respir Med</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma L, Xie W, Li D, Shi L, Ye G, Mao Y et al (2021) Evaluation of sex-related hormones and semen characteristics in reproductive-aged male COVID-19 patients. J Med Virol 93(1):456&#x2013;462</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32621617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnus MC, Gjessing HK, Eide HN, Wilcox AJ, Fell DB, H&#xe5;berg SE (2021) Covid-19 vaccination during pregnancy and first-trimester miscarriage. N Engl J Med 385(21):2008&#x2013;2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34670062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMc2114466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchevsky NG, Li G, Aley P, Clemens SAC, Barrett JR, Belij-Rammerstorfer S et al (2022) An exploratory analysis of the response to ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 (AZD1222) vaccine in males and females. eBioMedicine 81:104128</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markmann AJ, Giallourou N, Bhowmik DR, Hou YJ, Lerner A, Martinez DR et al (2021) Sex disparities and neutralizing-antibody durability to SARS-CoV-2 infection in convalescent individuals. mSphere 6(4):e0027521</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marquez EJ, Chung CH, Marches R, Rossi RJ, Nehar-Belaid D, Eroglu A et al (2020) Sexual-dimorphism in human immune system aging. Nat Commun 11(1):751</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32029736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7005316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-14396-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauvais-Jarvis F, Bairey Merz N, Barnes PJ, Brinton RD, Carrero JJ, DeMeo DL et al (2020) Sex and gender: modifiers of health, disease, and medicine. Lancet 396(10250):565&#x2013;582</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32828189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7440877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31561-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGurnaghan SJ, Weir A, Bishop J, Kennedy S, Blackbourn LAK, McAllister DA et al (2021) Risks of and risk factors for COVID-19 disease in people with diabetes: a cohort study of the total population of Scotland. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 9(2):82&#x2013;93</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33357491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(20)30405-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier A, Chang JJ, Chan ES, Pollard RB, Sidhu HK, Kulkarni S et al (2009) Sex differences in the Toll-like receptor-mediated response of plasmacytoid dendritic cells to HIV-1. Nat Med 15(8):955&#x2013;959</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19597505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2821111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.2004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menni C, Klaser K, May A, Polidori L, Capdevila J, Louca P et al (2021) Vaccine side-effects and SARS-CoV-2 infection after vaccination in users of the COVID Symptom Study app in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet Infect Dis 21(7):939&#x2013;949</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33930320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8078878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00224-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyts I, Bucciol G, Quinti I, Neven B, Fischer A, Seoane E et al (2021) Coronavirus disease 2019 in patients with inborn errors of immunity: an international study. J Allergy Clin Immunol 147(2):520&#x2013;531</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32980424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2020.09.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montopoli M, Zumerle S, Vettor R, Rugge M, Zorzi M, Catapano CV et al (2020) Androgen-deprivation therapies for prostate cancer and risk of infection by SARS-CoV-2: a population-based study (N = 4532). Ann Oncol 31(8):1040&#x2013;1045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2020.04.479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan R, Klein SL (2019) The intersection of sex and gender in the treatment of influenza. Curr Opin Virol 35:35&#x2013;41</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30901632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6556398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coviro.2019.02.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mourad M, Jacob T, Sadovsky E, Bejerano S, Simone GS, Bagalkot TR et al (2021) Placental response to maternal SARS-CoV-2 infection. Sci Rep 11(1):14390</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34257394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8277865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-93931-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng MW, Zhou G, Chong WP, Lee LW, Law HK, Zhang H et al (2007) The association of RANTES polymorphism with severe acute respiratory syndrome in Hong Kong and Beijing Chinese. BMC Infect Dis 7:50</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17540042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1899505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2334-7-50</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordstr&#xf6;m P, Ballin M, Nordstr&#xf6;m A (2022) Risk of infection, hospitalisation, and death up to 9 months after a second dose of COVID-19 vaccine: a retrospective, total population cohort study in Sweden. The Lancet 399(10327):814&#x2013;823</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(22)00089-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton AE, Broyles AD (2019) Drug allergy in children and adults: is it the double X chromosome? Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol 122(2):148&#x2013;155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anai.2018.11.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarte KI, Ver AT, Velasco JV, Pastrana A, Catahay JA, Salvagno GL et al (2022) Effects of age, sex, serostatus, and underlying comorbidities on humoral response post-SARS-CoV-2 Pfizer-BioNTech mRNA vaccination: a systematic review. Crit Rev Clin Lab Sci 1&#x2013;18</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okwan-Duodu D, Lim EC, You S, Engman DM (2021) TMPRSS2 activity may mediate sex differences in COVID-19 severity. Signal Transduct Target Ther 6(1):100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33649313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7919249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41392-021-00513-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostendorf BN, Patel MA, Bilanovic J, Hoffmann HH, Carrasco SE, Rice CM et al (2022) Common human genetic variants of APOE impact murine COVID-19 mortality. Nature</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostensen M (1999) Sex hormones and pregnancy in rheumatoid arthritis and systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann NY Acad Sci 876:131&#x2013;43</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pairo-Castineira E, Clohisey S, Klaric L, Bretherick AD, Rawlik K, Pasko D et al (2021) Genetic mechanisms of critical illness in COVID-19. Nature 591(7848):92&#x2013;98</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33307546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-020-03065-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palaiodimou L, Stefanou M-I, Katsanos AH, de Sousa DA, Coutinho JM, Lagiou P et al (2021) Cerebral venous sinus thrombosis and thrombotic events after vector-based COVID-19 vaccines: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurology 97(21):e2136&#x2013;e2147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34610990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000012896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel VG, Zhong X, Liaw B, Tremblay D, Tsao CK, Galsky MD et al (2020) Does androgen deprivation therapy protect against severe complications from COVID-19? Ann Oncol 31(10):1419&#x2013;1420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32653425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2020.06.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavord S, Scully M, Hunt BJ, Lester W, Bagot C, Craven B et al (2021) Clinical features of vaccine-induced immune thrombocytopenia and thrombosis. N Engl J Med 385(18):1680&#x2013;1689</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34379914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2109908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng J, Sun J, Zhao J, Deng X, Guo F, Chen L (2021) Age and gender differences in ACE2 and TMPRSS2 expressions in oral epithelial cells. J Transl Med 19(1):358</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34412632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8374411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-021-03037-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen A, Bressem K, Albrecht J, Thiess HM, Vahldiek J, Hamm B et al (2020) The role of visceral adiposity in the severity of COVID-19: highlights from a Unicenter cross-sectional pilot study in Germany. Metabolism 110:154317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32673651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7358176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2020.154317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pijls BG, Jolani S, Atherley A, Dijkstra JIR, Franssen GHL, Hendriks S et al (2022) Temporal trends of sex differences for COVID-19 infection, hospitalisation, severe disease, intensive care unit (ICU) admission and death: a meta-analysis of 229 studies covering over 10M patients. F1000Res 11:5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polack FP, Thomas SJ, Kitchin N, Absalon J, Gurtman A, Lockhart S et al (2020) Safety and Efficacy of the BNT162b2 mRNA Covid-19 vaccine. N Engl J Med 383(27):2603&#x2013;2615</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33301246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2034577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhu M, Murphy EA, Sukhu AC, Yee J, Singh S, Eng D et al (2021) Antibody response to coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) messenger RNA vaccination in pregnant women and transplacental passage into cord blood. Obstet Gynecol 138(2):278&#x2013;280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33910219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8288193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000004438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao Y, Wang XM, Mannan R, Pitchiaya S, Zhang Y, Wotring JW et al (2020) Targeting transcriptional regulation of SARS-CoV-2 entry factors ACE2 and TMPRSS2. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raparelli V, Palmieri L, Canevelli M, Pricci F, Unim B, Lo Noce C et al (2020) Sex differences in clinical phenotype and transitions of care among individuals dying of COVID-19 in Italy. Biol Sex Differ 11(1):57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33066823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7562690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13293-020-00334-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rastrelli G, Di Stasi V, Inglese F, Beccaria M, Garuti M, Di Costanzo D et al (2021) Low testosterone levels predict clinical adverse outcomes in SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia patients. Andrology 9(1):88&#x2013;98</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32436355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/andr.12821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson S, Hirsch JS, Narasimhan M, Crawford JM, McGinn T, Davidson KW et al (2020) Presenting characteristics, comorbidities, and outcomes among 5700 patients hospitalized with COVID-19 in the New York city area. JAMA 323(20):2052&#x2013;2059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32320003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7177629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.6775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risma KA, Edwards KM, Hummell DS, Little FF, Norton AE, Stallings A et al (2021) Potential mechanisms of anaphylaxis to COVID-19 mRNA vaccines. J Allergy Clin Immunol 147(6):2075&#x2013;82.e2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizk JG, Gupta A, Sardar P, Henry BM, Lewin JC, Lippi G et al (2021) Clinical characteristics and pharmacological management of COVID-19 vaccine&#x2013;induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia with cerebral venous sinus thrombosis: a review. JAMA Cardiol 6(12):1451&#x2013;1460</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34374713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2021.3444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robb H, Fausone CA, Rudy DR, McArthur S (1996) Side effects from influenza vaccination: differences between returned and random surveys. Mil Med 161(1):29&#x2013;32</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11082748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/milmed/161.1.29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rottenstreich M, Sela HY, Rotem R, Kadish E, Wiener-Well Y, Grisaru-Granovsky S (2022) Covid-19 vaccination during the third trimester of pregnancy: rate of vaccination and maternal and neonatal outcomes, a multicentre retrospective cohort study. BJOG 129(2):248&#x2013;255</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34554630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1471-0528.16941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz-Bedoya CA, Mota F, Ordonez AA, Foss CA, Singh AK, Praharaj M et al (2022) (124)I-Iodo-DPA-713 positron emission tomography in a hamster model of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Mol Imaging Biol 24(1):135&#x2013;143</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34424479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11307-021-01638-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadoff J, Gray G, Vandebosch A, C&#xe1;rdenas V, Shukarev G, Grinsztejn B et al (2021) Safety and efficacy of single-dose Ad26. COV2. S vaccine against Covid-19. New Engl J Med 384(23):2187&#x2013;201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sama IE, Ravera A, Santema BT, van Goor H, Ter Maaten JM, Cleland JGF et al (2020) Circulating plasma concentrations of angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 in men and women with heart failure and effects of renin-angiotensin-aldosterone inhibitors. Eur Heart J 41(19):1810&#x2013;1817</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32388565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7239195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt AL, Tucker MD, Bakouny Z, Labaki C, Hsu CY, Shyr Y et al (2021) Association between androgen deprivation therapy and mortality among patients with prostate Cancer and COVID-19. JAMA Netw Open 4(11):e2134330</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34767021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8590166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.34330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuler BA, Habermann AC, Plosa EJ, Taylor CJ, Jetter C, Negretti NM et al (2021) Age-determined expression of priming protease TMPRSS2 and localization of SARS-CoV-2 in lung epithelium. J Clin Invest 131(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz NH, S&#xf8;rvoll IH, Michelsen AE, Munthe LA, Lund-Johansen F, Ahlen MT et al (2021) Thrombosis and thrombocytopenia after ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccination. N Engl J Med 384(22):2124&#x2013;2130</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33835768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2104882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scully EP, Haverfield J, Ursin RL, Tannenbaum C, Klein SL (2020) Considering how biological sex impacts immune responses and COVID-19 outcomes. Nat Rev Immunol 20(7):442&#x2013;447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32528136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7288618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-020-0348-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scully M, Singh D, Lown R, Poles A, Solomon T, Levi M et al (2021a) Pathologic antibodies to platelet factor 4 after ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccination. N Engl J Med 384(23):2202&#x2013;2211</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33861525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2105385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scully EP, Schumock G, Fu M, Massaccesi G, Muschelli J, Betz J et al (2021b) Sex and gender differences in testing, hospital admission, clinical presentation, and drivers of severe outcomes from COVID-19. Open Forum Infect Dis 8(9):ofab448</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>See I, Su JR, Lale A, Woo EJ, Guh AY, Shimabukuro TT et al (2021) US case reports of cerebral venous sinus thrombosis with thrombocytopenia after Ad26. COV2. S Vaccination, March 2&#x2013;April 21, 2021. JAMA 325(24):2448&#x2013;56</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seessle J, Waterboer T, Hippchen T, Simon J, Kirchner M, Lim A et al (2022) Persistent symptoms in adult patients 1 year after coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a prospective cohort study. Clin Infect Dis 74(7):1191&#x2013;1198</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34223884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Servante J, Swallow G, Thornton JG, Myers B, Munireddy S, Malinowski AK et al (2021) Haemostatic and thrombo-embolic complications in pregnant women with COVID-19: a systematic review and critical analysis. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth 21(1):108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33546624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7863033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-021-03568-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro JR, Klein SL, Morgan R (2021) COVID-19: use intersectional analyses to close gaps in outcomes and vaccination. Nature 591(7849):202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33658677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/d41586-021-00577-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro JR, Sitaras I, Park H-S, Aytenfisu TY, Caputo C, Li M et al (2022) Association of frailty, age, and biological sex with SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccine-induced immunity in older adults. Clin Infect Dis ciac397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifian-Dorche M, Bahmanyar M, Sharifian-Dorche A, Mohammadi P, Nomovi M, Mowla A (2021) Vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia and cerebral venous sinus thrombosis post COVID-19 vaccination; a systematic review. J Neurol Sci 428:117607</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34365148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8330139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2021.117607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi G, Kenney AD, Kudryashova E, Zani A, Zhang L, Lai KK et al (2021) Opposing activities of IFITM proteins in SARS-CoV-2 infection. Embo J 40(3):e106501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33270927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15252/embj.2020106501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimabukuro TT, Cole M, Su JR (2021a) Reports of anaphylaxis after receipt of mRNA COVID-19 vaccines in the US&#x2014;December 14, 2020-January 18, 2021. JAMA 325(11):1101&#x2013;1102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33576785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8890485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.1967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimabukuro TT, Kim SY, Myers TR, Moro PL, Oduyebo T, Panagiotakopoulos L et al (2021b) Preliminary findings of mRNA Covid-19 vaccine safety in pregnant persons. N Engl J Med 384(24):2273&#x2013;2282</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33882218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2104983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva MVR, de Castro MV, Passos-Bueno MR, Otto PA, Naslavsky MS, Zatz M (2022) Men are the main COVID-19 transmitters: behavior or biology? Discov Ment Health 2(1):1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35174362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8785017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44192-022-00004-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonnet A, Chetboun M, Poissy J, Raverdy V, Noulette J, Duhamel A et al (2020) High prevalence of obesity in severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) requiring invasive mechanical ventilation. Obesity (silver Spring) 28(7):1195&#x2013;1199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32271993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.22831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solanich X, Vargas-Parra G, van der Made CI, Simons A, Schuurs-Hoeijmakers J, Antol&#xed; A et al (2021) Genetic screening for TLR7 variants in young and previously healthy men with severe COVID-19. Front Immunol 12:719115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34367187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8343010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.719115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somiya M, Mine S, Yasukawa K, Ikeda S (2021) Sex differences in the incidence of anaphylaxis to LNP-mRNA COVID-19 vaccines. Vaccine 39(25):3313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34020815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8101867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2021.04.066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souyris M, Cenac C, Azar P, Daviaud D, Canivet A, Grunenwald S et al (2018) TLR7 escapes X chromosome inactivation in immune cells. Sci Immunol 3(19)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stebbings R, Maguire S, Armour G, Jones C, Goodman J, Maguire AK et al (2021) Developmental and reproductive safety of AZD1222 (ChAdOx1 nCoV-19) in mice. Reprod Toxicol 104:134&#x2013;142</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34324966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9759091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.reprotox.2021.07.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stelzig KE, Canepa-Escaro F, Schiliro M, Berdnikovs S, Prakash YS, Chiarella SE (2020) Estrogen regulates the expression of SARS-CoV-2 receptor ACE2 in differentiated airway epithelial cells. Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol 318(6):L1280&#x2013;L1281</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32432918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7276982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajplung.00153.2020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungnak W, Huang N, Becavin C, Berg M, Queen R, Litvinukova M et al (2020) SARS-CoV-2 entry factors are highly expressed in nasal epithelial cells together with innate immune genes. Nat Med 26(5):681&#x2013;687</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32327758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8637938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-020-0868-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sylvester SV, Rusu R, Chan B, Bellows M, O&#x2019;Keefe C, Nicholson S (2022) Sex differences in sequelae from COVID-19 infection and in long COVID syndrome: a review. Curr Med Res Opin 38(8):1391&#x2013;1399</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35726132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03007995.2022.2081454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taglauer E, Benarroch Y, Rop K, Barnett E, Sabharwal V, Yarrington C et al (2020) Consistent localization of SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein and ACE2 over TMPRSS2 predominance in placental villi of 15 COVID-19 positive maternal-fetal dyads. Placenta 100:69&#x2013;74</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32862058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7445146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.placenta.2020.08.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi T, Ellingson MK, Wong P, Israelow B, Lucas C, Klein J et al (2020) Sex differences in immune responses that underlie COVID-19 disease outcomes. Nature 588(7837):315&#x2013;320</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32846427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7725931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-020-2700-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamanna S, Lumbers ER, Morosin SK, Delforce SJ, Pringle KG (2021) ACE2: a key modulator of the renin-angiotensin system and pregnancy. Am J Physiol-Regul Integr Comp Physiol 321(6):R833&#x2013;R843</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34668428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8862784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00211.2021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan M, Liu Y, Zhou R, Deng X, Li F, Liang K et al (2020) Immunopathological characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 cases in Guangzhou, China. Immunology 160(3):261&#x2013;268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32460357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7283723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/imm.13223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanacan A, Yazihan N, Erol SA, Anuk AT, Yucel Yetiskin FD, Biriken D et al (2021) The impact of COVID-19 infection on the cytokine profile of pregnant women: a prospective case-control study. Cytokine 140:155431</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33503581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7810028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cyto.2021.155431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The COVID-19 Sex-Disaggregated Data Tracker (2022) Global Health 50/50. Available from: https://globalhealth5050.org/the-sex-gender-and-covid-19-project/the-data-tracker/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theiler RN, Wick M, Mehta R, Weaver AL, Virk A, Swift M (2021) Pregnancy and birth outcomes after SARS-CoV-2 vaccination in pregnancy. Am J Obstet Gynecol MFM 3(6):100467</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34425297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8378017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajogmf.2021.100467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiede A, Sachs UJ, Czwalinna A, Werwitzke S, Bikker R, Krauss JK et al (2021) Prothrombotic immune thrombocytopenia after COVID-19 vaccination. Blood 138(4):350&#x2013;353</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34323939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8084604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.2021011958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tramunt B, Smati S, Coudol S, Wargny M, Pichelin M, Guyomarch B et al (2021) Sex disparities in COVID-19 outcomes of inpatients with diabetes: insights from the CORONADO study. Eur J Endocrinol 185(2):299&#x2013;311</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34085949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9494335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/EJE-21-0068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troy NM, Bosco A (2016) Respiratory viral infections and host responses; insights from genomics. Respir Res 17(1):156</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27871304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5117516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-016-0474-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu X, Chong WP, Zhai Y, Zhang H, Zhang F, Wang S et al (2015) Functional polymorphisms of the CCL2 and MBL genes cumulatively increase susceptibility to severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus infection. J Infect 71(1):101&#x2013;109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25818534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7112636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2015.03.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tukiainen T, Villani AC, Yen A, Rivas MA, Marshall JL, Satija R et al (2017) Landscape of X chromosome inactivation across human tissues. Nature 550(7675):244&#x2013;248</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29022598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5685192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature24265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ursin RL, Klein SL (2021) Sex differences in respiratory viral pathogenesis and treatments. Annu Rev Virol. 8(1):393&#x2013;414</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34081540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-virology-091919-092720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Made CI, Simons A, Schuurs-Hoeijmakers J, van den Heuvel G, Mantere T, Kersten S et al (2020) Presence of genetic variants among young men with severe COVID-19. JAMA 324(7):663&#x2013;673</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32706371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.13719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Made CI, Netea MG, van der Veerdonk FL, Hoischen A (2022) Clinical implications of host genetic variation and susceptibility to severe or critical COVID-19. Genome Med 14(1):96</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35986347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9390103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13073-022-01100-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Kammen MS, De Sousa DA, Poli S, Cordonnier C, Heldner MR, Van De Munckhof A et al (2021) Characteristics and outcomes of patients with cerebral venous sinus thrombosis in SARS-CoV-2 vaccine&#x2013;induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia. JAMA Neurol 78(11):1314&#x2013;1323</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2021.3619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma S, Joshi CS, Silverstein RB, He M, Carter EB, Mysorekar IU (2021) SARS-CoV-2 colonization of maternal and fetal cells of the human placenta promotes alteration of local renin-angiotensin system. Med (NY) 2(5):575&#x2013;90.e5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visci G, Zunarelli C, Mansour I, Porru S, Palma GD, Duval X et al (2022) Serological response after SARS-CoV2 vaccination in healthcare workers: a multicenter study. Med Lav 113(2):e2022022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35481576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9073755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>vom Steeg LG, Klein SL (2016) SeXX matters in infectious disease pathogenesis. PLoS Pathog 12(2):e1005374</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1005374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vries STD, Starokozhko V, Schellens IMM, Wijnans L, Enzmann H, Cavaleri M et al (2022) Attention for sex in COVID-19 trials: a review of regulatory dossiers. BMJ Glob Health 7(3):e008173</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wambier CG, Va&#xf1;o-Galv&#xe1;n S, McCoy J, Gomez-Zubiaur A, Herrera S, Hermosa-Gelbard &#xc1; et al (2020) Androgenetic alopecia present in the majority of patients hospitalized with COVID-19: the &#x201c;Gabrin sign.&#x201d; J Am Acad Dermatol 83(2):680&#x2013;682</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32446821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7242206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2020.05.079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warkentin TE, Sheppard J-AI, Sigouin CS, Kohlmann T, Eichler P, Greinacher A (2006) Gender imbalance and risk factor interactions in heparin-induced thrombocytopenia. Blood 108(9):2937&#x2013;2941</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson OJ, Barnsley G, Toor J, Hogan AB, Winskill P, Ghani AC (2022) Global impact of the first year of COVID-19 vaccination: a mathematical modelling study. Lancet Infect Dis 22:1293&#x2013;1302</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wel&#xe9;n K, Rosendal E, Gissl&#xe9;n M, Lenman A, Freyhult E, Fonseca-Rodr&#xed;guez O et al (2022) A phase 2 trial of the effect of antiandrogen therapy on COVID-19 outcome: no evidence of benefit, supported by epidemiology and in vitro data. Eur Urol 81(3):285&#x2013;293</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34980495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eururo.2021.12.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf ME, Luz B, Niehaus L, Bhogal P, B&#xe4;zner H, Henkes H (2021) Thrombocytopenia and intracranial venous sinus thrombosis after &#x201c;COVID-19 vaccine AstraZeneca&#x201d; exposure. J Clin Med 10(8):1599</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33918932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8069989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm10081599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Liang B, Chen C, Wang H, Fang Y, Shen S et al (2021) SARS-CoV-2 infection induces sustained humoral immune responses in convalescent patients following symptomatic COVID-19. Nat Commun 12(1):1813</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7985370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-22034-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu K, Chen Y, Yuan J, Yi P, Ding C, Wu W et al (2020) Factors associated with prolonged viral RNA shedding in patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Clin Infect Dis 71(15):799&#x2013;806</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32271376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciaa351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto S, Mizoue T, Tanaka A, Oshiro Y, Inamura N, Konishi M et al (2022) Sex-associated differences between BMI and SARS-CoV-2 antibody titers following the BNT162b2 vaccine. Obesity 30(5):999&#x2013;1003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35226399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.23417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X, Li F, Wang X, Yan J, Zhu F, Tang S et al (2020) Neutrophil to lymphocyte ratio as prognostic and predictive factor in patients with coronavirus disease 2019: a retrospective cross-sectional study. J Med Virol 92(11):2573&#x2013;2581</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32458459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7283791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q, Jacobs TM, McCallen JD, Moore DT, Huckaby JT, Edelstein JN et al (2016) Analysis of pre-existing IgG and IgM antibodies against polyethylene glycol (PEG) in the general population. Anal Chem 88(23):11804&#x2013;11812</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27804292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6512330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.analchem.6b03437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu C, Littleton S, Giroux NS, Mathew R, Ding S, Kalnitsky J et al (2021) Mucosal-associated invariant T cell responses differ by sex in COVID-19. Med 2(6):755&#x2013;72.e5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33870241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.medj.2021.04.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Bastard P, Liu Z, Le Pen J, Moncada-Velez M, Chen J et al (2020) Inborn errors of type I IFN immunity in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science 370(6515)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Sarangi V, Liu D, Ho M-F, Grassi AR, Wei L et al (2022) ACE2 and TMPRSS2 SARS-CoV-2 infectivity genes: deep mutational scanning and characterization of missense variants. Hum Mol Genet</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng S, Fan J, Yu F, Feng B, Lou B, Zou Q et al (2020) Viral load dynamics and disease severity in patients infected with SARS-CoV-2 in Zhejiang Province, China, January-March 2020: retrospective cohort study. BMJ 369:m1443</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32317267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7190077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m1443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z, Ren L, Zhang L, Zhong J, Xiao Y, Jia Z et al (2020) Heightened innate immune responses in the respiratory tract of COVID-19 patients. Cell Host Microbe 27(6):883&#x2013;90.e2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z, Xu L, Chen G (2021) Is there a difference in the efficacy of COVID-19 vaccine in males and females?&#x2014;a systematic review and meta-analysis. Hum Vaccin Immunother 17(12):4741&#x2013;4746</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34623224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8903917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21645515.2021.1984135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou X, Chen K, Zou J, Han P, Hao J, Han Z (2020) Single-cell RNA-seq data analysis on the receptor ACE2 expression reveals the potential risk of different human organs vulnerable to 2019-nCoV infection. Front Med 14(2):185&#x2013;192</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32170560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7088738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11684-020-0754-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>