<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37078648</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID and especially headache syndromes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>168</StartPage><EndPage>174</EndPage><MedlinePgn>168-174</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001153</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">This is an expert overview on recent literature about the complex relationship between coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) and headache.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Long COVID is a clinical syndrome characterized by the presence of persistent symptoms following the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection. Headache is one of the most common symptoms and is described most often as throbbing pain, associated with photo and phonofobia and worsening with physical exercise. In acute COVID-19, headache is usually described as moderate or severe, diffuse and oppressive although sometimes it has been described with a migraine-like phenotype, especially in patients with a previous history of migraine. Headache intensity during acute phase seems to be the most important predictor of duration of headache over time. Some COVID-19 cases can be associated with cerebrovascular complications, and red flags of secondary headaches (e.g. new worsening or unresponsive headache, or new onset of neurological focal signs) should be urgently investigated with imaging. Treatment goals are the reduction of number and intensity of headache crises, and the prevention of chronic forms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">This review can help clinicians to approach patients with headache and infection from SARS-CoV-2, with particular attention to persistent headache in long COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tana</LastName><ForeName>Claudio</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence on Headache, Geriatrics and COVID-19 Clinic, SS Annunziata Hospital of Chieti, Chieti.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giamberardino</LastName><ForeName>Maria Adele</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence on Headache, Geriatrics and COVID-19 Clinic, SS Annunziata Hospital of Chieti, Chieti.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Science of Aging and CAST, G. D'Annunzio University of Chieti.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martelletti</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine and Emergency Medicine, Sant' Andrea Hospital, Sapienza University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006261" MajorTopicYN="N">Headache</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008881" MajorTopicYN="Y">Migraine Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37078648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202306000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gholami M, Fawad I, Shadan S, et al. COVID-19 and healthcare workers: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Infect Dis 2021; 104:335&#x2013;346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renda G, Ricci F, Spinoni EG, et al. Predictors of mortality and cardiovascular outcome at 6 months after hospitalization for COVID-19. J Clin Med 2022; 11:729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feikin DR, Higdon MM, Abu-Raddad LJ, et al. Duration of effectiveness of vaccines against SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19 disease: results of a systematic review and meta-regression. Lancet 2022; 399:924&#x2013;944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews N, Stowe J, Kirsebom F, et al. Covid-19 vaccine effectiveness against the omicron (B.1.1.529) variant. N Engl J Med 2022; 386:1532&#x2013;1546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caronna E, van den Hoek TC, Bolay H, et al. Headache attributed to SARS-CoV-2 infection, vaccination and the impact on primary headache disorders of the COVID-19 pandemic: a comprehensive review. Cephalalgia 2023; 43:3331024221131337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Health Service. long-term effect of coronavirus (long COVID) 2022. https:/www.nhs.uk/conditions/coronavirus-covid-19/long-term-effects-of-coronavirus-long-covid/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallardo VJ, Shapiro RE, Caronna E, et al. The relationship of headache as a symptom to COVID-19 survival: a systematic review and meta-analysis of survival of 43,169 inpatients with COVID-19. Headache 2022; 62:1019&#x2013;1028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampaio Rocha-Filho PA. Headache associated with COVID-19: epidemiology, characteristics, pathophysiology, and management. Headache 2022; 62:650&#x2013;656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Headache classification committee of the international headache society the international classification of headache disorders, 3rd edition. Cephalalgia 2018; 38:1&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houhamdi L, Gautret P, Hoang VT, et al. Characteristics of the first 1119 SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variant cases, in Marseille, France, November-December 2021. J Med Virol 2022; 94:2290&#x2013;2295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menni C, Valdes AM, Polidori L, et al. Symptom prevalence, duration, and risk of hospital admission in individuals infected with SARS-CoV-2 during periods of omicron and delta variant dominance: a prospective observational study from the ZOE COVID Study. Lancet 2022; 399:1618&#x2013;1624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacobucci G. Covid-19: runny nose, headache, and fatigue are commonest symptoms of omicron, early data show. BMJ 2021; 375:n3103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahin BE, Celikbilek A, Kocak Y, et al. Patterns of COVID-19-related headache: a cross-sectional study. Clin Neurol Neurosurg 2022; 219:107339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Martinez A, Fanjul V, Ramos C, et al. Headache during SARS-CoV-2 infection as an early symptom associated with a more benign course of disease: a case-control study. Eur J Neurol 2021; 28:3426&#x2013;3436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman SA, Masters-Israilov A, Robbins MS. Secondary headache disorders: approach, workup, and special considerations for select populations. Semin Neurol 2022; 42:418&#x2013;427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tana C, Bentivegna E, Cho SJ, et al. Long COVID headache. J Headache Pain 2022; 23:93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan P. NICE guideline on long COVID. Lancet Respir Med 2021; 9:129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, et al. Headache as an acute and post-COVID-19 symptom in COVID-19 survivors: a meta-analysis of the current literature. Eur J Neurol 2021; 28:3820&#x2013;3825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Azorin D, Layos-Romero A, Porta-Etessam J, et al. Post-COVID-19 persistent headache: a multicentric 9-months follow-up study of 905 patients. Cephalalgia 2022; 42:804&#x2013;809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez-Garc&#xed;a LA, Escobedo G, Minguer-Uribe AG, Viurcos-Sanabria R, et al. Role of the renin-angiotensin system in the development of COVID-19-associated neurological manifestations. Front Cell Neurosci 2022; 16:977039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosentino G, Todisco M, Hota N, et al. Neuropathological findings from COVID-19 patients with neurological symptoms argue against a direct brain invasion of SARS-CoV-2: a critical systematic review. Eur J Neurol 2021; 28:3856&#x2013;3865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Files JK, Sarkar S, Fram TR, et al. Duration of post-COVID-19 symptoms is associated with sustained SARS-CoV-2-specific immune responses. JCI Insight 2021; 6:e151544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trigo J, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Sierra-Menc&#xed;a &#xc1;, et al. Cytokine and interleukin profile in patients with headache and COVID-19: a pilot, CASE-control, study on 104 patients. J Headache Pain 2021; 22:51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasilevska V, Guest PC, Bernstein HG, et al. Molecular mimicry of NMDA receptors may contribute to neuropsychiatric symptoms in severe COVID-19 cases. J Neuroinflammation 2021; 18:245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas JW, Bender FL, Ballou S, et al. Frequency of adverse events in the placebo arms of COVID-19 vaccine trials: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open 2022; 5:e2143955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekizoglu E, Gezegen H, Yalinay Dikmen P, et al. The characteristics of COVID-19 vaccine-related headache: clues gathered from the healthcare personnel in the pandemic. Cephalalgia 2022; 42:366&#x2013;375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg RK, Paliwal VK. Spectrum of neurological complications following COVID-19 vaccination. Neurol Sci 2022; 43:3&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castaldo M, Waliszewska-Pros&#xf3;&#x142; M, Koutsokera M, et al. Headache onset after vaccination against SARS-CoV-2: a systematic literature review and meta-analysis. J Headache Pain 2022; 23:41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galea M, Agius M, Vassallo N. Neurological manifestations and pathogenic mechanisms of COVID-19. Neurol Res 2022; 44:571&#x2013;582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez van Kammen M, Aguiar de Sousa D, Poli S. Characteristics and outcomes of patients with cerebral venous sinus thrombosis in SARS-CoV-2 vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia. JAMA Neurol 2021; 78:1314&#x2013;1323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Azorin D, Baykan B, Beghi E, et al. Timing of headache after COVID-19 vaccines and its association with cerebrovascular events: an analysis of 41,700 VAERS reports. Cephalalgia 2022; 42:1207&#x2013;1217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrao A, Agrippino R, Brescini M, et al. Thromboembolic events following mRNA vaccines for COVID 19: a case series. J Thromb Thrombolysis 2022; 53:971&#x2013;973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chui CSL, Fan M, Wan EYF, et al. Thromboembolic events and hemorrhagic stroke after mRNA (BNT162b2) and inactivated (CoronaVac) covid-19 vaccination: a self-controlled case series study. EClinicalMedicine 2022; 50:101504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goddard K, Hanson KE, Lewis N, et al. Incidence of myocarditis/pericarditis following mRNA COVID-19 vaccination among children and younger adults in the United States. Ann Intern Med 2022; 175:1169&#x2013;1771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Oxford/AstraZeneca (ChAdOx1-S [recombinant] vaccine) COVID-19 vaccine: what you need to know https://www.who.int/news-room/feature-stories/detail/the-oxford-astrazeneca-covid-19-vaccine-what-you-need-to-know .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martelletti P, Bentivegna E. Insights into headache 2022. Expert Rev Neurother 2022; 22:85&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacco S, Lampl C, Amin FM, et al. European Headache Federation (EHF) consensus on the definition of effective treatment of a migraine attack and of triptan failure. J Headache Pain 2022; 23:133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore N, Carleton B, Blin P, et al. NSAIDs and COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Drug Saf 2021; 44:929&#x2013;938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Sierra &#xc1;, Trigo J, et al. Frequency and phenotype of headache in covid-19: a study of 2194 patients. Sci Rep 2021; 11:14674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karada&#x15f; &#xd6;, &#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk B, Sonkaya AR, et al. Latent class cluster analysis identified hidden headache phenotypes in COVID-19: impact of pulmonary infiltration and IL-6. Neurol Sci 2021; 42:1665&#x2013;1673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krymchantowski AV, Silva-N&#xe9;to RP, Jevoux C, et al. Indomethacin for refractory COVID or post-COVID headache: a retrospective study. Acta Neurol Belg 2022; 122:465&#x2013;469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein M, Fathy W, Eid RA, et al. Relative frequency and risk factors of COVID-19 related headache in a sample of Egyptian population: a hospital-based study. Pain Med 2021; 22:2092&#x2013;2099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Martinez A, Guerrero-Peral &#xc1;L, Arias-Rivas S, et al. Amitriptyline for post-COVID headache: effectiveness, tolerability, and response predictors. J Neurol 2022; 269:5702&#x2013;5709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinyes D, Mu&#xf1;oz-Sellart M, Caballero TG. Local anesthetics as a therapeutic tool for post COVID-19 patients: a case report. Medicine (Baltimore) 2022; 101:e29358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Effect of Ganglion Sphenopalatine Block Versus Placebo on Persistent Headache Following COVID-19 Infection https://beta.clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT04636034?tab=results#publications .</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>