<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35838578</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2037-7452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of translational myology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Transl Myol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neuropsychological evaluation of cognitive disorders in children after COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10685</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4081/ejtm.2022.10685</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The article presents the results of neuropsychological remote and face-to-face testing of 25 children aged 12 to 17 years in the nearest (during and 1-2 weeks after the treatment) and later period (2-12 months) after COVID-19 infection with predominant respiratory tract infection, organized in Ekaterinburg in the State Autonomous Institution "Children's Hospital &#x2116; 8". Indication of family contact with patients with a new coronavirus infection was found in all patients, a positive nasopharyngeal swab for SARS-CoV-2 RNA by PCR was found in 58%, non-focal neurological complaints were found in 54% of children. The control group consisted of 25 pupils of Moscow comprehensive schools (14 girls and 11 boys) aged between 12 and 16 years who were examined before the pandemic. The methods included: investigation of the kinesthetic, spatial, dynamic, graphic praxis; auditory-motor coordination; visual, object-constructive gnosis; auditory-speech, visual memory; voluntary attention; thinking. Significant differences with the results of neuropsychological tests performed in children in the control group were found, allowing us to assert impairment of memory, attention, visual gnosis, visual-spatial function, kinesthetic and dynamic praxis, verbal and non-verbal component of thinking. According to A.R. Luria's theory, the topic of the disorders involves the temporo-parieto-occipital, mediobasal, frontotemporal parts of the brain, the reticular formation and limbic structures. This necessitates the development of corrective educational programs and an in-depth diagnostic algorithm that determines the morphological substrate of cognitive disorders in children, who have undergone COVID-19.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Troitskaya</LastName><ForeName>Lubov A</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pirogov Russian National Research Medical University, Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, Moscow. t-luba@mail.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plotnikova</LastName><ForeName>Inga A</ForeName><Initials>IA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Urals State Medical University, Ministry of Health of The Russian Federation, Ekaterinburg. inga63@bk.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Avakyan</LastName><ForeName>Georgy G</ForeName><Initials>GG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pirogov Russian National Research Medical University, Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, Moscow. avakyan_georgy@mail.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Erokhina</LastName><ForeName>Vera A</ForeName><Initials>VA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pirogov Russian National Research Medical University, Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, Moscow. verayerokhina@rambler.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Badalyan</LastName><ForeName>Oganes L</ForeName><Initials>OL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pirogov Russian National Research Medical University, Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, Moscow. epileptolog@mail.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muraveva</LastName><ForeName>Antonina V</ForeName><Initials>AV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ural Federal University named after the first President of Russia B.N. Yeltsin, Ekaterinburg. homosaltans@yandex.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zelentsova</LastName><ForeName>Vera L</ForeName><Initials>VL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Urals State Medical University, Ministry of Health of The Russian Federation, Ekaterinburg. vera-zelentsova@mail.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khodko</LastName><ForeName>Oksana K</ForeName><Initials>OK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's City Hospital &#x2116; 8, Ekaterinburg. dgb8-ok@yandex.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Safarova</LastName><ForeName>Sabina T</ForeName><Initials>ST</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Urals State Medical University, Ministry of Health of The Russian Federation, Ekaterinburg. safarovasabina@bk.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shirokova</LastName><ForeName>Evgenia I</ForeName><Initials>EI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Urals State Medical University, Ministry of Health of The Russian Federation, Ekaterinburg. eugenias2000@mail.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rusina</LastName><ForeName>Ekaterina A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Urals State Medical University, Ministry of Health of The Russian Federation, Ekaterinburg. Erusina82@yandex.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanina</LastName><ForeName>Natalia P</ForeName><Initials>NP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Budgetary Healthcare Institution of Moscow Region, M. F. Vladimirsky Moscow Regional Research and Clinical Institute, Moscow. nataliasanina2@yandex.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Terentev</LastName><ForeName>Kirill V</ForeName><Initials>KV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Budgetary Healthcare Institution of Moscow Region, M. F. Vladimirsky Moscow Regional Research and Clinical Institute, Moscow. kirillterentev184@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rachin</LastName><ForeName>Andrey P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal State Budgetary Institution "National medical research center for rehabilitation and balneology", Ministry of Health of Russia, Moscow. rachin&#x430;p@nmicrk.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Transl Myol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2037-7452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>We confirm that we have read the journal&#x2019;s position on ethical issues involved in publication and affirm that this report is consistent with those guidelines. <b>W</b>ith development of the COVID-19 pandemic, research is increasingly aimed at addressing its long-term effects. This complex of disorders, together with other effects of the new coronavirus infection, are grouped under the term "post-COVID syndrome" or Long Covid. Post-COVID syndrome is identified when signs and symptoms that develop during or after an infection that correspond to COVID-19 persist for more than 12 weeks and cannot be attributed to alternative diagnoses.<sup>,</sup> Patients with Post-COVID-19 syndrome are divided into "acute" (e.g. thromboembolic complications) and "chronic" - with a nonspecific clinical picture, often characterized by fatigue and shortness of breath. Patients with COVID-19 and CNS damage demonstrate behavioral changes, mental and cognitive disorders, retardation, feelings of 'stupefaction', reduced concentration. Many authors report long-term persistent symptoms after COVID-19 in individuals with a mild course of the disease, including asymptomatic/low-symptomatic children. In a recent study Buonsenso D. et al. (2021) reported persistence of symptoms 120 days after COVID-19 in more than half of the children previously diagnosed with COVID-19, in 42.6% of whom these disorders limited daily activities. Fatigue, muscle and joint pain, headache, insomnia, breathing difficulties and heart palpitations were particularly common. Cognitive disorders have been reported in 34.3% of patients who had COVID-19. The authors emphasize the need to monitor children for several months after hospitalization in order to preserve their mental health. In their opinion inclusion of a psychological evaluation in the diagnosis of children with Long Covid is a practical necessity. Neuropsychological symptoms reflect subtle functional changes in brain tissue. Today, cognitive and emotional studies in psychiatry and neurology, based on neuropsychological methods, are firmly embedded in the scientific and research practice of medical professionals and psychologists. New studies in these areas are relevant to clinical psychology (primarily neuropsychology), pediatrics, psychiatry and neurology. As part of a multidisciplinary approach to analysis, a study of higher mental functions in children in the immediate and long-term period after a new coronavirus infection was conducted at the premises of the autonomous public health care institution "Children's Hospital No. 8" in Ekaterinburg. Aims of the study were development of a comprehensive psychological evaluation of the cognitive and emotional state of children with Post-COVID-19 syndrome based on structural and functional features of the brain by: i). analyzing psychological content of the processes that ensure the cognitive activity of children with Post-COVID-19 syndrome - mnemastic, speech, visual-spatial gnosis and praxis and ii) characterizing the state of higher mental functions in children with COVID-19 using a special set of neuropsychological methods developed by A.R. Luria and his school.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35838578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/ejtm.2022.10685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, Hishmeh L. Managing the long term effects of covid-19: summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ. 2021. Jan 22;372:n136. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoreva MA. Postcovid syndrome &#x2014; a new reality. Zhurnal Nevrologii i Psikhiatrii imeni S.S. Korsakova. 2021;121(10):131-137. (In Russ.). doi: 10.17116/jnevro2021121101131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34874668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabi A, Mohanty A, Mohanty AP, Kumar S. Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: A LiteratureReview. Journal of Advances in Medicine and Medical Research. 2020. Vol.32, No. 24. &#x420;.289&#x2013;295. doi: 10.9734/JAMMR/2020/v32i2430781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefano GB, Ptacek R, Ptackova H, Martin A, Kream RM. Selective Neuronal Mitochondrial Targeting in SARS-CoV-2 Infection Affects Cognitive Processes to Induce 'Brain Fog' and Results in Behavioral Changes that Favor Viral Survival. Med Sci Monit. 2021. Jan 25;27:e930886. doi: 10.12659/MSM.930886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7845145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33487628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Munblit D, De Rose C, Sinatti D, Ricchiuto A, Carfi A, Valentini P. Preliminary evidence on long COVID in children. Acta Paediatr. 2021. Jul;110(7):2208-2211. doi: 10.1111/apa.15870. Epub 2021 Apr 18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33835507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeria M, Cejudo JC, Sotoca J, Deus J, Krupinski J. Cognitive profile following COVID-19 infection: Clinical predictors leading to neuropsychological impairment. Brain Behav Immun Health. 2020. Dec;9:100163. doi: 10.1016/j.bbih.2020.100163. Epub 2020 Oct 22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7581383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33111132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adrianov OS. On the principles of structural and functional organization of the brain. Selected works. Moscow-Leningrad: Nauka, 1999;280. Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luria A.R. Human higher cortical functions and their disorders in local brain lesions. A.R. Luria. St. Petersburg: &#x201c;Piter&#x201d;, 2008. (In Russ.).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chomskaya ED. Neuropsychology: 4th edition. ED. Chomskaya. St. Petersburg: &#x201c;Piter&#x201d;, 2005;496. Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhutina TV, Polonskaya NN, Yablokova LV. Neuropsychological analysis of individual differences in children: evaluation parameters Neuropsychology and psychophysiology of individual differences. Moscow-Orenburg, 2017;132-152. Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balashova EY, Kovyazina MS. Neuropsychological diagnostics. Classical stimulus materials. 5th ed. Genesis. 2015;70. Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glozman JM. Quantification of neuropsychological examination data. JM Glozman. 2019;25. (In Russ.).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>