<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38188200</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2307-8960</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>36</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of clinical cases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Clin Cases</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Spinal cord infarction attributed to SARS-CoV-2, with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19: A case report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>8542</StartPage><EndPage>8550</EndPage><MedlinePgn>8542-8550</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12998/wjcc.v11.i36.8542</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">While stroke and lower extremity venous thromboemboli have been commonly reported following acute infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), spinal cord infarction or ischemia has been extremely rare. Findings of long coronavirus disease (COVID) in this select population have not been studied.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE SUMMARY" NlmCategory="METHODS">We present the case of a 70-year-old female with sudden onset of trunk and lower extremity sensorimotor loss due to spinal cord infarction, attributed to acute infection with SARS-CoV-2. Diagnostic work up confirmed a T3 complete (ASIA impairment Scale A) paraplegia resulting from a thrombotic infarct. Her reported myalgias, neuropathic pain, spasticity, bladder spasms, and urinary tract infections exceeded the frequency and severity of many spinal cord injury (SCI) individuals of similar age and degree of neurologic impairment. In her first year after contracting COVID-19, she underwent 2 separate inpatient rehabilitation courses, but also required acute hospitalization 6 additional times for subsequent infections or uncontrolled pain. Yet other complications of complete non-traumatic SCI (NTSCI), including neurogenic bowel and temperature hypersensitivity, were mild, and pressure injuries were absent. She has now transitioned from the acute to chronic phase of spinal cord injury care, with subsequent development of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This individual experienced significant challenges with the combined effects of acute T3 NTSCI and acute COVID-19, with subsequent progression to PASC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2023. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oleson</LastName><ForeName>Christina V</ForeName><Initials>CV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Case Western Reserve University, MetroHealth Rehabilitation Institute, Cleveland, OH 44109, United States. coleson@metrohealth.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olsen</LastName><ForeName>Andrew C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Case Western Reserve University, MetroHealth Rehabilitation Institute, Cleveland, OH 44109, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shermon</LastName><ForeName>Suzanna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Case Western Reserve University, MetroHealth Rehabilitation Institute, Cleveland, OH 44109, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Clin Cases</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101618806</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2307-8960</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Case report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Paraplegia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal cord infarction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors have no conflict of interests that would be relevant for this publication to report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38188200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10768511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12998/wjcc.v11.i36.8542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Romi F, Naess H. Spinal Cord Infarction in Clinical Neurology: A Review of Characteristics and Long-Term Prognosis in Comparison to Cerebral Infarction. Eur Neurol. 2016;76:95&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27487411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novy J, Carruzzo A, Maeder P, Bogousslavsky J. Spinal cord ischemia: clinical and imaging patterns, pathogenesis, and outcomes in 27 patients. Arch Neurol. 2006;63:1113&#x2013;1120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16908737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampogna G, Tessitore N, Bianconi T, Leo A, Zarbo M, Montanari E, Spinelli M. Spinal cord dysfunction after COVID-19 infection. Spinal Cord Ser Cases. 2020;6:92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7525226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32999271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eissa M, Abdelhady M, Alqatami H, Salem K, Own A, El Beltagi AH. Spinal cord infarction in a 41-year-old male patient with COVID-19. Neuroradiol J. 2021;34:245&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8165895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33480310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bax F, Gigli GL, Iaiza F, Valente M. Spontaneous spinal cord ischemia during COVID-19 infection. J Neurol. 2021;268:4000&#x2013;4001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8080085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33909158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahan J, Gibson CJ, Strauss SB, Bronstein M, Winchell RJ, Barie PS, Segal AZ. Cervical spinal cord infarction associated with coronavirus infectious disease (COVID)-19. J Clin Neurosci. 2021;87:89&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7938747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33863542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Zhang J, Wang C, Chen X, Zhao X, Jing H, Liu H, Li Z, Wang L, Shi J. COVID19 and ischemic stroke: Mechanisms of hypercoagulability (Review) Int J Mol Med. 2021;47</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7849983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33448315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coperchini F, Chiovato L, Croce L, Magri F, Rotondi M. The cytokine storm in COVID-19: An overview of the involvement of the chemokine/chemokine-receptor system. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2020;53:25&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32446778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization.  WHO reference number. Available from: https://www.ukwhoswho.com/display/10.1093/ww/9780199540891.001.0001/ww-9780199540884-e-164854 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, Cook JR, Nordvig AS, Shalev D, Sehrawat TS, Ahluwalia N, Bikdeli B, Dietz D, Der-Nigoghossian C, Liyanage-Don N, Rosner GF, Bernstein EJ, Mohan S, Beckley AA, Seres DS, Choueiri TK, Uriel N, Ausiello JC, Accili D, Freedberg DE, Baldwin M, Schwartz A, Brodie D, Garcia CK, Elkind MSV, Connors JM, Bilezikian JP, Landry DW, Wan EY. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull-Otterson L, Baca S, Saydah S, Boehmer T, Adjei S, Gray S, Harris AM. Post&#x2013;COVID Conditions Among Adult COVID-19 Survivors Aged 18&#x2013;64 and &#x2265;65 Years &#x2014; United States, March 2020&#x2013;November 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71:713&#x2013;717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sneller MC, Liang CJ, Marques AR, Chung JY, Shanbhag SM, Fontana JR, Raza H, Okeke O, Dewar RL, Higgins BP, Tolstenko K, Kwan RW, Gittens KR, Seamon CA, McCormack G, Shaw JS, Okpali GM, Law M, Trihemasava K, Kennedy BD, Shi V, Justement JS, Buckner CM, Blazkova J, Moir S, Chun TW, Lane HC. A Longitudinal Study of COVID-19 Sequelae and Immunity: Baseline Findings. Ann Intern Med. 2022;175:969&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9128805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35605238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re'em Y, Redfield S, Austin JP, Akrami A. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Yi Q, Liu G, Shen X, Xuan L, Tian Y. Cerebral white matter injury and damage to myelin sheath following whole-brain ischemia. Brain Res. 2013;1495:11&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23246926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arana-Guajardo A, Villarreal-Alarc&#xf3;n M. CREST Syndrome: Clinical Expression of the Disease. J Clin Rheumatol. 2017;23:285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28742726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel CH, Richey M.  Lupus blood test results: What to know: HSS rheumatology. Hospital for Special Surgery. Available from: https://www.hss.edu/conditions_understanding-laboratory-tests-and-results-for-systemic-lupus-erythematosus.asp#aPL .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andre JB, Bammer R. Advanced diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging techniques of the human spinal cord. Top Magn Reson Imaging. 2010;21:367&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3985837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22158130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein LG, Gendelman HE. Human immunodeficiency virus type 1 infection of the nervous system: pathogenetic mechanisms. Ann Neurol. 1993;33:429&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8498818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mocchetti I, Bachis A, Avdoshina V. Neurotoxicity of human immunodeficiency virus-1: viral proteins and axonal transport. Neurotox Res. 2012;21:79&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4089041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21948112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siroky MB. Pathogenesis of bacteriuria and infection in the spinal cord injured patient. Am J Med. 2002;113 Suppl 1A:67S&#x2013;79S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12113873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.  (n.d.). Post-covid conditions. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. [Cited 7 March 2022]. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/Long-term-effects/index.html .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carod-Artal FJ. Neurological complications of coronavirus and COVID-19. Rev Neurol. 2020;70:311&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32329044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favas TT, Dev P, Chaurasia RN, Chakravarty K, Mishra R, Joshi D, Mishra VN, Kumar A, Singh VK, Pandey M, Pathak A. Neurological manifestations of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of proportions. Neurol Sci. 2020;41:3437&#x2013;3470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7577367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33089477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabacof L, Tosto-Mancuso J, Wood J, Cortes M, Kontorovich A, McCarthy D, Rizk D, Rozanski G, Breyman E, Nasr L, Kellner C, Herrera JE, Putrino D. Post-acute COVID-19 Syndrome Negatively Impacts Physical Function, Cognitive Function, Health-Related Quality of Life, and Participation. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;101:48&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8667685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34686631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oleson CV, Shermon S, Olsen AC.  Spinal Cord Infarction and Ischemia Attributed to Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus-2, with Progression to Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19: A case series. Presented at the Annual Meeting of the American Spinal Injury Association. St. Louis MO, USA. [Cited 8 July 2021]. Available from: https://probiologists.com/Article/Spinal-cord-infarction-associated-with-severe-acute-respiratory-syndrome-coronavirus-2:-A-case-series-of-diagnostic-challenges-and-post-acute-sequelae-of-COVID-19 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb LE, Timar R, Wills M, Dhar S, Lucas SM, Komnenov D, Chancellor MB, Dhar N. Long COVID and COVID-19-associated cystitis (CAC) Int Urol Nephrol. 2022;54:17&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8597545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34787782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb LE, Dhar N, Timar R, Wills M, Dhar S, Chancellor MB. COVID-19 inflammation results in urine cytokine elevation and causes COVID-19 associated cystitis (CAC) Med Hypotheses. 2020;145:110375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7644255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33213997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>