<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37725480</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-5415</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the American Geriatrics Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Am Geriatr Soc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Frailty as a risk factor for post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 among US veterans during the Delta and Omicron waves.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3826</StartPage><EndPage>3835</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3826-3835</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jgs.18584</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Older populations have suffered the highest rates of SARS-CoV-2 infection and associated complications, including Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC). Frailty is a geriatric syndrome that often coexists with COVID-19 infection. The vulnerability to stressors caused by multisystemic dysfunction that characterizes frailty may predispose older adults to develop PASC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Retrospective cohort study using the VA COVID-19 Shared Data Resource to identify US veterans testing positive for SARS-CoV-2 between July 2021 and February 2022, without prior positive tests and who were alive 30&#x2009;days after infection. Frailty was calculated using a 31-item VA Frailty Index generated from electronic health records. We categorized Veterans into robust (FI&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.10), prefrail (FI: &gt;0.10-&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.21), and frail (FI&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;0.21). We assessed the association between frailty and PASC and vaccination and PASC using Cox survival model, adjusting for covariates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We identified 245,857 COVID-19-positive veterans surviving 30&#x2009;days after infection. The mean age was 57.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;16.5&#x2009;years; 87.2% were males, 68.1% were white, and 9.0% were Hispanic. Almost half of the sample (48.9%) were classified as robust, while 28.3% were pre-frail and 22.7% were frail; 99,886 (40.6%) were fully vaccinated, and 33,516 (13.6%) received booster doses. Over a median follow-up of 143&#x2009;days (IQR&#x2009;=&#x2009;101), 23,890 (9.7%) patients developed PASC. Within 6&#x2009;months after infection, frailty and pre-frailty were associated with a 41% (adjusted HR [aHR]:1.40 (95% CI: 1.35-1.47) and 15% (aHR: 1.17 (95% CI: 1.11-1.19) increase in the risk of PASC compared with the robust, respectively. Vaccination and booster doses before infection were associated with a 27% (aHR: 0.73 (95% CI: 0.71-0.75) and 33% (aHR: 0.66 (95% CI: 0.63-0.69) reduction in the risk of developing PASC, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Frailty was associated with an increased risk of developing PASC. Vaccination was associated with a decreased risk of PASC, further reduced by booster doses. Early recognition of frailty in patients with COVID-19 may assist in the early identification and management of PASC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of The American Geriatrics Society. This article has been contributed to by U.S. Government employees and their work is in the public domain in the USA.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammel</LastName><ForeName>Iriana S</ForeName><Initials>IS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4562-8454</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geriatric Research Education and Clinical Center, Miami VA Healthcare System, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Geriatrics and Palliative Medicine, University of Miami Miller School of Medicine, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tosi</LastName><ForeName>Dominique M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geriatric Research Education and Clinical Center, Miami VA Healthcare System, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Geriatrics and Palliative Medicine, University of Miami Miller School of Medicine, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Fei</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geriatric Research Education and Clinical Center, Miami VA Healthcare System, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pott</LastName><ForeName>Henrique</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3126-2946</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Carlos, S&#xe3;o Carlos, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruiz</LastName><ForeName>Jorge G</ForeName><Initials>JG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geriatric Research Education and Clinical Center, Miami VA Healthcare System, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Geriatric Medicine, Memorial Healthcare System, Hollywood, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Am Geriatr Soc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7503062</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0002-8614</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073496" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frailty</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014728" MajorTopicYN="Y">Veterans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frailty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37725480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgs.18584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Taylor S. NICE guideline on long covid. Bmj-Brit Med J. 2020;371:m4938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet. 2022;399(10343):2263-2264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):601-615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munipalli B, Seim L, Dawson NL, Knight D, Dabrh AM. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): a meta-narrative review of pathophysiology, prevalence, and management. SN Compr Clin Med. 2022;4(1):90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambadapoodi RS, Deepti F, Anwer J, Fernandez-Botran R. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): association with inflammation and autoimmunity. Univ Louisville J Respir Infect. 2021;5(1):20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue S, Hatakeyama J, Kondo Y, et al. Post-intensive care syndrome: its pathophysiology, prevention, and future directions. Acute Med Surg. 2019;6(3):233-246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sher L. Post-COVID syndrome and suicide risk. QJM. 2021;114(2):95-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn K, Katz G, Bobos P. Understanding the post COVID-19 condition (long COVID) in adults and the expected burden for Ontario. Science Briefs of the Ontario COVID-19 Science Advisory Table. Vol 3; Science table covid-19 Advisory for ontario. 2022:65:1-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarte KI, Catahay JA, Velasco JV, et al. Impact of COVID-19 vaccination on the risk of developing long-COVID and on existing long-COVID symptoms: a systematic review. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;53:101624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang F, Hammel IS, Andrew MK, Ruiz JG. COVID-19 mRNA vaccine effectiveness against hospitalisation and death in veterans according to frailty status during the SARS-CoV-2 delta (B. 1.617. 2) variant surge in the USA: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet Healthy Longev. 2022;3(9):e589-e598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, et al. Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat Med. 2022;28(8):1706-1714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis. 2022;226(9):1593-1607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Mahoney LL, Routen A, Gillies C, et al. The prevalence and long-term health effects of long Covid among hospitalised and non-hospitalised populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;55:101762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerdes EOW, Vanichkachorn G, Verdoorn BP, et al. Role of senescence in the chronic health consequences of COVID-19. Transl Res. 2022;241:96-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang L, Liu Y, Shen M, et al. Influence of aging on deterioration of patients with COVID-19. Aging (Albany NY). 2020;12(24):26248-26262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weerahandi H, Rao M, Boockvar KS. Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection in nursing homes: do not forget the most vulnerable COMMENT. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2022;70(5):1352-1354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashan MR, Smoll N, King C, et al. Epidemiology and clinical features of COVID-19 outbreaks in aged care facilities: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eclinicalmedicine. 2021;33:100771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekerstad N, Cederholm T, Bostr&#xf6;m A-M, et al. Clinical frailty scale-a proxy estimate of biological age. Lakartidningen. 2022;119:22040.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltese G, Corsonello A, di Rosa M, et al. Frailty and COVID-19: a systematic scoping review. J Clin Med. 2020;9(7):2106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellelli G, Rebora P, Valsecchi MG, Bonfanti P, Citerio G. Frailty index predicts poor outcome in COVID-19 patients. Intensive Care Med. 2020;46:1634-1636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulop T, McElhaney J, Pawelec G, et al. Frailty, inflammation and immunosenescence. Frailty Aging. 2015;41:26-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guaraldi G, Milic J, Cesari M, et al. The interplay of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and aging: a biological, clinical and public health approach. Ageing Res Rev. 2022;9:101686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soiza RL, Scicluna C, Thomson EC. Efficacy and safety of COVID-19 vaccines in older people. Age Ageing. 2021;50(2):279-283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins JT, Short R, Carter B, et al. The clinical frailty scale: estimating the prevalence of frailty in older patients hospitalised with COVID-19. The cope study. Geriatrics-Basel. 2020;5(3):58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brill SE, Jarvis HC, Ozcan E, et al. COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study with focus on the over-80s and hospital-onset disease. BMC Med. 2020;18:1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Malley PA. Frailty and disability: predictors or outcomes or both in post COVID-19. Crit Care Med. 2022;50(1):1023-1025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salini S, Russo A, de Matteis G, et al. Frailty in elderly patients with Covid-19: a narrative review. Gerontol Geriatr Med. 2022;8:23337214221079956 233372142210799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumitrascu F, Branje KE, Hladkowicz ES, Lalu M, McIsaac DI. Association of frailty with outcomes in individuals with COVID-19: a living review and meta-analysis. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2021;69(9):2419-2429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covino M, Russo A, Salini S, et al. Long-term effects of hospitalization for COVID-19 on frailty and quality of life in older adults &gt;/=80&#x2009;years. J Clin Med. 2022;11(19):5787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prampart S, Le Gentil S, Bureau ML, et al. Functional decline, long term symptoms and course of frailty at 3-months follow-up in COVID-19 older survivors, a prospective observational cohort study. BMC Geriatr. 2022;22(1):542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damanti S, Cilla M, Cilona M, et al. Prevalence of long COVID-19 symptoms after hospital discharge in frail and robust patients. Front Med-Lausanne. 2022;9:9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fumagalli C, Zocchi C, Tassetti L, et al. Factors associated with persistence of symptoms 1 year after COVID-19: a longitudinal, prospective phone-based interview follow-up cohort study. Eur J Intern Med. 2022;97:36-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones R, Davis A, Stanley B, et al. Risk predictors and symptom features of long COVID within a broad primary care patient population including both tested and untested patients. Pragmat Obs Res. 2021;12:93-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannou GN, Locke E, Green P, et al. Risk factors for hospitalization, mechanical ventilation, or death among 10 131 US veterans with SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3(9):e2022310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang F, Hammel I, Andrew M, Ruiz JG. Frailty reduces vaccine effectiveness against SARS-CoV-2 infection: a test-negative case control study using national VA data. J Nutr Health Aging. 2023;2:1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannou GN, Baraff A, Fox A, et al. Rates and factors associated with documentation of diagnostic codes for long COVID in the National Veterans Affairs Health Care System. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(7):e2224359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orkaby AR, Nussbaum L, Ho YL, et al. The burden of frailty among US veterans and its association with mortality, 2002-2012. J Gerontol A-Biol. 2019;74(8):1257-1264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Searle SD, Mitnitski A, Gahbauer EA, Gill TM, Rockwood K. A standard procedure for creating a frailty index. BMC Geriatr. 2008;8:24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walston J, Bandeen-Roche K, Buta B, et al. Moving frailty toward clinical practice: NIA intramural frailty science symposium summary. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2019;67(8):1559-1564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson SW, Abbafati C, Aerts JG, et al. Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA. 2022;328(16):1604-1615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin-Chowdhury Z, Ladhani SN. Causation or confounding: why controls are critical for characterizing long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27(7):1129-1130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young-Xu Y, Korves C, Roberts J, et al. Coverage and estimated effectiveness of mRNA COVID-19 vaccines among US veterans. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(10):e2128391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93(2):1013-1022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khullar D, Zhang Y, Zang C, et al. Racial/ethnic disparities in post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection in New York: an EHR-based cohort study from the RECOVER program. J Gen Intern Med. 2023;38(5):1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. The prevalence of long COVID symptoms and COVID-19 complications. Home-Office for National Statistics (ons.gov.uk). 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hynes DM, Koelling K, Stroupe K, et al. Veterans' access to and use of Medicare and veterans affairs health care. Med Care. 2007;45(3):214-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan JM, Kho J, Akhunbay-Fudge M, et al. Atypical presentation of COVID-19 in hospitalised older adults. Ir J Med Sci (1971-). 2021;190:469-474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Treatment Guidelines Panel. Coronavirus Disease 2022 (COVID-19) Treatment Guidelines. National Institutes of Health 2022. Available from https://www.covid19treatmentguidelines.nih.gov/about-the-guidelines/whats-new/ Accessed September 5, 2022.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>