<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37386538</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2731-3786</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of anesthesia, analgesia and critical care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Anesth Analg Crit Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Timing of surgery and elective perioperative management of patients with previous SARS-CoV-2 infection: a SIAARTI expert consensus statement.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>29</StartPage><MedlinePgn>29</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">29</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s44158-022-00058-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The appropriate timing of surgery and perioperative management of patients with previous SARS-CoV-2 infection are open issues. The purpose of this document is to support the clinical decision-making process regarding the patient with previous Sars-CoV-2 infection to undergo elective surgery. The recipients of this document are physicians, nurses, healthcare personnel, and other professionals involved in the patient's surgical process.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The Italian Society of Anesthesia Analgesia Resuscitation and Intensive Care (SIAARTI) selected 11 experts to reach a consensus on key aspects of this theme in adult and pediatric population. The methods of this process document were in accordance to the principles of rapid review of the scientific literature and modified Delphi method. The experts produced statements and supporting reasons in the form of an informative text. The overall list of statements was subjected to a vote in order to express the degree of consent.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Patients should not undergo elective surgery within 7&#xa0;weeks of infection unless there is the risk of a negative evolution of the disease. To mitigate the risk of postsurgical mortality, a multidisciplinary approach seemed useful in addition to the use of validated algorithms to estimate the risk of perioperative morbidity and mortality; the risk related to SARS-CoV-2 infection should be added. The risk of potential nosocomial contagion from a positive patients should also be considered when deciding to proceed with surgery. Most of the evidence came from previous SARS-CoV-2 variants, so the evidence should be considered indirect.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A balanced preoperative multidisciplinary risk-benefit evaluation is needed in patients with previous infection by SARS-CoV-2 for elective surgery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cortegiani</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1416-9993</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical, Oncological and Oral Science (Di.Chir.On.S.), University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy. andrea.cortegiani@unipa.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, Intensive Care and Emergency, Policlinico Paolo Giaccone, University of Palermo, 90127, Palermo, Italy. andrea.cortegiani@unipa.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tripodi</LastName><ForeName>Vincenzo Francesco</ForeName><Initials>VF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Anesthesia and Intensive Care Unit, Policlinico Gaetano Martino, University of Messina, Messina, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castioni</LastName><ForeName>Carlo Alberto</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS, Istituto Delle Scienze Neurologiche, UOC Anestesia E Rianimazione, Bologna, Italia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esposito</LastName><ForeName>Clelia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Critical Area Department, Anesthesia and Intensive Care, AO Dei Colli, Vincenzo Monaldi Hospital, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Galdieri</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Critical Area Department, Intensive Care in Cardiac Surgery, Vincenzo Monaldi Hospital, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monzani</LastName><ForeName>Roberta</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia and Intensive Care, IRCCS Humanitas Research Hospital, Rozzano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rispoli</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Critical Area Department, Anesthesia and Intensive Care, AO Dei Colli, Vincenzo Monaldi Hospital, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simonini</LastName><ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Anesthesia and Intensive Care Unit, Salesi Children's Hospital, Ancona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torrano</LastName><ForeName>Vito</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency and Urgency, Anesthesia and Intensive Care 1, ASST Grande Ospedale Metropolitano Niguarda, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giarratano</LastName><ForeName>Antonino</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical, Oncological and Oral Science (Di.Chir.On.S.), University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, Intensive Care and Emergency, Policlinico Paolo Giaccone, University of Palermo, 90127, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gratarola</LastName><ForeName>Angelo</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency, Anesthesia and Intensive Care Unit, IRCCS for Oncology and Neuroscience, San Martino Policlinico Hospital, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Anesth Analg Crit Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918591885906676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2731-3786</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elective surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Perioperative morbidity and mortality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2 infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccination</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37386538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s44158-022-00058-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s44158-022-00058-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>El-Boghdadly K, Cook TM, Goodacre T, Kua J, Denmark S, McNally S, Mercer N, Moonesinghe SR, Summerton DJ. Timing of elective surgery and risk assessment after SARS-CoV-2 infection: an update: a multidisciplinary consensus statement on behalf of the Association of Anaesthetists, Centre for Perioperative Care, Federation of Surgical Specialty Associations, Royal College of Anaesthetists, Royal College of Surgeons of England. Anaesthesia. 2022. 10.1111/anae.15699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9111236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35194788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://guides.temple.edu; https://www.sheffield.ac.uk/scharr/research/themes/systematic-reviewing#STARR. (Accessed 23 May 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitch K, Bernstein SJ, Aguilar MD, Burnand B, LaCalle JR, Lazaro P, et al. (2001) The RAND/UCLA appropriateness method user&#x2019;s manual [Internet]. Available from: http://www.rand.org/pubs/monograph_reports/MR1269.html). (Accessed May 23, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timing della chirurgia e gestione perioperatoria in elezione di pazienti con infezione pregressa da SARS-CoV-2. Available from: https://www.siaarti.it/news/716737. (Accessed May 23, 2022)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott TEF, Fowler AJ, Dobbs TD, et al. Mortality after surgery with SARS-CoV-2 infection in England: a population-wide epidemiological study. Br J Anaesth. 2021;127:205&#x2013;214. doi: 10.1016/j.bja.2021.05.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2021.05.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8192173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34148733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhangu A, Nepogodiev D, Glasbey JC, et al. Mortality and pulmonary complications in patients undergoing surgery with perioperative SARS-CoV-2 infection: an international cohort study. Lancet. 2020;396:27&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31182-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31182-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7259900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32479829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID Surg Collaborative, GlobalSurg Collaborative Timing of surgery following SARS-CoV-2 infection: an international prospective cohort study. Anaesthesia. 2021;76:748&#x2013;758. doi: 10.1111/anae.15458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33690889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohatgi N, Smilowitz NR, Reejhsinghani R. Perioperative cardiovascular considerations prior to elective noncardiac surgery in patients with a history of COVID-19. J Am Med Assoc Surg. 2022.10.1001/jamasurg.2021.6953</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35019990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVIDSurg Collaborative, GlobalSurg Collaborative SARSCoV-2 vaccination modelling for safe surgery to save lives: data from an international prospective cohort study. Brit J Surg. 2021;108:1056&#x2013;1063. doi: 10.1093/bjs/znab101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjs/znab101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7995808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33761533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UK Health Security Agency. SARS-CoV-2 variants of concern and variants under investigation in England. Technical Briefing 34. 2022. https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/1050236/technicalbriefing-34-14-january-2022.pdf (Accessed 23 May 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah F, Myers J, Basu D, et al. Decreased severity of disease during the first global omicron variant COVID-19 outbreak in a large hospital in Tshwane, South Africa. Int J Infect Dis. 2022;116:38&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2021.12.357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2021.12.357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8713416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34971823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nepogodiev D, Abbott TE, Ademuyiwa AO, et al. Projecting COVID-19 disruption to elective surgery. Lancet. 2022;399:233&#x2013;234. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02836-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02836-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8676422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34922640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nepogodiev D, Omar OM, Glasbey JC, et al. Elective surgery cancellations due to the COVID-19 pandemic: global predictive modelling to inform surgical recovery plans. Br J Surg. 2020;107:1440&#x2013;1449. doi: 10.1002/bjs.11746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bjs.11746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32395848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasher O, Sutcliffe JR, Stewart RJ. Pediatric surgery during the COVID-19 pandemic: an international survey of current practice. Eur J Pediatr Surg. 2021;31(5):407&#x2013;413. doi: 10.1055/s-0040-1714714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0040-1714714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32851612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanmugam A, Vythilingam G, Singaravel S, Nah SA. Assess, adapt and act: a paediatric surgery division&#x2019;s initial approach in a rapidly evolving pandemic. Pediatr Surg Int. 2020;36:925&#x2013;931. doi: 10.1007/s00383-020-04704-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00383-020-04704-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7320241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32594243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balasubramanian S, Rao NM, Goenka A, Roderick M, Ramanan AV. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in children - what we know so far and what we do not. Indian Pediatr. 2020;57:435&#x2013;442. doi: 10.1007/s13312-020-1819-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13312-020-1819-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7240240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32273490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui X, Zhao Z, Zhang T, Guo W, Guo W, Zheng J, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of children with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) J Med Virol. 2021;93:1057&#x2013;1069. doi: 10.1002/jmv.26398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7436402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32761898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith C, Odd D, Harwood R, Ward J, Linney M, Clark M, Hargreaves D, Ladhani SN, Draper E, Davis PJ, Kenny SE, Whittaker E, Luyt K, Viner R, Fraser LK. Deaths in children and young people in England after SARS-CoV-2 infection during the first pandemic year. Nat Med. 2022;28(1):185&#x2013;192. doi: 10.1038/s41591-021-01578-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01578-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34764489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glasbey J; COVIDSurg and GlobalSurg Collaboratives Peri-operative outcomes of surgery in children with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Anaesthesia. 2022;77(1):108&#x2013;109. doi: 10.1111/anae.15614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8653269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34739137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies P, Evans C, Kanthimathinathan HK, Lillie J, Brierley J, Waters G, Johnson M, Griffiths B, du Pr&#xe9; P, Mohammad Z, Deep A, Playfor S, Singh D, Inwald D, Jardine M, Ross O, Shetty N, Worrall M, Sinha R, Koul A, Whittaker E, Vyas H, Scholefield BR, Ramnarayan P. Intensive care admissions of children with paediatric inflammatory multisystem syndrome temporally associated with SARS-CoV-2 (PIMS-TS) in the UK: a multicentre observational study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2020;4(9):669&#x2013;677. doi: 10.1016/S2352-4642(20)30215-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-4642(20)30215-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7347350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32653054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittaker E, Bamford A, Kenny J, Kaforou M, Jones CE, Shah P, Ramnarayan P, Fraisse A, Miller O, Davies P, Kucera F, Brierley J, McDougall M, Carter M, Tremoulet A, Shimizu C, Herberg J, Burns JC, Lyall H, Levin M, PIMS-TS Study Group and EUCLIDS and PERFORM Consortia Clinical characteristics of 58 children with a pediatric inflammatory multisystem syndrome temporally associated with SARS-CoV-2. JAMA. 2020;324(3):259&#x2013;269. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.10369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.10369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7281356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32511692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dufort EM, Koumans EH, Chow EJ, et al. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children in New York state. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:347. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2021756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2021756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7346766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32598830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valverde I, Singh Y, Sanchez-de-Toledo J, et al. Acute cardiovascular manifestations in 286 children with multisystem inflammatory syndrome associated with COVID-19 infection in Europe. Circulation. 2021;143:21. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.050065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.050065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D, Cheng Q, Suh HR, Magdy M, Loi K. Role of bariatric surgery in a COVID-19 era: a review of economic costs. Surg Obes Relat Dis. 2021;17(12):2091&#x2013;2096. doi: 10.1016/j.soard.2021.07.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soard.2021.07.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8310782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34417118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;ent&#xfc;rk M, El Tahan MR, Shelley B, Szegedi LL, Piccioni F, Licker MJ, Karzai W, Gil MG, Neskovic V, Vanpeteghem C, Pelosi P, Cohen E, Sorbello M, Bence J, Stoica R, Mourisse J, Brunelli A, Jimenez MJ, Drnovsek Globokar M, Yapici D, Morsy AS, Kawagoe I, V&#xe9;gh T, Navarro-Ripoll R, Marczin N, Paloczi B, Unzueta C, Gregorio GD, Wouters P, Rex S, Mukherjee C, Paternoster G, Guarracino F. Thoracic anesthesia during the COVID-19 pandemic: 2021 Updated Recommendations by the European Association of Cardiothoracic Anaesthesiology and Intensive Care (EACTAIC) Thoracic Subspecialty Committee. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2021;35(12):3528&#x2013;3546. doi: 10.1053/j.jvca.2021.07.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jvca.2021.07.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8313821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34479782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVIDSurg Collaborative, GlobalSurg Collaborative SARS-CoV-2 vaccination modelling for safe surgery to save lives: data from an international prospective cohort study. Br J Surg. 2021;108(9):1056&#x2013;1063. doi: 10.1093/bjs/znab101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjs/znab101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7995808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33761533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nick Andrews, Julia Stowe, Freja Kirsebom, Samuel Toffa, Tim Rickeard, Eileen Gallagher, Charlotte Gower, Meaghan Kall, Natalie Groves, Anne-Marie O&#x2019;Connell, David Simons, Paula B. Blomquist, Asad Zaidi, Sophie Nash, Nurin Iwani Binti Abdul Aziz, Simon Thelwall, Gavin Dabrera, Richard Myers, Gayatri Amirthalingam, Saheer Gharbia, Jeffrey C. Barrett, Richard Elson, Shamez N Ladhani, Neil Ferguson, Maria Zambon, Colin NJ Campbell, Kevin Brown, Susan Hopkins, Meera Chand, Mary Ramsay, Jamie Lopez Bernal. Effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccines against the Omicron (B.1.1.529) variant of concern. medRxiv 2021.12.14.21267615; doi:10.1101/2021.12.14.21267615</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas EJ, Angulo FJ, McLaughlin JM, Anis E, Singer SR, Khan F, Brooks N, Smaja M, Mircus G, Pan K, Southern J, Swerdlow DL, Jodar L, Levy Y, Alroy-Preis S. Impact and effectiveness of mRNA BNT162b2 vaccine against SARS-CoV-2 infections and COVID-19 cases, hospitalisations, and deaths following a nationwide vaccination campaign in Israel: an observational study using national surveillance data. Lancet. 2021;397(10287):1819&#x2013;1829. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00947-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00947-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8099315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33964222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho T, Krammer F, Iwasaki A. The first 12 months of COVID-19: a timeline of immunological insights. Nat Rev Immunol. 2021;21:245&#x2013;256. doi: 10.1038/s41577-021-00522-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-021-00522-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7958099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33723416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merritt-Genore H, Moosdorf R, Gillaspie E, Lother S, Engelman D, Ahmed S, Baciewicz FA, Grant MC, Milewski R, Cawcutt K, Hayanga JA, Chatterjee S, Arora RC, Society of Thoracic Surgeons Workforce on Critical Care Perioperative coronavirus vaccination-timing and implications: a guidance document. Ann Thorac Surg. 2021;112(5):1707&#x2013;1715. doi: 10.1016/j.athoracsur.2021.07.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.athoracsur.2021.07.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8349423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34370980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijeysundera DN, Khadaroo RG. Surgery after a previous SARS-CoV-2 infection: data, answers and questions. Anaesthesia. 2021;76(6):731&#x2013;735. doi: 10.1111/anae.15490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33864692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Boghdadly K, Cook TM, Goodacre T, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection, COVID-19 and timing of elective surgery: a multidisciplinary consensus statement on behalf of the Association of Anaesthetists, the Centre for Peri-operative Care, the Federation of Surgical Specialty Associations, the Royal College. Anaesthesia. 2021;76:940&#x2013;946. doi: 10.1111/anae.15464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33735942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celano CM, Villegas AC, Albanese AM, Gaggin HK, Huffman JC. Depression and anxiety in heart failure: a review. Harv Rev Psychiatry. 2018;26(4):175&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1097/HRP.0000000000000162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HRP.0000000000000162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6042975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29975336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flaherty LB, Wood T, Cheng A, Khan AR. Pre-existing psychological depression confers increased risk of adverse cardiovascular outcomes following cardiac surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2017;154(5):1578&#x2013;1586.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.jtcvs.2017.06.052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtcvs.2017.06.052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28818292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagliardi AR, Yip CYY, Irish J, Wright FC, Rubin B, Ross H, Green R, Abbey S, McAndrews MP, Stewart DE. The psychological burden of waiting for procedures and patient-centred strategies that could support the mental health of wait-listed patients and caregivers during the COVID-19 pandemic: a scoping review. Health Expect. 2021;24(3):978&#x2013;990. doi: 10.1111/hex.13241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hex.13241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8235883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33769657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Society of Anesthesiologists. https://www.asahq.org/quality-and-practice-management/coding-billing-and-payment/telehealth (Accessed 23 May 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihalj M, Carrel T, Gregoric ID, Andereggen L, Zinn PO, Doll D, Stueber F, Gabriel RA, Urman RD, Luedi MM. Telemedicine for preoperative assessment during a COVID-19 pandemic: recommendations for clinical care. Best Pract Res Clin Anaesthesiol. 2020;34(2):345&#x2013;351. doi: 10.1016/j.bpa.2020.05.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpa.2020.05.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32711839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasmin F, Bin Zafar MD, Salman A, Farooque U, Asghar MS, Khan AA, Mohiuddin O, Hassan SA. Exploring the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on pediatric surgical services. Minerva Pediatr Torino. 2021;73(5):460&#x2013;466. doi: 10.23736/S2724-5276.21.06146-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S2724-5276.21.06146-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33845565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werner RS, L&#xf6;rtscher A, Kirschner MB, Lauk O, Furrer K, Caviezel C, Schneiter D, Inci I, Hillinger S, Curioni-Fontecedro A, Opitz I. Surgical management of lung cancer during the COVID-19 pandemic - a narrative review and single-centre report. Swiss Med Wkly. 2022;152:w30109. doi: 10.4414/smw.2022.w30109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4414/smw.2022.w30109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35147390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuru B, Kale A, Basol G, Gundogdu EC, Yildiz G, Mat E, Usta T. Is it safe to perform elective gynaecologic surgery during the two peaks of COVID-19 pandemic? Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75(11):e14816. doi: 10.1111/ijcp.14816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijcp.14816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8646615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34486805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartoletta JJ, Rhee PC. Hand surgery during the COVID-19 pandemic: clinical care best practices. Hand Surgery and Rehabilitation. 2021;40(5):675&#x2013;681. doi: 10.1016/j.hansur.2021.05.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hansur.2021.05.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8166454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34082157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loganathan J, Doumouchtsis SK. CHORUS: an international collaboration for harmonising outcomes, research and standards in urogynaecology and women&#x2019;s health. Impact of COVID-19 on management of urogynaecology patients: a rapid review of the literature. Int Urogynecol J. 2021;32(10):2631&#x2013;2646. doi: 10.1007/s00192-021-04704-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-021-04704-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7856854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33533991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad NK, Lake R, Englum BR, Turner DJ, Siddiqui T, Mayorga-Carlin M, Sorkin JD, Lal BK. Increased complications in patients who test COVID-19 positive after elective surgery and implications for pre and postoperative screening. Am J Surg. 2022;223(2):380&#x2013;387. doi: 10.1016/j.amjsurg.2021.04.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjsurg.2021.04.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8045424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33894979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zdemir Y, Temiz A. Surgical treatment of gastrointestinal tumors in a COVID-19 pandemic hospital: can open versus minimally invasive surgery be safely performed? J Surg Oncol. 2021;124(8):1217&#x2013;1223. doi: 10.1002/jso.26653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jso.26653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8426937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34411309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindsey Wang, Nathan A. Berger, David C. Kaelber, Pamela B. Davis, Nora D. Volkow, Rong Xu. Comparison of outcomes from COVID infection in pediatric and adult patients before and after the emergence of Omicron. medRxiv 2021.12.30.21268495. 10.1101/2021.12.30.21268495</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolter N, Jassat W, Walaza S, et al. Early assessment of the clinical severity of the SARS-CoV-2 omicron variant in South Africa: a data linkage study. Lancet. 2022;399:437&#x2013;446. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(22)00017-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(22)00017-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8769664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35065011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ICNARC. ICNARC report on COVID-19 in critical care: England, Wales and Northern Ireland 14 January 2022. 2022. https://www.icnarc.org/DataServices/Attachments/Download/93440802-6975-ec11-913a-00505601089b (Accessed 23 May 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCEPOD. Surgical outcome risk tool v2 (SORT). 2021. http://sortsurgery.com/index.php (Accessed 23&#xa0;May 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short JA, van der Walt JH, Zoanetti DC. Immunization and anesthesia - an international survey. Pediatr Anesth. 2006;16:514&#x2013;522. doi: 10.1111/j.1460-9592.2006.01897.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1460-9592.2006.01897.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16677260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kothari AN, DiBrito SR, Lee JJ, Caudle AS, Clemens MW, Gottumukkala VN, Katz MHG, Offodile AC, Uppal A, D3CODE Team. Chang GJ. Surgical outcomes in cancer patients undergoing elective surgery after recovering from mild-to-moderate SARS- CoV-2 infection. Ann Surg Oncol. 2021;28(13):8046&#x2013;8053. doi: 10.1245/s10434-021-10291-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1245/s10434-021-10291-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8235912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34176060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASA and APSF Joint Statement on Elective Surgery and Anesthesia for Patients after COVID-19 Infection. March 9, 202. https://www.asahq.org/about-asa/newsroom/news-releases/2021/03/asa-and-apsf-joint-statement-on-elective-surgery-and-anesthesia-for-patients-after-covid-19-infection-rv (Accessed 23 May 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>.SAMBA statement on timing of elective ambulatory surgery during COVID-19 resurgence in the U.S. https://sambahq.org/education-research/samba_statements/ (Accessed 23 May 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales-Garc&#xed;a D, Docobo-Durantez F, Capit&#xe1;n Vallvey JM, Suarez-Grau JM, Campo-Cimarras ME, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Vinagre S, Hidalgo- Grau LA, Puigcercos-Fust&#xe9; JM, Zaragoza-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Valera-S&#xe1;nchez Z, Vega-Ruiz V; Grupo de Trabajo CIRUGIA-AEC-COVID-19. Consensus of the ambulatory surgery commite section of the Spanish Association of Surgeons on the role of ambulatory surgery in the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. Cir Esp (Engl Ed). 2021:S0009&#x2013;739X(21)00160&#x2013;3. English, Spanish. 10.1016/j.ciresp.2021.04.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8866086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35249855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Leary ST, Maldonado YA. Myocarditis after SARS-CoV-2 vaccination: true, true, and&#x2026;related? Pediatrics. 2021;148(3):e2021052644. doi: 10.1542/peds.2021-052644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2021-052644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34088761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salah HM, Metha JL. COVID-19 vaccine and myocarditis. Am J Cardiol. 2021;15(157):146&#x2013;148. doi: 10.1016/j.amjcard.2021.07.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2021.07.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8272967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34399967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA, Nemati H, Shahisavandi M, et al. Long COVID in children and adolescents. World J Pediatr. 2021;3:1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1007/s12519-021-00457-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12519-021-00457-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8414448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34478045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvapulle E.; Johnson D.; Darvall J.N. Risk stratification of individuals undergoing surgery after COVID-19 recovery. 10.1016/j.bja.2021.09.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8501215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34742543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bui N, Coetzer M, Schenning KJ, O&#x2019;Glasser AY. Preparing previously COVID-19-positive patients for elective surgery: a framework for preoperative evaluation. Perioper Med. 2021;10:1. doi: 10.1186/s13741-020-00172-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13741-020-00172-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7787702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33407898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eochag&#xe1;in AN, Hardman JG, Buggy DJ. SARS-CoV-2 in perioperative medicine: lessons learnt. Br J Anaesth. 2021;126(5):187&#x2013;188. doi: 10.1016/j.bja.2021.02.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2021.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7881704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33736872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlesworth M, Grossman R. Pre-operative SARS-CoV-2 testing, isolation, vaccination and remote prehabilitation &#x2013; the road to &#x2018;COVID-19 secure&#x2019;elective surgery. Anaesthesia. 2021;76:1439&#x2013;1441. doi: 10.1111/anae.15590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8653181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34541657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVIDSurg Collaborative, GlobalSurg Collaborative Effects of pre-operative isolation on postoperative pulmonary complications after elective surgery: an international prospective cohort study. Anaesthesia. 2021;76:1454&#x2013;1464. doi: 10.1111/anae.15560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34371522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marguerite M. Hoyler, Robert S. White, Christopher W. Tam. Anesthesia and the &#x201c;post-COVID syndrome&#x201d;: perioperative consideration s for patients with prior SARS-CoV-2 infection. 10.1016/j.jclinane.2021.110283</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8026274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33857843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer ME, Bernstein K, Dinges E, Delgado C, El-Sharawi N, Sultan P, et al. Obstetric anesthesia during the COVID-19 pandemic. Anesth Analg. 131;7&#x2013;15. 10.1213/ane.0000000000004856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7173093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32265365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Xu X, Chen Z, Duan J, Hashimoto K, Yang L, et al. Nervous system involvement after infection with COVID-19 and other coronaviruses. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:18&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2020.03.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2020.03.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32240762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobsson JG, Johnson MZ. (2016). Perioperative regional anaesthesia and postoperative longer-term outcomes. F1000 Res 5, F1000Res Faculty Rev&#x2013;2501. doi:10.12688/f1000research.9100.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5063036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27785357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappelleri G, Fanelli A, Ghisi D, Russo G, Giorgi A, Torrano V, Lo Bianco G, Salomone S, Fumagalli R. The role of regional anesthesia during the SARS-CoV2 pandemic: appraisal of clinical, pharmacological and organizational aspects. Front Pharmacol. 2021;12:574091. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2021.574091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2021.574091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8213435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34149401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matava CT, Peyton J, von Ungern-Sternberg BS. Pediatric airway management in times of COVID-19- a review of the evidence and controversies. Curr Anesthesiol Rep. 2021;11(3):243&#x2013;247. doi: 10.1007/s40140-021-00462-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40140-021-00462-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8302463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34335104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook TM. Risk to health from COVID-19 for anaesthetists and intensivists: a narrative review. Anaesthesia. 2020;75:1494&#x2013;1508. doi: 10.1111/anae.15220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7405109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32677708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>