<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35382075</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2158-8333</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>1-3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Season>Jan-Mar</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Innovations in clinical neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Innov Clin Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Could Palmitoylethanolamide Be an Effective Treatment for Long-COVID-19? Hypothesis and Insights in Potential Mechanisms of Action and Clinical Applications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>19</StartPage><EndPage>25</EndPage><MedlinePgn>19-25</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>COVID-19 is highly transmissive and contagious disease with a wide spectrum of clinicopathological issues, including respiratory, vasculo-coagulative, and immune disorders. In some cases of COVID-19, patients can be characterized by clinical sequelae with mild-to-moderate symptoms that persist long after the resolution of the acute infection, known as long-COVID, potentially affecting their quality of life. The main symptoms of long-COVID include persistent dyspnea, fatigue and weakness (that are typically out of proportion, to the degree of ongoing lung damage and gas exchange impairment), persistence of anosmia and dysgeusia, neuropsychiatric symptoms, and cognitive dysfunctions (such as brain fog or memory lapses). The appropriate management and prevention of potential long-COVID sequelae is still lacking. It is also believed that long-term symptoms of COVID-19 are related to an immunity over-response, namely a cytokine storm, involving the release of pro-inflammatory interleukins, monocyte chemoattractant proteins, and tissue necrosis factors. Palmitoylethanolamide (PEA) shows affinity for vanilloid receptor 1 and for cannabinoid-like G protein-coupled receptors, enhancing anandamide activity by means of an entourage effect. Due to its anti-inflammatory properties, PEA has been recently used as an early add-on therapy for respiratory problems in patients with COVID-19. It is believed that PEA mitigates the cytokine storm modulating cell-mediated immunity, as well as counteracts pain and oxidative stress. In this article, we theorize that PEA could be a potentially effective nutraceutical to treat long-COVID, with regard to fatigue and myalgia, where a mythocondrial dysfunction is hypothesizable.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022. Matrix Medical Communications. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raciti</LastName><ForeName>Loredana</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drs. Raciti, Arcadi, and Calabr&#xf2; are with IRCCS Centro Neurolesi "Bonino Pulejo" in Messina, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arcadi</LastName><ForeName>Francesca Antonia</ForeName><Initials>FA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drs. Raciti, Arcadi, and Calabr&#xf2; are with IRCCS Centro Neurolesi "Bonino Pulejo" in Messina, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calabr&#xf2;</LastName><ForeName>Rocco Salvatore</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drs. Raciti, Arcadi, and Calabr&#xf2; are with IRCCS Centro Neurolesi "Bonino Pulejo" in Messina, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Innov Clin Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549695</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2158-8333</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">abnormal immune response</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutraceuticals</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>DISCLOSURES: The authors have no conflicts of interest relevant to the content of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35382075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8970234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ibekwe T, Ibekwe P, Orimadegun EA. Third force in the treatment of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Med Surg (Lond). 2021;65:102218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8018907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33841878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roncati L, Ligabue G, Nasillo V et al. A proof of evidence supporting abnormal immunothrombosis in severe COVID-19: naked megakaryocyte nuclei increase in the bone marrow and lungs of critically ill patients. Platelets. 2020;31(8):1085&#x2013;1089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32857624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afrin LB, Weinstock LB, Molderings GJ. Covid-19 hyperinflammation and post-Covid-19 illness may be rooted in mast cell activation syndrome. Int J Infect Dis. 2020;100:327&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7529115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32920235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kritas SK, Ronconi G, Caraffa A et al. Mast cells contribute to coronavirus-induced inflammation: new anti-inflammatory strategy. J Biol Regul Homeost Agents. 2020;34(1):9&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32013309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikkert M. Innate immune evasion by human respiratory RNA viruses. J Innate Immun. 2020;12(1):4&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6959104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31610541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shokri-Mashhadi N, Kazemi M, Saadat S, Moradi S. Effects of select dietary supplements on the prevention and treatment of viral respiratory tract infections: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Expert Rev Respir Med. 2021;15(6):805&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33858268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roncati L, Nasillo V, Lusenti B, Riva G. Signals of Th2 immune response from COVID-19 patients requiring intensive care. Ann Hematol. 2020;99(6):1419&#x2013;1420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7205481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32382776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roncati L, Vadal&#xe0; M, Corazzari V, Palmieri B. COVID-19 vaccine and boosted immunity: nothing ad interim to do? Vaccine. 2020;38(48):7581&#x2013;7584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7546174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33071005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, McAuley DF, Brown M et al. COVID-19: consider cytokine storm syndromes and immunosuppression. Lancet. 2020;395(10229):1033&#x2013;1034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z, Shi L, Wang Y et al. Pathological findings of COVID-19 associated with acute respiratory distress syndrome. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8(4):420&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7164771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32085846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma BK, Kakker NK, Bhadouriya S, Chhabra R. Effect of TLR agonist on infections bronchitis virus replication and cytokine expression in embryonated chicken eggs. Mol Immunol. 2020;120:52&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7112572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32065987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X, Chu H, Wong BH-Y et al. Activation of C-type lectin receptor and (RIG)-I-like receptors contributes to proinflammatory response in Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus-infected macrophages. J Infect Dis. 2019;221(4):647&#x2013;659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7107474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31562757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fung SY, Yuen KS, Ye ZW et al. A tug-of-war between severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 and host antiviral defence: lessons from other pathogenic viruses. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2020;9(1):558&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7103735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32172672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Moltke J, Trinidad NJ, Moayeri M et al. Rapid induction of inflammatory lipid mediators by the inflammasome in vivo. Nature. 2012;490(7418):107&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3465483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22902502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gartung A, Yang J, Sukhatme VP et al. Suppression of chemotherapy-induced cytokine/lipid mediator surge and ovarian cancer by a dual COX-2/sEH inhibitor. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2019;116(5):1698&#x2013;1703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6358686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30647111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan CN. Pro-resolving lipid mediators are leads for resolution physiology. Nature. 2014;510(7503):92&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4263681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24899309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panigrahy D, Gilligan MM, Huang S et al. Inflammation resolution: a dual-pronged approach to averting cytokine storms in COVID-19? Cancer Metastasis Rev. 2020;39(2):337&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7207990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32385712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roncati L, Manenti A, Manco G et al. The COVID-19 arterial thromboembolic complications: from inflammation to immunothrombosis through anti-phospholipid autoantibodies. Ann Vasc Surg. 2021;72:216&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33387619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholls JM, Poon LLM, Lee KC et al. Lung pathology of fatal severe acute respiratory syndrome. Lancet. 2003;361(9371):1773&#x2013;1778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7112492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12781536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oronsky B, Larson C, Hammond TC A review of persistent post-COVID syndrome (PPCS). Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2021. pp. 1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33609255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscogiuri G, Barrea L, Savastano S, Colao A. Nutritional recommendations for COVID-19 quarantine. Eur J Clin Nutrition. 2020;74(6):850&#x2013;851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7155155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32286533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro ALR, Sousa NWA, Carvalho VO. What to do when the choice is no choice at all? A critical view on nutritional recommendations for CoVID-19 quarantine. Eur J Clin Nutrition. 2020;74(10):1488&#x2013;1489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32796923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gigli S, Seguella L, Pesce M et al. Cannabidiol restores intestinal barrier dysfunction and inhibits the apoptotic process induced by Clostridium difficile toxin A in Caco-2 cells. United European Gastroenterology J. 2017;5(8):1108&#x2013;1115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5721977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29238589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesce M, Esposito G, Sarnelli G. Endocannabinoids in the treatment of gasytrointestinal inflammation and symptoms. Curr Opin Pharmacol. 2018;43:81&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30218940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams CM, Kirkham TC. Anandamide induces overeating: mediation by central cannabinoid (CB1) receptors. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 1999;143(3):315&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10353436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das UN. Can bioactive lipids inactivate coronavirus (COVID-19)? Arch Med Res. 2020;51(3):282&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32229155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaffari S, Roshanravan N, Tutunchi H et al. Oleoylethanolamide, a bioactive lipid amide, as a promising treatment strategy for coronavirus/COVID-19. Arch Med Res. 2020;51(5):464&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32327293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onaivi ES, Sharma V. Cannabis for COVID-19: can cannabinoids quell the cytokine storm? Future Sci OA. 2020;6(8):FSO625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7451410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32974048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moscatelli F, Sessa F, Valenzano A et al. COVID-19: role of nutrition and supplementation. Nutrients. 2021;13(3):976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8002713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33803015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert DM, Di Marzo V. The palmitoylethanolamide and oleamide enigmas: are these two fatty acid amides cannabimimetic? Curr Med Chem. 1999;6(8):757&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10469890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wortley MA, Adcock JJ, Dubuis ED et al. Targeting fatty acid amide hydrolase as a therapeutic strategy for antitussive therapy. Eur Respir J. 2017;50(3):1700782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28931663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein R, Schwenk M, Templeton DM. Cytokine profiles in human exposure to metals (IUPAC Technical Report). Pure Appl Chem. 2006;78(11):2155&#x2013;2168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Turco V, Di Bella G, Furci P et al. Heavy metals content by ICP-OES in Sarda sarda, Sardinella aurita and Lepidopus caudatus from the Strait of Messina (Sicily, Italy). Nat Prod Res. 2013;27(6):518&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22472136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreca G, Bonforte A, Neri M. A pilot GIS database of active faults of Mt. Etna (Sicily): a tool for integrated hazard evaluation. J Volcanol Geotherm Res. 2013;251:170&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health Research. Living with Covid-19. A dynamic review of the evidence around ongoing Covid-19 symptoms (often called Long Covid). 2020. https://evidence.nihr.ac.uk/themedreview/living-with-covid19 Accessed 14 Jan 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raciti L, Calabr&#xf2; RS. Can volcanic trace elements facilitate Covid-19 diffusion? A hypothesis stemming from the Mount Etna area, Sicily. Med Hypotheses. 2020;144:110058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7320851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32758894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biradar V, Moran JL.  Adelaide, AU: University of Adelaide Press; 2011. SIRS, sepsis and multiorgan failure. In: Fitridge R, Thompson M, eds. Mechanisms of Vascular Disease: A Reference Book for Vascular Specialists. p. 17.https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK534275/ Accessed 14 Jan 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30485029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamers L, Kox M, Pickkers P. Sepsis-induced immunoparalysis: mechanisms, markers, and treatment options. Minerva Anestesiol. 2015;81(4):426&#x2013;439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24878876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu K, Cai H, Shen Y et al. [Management of corona virus disease-19 (COVID-19): the Zhejiang experience]. Zhejiang Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban. 2020;49(1):147&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8800711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32391658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giacomelli A, Pezzati L, Conti F et al. Self-reported olfactory and taste disorders in SARS-CoV-2 patients: a cross-sectional study. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71(15):889&#x2013;890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi H, Han X, Jiang N et al. Radiological findings from 81 patients with COVID-19 pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a descriptive study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20(4):425&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32105637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseiny M, Kooraki S, Gholamrezanezhad A et al. Radiology perspective of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): lessons from severe acute respiratory syndrome and Middle East respiratory syndrome. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2020;214(5):1078&#x2013;1082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32108495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian S, Hu W, Niu L et al. Pulmonary pathology of early-phase 2019 novel coronavirus (COVID-19) pneumonia in two patients with lung cancer. J Thorac Oncol. 2020;15(5):700&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32114094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell B, Moss C, George G et al. Associations between immune-suppressive and stimulating drugs and novel COVID-19&#x2013;a systematic review of current evidence. Ecancermedicalscience. 2020;14:1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7105343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32256705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johannson K, Collard HR. Acute exacerbation of idiopathic pulmonary fbrosis: a proposal. Curr Respir Care Rep. 2013;2(4):10.1007/s13665-013-0065-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3883625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24416637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Sayed S, Shokry D, Gomaa SM. Post-COVID-19 fatigue and anhedonia: a cross-sectional study and their correlation to post-recovery period. Neuropsychopharmacol Rep. 2021;41(1):50&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8182964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33332756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal M. Cardiovascular disease and COVID-19. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2020;14(3):247&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32247212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biernacka A, Frangogiannis NG. Aging and cardiac fibrosis. Aging Dis. 2011;2(2):158&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3153299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21837283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Xu X, Chen Z et al. Nervous system involvement after infection with COVID-19 and other coronaviruses. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:18&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32240762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aloe L, Leon A, Levi-Montalcini R. A proposed autacoid mechanism controlling mastocyte behaviour. Agents Actions. 1993;39:C145&#x2013;C147. Spec No.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7505999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Verme J, Fu J, Astarita G et al. The nuclear receptor peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-alpha mediates the anti-inflammatory actions of palmitoylethanolamide. Mol Pharmacol. 2005;67(1):15&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15465922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godlewski G, Offert&#xe1;ler L, Wagner JA, Kunos G. Receptors for acylethanolamides-GPR55 and GPR119. Prostaglandins Other Lipid Mediat. 2009;89(3-4):105&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2751869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19615459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho WS, Barrett DA, Randall MD. 'Entourage' effects of N-palmitoylethanolamide and N-oleoylethanolamide on vasorelaxation to anandamide occur through TRPV1 receptors. Br J Pharmacol. 2008;155(6):837&#x2013;846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2597234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18695637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsson KO, Vandevoorde S, Lambert DM et al. Effects of homologues and analogues of palmitoylethanolamide upon the inactivation of the endocannabinoid anandamide. Br J Pharmacol. 2001;133(8):1263&#x2013;1275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1621151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11498512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri D, Bruschetta G, Cordaro M et al. Micronized/ultramicronized palmitoylethanolamide displays superior oral efficacy compared to nonmicronized palmitoylethanolamide in a rat model of inflammatory pain. J Neuroinflammation. 2016;13(1):129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4888742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27245980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keppel Hesselink JM, de Boer T, Witkamp RF. Palmitoylethanolamide: a natural body-own anti-inflammatory agent, effective and safe against influenza and common cold. Int J Inflam. 2013;2013:151028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3771453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24066256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rankin L, Fowler CJ. The basal pharmacology of palmitoylethanolamide. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(21):7942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7662788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33114698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrosino S, Schiano Moriello A. Palmitoylethanolamide: a nutritional approach to keep neuroinflammation within physiological boundaries&#x2013;a systematic review. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(24):9526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7765232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33333772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito G, Capoccia E, Turco F et al. Palmitoylethanolamide improves colon inflammation through an enteric glia/toll like receptor 4-dependent PPAR-&#x3b1; activation. Gut. 2014;63(8):1300&#x2013;1312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24082036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarnelli G, Gigli S, Capocci E et al. Renin-angiotensin system: the unexpected flaw inside the human immune system revealed by SARS-CoV-2. Med Hypotheses. 2020;140:109686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32220710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordaro M, Cuzzocrea S, Crupi R. An update of palmitoylethanolamide and luteolin effects in preclinical and clinical studies of neuroinflammatory events. Antioxidants (Basel). 2020;9(3):216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7139331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32150935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarnelli G, Gigli S, Capoccia E et al. Palmitoylethanolamide exerts antiproliferative effect and downregulates VEGF signaling in Caco-2 human colon carcinoma cell line through a selective PPAR-&#x3b1;-dependent inhibition of Akt/mTOR pathway. Phytother Res. 2016;30(6):963&#x2013;970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26929026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magadum A, Engel FB. PPAR&#x3b2;/&#x3b4;: Linking metabolism to regeneration. Int J Mol Sci. 2018;19(7):2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6073704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29996502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korbecki J, Bobinski R, Dutka M. Self-regulation of the inflammatory response by peroxisome proliferator-activated receptors. Inflamm Res. 2019;68(6):443&#x2013;458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6517359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30927048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipriano M, Esposito G, Negro L et al. Palmitoylethanolamide regulates production of pro-angiogenic mediators in a model of &#x3b2; amyloid-induced astrogliosis in vitro. CNS Neurol Disord Drug Targets. 2015;14(7):828&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25801844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couch DG, Tasker C, Theophilidou E et al. Cannabidiol and palmitoylethanolamide are anti-inflammatoryin the acutely inflamed human colon. Clin Sci (Lond). 2017;131(21):2611&#x2013;2626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28954820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gigante A, Aquili A, Farinelli L et al. Sodium chromo-glycate and palmitoylethanolamide: a possible strategy to treat mast cell-induced lung inflammation in COVID-19. Med Hypotheses. 2010;143:109856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32460208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker JM, Krey JF, Chu CJ, Huang SM. Endocannabinoids and related fatty acid derivatives in pain modulation. Chem Phys Lipids. 2002;121:159&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12505698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Agostino G, Russo R, Avagliano C et al. Palmitoylethanolamide protects against the amyloid-&#x3b2;25-35-induced learning and memory impairment in mice, an experimental model of Alzheimer disease, Neuropsychopharmacology. 2012;37(7):1784&#x2013;1792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3358748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22414817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roncati L, Lusenti B, Pellati F, Corsi L. Micronized/ultramicronized palmitoylethanolamide (PEA) as natural neuroprotector against COVID-19 inflammation. Prostaglandins Other Lipid Mediat. 2021;154:106540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8137339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33636368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beggiato S, Tomasini MC, Ferraro L. Palmitoylethanolamide (PEA) as a potential therapeutic agent in Alzheimer's disease. Front Pharmacol. 2019;10:821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6667638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31396087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britti D, Crupi R, Impellizzeri D et al. A novel composite formulation of palmitoylethanolamide and quercetin decreases inflammation and relieves pain in inflammatory and osteoarthritic pain models. BMC Veterinary Research. 2013;13(1):229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5541643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28768536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito G, De Filippis D, Cirillo C et al. Cannabidiol in inflammatory bowel diseases: a brief overview. Phytother Res. 2013;27(5):633&#x2013;636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22815234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genovese T, Esposito E, Mazzon E et al. Effects of palmitoylethanolamide on signaling pathways implicated in the development of spinal cord injury. J Pharmacol Exper Ther. 2009;326(1):12&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18367664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grill M, H&#xf6;genauer C, Blesl A et al. Members of the endocannabinoid system are distinctly regulated in inflammatory bowel disease and colorectal cancer. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):2358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6382821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30787385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scuderi C, Esposito G, Blasio A et al. Palmitoylethanolamide counteracts reactive astrogliosis induced by &#x3b2;-amyloid peptide. J Cell Mol Med. 2011;15(12):2664&#x2013;2674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4373435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21255263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarnelli G, Seguella L, Pesce M et al. HIV-1 tat-induced diarrhea is improved by the PPARalpha agonist, palmitoylethanolamide, by suppressing theactivation of enteric glia. J Neuroinflammation. 2018;15(1):94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5866515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29573741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heide EC, Bindila L, Post JM et al. Prophylactic palmitoylethanolamide prolongs survival and decreases detrimental inflammation in aged mice with bacterial meningitis. Front Immunol. 2018;9:2671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6250830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30505308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lama A, Provensi G, Amoriello R et al. The anti-inflammatory and immune-modulatory effects of OEA limit DSS-induced colitis in mice. Biomed Pharmacother. 2020;129:110368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32559625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesce M, Seguella L, Cassarano S Phytotherapics in COVID:19: Why palmitoylethanolamide? Phytother Res. 2020. 10.1002/ptr.6978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33296131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntmann VO, Carerj ML, Wieters I et al. Outcomes of cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in patients recently recovered from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). [published correction appears in JAMA Cardiol. 2020; 5:(11)1308]. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5(11):1265&#x2013;1273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Rio C, Malani PN. New insights on a rapidly changing epidemic. J Amer Med Assoc. 2020;323(24):1339&#x2013;1340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32108857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi S, Qin M, Shen B et al. Association of cardiac injury with mortality in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5(7):802&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32211816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K, Straus SE, Hickie I et al. The chronic fatigue syndrome: a comprehensive approach to its definition and study. International Chronic Fatigue Syndrome Study Group. Ann Intern Med. 1994;121(12):953&#x2013;959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7978722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves WC, Lloyd A, Vernon SD et al. Identification of ambiguities in the 1994 chronic fatigue syndrome research case definition and recommendations for resolution. BMC Health Serv Res. 2003;3(1):25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC317472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14702202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blundell S, Ray KK, Buckland M, White PD. Chronic fatigue syndrome and circulating cytokines: a systematic review. Brain Behav Immun. 2015;50:186&#x2013;195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26148446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montoya JG, Holmes TH, Anderson JN et al. Cytokine signature associated with disease severity in chronic fatigue syndrome patients. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2017;114(34):E7150&#x2013;E7158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5576836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28760971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornig M, Montoya JG, Klimas NG et al. Distinct plasma immune signatures in ME/CFS are present early in the course of illness. Sci Adv. 2015;1(1):e1400121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26079000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell L, Broderick G, Taylor R et al. Illness progression in chronic fatigue syndrome: a shifting immune baseline. BMC Immunol. 2016;17:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4785654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26965484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croxford AL, Kulig P, Becher B. IL-12-and IL-23 in health and disease. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2014;25(4):415&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25130295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roerink ME, Knoop H, Bronkhorst EM et al. Cytokine signatures in chronic fatigue syndrome patients: a case control study and the effect of anakinra treatment. J Transl Med. 2017;15(1):267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5747240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29284500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cua DJ, Sherlock J, Chen Y et al. Interleukin-23 rather than interleukin-12 is the critical cytokine for autoimmune inflammation of the brain. Nature. 2003;421(6924):744&#x2013;748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12610626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xf6;nrich G, Raftery MJ, Samstag Y. Devilishly radical NETwork in COVID-19: oxidative stress, neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), and T cell suppression. Adv Biol Regul. 2020;77:100741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7334659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32773102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGonagle D, Sharif K, O&#x2019;Regan A, Bridgewood C. The role of cytokines including interleukin-6 in COVID-19 induced pneumonia and macrophage activation syndrome-like disease. Autoimmun Rev. 2020;19(6):102537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roncati L, Manenti A, Fabbiani L et al. HSV1 viremia with fulminant hepatitis as opportunistic sequela in severe COVID-19. Ann Hematol. 2022;101(1):229&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7811947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33458783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi N. Long covid: how to define it and how to manage it. BMJ. 2020;370:m3489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32895219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall M. The lasting misery of coronavirus long haulers. Nature. 2020;585(7825):339&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32929257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doykov I, H&#xe4;llqvist J, Gilmour KC et al. &#x2018;The long tail of Covid-19&#x2019; &#x2013;the detection of a prolonged inflammatory response after a SARS-CoV-2 infection in asymptomatic and mildly affected patients. F1000Res. 2020;9:134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7745182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33391730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>