<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37815903</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2152-5250</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Aging and disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Aging Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Role of Microglia, Decreased Neurogenesis and Oligodendrocyte Depletion in Long COVID-Mediated Brain Impairments.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1958</StartPage><EndPage>1966</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1958-1966</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14336/AD.2023.10918</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) is the cause of a recent worldwide coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19) pandemic. SARS-CoV-2 primarily causes an acute respiratory infection but can progress into significant neurological complications in some. Moreover, patients with severe acute COVID-19 could develop debilitating long-term sequela. Long-COVID is characterized by chronic symptoms that persist months after the initial infection. Common complaints are fatigue, myalgias, depression, anxiety, and "brain fog," or cognitive and memory impairments. A recent study demonstrated that a mild COVID-19 respiratory infection could generate elevated proinflammatory cytokines and chemokines in the cerebral spinal fluid. This commentary discusses findings from this study, demonstrating that even a mild respiratory SARS-CoV-2 infection can cause considerable neuroinflammation with microglial and macrophage reactivity. Such changes could also be gleaned by measuring chemokines and cytokines in the circulating blood. Moreover, neuroinflammation caused by mild SARS-CoV-2 infection can also impair hippocampal neurogenesis, deplete oligodendrocytes, and decrease myelinated axons. All these changes likely contribute to cognitive deficits in long-COVID syndrome. Therefore, strategies capable of restraining neuroinflammation, maintaining better hippocampal neurogenesis, and preserving oligodendrocyte lineage differentiation and maturation may prevent or reduce the incidence of long-COVID after SARS-CoV-2 respiratory infection.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Zhuang-Yao D</ForeName><Initials>ZD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Regenerative Medicine, Department of Cell Biology and Genetics, Texas A&amp;M University Health Science Center School of Medicine, College Station, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Ketty</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sam Houston State University College of Osteopathic Medicine, Conroe, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shetty</LastName><ForeName>Ashok K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Regenerative Medicine, Department of Cell Biology and Genetics, Texas A&amp;M University Health Science Center School of Medicine, College Station, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG075440</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS106907</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>RF1 AG074256</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Aging Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101540533</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2152-5250</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>
<b>Competing Interests</b>
. The authors declare that there are no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37815903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10676788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14336/AD.2023.10918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">AD.2023.10918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ciotti M, Ciccozzi M, Terrinoni A, Jiang W-C, Wang C-B, Bernardini S (2020). The COVID-19 pandemic. Crit Rev Clin Lab Sci, 57:365-388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32645276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Hu B, Hu C, Zhu F, Liu X, Zhang J, et al.. (2020). Clinical Characteristics of 138 Hospitalized Patients With 2019 Novel Coronavirus-Infected Pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA, 323:1061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Z-YD, Liang K, Shetty AK (2023). Complications of COVID-19 on the Central Nervous System: Mechanics and Potential Treatment for Easing Long COVID. Aging Dis, 14:1492-1510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10529748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37163427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L-q, Huang T, Wang Y-q, Wang Z-p, Liang Y, Huang T-b, et al.. (2020). COVID-19 patients' clinical characteristics, discharge rate, and fatality rate of meta-analysis. J Med Virol, 92:577-583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32162702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Xu X, Chen Z, Duan J, Hashimoto K, Yang L, et al.. (2020). Nervous system involvement after infection with COVID-19 and other coronaviruses. Brain Behav Immun, 87:18-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32240762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmer D, Gilbert M, Borman R, Clark KL (2002). Quantitative mRNA expression profiling of ACE 2, a novel homologue of angiotensin converting enzyme. FEBS Lett, 532:107-110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12459472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurendon T, Radulesco T, Mugnier J, G&#xe9;rault M, Chagnaud C, Ahmadi A-AE, et al.. (2020). Bilateral transient olfactory bulb edema during COVID-19-related anosmia. Neurology, 95:224-225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32444492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J, Radke J, Dittmayer C, Franz J, Thomas C, Mothes R, et al.. (2021). Olfactory transmucosal SARS-CoV-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with COVID-19. Nat Neurosci, 24:168-175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xydakis MS, Albers MW, Holbrook EH, Lyon DM, Shih RY, Frasnelli JA, et al.. (2021). Post-viral effects of COVID-19 in the olfactory system and their implications. Lancet Neurol, 20:753-761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8324113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seehusen F, Clark JJ, Sharma P, Bentley EG, Kirby A, Subramaniam K, et al.. (2022). Neuroinvasion and Neurotropism by SARS-CoV-2 Variants in the K18-hACE2 Mouse. Viruses, 14:1020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9146514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35632761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckman D, Bonillas A, Diniz GB, Ott S, Roh JW, Elizaldi SR, et al.. (2022). SARS-CoV-2 infects neurons and induces neuroinflammation in a non-human primate model of COVID-19. Cell Rep, 41:111573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9554328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36288725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston M, Zakharov A, Papaiconomou C, Salmasi G, Armstrong D (2004). Evidence of connections between cerebrospinal fluid and nasal lymphatic vessels in humans, non-human primates and other mammalian species. Cerebrospinal Fluid Res, 1:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC546409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15679948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zakharov A, Papaiconomou C, Koh L, Djenic J, Bozanovic-Sosic R, Johnston M (2004). Integrating the roles of extracranial lymphatics and intracranial veins in cerebrospinal fluid absorption in sheep. Microvasc Res, 67:96-104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14709407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brann DH, Tsukahara T, Weinreb C, Lipovsek M, Van den Berge K, Gong B, et al.. (2020). Non-neuronal expression of SARS-CoV-2 entry genes in the olfactory system suggests mechanisms underlying COVID-19-associated anosmia. Sci Adv, 6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10715684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32937591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achar A, Ghosh C (2020). COVID-19-Associated Neurological Disorders: The Potential Route of CNS Invasion and Blood-Brain Barrier Relevance. Cells, 9:2360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7692725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33120941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paniz-Mondolfi A, Bryce C, Grimes Z, Gordon RE, Reidy J, Lednicky J, et al.. (2020). Central nervous system involvement by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2). J Med Virol, 92:699-702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32314810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds JL, Mahajan SD (2021). SARS-COV2 Alters Blood Brain Barrier Integrity Contributing to Neuro-Inflammation. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol, 16:4-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7786155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33405097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson MA, Logsdon AF, Rhea EM, Hansen KM, Holden SJ, Banks WA, et al.. (2023). Blood-brain barrier penetration of non-replicating SARS-CoV-2 and S1 variants of concern induce neuroinflammation which is accentuated in a mouse model of Alzheimer's disease. Brain Behav Immun, 109:251-268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9867649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36682515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen W-B, Elahi M, Logue J, Yang P, Baracco L, Reece EA, et al..2022. SARS-CoV-2 invades cognitive centers of the brain and induces Alzheimer&#x2019;s-like neuropathology. bioRxiv.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Laurent S, Onur OA, Kleineberg NN, Fink GR, Schweitzer F, et al.. (2021). A systematic review of neurological symptoms and complications of COVID-19. J Neurol, 268:392-402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7370630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32691236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez-Garc&#xed;a LA, Carrillo-Ruiz JD, Solleiro-Villavicencio H (2023). Editorial: Short and long-term sequelae within the central nervous system due to COVID-19. Front Cell Neurosci, 17:1146839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9941658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36824312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV, Jayadevan R, Sashidharan S (2021). Long COVID: An overview. Erratum in: Diabetes Metab Syndr, 15: 869-875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Kapur S, Alberts J, Badley AD, Decker GA, et al.. (2021). Multi-organ impairment in low-risk individuals with long COVID. BMJ Open, 11:e048391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemanno F, Houdayer E, Parma A, Spina A, Forno AD, Scatolini A, et al.. (2021). COVID-19 cognitive deficits after respiratory assistance in the subacute phase: A COVID-rehabilitation unit experience. PLoS One, 16:e0246590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7870071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33556127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ (2021). Persistent Brainstem Dysfunction in Long-COVID: A Hypothesis. ACS Chem Neurosci, 12:573-580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ (2023). Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol, 21:133-146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sis&#xf3;-Almirall A, Brito-Zer&#xf3;n P, Conangla Ferr&#xed;n L, Kostov B, Moragas Moreno A, Mestres J, et al.. (2021). Long Covid-19: Proposed Primary Care Clinical Guidelines for Diagnosis and Disease Management. Int J Environ Res Public Health, 18:4350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33923972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ (2021). Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond), 53:737-754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodali M, Parihar VK, Hattiangady B, Mishra V, Shuai B, Shetty AK (2015). Resveratrol Prevents Age-Related Memory and Mood Dysfunction with Increased Hippocampal Neurogenesis and Microvasculature and Reduced Glial Activation. Sci Rep, 5:8075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4894403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25627672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodali M, Hattiangady B, Shetty GA, Bates A, Shuai B, Shetty AK (2018). Curcumin treatment leads to better cognitive and mood function in a model of Gulf War Illness with enhanced neurogenesis, and alleviation of inflammation and mitochondrial dysfunction in the hippocampus. Brain Behav Immun, 69:499-514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7023905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29454881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodali M, Mishra V, Hattiangady B, Attaluri S, Gonzalez JJ, Shuai B, et al.. (2021). Moderate, intermittent voluntary exercise in a model of Gulf War Illness improves cognitive and mood function with alleviation of activated microglia and astrocytes, and enhanced neurogenesis in the hippocampus. Brain Behav Immun, 97:135-149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9885810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34245811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madhu LN, Somayaji Y, Shetty AK (2022). Promise of irisin to attenuate cognitive dysfunction in aging and Alzheimer's disease. Ageing Res Rev, 78:101637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9844023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35504553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S-W, Jin Y, Shin J-H, Kim I-D, Lee H-K, Park S, et al.. (2012). Glycyrrhizic acid affords robust neuroprotection in the postischemic brain via anti-inflammatory effect by inhibiting HMGB1 phosphorylation and secretion. Neurobiol Dis, 46:147-156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22266336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lay&#xe9; S, Nadjar A, Joffre C, Bazinet RP (2018). Anti-Inflammatory Effects of Omega-3 Fatty Acids in the Brain: Physiological Mechanisms and Relevance to Pharmacology. Pharmacol Rev, 70:12-38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29217656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almazan A, Pallares JG, Buendia-Romero A, Martinez-Cava A, Franco-Lopez F, Sanchez-Alcaraz Martinez BJ, et al.. (2021). Post-COVID-19 Syndrome and the Potential Benefits of Exercise. Int J Environ Res Public Health, 18:5329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8156194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34067776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhya R, Shetty AK (2021). Extracellular Vesicles for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Parkinson's Disease. Aging Dis, 12:1438-1450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8407884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34527420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Casta&#xf1;eda A, Lu P, Geraghty AC, Song E, Lee M-H, Wood J, et al.. (2022). Mild respiratory COVID can cause multi-lineage neural cell and myelin dysregulation. Cell, 185:2452-2468.e16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9189143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35768006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villeda SA, Luo J, Mosher KI, Zou B, Britschgi M, Bieri G, et al.. (2011). The ageing systemic milieu negatively regulates neurogenesis and cognitive function. Nature, 477:90-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21886162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA, Akbari A, Emami A, Lotfi M, Rostamihosseinkhani M, Nemati H, et al.. (2022). Long COVID syndrome-associated brain fog. J Med Virol, 94:979-984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babkina AS, Yadgarov MY, Lyubomudrov MA, Ostrova IV, Volkov AV, Kuzovlev AN, et al.. (2023). Morphologic Findings in the Cerebral Cortex in COVID-19: Association of Microglial Changes with Clinical and Demographic Variables. Biomedicines, 11:1407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10216380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37239078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves VS, Santos SACS, Leite-Aguiar R, Paiva-Pereira E, dos Reis RR, Calazans ML, et al.. (2023). SARS-CoV-2 Spike protein alters microglial purinergic signaling. Front Immunol, 14:1158460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10126242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37114062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe4;ufer C, Schreiber CS, Hartke A-S, Denden I, Stanelle-Bertram S, Beck S, et al.. (2022). Microgliosis and neuronal proteinopathy in brain persist beyond viral clearance in SARS-CoV-2 hamster model. EBioMedicine, 79:103999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9013202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35439679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksson PS, Perfilieva E, Bjork-Eriksson T, Alborn AM, Nordborg C, Peterson DA, et al.. (1998). Neurogenesis in the adult human hippocampus. Nat Med, 4:1313-1317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9809557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hattiangady B, Shetty AK (2008). Implications of decreased hippocampal neurogenesis in chronic temporal lobe epilepsy. Epilepsia, 49:26-41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3612505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18522598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muddanna S, Rao BH, Shetty AK. (2008). Status Epilepticus During Old Age is not Associated With Enhanced Hippocampal Neurogenesis. Hippocampus, 18:931-944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3612499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18493929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boldrini M, Fulmore CA, Tartt AN, Simeon LR, Pavlova I, Poposka V, et al.. (2018). Human Hippocampal Neurogenesis Persists throughout Aging. Cell Stem Cell, 22:589-599.e585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5957089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29625071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Jim&#xe9;nez EP, Flor-Garc&#xed;a M, Terreros-Roncal J, R&#xe1;bano A, Cafini F, Pallas-Bazarra N, et al.. (2019). Adult hippocampal neurogenesis is abundant in neurologically healthy subjects and drops sharply in patients with Alzheimer's disease. Nat Med, 25:554-560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30911133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Su Y, Li S, Kennedy BC, Zhang DY, Bond AM, et al.. (2022). Molecular landscapes of human hippocampal immature neurons across lifespan. Nature, 607:527-533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9316413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35794479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parihar VK, Hattiangady B, Kuruba R, Shuai B, Shetty AK (2011). Predictable chronic mild stress improves mood, hippocampal neurogenesis and memory. Mol Psychiatry, 16:171-183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2891880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20010892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodali M, Megahed T, Mishra V, Shuai B, Hattiangady B, Shetty AK (2016). Voluntary Running Exercise-Mediated Enhanced Neurogenesis Does Not Obliterate Retrograde Spatial Memory. J Neurosci, 36:8112-8122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6601951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27488632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller SM, Sahay A (2019). Functions of adult-born neurons in hippocampal memory interference and indexing. Nat Neurosci, 22:1565-1575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7397477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31477897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y-D, Luo Y-J, Chen Z-K, Quintanilla L, Cherasse Y, Zhang L, et al.. (2022). Hypothalamic modulation of adult hippocampal neurogenesis in mice confers activity-dependent regulation of memory and anxiety-like behavior. Nat Neurosci, 25:630-645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9287980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35524139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tartt AN, Mariani MB, Hen R, Mann JJ, Boldrini M (2022). Dysregulation of adult hippocampal neuroplasticity in major depression: pathogenesis and therapeutic implications. Mol Psychiatry, 27:2689-2699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9167750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35354926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monje ML, Toda H, Palmer TD (2003). Inflammatory Blockade Restores Adult Hippocampal Neurogenesis. Science, 302:1760-1765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14615545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parajuli B, Horiuchi H, Mizuno T, Takeuchi H, Suzumura A (2015). CCL11 enhances excitotoxic neuronal death by producing reactive oxygen species in microglia. Glia, 63:2274-2284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26184677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolopoulos D, Manolakou T, Polissidis A, Filia A, Bertsias G, Koutmani Y, et al.. (2023). Microglia activation in the presence of intact blood-brain barrier and disruption of hippocampal neurogenesis via IL-6 and IL-18 mediate early diffuse neuropsychiatric lupus. Ann Rheum Dis, 82:646-657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10176423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36898766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soung AL, Vanderheiden A, Nordvig AS, Sissoko CA, Canoll P, Mariani MB, et al.. (2022). COVID-19 induces CNS cytokine expression and loss of hippocampal neurogenesis. Brain, 145:4193-4201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9452175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36004663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayat A-H, Azimi H, Hassani Moghaddam M, Ebrahimi V, Fathi M, Vakili K, et al.. (2022). COVID-19 causes neuronal degeneration and reduces neurogenesis in human hippocampus. Apoptosis, 27:852-868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9310365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35876935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malberg JE (2004). Implications of adult hippocampal neurogenesis in antidepressant action. J Psychiatry Neuroscie, 29:196-205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC400689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15173896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malberg JE, Schechter LE (2005). Increasing Hippocampal Neurogenesis: A Novel Mechanism for Antidepressant Drugs. Curr Pharm Des, 11:145-155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15638755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil JMAC, Mohapel P, Ara&#xfa;jo IM, Popovic N, Li J-Y, Brundin P, et al.. (2005). Reduced hippocampal neurogenesis in R6/2 transgenic Huntington's disease mice. Neurobiol Dis, 20:744-751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15951191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Canabal A (2014). Reconsidering hippocampal neurogenesis in Alzheimer's disease. Front Neurosci, 8:147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4052799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24966809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marxreiter F, Regensburger M, Winkler J (2013). Adult neurogenesis in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Cell Mol Life Sci, 70:459-473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11113680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22766974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoharides TC, Cholevas C, Polyzoidis K, Politis A (2021). Long-COVID syndrome-associated brain fog and chemofog: Luteolin to the rescue. Biofactors, 47:232-241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33847020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fajnzylber J, Regan J, Coxen K, Corry H, Wong C, Rosenthal A, et al.. (2020). SARS-CoV-2 viral load is associated with increased disease severity and mortality. Nat Commun, 11:5493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7603483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33127906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kempuraj D, Selvakumar GP, Ahmed ME, Raikwar SP, Thangavel R, Khan A, et al.. (2020). COVID-19, Mast Cells, Cytokine Storm, Psychological Stress, and Neuroinflammation. Neuroscientist, 26:402-414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32684080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy-O&#x2019;Reilly M, Ritzel RM, Conway SE, Staff I, Fortunato G, McCullough LD (2017). CCL11 (Eotaxin-1) Levels Predict Long-Term Functional Outcomes in Patients Following Ischemic Stroke. Transl Stroke Res, 8:578-584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5648599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28634890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherry JD, Stein TD, Tripodis Y, Alvarez VE, Huber BR, Au R, et al.. (2017). CCL11 is increased in the CNS in chronic traumatic encephalopathy but not in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. PLoS One, 12:e0185541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5614644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28950005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu D, Zhou J, Bi H, Li L, Gao W, Huang M, et al.. (2014). CCL11 as a potential diagnostic marker for asthma? J Asthma, 51:847-854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24796647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huibregtse ME, Ejima K, Chen Z, Kalbfell RM, Koppineni A, Kawata K (2020). Acute Time-Course Changes in CCL11, CCL2, and IL-10 Levels After Controlled Subconcussive Head Impacts: A Pilot Randomized Clinical Trial. J Head Trauma Rehabil, 35:308-316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32881764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang M-C, Chung R-H, Lin P-H, Kuo H-W, Liu T-H, Chen Y-Y, et al.. (2022). Increase in plasma CCL11 (Eotaxin-1) in patients with alcohol dependence and changes during detoxification. Brain Behav Immun, 99:83-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34571176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng W, Aimone JB, Gage FH (2010). New neurons and new memories: how does adult hippocampal neurogenesis affect learning and memory? Nat Rev Neurosci, 11:339-350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2886712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20354534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahay A, Hen R (2007). Adult hippocampal neurogenesis in depression. Nat Neurosci, 10:1110-1115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17726477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera A, Vanzuli I, Julio Rodr&#xed;guez Arellano J, Butt A (2016). Decreased Regenerative Capacity of Oligodendrocyte Progenitor Cells (NG2-Glia) in the Ageing Brain: A Vicious Cycle of Synaptic Dysfunction, Myelin Loss and Neuronal Disruption? Curr Alzheimer Res, 13:413-418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26567743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haroutunian V, Katsel P, Roussos P, Davis KL, Altshuler LL, Bartzokis G (2014). Myelination, oligodendrocytes, and serious mental illness. Glia, 62:1856-1877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25056210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal M, He C, Siddiqui J, Wei JT, Macoska JA (2013). CCL11 (eotaxin-1): A new diagnostic serum marker for prostate cancer. Prostate, 73:573-581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3594486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23059958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Holsinger RMD (2018). Exercise-induced brain-derived neurotrophic factor expression: Therapeutic implications for Alzheimer's dementia. Ageing Res Rev, 48:109-121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30326283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wuerch E, Lozinski B, Yong VW (2021). MedXercise: a promising strategy to promote remyelination. Curr Opin Pharmacol, 61:120-126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34688996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graciani AL, Gutierre MU, Coppi AA, Arida RM, Gutierre RC (2023). Myelin, aging, and physical exercise. Neurobiol Aging, 127:70-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37116408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>