<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38666878</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2079-7737</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biology (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>From Psychostasis to the Discovery of Cardiac Nerves: The Origins of the Modern Cardiac Neuromodulation Concept.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">266</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/biology13040266</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This review explores the historical development of cardiology knowledge, from ancient Egyptian psychostasis to the modern comprehension of cardiac neuromodulation. In ancient Egyptian religion, psychostasis was the ceremony in which the deceased was judged before gaining access to the afterlife. This ritual was also known as the "weighing of the heart" or "weighing of the soul". The Egyptians believed that the heart, not the brain, was the seat of human wisdom, emotions, and memory. They were the first to recognize the cardiocentric nature of the body, identifying the heart as the center of the circulatory system. Aristotle (fourth century BC) considered the importance of the heart in human physiology in his philosophical analyses. For Galen (third century AD), the heart muscle was the site of the vital spirit, which regulated body temperature. Cardiology knowledge advanced significantly in the 15th century, coinciding with Leonardo da Vinci and Vesalius's pioneering anatomical and physiological studies. It was William Harvey, in the 17th century, who introduced the concept of cardiac circulation. Servet's research and Marcello Malpighi's discovery of arterioles and capillaries provided a more detailed understanding of circulation. Richard Lower emerged as the foremost pioneer of experimental cardiology in the late 17th century. He demonstrated the heart's neural control by tying off the vagus nerve. In 1753, Albrecht von Haller, a professor at G&#xf6;ttingen, was the first to discover the heart's automaticity and the excitation of muscle fibers. Towards the end of the 18th century, Antonio Scarpa challenged the theories of Albrecht von Haller and Johann Bernhard Jacob Behrends, who maintained that the myocardium possessed its own "irritability", on which the heartbeat depended, and was independent of neuronal sensitivity. Instead, Scarpa argued that the heart required innervation to maintain life, refuting Galenic notions. In contemporary times, the study of cardiac innervation has regained prominence, particularly in understanding the post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2) infection (PASC), which frequently involves cardiorespiratory symptoms and dysregulation of the intrinsic cardiac innervation. Recently, it has been recognized that post-acute sequelae of acute respiratory infections (ARIs) due to other pathogens can also be a cause of long-term vegetative and somatic symptoms. Understanding cardiac innervation and modulation can help to recognize and treat long COVID and long non-COVID-19 (coronavirus disease 2019) ARIs. This analysis explores the historical foundations of cardiac neuromodulation and its contemporary relevance. By focusing on this concept, we aim to bridge the gap between historical understanding and modern applications. This will illuminate the complex interplay between cardiac function, neural modulation, cardiovascular health, and disease management in the context of long-term cardiorespiratory symptoms and dysregulation of intrinsic cardiac innervations.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paradiso</LastName><ForeName>Beatrice</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4319-4832</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lino Rossi Research Center, Department of Biomedical, Surgical and Dental Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Surgery, University of Milan, 20122 Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Consultant Cyto/Histopathologist (Anatomic Pathologist) Anatomic Pathology Unit, Dolo Hospital Venice, 30031 Dolo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pauza</LastName><ForeName>Dainius H</ForeName><Initials>DH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Institute of Anatomy, Lithuanian University of Health Sciences Kaunas, 44307 Kaunas, Lithuania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Limback</LastName><ForeName>Clara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oxford University Hospitals, NHS Trust, Oxford OX3 7JH, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ottaviani</LastName><ForeName>Giulia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6982-170X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lino Rossi Research Center, Department of Biomedical, Surgical and Dental Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Surgery, University of Milan, 20122 Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical, Surgical and Dental Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Surgery, University of Milan, 20122 Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, McGovern Medical School, University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, Houston, TX 77054, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thiene</LastName><ForeName>Gaetano</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8814-2577</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Pathology, Department of Cardiac, Thoracic, Vascular Sciences and Public Health, University of Padua, 35122 Padua, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Biology (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101587988</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2079-7737</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autonomic nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac innervations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac neuromodulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polyvagal theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychostasis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38666878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11047897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biology13040266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">biology13040266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ziskind B., Halioua B. La conception du coeur dans l&#x2019;Egypte ancienne (Concepts of the heart in Ancient Egypt) Med. Sci. 2004;20:367&#x2013;373. doi: 10.1051/medsci/2004203367. (In French)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/medsci/2004203367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15067585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziskind B. L&#x2019;examen cardiovasculaire a la lumi&#xe8;re des papyrus m&#xe9;dicaux de l&#x2019;Egypte ancienne (The cardiovascular examination in the light of the medical papyruses of old Egypt) Hist. Sci. Med. 2006;40:61&#x2013;68. (In French)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17152598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritner R.K. The cardiovascular system in ancient Egyptian thought. J. Near East. Stud. 2006;65:99&#x2013;109. doi: 10.1086/504985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/504985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stern L.C. In: Papyros Ebers: Das hermetische Buch &#xfc;ber die Arzeneimittel der alten &#xc4;gypter in hieratischer Schrift, herausgegeben mit Inhaltsangabe und Einleitung versehen von Georg Ebers, mit Hieroglyphisch-Lateinischem Glossar von Ludwig Stern, mit Unterst&#xfc;tzung des. 1st ed. Ebers G., editor. Volume 2. W. Englemann; Leipzig, Germany: 1875. (In German)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bardinet T. Les Papyrus M&#xe9;dicaux de l&#x2019;&#xc9;gypte Pharaonique. Fayard; Paris, France: 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loukas M., Youssef P., Gielecki J., Walocha J., Natsis K., Tubbs R.S. History of cardiac anatomy: A comprehensive review from the Egyptians to today. Clin. Anat. 2016;29:270&#x2013;284. doi: 10.1002/ca.22705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ca.22705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26918296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallis E.A. The Book of the Dead. The Papyrus of Ani. In the British Museum. The Egyptian Text with Interlinear Transliteration and Translation, a Running Translation, Introduction, etc. by Late keeper of Assyrian and Egyptian Antiquities in the British Museum. The British Museum; London, UK: 1895.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandon S.G.F. The Weighing of the Soul. In: Kitagawa J.M., Long C.H., editors. Myths and Symbols: Studies in Honor of Mircea Eliade. Chicago University Press; Chicago, IL, USA: 1969. pp. 91&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandon S.G.F. The Judgment of the Dead. An Historical and Comparative Study of the Idea of a Post-Mortem Judgment in the Major Religions. Weidenfeld and Nicolson; London, UK: 1967. p. 300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howes L. Ph.D. Thesis. University of Pretoria; Pretoria, South Africa: 2012. The Sayings Gospel Q within the Contexts of the Third and Renewed Quests for the Historical Jesus: Wisdom and Apocalypticism in the First Century.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham L.D. A Life in the Balance: Divine Judgement by Weighing. 2023.  [(accessed on 8 August 2023)].  Available online:  https://www.academia.edu/97194319/A_life_in_the_balance_Divine_judgement_by_weighing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Iliad Translated by Robert Fitzgerald with Drawings. Anchor Press/Doubleday Garden City; New York, NY, USA: 1974. Erni, H.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Judgment of Zeus: B.C. Dietrich Source: Rheinisches Museum f&#xfc;r Philologie, Neue Folge. J.D. Sauerl&#xe4;nders Verlag; Frankfurt, Germany: 1964. pp. 97&#x2013;125. 107. Bd., 2. H.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitagawa J.M., Long C.H., Brauer J.C., Hodgson M.G.S. Studies in Honor of Mircea Eliade. The University of Chicago Press; Chicago, IL, USA: 1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Qur&#x2019;an. Progressive Muslims Organization; Los Angeles, CA, USA: 2015. (In Arabic)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luke 21:34. Biblica; Palmer Lake, CO, USA: 2011. Bible New International Version (NIV)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthew 11:28-30. Biblica; Palmer Lake, CO, USA: 2011. Bible New International Version (NIV)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Eucharistic Miracles of the World, by Blessed Carlo Acutis.  [(accessed on 8 August 2023)].  Available online:  https://www.miracolieucaristici.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasuti N. The Eucharistic Miracle of Lanciano: Historical, Theological, Scientific and Photographic Documentation. Litografia Botolini Publisher; Lanciano, Italy: 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Histological, immunological and biochemiccal studies on the flesh and blood of the eucharistic miracle of Lanciano (8th century) Quad. Sclavo Diagn. 1971;7:661&#x2013;674. (In Italian)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4950729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H.E., McCorkell L., Vogel J.M., Topol E.J. Long COVID: Major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146. doi: 10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2. Erratum in Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2023, 21, 408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulze H., Charles James J., Trampe N., Richter D., Pakeerathan T., Siems N., Ayzenberg I., Gold R., Faissner S. Cross-sectional analysis of clinical aspects in patients with long-COVID and post-COVID syndrome. Front. Neurol. 2022;13:979152. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2022.979152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2022.979152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9614029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36313487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vecchio E., Gallicchio L., Caporusso N., Recchia V., Didonna L., Pezzuto G., Pisani L., Petruzzellis A., Delmonte V., Tamma F. Neurophysiological Aspects in SARS-CoV-2-Induced Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome. Front. Neurol. 2022;13:868538. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2022.868538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2022.868538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9149271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35651341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jareonsettasin P., Zeicu C., Diehl B., Harper R.M., Astin R. Inappropriate Ventilatory Homeostatic Responses in Hospitalized COVID-19 Patients. Front. Neurol. 2022;13:909915. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2022.909915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2022.909915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9240262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35785338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques K.C., Quaresma J.A.S., Falc&#xe3;o L.F.M. Cardiovascular autonomic dysfunction in &#x201c;Long COVID&#x201d;: Pathophysiology, heart rate variability, and inflammatory markers. Front. Cardiovasc. Med. 2023;10:1256512. doi: 10.3389/fcvm.2023.1256512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2023.1256512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10502909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37719983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shouman K., Vanichkachorn G., Cheshire W.P., Suarez M.D., Shelly S., Lamotte G.J., Sandroni P., Benarroch E.E., Berini S.E., Cutsforth-Gregory J.K., et al. Autonomic dysfunction following COVID-19 infection: An early experience. Clin. Auton. Res. 2021;31:385&#x2013;394. doi: 10.1007/s10286-021-00803-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10286-021-00803-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8050227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33860871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camus A. The Myth of Sisyphus and Other Essays. Alfred A. Knopf; New York, NY, USA: 1955. Translation originally published by Alfred A. Knopf, 1955 p 95. Originally published in France as Le Mythe de Sisyphe by Librairie Gallimard, 1942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts W., Salandy S., Mandal G., Holda M.K., Tomaszewksi K.A., Jerzy Gielecki R., Tubbs S., Loukas M. Across the centuries: Piecing together the anatomy of the heart. Transl. Res. Anat. 2019;17:100051. doi: 10.1016/j.tria.2019.100051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tria.2019.100051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoja M.M., Tubbs R.S., Loukas M., Ardalan M.R. The Aristotelian account of &#x201c;heart and veins&#x201d;. Int. J. Cardiol. 2008;125:304&#x2013;310. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2007.07.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2007.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17662491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsagkaris C., Kalachanis K., Iakovis P., Androutsos G., Karamanou M. Heart in the work of the eminent Greek philosopher and physician Aristotle (384&#x2013;322 BC) Arch. Balk. Med. Union. 2020;55:728&#x2013;730. doi: 10.31688/ABMU.2020.55.4.24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31688/ABMU.2020.55.4.24</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer W.G. Celsus De Medicina. Harvard University Press; Cambridge, MA, USA: 1971. Republication of the 1935 edition.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey W. Exercitatio Anatomica de Motu Cordis et Sanguinis in Animalibus. Sumptibus Guilielmi Fitzeri; Frankfurt-am-Main, Germany: 1628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aird W.C. Discovery of the cardiovascular system: From Galen to William Harvey. J. Thromb. Haemost. 2011;1:118&#x2013;129. doi: 10.1111/j.1538-7836.2011.04312.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1538-7836.2011.04312.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21781247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bragazzi N.L., Raffi A., Siri A., Tornali C., Martini M. La Medicina del Rinascimento e la Scoperta della Circolazione Minore: Il Ruolo di Michele Serveto (1511&#x2013;1553) (Renaissance Medicine and the Discovery of the Lesser Circulation: The Role of Michael Servetus (1511&#x2013;1553)) Acta Med. Hist. Adriat. 2017;15:271&#x2013;282. doi: 10.31952/amha.15.2.5. (In Italian)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31952/amha.15.2.5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29402117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forrester J.M. Malpighi&#x2019;s De polypo cordis: An annotated translation. Med. Hist. 1995;39:477&#x2013;492. doi: 10.1017/S0025727300060385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0025727300060385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1037031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8558994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortazavi M.M., Adeeb N., Latif B., Watanabe K., Deep A., Griessenauer C.J., Tubbs R.S., Fukushima T. Gabriele Fallopio (1523&#x2013;1562) and his contributions to the development of medicine and anatomy. Childs Nerv. Syst. 2013;29:877&#x2013;880. doi: 10.1007/s00381-012-1921-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-012-1921-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22965774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn P.M. Andreas Vesalius (1514&#x2013;1564), Padua, and the fetal &#x201c;shunts&#x201d;. Arch. Dis. Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2003;88:F157&#x2013;F159. doi: 10.1136/fn.88.2.F157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/fn.88.2.F157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1721528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12598509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklin K.J. The work of Richard Lower (1631&#x2013;1691) Proc. R. Soc. Med. 1932;25:113&#x2013;118. doi: 10.1177/003591573102500201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/003591573102500201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2182696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19988408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lower R. Cap I Cordis Anatome in Tractatus de Corde. Open Library; London, UK: 1669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tubbs R.S., Loukas M., Shoja M.M., Ardalan M.R., Oakes W.J. Richard Lower (1631&#x2013;1691) and his early contributions to cardiology. Int. J. Cardiol. 2008;128:17&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2007.11.069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2007.11.069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18201782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoff H.E. Vagal Stimulation before the Webers. Ann. Med. Hist. 1936;8:138&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7939828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33943495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Haller A. Elementa Physiologiae Corporis Humani. Biodiversity Heritage Library; Lausanne, Switzerland: 1757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dissertatio qua Demonstratur cor Nervis Career Addita Disquisitione de ve Nervorum Arterias Cingentium, by Johann Behrends, 1792, Box: 1, Folder: 1. Dissertatio qua Demonstratur cor Nervis Career Addita Disquisitione de ve Nervorum Arterias Cingentium/Johann Bernhard Jacob Behrends, MS C 221. Archives and Modern Manuscripts Collection.  [(accessed on 8 April 2024)]; Available online:  https://findingaids.nlm.nih.gov/repositories/4/archival_objects/507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plate 4 from Antonio Scarpa&#x2019;s Tabulae Nevrologicae.  [(accessed on 8 August 2023)]; Available online:  https://www.nlm.nih.gov/exhibition/historicalanatomies/scarpa_home.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee R. On the Ganglia and Nerves of the Heart. Philos. Trans. R. Soc. Lond. 1849;139:43&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaskell W.H. On the tonicity of the heart and blood vessels. J. Physiol. 1880;3:48. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.1880.sp000083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.1880.sp000083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1484826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16991305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terni T. Ricerche anatomiche sul sistema nervoso autonomo degli Uccelli. Arch. Ital. Anat. Embriol. 1923;20:433&#x2013;510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiene G., Paradiso B., Zanatta A., Basso C., Zampieri F. Tullio Terni (1888&#x2013;1946): The life of a neurocardioanatomist with a tragic epilogue. Int. J. Cardiol. 2019;289:153&#x2013;156. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2019.01.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2019.01.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30718136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olshansky B., Sabbah H.N., Hauptman P.J., Colucci W.S. Parasympathetic nervous system and heart failure: Pathophysiology and potential implications for therapy. Circulation. 2008;118:863&#x2013;871. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.107.760405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.107.760405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18711023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taggart P. Brain-heart interactions and cardiac ventricular arrhythmias. Neth. Heart J. 2013;21:78&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1007/s12471-012-0365-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12471-012-0365-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3547423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23239449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapa S., Venkatachalam K.L., Asirvatham S.J. The Autonomic Nervous System in Cardiac Electrophysiology. An Elegant Interaction and Emerging Concepts. Cardiol. Rev. 2010;18:275&#x2013;284. doi: 10.1097/CRD.0b013e3181ebb152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0b013e3181ebb152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20926936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physiological Researches upon Life and Death Bichat, Xavier, 1771&#x2013;1802. Smith &amp; Maxwell; Philadelphia, PA, USA: 1809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber E. Muskelbewegung. In: Wagner R., editor. Handworterbuch der Physiologie. Friedrich Vieweg; Braunschweig, Germany: 1846. pp. 1&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoff H.E. The History of vagal inhibition. Bull. Hist. Med. 1940;8:461&#x2013;496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fye W.B. Profiles in cardiology. Ernst, Wilhelm, and Eduard Weber. Clin. Cardiol. 2000;23:709&#x2013;710. doi: 10.1002/clc.4960230915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/clc.4960230915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6655061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11016024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stelling C. Experimentelle Untersuchungen &#xfc;ber den Einfluss des Nervus Depressor auf die Herzth&#xe4;tigkeit und den Blutdruck: Inaug. Diss. (Mit 1 lith. Taf.) Laakmann; Nottuln, Germany: 1867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard C. Le&#xe7;ons sur la Physiologie et la Pathologie du Syst&#xe8;me Nerveux. Volume 2 J.-B. Bailli&#xe8;re; Paris, France: 1858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown-S&#xe9;quard C.-&#xc9;. Experimental researches applied to physiology and pathology. Med. Exam. 1852;16:481&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10306739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38121219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cyon E., Ludwig C. Die Reflexe eines der sensiblen Nerven des Herzens auf die motorischen der Blutgef&#xe4;sse. Berichte &#xfc;ber die Verhandlungen der K&#xf6;niglich S&#xe4;chsischen Gesellschaft der Wissenschaften zu Leipzig. Math. Phys. Cl. 1866;18:307&#x2013;328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hering H.E. Die Karotissinusreflexe auf Herz und Gef&#xe4;sse vom Normalphysiologischen, Pathologisch-Physiologischen und Klinischen Standpunkt. Steinkopff; Dresden, Germany: 1927.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst J.W., Fye W.B., Zimmer H.G. Heinrich Ewald Hering and the carotid sinus reflex. Clin. Cardiol. 2004;27:485&#x2013;486. doi: 10.1002/clc.4960270813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/clc.4960270813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6654717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15346848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maehle A.H. &#x201c;Receptive substances&#x201d;: John Newport Langley (1852&#x2013;1925) and his path to a receptor theory of drug action. Med. Hist. 2004;48:153&#x2013;174. doi: 10.1017/S0025727300000090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0025727300000090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC546337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15151102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Euler U.S.V. A Specific Sympathomimetic Ergone in Adrenergic Nerve Fibres (Sympathin) and its Relations to Adrenaline and Nor-Adrenaline. Acta Physiol. Scand. 1946;12:73&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1111/j.1748-1716.1946.tb00368.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.1946.tb00368.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benarroch E.E. Central autonomic control. In: Robertson D., Biaggioni I., Burnstock G., Low P.A., Paton J.F.R., editors. Primer on the Autonomic Nervous System. Academic Press; Waltham, MA, USA: 2012. pp. 9&#x2013;12. Chapter 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C., Raven E.P., Duyn J.H. Brain&#x2013;heart interactions: Challenges and opportunities with functional magnetic resonance imaging at ultra-high field. Philos. Trans. R. Soc. A. 2016;374:20150188. doi: 10.1098/rsta.2015.0188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rsta.2015.0188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4822447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27044994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armour J.A. The little brain on the heart. Cleve Clin. J. Med. 2007;74:S48&#x2013;S51. doi: 10.3949/ccjm.74.Suppl_1.S48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3949/ccjm.74.Suppl_1.S48</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17455544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armour J.A. Potential clinical relevance of the &#x2018;little brain&#x2019; on the mammalian heart. Exp. Physiol. 2008;93:165&#x2013;176. doi: 10.1113/expphysiol.2007.041178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/expphysiol.2007.041178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17981929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardell J.L., Armour J.A. Neurocardiology: Structure-Based Function. Compr. Physiol. 2016;6:1635&#x2013;1653. doi: 10.1002/cphy.c150046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cphy.c150046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27783854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardell J.L., Andresen M.C., Armour J.A., Billman G.E., Chen P.S., Foreman R.D., Herring N., O&#x2019;Leary D.S., Sabbah H.N., Schultz H.D., et al. Translational neurocardiology: Preclinical models and cardioneural integrative aspects. J. Physiol. 2016;594:3877&#x2013;3909. doi: 10.1113/JP271869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP271869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4945715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27098459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Z., Powley T.L. Nucleus ambiguus projections to cardiac ganglia of rat atria: An anterograde tracing study. J. Comp. Neurol. 2000;424:588&#x2013;606. doi: 10.1002/1096-9861(20000904)424:4&lt;588::AID-CNE3&gt;3.0.CO;2-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1096-9861(20000904)424:4&lt;588::AID-CNE3&gt;3.0.CO;2-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10931483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones J.F. Vagal control of the rat heart. Exp. Physiol. 2001;86:797&#x2013;801. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-445X.2001.tb00047.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-445X.2001.tb00047.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11698976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coote J.H. Myths and realities of the cardiac vagus. J. Physiol. 2013;591:4073&#x2013;4085. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2013.257758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2013.257758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3779103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23878363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riemer H.J.A., Slart Ren&#xe9; A.T., Elsinga P.H., Schwaiger M. Autonomic Innervation of the Heart. Role of Molecular Imaging. Springer-Verlag; Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palma J.A., Benarroch E.E. Neural control of heart: Recent concepts and clinical correlations. Neurology. 2014;83:261&#x2013;271. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0000000000000605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000000605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24928126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanna P., Rajendran P.S., Ajijola O.A., Vaseghi M., Andrew Armour J., Ardell J.L., Shivkumar K. Cardiac neuroanatomy&#x2014;Imaging nerves to define functional control. Auton. Neurosci. 2017;207:48&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1016/j.autneu.2017.07.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2017.07.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5680093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28802636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanna P., Dacey M.J., Brennan J., Moss A., Robbins S., Achanta S., Biscola N.P., Swid M.A., Rajendran P.S., Mori S., et al. Innervation and Neuronal Control of the Mammalian Sinoatrial Node a Comprehensive Atlas. Circ. Res. 2021;128:1279&#x2013;1296. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.120.318458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.120.318458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8284939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33629877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakatta E.G., Maltsev V.A., Vinogradova T.M. A coupled SYSTEM of intracellular Ca2+ clocks and surface membrane voltage clocks controls the timekeeping mechanism of the heart&#x2019;s pacemaker. Circ. Res. 2010;106:659&#x2013;673. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.109.206078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.109.206078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2837285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20203315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsutsui K., Monfredi O.J., Sirenko-Tagirova S.G., Maltseva L.A., Bychkov R., Kim M.S., Ziman B.D., Tarasov K.V., Tarasova Y.S., Zhang J., et al. A coupled-clock system drives the automaticity of human sinoatrial nodal pacemaker cells. Sci. Signal. 2018;11:eaap7608. doi: 10.1126/scisignal.aap7608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scisignal.aap7608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6138244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29895616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakatta E.G., DiFrancesco D. What keeps us ticking: A funny current, a calcium clock, or both? J. Mol. Cell. Cardiol. 2009;47:157&#x2013;170. doi: 10.1016/j.yjmcc.2009.03.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yjmcc.2009.03.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4554526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19361514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bychkov R., Juhaszova M., Calvo-Rubio Barrera M., Donald L.A.H., Coletta C., Shumaker C., Moorman K., Sirenko S.T., Maltsev A.V., Sollott S.J., et al. The Heart&#x2019;s Pacemaker Mimics Brain Cytoarchitecture and Function: Novel Interstitial Cells Expose Complexity of the SAN. JACC Clin. Electrophysiol. 2022;8:1191&#x2013;1215. doi: 10.1016/j.jacep.2022.07.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacep.2022.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9665104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36182566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castillo J.G., Adams D.H. Cardiac Vagal Ganglia. In: Robertson D., Biaggioni I., Burnstock G., Low P.A., Paton J.F.R., editors. Primer on the Autonomic Nervous System. Academic Press; Waltham, MA, USA: 2012. pp. 181&#x2013;185. Chapter 37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gourine A., Gourine A.V. Neural mechanisms of cardioprotection. Physiology. 2014;29:133&#x2013;140. doi: 10.1152/physiol.00037.2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physiol.00037.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3949205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24583769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navickaite L., Pauziene N., Pauza D.H. Anatomical evidence of non-parasympathetic cardiac nitrergic nerve fibres in rat. J. Anat. 2021;238:20&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1111/joa.13291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joa.13291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rysevaite K., Saburkina I., Pauziene N., Vaitkevicius R., Noujaim S.F., Jalife J., Pauza D.H. Immunohistochemical characterization of the intrinsic cardiac neural plexus in whole-mount mouse heart preparations. Heart Rhythm. 2011;8:731&#x2013;738. doi: 10.1016/j.hrthm.2011.01.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hrthm.2011.01.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3081960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21232628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauziene N., Alaburda P., Rysevaite-Kyguoliene K., Pauza A.G., Inokaitis H., Masaityte A., Rudokaite G., Saburkina I., Plisiene J., Pauza D.H. Innervation of the rabbit cardiac ventricles. J. Anat. 2016;228:26&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1111/joa.12400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joa.12400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4694158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26510903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauziene N., Rysevaite-Kyguoliene K., Alaburda P., Pauza A.G., Skukauskaite M., Masaityte A., Laucaityte G., Saburkina I., Inokaitis H., Plisiene J., et al. Neuroanatomy of the Pig Cardiac Ventricles. A Stereomicroscopic, Confocal and Electron Microscope Study. Anat. Rec. 2017;300:1756&#x2013;1780. doi: 10.1002/ar.23619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ar.23619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28598580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauza D.H., Saburkina I., Rysevaite K., Inokaitis H., Jokubauskas M., Jalife J., Pauziene N. Neuroanatomy of the murine cardiac conduction system: A combined stereomicroscopic and fluorescence immunohistochemical study. Auton. Neurosci. 2013;176:32&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1016/j.autneu.2013.01.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2013.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23403121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauza D.H., Rysevaite K., Inokaitis H., Jokubauskas M., Pauza A.G., Brack K.E., Pauziene N. Innervation of sinoatrial nodal cardiomyocytes in mouse. A combined approach using immunofluorescent and electron microscopy. J. Mol. Cell Cardiol. 2014;75:188&#x2013;197. doi: 10.1016/j.yjmcc.2014.07.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yjmcc.2014.07.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25101952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inokaitis H., Pauziene N., Rysevaite-Kyguoliene K., Pauza D.H. Innervation of sinoatrial nodal cells in the rabbit. Ann. Anat. 2016;205:113&#x2013;121. doi: 10.1016/j.aanat.2016.03.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aanat.2016.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27045595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inokaitis H., Pauziene N., Pauza D.H. The distribution of sinoatrial nodal cells and their innervation in the pig. Anat. Rec. 2022;29:24998. doi: 10.1002/ar.24998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ar.24998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35643929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauziene N., Ranceviene D., Rysevaite-Kyguoliene K., Inokaitis H., Saburkina I., Plekhanova K., Sabeckiene D., Sabeckis I., Martinaityte R., Pilnikovaite E., et al. Comparative analysis of intracardiac neural structures in the aged rats with essential hypertension. Anat. Rec. 2022;7:25109. doi: 10.1002/ar.25109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ar.25109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36342958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomas R., Kristina R.K., Neringa P., Hermanas I., Dainius P.H. Intrinsic cardiac neurons of the adult pigs: Chemical types, abundance, parameters and distribution within ganglionated plexus. Ann. Anat. 2022;243:151935. doi: 10.1016/j.aanat.2022.151935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aanat.2022.151935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35331888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragauskas T., Rysevaite-Kyguoliene K., Pauziene N., Inokaitis H., Pauza D.H. Chemical phenotypes of intrinsic cardiac neurons in the newborn pig (Sus scrofa domesticus Erxleben, 1777) J. Morphol. 2022;283:51&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1002/jmor.21426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmor.21426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34727377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rysevaite K., Saburkina I., Pauziene N., Noujaim S.F., Jalife J., Pauza D.H. Morphologic pattern of the intrinsic ganglionated nerve plexus in mouse heart. Heart Rhythm. 2011;8:448&#x2013;454. doi: 10.1016/j.hrthm.2010.11.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hrthm.2010.11.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3138056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21075216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia A.J., 3rd, Koschnitzky J.E., Dashevskiy T., Ramirez J.M. Cardiorespiratory coupling in health and disease. Auton. Neurosci. 2013;175:26&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1016/j.autneu.2013.02.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2013.02.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3683976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23497744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayano J., Yasuma F., Okada A., Mukai S., Fujinami T. Respiratory sinus arrhythmia. A phenomenon improving pulmonary gas exchange and circulatory efficiency. Circulation. 1996;94:842&#x2013;847. doi: 10.1161/01.CIR.94.4.842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.94.4.842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8772709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Tal A., Shamailov S.S., Paton J.F. Evaluating the physiological significance of respiratory sinus arrhythmia: Looking beyond ventilation-perfusion efficiency. J. Physiol. 2012;590:1989&#x2013;2008. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2011.222422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2011.222422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3573317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22289913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remmers J.E., deGroot W.J., Sauerland E.K., Anch A.M. Pathogenesis of upper airway occlusion during sleep. J. Appl. Physiol. 1978;44:931&#x2013;938. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1978.44.6.931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1978.44.6.931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">670014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig A.D. Forebrain emotional asymmetry: A neuroanatomical basis? Trends Cogn. Sci. 2005;9:566&#x2013;571. doi: 10.1016/j.tics.2005.10.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tics.2005.10.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16275155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandstra T.E., Notenboom R.G.E., Wink J., Ki&#xe8;s P., Vliegen H.W., Egorova A.D., Schalij M.J., De Ruiter M.C., Jongbloed M.R.M. Asymmetry and Heterogeneity: Part and Parcel in Cardiac Autonomic Innervation and Function. Front. Physiol. 2021;12:665298. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2021.665298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.665298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8481575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34603069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silva A.L.G., Vieira L.D.P., Dias L.S., Prestes C.V., Back G.D., Goulart C.D.L., Arena R., Borghi-Silva A., Trimer R. Impact of long COVID on the heart rate variability at rest and during deep breathing maneuver. Sci. Rep. 2023;13:22695. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-50276-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-50276-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10733257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38123689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein D.S. Post-COVID dysautonomias: What we know and (mainly) what we don&#x2019;t know. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2024;20:99&#x2013;113. doi: 10.1038/s41582-023-00917-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41582-023-00917-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38212633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paton J.F., Boscan P., Pickering A.E., Nalivaiko E. The yin and yang of cardiac autonomic control: Vago-sympathetic interactions revisited. Brain Res. Brain Res. Rev. 2005;49:555&#x2013;565. doi: 10.1016/j.brainresrev.2005.02.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainresrev.2005.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16269319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Z., Powley T.L., Schwaber J.S., Doyle F.J., III Projections of the dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus to cardiac ganglia of rat atria: An anterograde tracing study. J. Comp. Neurol. 1999;410:320&#x2013;341. doi: 10.1002/(SICI)1096-9861(19990726)410:2&lt;320::AID-CNE12&gt;3.0.CO;2-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1096-9861(19990726)410:2&lt;320::AID-CNE12&gt;3.0.CO;2-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10414536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuhuber W.L., Berthoud H.R. Functional anatomy of the vagus system&#x2014;Emphasis on the somato-visceral interface. Auton. Neurosci. 2021;236:102887. doi: 10.1016/j.autneu.2021.102887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2021.102887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8627476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34634680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal P., Senecal J.M.M., Nagy J.I. Expression of the gap junction protein connexin36 in small intensely fluorescent (SIF) cells in cardiac parasympathetic ganglia of rodents. Neurosci. Lett. 2023;793:136989. doi: 10.1016/j.neulet.2022.136989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neulet.2022.136989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36471528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aksu T., Gopinathannair R., Gupta D., Pauza D.H. Intrinsic cardiac autonomic nervous system: What do clinical electrophysiologists need to know about the &#x201c;heart brain &#x201d;? J. Cardiovasc. Electrophysiol. 2021;32:1737&#x2013;1747. doi: 10.1111/jce.15058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jce.15058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33928710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porges S.W. Orienting in a defensive world: Mammalian modifications of our evolutionary heritage. A polyvagal theory. Psychophysiology. 1995;32:301&#x2013;318. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-8986.1995.tb01213.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8986.1995.tb01213.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7652107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porges S.W. The Polyvagal Theory: Neurophysiological Foundations of Emotions, Attachment, Communication, and Self-Regulation. 1st ed. W.W. Norton; New York, NY, USA: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson J.H. The Croonian lectures on evolution and dissolution of the nervous system. Br. Med. J. 1884;1:703&#x2013;707. doi: 10.1136/bmj.1.1215.703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.1.1215.703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2307198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20750870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan M.B., Erb M., Schmalzl L., Moonaz S., Noggle Taylor J., Porges S.W. Yoga Therapy and Polyvagal Theory: The Convergence of Traditional Wisdom and Contemporary Neuroscience for Self-Regulation and Resilience. Front. Hum. Neurosci. 2018;12:67. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2018.00067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2018.00067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5835127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29535617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Givone S. La voce del sacro e la voce della scienza convergono sulla natura (The voice of the sacred and the voice of science converge on nature) Luoghi Dell&#x2019;infinito. 2022;271:77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glasscock E. Genomic biomarkers of SUDEP in brain and heart. Epilepsy Behav. 2014;38:172&#x2013;179. doi: 10.1016/j.yebeh.2013.09.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2013.09.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3989471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24139807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porges S.W. The COVID-19 Pandemic is a paradoxical challenge to our nervous system: A Polyvagal Perspective. Clin. Neuropsychiatry. 2020;17:135&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8629069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34908984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porges S.W. The vagal paradox: A polyvagal solution. Compr. Psychoneuroendocrinol. 2023;16:100200. doi: 10.1016/j.cpnec.2023.100200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpnec.2023.100200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10724739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38108034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>