<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37492483</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1741-427X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2023</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Evidence-based complementary and alternative medicine : eCAM</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Amygdala and Insula Retraining (AIR) Significantly Reduces Fatigue and Increases Energy in People with Long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7068326</StartPage><MedlinePgn>7068326</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7068326</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2023/7068326</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long COVID affects approximately 10-30% of individuals after an acute COVID-19 infection (Ceban, Ling, et al. 2022; Ortona and Malorni, 2022). Numerous symptoms, including extreme fatigue, can persist for months, resulting in social and economic hardship for individuals and their families (Ortona and Malorni 2022). Therefore, approaches that offer some relief from Long COVID are urgently needed. Research suggests that Long COVID symptoms are akin to those of chronic conditions, such as myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) and are likely caused by inflammation and immune dysfunction (Scordo et al., 2021). Amygdala and Insula Retraining (AIR), a neuroplasticity program, has successfully alleviated chronic conditions (Gupta 2010; Sanabria-Mazo et al. 2020; Toussaint et al. 2012). In this randomized controlled trial, AIR was tested against a structurally equivalent health and wellness intervention for its effectiveness in treating the symptom of fatigue among Long COVID sufferers. Results showed a significant decrease in participants' fatigue and a significant increase in their energy after the 3-month AIR intervention. Additionally, the AIR group experienced more significant outcomes than the active control group. The AIR group demonstrated a fatigue reduction effect size four times that of the active control group, and the absolute reduction in mean scores for the AIR group was more than double that of the control group. Furthermore, the AIR group showed an effect size in energy enhancement twice that of the active control group, and the absolute increase in energy mean scores for the AIR group was almost double that of the control group. These novel findings suggest AIR is a viable means of reducing fatigue and increasing energy among Long COVID patients. Limitations and future research are discussed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Loren L. Toussaint and Alexandra J. Bratty.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toussaint</LastName><ForeName>Loren L</ForeName><Initials>LL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8876-1848</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Luther College, 700 College Drive, Decorah, IA 52101, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bratty</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4318-3164</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AB Research Consulting, 508 Summer Mesa Drive, Las Vegas, NV 89148, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101215021</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1741-427X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Alexandra J. Bratty is the CEO of AB Research Consulting, which provides consulting services to The Gupta Program, the commercial version of the Amygdala and Insula Retraining (AIR) intervention. Her company was compensated for this work by independent donors. She was not involved in data collection for this study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37492483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10365910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/7068326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ortona E., Malorni W. Long COVID: to investigate immunological mechanisms and sex/gender related aspects as fundamental steps for tailored therapy. European Respiratory Journal . 2022;59(2):1&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1183/13993003.02245-2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02245-2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8462012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34531277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F., Ling S., Lui L. M. W., et al. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity . 2022;101:93&#x2013;135. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2021.12.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2021.12.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes D. L., Holdsworth L., Jawad N., Gunasekera P., Morice A. H., Crooks M. G. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is Long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung . 2021;199(2):113&#x2013;119. doi: 10.1007/s00408-021-00423-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00408-021-00423-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F., Leber A., Jawad M. Y., et al. Registered clinical trials investigating treatment of long COVID: a scoping review and recommendations for research. Infectious Diseases . 2022;54(7):467&#x2013;477. doi: 10.1080/23744235.2022.2043560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23744235.2022.2043560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8935463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35282780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scordo K. A., Richmond M. M., Munro N. Post-COVID-19 syndrome: theoretical basis, identification, and management. AACN Advanced Critical Care . 2021;32(2):188&#x2013;194. doi: 10.4037/aacnacc2021492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4037/aacnacc2021492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33942071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A. Can amygdala retraining techniques improve the well-being of patients with chronic fatigue syndrome? Journal of Holistic Healthcare . 2010;7(2):12&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toussaint L. L., Whipple M. O., Abboud L. L., Vincent A., Wahner-Roedler D. L. A mind-body technique for symptoms related to Fibromyalgia and chronic fatigue. Explore . 2012;8(2):92&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1016/j.explore.2011.12.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.explore.2011.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22385563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanabria-Mazo J. P., Montero-Marin J., Feliu-Soler A., et al. Mindfulness-based program plus amygdala and insula retraining (MAIR) for the treatment of women with Fibromyalgia: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Journal of Clinical Medicine . 2020;9(10):32&#x2013;46. doi: 10.3390/jcm9103246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm9103246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7599726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33050630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray E., Khadjesari Z., White I., et al. Methodological challenges in online trials. Journal of Medical Internet Research . 2009;11(1):p. e9. doi: 10.2196/jmir.1052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smets E. M. A., Garssen B., Bonke B., De Haes J. C. J. M. The multidimensional fatigue inventory (MFI) psychometric qualities of an instrument to assess fatigue. Journal of Psychosomatic Research . 1995;39(3):315&#x2013;325. doi: 10.1016/0022-3999(94)00125-O.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-3999(94)00125-O</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7636775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smets E. M. A., Garssen B., Cull A., De Haes J. C. J. M. Application of the multidimensional fatigue inventory (MFI-20) in cancer patients receiving radiotherapy. British Journal of Cancer . 1996;73(2):241&#x2013;245. doi: 10.1038/bjc.1996.42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/bjc.1996.42</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2074317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8546913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart A. L., Ware J. E. Durham, NC, USA: Duke University Press; 1996. Measuring Functioning and Well-Being: The Medical Outcomes Study Approach.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware J. E. How to Score the Revised MOS Short-form Health Scale (SF-36&#xae;) Vol. 10. New England, USA: The Health Institute; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware J. E. Measuring patient function and well-being: some lessons from the medical outcomes study. In: Heitgoff K. A., Lohr K. N., editors. Effectiveness and Outcomes in Health Care: Proceedings of an Invitational Conference by the Institute of Medicine Division of Health Care Services . Washington, DC, USA: National Academy Press; 1990. pp. 107&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazier J. E., Harper R., Jones N. M., et al. Validating the SF-36 health survey questionnaire: new outcome measure for primary care. British Medical Journal . 1992;305(6846):160&#x2013;164. doi: 10.1136/bmj.305.6846.160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.305.6846.160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1883187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1285753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J. M. S., Brimmer D. J., Maloney E. M., Nyarko E., BeLue R., Reeves W. C. Further validation of the Multidimensional Fatigue Inventory in a US adult population sample. Population Health Metrics . 2009;7(1):18&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1186/1478-7954-7-18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1478-7954-7-18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2801470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20003524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanderWeele T. J., Mathur M. B. Some desirable properties of the Bonferroni correction: is the Bonferroni correction really so bad? American Journal of Epidemiology . 2019;188(3):617&#x2013;618. doi: 10.1093/aje/kwy250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aje/kwy250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6395159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30452538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A. Unconscious amygdalar fear conditioning in a subset of chronic fatigue syndrome patients. Medical Hypotheses . 2002;59(6):727&#x2013;735. doi: 10.1016/S0306-9877(02)00321-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0306-9877(02)00321-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12445517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koren T., Yifa R., Amer M., et al. Insular cortex neurons encode and retrieve specific immune responses. Cell . 2021;184(24):5902&#x2013;5915.e17. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2021.10.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2021.10.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34752731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>