<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38646408</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of Original Neurofeedback Treatment Method for Brain Fog From COVID-19: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e56519</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e56519</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e56519</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.56519</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Brain fog is one of the most well-known sequelae of long COVID. It causes cognitive problems, mostly short-term memory disturbances, attention impairments, and problems with concentration. Although trials for treatment methods for brain fog have been carried out worldwide, effective methods have not yet been reported. Neurofeedback is effective for several common disorders and symptoms, including anxiety, depression, headaches, and pain. Neurofeedback is also reported to improve cognitive functions, such as processing speed and executive functions, including attention, planning, organization, problem-solving, and performance. Furthermore, neurofeedback is effective for "chemofog" and "chemobrain," which occur after chemotherapy and cause cognitive impairments in a similar manner to brain fog. However, there have been no reports of neurofeedback treatments for brain fog. Therefore, we have started to develop an original neurofeedback treatment method for brain fog using a Z-score neurofeedback technique. In this study, we present the first case report of a patient who has successfully recovered from brain fog via neurofeedback. Pain and psychological assessments revealed that the patient's pain improved&#xa0;and that the patient recovered from anxiety. Electroencephalograph data revealed several noble findings. C4 was thought to be the most affected site by brain fog, and this improved after treatment. The percentage increase at alpha wavelengths increased at almost all sites, and beta 1, beta 2, beta 3, and Hi beta decreased at almost all sites. The increased values at theta and alpha wavelengths after the 1st and 2nd sessions and the decreased values at higher beta wavelengths, such as beta 3 and Hi beta, were shown at all sessions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Masuko et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masuko</LastName><ForeName>Tatsuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Emerald Orthopedic &amp; Pain Clinic, Sapporo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sasai-Masuko</LastName><ForeName>Harue</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Emerald Orthopedic &amp; Pain Clinic, Sapporo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain fog</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electroencephalography (eeg)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mild to severe cognitive dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurofeedback therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">z-score</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38646408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11026996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.56519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Neurological associations of COVID-19. Ellul MA, Benjamin L, Singh B, et al. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19:767&#x2013;783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7332267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32622375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>'I can't cope with multiple inputs': a qualitative study of the lived experience of 'brain fog' after COVID-19. Callan C, Ladds E, Husain L, Pattinson K, Greenhalgh T. BMJ Open. 2022;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8844964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35149572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan G, Shaffer F, Lyle R, Teo I. Association for Applied Psychophysiology and Biofeedback, Wheat Ridge, USA. Wheat Ridge, CO: Association for Applied Psychophysiology and Biofeeback; 2016. Evidence-Based Practice in Biofeedback &amp; Neurofeedback, 3rd Edition.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EEG neurofeedback: a brief overview and an example of peak alpha frequency training for cognitive enhancement in the elderly. Angelakis E, Stathopoulou S, Frymiare JL, Green DL, Lubar JF, Kounios J. Clin Neuropsychol. 2007;21:110&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17366280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-COVID syndrome-associated brain fog and chemofog: luteolin to the rescue. Theoharides TC, Cholevas C, Polyzoidis K, Politis A. Biofactors. 2021;47:232&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33847020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smaller regional volumes of brain gray and white matter demonstrated in breast cancer survivors exposed to adjuvant chemotherapy. Inagaki M, Yoshikawa E, Matsuoka Y, et al. Cancer. 2007;109:146&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17131349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of EEG biofeedback on reducing postcancer cognitive impairment. Alvarez J, Meyer FL, Granoff DL, Lundy A. Integr Cancer Ther. 2013;12:475&#x2013;487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23584550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Translation and reliability and validity of a Japanese version of the revised Short-Form McGill Pain Questionnaire (SF-MPQ-2). (Article in Japanese) Maruo T, Nakae A, Maeda L, Takahashi K. Pain Res. 2013;28:43&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A multidimensional measure of pain interference: reliability and validity of the pain disability assessment scale. Yamashiro K, Arimura T, Iwaki R, Jensen MP, Kubo C, Hosoi M. Clin J Pain. 2011;27:338&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21178590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A short version of the Pain Anxiety Symptoms Scale (PASS-20): preliminary development and validity. McCracken LM, Dhingra L. Pain Res Manag. 2002;7:45&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16231066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS) accuracy in cancer patients. Annunziata MA, Muzzatti B, Bidoli E, et al. Support Care Cancer. 2020;28:3921&#x2013;3926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31858249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A self-rating depression scale. Zung WW. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 1965;12:63&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14221692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demos JN. Getting Started With EEG Neurofeedback, Second Edition. New York, NY: WW Norton; 2019. Electrode placements; pp. 27&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demos JN. Getting Started With EEG Neurofeedback, Second Edition. New York, NY: WW Norton; 2019. Matching EEG signatures to common symptoms and disorders; pp. 99&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo R. A Consumer's Guide to Understanding QEEG Brain Mapping and Neurofeedback Training. Greenville, SC: Foundation for Neurofeedback &amp; Neuromodulation Research; 2021. What is quantitative electroencephalography (QEEG) brain mapping? pp. 33&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demos JN. Getting Started With EEG Neurofeedback, Second Edition. New York, NY: WW Norton; 2019. Thresholds: advanced theory of protocol operation; pp. 197&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demos JN. Getting Started With EEG Neurofeedback, Second Edition. New York, NY: WW Norton; 2019. Z-score training concepts and concerns; pp. 206&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo R. A Consumer's Guide to Understanding QEEG Brain Mapping and Neurofeedback Training. Greenville, SC: Foundation for Neurofeedback &amp; Neuromodulation Research; 2021. Chapter One. What is quantitative electroencephalography (QEEG) brain mapping? pp. 17&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo R. A Consumer's Guide to Understanding QEEG Brain Mapping and Neurofeedback Training. Greenville, SC: Foundation for Neurofeedback &amp; Neuromodulation Research; 2021. Introduction; pp. 15&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo R. A Consumer's Guide to Understanding QEEG Brain Mapping and Neurofeedback Training. Greenville, SC: Foundation for Neurofeedback &amp; Neuromodulation Research; 2021. Preparing for neurofeedback; pp. 29&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>