<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36950279</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1092-8480</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current treatment options in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Treat Options Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cerebrovascular Manifestations of SARS-CoV-2: A Comprehensive Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>71</StartPage><EndPage>92</EndPage><MedlinePgn>71-92</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11940-023-00747-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">The risks of cerebrovascular manifestations due to SARS-CoV-2 infection are significantly increased within the first 6 months of the infection. Our work aims to give an update on current clinical aspects of diagnosis and treatment of cerebrovascular manifestations during acute and long-term SARS-CoV-2 infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">The incidence of acute ischemic stroke and haemorrhagic stroke during acute SARS-CoV-2 patients is estimated at 0.9 to 4.6% and 0.5-0.9%, respectively, and were associated with increased mortality. The majority presented with hemiparesis, dysarthria, sensory deficits, and a NIHSS score within 5-15. In addition, beyond the first 30 days of infection people with COVID-19 exhibited increased risk of stroke. During acute phase, age, hypertension, diabetes, and medical history of vascular disease were increased in patients with COVID-19 with new onset of cerebrovascular manifestations, while during long-COVID-19, the risk of cerebrovascular manifestations were found increased regardless of these factors. The management of patients with large-vessel ischemic stroke fulfilling the intravenous thrombolysis criteria are successfully treated according to the guidelines, while hyperosmolar therapy is typically administered in 4- to 6-h intervals. In addition, prophylaxis of anticoagulation therapy is associated with a better prognosis and low mortality during acute and post hospital discharge of patients with COVID-19.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">In this work, we provide a comprehensive review of the current literature on acute and post-acute COVID-19 cerebrovascular sequelae, symptomatology, and its pathophysiology mechanisms. Moreover, we discuss therapeutic strategies for these patients during acute and long-term care and point populations at risk. Our findings suggest that older patients with risk factors such as hypertension, diabetes, and medical history of vascular disease are more likely to develop cerebrovascular complications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature 2023, Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stefanou</LastName><ForeName>Eleni</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1452-1192</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Artificial Kidney Unit, General Hospital of Messinia, Kalamata, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karvelas</LastName><ForeName>Nikolaos</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bennett</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4514-4388</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kole</LastName><ForeName>Christo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4695-3723</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Department, Sismanoglio General Hospital of Attica, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Treat Options Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9815940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1092-8480</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute-COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebrovascular manifestations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Haemorrhagic stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ischemic stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-COVID-19</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of InterestNikolaos Karvelas declares that he has no conflict of interest. &#x395;leni Stefanou declares that she has no conflict of interest. Samuel Bennett declares that he has no conflict of interest. Christo Kole declares that he has no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36950279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9984763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11940-023-00747-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References and Recommended Reading</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Papers of particular interest, published recently, have been highlighted as: &#x2022; Of importance &#x2022;&#x2022; Of major importance</Title><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Hu B, Hu C, Zhu F, Liu X, Zhang J, Wang B, Xiang H, Cheng Z, Xiong Y, Zhao Y, Li Y, Wang X, Peng Z. Clinical characteristics of 138 hospitalized patients with 2019 novel coronavirus-infected pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA. 2020;323:1061&#x2013;1069. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.1585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.1585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P, Yang XL, Wang XG, Hu B, Zhang L, Zhang W, Si HR, Zhu Y, Li B, Huang CL, Chen HD, Chen J, Luo Y, Guo H, Jiang RD, Liu MQ, Chen Y, Shen XR, Wang X, Zheng XS, Zhao K, Chen QJ, Deng F, Liu LL, Yan B, Zhan FX, Wang YY, Xiao GF, Shi ZL. A pneumonia outbreak associated with a new coronavirus of probable bat origin. Nature. 2020;579:270&#x2013;273. doi: 10.1038/s41586-020-2012-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-020-2012-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu F, Zhao S, Yu B, Chen YM, Wang W, Song ZG, Hu Y, Tao ZW, Tian JH, Pei YY, Yuan ML, Zhang YL, Dai FH, Liu Y, Wang QM, Zheng JJ, Xu L, Holmes EC, Zhang YZ. A new coronavirus associated with human respiratory disease in China. Nature. 2020;579:265&#x2013;269. doi: 10.1038/s41586-020-2008-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-020-2008-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organisation WHO. Coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic, Coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard. 2023. Webpage: https://covid19.who.int/. Accesed 2 Feb 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022;&#x2022; Cui J, Li F, Shi ZL (2019) Origin and evolution of pathogenic coronaviruses. Nat Rev Microbiol. 17:181&#x2013;92. A landmark review on the current knowledge on the origin and evolution of pathogenic coronaviruses and discuss their receptor usage.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30531947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai MM, Cavanagh D. The molecular biology of coronaviruses. Adv Virus Res. 1997;48:1&#x2013;100. doi: 10.1016/S0065-3527(08)60286-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0065-3527(08)60286-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7130985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9233431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu R, Zhao X, Li J, Niu P, Yang B, Wu H, Wang W, Song H, Huang B, Zhu N, Bi Y, Ma X, Zhan F, Wang L, Hu T, Zhou H, Hu Z, Zhou W, Zhao L, Chen J, Meng Y, Wang J, Lin Y, Yuan J, Xie Z, Ma J, Liu WJ, Wang D, Xu W, Holmes EC, Gao GF, Wu G, Chen W, Shi W, Tan W. Genomic characterisation and epidemiology of 2019 novel coronavirus: implications for virus origins and receptor binding. Lancet. 2020;395:565&#x2013;574. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30251-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30251-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32007145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Walls AC, Park YJ, Tortorici MA, Wall A, McGuire AT, Veesler D (2020) Structure, function, and antigenicity of the SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein. Cell 181:281&#x2013;92e6. An important study showing SARS-CoV-2 S glycoprotein uses human ACE2 receptor to enter hosts&#x2019; cells.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32155444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crackower MA, Sarao R, Oudit GY, Yagil C, Kozieradzki I, Scanga SE, Oliveira-dos-Santos AJ, da Costa J, Zhang L, Pei Y, Scholey J, Ferrario CM, Manoukian AS, Chappell MC, Backx PH, Yagil Y, Penninger JM. Angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 is an essential regulator of heart function. Nature. 2002;417:822&#x2013;828. doi: 10.1038/nature00786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature00786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12075344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Li X, Chen M, Feng Y, Xiong C. The ACE2 expression in human heart indicates new potential mechanism of heart injury among patients infected with SARS-CoV-2. Cardiovasc Res. 2020;116:1097&#x2013;1100. doi: 10.1093/cvr/cvaa078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cvr/cvaa078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32227090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wrapp D, Wang N, Corbett KS, Goldsmith JA, Hsieh CL, Abiona O, Graham BS, McLellan JS. Cryo-EM structure of the 2019-nCoV spike in the prefusion conformation. bioRxiv; 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7164637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32075877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Meng B, Abdullahi A, Ferreira I, Goonawardane N, Saito A, Kimura I, Yamasoba D, Gerber PP, Fatihi S, Rathore S, Zepeda SK, Papa G, Kemp SA, Ikeda T, Toyoda M, Tan TS, Kuramochi J, Mitsunaga S, Ueno T, Shirakawa K, Takaori-Kondo A, Brevini T, Mallery DL, Charles OJ, Collaboration C-NBC-, Genotype to Phenotype Japan C, Ecuador CC, Bowen JE, Joshi A, Walls AC, Jackson L, Martin D, Smith KGC, Bradley J, Briggs JAG, Choi J, Madissoon E, Meyer KB, Mlcochova P, Ceron-Gutierrez L, Doffinger R, Teichmann SA, Fisher AJ, Pizzuto MS, de Marco A, Corti D, Hosmillo M, Lee JH, James LC, Thukral L, Veesler D, Sigal A, Sampaziotis F, Goodfellow IG, Matheson NJ, Sato K, Gupta RK. Altered TMPRSS2 usage by SARS-CoV-2 Omicron impacts infectivity and fusogenicity. Nature. 2022. An important study showing the importance of TMPRSS2 in facilitating the entry of the virus by fusion of the viral membrane with the membrane of the host cell.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia HP, Look DC, Shi L, Hickey M, Pewe L, Netland J, Farzan M, Wohlford-Lenane C, Perlman S, McCray PB., Jr ACE2 receptor expression and severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus infection depend on differentiation of human airway epithelia. J Virol. 2005;79:14614&#x2013;14621. doi: 10.1128/JVI.79.23.14614-14621.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.79.23.14614-14621.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1287568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16282461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamming I, Timens W, Bulthuis ML, Lely AT, Navis G, van Goor H. Tissue distribution of ACE2 protein, the functional receptor for SARS coronavirus. A first step in understanding SARS pathogenesis. J Pathol. 2004;203:631&#x2013;637. doi: 10.1002/path.1570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/path.1570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7167720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15141377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Xie X, Tu Z, Fu J, Xu D, Zhou Y. The signal pathways and treatment of cytokine storm in COVID-19. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6:255. doi: 10.1038/s41392-021-00679-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41392-021-00679-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8261820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34234112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y, Zhang L, Fan G, Xu J, Gu X, Cheng Z, Yu T, Xia J, Wei Y, Wu W, Xie X, Yin W, Li H, Liu M, Xiao Y, Gao H, Guo L, Xie J, Wang G, Jiang R, Gao Z, Jin Q, Wang J, Cao B. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020;395:497&#x2013;506. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Yu T, Du R, Fan G, Liu Y, Liu Z, Xiang J, Wang Y, Song B, Gu X, Guan L, Wei Y, Li H, Wu X, Xu J, Tu S, Zhang Y, Chen H, Cao B. Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet. 2020;395:1054&#x2013;1062. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30566-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30566-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32171076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libby P, Simon DI. Inflammation and thrombosis: the clot thickens. Circulation. 2001;103:1718&#x2013;1720. doi: 10.1161/01.CIR.103.13.1718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.103.13.1718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11282900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry BM, Lippi G. Poor survival with extracorporeal membrane oxygenation in acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) due to coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): Pooled analysis of early reports. J Crit Care. 2020;58:27&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1016/j.jcrc.2020.03.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcrc.2020.03.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32279018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tay MZ, Poh CM, Renia L, MacAry PA, Ng LFP. The trinity of COVID-19: immunity, inflammation and intervention. Nat Rev Immunol. 2020;20:363&#x2013;374. doi: 10.1038/s41577-020-0311-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-020-0311-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32346093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bikdeli B, Madhavan MV, Jimenez D, Chuich T, Dreyfus I, Driggin E, Nigoghossian C, Ageno W, Madjid M, Guo Y, Tang LV, Hu Y, Giri J, Cushman M, Quere I, Dimakakos EP, Gibson CM, Lippi G, Favaloro EJ, Fareed J, Caprini JA, Tafur AJ, Burton JR, Francese DP, Wang EY, Falanga A, McLintock C, Hunt BJ, Spyropoulos AC, Barnes GD, Eikelboom JW, Weinberg I, Schulman S, Carrier M, Piazza G, Beckman JA, Steg PG, Stone GW, Rosenkranz S, Goldhaber SZ, Parikh SA, Monreal M, Krumholz HM, Konstantinides SV, Weitz JI, Lip GYH, Global Covid-19 Thrombosis Collaborative Group EbtINE. the Iua SbtESCWGoPC. Right Ventricular F COVID-19 and thrombotic or thromboembolic disease: implications for prevention, antithrombotic therapy, and follow-up: JACC State-of-the-Art Review. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;75:2950&#x2013;2973. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2020.04.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2020.04.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7164881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32311448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkai I, Mayer MG, Hellmers LM, Ning B, Huang Z, Monjure CJ, Coyne C, Silvestri R, Golden N, Hensley K, Chandler K, Lehmicke G, Bix GJ, Maness NJ, Russell-Lodrigue K, Hu TY, Roy CJ, Blair RV, Bohm R, Doyle-Meyers LA, Rappaport J, Fischer T. Neuropathology and virus in brain of SARS-CoV-2 infected non-human primates. Nat Commun. 2022;13:1745. doi: 10.1038/s41467-022-29440-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-29440-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8975902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35365631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vuorio A, Raal F, Ij&#xe4;s P, Kaste M, Kovanen PT. Long-term cardiovascular and cerebrovascular challenges posed by COVID-19 in patients with familial hypercholesterolemia. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:1758. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2022.890141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.890141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9131188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35645833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung TYM, Chan AYL, Chan EW, Chan VKY, Chui CSL, Cowling BJ, Gao L, Ge MQ, Hung IFN, Ip MSM, Ip P, Lau KK, Lau CS, Lau LKW, Leung WK, Li X, Luo H, Man KKC, Ng VWS, Siu CW, Wan EYF, Wing YK, Wong CSM, Wong KHT, Wong ICK. Short- and potential long-term adverse health outcomes of COVID-19: a rapid review. Emerging Microbes &amp; Infections. 2020;9:2190&#x2013;2199. doi: 10.1080/22221751.2020.1825914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/22221751.2020.1825914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7586446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32940572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, Hishmeh L. Managing the long term effects of covid-19: summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ. 2021;372:n136. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendren NS, Drazner MH, Bozkurt B, Cooper LT., Jr Description and proposed management of the acute COVID-19 cardiovascular syndrome. Circulation. 2020;141:1903&#x2013;1914. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.047349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.047349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7314493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32297796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trifan G, Goldenberg FD, Caprio FZ, Biller J, Schneck M, Khaja A, Terna T, Brorson J, Lazaridis C, Bulwa Z, Alvarado Dyer R, Saleh Velez FG, Prabhakaran S, Liotta EM, Batra A, Reish NJ, Ruland S, Teitcher M, Taylor W, De la Pena P, Conners JJ, Grewal PK, Pinna P, Dafer RM, Osteraas ND, DaSilva I, Hall JP, John S, Shafi N, Miller K, Moustafa B, Vargas A, Gorelick PB, Testai FD. Characteristics of a diverse cohort of stroke patients with SARS-CoV-2 and outcome by sex. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2020;29:105314. doi: 10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2020.105314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2020.105314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32951959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaghi S, Ishida K, Torres J, Mac Grory B, Raz E, Humbert K, Henninger N, Trivedi T, Lillemoe K, Alam S, Sanger M, Kim S, Scher E, Dehkharghani S, Wachs M, Tanweer O, Volpicelli F, Bosworth B, Lord A, Frontera J. SARS-CoV-2 and stroke in a New York healthcare system. Stroke. 2020;51:2002&#x2013;2011. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.030335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.030335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7258764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32432996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022;&#x2022; Qureshi AI, Baskett WI, Huang W, Shyu D, Myers D, Raju M, Lobanova I, Suri MFK, Naqvi SH, French BR, Siddiq F, Gomez CR, Shyu CR. Acute ischemic stroke and COVID-19: an analysis of 27676 patients. Stroke. 2021;52:905&#x2013;12. A very important study that assessed the prevalence of stroke in COVID-19 patients. In addition, among all patients with COVID-19, the proportion of patients with hypertension, diabetes, hyperlipidemia, atrial fibrillation, and congestive heart failure was significantly higher among those with acute ischemic stroke.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaddaj-Mallat R, Aldib N, Bernard M, Paquette AS, Ferreira A, Lecordier S, Saghatelyan A, Flamand L, ElAli A. SARS-CoV-2 deregulates the vascular and immune functions of brain pericytes via Spike protein. Neurobiol Dis. 2021;161:105561. doi: 10.1016/j.nbd.2021.105561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2021.105561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8590447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34780863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlov V, Beylerli O, Gareev I, Torres Solis LF, Solis Herrera A, Aliev G. COVID-19-Related Intracerebral Hemorrhage. Front Aging Neurosci. 2020;12:600172. doi: 10.3389/fnagi.2020.600172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2020.600172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7642875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33192492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fara MG, Stein LK, Skliut M, Morgello S, Fifi JT, Dhamoon MS. Macrothrombosis and stroke in patients with mild Covid-19 infection. J Thromb Haemost. 2020;18:2031&#x2013;2033. doi: 10.1111/jth.14938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jth.14938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7283879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32464707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Kruip M, van der Meer NJM, Arbous MS, Gommers D, Kant KM, Kaptein FHJ, van Paassen J, Stals MAM, Huisman MV, Endeman H. Incidence of thrombotic complications in critically ill ICU patients with COVID-19. Thromb Res. 2020;191:145&#x2013;147. doi: 10.1016/j.thromres.2020.04.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.thromres.2020.04.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32291094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kananeh MF, Thomas T, Sharma K, Herpich F, Urtecho J, Athar MK, Jabbour P, Shah SO. Arterial and venous strokes in the setting of COVID-19. J Clin Neurosci. 2020;79:60&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1016/j.jocn.2020.07.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocn.2020.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7340078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33070919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esenwa C, Cheng NT, Luna J, Willey J, Boehme AK, Kirchoff-Torres K, Labovitz D, Liberman AL, Mabie P, Moncrieffe K, Soetanto A, Lendaris A, Seiden J, Goldman I, Altschul D, Holland R, Benton J, Dardick J, Fernandez-Torres J, Flomenbaum D, Lu J, Malaviya A, Patel N, Toma A, Lord A, Ishida K, Torres J, Snyder T, Frontera J, Yaghi S. Biomarkers of coagulation and inflammation in COVID-19-associated ischemic stroke. Stroke. 2021;52:e706&#x2013;e709. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.121.035045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.121.035045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8547586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34428931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal N, Sodani AK, Jain R, Ram H. Do elevated levels of inflammatory biomarkers predict the risk of occurrence of ischemic stroke in SARS-CoV2 ?: An Observational Study. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;30:106063. doi: 10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.106063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.106063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8376664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34464929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genchi A, Semerano A, Schwarz G, Dell'Acqua B, Gullotta GS, Sampaolo M, Boeri E, Quattrini A, Sanvito F, Diamanti S, Bergamaschi A, Grassi S, Podini P, Panni P, Michelozzi C, Simionato F, Scomazzoni F, Remida P, Valvassori L, Falini A, Ferrarese C, Michel P, Saliou G, Hajdu S, Beretta S, Roveri L, Filippi M, Strambo D, Martino G, Bacigaluppi M. Neutrophils predominate the immune signature of cerebral thrombi in COVID-19 stroke patients. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2022;10:14. doi: 10.1186/s40478-022-01313-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-022-01313-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8805426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng JH, Liu YX, Yuan J, Wang FX, Wu WB, Li JX, Wang LF, Gao H, Wang Y, Dong CF, Li YJ, Xie XJ, Feng C, Liu L. First case of COVID-19 complicated with fulminant myocarditis: a case report and insights. Infection. 2020;48:773&#x2013;777. doi: 10.1007/s15010-020-01424-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s15010-020-01424-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32277408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long B, Brady WJ, Koyfman A, Gottlieb M. Cardiovascular complications in COVID-19. Am J Emerg Med. 2020;38:1504&#x2013;1507. doi: 10.1016/j.ajem.2020.04.048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajem.2020.04.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7165109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32317203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Shao W, Zhang J, Ma J, Huang S, Yu P, Zhu W, Liu X. Prevalence of atrial fibrillation and associated mortality among hospitalized patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2021;8:720129. doi: 10.3389/fcvm.2021.720129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2021.720129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8548384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34722658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatla A, Mayer MM, Adusumalli S, Hyman MC, Oh E, Tierney A, Moss J, Chahal AA, Anesi G, Denduluri S, Domenico CM, Arkles J, Abella BS, Bullinga JR, Callans DJ, Dixit S, Epstein AE, Frankel DS, Garcia FC, Kumareswaram R, Nazarian S, Riley MP, Santangeli P, Schaller RD, Supple GE, Lin D, Marchlinski F, Deo R. COVID-19 and cardiac arrhythmias. Heart Rhythm. 2020;17:1439&#x2013;1444. doi: 10.1016/j.hrthm.2020.06.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hrthm.2020.06.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7307518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32585191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvernland A, Kumar A, Yaghi S, Raz E, Frontera J, Lewis A, Czeisler B, Kahn DE, Zhou T, Ishida K, Torres J, Riina HA, Shapiro M, Nossek E, Nelson PK, Tanweer O, Gordon D, Jain R, Dehkharghani S, Henninger N, de Havenon A, Grory BM, Lord A, Melmed K. Anticoagulation use and hemorrhagic stroke in SARS-CoV-2 patients treated at a New York healthcare system. Neurocrit Care. 2021;34:748&#x2013;759. doi: 10.1007/s12028-020-01077-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12028-020-01077-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7444897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32839867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melmed KR, Cao M, Dogra S, Zhang R, Yaghi S, Lewis A, Jain R, Bilaloglu S, Chen J, Czeisler BM, Raz E, Lord A, Berger JS, Frontera JA. Risk factors for intracerebral hemorrhage in patients with COVID-19. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2021;51:953&#x2013;960. doi: 10.1007/s11239-020-02288-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11239-020-02288-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7511245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32968850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omidian N, Mohammadi P, Sadeghalvad M, Mohammadi-Motlagh HR. Cerebral microvascular complications associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection: how did it occur and how should it be treated? Biomed Pharmacother. 2022;154:113534. doi: 10.1016/j.biopha.2022.113534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2022.113534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9381434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35994816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon L, McNamara C, Gaur P, Mallon D, Coughlan C, Tona F, Jan W, Wilson M, Jones B. Cerebral microhaemorrhage in COVID-19: a critical illness related phenomenon? Stroke Vasc Neurol. 2020;5:315&#x2013;322. doi: 10.1136/svn-2020-000652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/svn-2020-000652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7681795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33208493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo D, Falasca L, Marchioni L, Tammaro A, Adebanjo GAR, Ippolito G, Zumla A, Piacentini M, Nardacci R, Del Nonno F. Neuropathology and inflammatory cell characterization in 10 autoptic COVID-19 brains. Cells. 2021;10:2262. doi: 10.3390/cells10092262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells10092262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8469459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34571912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke J, Lutgehetmann M, Hagel C, Sperhake JP, Schroder AS, Edler C, Mushumba H, Fitzek A, Allweiss L, Dandri M, Dottermusch M, Heinemann A, Pfefferle S, Schwabenland M, Sumner Magruder D, Bonn S, Prinz M, Gerloff C, Puschel K, Krasemann S, Aepfelbacher M, Glatzel M. Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19:919&#x2013;929. doi: 10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30308-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30308-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7535629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirschenbaum D, Imbach LL, Rushing EJ, Frauenknecht KBM, Gascho D, Ineichen BV, Keller E, Kohler S, Lichtblau M, Reimann RR, Schreib K, Ulrich S, Steiger P, Aguzzi A, Frontzek K. Intracerebral endotheliitis and microbleeds are neuropathological features of COVID-19. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol. 2021;47:454&#x2013;459. doi: 10.1111/nan.12677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33249605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MH, Perl DP, Nair G, Li W, Maric D, Murray H, Dodd SJ, Koretsky AP, Watts JA, Cheung V, Masliah E, Horkayne-Szakaly I, Jones R, Stram MN, Moncur J, Hefti M, Folkerth RD, Nath A. Microvascular injury in the brains of patients with Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:481&#x2013;483. doi: 10.1056/NEJMc2033369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMc2033369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7787217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33378608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziai WC, Cho SM, Johansen MC, Ergin B, Bahouth MN. Transcranial Doppler in acute COVID-19 infection: unexpected associations. Stroke. 2021;52:2422&#x2013;2426. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.032150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.032150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8240491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33878893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin Y, Wu J, Chen T, Li J, Zhang G, Wu D, Zhou Y, Zheng N, Cai A, Ning Q, Manyande A, Xu F, Wang J, Zhu W. Long-term microstructure and cerebral blood flow changes in patients recovered from COVID-19 without neurological manifestations. J Clin Invest. 2021;131:e147329. doi: 10.1172/JCI147329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI147329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8262559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33630760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Li Y, Li M, Wang M, Zhou Y, Chang J, Xian Y, Wang D, Mao L, Jin H, Hu B. Acute cerebrovascular disease following COVID-19: a single center, retrospective, observational study. Stroke Vasc Neurol. 2020;5:279&#x2013;84. An important retrospective, observational study reporting the incidence of ischemic stroke and intracerebral hemorrhage. Moreover, the authors report significant findings in the management of these patients.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7371480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32616524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Zhang H, He Y, Qin C, Liu X, Liu M, Tang Y, Li X, Yang G, Tang Y, Liang G, Xu S, Wang W. Association between ischemic stroke and COVID-19 in China: a population-based retrospective study. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021;8:792487. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2021.792487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.792487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8898959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35265632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merkler AE, Parikh NS, Mir S, Gupta A, Kamel H, Lin E, Lantos J, Schenck EJ, Goyal P, Bruce SS, Kahan J, Lansdale KN, LeMoss NM, Murthy SB, Stieg PE, Fink ME, Iadecola C, Segal AZ, Cusick M, Campion TR, Jr, Diaz I, Zhang C, Navi BB. Risk of ischemic stroke in patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) vs patients with influenza. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.2730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.2730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7333175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32614385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein A, Oldridge O, Schwennesen H, Do D, Cucchiara BL. Acute Cerebrovascular Events in Hospitalized COVID-19 Patients. Stroke. 2020;51:e219&#x2013;e222. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.030995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.030995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7386677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32684145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantador E, Nunez A, Sobrino P, Espejo V, Fabia L, Vela L, de Benito L, Botas J. Incidence and consequences of systemic arterial thrombotic events in COVID-19 patients. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2020;50:543&#x2013;547. doi: 10.1007/s11239-020-02176-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11239-020-02176-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7282535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32519165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodigiani C, Iapichino G, Carenzo L, Cecconi M, Ferrazzi P, Sebastian T, Kucher N, Studt JD, Sacco C, Bertuzzi A, Sandri MT, Barco S, Humanitas C-TF. Venous and arterial thromboembolic complications in COVID-19 patients admitted to an academic hospital in Milan, Italy. Thromb Res. 2020;191:9&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1016/j.thromres.2020.04.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.thromres.2020.04.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7177070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32353746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain R, Young M, Dogra S, Kennedy H, Nguyen V, Jones S, Bilaloglu S, Hochman K, Raz E, Galetta S, Horwtiz L. COVID-19 related neuroimaging findings: a signal of thromboembolic complications and a strong prognostic marker of poor patient outcome. J Neurol Sci. 2020;414:116923. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2020.116923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2020.116923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32447193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekelis K, Missios S, Ahmad J, Labropoulos N, Schirmer CM, Calnan DR, Skinner J, MacKenzie TA. Ischemic stroke occurs less frequently in patients with COVID-19: a multicenter cross-sectional study. Stroke. 2020;51:3570&#x2013;3576. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.031217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.031217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7678670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33106109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo W, Liu X, Bao K, Huang C. Ischemic stroke associated with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol. 2022;269:1731&#x2013;1740. doi: 10.1007/s00415-021-10837-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-021-10837-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8517946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34652503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Katsanos AH, Palaiodimou L, Zand R, Yaghi S, Kamel H, Navi BB, Turc G, Romoli M, Sharma VK, Mavridis D, Shahjouei S, Catanese L, Shoamanesh A, Vadikolias K, Tsioufis K, Lagiou P, Alexandrov AV, Tsiodras S, Tsivgoulis G. The impact of SARS-CoV-2 on stroke epidemiology and care: a meta-analysis. Ann Neurol. 2021;89:380&#x2013;8. An important meta&#x2010;analysis study on the impact of SARS-CoV-2 on stroke epidemiology and care.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33219563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahjouei S, Naderi S, Li J, Khan A, Chaudhary D, Farahmand G, Male S, Griessenauer C, Sabra M, Mondello S, Cernigliaro A, Khodadadi F, Dev A, Goyal N, Ranji-Burachaloo S, Olulana O, Avula V, Ebrahimzadeh SA, Alizada O, Hanci MM, Ghorbani A, Vaghefi Far A, Ranta A, Punter M, Ramezani M, Ostadrahimi N, Tsivgoulis G, Fragkou PC, Nowrouzi-Sohrabi P, Karofylakis E, Tsiodras S, Neshin Aghayari Sheikh S, Saberi A, Niemela M, Rezai Jahromi B, Mowla A, Mashayekhi M, Bavarsad Shahripour R, Sajedi SA, Ghorbani M, Kia A, Rahimian N, Abedi V, Zand R. Risk of stroke in hospitalized SARS-CoV-2 infected patients: a multinational study. EBioMedicine. 2020;59:102939. doi: 10.1016/j.ebiom.2020.102939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2020.102939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32818804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finsterer J, Scorza FA. Ischemic Stroke in COVID-19 Patients May Be Incidentally but Not Causally Related to the Infection. Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;50:361&#x2013;362. doi: 10.1159/000513915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000513915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8018205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33601396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alawieh AM, Spiotta AM. Letter: May cooler heads prevail during a pandemic: stroke in COVID-19 patients or COVID-19 in stroke patients? Neurosurgery. 2020;87:E522. doi: 10.1093/neuros/nyaa283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/neuros/nyaa283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7337816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32548632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller A, Segan S, Rehmani R, Shabsigh R, Rahme R. Letter: Dismantling the apocalypse narrative: the myth of the COVID-19 stroke. Neurosurgery. 2020;87:E703&#x2013;E704. doi: 10.1093/neuros/nyaa419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/neuros/nyaa419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7499741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32888311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dmytriw AA, Dibas M, Schirmer CM, Settecase F, Heran MKS, Efendizade A, Kuhn AL, Puri AS, Ospel J, Menon B, Sivakumar S, Mowla A, Vela-Duarte D, Linfante I, Dabus G, Regenhardt RW, Patel AB, Leslie-Mazwi T, D'Amato S, Rosenthal J, Zha A, Talukder N, Sheth S, Cooke D, Leung LY, Malek A, Voetsch B, Sehgal S, Wakhloo AK, Wu H, Cohen J, Turkel-Parella D, Xavier A, Tiwari A, North American Neurovascular C-C. age and acute ischemic stroke outcome in North American patients with COVID-19. J Am Heart Assoc. 2021;10:e021046. doi: 10.1161/JAHA.121.021046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.121.021046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8483479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34219466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beslow LA, Linds AB, Fox CK, Kossorotoff M, Zuniga Zambrano YC, Hernandez-Chavez M, Hassanein SMA, Byrne S, Lim M, Maduaka N, Zafeiriou D, Dowling MM, Felling RJ, Rafay MF, Lehman LL, Noetzel MJ, Bernard TJ, Dlamini N, International Pediatric Stroke Study G Pediatric ischemic stroke: an infrequent complication of SARS-CoV-2. Ann Neurol. 2021;89:657&#x2013;665. doi: 10.1002/ana.25991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33332607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathew T, John SK, Sarma G, Nadig R, Kumar RS, Murgod U, Mahadevappa M, Javali M, Acharya PT, Hosurkar G, Krishnan P, Kamath V, Badachi S, Souza DD, Iyer RB, Nagarajaiah RK, Anand B, Kumar S, Kodapala S, Shivde S, Avati A, Baddala R, Potharlanka PB, Pavuluri S, Varidireddy A, Awatare P, Shobha N, Renukaradhya U, Kumar SP, Ramachandran J, Arumugam R, Deepalam S, Kumar S, Huded V. COVID-19-related strokes are associated with increased mortality and morbidity: a multicenter comparative study from Bengaluru, South India. Int J Stroke. 2021;16:429&#x2013;436. doi: 10.1177/1747493020968236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1747493020968236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7723737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33034546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ntaios G, Michel P, Georgiopoulos G, Guo Y, Li W, Xiong J, Calleja P, Ostos F, Gonzalez-Ortega G, Fuentes B, Alonso de Lecinana M, Diez-Tejedor E, Garcia-Madrona S, Masjuan J, DeFelipe A, Turc G, Goncalves B, Domigo V, Dan GA, Vezeteu R, Christensen H, Christensen LM, Meden P, Hajdarevic L, Rodriguez-Lopez A, Diaz-Otero F, Garcia-Pastor A, Gil-Nunez A, Maslias E, Strambo D, Werring DJ, Chandratheva A, Benjamin L, Simister R, Perry R, Beyrouti R, Jabbour P, Sweid A, Tjoumakaris S, Cuadrado-Godia E, Campello AR, Roquer J, Moreira T, Mazya MV, Bandini F, Matz K, Iversen HK, Gonzalez-Duarte A, Tiu C, Ferrari J, Vosko MR, Salzer HJF, Lamprecht B, Dunser MW, Cereda CW, Quintero ABC, Korompoki E, Soriano-Navarro E, Soto-Ramirez LE, Castaneda-Mendez PF, Bay-Sansores D, Arauz A, Cano-Nigenda V, Kristoffersen ES, Tiainen M, Strbian D, Putaala J, Lip GYH. Characteristics and outcomes in patients with COVID-19 and acute ischemic stroke: the global COVID-19 stroke registry. Stroke. 2020;51:e254&#x2013;e258. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.031208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.031208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7359900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32787707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahjouei S, Tsivgoulis G, Farahmand G, Koza E, Mowla A, Vafaei Sadr A, Kia A, Vaghefi Far A, Mondello S, Cernigliaro A, Ranta A, Punter M, Khodadadi F, Naderi S, Sabra M, Ramezani M, Amini Harandi A, Olulana O, Chaudhary D, Lyoubi A, Campbell BCV, Arenillas JF, Bock D, Montaner J, Aghayari Sheikh Neshin S, Aguiar de Sousa D, Tenser MS, Aires A, Alfonso ML, Alizada O, Azevedo E, Goyal N, Babaeepour Z, Banihashemi G, Bonati LH, Cereda CW, Chang JJ, Crnjakovic M, De Marchis GM, Del Sette M, Ebrahimzadeh SA, Farhoudi M, Gandoglia I, Goncalves B, Griessenauer CJ, Murat Hanci M, Katsanos AH, Krogias C, Leker RR, Lotman L, Mai J, Male S, Malhotra K, Malojcic B, Mesquita T, Mir Ghasemi A, Mohamed Aref H, Mohseni Afshar Z, Moon J, Niemela M, Rezai Jahromi B, Nolan L, Pandhi A, Park JH, Marto JP, Purroy F, Ranji-Burachaloo S, Carreira NR, Requena M, Rubiera M, Sajedi SA, Sargento-Freitas J, Sharma VK, Steiner T, Tempro K, Turc G, Ahmadzadeh Y, Almasi-Dooghaee M, Assarzadegan F, Babazadeh A, Baharvahdat H, Cardoso FB, Dev A, Ghorbani M, Hamidi A, Hasheminejad ZS, Hojjat-Anasri Komachali S, Khorvash F, Kobeissy F, Mirkarimi H, Mohammadi-Vosough E, Misra D, Noorian AR, Nowrouzi-Sohrabi P, Paybast S, Poorsaadat L, Roozbeh M, Sabayan B, Salehizadeh S, Saberi A, Sepehrnia M, Vahabizad F, Yasuda TA, Ghabaee M, Rahimian N, Harirchian MH, Borhani-Haghighi A, Azarpazhooh MR, Arora R, Ansari S, Avula V, Li J, Abedi V, Zand R. SARS-CoV-2 and stroke characteristics: a report from the multinational COVID-19 stroke study group. Stroke. 2021;52:e117&#x2013;e130. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.032927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.032927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8078130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33878892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Araque ME, Siegler JE, Ribo M, Requena M, Lopez C, de Lera M, Arenillas JF, Perez IH, Gomez-Vicente B, Talavera B, Portela PC, Guillen AN, Urra X, Llull L, Renu A, Nguyen TN, Jillella D, Nahab F, Nogueira R, Haussen D, Then R, Thon JM, Esparragoza LR, Hernandez-Perez M, Bustamante A, Mansour OY, Megahed M, Hassan T, Liebeskind DS, Hassan A, Bushnaq S, Osman M, Vazquez AR, Registry SM, Task F. Stroke etiologies in patients with COVID-19: the SVIN COVID-19 multinational registry. BMC Neurol. 2021;21:43. doi: 10.1186/s12883-021-02075-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12883-021-02075-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7846488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33514335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhamoon MS, Thaler A, Gururangan K, Kohli A, Sisniega D, Wheelwright D, Mensching C, Fifi JT, Fara MG, Jette N, Cohen E, Dave P, DiRisio AC, Goldstein J, Loebel EM, Mayman NA, Sharma A, Thomas DS, Vega Perez RD, Weingarten MR, Wen HH, Tuhrim S, Stein LK, Mount Sinai Stroke I. Acute cerebrovascular events with COVID-19 infection. Stroke. 2021;52:48&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.031668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.031668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33280551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sluis WM, Linschoten M, Buijs JE, Biesbroek JM, den Hertog HM, Ribbers T, Nieuwkamp DJ, van Houwelingen RC, Dias A, van Uden IWM, Kerklaan JP, Bienfait HP, Vermeer SE, de Jong SW, Ali M, Wermer MJH, de Graaf MT, Brouwers P, Asselbergs FW, Kappelle LJ, van der Worp HB, Algra AM, Consortium* C-CC Risk, clinical course, and outcome of ischemic stroke in patients hospitalized with COVID-19: a multicenter cohort study. Stroke. 2021;52:3978&#x2013;3986. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.121.034787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.121.034787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8607920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34732073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khedr EM, Soliman RK, Abo-Elfetof N, Amin M, Mansour OY, Aly A, Zaki AF, Saber M. Clinical and Radiological Characteristics of Acute Cerebrovascular Diseases Among Egyptian Patients With COVID-19 in Upper Egypt. Front Neurol. 2021;12:635856. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2021.635856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2021.635856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8019810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33828521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khandelwal P, Al-Mufti F, Tiwari A, Singla A, Dmytriw AA, Piano M, Quilici L, Pero G, Renieri L, Limbucci N, Martinez-Galdamez M, Schuller-Arteaga M, Galvan J, Arenillas-Lara JF, Hashim Z, Nayak S, Desousa K, Sun H, Agarwalla PK, Nanda A, Roychowdhury JS, Nourollahzadeh E, Prakash T, Gandhi CD, Xavier AR, Lozano JD, Gupta G, Yavagal DR. Incidence, characteristics and outcomes of large vessel stroke in COVID-19 cohort: an international multicenter study. Neurosurgery. 2021;89:E35&#x2013;E41. doi: 10.1093/neuros/nyab111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/neuros/nyab111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33734404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagraj S, Varrias D, Hernandez Romero G, Santos HT, Karamanis D, Sagris D, Korompoki E, Milionis H, Palaiodimos L, Ntaios G. Incidence of stroke in randomized trials of COVID-19 therapeutics: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Stroke. 2022;53:3410&#x2013;3418. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.122.040233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.122.040233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36000394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leasure AC, Khan YM, Iyer R, Elkind MSV, Sansing LH, Falcone GJ, Sheth KN. Intracerebral hemorrhage in patients with COVID-19: an analysis from the COVID-19 cardiovascular disease registry. Stroke. 2021;52:e321&#x2013;e323. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.121.034215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.121.034215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8238884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34082576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qureshi AI, Baskett WI, Huang W, Shyu D, Myers D, Lobanova I, Ishfaq MF, Naqvi SH, French BR, Siddiq F, Gomez CR, Shyu CR. Subarachnoid hemorrhage and COVID-19: an analysis of 282,718 patients. World Neurosurg. 2021;151:e615&#x2013;e620. doi: 10.1016/j.wneu.2021.04.089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wneu.2021.04.089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8086384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33940263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dogra S, Jain R, Cao M, Bilaloglu S, Zagzag D, Hochman S, Lewis A, Melmed K, Hochman K, Horwitz L, Galetta S, Berger J. Hemorrhagic stroke and anticoagulation in COVID-19. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2020;29:104984. doi: 10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2020.104984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2020.104984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32689588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra S, Choueka M, Wang Q, Hu C, Visone S, Silver M, Stein EG, Levine SR, Wang QT. Intracranial hemorrhage in COVID-19 patients. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;30:105603. doi: 10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.105603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.105603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7831866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33484980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morotti A, Pilotto A, Mazzoleni V, Fainardi E, Casetta I, Cavallini A, Del Moro G, Candeloro E, Janes F, Costa P, Zini A, Leuci E, Mazzacane F, Magno S, Rustemi O, Raneri F, Canova G, Valente M, Giorgianni A, Solazzo F, Versino M, Mauri M, Gentile M, Migliaccio L, Forlivesi S, Magni E, Del Zotto E, Benussi A, Premi E, Gamba M, Poli L, Pezzini A, Gasparotti R, Magoni M, Gipponi S, Padovani A. Imaging features and ultraearly hematoma growth in intracerebral hemorrhage associated with COVID-19. Neuroradiology. 2022;64:1367&#x2013;1372. doi: 10.1007/s00234-021-02861-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00234-021-02861-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8761086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35034151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bikdeli B, Chatterjee S, Arora S, Monreal M, Jimenez D, Krumholz HM, Goldhaber SZ, Elkind MSV, Piazza G. Cerebral venous sinus thrombosis in the U.S. population, after adenovirus-based SARS-CoV-2 vaccination, and after COVID-19. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;78:408&#x2013;411. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2021.06.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2021.06.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8186447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34116145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guendouz C, Quenardelle V, Riou-Comte N, Welfringer P, Wolff V, Zuily S, Jager L, Humbertjean Selton L, Mione G, Pop R, Gory B, Richard S. Pathogeny of cerebral venous thrombosis in SARS-Cov-2 infection: case reports. Medicine (Baltimore) 2021;100:e24708. doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000024708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000024708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7969213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33725828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalkader M, Shaikh SP, Siegler JE, Cervantes-Arslanian AM, Tiu C, Radu RA, Tiu VE, Jillella DV, Mansour OY, Vera V, Chamorro A, Blasco J, Lopez A, Farooqui M, Thau L, Smith A, Gutierrez SO, Nguyen TN, Jovin TG. Cerebral venous sinus thrombosis in COVID-19 patients: a multicenter study and review of literature. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;30:105733. doi: 10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.105733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.105733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7931726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33743411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hameed S, Wasay M, Soomro BA, Mansour O, Abd-Allah F, Tu T, Farhat R, Shahbaz N, Hashim H, Alamgir W, Iqbal A, Khan M. Cerebral venous thrombosis associated with COVID-19 infection: an observational, multicenter study. Cerebrovasc Dis Extra. 2021;11:55&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1159/000516641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000516641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8215987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33975306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalekar T, Thakker V, Bansal A. Role of neuroimaging in COVID 19 infection&#x2014;a retrospective study. J Radiol Nurs. 2021;40:370&#x2013;376. doi: 10.1016/j.jradnu.2021.09.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jradnu.2021.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8445804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34548849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Beltagi AH, Vattoth S, Abdelhady M, Ahmed I, Paksoy Y, Abou Kamar M, Alsoub H, Almaslamani M, Alkhal AL, Own A, Elsotouhy A. Spectrum of neuroimaging findings in COVID-19. Br J Radiol. 2021;94:20200812. doi: 10.1259/bjr.20200812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1259/bjr.20200812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7774681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33305996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arandela K, Samudrala S, Abdalkader M, Anand P, Daneshmand A, Dasenbrock H, Nguyen T, Ong C, Takahashi C, Shulman J, Babi MA, Sivakumar S, Shah N, Jain S, Anand S, Nobleza COS, Shekhar S, Venkatasubramanian C, Salahuddin H, Taqi MA, Nour HA, Nofar JB, Cervantes-Arslanian AM. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome in patients with coronavirus disease: a multicenter case series. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;30:106118. doi: 10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.106118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.106118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8445803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34560378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansoor T, Alsarah AA, Mousavi H, Khader Eliyas J, Girotra T, Hussein O. COVID-19 associated reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome successfully treated with nimodipine and aspirin. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;30:105822. doi: 10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.105822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.105822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8041144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33895426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Call GK, Fleming MC, Sealfon S, Levine H, Kistler JP, Fisher CM. Reversible cerebral segmental vasoconstriction. Stroke. 1988;19:1159&#x2013;1170. doi: 10.1161/01.STR.19.9.1159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.STR.19.9.1159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3046073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day JW, Raskin NH. Thunderclap headache: symptom of unruptured cerebral aneurysm. Lancet. 1986;2:1247&#x2013;1248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2878133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serdaru M, Chiras J, Cujas M, Lhermitte F. Isolated benign cerebral vasculitis or migrainous vasospasm? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1984;47:73&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1136/jnnp.47.1.73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.47.1.73</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1027644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6693916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappelen-Smith C, Calic Z, Cordato D. Reversible Cerebral Vasoconstriction Syndrome: Recognition and Treatment. Curr Treat Options Neurol. 2017;19:21. doi: 10.1007/s11940-017-0460-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11940-017-0460-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28456915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghizadeh A, Pourmoghaddas Z, Zandifar A, Tara SZ, Rahimi H, Saleh R, Ramezani S, Ghazavi M, Yaghini O, Hosseini N, Aslani N, Saadatnia M, Vossough A. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome and multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children with COVID-19. Pediatr Neurol. 2022;129:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2021.12.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2021.12.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8730706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudulagunta SR, Sodalagunta MB, Kumbhat M, Settikere Nataraju A. Posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome(PRES) Oxf Med Case Reports. 2017;2017:omx011. doi: 10.1093/omcr/omx011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/omcr/omx011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5410886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28473920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo A, Martinelli Boneschi F, Beretta S, Bresolin N, Versino M, Lorusso L, Spagnoli D, Nastasi G, Vallauri D, Rota S, Repaci M, Ferrarini M, Pozzato M, Princiotta Cariddi L, Tabaee Damavandi P, Carimati F, Banfi P, Clemenzi A, Marelli M, Giorgianni A, Vinacci G, Mauri M, Melzi P, Di Stefano M, Tetto A, Canesi M, Salmaggi A. Posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome and COVID-19: a series of 6 cases from Lombardy. Italy eNeurologicalSci. 2021;22:100306. doi: 10.1016/j.ensci.2020.100306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ensci.2020.100306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7806512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33490654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin R. As their numbers grow, COVID-19 &#x201c;long haulers&#x201d; stump experts. JAMA. 2020;324:1381&#x2013;1383. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.17709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.17709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32965460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Toro A, Bozzani A, Tavazzi G, Urtis M, Giuliani L, Pizzoccheri R, Aliberti F, Fergnani V, Arbustini E. Long COVID: long-term effects? Eur Heart J Suppl. 2021;23:E1&#x2013;E5. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/suab080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/suab080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8503490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34650349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi N. Long covid: how to define it and how to manage it. BMJ. 2020;370:m3489. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m3489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m3489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32895219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu TM, Seet CYH, Koh JS, Tham CH, Chiew HJ, De Leon JA, Chua CYK, Hui AC, Tan SSY, Vasoo SS, Tan BY, Umapathi NT, Tambyah PA, Yeo LLL. Acute ischemic stroke during the convalescent phase of asymptomatic COVID-2019 infection in men. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e217498. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.7498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.7498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8063067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33885771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Wang W, Wang C-Y, Wang S-I, Wei JC-C. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes in COVID-19 survivors among non-vaccinated population: a retrospective cohort study from the TriNetX US collaborative networks. eClinicalMedicine. 2022;53. An important study reporting that the 12-month risk of incidental cerebrovascular diseases is substantially higher in the COVID-19 survivors.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9366236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35971425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022. An important study reporting the long-term COVID-19 cerebrovascular manifestations.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35132265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Meijenfeldt FA, Havervall S, Adelmeijer J, Lundstrom A, Magnusson M, Mackman N, Thalin C, Lisman T. Sustained prothrombotic changes in COVID-19 patients 4 months after hospital discharge. Blood Adv. 2021;5:756&#x2013;759. doi: 10.1182/bloodadvances.2020003968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2020003968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33560386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Zhou L, Sun X, Yan Z, Hu C, Wu J, Xu L, Li X, Liu H, Yin P, Li K, Zhao J, Li Y, Wang X, Li Y, Zhang Q, Xu G, Chen H. Altered lipid metabolism in recovered SARS patients twelve years after infection. Sci Rep. 2017;7:9110. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-09536-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-09536-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5567209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28831119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vuorio A, Raal F, Ijas P, Kaste M, Kovanen PT. Long-term cardiovascular and cerebrovascular challenges posed by COVID-19 in patients with familial hypercholesterolemia. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:890141. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2022.890141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.890141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9131188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35645833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thachil J, Tang N, Gando S, Falanga A, Cattaneo M, Levi M, Clark C, Iba T. ISTH interim guidance on recognition and management of coagulopathy in COVID-19. J Thromb Haemost. 2020;18:1023&#x2013;1026. doi: 10.1111/jth.14810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jth.14810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9906133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32338827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vivas D, Roldan V, Esteve-Pastor MA, Roldan I, Tello-Montoliu A, Ruiz-Nodar JM, Cosin-Sales J, Gamez JM, Consuegra L, Ferreiro JL, Marin F, Revisores E. Recommendations on antithrombotic treatment during the COVID-19 pandemic. Position statement of the Working Group on Cardiovascular Thrombosis of the Spanish Society of Cardiology. Rev Esp Cardiol. 2020;73:749&#x2013;757. doi: 10.1016/j.recesp.2020.04.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.recesp.2020.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7303617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32694078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuker A, Tseng EK, Nieuwlaat R, Angchaisuksiri P, Blair C, Dane K, Davila J, DeSancho MT, Diuguid D, Griffin DO, Kahn SR, Klok FA, Lee AI, Neumann I, Pai A, Righini M, Sanfilippo KM, Siegal D, Skara M, Terrell DR, Touri K, Akl EA, Bou Akl I, Bognanni A, Boulos M, Brignardello-Petersen R, Charide R, Chan M, Dearness K, Darzi AJ, Kolb P, Colunga-Lozano LE, Mansour R, Morgano GP, Morsi RZ, Muti-Schunemann G, Noori A, Philip BA, Piggott T, Qiu Y, Roldan Y, Schunemann F, Stevens A, Solo K, Wiercioch W, Mustafa RA, Schunemann HJ. American Society of Hematology living guidelines on the use of anticoagulation for thromboprophylaxis in patients with COVID-19: May 2021 update on the use of intermediate-intensity anticoagulation in critically ill patients. Blood Adv. 2021;5:3951&#x2013;3959. doi: 10.1182/bloodadvances.2021005493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2021005493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8416320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34474482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janes F, Gigli GL, Kuris F, Morassi M, Costa P, Nesi L, Giacomello R, Mazzacane F, Leuci E, Cavallini A, Valente M. Failure of therapeutic anticoagulation in COVID-19 patients with acute ischemic stroke. A Retrospective Multicenter Study Front Neurol. 2022;13:834469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8931401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J, Severac F, Merdji H, Schenck M, Clere-Jehl R, Baldacini M, Ohana M, Grunebaum L, Castelain V, Angles-Cano E, Sattler L, Meziani F, Group CT. Higher anticoagulation targets and risk of thrombotic events in severe COVID-19 patients: bi-center cohort study. Ann Intensive Care. 2021;11:14. doi: 10.1186/s13613-021-00809-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13613-021-00809-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7829649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33492445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers WJ, Rabinstein AA, Ackerson T, Adeoye OM, Bambakidis NC, Becker K, Biller J, Brown M, Demaerschalk BM, Hoh B, Jauch EC, Kidwell CS, Leslie-Mazwi TM, Ovbiagele B, Scott PA, Sheth KN, Southerland AM, Summers DV, Tirschwell DL. Guidelines for the early management of patients with acute ischemic stroke: 2019 update to the 2018 guidelines for the early management of acute ischemic stroke: a guideline for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke. 2019;50:e344&#x2013;e418. doi: 10.1161/STR.0000000000000211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STR.0000000000000211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31662037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahai A, Bhandari R, Godwin M, McIntyre T, Chung MK, Iskandar JP, Kamran H, Hariri E, Aggarwal A, Burton R, Kalra A, Bartholomew JR, McCrae KR, Elbadawi A, Bena J, Svensson LG, Kapadia S, Cameron SJ. Effect of aspirin on short-term outcomes in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Vasc Med. 2021;26:626&#x2013;632. doi: 10.1177/1358863X211012754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1358863X211012754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8137864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34010070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen NJ, Schleich MA, Karp DR. Multifaceted effects of hydroxychloroquine in human disease. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2013;43:264&#x2013;272. doi: 10.1016/j.semarthrit.2013.01.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semarthrit.2013.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23481418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z, Fu Y, Tian D, Sun N, Han W, Chang G, Dong Y, Xu X, Liu Q, Huang D, Shi FD. Combination of the immune modulator fingolimod with alteplase in acute ischemic stroke: a pilot trial. Circulation. 2015;132:1104&#x2013;1112. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.115.016371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.115.016371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4580515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26202811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasanejad P, Afshar Hezarkhani L, Arsang-Jang S, Tsivgoulis G, Ghoreishi A, Kristian B, Rahmig J, Farhoudi M, Sadeghi Hokmabadi E, Borhani-Haghighi A, Sariaslani P, Sharifi-Razavi A, Ghandehari K, Khosravi A, Smith C, Nilanont Y, Akbari Y, Nguyen TN, Bersano A, Yassi N, Yoshimoto T, Lattanzi S, Gupta A, Zand R, Rafie S, Pourandokht Mousavian S, Reza Shahsavaripour M, Amini S, Kamenova SU, Kondybayeva A, Zhanuzakov M, Macri EM, Nobleza COS, Ruland S, Cervantes-Arslanian AM, Desai MJ, Ranta A, Moghadam Ahmadi A, Rostamihosseinkhani M, Foroughi R, Hooshmandi E, Akhoundi FH, Shuaib A, Liebeskind DS, Siegler J, Romano JG, Mayer SA, Bavarsad Shahripour R, Zamani B, Woolsey A, Fazli Y, Mojtaba K, Isaac CF, Biller J, Di Napoli M, Azarpazhooh MR. Safety and outcomes of intravenous thrombolytic therapy in ischemic stroke patients with COVID-19: CASCADE initiative. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;30:106121. doi: 10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.106121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.106121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34601242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobolewski P, Antecki J, Brola W, Fudala M, Bieniaszewski L, Kozera G. Systemic thrombolysis in ischaemic stroke patients with COVID-19. Acta Neurol Scand. 2022;145:47&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1111/ane.13520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ane.13520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34415051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cagnazzo F, Piotin M, Escalard S, Maier B, Ribo M, Requena M, Pop R, Hasiu A, Gasparotti R, Mardighian D, Piano M, Cervo A, Eker OF, Durous V, Sourour NA, Elhorany M, Zini A, Simonetti L, Marcheselli S, Paolo NN, Houdart E, Guedon A, Ligot N, Mine B, Consoli A, Lapergue B, Cordona Portela P, Urra X, Rodriguez A, Bolognini F, Lebedinsky PA, Pasco-Papon A, Godard S, Marnat G, Sibon I, Limbucci N, Nencini P, Nappini S, Saia V, Caldiera V, Romano D, Frauenfelder G, Gallesio I, Gola G, Menozzi R, Genovese A, Terrana A, Giorgianni A, Cappellari M, Augelli R, Invernizzi P, Pavia M, Lafe E, Cavallini A, Giossi A, Besana M, Valvassori L, Macera A, Castellan L, Salsano G, Di Caterino F, Biondi A, Arquizan C, Lebreuche J, Galvano G, Cannella A, Cosottini M, Lazzarotti G, Guizzardi G, Stecco A, Tassi R, Bracco S, Bianchini E, Micieli C, Pascarella R, Napoli M, Causin F, Desal H, Cotton F, Costalat V, Group* E-C-S European multicenter study of ET-COVID-19. Stroke. 2021;52:31&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.031514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.031514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33222617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Styczen H, Maus V, Goertz L, Kohrmann M, Kleinschnitz C, Fischer S, Mohlenbruch M, Muhlen I, Kallmunzer B, Dorn F, Lakghomi A, Gawlitza M, Kaiser D, Klisch J, Lobsien D, Rohde S, Ellrichmann G, Behme D, Thormann M, Flottmann F, Winkelmeier L, Gizewski ER, Mayer-Suess L, Boeckh-Behrens T, Riederer I, Klingebiel R, Berger B, Schlunz-Hendann M, Grieb D, Khanafer A, du Mesnil de Rochemont R, Arendt C, Altenbernd J, Schlump JU, Ringelstein A, Sanio VJM, Loehr C, Dahlke AM, Brockmann C, Reder S, Sure U, Li Y, Muhl-Benninghaus R, Rodt T, Kallenberg K, Durutya A, Elsharkawy M, Stracke P, Schumann MG, Bock A, Nikoubashman O, Wiesmann M, Henkes H, Mosimann PJ, Chapot R, Forsting M, Deuschl C. Mechanical thrombectomy for acute ischemic stroke in COVID-19 patients: multicenter experience in 111 cases. J Neurointerv Surg. 2022;14:858&#x2013;862. doi: 10.1136/neurintsurg-2022-018723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/neurintsurg-2022-018723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35292572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roquilly A, Moyer JD, Huet O, Lasocki S, Cohen B, Dahyot-Fizelier C, Chalard K, Seguin P, Jeantrelle C, Vermeersch V, Gaillard T, Cinotti R, Demeure Dit Latte D, Mahe PJ, Vourc&#x2019;h M, Martin FP, Chopin A, Lerebourg C, Flet L, Chiffoleau A, Feuillet F, Asehnoune K, Atlanrea Study G. the Societe Francaise d&#x2019;Anesthesie Reanimation Research N Effect of continuous infusion of hypertonic saline vs standard care on 6-month neurological outcomes in patients with traumatic brain injury: the COBI randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2021;325:2056&#x2013;2066. doi: 10.1001/jama.2021.5561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.5561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8150692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34032829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook AM, Morgan Jones G, Hawryluk GWJ, Mailloux P, McLaughlin D, Papangelou A, Samuel S, Tokumaru S, Venkatasubramanian C, Zacko C, Zimmermann LL, Hirsch K, Shutter L. Guidelines for the acute treatment of cerebral edema in neurocritical care patients. Neurocrit Care. 2020;32:647&#x2013;666. doi: 10.1007/s12028-020-00959-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12028-020-00959-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32227294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang JW, Reynolds AS, Reilly K, Lay C, Kellner CP, Shigematsu T, Gilligan J, Majidi S, Al-Mufti F, Bederson JB, Mocco J, Dhamoon MS, Dangayach NS, Mount Sinai Stroke I. COVID-19 and decompressive hemicraniectomy for acute ischemic stroke. Stroke. 2020;51:e215&#x2013;e218. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.030804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.030804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7359903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32639861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meschia JF, Malkoff MD, Biller J. Reversible segmental cerebral arterial vasospasm and cerebral infarction: possible association with excessive use of sumatriptan and Midrin. Arch Neurol. 1998;55:712&#x2013;714. doi: 10.1001/archneur.55.5.712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneur.55.5.712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9605729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis SM, Donnan GA. Clinical practice. Secondary prevention after ischemic stroke or transient ischemic attack. N Engl J Med. 2012;366:1914&#x2013;1922. doi: 10.1056/NEJMcp1107281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMcp1107281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22591297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022;&#x2022; Kleindorfer DO, Towfighi A, Chaturvedi S, Cockroft KM, Gutierrez J, Lombardi-Hill D, Kamel H, Kernan WN, Kittner SJ, Leira EC, Lennon O, Meschia JF, Nguyen TN, Pollak PM, Santangeli P, Sharrief AZ, Smith SC, Jr., Turan TN, Williams LS.&#xa0;2021 Guideline for the prevention of stroke in patients with stroke and transient ischemic attack: a guideline from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke. 2021;52:e364-467.&#xa0;2021 guideline for the prevention of stroke in patients with stroke and transient ischemic attack.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Donnell MJ, Chin SL, Rangarajan S, Xavier D, Liu L, Zhang H, Rao-Melacini P, Zhang X, Pais P, Agapay S, Lopez-Jaramillo P, Damasceno A, Langhorne P, McQueen MJ, Rosengren A, Dehghan M, Hankey GJ, Dans AL, Elsayed A, Avezum A, Mondo C, Diener HC, Ryglewicz D, Czlonkowska A, Pogosova N, Weimar C, Iqbal R, Diaz R, Yusoff K, Yusufali A, Oguz A, Wang X, Penaherrera E, Lanas F, Ogah OS, Ogunniyi A, Iversen HK, Malaga G, Rumboldt Z, Oveisgharan S, Al Hussain F, Magazi D, Nilanont Y, Ferguson J, Pare G, Yusuf S, Investigators I. Global and regional effects of potentially modifiable risk factors associated with acute stroke in 32 countries (INTERSTROKE): a case-control study. Lancet. 2016;388:761&#x2013;775. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(16)30506-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(16)30506-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27431356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diener HC, Bogousslavsky J, Brass LM, Cimminiello C, Csiba L, Kaste M, Leys D, Matias-Guiu J, Rupprecht HJ, Investigators M. Aspirin and clopidogrel compared with clopidogrel alone after recent ischaemic stroke or transient ischaemic attack in high-risk patients (MATCH): randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet. 2004;364:331&#x2013;337. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(04)16721-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(04)16721-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15276392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Johnston SC, Easton JD, Farrant M, Barsan W, Conwit RA, Elm JJ, Kim AS, Lindblad AS, Palesch YY, Clinical Research Collaboration NETTN, the PI. Clopidogrel and aspirin in acute ischemic stroke and high-risk TIA. N Engl J Med. 2018;379:215&#x2013;25. An important randomized trial assessing the effect of combination antiplatelet therapy with clopidogrel and aspirin in patients ischemic stroke or high-risk TIA.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6193486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29766750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr JP, Thompson JL, Lazar RM, Levin B, Sacco RL, Furie KL, Kistler JP, Albers GW, Pettigrew LC, Adams HP, Jr, Jackson CM, Pullicino P, Warfarin-Aspirin Recurrent Stroke Study G A comparison of warfarin and aspirin for the prevention of recurrent ischemic stroke. N Engl J Med. 2001;345:1444&#x2013;1451. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa011258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa011258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11794192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee CS. A randomised, blinded, trial of clopidogrel versus aspirin in patients at risk of ischaemic events (CAPRIE) CAPRIE Steering Committee Lancet. 1996;348:1329&#x2013;1339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8918275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albay CEQ, Leyson FGD, Cheng FC. Dual versus mono antiplatelet therapy for acute non- cardio embolic ischemic stroke or transient ischemic attack, an efficacy and safety analysis - updated meta-analysis. BMC Neurol. 2020;20:224. doi: 10.1186/s12883-020-01808-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12883-020-01808-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7268473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32493229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothwell PM, Cook NR, Gaziano JM, Price JF, Belch JFF, Roncaglioni MC, Morimoto T, Mehta Z. Effects of aspirin on risks of vascular events and cancer according to bodyweight and dose: analysis of individual patient data from randomised trials. Lancet. 2018;392:387&#x2013;399. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31133-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31133-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6083400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30017552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston SC, Amarenco P, Denison H, Evans SR, Himmelmann A, James S, Knutsson M, Ladenvall P, Molina CA, Wang Y, Investigators T. Ticagrelor and aspirin or Aspirin Alone in Acute Ischemic Stroke or TIA. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:207&#x2013;217. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1916870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1916870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32668111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulia EPB, Maghfirah I, Rachmi DA, Julario R. Atrial arrhythmia and its association with COVID-19 outcome: a pooled analysis. Diagnosis (Berl) 2021;8:532&#x2013;535. doi: 10.1515/dx-2020-0155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/dx-2020-0155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33470951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hull RD, Schellong SM, Tapson VF, Monreal M, Samama MM, Nicol P, Vicaut E, Turpie AG, Yusen RD, Study E. Extended-duration venous thromboembolism prophylaxis in acutely ill medical patients with recently reduced mobility: a randomized trial. Ann Intern Med. 2010;153:8&#x2013;18. doi: 10.7326/0003-4819-153-1-201007060-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-153-1-201007060-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20621900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen AT, Harrington RA, Goldhaber SZ, Hull RD, Wiens BL, Gold A, Hernandez AF, Gibson CM, Investigators A. Extended thromboprophylaxis with betrixaban in acutely ill medical patients. N Engl J Med. 2016;375:534&#x2013;544. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1601747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1601747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27232649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen AT, Spiro TE, Buller HR, Haskell L, Hu D, Hull R, Mebazaa A, Merli G, Schellong S, Spyropoulos AC, Tapson V, Investigators M. Rivaroxaban for thromboprophylaxis in acutely ill medical patients. N Engl J Med. 2013;368:513&#x2013;523. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1111096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1111096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23388003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022;&#x2022; Spyropoulos AC, Ageno W, Albers GW, Elliott CG, Halperin JL, Hiatt WR, Maynard GA, Steg PG, Weitz JI, Suh E, Spiro TE, Barnathan ES, Raskob GE, Investigators M. Rivaroxaban for thromboprophylaxis after hospitalization for medical illness. N Engl J Med. 2018;379:1118&#x2013;27. A very important clinical trial assessing the effect of Rivaroxaban on the venous thromboembolic risk in post-hospital discharge patients.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dentali F, Mumoli N, Prisco D, Fontanella A, Di Minno MN. Efficacy and safety of extended thromboprophylaxis for medically ill patients. A meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Thromb Haemost. 2017;117:606&#x2013;617. doi: 10.1160/TH16-08-0595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1160/TH16-08-0595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28078350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schindewolf M, Weitz JI. Broadening the categories of patients eligible for extended venous thromboembolism treatment. Thromb Haemost. 2020;120:14&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1055/s-0039-3400302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0039-3400302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31858522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Brutto VJ, Chaturvedi S, Diener H-C, Romano JG, Sacco RL. Antithrombotic therapy to prevent recurrent strokes in ischemic cerebrovascular disease: JACC Scientific Expert Panel. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;74:786&#x2013;803. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2019.06.039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2019.06.039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7291776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31395130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>