<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36917827</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1809-452X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Season>May-Jun</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Revista brasileira de psiquiatria (Sao Paulo, Brazil : 1999)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Braz J Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Increased insulin resistance due to Long COVID is associated with depressive symptoms and partly predicted by the inflammatory response during acute infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>205</StartPage><EndPage>215</EndPage><MedlinePgn>205-215</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.47626/1516-4446-2022-3002</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Some months after the remission of acute COVID-19, some individuals show depressive symptoms, which are predicted by increased peak body temperature (PBT) and decreased blood oxygen saturation (SpO2). The present study aimed to examine data on whether long COVID is associated with increased insulin resistance (IR) in association with neuroimmune and oxidative (NIO) processes during the acute infectious and long COVID phases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This case-control, retrospective cohort study used the Homeostasis Model Assessment 2 (HOMA2) calculator&#xa9; to compute &#xdf;-cell function (HOMA2%B) and insulin sensitivity (HOMA2%S) and resistance (HOMA2-IR) and administered the Beck Depression Inventory (BDI) and Hamilton Depression Rating Scale (HAMD) to 86 patients with long COVID and 39 controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Long COVID (3-4 months after the acute infection) is accompanied by increased HOMA2-IR, fasting blood glucose (FBG), and insulin levels; 33.7% of the patients vs. 0% of the controls had HOMA2-IR values &gt; 1.8, suggesting IR. Increased IR was predicted by PBT during acute infection and associated with depressive symptoms above and beyond the effects of NIO pathways (nucleotide-binding domain, leucine-rich repeat, and pyrin domain-containing protein 3 [NLRP3] inflammasome, myeloperoxidase [MPO], protein oxidation). There were no significant associations between increased IR and the activated NIO pathways during long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Long COVID is associated with new-onset IR, which may contribute to onset of depressive symptoms due to long COVID by enhancing overall neurotoxicity.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Hakeim</LastName><ForeName>Hussein Kadhem</ForeName><Initials>HK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, College of Science, University of Kufa, Kufa, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Rubaye</LastName><ForeName>Haneen Tahseen</ForeName><Initials>HT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medical Laboratory Techniques, Imam Ja'afar Al-Sadiq University, Najaf, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jubran</LastName><ForeName>Abdulsahib S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Dentistry, University of Alkafeel, Najaf, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almulla</LastName><ForeName>Abbas F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Laboratory Technology Department, College of Medical Technology, The Islamic University, Najaf, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moustafa</LastName><ForeName>Shatha Rouf</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Analysis Department, College of Pharmacy, Hawler Medical University, Erbil, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maes</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand. Department of Psychiatry, Medical University of Plovdiv, Plovdiv, Bulgaria. Institute for Mental and Physical Health and Clinical Translation, School of Medicine, Barwon Health, Deakin University, Geelong, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Brazil</Country><MedlineTA>Braz J Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100895975</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1516-4446</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007328">Insulin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007333" MajorTopicYN="Y">Insulin Resistance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007328" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">major depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mood disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxidative and nitrosative stress</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36917827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10288478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47626/1516-4446-2022-3002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maes M, Del Tedesco WL, Junior, Lozovoy MAB, Mori MTE, Danelli T, Almeida ERD, et al. In COVID-19, NLRP3 inflammasome genetic variants are associated with critical disease and these effects are partly mediated by the sickness symptom complex: a nomothetic network approach. Mol Psychiatry. 2022;27:1945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8752583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35022530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamers MM, Haagmans BL. SARS-CoV-2 pathogenesis. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2022;20:270&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35354968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason RJ. Pathogenesis of COVID-19 from a cell biology perspective. Eur Respir J. 2020;55:2000607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7144260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32269085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagulkoo P, Plaimas K, Suratanee A, Sim&#xe3;o ANC, EMV, Maes M. Immunopathogenesis and immunogenetic variants in COVID-19. Curr Pharm Des. 2022;28:1780&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35598232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira AC, Soares VC, de Azevedo-Quintanilha IG, Dias SSG, Fintelman-Rodrigues N, Sacramento CQ, et al. SARS-CoV-2 engages inflammasome and pyroptosis in human primary monocytes. Cell Death Discov. 2021;7:43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7919254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33649297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong TL, Weitzer DJ. Long COVID and Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS)-A systemic review and comparison of clinical presentation and symptomatology. Medicina (Kaunas) 2021;57:418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8145228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33925784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, Hishmeh L. Managing the long term effects of covid-19: summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ. 2021;372:n136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cares-Marambio K, Montenegro-Jim&#xe9;nez Y, Torres-Castro R, Vera-Uribe R, Torralba Y, Alsina-Restoy X, et al. Prevalence of potential respiratory symptoms in survivors of hospital admission after coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Chron Respir Dis. 2021;18:14799731211002240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7975482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33729021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT, Hamilton FW, Milne A, Morley AJ, Viner J, Attwood M, et al. Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up: results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax. 2021;76:399&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re'em Y, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simani L, Ramezani M, Darazam IA, Sagharichi M, Aalipour MA, Ghorbani F, et al. Prevalence and correlates of chronic fatigue syndrome and post-traumatic stress disorder after the outbreak of the COVID-19. J Neurovirol. 2021;27:154&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7852482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33528827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirulli ET, Schiabor Barrett KM, Riffle S, Bolze A, Neveux I, Dabe S, et al. Long-term COVID-19 symptoms in a large unselected population. medRxiv. 2020. 2020.10.07.20208702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.10.07.20208702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li X, Geng D, Mei N, Wu PY, Huang CC, et al. Cerebral micro-structural changes in COVID-19 patients &#x2013; an MRI-based 3-month follow-up study. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B, Peters JB, Brink M, Schoon Y, Bleeker-Rovers CP, Schers H, et al. Comprehensive health assessment 3 months after recovery from acute coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e1089&#x2013;e98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hakeim HK, Al-Rubaye HT, Al-Hadrawi DS, Almulla AF, Maes M. Long-COVID post-viral chronic fatigue and affective symptoms are associated with oxidative damage, lowered antioxidant defenses and inflammation: a proof of concept and mechanism study. Mol Psychiatry. 2023;28:564&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9589528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36280755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hakeim HK, Al-Rubaye HT, Almulla AF, Al-Hadrawi DS, Maes M. Chronic fatigue, depression and anxiety symptoms in Long COVID are strongly predicted by neuroimmune and neuro-oxidative pathways which are caused by the inflammation during acute infection. J Clin Med. 2023;12:511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9865328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36675440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Jassas HK, Al-Hakeim HK, Maes M. Intersections between pneumonia, lowered oxygen saturation percentage and immune activation mediate depression, anxiety, and chronic fatigue syndrome-like symptoms due to COVID-19: a nomothetic network approach. J Affect Disord. 2022;297:233&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8541833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34699853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hadrawi DS, Al-Rubaye HT, Almulla AF, Al-Hakeim HK, Maes M. Lowered oxygen saturation and increased body temperature in acute COVID-19 largely predict chronic fatigue syndrome and affective symptoms due to Long COVID: a precision nomothetic approach. Acta Neuropsychiatr. 2022 Sep 22:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1017/neu.2022.21. Online ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/neu.2022.21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36134517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tharakan S, Nomoto K, Miyashita S, Ishikawa K. Body temperature correlates with mortality in COVID-19 patients. Crit Care. 2020;24:298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7274509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32503659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M. Precision nomothetic medicine in depression research: a new depression model, and new endophenotype classes and pathway phenotypes, and a digital self. J Pers Med. 2022;12:403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8955533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35330403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Risks and burdens of incident diabetes in long COVID: a cohort study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2022;10:311&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8937253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35325624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montefusco L, Ben Nasr M, D&#x2019;Addio F, Loretelli C, Rossi A, Pastore I, et al. Acute and long-term disruption of glycometabolic control after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Metab. 2021;3:774&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9931026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34035524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M, Carvalho AF. The Compensatory Immune-Regulatory Reflex System (CIRS) in depression and bipolar disorder. Mol Neurobiol. 2018;55:8885&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29611101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morelli NR, Maes M, Bonifacio KL, Vargas HO, Nunes SOV, Barbosa DS. Increased nitro-oxidative toxicity in association with metabolic syndrome, atherogenicity and insulin resistance in patients with affective disorders. J Affect Disord. 2021;294:410&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34320448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Melo LGP, Nunes SOV, Anderson G, Vargas HO, Barbosa DS, Galecki P, et al. Shared metabolic and immune-inflammatory, oxidative and nitrosative stress pathways in the metabolic syndrome and mood disorders. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2017;78:34&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28438472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva N, Atlantis E, Ismail K. A review of the association between depression and insulin resistance: pitfalls of secondary analyses or a promising new approach to prevention of type 2 diabetes? Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2012;14:8&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22094982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kan C, Silva N, Golden SH, Rajala U, Timonen M, Stahl D, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of the association between depression and insulin resistance. Diabetes Care. 2013;36:480&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3554272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23349152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte-Silva E, de Melo MG, Maes M, Chaves AJM, Filho, Macedo D, Peixoto CA. Shared metabolic and neuroimmune mechanisms underlying type 2 diabetes mellitus and major depressive disorder. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2021;111:110351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34000290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoelson SE, Lee J, Goldfine AB. Inflammation and insulin resistance. J Clin Invest. 2006;116:1793&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1483173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16823477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rheinheimer J, de Souza BM, Cardoso NS, Bauer AC, Crispim D. Current role of the NLRP3 inflammasome on obesity and insulin resistance: a systematic review. Metabolism. 2017;74:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28764843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO)  A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021 [Internet] 2021 [cited 2023 Feb 15]. reliefweb.int/report/world/clinical-case-definition-post-covid-19-condition-delphi-consensus-6-october-2021?gclid=Cj0KCQiAorKfBhC0ARIsAHDzslsoI9NNzjwYbyfiO3UuYiLkGKNvbxe_2xd1d22RheFwqyjItYltOVEaAgz7EALw_wcB</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton M. A rating scale for depression. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1960;23:56&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC495331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14399272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangeeta S. Metformin and pioglitazone in polycystic ovarian syndrome: a comparative study. J Obstet Gynaecol India. 2012;62:551&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3526710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24082557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pernicova I, Korbonits M. Metformin &#x2013; mode of action and clinical implications for diabetes and cancer. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2014;10:143&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24393785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck AT, Steer RA, Brown GK. Beck depression inventory (BDI-II) London: Pearson; 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geloneze B, Vasques ACJ, Stabe CFC, Pareja JC, Rosado LEFPdL, de Queiroz EC, et al. HOMA1-IR and HOMA2-IR indexes in identifying insulin resistance and metabolic syndrome: Brazilian Metabolic Syndrome Study (BRAMS) Arq Bras Endocrinol Metabol. 2009;53:281&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19466221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringle CM, Wende S, Becker JM. SmartPLS 3. B&#xf6;nningstedt: SmartPLS; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y, He H, Zhang J, Ou Y, Fan N. Changes in serum TNF-&#x3b1;, IL-18, and IL-6 concentrations in patients with chronic schizophrenia at admission and at discharge. Compr Psychiatry. 2019;90:82&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30782515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govender N, Khaliq OP, Moodley J, Naicker T. Insulin resistance in COVID-19 and diabetes. Prim Care Diabetes. 2021;15:629&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8031259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33849817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He X, Liu C, Peng J, Li Z, Li F, Wang J, et al. COVID-19 induces new-onset insulin resistance and lipid metabolic dysregulation via regulation of secreted metabolic factors. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6:427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8674414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34916489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramczyk U, Nowaczy&#x144;ski M, S&#x142;omczy&#x144;ski A, Wojnicz P, Zatyka P, Kuzan A. Consequences of COVID-19 for the pancreas. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8776154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35055050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan WJ, Ni ZY, Hu Y, Liang WH, Ou CQ, He JX, et al. Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:1708&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32109013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan WJ, Liang WH, Zhao Y, Liang HR, Chen ZS, Li YM, et al. Comorbidity and its impact on 1590 patients with COVID-19 in China: a nationwide analysis. T Eur Respir J. 2020;55:2000547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7098485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bornstein SR, Rubino F, Khunti K, Mingrone G, Hopkins D, Birkenfeld AL, et al. Practical recommendations for the management of diabetes in patients with COVID-19. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2020;8:546&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7180013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32334646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho Vidigal F, Cocate PG, Pereira LG, Alfenas RCCG. The role of hyperglycemia in the induction of oxidative stress and inflammatory process. Nutr Hosp. 2012;27:1391&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23478683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddaloni E, Buzzetti R. Covid-19 and diabetes mellitus: unveiling the interaction of two pandemics. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2020;36:e33213321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32233018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prete M, Favoino E, Catacchio G, Racanelli V, Perosa F. SARS-CoV-2 inflammatory syndrome. Clinical features and rationale for immunological treatment. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:3377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7247005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32397684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiappetta S, Sharma AM, Bottino V, Stier C. COVID-19 and the role of chronic inflammation in patients with obesity. Int J Obes (Lond) 2020;44:1790&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7224343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32409680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mraz M, Haluzik M. The role of adipose tissue immune cells in obesity and low-grade inflammation. J Endocrinol. 2014;222:R113&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25006217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Luca C, Olefsky JM. Inflammation and insulin resistance. FEBS Lett. 2008;582:97&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2246086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18053812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Long YS, Gozal D, Epstein PN. &#x3b2;-cell death and proliferation after intermittent hypoxia: role of oxidative stress. Free Radic Biol Med. 2009;46:783&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19133326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantley J, Grey ST, Maxwell PH, Withers DJ. The hypoxia response pathway and &#x3b2;-cell function. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2010;12(Suppl 2):159&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21029313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber PA, Rutter GA. The role of oxidative stress and hypoxia in pancreatic beta-cell dysfunction in diabetes mellitus. Antioxid Redox Signal. 2017;26:501&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5372767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27225690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiedge M, Lortz S, Drinkgern J, Lenzen S. Relation between antioxidant enzyme gene expression and antioxidative defense status of insulin-producing cells. Diabetes. 1997;46:1733&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9356019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenzen S, Drinkgern J, Tiedge M. Low antioxidant enzyme gene expression in pancreatic islets compared with various other mouse tissues. Free Radic Biol Med. 1996;20:463&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8720919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negoro S, Kunisada K, Fujio Y, Funamoto M, Darville MI, Eizirik DL, et al. Activation of signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 protects cardiomyocytes from hypoxia/reoxygenation-induced oxidative stress through the upregulation of manganese superoxide dismutase. Circulation. 2001;104:979&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11524388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurrle S, Hsu WH. The etiology of oxidative stress in insulin resistance. Biomed J. 2017;40:257&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6138814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29179880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The OpenSAFELY Collaborative, Tazare J, Walker AJ, Tomlinson LT, Hickman G, Rentsch CT, et al. Rates of serious clinical outcomes in survivors of hospitalisation with COVID-19: a descriptive cohort study within the OpenSAFELY platform. MedRxiv. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.01.22.21250304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10285340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37362009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathish T, Kapoor N, Cao Y, Tapp RJ, Zimmet P. Proportion of newly diagnosed diabetes in COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2021;23:870&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33245182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CT, Lidsky PV, Xiao Y, Lee IT, Cheng R, Nakayama T, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infects human pancreatic &#x3b2; cells and elicits &#x3b2; cell impairment. Cell Metab. 2021;33:1565&#x2013;76.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8130512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34081912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller JA, Gro&#xdf; R, Conzelmann C, Kr&#xfc;ger J, Merle U, Steinhart J, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infects and replicates in cells of the human endocrine and exocrine pancreas. Nat Metab. 2021;3:149&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33536639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaharuddin SH, Wang V, Santos RS, Gross A, Wang Y, Jawanda H, et al. Deleterious effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on human pancreatic cells. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2021;11:678482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8285288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34282405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayden MR, Yang Y, Habibi J, Bagree SV, Sowers JR. Pericytopathy: oxidative stress and impaired cellular longevity in the pancreas and skeletal muscle in metabolic syndrome and type 2 diabetes. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2010;3:290&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3154033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21150342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kusmartseva I, Wu W, Syed F, Van Der Heide V, Jorgensen M, Joseph P, et al. Expression of SARS-CoV-2 entry factors in the pancreas of normal organ donors and individuals with COVID-19. Cell Metab. 2020;32:1041&#x2013;51.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7664515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33207244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima-Mart&#xed;nez MM, Boada CC, Madera-Silva MD, Mar&#xed;n W, Contreras M. COVID-19 and diabetes: a bidirectional relationship. Clin Investig Arterioscler. 2021;33:151&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7598432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azar WS, Njeim R, Fares AH, Azar NS, Azar ST, El Sayed M, et al. COVID-19 and diabetes mellitus: how one pandemic worsens the other. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2020;21:451&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7395898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32743793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou-Ismail MY, Diamond A, Kapoor S, Arafah Y, Nayak L. The hypercoagulable state in COVID-19: incidence, pathophysiology, and management. Thromb Res. 2020;194:101&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7305763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhania N, Bansal S, Nimmatoori DP, Ejaz AA, McCullough PA, Singhania G. Current overview on hypercoagulability in COVID-19. Am J Cardiovasc Drugs. 2020;20:393&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7398761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32748336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowenstein CJ, Solomon SD. Severe COVID-19 is a microvascular disease. Circulation. 2020;142:1609&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7580651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32877231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrow RM, Picard M, Derbeneva O, Leipzig J, McManus MJ, Gouspillou G, et al. Mitochondrial energy deficiency leads to hyperproliferation of skeletal muscle mitochondria and enhanced insulin sensitivity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2017;114:2705&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5347565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28223503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M, Galecki P, Chang YS, Berk M. A review on the oxidative and nitrosative stress (O&amp;NS) pathways in major depression and their possible contribution to the (neuro) degenerative processes in that illness. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2011;35:676&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20471444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hakeim HK, Al-Naqeeb TH, Almulla AF, Maes M. The physio-affective phenome of major depression is strongly associated with biomarkers of astroglial and neuronal projection toxicity which in turn are associated with peripheral inflammation, insulin resistance and lowered calcium. medRxiv. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13140/RG.2.2.17977.85606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36996718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenna H, Hoeft F, Kelley R, Wroolie T, DeMuth B, Reiss A, et al. Fasting plasma insulin and the default mode network in women at risk for Alzheimer's disease. Neurobiol Aging. 2013;34:641&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4769033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22770543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasgon NL, Kenna HA, Wroolie TE, Kelley R, Silverman D, Brooks J, et al. Insulin resistance and hippocampal volume in women at risk for Alzheimer's disease. Neurobiol Aging. 2011;32:1942&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2891925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20031276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasgon NL, Kenna HA, Wroolie TE, Williams KE, DeMuth BN, Silverman DH. Insulin resistance and medial prefrontal gyrus metabolism in women receiving hormone therapy. Psychiatry Res. 2014;223:28&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24819305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milstein JL, Ferris HA. The brain as an insulin-sensitive metabolic organ. Mol Metab. 2021;52:101234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8513144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33845179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park L, Furey M, Nugent AC, Farmer C, Ellis J, Szczepanik J, et al. Neurophysiological changes associated with antidepressant response to ketamine not observed in a negative trial of scopolamine in major depressive disorder. Int J Neuropsychopharmacol. 2019;22:10&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6313153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30184133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janus A, Szahidewicz-Krupska E, Mazur G, Doroszko A. Insulin resistance and endothelial dysfunction constitute a common therapeutic target in cardiometabolic disorders. Mediators Inflamm. 2016;2016:3634948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4931075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27413253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleinridders A, Cai W, Cappellucci L, Ghazarian A, Collins WR, Vienberg SG, et al. Insulin resistance in brain alters dopamine turnover and causes behavioral disorders. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2015;112:3463&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4371978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25733901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodd S, Sominsky L, Siskind D, Bortolasci CC, Carvalho AF, Maes M, et al. The role of metformin as a treatment for neuropsychiatric illness. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2022;64:32&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36191545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey CJ, Gwilt M. Diabetes, metformin and the clinical course of covid-19: outcomes, mechanisms and suggestions on the therapeutic use of metformin. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:784459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8964397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35370738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Z, Yang KY, Huang Y, Lui KO. Endothelial contribution to COVID-19: an update on mechanisms and therapeutic implications. J Mol Cell Cardiol. 2022;164:69&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8610843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34838588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>