<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37380640</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2058-7716</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cell death discovery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cell Death Discov</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on human brain and memory.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>196</StartPage><MedlinePgn>196</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">196</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41420-023-01512-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) variants have caused several waves of outbreaks. From the ancestral strain to Omicron variant, SARS-CoV-2 has evolved with the high transmissibility and increased immune escape against vaccines. Because of the multiple basic amino acids in the S1-S2 junction of spike protein, the widespread distribution of angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) receptor in human body and the high transmissibility, SARS-CoV-2 can infect multiple organs and has led to over 0.7 billion infectious cases. Studies showed that SARS-CoV-2 infection can cause more than 10% patients with the Long-COVID syndrome, including pathological changes in brains. This review mainly provides the molecular foundations for understanding the mechanism of SARS-CoV-2 invading human brain and the molecular basis of SARS-CoV-2 infection interfering with human brain and memory, which are associated with the immune dysfunction, syncytia-induced cell death, the persistence of SARS-CoV-2 infection, microclots and biopsychosocial aspects. We also discuss the strategies for reducing the Long-COVID syndrome. Further studies and analysis of shared researches will allow for further clarity regarding the long-term health consequences.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Qiulu</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Finance and Business, Shanghai Normal University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Education, Shanghai Normal University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>HanJun</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-9014-6972</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, School of Clinical Medicine, LKS Faculty of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Pokfulam, Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, China. hjzhao13@hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Virology, Vaccinology and Therapeutics, Science Park, Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, China. hjzhao13@hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cell Death Discov</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101665035</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2058-7716</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37380640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10307823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41420-023-01512-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41420-023-01512-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hosp JA, Dressing A, Blazhenets G, Bormann T, Rau A, Schwabenland M, et al. Cognitive impairment and altered cerebral glucose metabolism in the subacute stage of COVID-19. Brain. 2021;144:1263&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8083602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33822001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93:1013&#x2013;22..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues E, Janvier P, Kherabi Y, Le Bot A, Hamon A, Gouze H, et al. Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. J Infect. 2020;81:e4&#x2013;e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo MS, Malsy J, P&#xf6;ttgen J, Seddiq Zai S, Ufer F, Hadjilaou A, et al. Frequent neurocognitive deficits after recovery from mild COVID-19. Brain Commun. 2020;2:fcaa205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33376990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Desai AD, Wan EY. Post-COVID-19 Condition. Annu Rev Med. 2023;74:55&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35914765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236&#x2009;379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416&#x2013;27..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guasp M, Mu&#xf1;oz-S&#xe1;nchez G, Mart&#xed;nez-Hern&#xe1;ndez E, Santana D, Carbayo &#xc1;, Naranjo L, et al. CSF biomarkers in COVID-19 associated encephalopathy and encephalitis predict long-term outcome. Front Immunol. 2022;13:866153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9035899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35479062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francistiov&#xe1; L, Klepe A, Curley G, Gulya K, Dinny&#xe9;s A, Filkor K. Cellular and molecular effects of SARS-CoV-2 linking lung infection to the brain. Front Immunol. 2021;12:730088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8414801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34484241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J, Radke J, Dittmayer C, Franz J, Thomas C, Mothes R, et al. Olfactory transmucosal SARS-CoV-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with COVID-19. Nat Neurosci. 2021;24:168&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mjokane N, Folorunso OS, Ogundeji AO, Sebolai OM. The possible role of microbial proteases in facilitating SARS-CoV-2 brain invasion. Biology. 2021;10:966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8533249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34681064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krasemann S, Haferkamp U, Pfefferle S, Woo MS, Heinrich F, Schweizer M, et al. The blood-brain barrier is dysregulated in COVID-19 and serves as a CNS entry route for SARS-CoV-2. Stem Cell Rep. 2022;17:307&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8772030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35063125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forrester JV, McMenamin PG, Dando SJ. CNS infection and immune privilege. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2018;19:655&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30310148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casagrande M, Fitzek A, Spitzer M, P&#xfc;schel K, Glatzel M, Krasemann S, et al. Detection of SARS-CoV-2 genomic and subgenomic RNA in retina and optic nerve of patients with COVID-19. Br J Ophthalmol. 2022;106:1313&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8042582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casagrande M, Fitzek A, P&#xfc;schel K, Aleshcheva G, Schultheiss HP, Berneking L, et al. Detection of SARS-CoV-2 in human retinal biopsies of deceased COVID-19 patients. Ocul Immunol Inflamm. 2020;28:721&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinho PM, Marcos AAA, Romano AC, Nascimento H, Belfort R., Jr Retinal findings in patients with COVID-19. Lancet. 2020;395:1610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7217650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32405105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YP, Ma Y, Wang N, Jin ZB. Eyes on coronavirus. Stem Cell Res. 2021;51:102200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7838582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33535156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atum M, Boz AAE, &#xc7;ak&#x131;r B, Karabay O, K&#xf6;ro&#x11f;lu M, &#xd6;&#x11f;&#xfc;tl&#xfc; A, et al. Evaluation of conjunctival swab PCR results in patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Ocul Immunol Inflamm. 2020;28:745&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32569495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozturker ZK. Conjunctivitis as sole symptom of COVID-19: a case report and review of literature. Eur J Ophthalmol. 2021;31:Np161&#x2013;np6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32703010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scalinci SZ, Trovato Battagliola E. Conjunctivitis can be the only presenting sign and symptom of COVID-19. IDCases. 2020;20:e00774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32373467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu P, Liang L, Chen C, Nie S. A child confirmed COVID-19 with only symptoms of conjunctivitis and eyelid dermatitis. Graef Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2020;258:1565&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7181963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32333104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szcz&#x119;&#x15b;niak M, Brydak-Godowska J. SARS-CoV-2 and the eyes: a review of the literature on transmission, detection, and ocular manifestations. Med Sci Monit. 2021;27:e931863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8439119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34508064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitazawa K, Deinhardt-Emmer S, Inomata T, Deshpande S, Sotozono C. The transmission of SARS-CoV-2 infection on the ocular surface and prevention strategies. Cells. 2021;10:796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8065845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33918318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E, Zhang C, Israelow B, Lu-Culligan A, Prado AV, Skriabine S, et al. Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 in human and mouse brain. J Exp Med. 2021;218:e20202135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashraf UM, Abokor AA, Edwards JM, Waigi EW, Royfman RS, Hasan SA, et al. SARS-CoV-2, ACE2 expression, and systemic organ invasion. Physiol Genom. 2021;53:51&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7900915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33275540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrini L, Albecka A, Mallery DL, Kellner MJ, Paul D, Carter AP, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infects the brain choroid plexus and disrupts the blood-CSF barrier in human brain organoids. Cell Stem Cell. 2020;27:951&#x2013;61.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7553118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33113348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R, Wang K, Yu J, Howard D, French L, Chen Z, et al. The spatial and cell-type distribution of SARS-CoV-2 receptor ACE2 in the human and mouse brains. Front Neurol. 2020;11:573095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7855591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33551947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang BZ, Chu H, Han S, Shuai H, Deng J, Hu YF, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infects human neural progenitor cells and brain organoids. Cell Res. 2020;30:928&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7399356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson CB, Farzan M, Chen B, Choe H. Mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2 entry into cells. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2022;23:3&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8491763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clausen TM, Sandoval DR, Spliid CB, Pihl J, Perrett HR, Painter CD, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection depends on cellular heparan sulfate and ACE2. Cell. 2020;183:1043&#x2013;57.e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7489987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32970989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, Chen W, Zhang Z, Deng Y, Lian JQ, Du P, et al. CD147-spike protein is a novel route for SARS-CoV-2 infection to host cells. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2020;5:283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7714896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33277466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shilts J, Crozier TWM, Greenwood EJD, Lehner PJ, Wright GJ. No evidence for basigin/CD147 as a direct SARS-CoV-2 spike binding receptor. Sci Rep. 2021;11:413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7801465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33432067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Qiu Z, Hou Y, Deng X, Xu W, Zheng T, et al. AXL is a candidate receptor for SARS-CoV-2 that promotes infection of pulmonary and bronchial epithelial cells. Cell Res. 2021;31:126&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7791157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33420426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantuti-Castelvetri L, Ojha R, Pedro LD, Djannatian M, Franz J, Kuivanen S, et al. Neuropilin-1 facilitates SARS-CoV-2 cell entry and infectivity. Science. 2020;370:856&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33082293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies J, Randeva HS, Chatha K, Hall M, Spandidos DA, Karteris E, et al. Neuropilin&#x2011;1 as a new potential SARS&#x2011;CoV&#x2011;2 infection mediator implicated in the neurologic features and central nervous system involvement of COVID&#x2011;19. Mol Med Rep. 2020;22:4221&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7533503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33000221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spudich S, Nath A. Nervous system consequences of COVID-19. Science. 2022;375:267&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35050660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, Cheng V, Dagens A, Hastie C, et al. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6:e005427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pintos-Pascual I, Moreno-Torres V, Ib&#xe1;nez-Est&#xe9;llez F, Corrales-Rodriguez P, Trevi&#xf1;o A, Corpas M, et al. Is SARS-CoV-2 the only cause of long-COVID? AIDS Rev. 2022;24:183&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36427058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale-Cross L, Szalayova I, Scoggins A, Palkovits M, Mezey E. SARS-CoV-2 entry sites are present in all structural elements of the human glossopharyngeal and vagal nerves: clinical implications. EBioMedicine. 2022;78:103981..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8978584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35390636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryce C, Grimes Z, Pujadas E, Ahuja S, Beasley MB, Albrecht R, et al. Pathophysiology of SARS-CoV-2: the Mount Sinai COVID-19 autopsy experience. Mod Pathol. 2021;34:1456&#x2013;67..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8015313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33795830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F, Arthofer C, Wang C, McCarthy P, et al. SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature. 2022;604:697&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9046077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kremer S, J&#xe4;ger HR. Brain changes after COVID-19&#x2014;how concerned should we be? Nat Rev Neurol. 2022;18:321&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9022737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35449462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson RW, Brown RL, Benjamin L, Nortley R, Wiethoff S, Bharucha T, et al. The emerging spectrum of COVID-19 neurology: clinical, radiological and laboratory findings. Brain. 2020;143:3104&#x2013;20..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32637987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkai I, Mayer MG, Hellmers LM, Ning B, Huang Z, Monjure CJ, et al. Neuropathology and virus in brain of SARS-CoV-2 infected non-human primates. Nat Commun. 2022;13:1745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8975902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35365631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen WB, Logue J, Yang P, Baracco L, Elahi M, Reece EA, et al. SARS-CoV-2 invades cognitive centers of the brain and induces Alzheimer&#x2019;s-like neuropathology. bioRxiv:478476v3 [Preprint]. 2022. Available from: 10.1101/2022.01.31.478476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Meng X, Peng Z, Lam H, Zhang C, Zhou X, et al. Fusion-inhibition peptide broadly inhibits influenza virus and SARS-CoV-2, including Delta and Omicron variants. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2022;11:926&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8973381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35259078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braga L, Ali H, Secco I, Chiavacci E, Neves G, Goldhill D, et al. Drugs that inhibit TMEM16 proteins block SARS-CoV-2 spike-induced syncytia. Nature. 2021;594:88&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33827113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z, Shi L, Wang Y, Zhang J, Huang L, Zhang C, et al. Pathological findings of COVID-19 associated with acute respiratory distress syndrome. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8:420&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7164771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32085846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bussani R, Schneider E, Zentilin L, Collesi C, Ali H, Braga L, et al. Persistence of viral RNA, pneumocyte syncytia and thrombosis are hallmarks of advanced COVID-19 pathology. EBioMedicine. 2020;61:103104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7677597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33158808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma H, Zhu Z, Lin H, Wang S, Zhang P, Li Y, et al. Pyroptosis of syncytia formed by fusion of SARS-CoV-2 spike and ACE2-expressing cells. Cell Discov. 2021;7:73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8384103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34429403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osorio C, Sfera A, Anton JJ, Thomas KG, Andronescu CV, Li E, et al. Virus-induced membrane fusion in neurodegenerative disorders. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2022;12:845580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9070112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35531328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L, Li Q, Wang Y, Shi Y. Syncytia formation during SARS-CoV-2 lung infection: a disastrous unity to eliminate lymphocytes. Cell Death Differ. 2021;28:2019&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8114657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33981020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y, Zhou LL, Su Y, Sun Q. Cell fusion in the pathogenesis of COVID-19. Mil Med Res. 2021;8:68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8684830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34924024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arga&#xf1;araz GA, Palmeira JDF, Arga&#xf1;araz ER. Phosphatidylserine inside out: a possible underlying mechanism in the inflammation and coagulation abnormalities of COVID-19. Cell Commun Signal. 2020;18:190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7765775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33357215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Zheng Y, Niu Z, Zhang B, Wang C, Yao X, et al. SARS-CoV-2 spike protein dictates syncytium-mediated lymphocyte elimination. Cell Death Differ. 2021;28:2765&#x2013;77..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33879858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, To KKW, Lam H, Zhou X, Chan JF, Peng Z, et al. Cross-linking peptide and repurposed drugs inhibit both entry pathways of SARS-CoV-2. Nat Commun. 2021;12:1517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7943568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33750821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Marmol R, Giordano-Santini R, Kaulich E, Cho A-N, Riyadh MA, Robinson E, et al. The SARS-CoV-2 spike (S) and the orthoreovirus p15 cause neuronal and glial fusion. bioRxiv:458544v1. [Preprint]. 2021. Available from: 10.1101/2021.09.01.458544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitamura T, Ogawa SK, Roy DS, Okuyama T, Morrissey MD, Smith LM, et al. Engrams and circuits crucial for systems consolidation of a memory. Science. 2017;356:73&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5493329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28386011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy DS, Park YG, Kim ME, Zhang Y, Ogawa SK, DiNapoli N, et al. Brain-wide mapping reveals that engrams for a single memory are distributed across multiple brain regions. Nat Commun. 2022;13:1799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8980018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35379803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson LT. Memory and the brain. J Dent Educ. 2002;66:30&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12358099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumaria A, Noah A, Kirkman MA. Does covid-19 impair endogenous neurogenesis? J Clin Neurosci. 2022;105:79&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36113246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano GE, Walker JE, Tremblay C, Piras IS, Huentelman MJ, Belden CM, et al. ShareSARS-CoV-2 Brain Regional Detection, Histopathology, Gene Expression, and Immunomodulatory Changes in Decedents with COVID-19. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2022;81:666&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9278252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35818336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crunfli F, Carregari VC, Veras FP, Silva LS, Nogueira MH, Antunes A, et al. Morphological, cellular, and molecular basis of brain infection in COVID-19 patients. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2022;119:e2200960119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9436354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35951647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnefeesi Y, Siegel A, Lui LMW, Teopiz KM, Ho RCM, Lee Y, et al. Impact of SARS-CoV-2 infection on cognitive function: a systematic review. Front Psychiatry. 2020;11:621773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7902710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33643083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wulf Hanson S, Abbafati C, Aerts JG, Al-Aly Z, Ashbaugh C, Ballouz T, et al. Estimated Global Proportions of Individuals With Persistent Fatigue, Cognitive, and Respiratory Symptom Clusters Following Symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA. 2022;328:1604&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trapani G, Verlato G, Bertino E, Maiocco G, Vesentini R, Spadavecchia A, et al. Long COVID-19 in children: an Italian cohort study. Ital J Pediatr. 2022;48:83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9163526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35659358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Pujol FE, Munblit D, Pata D, McFarland S, Simpson FK. Clinical characteristics, activity levels and mental health problems in children with long coronavirus disease: a survey of 510 children. Future Microbiol. 2022;17:577&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9248023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35360923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blows WT. Child brain development. Nurs. 2003;99:28&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12747179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camacho MC, Qui&#xf1;ones-Camacho LE, Perlman SB. Does the child brain rest?: An examination and interpretation of resting cognition in developmental cognitive neuroscience. Neuroimage. 2020;212:116688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7190083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32114148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes I, Karmirian K, Oliveira JT, Pedrosa C, Mendes MA, Rosman FC, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection of the central nervous system in a 14-month-old child: a case report of a complete autopsy. Lancet Reg Health Am. 2021;2:100046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8397543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34485969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horikoshi Y, Shibata M, Funakoshi H, Baba S, Miyama S. Post COVID-19 condition in children at a children&#x2019;s hospital in Japan. Pediatr Int. 2023;65:e15458..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9880635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36560907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond MS, Kanneganti TD. Innate immunity: the first line of defense against SARS-CoV-2. Nat Immunol. 2022;23:165&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8935980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soung AL, Vanderheiden A, Nordvig AS, Sissoko CA, Canoll P, Mariani MB, et al. COVID-19 induces CNS cytokine expression and loss of hippocampal neurogenesis. Brain. 2022;145:4193&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9452175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36004663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo P, Benito Ballesteros A, Yeung SP, Liu R, Saha A, Curtis L, et al. COVCOG 2: cognitive and memory deficits in long COVID: a second publication from the COVID and cognition study. Front Aging Neurosci. 2022;14:804937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8967943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35370620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathew D, Giles JR, Baxter AE, Oldridge DA, Greenplate AR, Wu JE, et al. Deep immune profiling of COVID-19 patients reveals distinct immunotypes with therapeutic implications. Science. 2020;369:eabc8511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7402624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32669297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soy M, Keser G, Atag&#xfc;nd&#xfc;z P, Tabak F, Atag&#xfc;nd&#xfc;z I, Kayhan S. Cytokine storm in COVID-19: pathogenesis and overview of anti-inflammatory agents used in treatment. Clin Rheumatol. 2020;39:2085&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7260446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32474885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGonagle D, Sharif K, O'Regan A, Bridgewood C. The role of cytokines including interleukin-6 in COVID-19 induced pneumonia and macrophage activation syndrome-like disease. Autoimmun Rev. 2020;19:102537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad S, Lokensgard JR. Brain-resident T cells following viral infection. Viral Immunol. 2019;32:48&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6350058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30230418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smolders J, Heutinck KM, Fransen NL, Remmerswaal EBM, Hombrink P, Ten Berge IJM, et al. Tissue-resident memory T cells populate the human brain. Nat Commun. 2018;9:4593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6214977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30389931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastard P, Rosen LB, Zhang Q, Michailidis E, Hoffmann HH, Zhang Y, et al. Autoantibodies against type I IFNs in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science. 2020;370:eabd4585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Y, Estes SK, Ali RA, Gandhi AA, Yalavarthi S, Shi H, et al. Prothrombotic autoantibodies in serum from patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Sci Transl Med. 2020;12:eabd3876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7724273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33139519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tejerina F, Catalan P, Rodriguez-Grande C, Adan J, Rodriguez-Gonzalez C, Mu&#xf1;oz P, et al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome. SARS-CoV-2 RNA detection in plasma, stool, and urine in patients with persistent symptoms after COVID-19. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22:211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8892394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35240997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Hang X, Wei B, Li D, Chen F, Liu W, et al. Persistent SARS-COV-2 RNA positivity in a patient for 92 days after disease onset: a case report. Medicine. 2020;99:e21865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7447437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32846839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truong TT, Ryutov A, Pandey U, Yee R, Goldberg L, Bhojwani D, et al. Increased viral variants in children and young adults with impaired humoral immunity and persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection: a consecutive case series. EBioMedicine. 2021;67:103355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33915337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma MJ, Qiu SF, Cui XM, Ni M, Liu HJ, Ye RZ, et al. Persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection in asymptomatic young adults. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2022;7:77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8905556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35264553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caba&#xf1;ero-Navalon MD, Garcia-Bustos V, Ruiz-Rodriguez P, Comas I, Coscoll&#xe1; M, Martinez-Priego L, et al. Persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection with repeated clinical recurrence in a patient with common variable immunodeficiency. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28:308&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8579735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34774757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B, Fan J, Huang J, Guo E, Fu Y, Liu S, et al. Clinical and molecular characteristics of COVID-19 patients with persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Commun. 2021;12:3501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8190301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34108465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank MG, Nguyen KH, Ball JB, Hopkins S, Kelley T, Baratta MV, et al. SARS-CoV-2 spike S1 subunit induces neuroinflammatory, microglial and behavioral sickness responses: evidence of PAMP-like properties. Brain Behav Immun. 2022;100:267&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8667429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34915155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang HP, Sun YL, Wang YF, Yazici D, Azkur D, Ogulur I, et al. Recent developments in the immunopathology of COVID-19. Allergy. 2023;78:369&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10108124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36420736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kell DB, Laubscher GJ, Pretorius E. A central role for amyloid fibrin microclots in long COVID/PASC: origins and therapeutic implications. Biochem J. 2022;479:537&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8883497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35195253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruger A, Vlok M, Turner S, Venter C, Laubscher GJ, Kell DB, et al. Proteomics of fibrin amyloid microclots in long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) shows many entrapped pro-inflammatory molecules that may also contribute to a failed fibrinolytic system. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21:190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9491257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36131342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH, Crooks MG. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is Long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;199:113&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelmann P, L&#xf6;we B, Brehm TT, Weigel A, Ullrich F, Addo MM, et al. Risk factors for worsening of somatic symptom burden in a prospective cohort during the COVID-19 pandemic. Front Psychol. 2022;13:1022203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9631939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36337508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastie CE, Lowe DJ, McAuley A, Winter AJ, Mills NL, Black C, et al. Outcomes among confirmed cases and a matched comparison group in the Long-COVID in Scotland study. Nat Commun. 2022;13:5663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9556711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36224173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slurink IAL, Smaardijk VR, Kop WJ, Kupper N, Mols F, Schoormans D, et al. Changes in perceived stress and lifestyle behaviors in response to the COVID-19 pandemic in the netherlands: an online longitudinal survey study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:4375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8998601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35410055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Rockl&#xf6;v J. The effective reproductive number of the Omicron variant of SARS-CoV-2 is several times relative to Delta. J Travel Med. 2022;29:taac037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8992231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35262737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedetti F, Mazza M, Cavalli G, Ciceri F, Dagna L, Rovere-Querini P. Can Cytokine Blocking Prevent Depression in COVID-19 Survivors? J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2021;16:1&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7587545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33107012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palladini M, Bravi B, Colombo F, Caselani E, Di Pasquasio C, D&#x2019;Orsi G, et al. Cognitive remediation therapy for post-acute persistent cognitive deficits in COVID-19 survivors: a proof-of-concept study. Neuropsychol Rehabil. 2022;18:1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35583357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bousquet J, Anto JM, Czarlewski W, Haahtela T, Fonseca SC, Iaccarino G, et al. Cabbage and fermented vegetables: from death rate heterogeneity in countries to candidates for mitigation strategies of severe COVID-19. Allergy. 2021;76:735&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7436771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32762135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piazza M, Di Cicco M, Pecoraro L, Ghezzi M, Peroni D, Comberiati P. Long COVID-19 in children: from the pathogenesis to the biologically plausible roots of the syndrome. Biomolecules. 2022;12:556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9024951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35454144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy E, Delvin E, Marcil V, Spahis S. Can phytotherapy with polyphenols serve as a powerful approach for the prevention and therapy tool of novel coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19)? Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2020;319:E689&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7518070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32755302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungnak W, Huang N, B&#xe9;cavin C, Berg M, Queen R, Litvinukova M, et al. SARS-CoV-2 entry factors are highly expressed in nasal epithelial cells together with innate immune genes. Nat Med. 2020;26:681&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8637938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32327758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muramatsu T. Basigin (CD147), a multifunctional transmembrane glycoprotein with various binding partners. J Biochem. 2016;159:481&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4846773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26684586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett TJ, Bilaloglu S, Cornwell M, Burgess HM, Virginio VW, Drenkova K, et al. Platelets contribute to disease severity in COVID-19. J Thromb Haemost. 2021;19:3139&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8646651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34538015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohan D, Van Ert H, Ruggio N, Rogers KJ, Badreddine M, Aguilar Brise&#xf1;o JA, et al. Phosphatidylserine receptors enhance SARS-CoV-2 infection. PLoS Pathog. 2021;17:e1009743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8641883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34797899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amraei R, Yin W, Napoleon MA, Suder EL, Berrigan J, Zhao Q, et al. CD209L/L-SIGN and CD209/DC-SIGN act as receptors for SARS-CoV-2. ACS Cent Sci. 2021;7:1156&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8265543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34341769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi N. C-type lectin CD209L/L-SIGN and CD209/DC-SIGN: cell adhesion molecules turned to pathogen recognition receptors. Biology. 2020;10:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7822156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33375175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karki R, Sharma BR, Tuladhar S, Williams EP, Zalduondo L, Samir P, et al. Synergism of TNF-&#x3b1; and IFN-&#x3b3; triggers inflammatory cell death, tissue damage, and mortality in SARS-CoV-2 infection and cytokine shock syndromes. Cell. 2021;184:149&#x2013;68.e17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7674074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33278357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damoiseaux J, Dotan A, Fritzler MJ, Bogdanos DP, Meroni PL, Roggenbuck D, et al. Autoantibodies and SARS-CoV2 infection: the spectrum from association to clinical implication: report of the 15th Dresden Symposium on Autoantibodies. Autoimmun Rev. 2022;21:103012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8656211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34896650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner S, Naidoo CA, Usher TJ, Kruger A, Venter C, Laubscher GJ, et al. Increased levels of inflammatory molecules in blood of Long COVID patients point to thrombotic endotheliitis. Semin Thromb Hemost. 2023; online ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37207671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfc;rnberger P, von Lewinski D, Rothenh&#xe4;usler HB, Braun C, Reinbacher P, Kolesnik E, et al. A biopsychosocial model of severe fear of COVID-19. PLoS ONE. 2022;17:e0264357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8884481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35226661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>