<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37655303</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2050-3121</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>SAGE open medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>SAGE Open Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID as a functional somatic symptom disorder caused by abnormally precise prior expectations during Bayesian perceptual processing: A new hypothesis and implications for pandemic response.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20503121231194400</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20503121231194400</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20503121231194400</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/20503121231194400</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This review proposes a model of Long-COVID where the constellation of symptoms are in fact genuinely experienced persistent physical symptoms that are usually functional in nature and therefore potentially reversible, that is, Long-COVID is a somatic symptom disorder. First, we describe what is currently known about Long-COVID in children and adults. Second, we examine reported "Long-Pandemic" effects that create a risk for similar somatic symptoms to develop in non-COVID-19 patients. Third, we describe what was known about somatization and somatic symptom disorder before the COVID-19 pandemic, and suggest that by analogy, Long-COVID may best be conceptualized as one of these disorders, with similar symptoms and predisposing, precipitating, and perpetuating factors. Fourth, we review the phenomenon of mass sociogenic (functional) illness, and the concept of nocebo effects, and suggest that by analogy, Long-COVID is compatible with these descriptions. Fifth, we describe the current theoretical model of the mechanism underlying functional disorders, the Bayesian predictive coding model for perception. This model accounts for moderators that can make symptom inferences functionally inaccurate and therefore can explain how to understand common predisposing, precipitating, and perpetuating factors. Finally, we discuss the implications of this framework for improved public health messaging during a pandemic, with recommendations for the management of Long-COVID symptoms in healthcare systems. We argue that the current public health approach has induced fear of Long-COVID in the population, including from constant messaging about disabling symptoms of Long-COVID and theorizing irreversible tissue damage as the cause of Long-COVID. This has created a self-fulfilling prophecy by inducing the very predisposing, precipitating, and perpetuating factors for the syndrome. Finally, we introduce the term "Pandemic-Response Syndrome" to describe what previously was labeled Long-COVID. This alternative perspective aims to stimulate research and serve as a lesson learned to avoid a repeat performance in the future.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joffe</LastName><ForeName>Ari R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4583-707X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elliott</LastName><ForeName>April</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>SAGE Open Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101624744</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-3121</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bayesian predictive processing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mass sociogenic illness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">somatic symptom disorder</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37655303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10467233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20503121231194400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_20503121231194400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, et al.. WHO clinical case definition working group on post-COVID-19 condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis 2022; 22(4): e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Gibney RTN, Blackman C, Fan E, et al.. COVID-19 pandemic: the impact on Canada&#x2019;s intensive care units. An RSC Policy Briefing. Royal Society of Canada. June 2022. Available at: https://rsc-src.ca/en/covid-19-policy-briefing-recent/covid-19-pandemic-impact-canada%E2%80%99s-intensive-care-units (Accessed 1 May, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus JV, Romero D, Kopka CJ, et al.. A multinational Delphi consensus to end the COVID-19 public health threat. Nature 2022; 611: 332&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9646517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36329272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE, et al.. Short-term and long-term rates of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. A systematic review. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4(10): e2128568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34643720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Manhas KP, Kania-Richmond A, Cunningham C, et al.. For the COVID-19 scientific advisory group rapid evidence report. Updated review of prolonged symptoms after acute COVID-19 infection. AHS July 12, 2021. https://www.albertahealthservices.ca/assets/info/ppih/if-ppih-covid-19-sag-chronic-symptoms-of-covid-rapid-review.pdf (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkodaymi MS, Omrani OA, Fawzy NA, et al.. Prevalence of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome symptoms at different follow-up periods: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect 2022; 28: 757&#x2013;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8812092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Burden of Disease Long COVID Collaborators. Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA 2022; 328(16): 1604&#x2013;1615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontera JA, Simon NM. Bridging knowledge gaps in the diagnosis and management of neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19. JAMA Psychiatry 2022; 79(8): 811&#x2013;817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35767287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, et al.. Long covid&#x2013;mechanisms, risk factors, and management. State of the art review. BMJ 2021; 374: n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson JL, Le Saux N. Children and long-COVID: Do they go together? J Assoc Med Micro Infect Dis 2022; 7(4): 300&#x2013;306. DOI: 10.3138/jammi-2022-09-26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3138/jammi-2022-09-26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10312225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37397825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Au L, Capotescu C, Eyal G, et al.. Long covid and medical gaslighting: dismissal, delayed diagnosis, and deferred treatment. SSM Qual Res Health 2022; 2: 100167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9448633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36092770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirt J, Janiaud P, Gloy V, et al.. Robustness of reported postacute health outcomes in children with SARS-CoV-2 infection: a systematic review. Arch Dis Child 2022; 108(6): 498&#x2013;505. DOI: 10.1136/archdischild-2022-324455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/archdischild-2022-324455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10314012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36719840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Pittet LF, Curtis N. How common is long COVID in children and adolescents? Pediatr Infect Dis J 2021; 40(12): e482&#x2013;e487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34870392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Pittet LF, Curtis N. The challenge of studying Long COVID: an updated review. Pediatr Infect Dis J 2022; 41: 424&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8997013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35213866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, del Valle NCA, et al.. Long-COVID in children and adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Sci Rep 2022; 12: 9950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9226045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35739136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Shafran R, Ladhani SN. Long COVID in children and adolescents. Curr Opin Infect Dis 2022; 35: 461&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9553244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36098262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behnood SA, Shafran R, Bennett SD, et al.. Persistent symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection amongst children and young people: a meta-analysis of controlled and uncontrolled studies. J Infect 2022; 84(2): 158&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8604800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34813820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira SMP, Shafran R, Nugawela MD, et al.. Natural course of health and well-being in non-hospitalized children and young people after testing for SARS-CoV-2: a prospective follow-up study over 12 months. Lancet 2023; 25: 100554. DOI: 10.1016/j.lanepe.2022.100554</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanepe.2022.100554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9719829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36504922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radtke T, Ulyte A, Puhan MA, et al.. Long-term symptoms after SARS-CoV-2 infection in children and adolescents. JAMA 2021; 326(9): 869&#x2013;871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8283661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34264266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blankenburg J, Wekenborg M, Reichert J, et al.. Comparison of mental health outcomes in seropositive and seronegative adolescents during the COVID19 pandemic. Sci Rep 2022; 12: 2246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8831534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35145161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zavala M, Ireland G, Amin-Chowdhury Z, et al.. Acute and persistent symptoms in children with PCR-confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection compared to test-negative children in England: active, prospective, national surveillance. Clin Infect Dis 2022; 75(1): e191&#x2013;e200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8767867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34849658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funk AL, Kuppermann N, Florin TA, et al.. Post-COVID-19 conditions among children 90 days after SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA Netw Open 2022; 5(7): e2223253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9308058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35867061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad A, Janda A, Renk H, et al.. Long COVID symptoms in exposed and infected children, adolescents and their parents one year after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a prospective observational cohort study. eBioMedicine 2022; 84: 104245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9495281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36155957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorg AL, Becht S, Jank M, et al.. Association of SARS-CoV-2 seropositivity with myalgic encephalomyelitis and/or chronic fatigue syndrome among children and adolescents in Germany. JAMA Netw Open 2022; 5(9): e2233454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9516317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36166227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borch L, Holm M, Knudsen M, et al.. Long COVID symptoms and duration in SARS-CoV-2 positive children&#x2013;a nationwide cohort study. Eur J Pediatr 2022; 181(4): 1597&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8742700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35000003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg SK, Palm P, Nygaard U, et al.. Long COVID symptoms in SARS-CoV-2-positive children aged 0-14 years and matched controls in Denmark (LongCOVIDKidsDK): a national, cross-sectional study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2022; 6(9): P614&#x2013;P623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9221683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35752194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg SK, Nielsen SD, Nygaard U, et al.. Long COVID symptoms in SARS-CoV-2-positive adolescents and matched controls (LongCOVIDKidsDK): a national, cross-sectional study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2022; 6: 240&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8820960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kompaniyets L, Bull-Otterson L, Boehmer TK, et al.. Post-COVID-19 symptoms and conditions among children and adolescents&#x2013;United States, March 1, 2020-January 31, 2002. MMWR 2022; 71(31): 993&#x2013;999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9368731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35925799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao S, Lee GM, Razzaghi H, et al.. Clinical features and burden of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection in children and adolescents. JAMA Pediatr 2022; 176(10): 1000&#x2013;1009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9396470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35994282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Romieu AC, Carton TW, Saydah S, et al.. Prevalence of select new symptoms and conditions among persons aged younger than 20 years and 20 years or older at 31 to 150 days after testing positive or negative for SARS-CoV-2. JAMA Netw Open 2022; 5(2): e2147053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8817203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35119459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Pereira SMP, Shafran R, et al.. Physical and mental health 3 months after SARS-CoV-2 infection (long COVID) among adolescents in England (CLoCk): a national matched cohort study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2022; 6: 230&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8820961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne AB, Gilani Z, Godfred-Cato S, et al.. Incidence of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children among US persons infected with SARS-CoV-2. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4: e2116420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8193431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34110391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Munblit D, De Rose C, et al.. Preliminary evidence on long COVID in children. Acta Paediatrica 2021; 110(7): 2208&#x2013;2211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33835507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Say D, Crawford N, McNab S, et al.. Post-acute COVID-19 outcomes in children with mild and asymptomatic disease. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2021; 5: e22&#x2013;e23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8057863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33891880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson K, Skyrud KD, Greve-Isdahl M, et al.. Healthcare use in 700 000 children and adolescents for six months after covid-19: before and after register based cohort study. BMJ 2022; 376: e066089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8762452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35039315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller F, Nguyen V, Navaratnam AMD, et al.. Prevalence of persistent symptoms in children during the COVID-19 pandemic: evidence from a household cohort study in England and Wales. Pediatr Infect Dis J 2022; 41(12): 979&#x2013;984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9645448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36375098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraaijeveld SR, Gur-Arie R, Jamrozik E. Against COVID-19 vaccination of healthy children. Bioethics 2022; 36: 687&#x2013;698. DOI: 10.1111/bioe.13015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bioe.13015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9111802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35332941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Hoog MLA, Sluiter-Post JGC, Westerhof I, et al.. Longitudinal household assessment of respiratory illness in children and parents during the COVID-19 pandemic. JAMA Netw Open 2022; 5(10): e2237522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9585428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36264578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rytter MJH. Difficult questions about long COVID in children. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2022; 6(9): P595&#x2013;P597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9221929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35752193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T, Hittle M, Goodman SN. Assessment of the frequency and variety of persistent symptoms among patients with COVID-19: a systematic review. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4(5): e2111417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8155823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34037731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson EJ, Williams DM, Walker AJ, et al.. Long COVID burden and risk factors in 10 UK longitudinal studies and electronic health records. Nat Commun 2022; 13: 3528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9240035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35764621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, et al.. Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or Long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis 2022; 226(9): 1593&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durstenfield MS, Sun K, Tahir P, et al.. Use of cardiopulmonary exercise testing to evaluate Long COVID-19 symptoms in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open 2022; 5(10): e2236057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9557896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36223120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasiam A, Prasad V. Comparability of control and comparison groups in studies assessing Long COVID. Am J Med. Epub ahead of print 25 January 2023. DOI: 10.1016/j.amjmed.2023.01.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2023.01.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9912142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36708796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Ling S, Lui LMW, et al.. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in post-COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun 2022; 101: 93&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin-Chowdhury Z, Ladhani SN. Causation or confounding: why controls are critical for characterizing long COVID. Nat Med 2021; 27: 1129&#x2013;1130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34140704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittaker HR, Gulea C, Koteci A, et al.. GP consultation rates for sequelae after acute covid-19 in patients managed in the community or hospital in the UK: population based study. BMJ 2021; 375: e065834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty SE, Guo Y, Heath K, et al.. Risk of clinical sequelae after the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection: retrospective cohort study. BMJ 2021; 373: n1098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8132065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Office for National Statistics. Technical article: updated estimates of the prevalence of post-acute symptoms among people with coronavirus (COVID-19) in the UK: 26 April 2020 to 1 August 2021, 2021. https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/articles/technicalarticleupdatedestimatesoftheprevalenceofpostacutesymptomsamongpeoplewithcoronaviruscovid19intheuk/26april2020to1august2021 (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, et al.. Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat Med 2022; 28: 1706&#x2013;1714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlis RH, Santillana M, Ognyanova K, et al.. Prevalence and correlates of long COVID symptoms among US adults. JAMA Netw Open 2022; 5(10): e223804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9614581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36301542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull-Otterson L, Baca S, Saydah S, et al.. Post-COVID conditions among adult COVID-19 survivors aged 18-64 and &#x2a7e;65 years&#x2013;Unites States, March 2020-November 2021. MMWR 2022; 71(21): 713&#x2013;717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, McAuley H, Harrison EM, et al.. Physical, cognitive, and mental health impacts of COVID-19 after hospitalization: a UK multicentre, prospective cohort study. Lancet Respir Med 2021; 9(11): 1275&#x2013;1287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34627560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et al.. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine 2021; 38: 101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziauddeen N, Gurdasani D, O&#x2019;Hara ME, et al.. Characteristics of long COVID: findings from a social media survey. PLoS One 2022; 17(3): e0264331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8903286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35259179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampshire A, Trender W, Chamberlain SR, et al.. Cognitive deficits in people who have recovered from COVID-19. EClinicalMedicine 2021; 39: 101044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8298139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34316551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan NA. The road to addressing long Covid. Science 2021; 373(6554): 491&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34326224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine RL. Addressing the long-term effects of COVID-19. JAMA 2022; 328(9): 823&#x2013;824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35921084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Hare AM, Vig EK, Iwashyna TJ, et al.. Complexity and challenges of the clinical diagnosis and management of long COVID. JAMA Netw Open 2022; 5(11): e2240332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9634500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36326761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soraas A, Bo R, Kalleberg KT, et al.. Self-reported memory problems 8 months after COVID-19 infection. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4(7): e2118717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8322992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34323987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abel KM, Carr MJ, Shcroft DM, et al.. Association of SARS-CoV-2 infection with psychological distress, psychotropic prescribing, fatigue, and sleep problems among UK primary care patients. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4(11): e2134803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8596199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34783824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kieran A, Ranger TA, Patone M, et al.. Neuropsychiatric ramifications of severe COVID-19 and other severe acute respiratory infections. JAMA Psychiatry 2022; 79(7): 690&#x2013;698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9096686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35544272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisk LE, Gottlieb MA, Spatz ES, et al.. Association of initial SARS-CoV-2 test positivity with patient-reported well-being 3 months after a symptomatic illness. JAMA Netw Open 2022; 5(12): e2244486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9716377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36454572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature 2021; 594: 259&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joy G, Artico J, Kurdi H, et al.. Prospective case-control study of cardiovascular abnormalities 6 months following mild COVID-19 in healthcare workers. JACC 2021; 14(11): 2155&#x2013;2166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8105493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33975819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, et al.. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry 2021; 8: 416&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattioli F, Stampatori C, Righetti F, et al.. Neurological and cognitive sequelae of Covid-19: a four month follow-up. J Neurol 2021; 268: 4422&#x2013;4428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8088203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33932157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkan M, Dvir A, Zaidenstein R, et al.. Patient-reported outcome measures after hospitalization during the COVID-19 pandemic: a survey among COVID-19 and non-COVID-19 patients. Int J Gen Med 2021; 14: 4829&#x2013;4836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8405220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34471377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, et al.. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet 2022; 39910343: 2263&#x2013;2264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35717982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehme M, Vetter P, Chappuis F, et al.. Prevalence of post-COVID condition 12 weeks after Omicron infection compared to negative controls and association with vaccination status. Clin Infect Dis 2022; 76(9): 1567&#x2013;1575. DOI: 10.1093/cid/ciac947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciac947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36519381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodrow M, Carey C, Ziauddeen N, et al.. Systematic review of the prevalence of long COVID. Open Forum Infect Dis 2023; 10(7): ofad233. DOI: 10.1093/ofid/ofad233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ofid/ofad233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10316694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37404951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampasian V, Elghazaly H, Chattopadhyay R, et al.. Risk factors associated with post-COVID-19 condition: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Intern Med 2023; 183(6): 566&#x2013;580. DOI: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.0750 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.0750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10037203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, et al.. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One 2020; 15(11): e0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robineau O, Zins M, Touvier M, et al.. Long-lasting symptoms after an acute COVID-19 infection and factors associated with their resolution. JAMA Netw Open 2022; 5(11): e2240985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9647489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36350653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McPeake J, Shaw M, MacTavish P, et al.. Long-term outcomes following severe COVID-19 infection: a propensity matched cohort study. BMJ Open Resp Res 2021; 8: e001080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8663070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34887318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Huang T, Weisskopf MG, et al.. Multidimensional sleep health prior to SARS-CoV-2 infection and risk of post-COVID-19 condition. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 6(5): e2315885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10230315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37252741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monje M, Iwasaki A. The neurobiology of long COVID. Neuron 2022; 110: 3484&#x2013;3496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9537254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36288726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sutherland S. The brain and long COVID. Millions of people are still suffering long after infection. Now researchers are finding neurological causes for their symptoms. Sci Am
2023; 328(3): 26&#x2013;33. https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/long-covid-now-looks-like-a-neurological-disease-helping-doctors-to-focus-treatments/ (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39017131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein SR, Ramelli SC, Grazioli A, et al.. SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence in the human body and brain at autopsy. Nature 2022; 612; 758&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9749650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36517603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer PT, Hellwig S, Blazhenets G, et al.. Molecular imaging findings on acute and long-term effects of COVID-19 on the brain: a systematic review. J Nucl Med 2022; 63: 971&#x2013;980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9258567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35177424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Kapur S, et al.. Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open 2021; 11(3): e048391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kremer S, Jager HR. Brain changes after COVID-19 &#x2013; how concerned should we be? Nature Rev Neurology 2022; 18: 321&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9022737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35449462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sneller MC, Liang J, Marques AR, et al.. A longitudinal study of COVID-19 sequelae and immunity: baseline findings. Ann Intern Med 2022; 175(7): 969&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9128805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35605238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubota T, Kuroda N, Sone D. Neuropsychiatric aspects of long COVID: a comprehensive review. Psychiatry Clin Neurosci 2023; 77: 84&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10108156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36385449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, et al.. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nature Rev Microbiol 2023; 21: 133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Nemer M, Da Silva RB, Cheung A, et al.. Post-COVID-19 condition in Canada: what we know, what we don&#x2019;t know and a framework for action. Ottawa, Canada: Office of the Chief Science Advisor of Canada, 2022. https://science.gc.ca/site/science/en/office-chief-science-advisor/initiatives-covid-19/post-covid-19-condition-canada-what-we-know-what-we-dont-know-and-framework-action-pre-report (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baroni C, Potito J, Perticone ME, et al.. How does long-COVID impact prognosis and the long-term sequelae? Viruses 2023; 15: 1173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10222218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37243259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazdar S, Kwee AKAL, Houweling L, et al.. A systematic review of chest imaging findings in long COVID patients. J Pers Med 2023; 13: 282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9965323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36836515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bocchino M, Rea G, Capitelli L, et al.. Chest CT lung abnormalities 1 year after COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Radiology 2023; 308(1): e230535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37404150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng N, Zhao YM, Yan W, et al.. A systematic review and meta-analysis of long term physical and mental sequelae of COVID-19 pandemic: call for research priority and action. Mol Psychiatry 2023; 28: 423&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9168643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35668159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
AAP, AACAP, CHA declare national emergency in children&#x2019;s mental health. American Academy of Pediatrics News, 19 October 2021. https://publications.aap.org/aapnews/news/17718?autologincheck=redirected (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
SickKids. SickKids releases new research on how COVID-19 pandemic has impacted child and youth mental, physical health. July 8 2021. https://www.sickkids.ca/en/news/archive/2021/research-covid-19-pandemic-impact-child-youth-mental-physical-health/ (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viner R, Russell S, Saulle R, et al.. School closures during social lockdown and mental health, health behaviors, and well-being among children and adolescents during the first COVID-19 wave. A systematic review. JAMA Pediatr 2022; 176(4): 400&#x2013;409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35040870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racine N, McArthur BA, Cooke JE, et al.. Global prevalence of depressive and anxiety symptoms in children and adolescents during COVID-19. A Meta-analysis. JAMA Pediatr 2021; 175(11): 1142&#x2013;1150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8353576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34369987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar M, Akbarialiabad H, Kouhanjani MF, et al.. Association of major disease outbreaks with adolescent and youth mental health in low- and middle-income countries: a systematic scoping review. JAMA Psychiatry 2022; 79(12): 1232&#x2013;1240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36223094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Miranda DM, da Silva, Athanasio B, Oliviera ACS, et al.. How is COVID-19 pandemic impacting mental health of children and adolescents? Int J Disaster Risk Reduct 2020; 51: 101845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7481176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32929399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Araujo LA, Veloso CF, de Cqampos Souza M, et al.. The potential impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on child growth and development: a systematic review. J Pediatr (Rio J) 2021; 97(4): 369&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7510529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32980318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loades ME, Chatburn E, Higson-Sweeney N, et al.. Rapid systematic review: the impact of social isolation and loneliness on the mental health of children and adolescents in the context of COVID-19. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry 2020; 59(11): 1218&#x2013;1239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32504808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotlib IH, Miller JG, Borchers LR, et al.. Effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on mental health and brain maturation in adolescents: implications for analyzing longitudinal data. Biol Psych Global Open Sci 2022. In Press. DOI: 10.1016/j.bpsgos.2022.11.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpsgos.2022.11.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9713854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36471743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madigan S, Eirich R, Pador P, et al.. Assessment of changes in child and adolescent screen time during the COVID-19 pandemic. A systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Pediatr 2022; 176(12): 1188&#x2013;1198. DOI: 10.1001/jamapediatrics.2022.4116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2022.4116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9641597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36342702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radhakrishnan L, Leeb RT, Bitsko RH, et al.. Pediatric emergency department visits associated with mental health conditions before and during the COVID-19 pandemic&#x2013;United States, January 2019-January 2022. MMWR 2022; 71(8): 319&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35202358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones SE, Ethier KA, Hertz M, et al.. Mental health, suicidality, and connectedness among high school students during the COVID-19 pandemic &#x2013; Adolescent behavior and experiences survey, United States, January-June 2021. MMWR 2022; 71(3): 16&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8979602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35358165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebrun-Harris LA, Bhandour RM, Kogan MD, et al.. Five-year trends in US children&#x2019;s health and well-being, 2016-2020. JAMA Pediatr 2022; 176(7): e220056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8922203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35285883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman-Munick SM, Lin JA, Milliren CE, et al.. Association of the COVID-19 pandemic with adolescent and young adult eating disorder care volume. JAMA Pediatr 2022; 176(12): 1225&#x2013;1232. DOI: jamapediatrics.2022.4346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9641596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36342721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haripersad YV, Kannegiesser-Bailey M, Morton K, et al.. Outbreak of anorexia nervosa admissions during the COVID-19 pandemic. Arch Dis Child 2021; 106(3): e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32709684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Termorshuizen JD, Watson HJ, Thornton LM, et al.. Early impact of COVID-19 on individuals with self-reported eating disorders: a survey of ~1000 individuals in the United States and the Netherlands. Int J Eat Disord 2020; 53(11): 1780&#x2013;1790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32720399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branley-Bell D, Talbot CV. Exploring the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic and UK lockdown on individuals with experience of eating disorders. J Eat Disord 2020; 8: 44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7444862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32874585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vyver E, Katzman DK. Anorexia nervosa: A paediatric health crisis during the COVID-19 pandemic. Paediatr Child Health 2021; 26(5): 317&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8318539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34336061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaffee BW, Cheng J, Couch ET, et al.. Adolescents&#x2019; substance use and physical activity before and during the COVID-19 pandemic. JAMA Pediatr 2021;175(7):715-722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8094031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33938922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagoto SL, Conroy DE. Revitalizing adolescent health behavior after the COVID-19 pandemic. JAMA Pediatr 2021; 175(7): 677&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33938945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neville RD, Lakes KD, Hopkins WG, et al.. Global changes in child and adolescent physical activity during the COVID-19 pandemic: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Pediatr 2022; 176(9): 886&#x2013;894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9274449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35816330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearce M, Garcia L, Abbas A, et al.. Association between physical activity and risk of depression. A systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatry 2022; 79(6): 550&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9008579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35416941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolford SJ, Sidell M, Li X, et al.. Changes in body mass index among children and adolescents during the COVID-19 pandemic. JAMA 2021; 326(14): 1434&#x2013;1436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8511973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34448817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knapp EA, Dong Y, Dunlop AL, et al.. Changes in BMI during the COVID-19 pandemic. Pediatrics 2022; 150(3): e2022056552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9444980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35768891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarnig G, Jaunig J, van Poppel MNM. Association of COVID-19 mitigation measures with changes in cardiorespiratory fitness and body mass index among children aged 7 to 10 years in Austria. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4(8): e2121675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8391099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34436611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christie D, Elliott A. A year supporting youth within a pandemic: a shared reflection. Clin Child Psychol Psychiatry 2021; 26(2): 309&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33736476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salari N, Hosseinian-Far A, Jalali R, et al.. Prevalence of stress, anxiety, depression among the general population during the COVID-19 pandemic: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Global Health 2021; 16: 57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7338126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32631403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Mental Disorders Collaborators. Global prevalence and burden of depressive and anxiety disorders in 204 countries and territories in 2020 due to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet 2021; 398(10312): P1700&#x2013;P1712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34634250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czeisler ME, Lane RI, Wiley JF, et al.. Follow-up survey of US adult reports of mental health, substance use, and suicidal ideation during the COVID-19 pandemic, September 2020. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4(2): e2037665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33606030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaninotto P, Iob E, Demakakos P, et al.. Immediate and longer-term changes in the mental health and well-being of older adults in England during the COVID-19 pandemic. JAMA Psychiatry 2022; 79(2): 151&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8696687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34935862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sidley G. A year of fear. The Critic. 23
March, 2021. https://thecritic.co.uk/a-year-of-fear/ (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Rayner G. Use of fear to control behavior in Covid crisis was &#x2018;totalitarian&#x2019;, admit scientists. Members of scientific pandemic influenza group on behaviour express regret about &#x2018;unethical&#x2019; methods. The Telegraph, 14 May 2021. https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2021/05/14/scientists-admit-totalitarian-use-fear-control-behaviour-covid/ (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor S. COVID stress syndrome: Clinical and nosological considerations. Curr Psychiatry Rep 2021; 23: 19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7927783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33660068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Li Y, Yue Y, et al.. Adherence to healthy lifestyle prior to infection and risk of post-COVID-19 condition. JAMA Intern Med 2023; 183(3): 232&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9989904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36745445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Quan L, Chavarro JE, et al.. Associations of depression, anxiety, worry, perceived stress, and loneliness prior to infection with risk of post-COVID-19 conditions. JAMA Psychiatry 2022; 79(11): 1081&#x2013;1091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9453634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36069885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mondelli V, Pariante CM. What can neuroimmunology teach us about the symptoms of long-COVID? Oxf Open Immunol 2021; 2(1): iqab004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7928677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34192271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson AJ, McWhirter L. Cognitive behavioral therapy: Principles, science, and patient selection in neurology. Semin Neurol 2022; 42: 114&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35675820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brusaferri L, Alshelh Z, Martins D, et al.. The pandemic brain: neuroinflammation in non-infected individuals during the COVID-19 pandemic. Brain Behav Immun 2022; 102: 89&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8847082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35181440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kronish IM, Shechter A. Covid-19 and the amplification of cardiovascular risk by psychological distress. Nat Cardiovasc Res 2022; 1: 968&#x2013;970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10153572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37138789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranger TA, Kieran A, Patone M, et al.. Preexisting neuropsychiatric conditions and associated risk of severe COVID-19 infection and other acute respiratory infections. JAMA Psychiatry 2023; 80(1): 57&#x2013;65. DOI: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.3614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.3614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9647578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36350602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddin C, Murphy R, Hankey GJ, et al.. Association of psychosocial stress with risk of acute stroke. JAMA Netw Open 2022; 5(12): e2244836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9856236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36484991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Na PJ, Jest DV, Pietrzak RH. Social disconnection as a global behavioral epidemic - a call to action about a major health risk factor. JAMA Psychiatry 2023; 80(2): 101&#x2013;102. DOI: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.4162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.4162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11112624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36515940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Gao Y, Han Z, et al.. A systematic review and meta-analysis of 90 cohort studies of social isolation, loneliness and mortality. Nat Hum Behav. Epub ahead of print 19 June 2023. DOI: 10.1038/s41562-023-01617-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41562-023-01617-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37337095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton C, Fink P, Henningsen P, et al.. Functional somatic disorders: discussion paper for a new common classification for research and clinical use. BMC Med 2020; 18: 34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7052963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32122350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henningsen P, Zipfel S, Herzog W. Management of functional somatic syndromes. Lancet 2007; 369: 946&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17368156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henningsen P. Management of somatic symptom disorder. Dialogues Clin Neurosci 2018; 20: 23&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6016049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe B, Levenson J, Depping M, et al.. Somatic symptom disorder: a scoping review on the empirical evidence of a new diagnosis. Psychol Med 2022; 52: 632&#x2013;648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8961337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34776017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malas N, Ortiz-Aguayo R, Giles L, et al.. Pediatric somatic symptom disorders. Curr Psychiatry Rev 2017; 19: 11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28188588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker J, Sharpe M, Wessely S. Commentary: symptoms not associated with disease: an unmet public health challenge. Int J Epidemiol 2006; 35: 477&#x2013;478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16510535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalder T, Willis C. Chapter 18 - Medically unexplained symptoms. In: Llewellyn CD, Ayers S, McManus C, et al.. (eds.), Cambridge handbook of psychology, health and medicine, 3rd ed. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2019, pp. 78&#x2013;83. DOI: 10.1017/9781316783269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/9781316783269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husain M, Chalder T. Medically unexplained symptoms: assessment and management. Clin Med 2021; 21(1): 13&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33479063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders NR, Gandhi S, Chen S, et al.. Health care use and costs of children, adolescents, and young adults with somatic symptom and related disorders. JAMA Netw Open 2020; 3(7): e2011295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7378752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32701161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rask MT, Rosendal M, Fenger-Gron M, et al.. Sick leave and work disability in primary care patients with recent-onset multiple medically unexplained symptoms and persistent somatoform disorders: a 10-year follow-up of the FIP study. Gen Hosp Psychiatry 2015; 37: 53&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25456975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choutka J, Jansari V, Hornig M, Iwasaki A. Unexplained post-acute infection syndromes. Nat Med 2022; 28: 9110923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35585196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loades ME, Crawley E, Chalder T, et al.. Paediatric chronic fatigue syndrome: 25 year perspective. Clin Child Psychol Psychiatry 2021; 26(1): 8&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33300388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulme K, Hudson JL, Rojckzyk P, et al.. Biopsychosocial risk factors of persistent fatigue after acute infection: a systematic review to inform interventions. J Psychosomatic Res 2017; 99: 120&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28712416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickie I, Davenport T, Wakefield D, et al.. Post-infective and chronic fatigue syndromes precipitated by viral and non-viral pathogens: prospective cohort study. BMJ 2006; 333(7568): 575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1569956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16950834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnus P, Gunnes N, Tveito K, et al.. Chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME) is associated with pandemic influenza infection, but not with an adjuvanted pandemic influenza vaccine. Vaccine 2015; 33: 6173&#x2013;6177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26475444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poenaru S, Abdallah SJ, Corrales-Medina V, et al.. COVID-19 and post-infectious myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a narrative review. Ther Adv Infectious Dis 2021; 8: 1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8060761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33959278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aaron LA, Buchwald D. A review of the evidence for overlap among unexplained clinical conditions. Ann Intern Med 2001; 134: 868&#x2013;881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11346323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Morales R, Bermudez-Benitez E, Martinez-Martinez LA, et al.. Clinical overlap between fibromyalgia and myalgic encephalomyelitis. A systematic review and meta-analysis. Autoimmun Rev 2022; 21: 103129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35690247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharpe M, Carson A. Unexplained symptoms, functional syndromes, and somatization: do we need a paradigm shift? Ann Intern Med 2001; 134: 926&#x2013;930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11346330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart DE. The changing faces of somatization. Psychoso-matics 1990; 31(2): 153&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2330395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wormser GP, McKenna D, Shaffer SD, et al.. Evaluation of selected variables to determine if any had predictive value for, or correlated with, residual symptoms at approximately 12 months after diagnosis and treatment of early Lyme disease. Diagn Micro Infect Dis 2021; 100: 115348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33774355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassett AL, Radvanski DC, Buyske S, et al.. Role of psychiatric comorbidity in chronic lyme disease. Arthritis Rheum 2008; 59(12): 1742&#x2013;1749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19035409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassett AL, Radvanski DC, Buyske S, et al.. Psychiatric comorbidity and other psychological factors in patients with &#x201c;Chronic Lyme Disease&#x201d;. Am J Med 2009; 122: 843&#x2013;850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2751626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19699380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon SP, Hilton E, Weinschel BS, et al.. Psychological factors in the prediction of lyme disease course. Arthritis Care Res 1998; 11(5): 419&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9830887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson A, Lehn A, Ludwig L, et al.. Explaining functional disorders in the neurology clinic: a photo story. Pract Neurol 2016; 16: 56&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26769761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams C, Anderson J, Madva EN, et al.. You&#x2019;ve made the diagnosis of functional neurological disorder: now what? Pract Neurol 2018; 18: 323&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6372294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29764988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone J, Burton C, Carson A. Recognizing and explaining functional neurological disorder. BMJ 2020; 371: m3745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33087335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez DL, Nicholson TR, Asadi-Pooya AA, et al.. Neuroimaging in functional neurological disorder: state of the field and research agenda. NeuroImage Clin 2021; 30: 102623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8111317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34215138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallett M, Aybek S, Dworetzky BA, et al.. Functional neurologic disorder: new subtypes and shared mechanisms. Lancet Neurol 2022; 21: 537&#x2013;550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9107510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35430029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espay AJ, Aybek S, Carson A, et al.. Current concepts in diagnosis and treatment of functional neurological disorders. JAMA Neurol 2018; 75(9): 1132&#x2013;1141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7293766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29868890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra A, Pandey S. Functional neurological disorders. Clinical spectrum, diagnosis, and treatment. Neurologist 2022; 27: 276&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35858632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong K, Chin RFM, Shetty J, et al.. Functional neurological disorder in children and young people: incidence, clinical features, and prognosis. Dev Med Child Neurol 2023; 65(9): 1238&#x2013;1246. DOI: 10.1111/dmcn.15538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dmcn.15538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36752054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett K, Diamond C, Hoeritzauer I, et al.. A practical review of functional neurological disorder (FND) for the general physician. Clin Med 2021; 21(1): 28&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33479065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludwig L, Pasman JA, Nicholson T, et al.. Stressful life events and maltreatment in conversion (functional neurological) disorder: systematic review and meta-analysis of case-control studies. Lancet Psychiatry 2018; 5: 307&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29526521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball HA, McWhirter L, Ballard C, et al.. Functional cognitive disorder: dementia&#x2019;s blind spot. Brain 2020; 143: 2895&#x2013;2903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7586080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32791521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teodoro T, Edwards MJ, Isaacs JD. A unifying theory for cognitive abnormalities in functional neurological disorders, fibromyalgia and chronic fatigue syndrome: systematic review. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2018; 89: 1308&#x2013;1319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6288708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29735513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McWhirter L, Carson A. Functional cognitive disorders: clinical presentations and treatment approaches. Pract Neurol 2023; 23: 104&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36601750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McWhirter L, Ritchie C, Stone J, et al.. Functional cognitive disorders: a systematic review. Lancet Psychiatry 2020; 7: 191&#x2013;207. DOI: 10.1016/s2215-0366(19)30405-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s2215-0366(19)30405-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31732482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McWhirter L, Smyth H, Hoeritzauer I, et al.. What is brain fog? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2023; 94: 321&#x2013;325. DOI: 10.1136/jnnp-2022-329683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2022-329683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36600580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvakumar J, Haval LB, Drevvatne M, et al.. Prevalence and characteristics associated with post-COVID-19 condition among nonhospitalized adolescents and young adults. JAMA Netw Open 2023; 6(3): e235763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10064252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36995712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera JA, Sabaia S, Yang D, et al.. Life stressors significantly impact long-term outcomes and post-acute symptoms 12-months after COVID-19 hospitalization. J Neurol Sci 2022; 443: 120487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9637014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36379135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Liu Y, Liu Y. Somatic symptoms and concern regarding COVID-19 among Chinese college and primary school students: a cross-sectional survey. Psychiatry Res 2020; 289: 113070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7227526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kachaner A, Lemogne C, Dave J, et al.. Somatic symptoms disorder in patients with post-COVID-19 neurological symptoms: a preliminary report from the somatic study (Somatic Symptom Disorder Triggered by COVID-19). J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022; 93: 1174&#x2013;1180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36008115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willis C, Chalder T. Concern for Covid-19 cough, fever and impact on mental health. What about risk of somatic symptom disorder? J Mental Health 2021; 30(5): 551&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33522343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders C, Sperling S, Bendstrup E. A new paradigm is needed to explain long COVID. Lancet Respir Med 2023; 11(2): e12&#x2013;e13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36620963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantovani E, Mariotto S, Gabbiani D, et al.. Chronic fatigue syndrome: an emerging sequela in COVID-19 survivors? J NeuroVirology 2021; 27: 631&#x2013;637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8328351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34341960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedor C, Freitag H, Meyer-Arndt L, et al.. A prospective observational study of post-COVID-19 chronic fatigue syndrome following the first pandemic wave in Germany and biomarkers associated with symptom severity. Nat Commun 2022; 13: 5104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9426365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36042189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wildwing T, Holt N. The neurological symptoms of COVID-19: a systematic overview of systematic reviews, comparison with other neurological conditions and implications for healthcare services. Ther Adv Chronic Dis 2021; 12: 204062230976979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7970685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33796241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul BD, Lemle MD, Komaroff AL, et al.. Redox imbalance links COVID-19 and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. PNAS 2021; 118(34): e2024358118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8403932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34400495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salari N, Khodayari Y, Hosseinian-Farr A, et al.. Global prevalence of chronic fatigue syndrome among long COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Biopsychosoc Med 2022; 16: 21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9589726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36274177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherlinger M, Felton R, Gallais F, et al.. Refining &#x201c;Long-COVID&#x201d; by a prospective multimodal evaluation of patients with long-term symptoms attributed to SARS-CoV-2 infection. Infect Dis Ther 2021; 10: 1747&#x2013;1763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8270770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34245450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hull M, Parnes M, Jankovic J. Increased incidence of functional (psychogenic) movement disorders in children and adults amid the COVID-19 pandemic. A cross-sectional study. Neurol: Clin Pract 2021; 11(5): e686&#x2013;e690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8610548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34840884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen-Aguilar R, Galindez-de la, Portilla JP, Gomez-Alcorta R, et al.. Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the incidence of patients with functional neurological disorder seen in a neurological emergency department. Psychiatry Clin Neurosci 2022; 77(11): 595&#x2013;596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35946916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saldivar-Davila S, Medina-Rioja R, Rodriguez-Rivas R. Functional neurological disorder in a neurological emergency department during the COVID-19 pandemic. Neurology 2021; 96(Suppl15): 2615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horner O, Hedderly T, Malik O. The changing landscape of childhood tic disorders following COVID-19. Paediatr Child Health 2022; 32(10): 363&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9359930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35967969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martindale JM, Mink JW. The rise of functional tic-like behaviors: what do the COVID-19 pandemic and social media have to do with it? A narrative review. Front Pediatr 2022; 10: 863919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9309505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35899132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amorelli G, Martino D, Pringsheim T. Rapid onset functional tic-like disorder outbreak: a challenging differential diagnosis in the COVID-19 pandemic. Can Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry 2022; 31(3): 144&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9275373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35919901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyman I, Liang H, Hedderly T. COVID-19 related increase in childhood tics and tic-like attacks. Arch Dis Child 2021; 106(5): 420&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33677431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valent KD, Alessi R, Baroni G, et al.. The COVID-19 outbreak and PNES: the impact of a ubiquitously felt stressor. Epilepsy Behav 2021; 117: 107852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9760557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33636526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza A, Jacques R, Mohan S. Vaccine-induced functional neurological disorders in the Covid-19 era. Can J Neurol Sci 2023; 50(3): 346&#x2013;350. DOI: 10.1017/cjn.2022.48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/cjn.2022.48</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35466898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu A, Burke MJ. Functional neurological disorder associated with SARS-CoV-2 vaccination. CMAJ 2022; 194: E1086&#x2013;E1068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9377566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35970543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fung WKW, Sa'di Q, Katzberg H, et al.. Functional disorders as a common motor manifestation of COVID-19 infection or vaccination. Eur J Neurol 2023; 30: 678&#x2013;691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9878181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36366936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassett AL, Sigal LH. Unforeseen consequences of terrorism. Medically unexplained symptoms in a time of fear. Arch Intern Med 2002; 162: 1809&#x2013;1813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12196078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boss LP. Epidemic hysteria: a review of the published literature. Epidemiol Rev 1997; 19(2): 233&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9494785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balaratnasingam S, Janca A. Mass hysteria revisited. Curr Opin Psychiatry 2006; 19: 171&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16612198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir E. Mass sociogenic illness. CMAJ 2005; 172(1): 36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC543940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15632400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagus P, Pena-Ramos JA, Sanchez-Bayon A. COVID-19 and the political economy of mass hysteria. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021; 18(4): 1376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7913136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33546144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerriero RM, Pier DB, de Gusmao CM, et al.. Increased pediatric functional neurological symptom disorders after the boston marathon bombings: a case series. Pediatric Neurol 2014; 51: 619&#x2013;623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25152961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raker E, Zacher M, Lowe SR. Lessons from Hurricane Katrina for predicting the indirect health consequences of the COVID-19 pandemic. PNAS 2020; 117(23): 12595&#x2013;12597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7293707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32424085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honigsbaum M. The great dread: cultural and psychological impacts and responses to the &#x2018;Russian&#x2019; influenza in the United Kingdom, 1889-1893. Soc Hist Med 2010; 23(2): 299&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honigsbaum M, Krishnan L. Taking pandemic sequelae seriously: from the Russian influenza to COVID-19 long-haulers. Lancet 2020; 396: 1389&#x2013;1391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7550169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33058777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Spinney L. What long flu sufferers of the 1918-1919 pandemic can tell us about long COVID today. Time Magazine, 31
December
2020. https://time.com/5915616/long-flu-1918-pandemic/ (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eghigian G. The Spanish flu pandemic and mental health: a historical perspective. Psychiatric Times 2020; 37(5): 26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briggs NC, Levine PH. A comparative review of systemic and neurological symptomatology in 12 outbreaks collectively described as chronic fatigue syndrome, epidemic neuromyasthenia, and myalgic encephalomyelitis. Clin Infect Dis 1994; 18(Suppl 1): S32&#x2013;S42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8148451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones E, Wessely S. War syndromes: the impact of culture on medically unexplained symptoms. Med Hist 2005; 49: 55&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1088250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15730130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail K, Lewis G. Multi-symptom illnesses, unexplained illness and gulf war syndrome. Phil Trans R Soc B 2006; 361: 543&#x2013;551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1569616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16687260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olvera C, Stebbins GT, Goetz CG, et al.. TikTok Tics: a pandemic within a pandemic. Mov Disord Clin Pract 2021; 8(8): 1200&#x2013;1205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8564823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34765687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colloca L, Barsky AJ. Placebo and nocebo effects. NEJM 2020; 382(6): 554&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32023375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas KB. General practice consultations: is there any point in being positive. BMJ 1987; 294: 1200&#x2013;1202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1246362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3109581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiorio M, Braga M, Marotta A, et al.. Functional neurological disorder and placebo and nocebo effects: shared mechanisms. Nat Rev Neurol 2022; 18: 624&#x2013;635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36075980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matta J, Wiernik E, Robineau O, et al.. Association of self-reported COVID-19 infection and SARS-CoV-2 serology test results with persistent physical symptoms among French adults during the COVID-19 pandemic. JAMA Intern Med 2022; 182(1): 19&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8576624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34747982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertran M, Pereira SMP, Nugawela MD, et al.. The relationship between Post COVID symptoms in young people and their parents. J Infect 2022; 85(6): 762&#x2013;769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36216186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouquette A, Descarpentry A, Dione F, et al.. Comparison of depression and anxiety following self-reported COVID-19-like symptoms vs SARS-CoV-2 seropositivity in France. JAMA Netw Open 2023; 6(5): e2312892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10176124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37166797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu TC, Yoo SM, Sim MS, et al.. Perceived cognitive deficits in patients with symptomatic SARS-CoV-2 and their association with post-COVID-19 condition. JAMA Netw Open 2023; 6(5): e2311974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10715897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37145596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amanzio M, Howick J, Bartoli M, et al.. How do nocebo phenomena provide a theoretical framework for the COVID-19 pandemic? Front Psychol 2020; 11: 589884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7661580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33192929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Reardon S. Long COVID risk falls only slightly after vaccination, huge study shows. Results suggest that vaccines offer less protection against lingering symptoms than expected. Nature, 25
May
25
2022. https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-022-01453-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35614263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Bermingham C, Pouwels KB, et al.. Trajectory of long covid symptoms after covid-19 vaccination: community based cohort study. BMJ 2022; 377: e069676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35584816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards MJ, Adams RA, Brown H, et al.. A Bayesian account of &#x2018;hysteria&#x2019;. Brain 2012; 135: 3495&#x2013;3512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3501967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22641838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joffe AR, Elliott A, Eapen R, et al.. Is vaccination acting as a placebo in preventing symptoms of Long-COVID? Clin Infect Dis. Epub ahead of print 19 April 2023. DOI: 10.1093/cid/ciad234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciad234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37072835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Finley I. The CDC&#x2019;s long-covid deception. A recent study exaggerates the incidence of postviral symptoms among young adults and deflects attention from misconceived pandemic policies. Wall Street Journal, 9 Febraury 2023. https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-cdcs-long-covid-deception-depression-anxiety-vaccine-mandate-university-gwu-testing-mental-health-48bdd11b (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henningsen P, Gundel H, Kop WJ, et al.. Persistent physical symptoms as perceptual dysregulation: a neuropsychobehavioral model and its clinical implications. Psychosom Med 2018; 80: 422&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29621046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bergh O, Witthoft M, Petersen S, et al.. Symptoms and the body: taking the inferential leap. Neurosci Biobehav Rev 2017; 74: 185&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28108416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ongaro G, Kaptchuk TJ. Symptom perception, placebo effects, and the Bayesian brain. Pain 2019; 160(1): 1&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6319577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30086114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petzschner FH, Weber LAE, Gard T, et al.. Computational psychosomatics and computational psychiatry: toward a joint framework for differential diagnosis. Biol Psychiatry 2017; 82: 421&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28619481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petzschner FH, Garfinkel SN, Paulus MP, et al.. Computational models of interoception and body regulation. Trends Neurosci 2021; 44(1): 63&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8109616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33378658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barsky AJ, Silbersweig DA. The amplification of symptoms in the medically ill. J Gen Intern Med 2023; 38: 195&#x2013;202. DOI: 10.1007/s11606-022-07699-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-022-07699-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9849656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35829874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolters C, Gerlach AL, Pohl A. Interoceptive accuracy and bias in somatic symptoms disorder, illness anxiety disorder, and functional syndromes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One 2022; 17(8): e0271717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9387777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35980959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kube T, Rozenkrantz L, Rief W, et al.. Understanding persistent physical symptoms: conceptual integration of psychological expectation models and predictive processing accounts. Clin Psychol Rev 2020; 76: 101829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32062101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pezzullo AM, Axfors C, Contopoulos-Ioannidis CG, et al.. Age-stratified infection fatality rate of COVID-19 in the non-elderly population. Environ Res 2023; 216: 114655. DOI: 10.1016/j.envres.2022.114655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2022.114655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9613797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36341800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joffe AR, Redman D. The SARS-CoV-2 pandemic in high income countries such as Canada: a better way forward without lockdowns. Front Public Health 2021; 9: 715904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8672418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34926364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esper FP, Adhikari TM, Tu ZJ, et al.. Alpha to Omicron: disease severity and clinical outcomes of major SARS-CoV-2 variants. J Infect Dis 2023; 227(3): 344&#x2013;352. DOI: 10.1093/infdis/jiac411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiac411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9619650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36214810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hani E, Bertran M, Powell A, et al.. Significantly lower infection fatality rates associated with SARS-CoV-2 Omicron (B.1.1.529) infection in children and young people: active, prospective national surveillance, January-March 2022, England. J Infect 2023; 86(4): 397&#x2013;398. DOI: 10.1016/j.jinf.2023.01.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2023.01.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9872565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36706963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Axfors C, Ioannidis JPA. Infection fatality rate of COVID-19 in community-dwelling elderly populations. Eur J Epidemiol 2022; 37(3): 235&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8934243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35306604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Herby J, Jonung L, Hanke SH. A literature review and meta-analysis of the effects of lockdowns on COVID-19 mortality - II. studies in applied economics (SAE) No.210. May 2022. Johns Hopkins institute for applied economics, global health, and the study of business enterprise. https://sites.krieger.jhu.edu/iae/files/2022/06/A-Systematic-Review-and-Meta-Analysis-of-the-Effects-of-Lockdowns-of-COVID-19-Mortality-II.pdf (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickers DM, Baral S, Mishra S, et al.. Stringency of containment and closures on the growth of SARS-CoV-2 in Canada prior to accelerated vaccine roll-out. Int J Infect Dis 2022; 118: 73&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8863413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35202783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Allen D. Lockdown: a final assessment. Vancouver, Canada: Frasier Institute, 2023. https://www.fraserinstitute.org/sites/default/files/covid-19-lessons-essay5-lockdown-a-final-assessment.pdf (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gehlhar A, Schmidt N, Eisenburger N, et al.. Impact of physical activity on COVID-19-related symptoms and perception of physical performance, fatigue and exhaustion during stay-at-home orders. BMJ Open Sp Ex Med 2022; 8: e001319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9072782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35539285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joffe AR. COVID-19: rethinking the lockdown groupthink. Front Public Health 2021; 9: 625778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7952324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33718322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bark D, Dhillo N, St-Jean M, et al.. SARS-CoV-2 transmission in kindergarten to grade 12 schools in the Vancouver coastal health region: a descriptive epidemiologic study. CMAJ Open 2021: 9: E810&#x2013;E817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8432285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34429325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ertem Z, Schechter-Perkins EM, Oster E, et al.. The impact of school opening model on SARS-CoV-2 community incidence and mortality. Nat Med 2021; 27: 2120&#x2013;2126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34707317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh S, Chowdhury A, Braithwiate V, et al.. Do school closures and school reopenings affect community transmission of COVID-19? A systematic review of observational studies. BMJ Open 2021; 11: e053371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8375447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34404718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenton L, Gribben C, Caldwell D, et al.. Risk of hospital admission with COVID-19 among teachers compared with healthcare workers and other adults of working age in Scotland, March 2020 to July 2021: population based case-control study. BMJ 2021; 374: n2060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8408959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34470747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somekh I, Boker LK, Shohat T, et al.. Comparison of COVID-19 incidence rates before and after school reopening in Israel. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4: e217105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8076960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33900403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukumoto K, McClean CT, Nakagawa K. No causal effect of school closure in Japan on the spread of COVID-19 in spring 2020. Nat Med 2021; 27: 2111&#x2013;2119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8674136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34707318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandini S, Rainisio M, Iannuzzo ML, et al.. Cross-sectional and prospective cohort study of the role of schools in the SARS-CoV-2 second wave in Italy. Lancet Reg Health Eur 2021; 5: 100092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7995620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34104904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciaranello A, Bell T. Using data and modeling to understand the risks of in-person education. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4: e214619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33787915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfarb DM, Masse LC, Watts AW, et al.. SARS-CoV-2 seroprevalence among Vancouver public school staff in British Columbia, Canada: a cross-sectional study. BMJ Open 2021; 12(4): e057846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8983418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35383082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood R, Thomson E, Galbraith R, et al.. Sharing a household with children and risk of COVID-19: a study of over 300 000 adults living in healthcare worker households in Scotland. Arch Dis Child 2021; 106: 1212&#x2013;1217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7985971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33737319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Golden A, Whatley S. Don&#x2019;t make the unvaxxed scapegoats for hospital overcrowding. National Post, 17 Febraury 2022. https://nationalpost.com/opinion/alanna-golden-and-shawn-whatley-dont-make-the-unvaxxed-scapegoats-for-hospital-overcrowding (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Crawley M. Some of Ontario&#x2019;s biggest hospitals are filled beyond capacity nearly every day, new data reveals. CBC News analysis reveals extent of &#x201c;hallway medicine&#x201d; &#x2013; something Doug Ford has promised to end. CBC News, 22
January
2020. https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/ontario-hospital-hallway-medicine-healthcare-beyond-capacity-1.5420434 (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Eggertson L. No beds at sick kids: Get used to it. The Globe and Mail. 26
March
2005. https://www.theglobeandmail.com/news/national/no-beds-at-sick-kids-get-used-to-it/article977703/ (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Furey A. When hospitals can&#x2019;t keep doors open, it&#x2019;s time to fire people. Toronto Sun. 8
August
2022. https://torontosun.com/opinion/columnists/furey-when-hospitals-cant-keep-doors-open-its-time-to-fire-people (accessed 1 May, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Redman D. Briefing note. A recovery plan: Canada post-pandemic COVID-19. Frontier Center for Public Policy, February
2022. https://fcpp.org/wp-content/uploads/BriefingNote-COVID_Recovery_PlanFB0922.pdf (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neilson S. The surgical mask is a bad fit for risk reduction. CMAJ 2016; 188(8): 606&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4868614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27067817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jefferson T, Del Mar CB, Dooley L, et al.. Physical interventions to interrupt or reduce the spread of respiratory viruses. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2020; 11: CD006207. DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD006207.pub5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD006207.pub5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8094623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33215698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization. Non-pharmaceutical public health measures for mitigating the risk and impact of epidemic and pandemic influenza. Licence: CC BY-NC-SA 3.0 IGO, 2019. https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/329438/9789241516839-eng.pdf (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao J, Shiu EYC, Gao H, et al.. Nonpharmaceutical measures for pandemic influenza in nonhealthcare settings &#x2013; personal protective and environmental measures. Emerg Infect Dis 2020; 26(5): 967&#x2013;975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7181938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32027586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bundgaard H, Bundgaard JS, Raaschau-Pedersen DET, et al.. Effectiveness of adding a mask recommendation to other public health measures to prevent SARS-CoV-2 infection in Danish mask wearers: a randomized controlled trial. Ann Intern Med 2021; 174(3): 335&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7707213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33205991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abaluck J, Kwong LH, Styczynski A, et al.. Impact of community masking on COVID-19: a cluster-randomized trial in Bangladesh. Science 2022; 375(6577): eabi9069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9036942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34855513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chikina M, Pegden W, Recht B. Re-analysis on the statistical sampling biases of a mask promotion trial in Bangladesh: a statistical replication. Trials 2022; 23: 786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9479361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36109816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenton N. The Bangladesh mask study: A Bayesian perspective. ResearchGate 2022; Preprint. DOI: 10.13140/RG.2.2.26189.92649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13140/RG.2.2.26189.92649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Jefferson T, Dooley L, Ferroni E, et al.. Physical interventions to interrupt or reduce the spread of respiratory viruses. Cochrane Database Syst Rev
2023; 1(1): CD006207. https://www.cochranelibrary.com/cdsr/doi/10.1002/14651858.CD006207.pub6/full?mibextid=Zxz2cZ</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD006207.pub6/full?mibextid=Zxz2cZ</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9885521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36715243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coma E, Catala M, Mendez-Boo L, et al.. Unravelling the role of the mandatory use of face covering masks for the control of SARS-CoV-2 in schools: a quasi-experimental study nested in a population-based cohort in Catalonia (Spain). Arch Dis Child 2023; 108: 131&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35999036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandra A, Hoeg TB. Lack of correlation between school mask mandates and paediatric COVID-19 cases in a large cohort. J Infect 2022; 85(6): P671&#x2013;P675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9539411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36183909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Hoeg TB. NEJM&#x2019;s disappointing decision to publish the Boston school mask study. A point-by-point analysis of Cowger TL, et al. Sensible medicine substack. November
12, 2022. https://sensiblemed.substack.com/p/nejms-disappointing-decision-to-publish (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Redman D. Canada&#x2019;s deadly response to COVID-19. Frontier Center for Public Policy. Policy Series No. 237. 2021. https://fcpp.org/2021/07/19/canadas-deadly-response-to-covid-19/. (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schippers MC, Ioannidis JPA, Joffe AR. Aggressive measures, rising inequalities, and mass formation during the COVID-19 crisis: an overview and proposed way forward. Front Public Health 2022; 10: 950965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9491114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36159300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joffe AR, Milburn CR. Avoidable intensive care resource use of unvaccinated COVID-19 patients: Interpretation and ethically defensible policy implications. 2023; Preprints, 2022110497. DOI: preprints202211.0497.v2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn KL, Stukel TA, Huang A, et al.. Comparison of medical and mental health sequelae following hospitalization for COVID-19, Influenza, and sepsis. JAMA Intern Med. Epub ahead of print 20 June 2023. DOI: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.2228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.2228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10282961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37338892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teodoro T, Chen J, Gelauff J, et al.. Functional neurological disorder in people with long COVID: a systematic review. Eur J Neurol 2023; 30: 1505&#x2013;1514. DOI: 10.1111/ene.15721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36719069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman L, Bested AC, Bonilla HF, et al.. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/Chronic fatigue syndrome: essentials of diagnosis and management. Mayo Clin Proc 2021; 96(11): 2861&#x2013;2878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee on the Diagnostic Criteria for Myalgic Ence-phalomyelitis/Chronic fatigue syndrome. Beyond Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: redefining an illness. Washington, D.C.: Institute of Medicine of the National Academies, The National Academies Press, 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink M, Vink-Niese F. Is it useful to question the recovery behaviour of patients with ME/CFS or long COVID? Healthcare 2022; 10: 392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8872229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35207003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holden S, Maksoud R, Eaton-Fitch N, et al.. A systematic review of mitochondrial abnormalities in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome/systemic exertion intolerance disease. J Transl Med 2020; 18: 290. DOI: 10.1186/s12967-020-02452-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-020-02452-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32727475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raanes EFW, Stiles TC. Associations between psychological and immunological variables in chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis: a systematic review. Front Psychiatry 2021; 12: 716320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8650213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34887782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingman T, Smakowski A, Goldsmith K, et al.. A systematic literature review of randomized controlled trials evaluating prognosis following treatment for adults with chronic fatigue syndrome. Psychol Med 2022; 52: 2917&#x2013;2929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9693680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36059125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DY, Lee JK, Park SY, et al.. Systematic review of randomized controlled trials for chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME). J Transl Med 2020; 18: 7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6943902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31906979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casson S, Jones MD, Cassar J, et al.. The effectiveness of activity pacing interventions for people with chronic fatigue syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Disabil Rehabil. Epub ahead of print 13 May 2022. DOI: 10.1080/09638288.2022.2135776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638288.2022.2135776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36345726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochrane M, Mitchell E, Hollingworth W, et al.. Cost-effectiveness of interventions for chronic fatigue syndrome or myalgic encephalomyelitis: a systematic review of economic evaluations. Appl Health Econ Health Policy 2021; 19: 473&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7917957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33646528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi B, Sudry T, Flaks-Manov N, et al.. Long covid outcomes at one year after mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: a nationwide cohort study. BMJ 2023; 380: e072529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9832503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36631153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
The New York State Insurance Fund. Shining a light on long COVID: an analysis of workers&#x2019; compensation data. NYSIF, January
2023. https://ww3.nysif.com/en/FooterPages/Column1/AboutNYSIF/NYSIF_News/2023/20230124LongCovid (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Wise J. Long COVID comes into the light. We&#x2019;re finally starting to see the truth about the vexing condition. It&#x2019;s not what we thought. SLATE Magazine, 19
March
2023. https://slate.com/technology/2023/03/long-covid-symptoms-studies-research-variant.html (accessed 1 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuut TA, Muller F, Csorba I, et al.. Efficacy of cognitive behavioral therapy targeting severe fatigue following COVID-19: results of a randomized controlled trial. Clin Infect Dis. Epub ahead of print 8 May 2023. DOI: 10.1093/cid/ciad257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciad257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almazan A, Franco-Lopez F, Buendia-Romero A, et al.. Rehabilitation for post-COVID-19 condition through a supervised exercise intervention: a randomized controlled trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports 2022; 32: 1791&#x2013;1801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36111386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>