<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37731320</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1544-0591</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of dental research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Dent Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biogeographical Impacts of Dental, Oral, and Craniofacial Microbial Reservoirs.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1303</StartPage><EndPage>1314</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1303-1314</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/00220345231191115</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The human mouth, or oral cavity, is at the crossroads of our external and internal environments, and it is increasingly evident that local colonization of dental, oral, and craniofacial (DOC) tissues and cells by bacteria and viruses may also have systemic effects across myriad diseases and disorders. Better understanding of this phenomenon will require a holistic understanding of host-microbial interactions in both spatiotemporal and biogeographical contexts while also considering person-, organ-, tissue-, cell-, and molecular-level variation. After the acute phase interaction with microbes, the establishment of site-specific reservoirs constitutes an important relationship to understand within the human body; however, despite a preliminary understanding of how viral reservoirs originate and persist across the human body, the landscape of single-cell and spatial multiomic tools has challenged our current understanding of what cells and niches can support microbial reservoirs. The lack of complete understanding impacts research into these relevant topics and implementing precision care for microbial-induced or microbial-influenced diseases. Here, via the lens of acute and chronic microbial infections of the DOC tissues, the goal of this review is to highlight and link the emerging spatiotemporal biogeography of host-viral interactomics at 3 levels: (1) DOC cell types in distinct tissues, (2) DOC-associated microbes, and (3) niche-specific DOC pathologies. Further, we will focus on the impact of postacute infectious syndromes such as long COVID, neurodegenerative disorders, and other underappreciated postviral conditions. We will provide hypotheses about how DOC tissues may play roles systemically in these conditions. Throughout, we will underscore how COVID-19 has catalyzed a new understanding of these biological questions, discuss future directions to study these phenomena, and highlight the utility of noninvasive oral biofluids in screening, monitoring, and intervening to prevent and/or ameliorate human infectious diseases.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Easter</LastName><ForeName>Q T</ForeName><Initials>QT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lab of Oral &amp; Craniofacial Innovation (LOCI), Department of Innovation &amp; Technology Research, ADA Science &amp; Research Institute, Gaithersburg, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matuck</LastName><ForeName>B Fernandes</ForeName><Initials>BF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lab of Oral &amp; Craniofacial Innovation (LOCI), Department of Innovation &amp; Technology Research, ADA Science &amp; Research Institute, Gaithersburg, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Warner</LastName><ForeName>B M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Salivary Disorders Unit, National Institute of Dental and Craniofacial Research, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Byrd</LastName><ForeName>K M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5565-0524</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lab of Oral &amp; Craniofacial Innovation (LOCI), Department of Innovation &amp; Technology Research, ADA Science &amp; Research Institute, Gaithersburg, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Salivary Disorders Unit, National Institute of Dental and Craniofacial Research, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Oral &amp; Craniofacial Health Sciences, Adams School of Dentistry, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Dent Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0354343</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-0345</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064307" MajorTopicYN="Y">Microbiota</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009055" MajorTopicYN="N">Mouth</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001419" MajorTopicYN="N">Bacteria</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000095028" MajorTopicYN="N">Multiomics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microbiome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral pathology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">saliva</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">virology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Conflicting InterestsThe authors declared the following potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest. Although the authors view each of these as noncompeting financial interests, we report that Q.T. Easter, B.F. Matuck, and K.M. Byrd are active members of the Human Cell Atlas. In addition, K.M. Byrd is a scientific advisor at Arcato Laboratories, Inc. (Durham, NC).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37731320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10714378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00220345231191115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Apostolou E, Rizwan M, Moustardas P, Sj&#xf6;gren P, Bertilson BC, Brag&#xe9;e B, Polo O, Ros&#xe9;n A. 2022. Saliva antibody-fingerprint of reactivated latent viruses after mild/asymptomatic COVID-19 is unique in patients with myalgic-encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Front Immunol. 13:949787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9630598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36341457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedard MC, Chihanga T, Carlile A, Jackson R, Brusadelli MG, Lee D, VonHandorf A, Rochman M, Dexheimer PJ, Chalmers J, et al.. 2023. Single cell transcriptomic analysis of HPV16-infected epithelium identifies a keratinocyte subpopulation implicated in cancer. Nat Commun. 14(1):1975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10082832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37031202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benfield AH, Henriques ST. 2020. Mode-of-action of antimicrobial peptides: membrane disruption vs. intracellular mechanisms. Front Med Technol. 2:610997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8757789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35047892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonam SR, Muller S. 2020. Parkinson&#x2019;s disease is an autoimmune disease: a reappraisal. Autoimmun Rev. 19(12):102684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33131704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brook I. 2009. The bacteriology of salivary gland infections. Oral Maxillofac Surg Clin North Am. 21(3):269&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19608044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrd KM, Gulati AS. 2021. The &#x201c;gum-gut&#x201d; axis in inflammatory bowel diseases: a hypothesis-driven review of associations and advances. Front Immunol. 12:620124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7933581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33679761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caetano AJ, Human Cell Atlas Oral and Craniofacial Bionetwork, Sequeira I, Byrd KM. 2022. A roadmap for the human oral and craniofacial cell atlas. J Dent Res. 101(11):1274&#x2013;1288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9516614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36154725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caetano AJ, Yianni V, Volponi A, Booth V, D&#x2019;Agostino EM, Sharpe P. 2021. Defining human mesenchymal and epithelial heterogeneity in response to oral inflammatory disease. ELife. 10:e62810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7781605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33393902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cate T. 2016. Oral histology. 9th ed. Halifax (NS): Elsevier.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang R, Yen-Ting Chen T, Wang SI, Hung YM, Chen HY, Wei CJ. 2023. Risk of autoimmune diseases in patients with COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study. EClinicalMedicine. 56:101783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9830133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36643619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choutka J, Jansari V, Hornig M, Iwasaki A. 2022. Unexplained post-acute infection syndromes. Nat Med. 28(5):911&#x2013;923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35585196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobbs C. 2019. Cytomegalovirus is a tumor-associated virus: armed and dangerous. Curr Opin Virol. 39:49&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31525538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corstjens PL, Abrams WR, Malamud D. 2016. Saliva and viral infections. Periodontol 2000. 70(1):93&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7167623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26662485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa-da-Silva AC, Aure MH, Dodge J, Martin D, Dhamala S, Cho M, Rose JJ, Bassim CW, Ambatipudi K, Hakim FT, et al.. 2022. Salivary ZG16B expression loss follows exocrine gland dysfunction related to oral chronic graft-versus-host disease. iScience. 25(1):103592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8718990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35005541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. 2023. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 21(3):133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devaux CA, Mezouar S, Mege JL. 2019. The e-cadherin cleavage associated to pathogenic bacteria infections can favor bacterial invasion and transmigration, dysregulation of the immune response and cancer induction in humans. Front Microbiol. 10:2598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6857109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31781079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominy SS, Lynch C, Ermini F, Benedyk M, Marczyk A, Konradi A, Nguyen M, Haditsch U, Raha D, Griffin C, et al.. 2019. Porphyromonas gingivalis in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease brains: evidence for disease causation and treatment with small-molecule inhibitors. Sci Adv. 5(1):eaau3333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6357742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30746447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engering A, Hogerwerf L, Slingenbergh J. 2013. Pathogen&#x2013;host&#x2013;environment interplay and disease emergence. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3630490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26038452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eren AM, Borisy GG, Huse SM, Mark Welch JL. 2014. Oligotyping analysis of the human oral microbiome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 111(28):E2875&#x2013;E2884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4104879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24965363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes Matuck B, Dolhnikoff M, Maia GVA, Isaac Sendyk D, Zarpellon A, Costa Gomes S, Duarte-Neto AN, Rebello Pinho JR, Gomes-Gouv&#xea;a MS, Sousa S, et al.. 2020. Periodontal tissues are targets for Sars-Cov-2: a post-mortem study. J Oral Microbiol. 13(1):1848135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33391625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes Matuck B, Ferraz da Silva LF, Warner BM, Byrd KM. 2023. The need for integrated research autopsies in the era of precision oral medicine. J Am Dent Assoc. 154(3):194&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9974796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36710158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzpatrick SG, Cohen DM, Clark AN. 2019. Ulcerated lesions of the oral mucosa: clinical and histologic review. Head Neck Pathol. 13(1):91&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6405793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30701449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fournier B, Boutboul D, Bruneau J, Miot C, Boulanger C, Malphettes M, Pellier I, Dunogu&#xe9; B, Terrier B, Suarez F, et al.. 2020. Rapid identification and characterization of infected cells in blood during chronic active Epstein-Barr virus infection. J Exp Med. 217(11):e20192262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7596820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32812031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y-D, Ding M, Dong X, Zhang J-J, Kursat Azkur A, Azkur D, Gan H, Sun Y-L, Fu W, Li W, et al.. 2021. Risk factors for severe and critically ill COVID-19 patients: a review. Allergy. 76(2):428&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33185910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh S, Kumar M, Santiana M, Mishra A, Zhang M, Labayo H, Chibly AM, Nakamura H, Tanaka T, Henderson W, et al.. 2022. Enteric viruses replicate in salivary glands and infect through saliva. Nature. 607(7918):345&#x2013;350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9243862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35768512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbertson B, Edenborough K, McVernon J, Brown LE. 2019. Inhibition of influenza A virus by human infant saliva. Viruses. 11(8):766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6723162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31434247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant M, Kilsg&#xe5;rd O, &#xc5;kerman S, Klinge B, Demmer RT, Malmstr&#xf6;m J, J&#xf6;nsson D. 2019. The human salivary antimicrobial peptide profile according to the oral microbiota in health, periodontitis and smoking. J Innate Immun. 11(5):432&#x2013;444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6738235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30485856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin DE. 2022. Why does viral RNA sometimes persist after recovery from acute infections? PLoS Biol. 20(6):e3001687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9191737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35648781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groeger S, Meyle J. 2019. Oral mucosal epithelial cells. Front Immunol. 10:208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6383680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30837987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guimar&#xe3;es D, Pissarra R, Reis-Melo A, Guimar&#xe3;es H. 2021. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MISC): a systematic review. Int J Clin Pract. 75(11):e14450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34105843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta S, Mohindra R, Chauhan PK, Singla V, Goyal K, Sahni V, Gaur R, Verma DK, Ghosh A, Soni RK, et al.. 2021. SARS-CoV-2 detection in gingival crevicular fluid. J Dent Res. 100(2):187&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7642823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33138663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haran JP, Bradley E, Zeamer AL, Cincotta L, Salive MC, Dutta P, Mutaawe S, Anya O, Meza-Segura M, Moormann AM, et al.. 2021. Inflammation-type dysbiosis of the oral microbiome associates with the duration of COVID-19 symptoms and long COVID. JCI Insight. 6(20):e152346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8564890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34403368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartshorn KL, White MR, Tecle T, Holmskov U, Crouch EC. 2006. Innate defense against influenza A virus: activity of human neutrophil defensins and interactions of defensins with surfactant protein D. J Immunol. 176(11):6962&#x2013;6972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16709857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou YJ, Okuda K, Edwards CE, Martinez DR, Asakura T, Dinnon KH, III, Kato T, Lee RE, Yount BL, Mascenik TM, et al.. 2020. SARS-CoV-2 reverse genetics reveals a variable infection gradient in the respiratory tract. Cell. 182(2):429&#x2013;446.e14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7250779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32526206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houen G, Trier NH. 2021. Epstein-Barr virus and systemic autoimmune diseases. Front Immunol. 11:587380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7817975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33488588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang N, P&#xe9;rez P, Kato T, Mikami Y, Okuda K, Gilmore RC, Conde CD, Gasmi B, Stein S, Beach M, et al.. 2021. SARS-CoV-2 infection of the oral cavity and saliva. Nat Med. 27(5):892&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8240394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33767405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulo C, de Castro E, Masson P, Bougueleret L, Bairoch A, Xenarios I, Le Mercier P. 2011. Viralzone: a knowledge resource to understand virus diversity. Nucleic Acids Res. 39(Database issue):D576&#x2013;D582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3013774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20947564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamieson GA, Maitland NJ, Wilcock GK, Craske J, Itzhaki RF. 1991. Latent herpes simplex virus type 1 in normal and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease brains. J Med Virol. 33(4):224&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1649907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffers L, Webster-Cyriaque JY. 2011. Viruses and salivary gland disease (SGD): lessons from HIV SGD. Adv Dent Res. 23(1):79&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3144046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21441486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji S, Choi Y. 2020. Microbial and host factors that affect bacterial invasion of the gingiva. J Dent Res. 99(9):1013&#x2013;1020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32392459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kincer LP, Joseph SB, Gilleece MM, Hauser BM, Sizemore S, Zhou S, Di Germanio C, Zetterberg H, Fuchs D, Deeks SG, et al.. 2023. Rebound HIV-1 in cerebrospinal fluid after antiviral therapy interruption is mainly clonally amplified R5 T cell-tropic virus. Nat Microbiol. 8(2):260&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10201410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36717718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Rosa GRM, Libra M, De Pasquale R, Ferlito S, Pedull&#xe0; E. 2020. Association of viral infections with oral cavity lesions: role of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Front Med (Lausanne). 7:571214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7840611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33521007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine KS, Leonard HL, Blauwendraat C, Iwaki H, Johnson N, Bandres-Ciga S, Ferrucci L, Faghri F, Singleton AB, Nalls MA. 2023. Virus exposure and neurodegenerative disease risk across national biobanks. Neuron. 111(7):1086&#x2013;1093.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10079561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36669485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Chu A. 2021. Sj&#xf6;gren&#x2019;s syndrome and viral infections. Rheumatol Ther. 8(3):1051&#x2013;1059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8380615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34227038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madissoon E, Oliver AJ, Kleshchevnikov V, Wilbrey-Clark A, Polanski K, Richoz N, Ribeiro Orsi A, Mamanova L, Bolt L, Elmentaite R, et al.. 2023. A spatially resolved atlas of the human lung characterizes a gland-associated immune niche. Nat Genet. 55(1):66&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36543915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchesan JT, Warner BM, Byrd KM. 2021. The &#x201c;oral&#x201d; history of COVID-19: primary infection, salivary transmission, and post-acute implications. J Periodontol. 92(10):1357&#x2013;1367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9374061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34390597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mark Welch JL, Dewhirst FE, Borisy GG. 2019. Biogeography of the oral microbiome: the site-specialist hypothesis. Annu Rev Microbiol. 73:335&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7153577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31180804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mark Welch JL, Rossetti BJ, Rieken CW, Dewhirst FE, Borisy GG. 2016. Biogeography of a human oral microbiome at the micron scale. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 113(6):E791&#x2013;E800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4760785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26811460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martelli J&#xfa;nior H, Gueiros LA, de Lucena EG, Coletta RD. 2022. Increase in the number of Sj&#xf6;gren&#x2019;s syndrome cases in Brazil in the COVID-19 era. Oral Dis. 28 Suppl 2:2588&#x2013;2590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34042242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mothes R, Pascual-Reguant A, Koehler R, Liebeskind J, Liebheit A, Bauherr S, Philipsen L, Dittmayer C, Laue M, von Manitius R, et al.. 2023. Distinct tissue niches direct lung immunopathology via CCL18 and CCL21 in severe COVID-19. Nat Commun. 14(1):791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9922044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36774347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan A, Zlitni S, Brooks EF, Vance SE, Dahlen A, Hedlin H, Park RM, Han A, Schmidtke DT, Verma R, et al.. 2022. Gastrointestinal symptoms and fecal shedding of SARS-CoV-2 RNA suggest prolonged gastrointestinal infection. Med. 3(6):371&#x2013;387.e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9005383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35434682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deeks SG, Mustapic M, Kapogiannis D, Henrich TJ, Lu S, Goldberg SA, Hoh R, Chen JY, Martinez EO, et al.. 2022. SARS-CoV-2 and mitochondrial proteins in neural-derived exosomes of COVID-19. Ann Neurol. 91(6):772&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9082480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35285072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng X, Cheng L, You Y, Tang C, Ren B, Li Y, Xu X, Zhou X. 2022. Oral microbiota in human systematic diseases. Int J Oral Sci. 14(1):14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8891310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35236828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajasuo A, Jousimies-Somer H, Savolainen S, Lepp&#xe4;nen J, Murtomaa H, Meurman JH. 1996. Bacteriologic findings in tonsillitis and pericoronitis. Clin Infect Dis. 23(1):51&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8816129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajewsky N, Almouzni G, Gorski SA, Aerts S, Amit I, Bertero MG, Bock C, Bredenoord AL, Cavalli G, Chiocca S, et al.. 2020. LifeTime and improving European healthcare through cell-based interceptive medicine. Nature. 587(7834):377&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7656507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32894860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzo R. 2020. Controversial role of herpesviruses in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. PLoS Pathog. 16(6):e1008575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7302436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32555685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudney JD, Chen R, Sedgewick GJ. 2001. Intracellular actinobacillus actinomycetemcomitans and porphyromonas gingivalis in buccal epithelial cells collected from human subjects. Infect Immun. 69(4):2700&#x2013;2707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC98209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11254637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shine N, Konopka K, D&#xfc;zg&#xfc;ne&#x15f; N. 1997. The anti-HIV-1 activity associated with saliva. J Dent Res. 76(2):634&#x2013;640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9062556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shugars DC, Sweet SP, Malamud D, Kazmi SH, Page-Shafer K, Challacombe SJ. 2002. Saliva and inhibition of HIV-1 infection: molecular mechanisms. Oral Dis. 8 Suppl 2:169&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12164652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soukup V, Hor&#xe1;cek I, Cerny R. 2013. Development and evolution of the vertebrate primary mouth. J Anat. 222(1):79&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3552417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22804777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein SR, Ramelli SC, Grazioli A, Chung JY, Singh M, Yinda CK, Winkler CW, Sun J, Dickey JM, Ylaya K, et al.. 2022. SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence in the human body and brain at autopsy. Nature. 612(7941):758&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9749650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36517603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun W, Gao C, Hartana CA, Osborn MR, Einkauf KB, Lian X, Bone B, Bonheur N, Chun TW, Rosenberg ES, et al.. 2023. Phenotypic signatures of immune selection in HIV-1 reservoir cells. Nature. 614(7947):309&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9908552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36599977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur A, Mikkelsen H, Jungersen G. 2019. Intracellular pathogens: host immunity and microbial persistence strategies. J Immunol Res. 2019:1356540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6487120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31111075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomov VT, Palko O, Lau CW, Pattekar A, Sun Y, Tacheva R, Bengsch B, Manne S, Cosma GL, Eisenlohr LC, et al.. 2017. Differentiation and protective capacity of virus-specific CD8+ T cells suggest murine norovirus persistence in an immune-privileged enteric niche. Immunity. 47(4):723&#x2013;738.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6077984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29031786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travaglini KJ, Nabhan AN, Penland L, Sinha R, Gillich A, Sit RV, Chang S, Conley SD, Mori Y, Seita J, et al.. 2020. A molecular cell atlas of the human lung from single-cell RNA sequencing. Nature. 587(7835):619&#x2013;625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7704697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33208946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veenhuis RT, Abreu CM, Costa PAG, Ferreira EA, Ratliff J, Pohlenz L, Shirk EN, Rubin LH, Blankson JN, Gama L, et al.. 2023. Monocyte-derived macrophages contain persistent latent HIV reservoirs. Nat Microbiol. 8(5):833&#x2013;844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10159852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36973419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weaver DF. 2023. Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease as an innate autoimmune disease (AD2): a new molecular paradigm. Alzheimers Dement. 19(3):1086&#x2013;1098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36165334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams DW, Greenwell-Wild T, Brenchley L, Dutzan N, Overmiller A, Sawaya AP, Webb S, Martin D, NIDCD/NIDCR Genomics and Computational Biology Core, Hajishengallis G, et al.. 2021. Human oral mucosa cell atlas reveals a stromal-neutrophil axis regulating tissue immunity. Cell. 184(15):4090&#x2013;4104.e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8359928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34129837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>