<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37577106</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2040-6223</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Therapeutic advances in chronic disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ther Adv Chronic Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The use of complementary and alternative medicine for the treatment of gastrointestinal symptoms in Long COVID: a systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20406223231190548</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20406223231190548</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20406223231190548</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/20406223231190548</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Most people with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) experience resolution of symptoms within days to weeks following initial infection. In a subset of individuals, symptoms persist longer than 4&#x2009;weeks, known as 'Long COVID'. Many gastrointestinal (GI) symptoms persist as part of this syndrome; yet, an approach to treatment remains unclear. Prior studies have demonstrated the efficacy of complementary and alternative medicine (CAM) for the treatment of acute COVID-19 infections, but little data exist regarding the potential use of CAM in the treatment of Long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Identify CAM approaches useful in treating the GI symptoms of Long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A systematic review of studies reporting on the use of CAM for the treatment of GI symptoms of Long COVID was performed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Five electronic databases were searched from January 2019 to November 2022. Studies describing the use of CAM to treat GI symptoms of Long COVID were included and assessed by two independent reviewers. Studies not reporting on GI symptoms or using CAM were excluded. Studies chosen for final review underwent quality and bias assessment using predetermined criteria. The extracted data were synthesized utilizing a framework derived from the National Center of Complementary and Integrative Health categories.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The initial search yielded 396 articles. After applying the eligibility criteria, a total of four studies (three case reports and one case series) were included for final review. Two studies used nutritional supplements and two studies used traditional Chinese medicine. Reductions in nausea, loss of appetite, diarrhea, acid reflux, epigastric pain, and bloating were reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This is the first systematic review to explore the role of CAM in treating GI manifestations of Long COVID. The review identified four studies, all reporting reductions in the GI symptoms of Long COVID. Despite the positive studies included in this review, the overall search yielded few results, all of which were non-experimental. As the post-infectious sequelae of COVID-19 become better recognized in the wake of the pandemic, higher-quality clinical studies are needed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), 2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gawey</LastName><ForeName>Brent</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4046-7679</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic, 200 First Street SW, Rochester, MN 55905, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic, Research Services, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bauer</LastName><ForeName>Brent</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Joanne</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiao Jing</ForeName><Initials>XJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ther Adv Chronic Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101532140</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2040-6223</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complementary and alternative medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastrointestinal symptoms</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37577106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10422885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20406223231190548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_20406223231190548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wiersinga WJ, Rhodes A, Cheng AC, et al.. Pathophysiology, transmission, diagnosis, and treatment of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a review. JAMA 2020; 324: 782&#x2013;793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32648899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
WHO. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Situation Report &#x2013; 51, https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/situation-reports/20200311-sitrep-51-covid-19.pdf?sfvrsn=1ba62e57_6 (2020, accessed 10 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin L, Savale L, Pham T, et al.. Four-month clinical status of a cohort of patients after hospitalization for COVID-19. JAMA 2021; 325: 1525&#x2013;1534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7970386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33729425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
CDC. Long COVID or post-COVID conditions, https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html (2023, accessed 8 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Tariq R, Jena A, et al.. Gastrointestinal manifestations of long COVID: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Therap Adv Gastroenterol 2022; 15: 17562848221118403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9393939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36004306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghoshal UC, Ghoshal U, Rahman MM, et al.. Post-infection functional gastrointestinal disorders following coronavirus disease-19: a case-control study. J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2022; 37: 489&#x2013;498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8657345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al.. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med 2021; 27: 601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, et al.. Managing the long term effects of covid-19: summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ 2021; 372: n136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Health NCfCaI. Complementary, Alternative, or Integrative Health: what&#x2019;s In a Name?, https://www.nccih.nih.gov/health/complementary-alternative-or-integrative-health-whats-in-a-name (2021, accessed 12 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badakhsh M, Dastras M, Sarchahi Z, et al.. Complementary and alternative medicine therapies and COVID-19: a systematic review. Rev Environ Health 2021; 36: 443&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33838089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousa HA. Prevention and treatment of influenza, influenza-like illness, and common cold by herbal, complementary, and natural therapies. J Evid Based Complementary Altern Med 2017; 22: 166&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5871211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27055821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemil&#xe4; H, Chalker E. The effectiveness of high dose zinc acetate lozenges on various common cold symptoms: a meta-analysis. BMC Fam Pract 2015; 16: 24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4359576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25888289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livingston C, Cozzens J, Hamilton A. FPIN&#x2019;s clinical inquiries. Treatments for symptoms of the common cold. Am Fam Physician 2013; 88: Online.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24364554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Science M, Johnstone J, Roth DE, et al.. Zinc for the treatment of the common cold: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. CMAJ 2012; 184: E551&#x2013;E561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3394849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22566526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkins J, Baker C, Cherry L, et al.. Black elderberry (Sambucus nigra) supplementation effectively treats upper respiratory symptoms: a meta-analysis of randomized, controlled clinical trials. Complement Ther Med 2019; 42: 361&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30670267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams KK, Baker WL, Sobieraj DM. Myth busters: dietary supplements and COVID-19. Ann Pharmacother 2020; 54: 820&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8685478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32396382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiralongo E, Wee SS, Lea RA. Elderberry supplementation reduces cold duration and symptoms in air-travellers: a randomized, double-blind placebo-controlled clinical trial. Nutrients 2016; 8: 182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4848651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27023596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King S, Glanville J, Sanders ME, et al.. Effectiveness of probiotics on the duration of illness in healthy children and adults who develop common acute respiratory infectious conditions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Nutr 2014; 112: 41&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4054664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24780623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadkam MN, Mozaffari-Khosravi H, Mozayan MR. A comparison of the effect of honey, dextromethorphan, and diphenhydramine on nightly cough and sleep quality in children and their parents. J Altern Complement Med 2010; 16: 787&#x2013;793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20618098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmer A, G&#xfc;nther J, Motschall E, et al.. Pelargonium sidoides extract for treating acute respiratory tract infections. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2013; 3: Cd006323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24146345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lizogub VG, Riley DS, Heger M. Efficacy of a pelargonium sidoides preparation in patients with the common cold: a randomized, double blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Explore (NY) 2007; 3: 573&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18005909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu ST, Zhan C, Ma YJ, et al.. Effect of qigong exercise and acupressure rehabilitation program on pulmonary function and respiratory symptoms in patients hospitalized with severe COVID-19: a randomized controlled trial. Integr Med Res 2021; 10: 100796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8553411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34733607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung A, Kang N, Bollom A, et al.. Complementary and alternative medicine use is prevalent among patients with gastrointestinal diseases. Dig Dis Sci 2015; 60: 1883&#x2013;1888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25556585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al.. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Int J Surg 2010; 8: 336&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20171303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riley DS, Barber MS, Kienle GS, et al.. CARE guidelines for case reports: explanation and elaboration document. J Clin Epidemiol 2017; 89: 218&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28529185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagnier JJ, Kienle G, Altman DG, et al.. The CARE guidelines: consensus-based clinical case reporting guideline development. Glob Adv Health Med 2013; 2: 38&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3833570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24416692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Wu G, Zhao L, et al.. Nutritional modulation of Gut microbiota alleviates severe gastrointestinal symptoms in a patient with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. mBio 2022; 13: e0380121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9040862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35254129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morello R, De Rose C, Cardinali S, et al.. Lactoferrin as possible treatment for chronic gastrointestinal symptoms in children with long COVID: case series and literature review. Children (Basel) 2022; 9: 1446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9600357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36291381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jania C. The treatment of long COVID with Chinese medicine: a case report. J Chin Med 2021; 2021: 17+.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang D. Guidelines for patient-practitioner contact and TCM management in post-COVID syndromes. J Chin Med 2021; 2021: 71&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Mak JWY, Su Q, et al.. Gut microbiota dynamics in a prospective cohort of patients with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Gut 2022; 71: 544&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard-Raichon L, Venzon M, Klein J, et al.. Gut microbiome dysbiosis in antibiotic-treated COVID-19 patients is associated with microbial translocation and bacteremia. Nat Commun 2022; 13: 5926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9626559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36319618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo T, Zhang F, Lui GCY, et al.. Alterations in Gut microbiota of patients with COVID-19 during time of hospitalization. Gastroenterology 2020; 159: 944&#x2013;955.e948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7237927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeoh YK, Zuo T, Lui GC, et al.. Gut microbiota composition reflects disease severity and dysfunctional immune responses in patients with COVID-19. Gut 2021; 70: 698&#x2013;706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7804842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33431578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo T, Wu X, Wen W, et al.. Gut microbiome alterations in COVID-19. Genomics Proteomics Bioinformatics 2021; 19: 679&#x2013;688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34560321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell&#xe9;s A, Aguirre-Ram&#xed;rez D, Abad I, et al.. Lactoferrin modulates gut microbiota and toll-like receptors (TLRs) in mice with dysbiosis induced by antibiotics. Food Funct 2022; 13: 5854&#x2013;5869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35545893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Embleton ND, Berrington JE. Clinical trials of lactoferrin in the newborn: effects on infection and the Gut microbiome. Nestle Nutr Inst Workshop Ser 2020; 94: 141&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32160617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dix C, Wright O. Bioavailability of a novel form of microencapsulated bovine lactoferrin and its effect on inflammatory markers and the gut microbiome: a pilot study. Nutrients 2018; 10: 1115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6115941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30126153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo M, Tao W, Flavell RA, et al.. Potential intestinal infection and faecal-oral transmission of SARS-CoV-2. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol 2021; 18: 269&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7883337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33589829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Guo C, Tang L, et al.. Prolonged presence of SARS-CoV-2 viral RNA in faecal samples. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol 2020; 5: 434&#x2013;435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32199469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Li X, Zhu B, et al.. Characteristics of pediatric SARS-CoV-2 infection and potential evidence for persistent fecal viral shedding. Nat Med 2020; 26: 502&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32284613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HH, Choi YY, Choi MG. The efficacy of hypnotherapy in the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurogastroenterol Motil 2014; 20: 152&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4015203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24840368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters SL, Yao CK, Philpott H, et al.. Randomised clinical trial: the efficacy of gut-directed hypnotherapy is similar to that of the low FODMAP diet for the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2016; 44: 447&#x2013;459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27397586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Silva A, Marshall DA, Vallance JK, et al.. Meditation and yoga for irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized clinical trial. Am J Gastroenterol 2022; 118: 329&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9889201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36422517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M. Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nat Immunol 2022; 23: 194&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Gou CY, Li XM, et al.. Effects of Chinese medicine on symptoms, syndrome evolution, and lung inflammation absorption in COVID-19 convalescent patients during 84-day follow-up after hospital discharge: a prospective cohort and nested case-control study. Chin J Integr Med 2021; 27: 245&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33534076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi N, Mo Q, Yang S, et al.. Treatment of pulmonary fibrosis in one convalescent patient with corona virus disease 2019 by oral traditional Chinese medicine decoction: a case report. J Integr Med 2021; 19: 185&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33349611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas R, Aldous J, Forsyth R, et al.. The influence of a blend of probiotic lactobacillus and prebiotic inulin on the duration and severity of symptoms among individuals with Covid-19. Infect Dis: Res Treat 2021; 05: 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trager RJ, Brewka EC, Kaiser CM, et al.. Acupuncture in multidisciplinary treatment for post-COVID-19 syndrome. Med Acupunct 2022; 34: 177&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9248328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35821795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astin JA. Why patients use alternative medicine: results of a national study. JAMA 1998; 279: 1548&#x2013;1553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9605899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>