<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36654638</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prolonged COVID-19 in a Multiple Sclerosis Patient Treated With Rituximab.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e32523</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e32523</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e32523</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.32523</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Immunocompromised patients commonly present prolonged viral shedding of the novel coronavirus SARS-CoV-2, detected through reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) in nasopharyngeal or oropharyngeal swabs. The detection and estimation of the viral load in patients with COVID-19 is of utmost importance, not only for the effective isolation of the patient but also from a therapeutic point of view. In the current study, we present the case of an immunocompromised patient receiving rituximab infusions for the treatment of multiple sclerosis who exhibited COVID-19 clinical symptomatology for an extended period of time along with prolonged viral shedding while at the same time being unable to organize sufficient humoral immunity. Despite being fully vaccinated and having suffered symptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infections, antibodies against the virus remained undetected. Clinical relapse of his symptoms led to the trialing of a multitude of therapeutic interventions in order to combat the disease, with an extended remdesivir regimen proving the most efficacious in the alleviation of his symptoms. This case demonstrates how immunocompromised&#xa0;COVID-19 patients should be regarded under a different scope when it comes to the diagnosis, management, and resolution of their SARS-CoV-2 infection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022, Kintrilis et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kintrilis</LastName><ForeName>Nikos</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gkinos</LastName><ForeName>Charilaos P</ForeName><Initials>CP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Second Department of Internal Medicine, 401 General Military Hospital of Athens, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Galinos</LastName><ForeName>Iosif</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Unit, 401 General Military Hospital of Athens, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronavirus disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">humoral immunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunosuppression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">novel coronavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">remdesivir</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rituximab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sars-cov-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36654638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9840416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.32523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>A novel coronavirus from patients with pneumonia in China, 2019. Zhu N, Zhang D, Wang W, et al. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:727&#x2013;733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31978945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 coronavirus pandemic.  [
Nov;
2022 
]. 2022. https://www.worldometers.info/coronavirus/ https://www.worldometers.info/coronavirus/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comprehensive review of COVID-19 characteristics. Esakandari H, Nabi-Afjadi M, Fakkari-Afjadi J, Farahmandian N, Miresmaeili SM, Bahreini E. Biol Proced Online. 2020;22:19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7402395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32774178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dynamics of SARS-CoV-2 shedding in the respiratory tract depends on the severity of disease in COVID-19 patients. Munker D, Osterman A, Stubbe H, et al. Eur Respir J. 2021;58</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7898160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33602859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The proportion of SARS-CoV-2 infections that are asymptomatic: a systematic review . Oran DP, Topol EJ. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174:655&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7839426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33481642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inferred duration of infectious period of SARS-CoV-2: rapid scoping review and analysis of available evidence for asymptomatic and symptomatic COVID-19 cases. Byrne AW, McEvoy D, Collins AB, et al. BMJ Open. 2020;10:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7409948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duration of infectious shedding of SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variant and its relation with symptoms. Keske &#x15e;, G&#xfc;ney-Esken G, Vatansever C, et al. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9287585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35853589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prolonged viral shedding of SARS-CoV-2 in an immunocompromised patient. Nakajima Y, Ogai A, Furukawa K, et al. J Infect Chemother. 2021;27:387&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33328135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 in an immunocompromised host: persistent shedding of viable SARS-CoV-2 and emergence of multiple mutations: a case report. Leung WF, Chorlton S, Tyson J, et al. Int J Infect Dis. 2022;114:178&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8553657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34757008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prolonged viral shedding of SARS-CoV-2 in two immunocompromised patients, a case report. Niyonkuru M, Pedersen RM, Assing K, Andersen TE, Skov MN, Johansen IS, Madsen LW. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21:743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8330202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34344321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prolonged SARS-CoV-2 infection following rituximab treatment: clinical course and response to therapeutic interventions correlated with quantitative viral cultures and cycle threshold values. Thornton CS, Huntley K, Berenger BM, et al. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2022;11:28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8817557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35123573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent viral shedding of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 after treatment with bendamustine and rituximab: a case report. Arai T, Mukai S, Kazama R, Ogawa Y, Nishida K, Hatanaka K, Gohma I. J Infect Chemother. 2022;28:810&#x2013;813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8801906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35115239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prolonged severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 replication in an immunocompromised patient . Baang JH, Smith C, Mirabelli C, et al. J Infect Dis. 2021;223:23&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7797758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33089317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistence and evolution of SARS-CoV-2 in an immunocompromised host. Choi B, Choudhary MC, Regan J, et al. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:2291&#x2013;2293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7673303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33176080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prolonged shedding of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) at high viral loads among hospitalized immunocompromised persons living with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), South Africa. Meiring S, Tempia S, Bhiman JN, et al. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;75:0&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8903337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35134129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 in B cell-depleted patients after rituximab: a diagnostic and therapeutic challenge. Furlan A, Forner G, Cipriani L, Vian E, Rigoli R, Gherlinzoni F, Scotton P. Front Immunol. 2021;12:763412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8595333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34804051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remdesivir in coronavirus disease 2019 patients treated with anti-CD20 monoclonal antibodies: a case series. R&#xfc;fenacht S, Gantenbein P, Boggian K, et al. Infection. 2022;50:783&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9010446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35426564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 prophylaxis in immunosuppressed patients: Beyond vaccination. Gentile I, Schiano Moriello N. PLoS Med. 2022;19:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8836303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35089920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Three doses of an mRNA COVID-19 vaccine in solid-organ transplant recipients. Kamar N, Abravanel F, Marion O, Couat C, Izopet J, Del Bello A. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:661&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8262620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34161700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 vaccination in rituximab-treated patients: b cells promote humoral immune responses in the presence of T-cell-mediated immunity. Mrak D, Tobudic S, Koblischke M, et al. Ann Rheum Dis. 2021;80:1345&#x2013;1350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34285048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dexamethasone in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Horby P, Lim WS, Emberson JR, et al. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:693&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32678530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dexamethasone in hospitalised patients with COVID-19: addressing uncertainties. Matthay MA, Thompson BT. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8:1170&#x2013;1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7598750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33129421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low rate of bacterial co-infection in patients with COVID-19. Adler H, Ball R, Fisher M, Mortimer K, Vardhan MS. Lancet Microbe. 2020;1:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7279742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32835331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duration of isolation and precautions in immunocompromised patients with COVID-19. Taramasso L, Sepulcri C, Mikulska M, et al. J Hosp Infect. 2021;111:202&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7898969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33631234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ending isolation and precautions for people with COVID-19: interim guidance.  [
Nov;
2022 
]. 2022. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/duration-isolation.html https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/duration-isolation.html</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>