<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36718484</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2383-4625</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical and experimental emergency medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Exp Emerg Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 syndrome presenting as postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>18</StartPage><EndPage>25</EndPage><MedlinePgn>18-25</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.15441/ceem.22.409</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The novel SARS-CoV-2 emerged in 2019, and the global COVID-19 pandemic continues into 2022. It has been known that a subset of patients develops chronic, debilitating symptoms after otherwise complete recovery from acute infection of COVID-19. Multiple terms have been used to describe this constellation of symptoms, including long COVID, long-haul COVID, and postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 syndrome (PASC). PASC is broadly defined as a wide range of new, returning, or ongoing symptoms at least four weeks after infection. Those patients are often seen in emergency departments after acute COVID-19 infection, but their symptoms are not adequately managed because the underlying pathophysiology of PASC is not well understood. Among patients with PASC, postural orthostatic tachycardic syndrome (POTS) has been increasingly recognized. POTS is one of the most common forms of autonomic dysfunction and defined by a sustained orthostatic tachycardia during active standing or head-up tilt test in the absence of orthostatic hypotension or other cardiopulmonary diseases. Because POTS is a treatable condition, it is important to recognize POTS among PASC patients. Herein, we reviewed the current literature on POTS and dysautonomia in PASC in order to better understand the overlap and distinction between these pathologies.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diekman</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diekman Dysautonomia LLC, Oakland, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, University of North Carolina Gillings School of Global Public Health, Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chung</LastName><ForeName>Tae</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Exp Emerg Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101657493</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2383-4625</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postural tachycardia syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>CONFLICT OF INTEREST</b>
. No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36718484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10090716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15441/ceem.22.409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ceem.22.409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Finelli L, Gupta V, Petigara T, Yu K, Bauer KA, Puzniak LA. Mortality among US patients hospitalized with SARS-CoV-2 infection in 2020. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e216556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8033442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33830226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nka AD, Ka&#x2019;e AC, Bouba Y, et al. Global burden of SARS-CoV-2 infection, hospitalization and case fatality rate among COVID-19 vaccinated individuals and its associated factors: a systematic review and meta-analysis protocol. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0272839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9362926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35943981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alimohamadi Y, Tola HH, Abbasi-Ghahramanloo A, Janani M, Sepandi M. Case fatality rate of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Prev Med Hyg. 2021;62:E311&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8451339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34604571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)  COVID-19: long COVID [Internet]  CDC; 2022 [cited 2022 Dec 1]. Available from:  https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html#print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR, Guzman JC, Harvey P, et al. Canadian cardiovascular society position statement on postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) and related disorders of chronic orthostatic intolerance. Can J Cardiol. 2020;36:357&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32145864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miglis MG, Prieto T, Shaik R, Muppidi S, Sinn DI, Jaradeh S. A case report of postural tachycardia syndrome after COVID-19. Clin Auton Res. 2020;30:449&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7471493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32880754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanjwal K, Jamal S, Kichloo A, Grubb BP. New-onset postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome following coronavirus disease 2019 infection. J Innov Card Rhythm Manag. 2020;11:4302&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7685310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33262898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umapathi T, Poh MQ, Fan BE, Li KF, George J, Tan JY. Acute hyperhidrosis and postural tachycardia in a COVID-19 patient. Clin Auton Res. 2020;30:571&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7511524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32970212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishibashi Y, Yoneyama K, Tsuchida T, Akashi YJ. Post-COVID-19 postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. Intern Med. 2021;60:2345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8355393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34053992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ocher RA, Padilla E, Hsu JC, Taub PR. Clinical and laboratory improvement in hyperadrenergic postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) after COVID-19 infection. Case Rep Cardiol. 2021;2021:7809231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8405341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34471549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Sullivan JS, Lyne A, Vaughan CJ. COVID-19-induced postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome treated with ivabradine. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14:e243585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8204164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34127505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson M, Stahlberg M, Runold M, et al. Long-haul post-COVID-19 symptoms presenting as a variant of postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome: the Swedish experience. JACC Case Rep. 2021;3:573&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7946344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33723532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petracek LS, Suskauer SJ, Vickers RF, et al. Adolescent and young adult ME/CFS after confirmed or probable COVID-19. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021;8:668944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8116546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33996867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S, Whitelaw S. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) and other autonomic disorders after COVID-19 infection: a case series of 20 patients. Immunol Res. 2021;69:205&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8009458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33786700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchhorn R, Willaschek C, Baumann C. SARS-CoV-2 infections and the autonomic nervous system. Monatsschr Kinderheilkd. 2021;169:645&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8076666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33935300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman BP, Khoury JA, Blair JE, Grill MF. COVID-19 dysautonomia. Front Neurol. 2021;12:624968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8076737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33927679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schofield JR. Persistent antiphospholipid antibodies, mast cell activation syndrome, postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome and post-COVID syndrome: 1 year on. Eur J Case Rep Intern Med. 2021;8:002378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8046288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33869099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco J, Titano R. Severe post-COVID-19 dysautonomia: a case report. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22:214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8892817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35241011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agnihotri SP, Luis CV, Kazamel M. Autonomic neuropathy as post-acute sequela of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a case report. J Neurovirol. 2022;28:158&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8856878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35181863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai AD, Boursiquot BC, Moore CJ, et al. Autonomic dysfunction post-acute COVID-19 infection. HeartRhythm Case Rep. 2022;8:143&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8626157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34868880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buoite Stella A, Furlanis G, Frezza NA, Valentinotti R, Ajcevic M, Manganotti P. Autonomic dysfunction in post-COVID patients with and without neurological symptoms: a prospective multidomain observational study. J Neurol. 2022;269:587&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8359764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34386903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallukat G, Hohberger B, Wenzel K, et al. Functional autoantibodies against G-protein coupled receptors in patients with persistent long-COVID-19 symptoms. J Transl Autoimmun. 2021;4:100100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8049853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33880442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shouman K, Vanichkachorn G, Cheshire WP, et al. Autonomic dysfunction following COVID-19 infection: an early experience. Clin Auton Res. 2021;31:385&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8050227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33860871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal SM, Landers DB, Hollenberg SM, et al. Prospective evaluation of autonomic dysfunction in post-acute sequela of COVID-19. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79:2325&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8976261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35381331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermel M, Sweeney M, Abud E, et al. COVID-19 vaccination might induce postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome: a case report. Vaccines (Basel) 2022;10:991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9323926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35891154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy S, Reddy S, Arora M. A case of postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome secondary to the messenger RNA COVID-19 vaccine. Cureus. 2021;13:e14837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8101507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33968543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J, Kim S, Lee J, An JY. A case of transient POTS following COVID-19 vaccine. Acta Neurol Belg. 2022;122:1081&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9208536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35725868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choutka J, Jansari V, Hornig M, Iwasaki A. Unexplained postacute infection syndromes. Nat Med. 2022;28:911&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35585196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourne KM, Chew DS, Stiles LE, et al. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome is associated with significant employment and economic loss. J Intern Med. 2021;290:203&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9156448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33586284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw BH, Stiles LE, Bourne K, et al. The face of postural tachycardia syndrome: insights from a large cross-sectional online community-based survey. J Intern Med. 2019;286:438&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6790699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30861229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedorowski A. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome: clinical presentation, aetiology and management. J Intern Med. 2019;285:352&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30372565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renaud M, Thibault C, Le Normand F, et al. Clinical outcomes for patients with anosmia 1 year after COVID-19 diagnosis. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2115352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8226421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34165581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak P, Mukerji SS, Alabsi HS, et al. Multisystem Involvement in post-acute sequelae of coronavirus disease 19. Ann Neurol. 2022;91:367&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9011495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34952975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak P, Giannetti MP, Weller E, et al. Network autonomic analysis of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 and postural tachycardia syndrome. Neurol Sci. 2022;43:6627&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9517969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36169757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polydefkis M, Hauer P, Sheth S, Sirdofsky M, Griffin JW, McArthur JC. The time course of epidermal nerve fibre regeneration: studies in normal controls and in people with diabetes, with and without neuropathy. Brain. 2004;127(Pt 7):1606&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15128618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plash WB, Diedrich A, Biaggioni I, et al. Diagnosing postural tachycardia syndrome: comparison of tilt testing compared with standing haemodynamics. Clin Sci (Lond) 2013;124:109&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3478101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22931296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal Y, Shoenfeld Y. Vaccine-induced autoimmunity: the role of molecular mimicry and immune crossreaction. Cell Mol Immunol. 2018;15:586&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6078966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29503439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>