<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37725530</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2563-6316</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIRx med</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIRx Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Postacute Sequelae of COVID-19 and Adverse Psychiatric Outcomes: Protocol for an Etiology and Risk Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e43880</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e43880</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e43880</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/43880</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The postacute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) is a syndrome characterized by persistent COVID-19 symptoms or the onset of new symptoms following recovery from the initial or acute phase of the illness. Such symptoms often occur 4 or more weeks after being diagnosed with COVID-19. Although a lot of work has gone into understanding the long-term mental health effects of PASC, many questions related to the etiology and risk of this condition remain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This protocol is for a systematic review assessing the association between PASC and adverse psychiatric outcomes and whether people with PASC are at greater risk of developing an adverse psychiatric outcome than those without PASC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Various medical literature databases (eg, PubMed and EMBASE) will be searched for eligible articles, using predefined search criteria. Gray literature will also be explored. Epidemiological observational studies and secondary analyses of randomized controlled trials that report a quantitative relationship between PASC and at least one adverse psychiatric outcome will be included. The Population, Exposure of interest, Comparator, and Outcome framework will be used as a standardized framework for the inclusion criteria. The Joanna Briggs Institute critical appraisal tools will be used to assess methodological quality and critically appraise the risk of bias in included studies. A random-effects meta-analysis will be conducted if possible. A formal narrative synthesis will be performed if a meta-analysis is impossible due to substantial heterogeneity across studies. The Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluation approach will be used to rate the cumulative certainty of the evidence for all outcomes. Ethical approval is not required. The study results will be published in a peer-reviewed journal.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This study documents and addresses etiology, risk factors, and long-term symptoms of COVID-19 among people with PASC. It focuses on a key priority area for new evidence syntheses on the clinical management of COVID-19 and pandemic-related conditions. It will include evidence on nonhospitalized and hospitalized patients with a history of PASC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Substantial heterogeneity across studies may limit the ability to perform a meta-analysis. Findings will inform disease prevention, decision-making, health care policy, and clinical research (Reviewed by the Plan P #PeerRef Community).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">PROSPERO CRD42022308737; https://www.crd.york.ac.uk/prospero/display_record.php?RecordID=308737.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Andem Effiong. Originally published in JMIRx Med (https://med.jmirx.org), 14.03.2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Effiong</LastName><ForeName>Andem</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2899-9656</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Memorial University, St John's, NL, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIRx Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101776650</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2563-6316</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>JMIRx Med. 1:e43880.</RefSource></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">evidence-based medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postacute sequelae of COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychiatry</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37725530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10414129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/43880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v4i1e43880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, Cook JR, Nordvig AS, Shalev D, Sehrawat TS, Ahluwalia N, Bikdeli B, Dietz D, Der-Nigoghossian C, Liyanage-Don N, Rosner GF, Bernstein EJ, Mohan S, Beckley AA, Seres DS, Choueiri TK, Uriel N, Ausiello JC, Accili D, Freedberg DE, Baldwin M, Schwartz A, Brodie D, Garcia CK, Elkind MSV, Connors JM, Bilezikian JP, Landry DW, Wan EY. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021 Apr 22;27(4):601&#x2013;615. doi: 10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z. 
 
10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022 Apr;22(4):e102&#x2013;e107. doi: 10.1016/s1473-3099(21)00703-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1473-3099(21)00703-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, Hishmeh L. Managing the long term effects of covid-19: summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ. 2021 Jan 22;372:n136. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postolache TT, Benros ME, Brenner LA. Targetable biological mechanisms implicated in emergent psychiatric conditions associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA Psychiatry. 2020 Jul 31;78(4):353. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.2795.2769084</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.2795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32735332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236&#x2009;379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiat. 2021 May;8(5):416&#x2013;427. doi: 10.1016/s2215-0366(21)00084-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s2215-0366(21)00084-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santomauro DF, Mantilla Herrera AM, Shadid J, Zheng P, Ashbaugh C, Pigott DM, Abbafati C, Adolph C, Amlag JO, Aravkin AY, Bang-Jensen BL, Bertolacci GJ, Bloom SS, Castellano R, Castro E, Chakrabarti S, Chattopadhyay J, Cogen RM, Collins JK, Dai X, Dangel WJ, Dapper C, Deen A, Erickson M, Ewald SB, Flaxman AD, Frostad JJ, Fullman N, Giles JR, Giref AZ, Guo G, He J, Helak M, Hulland EN, Idrisov B, Lindstrom A, Linebarger E, Lotufo PA, Lozano R, Magistro B, Malta DC, M&#xe5;nsson JC, Marinho F, Mokdad AH, Monasta L, Naik P, Nomura S, O'Halloran JK, Ostroff SM, Pasovic M, Penberthy L, Reiner Jr RC, Reinke G, Ribeiro ALP, Sholokhov A, Sorensen RJD, Varavikova E, Vo AT, Walcott R, Watson S, Wiysonge CS, Zigler B, Hay SI, Vos T, Murray CJL, Whiteford HA, Ferrari AJ. Global prevalence and burden of depressive and anxiety disorders in 204 countries and territories in 2020 due to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet. 2021 Nov;398(10312):1700&#x2013;1712. doi: 10.1016/s0140-6736(21)02143-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(21)02143-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34634250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan FC, Zhang SY, Cheng Y. Incidence of psychological illness after coronavirus outbreak: a meta-analysis study. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2021 Sep 25;75(9):836&#x2013;842. doi: 10.1136/jech-2020-215927. 
 
jech-2020-215927</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jech-2020-215927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7908057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33632722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Harrison PJ. Bidirectional associations between COVID-19 and psychiatric disorder: retrospective cohort studies of 62&#x2008;354 COVID-19 cases in the USA. Lancet Psychiat. 2021 Feb;8(2):130&#x2013;140. doi: 10.1016/s2215-0366(20)30462-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s2215-0366(20)30462-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers JP, Chesney E, Oliver D, Pollak TA, McGuire P, Fusar-Poli P, Zandi MS, Lewis G, David AS. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: a systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet Psychiat. 2020 Jul;7(7):611&#x2013;627. doi: 10.1016/s2215-0366(20)30203-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s2215-0366(20)30203-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7234781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaseda ET, Levine AJ. Post-traumatic stress disorder: A differential diagnostic consideration for COVID-19 survivors. Clin Neuropsychol. 2020 Aug 26;34(7-8):1498&#x2013;1514. doi: 10.1080/13854046.2020.1811894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13854046.2020.1811894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32847484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez Oscar, Merino E, Leon-Ramirez J, Andres M, Ramos JM, Arenas-Jim&#xe9;nez Juan, Asensio S, Sanchez R, Ruiz-Torregrosa P, Galan I, Scholz A, Amo A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-delaAleja Pilar, Boix V, Gil J, COVID19-ALC research group  Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: A Mediterranean cohort study. J Infect. 2021 Mar;82(3):378&#x2013;383. doi: 10.1016/j.jinf.2021.01.004. 
 
S0163-4453(21)00009-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2021.01.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7802523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021 Jul 26;374:n1648. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n1648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez R, Balanz&#xe1;-Mart&#xed;nez V, Luperdi S, Estrada I, Latorre A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Jim&#xe9;nez P, Feced L, Bouzas L, Y&#xe9;pez K, Ferrando A, Herv&#xe1;s D, Zald&#xed;var E, Reyes S, Berk M, Men&#xe9;ndez R. Short-term neuropsychiatric outcomes and quality of life in COVID-19 survivors. J Intern Med. 2021 Sep;290(3):621&#x2013;631. doi: 10.1111/joim.13262. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joim.13262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33533521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vannorsdall T, Oh ES. Post-acute cognitive and mental health outcomes amongst COVID-19 survivors: early findings and a call for further investigation. J Intern Med. 2021 Sep 13;290(3):752&#x2013;754. doi: 10.1111/joim.13271. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joim.13271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33713509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin M, Schommers P, Stecher M, Dewald F, Gieselmann L, Gruell H, Horn C, Vanshylla K, Cristanziano VD, Osebold L, Roventa M, Riaz T, Tschernoster N, Altmueller J, Rose L, Salomon S, Priesner V, Luers JC, Albus C, Rosenkranz S, Gathof B, F&#xe4;tkenheuer Gerd, Hallek M, Klein F, Su&#xe1;rez Isabelle, Lehmann C. Post-COVID syndrome in non-hospitalised patients with COVID-19: a longitudinal prospective cohort study. Lancet Reg Health Eur. 2021 Jul;6:100122. doi: 10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100122. 
 
S2666-7762(21)00099-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8129613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34027514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khubchandani J, Price JH, Sharma S, Wiblishauser MJ, Webb FJ. COVID-19 infection survivors and the risk of depression and anxiety symptoms: A nationwide study of adults in the United States. Eur J Intern Med. 2022 Mar;97:119&#x2013;121. doi: 10.1016/j.ejim.2022.01.021. 
 
S0953-6205(22)00021-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejim.2022.01.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8752310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35063358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE, Ba DM, Parsons N, Poudel GR, Lekoubou A, Oh JS, Ericson JE, Ssentongo P, Chinchilli VM. Short-term and long-term rates of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a systematic review. JAMA Netw Open. 2021 Oct 01;4(10):e2128568. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.28568. 
 
2784918</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.28568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34643720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forte G, Favieri F, Tambelli R, Casagrande M. COVID-19 pandemic in the Italian population: validation of a post-traumatic stress disorder questionnaire and prevalence of PTSD symptomatology. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020 Jun 10;17(11):4151. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17114151. 
 
ijerph17114151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17114151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7312976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32532077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varatharaj A, Thomas N, Ellul M, Davies NW, Pollak T, Tenorio E, Sultan M, Easton A, Breen G, Zandi M, Coles JP, Manji H, Al-Shahi Salman R, Menon D, Nicholson T, Benjamin L, Carson A, Smith C, Turner MR, Solomon T, Kneen R, Pett S, Galea I, Thomas RH, Michael B. UK-wide surveillance of neurological and neuropsychiatric complications of COVID-19: the first 153 patients. SSRN Journal. 2020 doi: 10.2139/ssrn.3601761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.3601761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7316461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32593341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinna P, Grewal P, Hall JP, Tavarez T, Dafer RM, Garg R, Osteraas ND, Pellack DR, Asthana A, Fegan K, Patel V, Conners JJ, John S, Silva ID. Neurological manifestations and COVID-19: experiences from a tertiary care center at the frontline. J Neurol Sci. 2020 Aug 15;415:116969. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2020.116969. 
 
S0022-510X(20)30306-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2020.116969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32570113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr&#xf9; Graziella, Ciacchini Rebecca, Gemignani A, Conversano C. Psychological intervention measures during the Covid-19 pandemic. Clin Neuropsychiatry. 2020 Apr;17(2):76&#x2013;79. doi: 10.36131/CN20200208. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36131/CN20200208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8629089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34908972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biagianti B, Zito S, Fornoni C, Ginex V, Bellani M, Bressi C, Brambilla P. Developing a brief tele-psychotherapy model for COVID-19 patients and their family members. Front Psychol. 2021 Dec 2;12:784685. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2021.784685. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.784685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8674425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34925187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damiano RF, Di Santi T, Beach S, Pan PM, Lucchetti AL, Smith FA, Forlenza OV, Fricchione GL, Miguel EC, Lucchetti G. Mental health interventions following COVID-19 and other coronavirus infections: a systematic review of current recommendations and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Braz J Psychiatry. 2021 Dec;43(6):665&#x2013;678. doi: 10.1590/1516-4446-2020-1582. 
 
S1516-44462021005011201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1516-4446-2020-1582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8639008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33852690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Chen Y, Wu D, Lin R, Wang Z, Pan L. Effects of progressive muscle relaxation on anxiety and sleep quality in patients with COVID-19. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2020 May;39:101132. doi: 10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101132. 
 
S1744-3881(20)30278-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gharaati Sotoudeh H, Alavi SS, Akbari Z, Jannatifard F, Artounian V. The effect of Brief Crisis Intervention Package on improving quality of life and mental health in patients with COVID-19. Iran J Psychiatry. 2020 Jul 29;15(3):205&#x2013;212. doi: 10.18502/ijps.v15i3.3812. 
 
IJPS-15-205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18502/ijps.v15i3.3812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7603589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33193768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam MN, Islam AKMN. A systematic review of the digital interventions for fighting COVID-19: the Bangladesh perspective. IEEE Access. 2020;8:114078&#x2013;114087. doi: 10.1109/access.2020.3002445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2020.3002445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8043502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34192108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauschenberg C, Schick A, Hirjak D, Seidler A, Paetzold I, Apfelbacher C, Riedel-Heller SG, Reininghaus U. Evidence synthesis of digital interventions to mitigate the negative impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on public mental health: rapid meta-review. J Med Internet Res. 2021 Mar 10;23(3):e23365. doi: 10.2196/23365. 
 
v23i3e23365</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/23365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7951054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33606657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khilnani A, Schulz J, Robinson L. The COVID-19 pandemic: new concerns and connections between eHealth and digital inequalities. JICES. 2020 Jun 25;18(3):393&#x2013;403. doi: 10.1108/jices-04-2020-0052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/jices-04-2020-0052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gega L, Aboujaoude E. How digital technology mediated the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on mental health: the good, the bad, and the indifferent. Front Digit Health. 2021 Sep 14;3:733151. doi: 10.3389/fdgth.2021.733151. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2021.733151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8521901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34713202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong AW, Shah AS, Johnston JC, Carlsten C, Ryerson CJ. Patient-reported outcome measures after COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2020 Nov 02;56(5):2003276. doi: 10.1183/13993003.03276-2020. 
 
13993003.03276-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.03276-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7530908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33008936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Shamseer L, Clarke M, Ghersi D, Liberati A, Petticrew M, Shekelle P, Stewart LA, PRISMA-P Group  Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015 statement. Syst Rev. 2015 Jan 01;4(1):1. doi: 10.1186/2046-4053-4-1. 
 
2046-4053-4-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2046-4053-4-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2046-4053-4-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4320440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25554246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schou TM, Joca S, Wegener G, Bay-Richter C. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19 - a systematic review. Brain Behav Immun. 2021 Oct;97:328&#x2013;348. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2021.07.018.S0889-1591(21)00281-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2021.07.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8363196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab K, Schwitzer E, Qadir N. Postacute sequelae of COVID-19 critical illness. Crit Care Clin. 2022 Jul;38(3):455&#x2013;472. doi: 10.1016/j.ccc.2022.01.001. 
 
S0749-0704(22)00001-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccc.2022.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8743493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35667737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caliendo AM, Hanson KE. COVID-19: Diagnosis. UpToDate. 2022.  [2023-01-12].  
 https://tinyurl.com/53h6me78
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffith GJ, Morris TT, Tudball MJ, Herbert A, Mancano G, Pike L, Sharp GC, Sterne J, Palmer TM, Davey Smith G, Tilling K, Zuccolo L, Davies NM, Hemani G. Collider bias undermines our understanding of COVID-19 disease risk and severity. Nat Commun. 2020 Nov 12;11(1):5749. doi: 10.1038/s41467-020-19478-2. doi: 10.1038/s41467-020-19478-2. 10.1038/s41467-020-19478-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-19478-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-19478-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33184277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page M, McKenzie J, Bossuyt P, Boutron I, Hoffmann T, Mulrow C, Shamseer L, Tetzlaff J, Akl E, Brennan S, Chou R, Glanville Julie, Grimshaw Jeremy M, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson Asbj&#xf8;rn, Lalu Manoj M, Li Tianjing, Loder Elizabeth W, Mayo-Wilson Evan, McDonald Steve, McGuinness Luke A, Stewart Lesley A, Thomas James, Tricco Andrea C, Welch Vivian A, Whiting Penny, Moher David. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021 Mar 29;372:n71. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n71. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>