<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37475709</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-2500</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pain practice : the official journal of World Institute of Pain</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pain Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Consistency of inconsistency in long-COVID-19 pain symptoms persistency: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>120</StartPage><EndPage>159</EndPage><MedlinePgn>120-159</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/papr.13277</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Individuals recovering from acute COVID-19 episodes may continue to suffer from various ongoing symptoms, collectively referred to as Long-COVID. Long-term pain symptoms are amongst the most common and clinically significant symptoms to be reported for this post-COVID-19 syndrome.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This systematic review and meta-analysis aimed to evaluate the proportions of persisting pain symptoms experienced by individuals past the acute phase of COVID-19 and to identify their associated functional consequences and inflammatory correlates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Two online databases were systematically searched from their inception until 31 March 2022. We searched primary research articles in English, which evaluated individuals after laboratory-confirmed COVID-19 acute phase resolution and specifically reported on pain symptoms and their inflammatory and/or functional outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 611 identified articles, 26 were included, used for data extraction, and assessed for their methodological quality and risk of bias by two independent reviewers. Pain symptoms were grouped under one of six major pain domains, serving as our primary co-outcomes. Proportional meta-analyses of pooled logit-transformed values of single proportions were performed using the random-effects-restricted maximum-likelihood model. An estimated 8%, 6%, 18%, 18%, 17%, and 12% of individuals continued to report the persistence of chest, gastrointestinal, musculoskeletal joint, musculoskeletal muscle, general body, and nervous system-related pain symptoms, respectively, for up to one year after acute phase resolution of COVID-19. Considerable levels of heterogeneity were demonstrated across all results. Functional and quality-of-life impairments and some inflammatory biomarker elevations were associated with the persistence of long-COVID pain symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study's findings suggest that although not well characterized, long-COVID pain symptoms are being experienced by non-negligible proportions of those recovering from acute COVID-19 episodes, thus highlighting the importance of future research efforts to focus on this aspect.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Pain Practice published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of World Institute of Pain.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerzhner</LastName><ForeName>Oleg</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6752-0578</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Loewenstein Rehabilitation Medical Center, Ra'anana, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berla</LastName><ForeName>Einat</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6313-9582</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Israel Defense Forces Medical Corps, Ramat Gan, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Har-Even</LastName><ForeName>Meirav</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6294-6913</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Anthropology, School of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ratmansky</LastName><ForeName>Motti</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1401-3393</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pain Clinic, Sheba Medical Center, Ramat Gan, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goor-Aryeh</LastName><ForeName>Itay</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2548-2256</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pain Clinic, Sheba Medical Center, Ramat Gan, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pain Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101130835</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1530-7085</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010146" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002908" MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID&#xa0;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pain symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37475709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/papr.13277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Liu Y-C, Kuo R-L, Shih S-R. COVID-19: the first documented coronavirus pandemic in history. Biom J. 2020;43:328-333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koelle K, Martin MA, Antia R, Lopman B, Dean NE. The changing epidemiology of SARS-CoV-2. Science. 1979;2022(375):1116-1121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SDGs Sustainable Development Goals. 2022. Available from: http://apps.who.int/bookorders</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d'Ettorre G, Gentilini Cacciola E, Santinelli L, de Girolamo G, Spagnolello O, Russo A, et al. Covid-19 sequelae in working age patients: a systematic review. J Med Virol. 2022;94:858-868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebru AA, Birhanu T, Wendimu E, Ayalew AF, Mulat S, Abasimel HZ, et al. Global burden of COVID-19: situational analysis and review. Hum Antibodies. 2021;29:139-148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CC, Wang CY, Wang YH, Hsueh SC, Ko WC, Hsueh PR. Global epidemiology of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): disease incidence, daily cumulative index, mortality, and their association with country healthcare resources and economic status. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2020;55:105946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith Jervelund S, Eikemo TA. The double burden of COVID-19. Scand J Public Health. 2021;49:1-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anaya JM, Rojas M, Salinas ML, Rodr&#xed;guez Y, Roa G, Lozano M, et al. Post-COVID syndrome. A case series and comprehensive review. Autoimmun Rev. 2021;20:102947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B, Guo H, Zhou P, Shi Z-L. Characteristics of SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2021;19:141-154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochani RK, Kumar Ochani R, Asad A, Yasmin F, Shaikh S, Khalid H, et al. COVID-19 pandemic: from origins to outcomes. A comprehensive review of viral pathogenesis, clinical manifestations, diagnostic evaluation, and management. Infez Med. 2021;29:20-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osikomaiya B, Erinoso O, Wright KO, Odusola AO, Thomas B, Adeyemi O, et al. &#x2018;Long COVID&#x2019;: persistent COVID-19 symptoms in survivors managed in Lagos State, Nigeria. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21:304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Huang DQ, Zou B, Yang H, Hui WZ, Rui F, et al. Epidemiology of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical characteristics, risk factors, and outcomes. J Med Virol. 2021;93:1449-1458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera Martimbianco AL, Pacheco RL, Bagattini &#xc2;M, Riera R. Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID-19: a systematic review. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:e14357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH, Crooks MG. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;199:113-119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramakrishnan RK, Kashour T, Hamid Q, Halwani R, Tleyjeh IM. Unraveling the mystery surrounding post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2021;12:686029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T, Yan MZ, Li X, Lau EHY. Sequelae of COVID-19 among previously hospitalized patients up to 1 year after discharge: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Infection. 2022;50:1067-1109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, Rivera SC, McMullan C, Chandan JS, et al. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med. 2021;114:428-442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA, Akbari A, Emami A, Lotfi M, Rostamihosseinkhani M, Nemati H, et al. Risk factors associated with long covid syndrome: a retrospective study. Iran J Med Sci. 2021;46:428-436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, Nicholson T, Akrami A, Apfelbacher C, Chen J, de Groote W, et al. A core outcome set for post-COVID-19 condition in adults for use in clinical practice and research: an international Delphi consensus study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10:715-724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV. Long COVID-19: challenges in the diagnosis and proposed diagnostic criteria. Diabetes Metab Syndr Clin Res Rev. 2021;15:145-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A'Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. Management of post-acute COVID-19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020;370:m3026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz J. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:e102-e107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, Hishmeh L. Managing the long term effects of covid-19: summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ. 2021;372:n136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vehar S, Boushra M, Ntiamoah P, Biehl M. Update to post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: caring for the &#x201c;long-haulers&#x201d;. Cleve Clin J Med. 2021;88:267-272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkodaymi MS, Omrani OA, Fawzy NA, Shaar BA, Almamlouk R, Riaz M, et al. Prevalence of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome symptoms at different follow-up periods: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28:657-666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan M, McGroder C, Stevens JS, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601-615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zayet S, Zahra H, Royer PY, Tipirdamaz C, Mercier J, Gendrin V, et al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome: nine months after SARS-CoV-2 infection in a cohort of 354 patients: data from the first wave of COVID-19 in nord franche-comt&#xe9; hospital, France. Microorganisms. 2021;9:1719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Husain M, Harrison PJ. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 2021;18:e1003773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, Plaza-Manzano G, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, Arendt-Nielsen L. Time course prevalence of post-COVID pain symptoms of musculoskeletal origin in patients who had survived severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pain. 2022;163:1220-1231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbarialiabad H, Taghrir MH, Abdollahi A, Ghahramani N, Kumar M, Paydar S, et al. Long COVID, a comprehensive systematic scoping review. Infection. 2021;49:1163-1186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bileviciute-Ljungar I, Norrefalk JR, Borg K. Pain burden in post-COVID-19 syndrome following mild COVID-19 infection. J Clin Med. 2022;11:771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Cancela-Cilleruelo I, Moro-L&#xf3;pez-Menchero P, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Torres-Macho J, et al. Prevalence of musculoskeletal post-COVID pain in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors depending on infection with the historical, alpha or Delta SARS-CoV-2 variant. Biomedicine. 2022;10:1951. https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines10081951</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Fuensalida-Novo S, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a M, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Florencio LL, et al. Myalgia as a symptom at hospital admission by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection is associated with persistent musculoskeletal pain as long-term post-COVID sequelae: a case-control study. Pain. 2021;162:2832-2840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayaaslan B, Eser F, Kalem AK, Kaya G, Kaplan B, Kacar D, et al. Post-COVID syndrome: a single-center questionnaire study on 1007 participants recovered from COVID-19. J Med Virol. 2021;93:6566-6574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer-Frie&#xdf;em CH, Gierthm&#xfc;hlen J, Baron R, Sommer C, &#xdc;&#xe7;eyler N, Enax-Krumova EK. Pain during and after COVID-19 in Germany and worldwide: a narrative review of current knowledge. Pain Rep. 2021;6:e893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares FHC, Kubota GT, Fernandes AM, Hojo B, Couras C, Costa BV, et al. Prevalence and characteristics of new-onset pain in COVID-19 survivours, a controlled study. Eur J Pain. 2021;25:1342-1354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydin S, Unver E, Karavas E, Yalcin S, Kantarci M. Computed tomography at every step: long coronavirus disease. Respir Investig. 2021;59:622-627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bak&#x131;lan F, G&#xf6;kmen &#x130;G, Ortanca B, U&#xe7;an A, Eker G&#xfc;ven&#xe7; &#x15e;, &#x15e;ahin Mutlu F, et al. Musculoskeletal symptoms and related factors in postacute COVID-19 patients. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:e14734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603-605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catal&#xe1;n IP, Mart&#xed; CR, Sota DP d l, &#xc1;lvarez AC, Gimeno MJE, Juana SF, et al. Corticosteroids for COVID-19 symptoms and quality of life at 1 year from admission. J Med Virol. 2022;94:205-210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher A, Balfanz P, Cornelissen C, M&#xfc;ller A, Bergs I, Marx N, et al. Follow up of patients with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): pulmonary and extrapulmonary disease sequelae. Respir Med. 2020;174:106197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, Florencio LL, Guerrero AL, et al. The presence of headache at onset in SARS-CoV-2 infection is associated with long-term post-COVID headache and fatigue: a case-control study. Cephalalgia. 2021;41:1332-1341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-De-las-Penas C, Guijarro C, Torres-Macho J, Velasco-Arribas M, Plaza-Canteli S, Hern&#xf3;andez-Barrera V, et al. Diabetes and the risk of long-term post-COVID symptoms. Diabetes. 2021;70:2917-2921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Andrade F. Post-COVID-19 conditions in Ecuadorian patients: an observational study. Lancet Reg Health Am. 2022;5:100088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham EL, Clark JR, Orban ZS, Lim PH, Szymanski AL, Taylor C, et al. Persistent neurologic symptoms and cognitive dysfunction in non-hospitalized Covid-19 &#x201c;long haulers.&#x201d;. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2021;8:1073-1085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain MA, Hossain KMA, Saunders K, Uddin Z, Walton LM, Raigangar V, et al. Prevalence of long COVID symptoms in Bangladesh: a prospective inception cohort study of COVID-19 survivors. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6:e006838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, Wang Q, Ren L, Wang Y, et al. 1-Year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398:747-758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karaarslan F, Demircio&#x11f;lu G&#xfc;neri F, Karde&#x15f; S. Postdischarge rheumatic and musculoskeletal symptoms following hospitalization for COVID-19: prospective follow-up by phone interviews. Rheumatol Int. 2021;41:1263-1271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maamar M, Artime A, Pariente E, Fierro P, Ruiz Y, Guti&#xe9;rrez S, et al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome, low-grade inflammation and inflammatory markers: a cross-sectional study. Curr Med Res Opin. 2022;38:901-909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendelsohn AS, Nath N, de S&#xe1; A, von Pressentin KB. Two months follow-up of patients with non-critical COVID-19 in Cape Town, South Africa. S Afr Fam Pract. 2022;64:e1-e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik S, Haldar SN, Soneja M, Mundadan NG, Garg P, Mittal A, et al. Post COVID-19 sequelae: a prospective observational study from northern India. Drug Discov Ther. 2021;15:254-260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehme M, Braillard O, Chappuis F, Courvoisier DS, Guessous I. Prevalence of symptoms more than seven months after diagnosis of symptomatic COVID-19 in an outpatient setting. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174:1252-1260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Och A, Tylicki P, Polewska K, Puchalska-Regli&#x144;ska E, Parczewska A, Szabat K, et al. Persistent post-COVID-19 syndrome in hemodialyzed patients-a longitudinal cohort study from the north of Poland. J Clin Med. 2021;10:4451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Duarte &#xc1;, Rivera-Izquierdo M, Guerrero-Fern&#xe1;ndez de Alba I, P&#xe9;rez-Contreras M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Mart&#xed;nez NF, Ruiz-Montero R, et al. Sequelae, persistent symptomatology and outcomes after COVID-19 hospitalization: the ANCOHVID multicentre 6-month follow-up study. BMC Med. 2021;19:129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taha SI, Samaan SF, Ibrahim RA, El-Sehsah EM, Youssef MK. Post-COVID-19 arthritis: is it hyperinflammation or autoimmunity? Eur Cytokine Netw. 2021;32:83-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tetik B, Demir G, Kurt O, Derya S. Post-COVID pain frequency and affecting factors. Med Sci Int Med J. 2021;10:1304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan F, Ye T, Sun P, Gui S, Liang B, Li L, et al. Time course of lung changes on chest CT during recovery from 2019 novel coronavirus (COVID-19) pneumonia. Radiology. 2020;295(3):715-721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Halpin SJ, Gee J. Assessing long-term rehabilitation needs in COVID-19 survivors using a telephone screening tool (C19-YRS tool). Adv Clin Neurosci Rehabil. 2020;19:14-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stang A. Critical evaluation of the Newcastle-Ottawa scale for the assessment of the quality of nonrandomized studies in meta-analyses. Eur J Epidemiol. 2010;25:603-605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huedo-Medina TB, S&#xe1;nchez-Meca J, Mar&#xed;n-Mart&#xed;nez F, Botella J. Assessing heterogeneity in meta-analysis: Q statistic or I2 index? Psychol Methods. 2006;11:193-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenward MG, Roger JH. Small sample inference for fixed effects from restricted maximum likelihood. Biometrics. 1997;53:983-997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balduzzi S, R&#xfc;cker G, Schwarzer G. How to perform a meta-analysis with R: a practical tutorial. Evid Based Ment Health. 2019;22:153-160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barendregt JJ, Doi SA, Lee YY, Norman RE, Vos T. Meta-analysis of prevalence. J Epidemiol Community Health. 1978;2013(67):974-978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murad MH, Sultan S, Haffar S, Bazerbachi F. Methodological quality and synthesis of case series and case reports. Evid Based Med. 2018;23:60-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Higgins JPT. Meta-analysis and subgroups. Prev Sci. 2013;14:134-143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartling L, Milne A, Hamm MP, Vandermeer B, Ansari M, Tsertsvadze A, et al. Testing the Newcastle Ottawa Scale showed low reliability between individual reviewers. J Clin Epidemiol. 2013;66:982-993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luchini C, Stubbs B, Solmi M, Veronese N. Assessing the quality of studies in meta-analyses: advantages and limitations of the Newcastle Ottawa Scale. World J Metaanal. 2017;5:80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oremus M, Oremus C, Hall GBC, McKinnon MC, Graham A, Gregory C, et al. Inter-rater and test-retest reliability of quality assessments by novice student raters using the Jadad and Newcastle-Ottawa Scales. BMJ Open. 2012;2:e001368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Higgins JPT, Altman DG. Analysing data and undertaking meta-analyses. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd; 2008. p. 243-296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. editors. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. 2nd ed. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannidis JPA, Trikalinos TA. The appropriateness of asymmetry tests for publication bias in meta-analyses: a large survey. CMAJ. 2007;176:1091-1096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L, Chu H. Quantifying publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics. 2018;74:785-794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenblad A. Introduction to meta-analysis by Michael Borenstein, Larry V. Hedges, Julian P.T. Higgins, Hannah R. Rothstein. Int Stat Rev. 2009;77:478-479. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1751-5823.2009.00095_15.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batur EB, Korez MK, Gezer IA, Levendoglu F, Ural O. Musculoskeletal symptoms and relationship with laboratory findings in patients with COVID-19. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:e14135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubio-Rivas M, Corbella X, Mora-Luj&#xe1;n JM, Loureiro-Amigo J, L&#xf3;pez Sampalo A, Yera Bergua C, et al. Predicting clinical outcome with phenotypic clusters in COVID-19 pneumonia: an analysis of 12,066 hospitalized patients from the Spanish registry SEMI-COVID-19. J Clin Med. 2020;9:3488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin D, Margalit I, Nehme M, Bordas-Mart&#xed;nez J, Pistelli F, Yahav D, et al. Patterns of long COVID symptoms: a multi-center cross sectional study. J Clin Med. 2022;11:898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauw DJ, H&#xe4;user W, Cohen SP, Fitzcharles M-A. Considering the potential for an increase in chronic pain after the COVID-19 pandemic. Pain. 2020;161:1694-1697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song X-J, Xiong D-L, Wang Z-Y, Yang D, Zhou L, Li R-C. Pain management during the COVID-19 pandemic in China: lessons learned. Pain Med. 2020;21:1319-1323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struyf T, Deeks JJ, Dinnes J, Takwoingi Y, Davenport C, Leeflang MM, et al. Signs and symptoms to determine if a patient presenting in primary care or hospital outpatient settings has COVID-19 disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020;7:CD013665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanares-Zapatero D, Chalon P, Kohn L, Dauvrin M, Detollenaere J, Maertens de Noordhout C, et al. Pathophysiology and mechanism of long COVID: a comprehensive review. Ann Med. 2022;54:1473-1487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M. Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nat Immunol. 2022;23:194-202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV, Jayadevan R, Sashidharan S. Long COVID: an overview. Diabetes Metab Syndr Clin Res Rev. 2021;15:869-875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam MH-B. Mental morbidities and chronic fatigue in severe acute respiratory syndrome survivors. Arch Intern Med. 2009;169:2142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Sullivan O. Long-term sequelae following previous coronavirus epidemics. Clin Med. 2021;21:e68-e70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers JP, Chesney E, Oliver D, Pollak TA, McGuire P, Fusar-Poli P, et al. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: a systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;7:611-627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed H, Patel K, Greenwood D, Halpin S, Lewthwaite P, Salawu A, et al. Long-term clinical outcomes in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus outbreaks after hospitalisation or ICU admission: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Rehabil Med. 2020;52:jrm00063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui DS. Impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) on pulmonary function, functional capacity and quality of life in a cohort of survivors. Thorax. 2005;60:401-409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Shin H-S, Park HY, Kim JL, Lee JJ, Lee H, et al. Depression as a mediator of chronic fatigue and post-traumatic stress symptoms in Middle East respiratory syndrome survivors. Psychiatry Investig. 2019;16:59-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moldofsky H, Patcai J. Chronic widespread musculoskeletal pain, fatigue, depression and disordered sleep in chronic post-SARS syndrome; a case-controlled study. BMC Neurol. 2011;11:37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngai JC, Ko FW, Ng SS, To K-W, Tong M, Hui DS. The long-term impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome on pulmonary function, exercise capacity and health status. Respirology. 2010;15:543-550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong K-C. Pulmonary function and exercise capacity in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome. Eur Respir J. 2004;24:436-442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong TL, Weitzer DJ. Long COVID and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS)-a systemic review and comparison of clinical presentation and symptomatology. Medicina (Kaunas). 2021;57:418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taboada M, Cari&#xf1;ena A, Moreno E, Rodr&#xed;guez N, Dom&#xed;nguez MJ, Casal A, et al. Post-COVID-19 functional status six-months after hospitalization. J Infect. 2021;82:e31-e33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiala K, Martens J, Abd-Elsayed A. Post-COVID pain syndromes. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 2022;26:379-383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahroum N, Shoenfeld Y. Autoimmune autonomic dysfunction syndromes: potential involvement and pathophysiology related to complex regional pain syndrome, fibromyalgia, chronic fatigue syndrome, silicone breast implant-related symptoms and post-COVID syndrome. Pathophysiology. 2022;29:414-425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampaio Rocha-Filho PA. Headache associated with COVID-19: epidemiology, characteristics, pathophysiology, and management. Headache. 2022;62:650-656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe F, Clauw DJ, Fitzcharles M-A, Goldenberg DL, H&#xe4;user W, Katz RL, et al. 2016 Revisions to the 2010/2011 fibromyalgia diagnostic criteria. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2016;46:319-329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinn S, Caldwell W, Gritsenko K. Fibromyalgia pathogenesis and treatment options update. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 2016;20:25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarzi-Puttini P, Giorgi V, Marotto D, Atzeni F. Fibromyalgia: an update on clinical characteristics, aetiopathogenesis and treatment. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2020;16:645-660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siracusa R, di Paola R, Cuzzocrea S, Impellizzeri D. Fibromyalgia: pathogenesis, mechanisms, diagnosis and treatment options update. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:3891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohabbat AB, Mohabbat NML, Wight EC. Fibromyalgia and chronic fatigue syndrome in the age of COVID-19. Mayo Clin Proc Innov Qual Outcomes. 2020;4:764-766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavrilova N, Soprun L, Lukashenko M, Ryabkova V, Fedotkina T, Churilov LP, et al. New clinical phenotype of the post-Covid syndrome: fibromyalgia and joint hypermobility condition. Pathophysiology. 2022;29:24-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gheita TA, Fathi HM, ElAdle SS, Eesa NN, Hammam NH. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) an emerging trigger for primary fibromyalgia syndrome: a tale of three cases post-COVID-19. Int J Clin Rheumatol. 2021;16:129-135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ursini F, Ciaffi J, Mancarella L, Lisi L, Brusi V, Cavallari C, et al. Fibromyalgia: a new facet of the post-COVID-19 syndrome spectrum? Results from a web-based survey. RMD Open. 2021;7:e001735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borchers AT, Gershwin ME. Fibromyalgia: a critical and comprehensive review. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2015;49:100-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg M, Maralakunte M, Garg S, Dhooria S, Sehgal I, Bhalla AS, et al. The conundrum of &#x201c;long-COVID-19&#x201d;: a narrative review. Int J Gen Med. 2021;14:2491-2506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Z, Yang M, Lai C-L. Long COVID-19 syndrome: a comprehensive review of its effect on various organ systems and recommendation on rehabilitation plans. Biomedicine. 2021;9:966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korompoki E, Gavriatopoulou M, Hicklen RS, Ntanasis-Stathopoulos I, Kastritis E, Fotiou D, et al. Epidemiology and organ specific sequelae of post-acute COVID19: a narrative review. J Infect. 2021;83:1-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merad M, Martin JC. Pathological inflammation in patients with COVID-19: a key role for monocytes and macrophages. Nat Rev Immunol. 2020;20:355-362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg P, Arora U, Kumar A, Wig N. The &#x201c;post-COVID&#x201d; syndrome: how deep is the damage? J Med Virol. 2021;93:673-674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khazaal S, Harb J, Rima M, Annweiler C, Wu Y, Cao Z, et al. The pathophysiology of long COVID throughout the renin-angiotensin system. Molecules. 2022;27:2903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourgonje AR, Abdulle AE, Timens W, Hillebrands JL, Navis GJ, Gordijn SJ, et al. Angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2), SARS-CoV-2 and the pathophysiology of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). J Pathol. 2020;251:228-248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamming I, Timens W, Bulthuis MLC, Lely AT, Navis GJ, van Goor H. Tissue distribution of ACE2 protein, the functional receptor for SARS coronavirus. A first step in understanding SARS pathogenesis. J Pathol. 2004;203:631-637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty H, Townsend L, Morrin H, Ahmad A, Comerford C, Karampini E, et al. Irish COVID-19 Vasculopathy Study (iCVS) investigators. Persistent endotheliopathy in the pathogenesis of long COVID syndrome. J Thromb Haemost. 2021;19:2546-2553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sollini M, Ciccarelli M, Cecconi M, Aghemo A, Morelli P, Gelardi F, et al. Vasculitis changes in COVID-19 survivors with persistent symptoms: an [18F]FDG-PET/CT study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48:1460-1466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libby P, L&#xfc;scher T. COVID-19 is, in the end, an endothelial disease. Eur Heart J. 2020;41:3038-3044.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oronsky B, Larson C, Hammond TC, Oronsky A, Kesari S, Lybeck M, et al. A review of persistent post-COVID syndrome (PPCS). Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2021;64:66-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis. 2021;53:737-754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long COVID-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khetpal V, Berkowitz J, Vijayakumar S, Choudhary G, Mukand JA, Rudolph JL, et al. Long-term cardiovascular manifestations and complications of COVID-19: Spectrum and approach to diagnosis and management. R I Med J. 2013;2022(105):16-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magadum A, Kishore R. Cardiovascular manifestations of COVID-19 infection. Cell. 2020;9:2508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd8;stergaard L. SARS CoV-2 related microvascular damage and symptoms during and after COVID-19: consequences of capillary transit-time changes, tissue hypoxia and inflammation. Physiol Rep. 2021;9:e14726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer HP, Med M. Myofascial pain syndrome and its suggested role in the pathogenesis and treatment of fibromyalgia syndrome. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 2002;6:274-283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL, Lipkin WI. Insights from myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome may help unravel the pathogenesis of postacute COVID-19 syndrome. Trends Mol Med. 2021;27:895-906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellato E, Marini E, Castoldi F, Barbasetti N, Mattei L, Bonasia DE, et al. Fibromyalgia syndrome: etiology, pathogenesis, diagnosis, and treatment. Pain Res Treat. 2012;2012:1-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Campion JY, Dudouet P, Kaphan E, Bregeon F, Tissot-Dupont H, et al. 18F-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in patients with long COVID. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48:2823-2833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M-H, Perl DP, Nair G, Li W, Maric D, Murray H, et al. Microvascular injury in the brains of patients with COVID-19. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:481-483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brosschot JF. Cognitive-emotional sensitization and somatic health complaints. Scand J Psychol. 2002;43:113-121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce OJ. Sensitization, conditioning, and learning: can they help us understand somatization and disability? Scand J Psychol. 2002;43:105-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galhardoni R, da Silva VA, Garc&#xed;a-Larrea L, Dale C, Baptista AF, Barbosa LM, et al. Insular and anterior cingulate cortex deep stimulation for central neuropathic pain disassembling the percept of pain. Neurology. 2019;92:E2165-E2175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauw DJ. Fibromyalgia and related conditions. Mayo Clin Proc. 2015;90:680-692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malatji BG, Mason S, Mienie LJ, Wevers RA, Meyer H, van Reenen M, et al. The GC-MS metabolomics signature in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome directs to dysbiosis as an aspect contributing factor of FMS pathophysiology. Metabolomics. 2019;15:54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vierck CJ. Mechanisms underlying development of spatially distributed chronic pain (fibromyalgia). Pain. 2006;124:242-263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong J, Lipsitz O, Nasri F, Lui LMW, Gill H, Phan L, et al. Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on mental health in the general population: a systematic review. J Affect Disord. 2020;277:55-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batra A, Clark JR, LaHaye K, Shlobin NA, Hoffman SC, Orban ZS, et al. Transcranial Doppler ultrasound evidence of active cerebral embolization in COVID-19. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;30:105542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nauen DW, Hooper JE, Stewart CM, Solomon IH. Assessing brain capillaries in coronavirus disease 2019. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78:760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collado A, Gomez E, Coscolla R, Sunyol R, Sol&#xe9; E, Rivera J, et al. Work, family and social environment in patients with fibromyalgia in Spain: an epidemiological study: EPIFFAC study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2014;14:513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson PL, Meltzoff AN, Decety J. How do we perceive the pain of others? A window into the neural processes involved in empathy. Neuroimage. 2005;24:771-779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simani L, Ramezani M, Darazam IA, Sagharichi M, Aalipour MA, Ghorbani F, et al. Prevalence and correlates of chronic fatigue syndrome and post-traumatic stress disorder after the outbreak of the COVID-19. J Neurovirol. 2021;27:154-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji RR, Nackley A, Huh Y, Terrando N, Maixner W. Neuroinflammation and central sensitization in chronic and widespread pain. Anesthesiology. 2018;129:343-366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji RR, Xu ZZ, Gao YJ. Emerging targets in neuroinflammation-driven chronic pain. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2014;13:533-548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Q, Dong X, Green DP, Dong X. Peripheral mechanisms of chronic pain. Med Rev. 2022;2:251-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonneville R, Klein I, de Broucker T, Wolff M. Post-infectious encephalitis in adults: diagnosis and management. J Infect. 2009;58:321-328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biomarkers Definitions Working Group. Biomarkers and surrogate endpoints: preferred definitions and conceptual framework. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2001;69:89-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Y, Wang TJ. Circulating, imaging, and genetic biomarkers in cardiovascular risk prediction. Trends Cardiovasc Med. 2011;21:105-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasan RS. Biomarkers of cardiovascular disease: molecular basis and practical considerations. Circulation. 2006;113:2335-2362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonaccio M, Pounis G, Cerletti C, Donati MB, Iacoviello L, de Gaetano G. Mediterranean diet, dietary polyphenols and low grade inflammation: results from the MOLI-SANI study. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2017;83:107-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonaccio M, di Castelnuovo A, Pounis G, de Curtis A, Costanzo S, Persichillo M, et al. A score of low-grade inflammation and risk of mortality: prospective findings from the Moli-Sani study. Haematologica. 2016;101:1434-1441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu M, Zhang X, Chen J, Zha M, Yuan K, Huang K, et al. A score of low-grade inflammation for predicting stroke recurrence in patients with ischemic stroke. J Inflamm Res. 2021;14:4605-4614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geovanini GR, Libby P. Atherosclerosis and inflammation: overview and updates. Clin Sci (Lond). 2018;132:1243-1252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taleb S. Inflammation in atherosclerosis. Arch Cardiovasc Dis. 2016;109:708-715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf D, Ley K. Immunity and inflammation in atherosclerosis. Circ Res. 2019;124:315-327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galkina E, Ley K. Immune and inflammatory mechanisms of atherosclerosis. Annu Rev Immunol. 2009;27:165-197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobiyama K, Ley K. Atherosclerosis a chronic inflammatory disease with an autoimmune component. Circ Res. 2018;123:1118-1120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libby P, Buring JE, Badimon L, Hansson GK, Deanfield J, Bittencourt MS, et al. Atherosclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2019;5:56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dadu RT, Nambi V, Ballantyne CM. Developing and assessing cardiovascular biomarkers. Transl Res. 2012;159:265-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palavra F, Reis F, Marado D, Sena A. In: Palavra F, Reis F, Marado D, Sena A, editors. Biomarkers of Cardiometabolic risk, inflammation and disease. Switzerland: Springer International Publishing; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbaresko J, Koch M, Schulze MB, N&#xf6;thlings U. Dietary pattern analysis and biomarkers of low-grade inflammation: a systematic literature review. Nutr Rev. 2013;71:511-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93:1013-1022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220-232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peghin M, Palese A, Venturini M, de Martino M, Gerussi V, Graziano E, et al. Post-COVID-19 symptoms 6 months after acute infection among hospitalized and non-hospitalized patients. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:1507-1513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen MS, Kristiansen MF, Hanusson KD, Danielsen ME, &#xe1; Steig B, Gaini S, et al. Long COVID in The Faroe Islands: a longitudinal study among nonhospitalized patients. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e4058-e4063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poyraz B&#xc7;, Poyraz CA, Olgun Y, G&#xfc;rel &#xd6;, Alkan S, &#xd6;zdemir YE, et al. Psychiatric morbidity and protracted symptoms after COVID-19. Psychiatry Res. 2021;295:113604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27:626-631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, Dunne J, Mooney A, Gaffney F, et al. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PloS One. 2020;15:e0240784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez O, Merino E, Leon-Ramirez J-M, Andres M, Ramos JM, Arenas-Jim&#xe9;nez J, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: a Mediterranean cohort study. J Infect. 2021;82:378-383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, Ghanima W, Olsen MK, Gilboe HM, Einvik G. Persistent symptoms 1.5-6 months after COVID-19 in non-hospitalised subjects: a population-based cohort study. Thorax. 2021;76:405-407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills SEE, Nicolson KP, Smith BH. Chronic pain: a review of its epidemiology and associated factors in population-based studies. Br J Anaesth. 2019;123:e273-e283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natelson BH. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome and fibromyalgia: definitions, similarities, and differences. Clin Ther. 2019;41:612-618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S, Montero MTV, Rowe K, Kirton R, Kunik F. Epidemiology, pathogenesis, clinical presentations, diagnosis and treatment of COVID-19: a review of current evidence. Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol. 2021;14:601-621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B, Peters JB, Brink M, Schoon Y, Bleeker-Rovers CP, Schers H, et al. Comprehensive health assessment 3 months after recovery from acute coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e1089-e1098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li X, Geng D, Mei N, Wu P-Y, Huang C-C, et al. Cerebral micro-structural changes in COVID-19 patients - an MRI-based 3-month follow-up study. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazato Y, Morioka S, Tsuzuki S, Akashi M, Osanai Y, Tanaka K, et al. Prolonged and late-onset symptoms of coronavirus disease 2019. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2020;7:ofaa507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Cassar MP, Tunnicliffe EM, Filippini N, Griffanti L, Alfaro-Almagro F, et al. Medium-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on multiple vital organs, exercise capacity, cognition, quality of life and mental health, post-hospital discharge. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;31:100683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad MH, Teo SP. Post-intensive care syndrome. Ann Geriatr Med Res. 2021;25:72-78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue S, Hatakeyama J, Kondo Y, Hifumi T, Sakuramoto H, Kawasaki T, et al. Post-intensive care syndrome: its pathophysiology, prevention, and future directions. Acute Med Surg. 2019;6:233-246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawal G, Yadav S, Kumar R. Post-intensive care syndrome: an overview. J Transl Int Med. 2017;5:90-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vrettou CS, Mantziou V, Vassiliou AG, Orfanos SE, Kotanidou A, Dimopoulou I. Post-intensive care syndrome in survivors from critical illness including COVID-19 patients: a narrative review. Life. 2022;12:107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakanishi N, Liu K, Kawakami D, Kawai Y, Morisawa T, Nishida T, et al. Post-intensive care syndrome and its new challenges in coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic: a review of recent advances and perspectives. J Clin Med. 2021;10:3870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deer RR, Rock MA, Vasilevsky N, Carmody L, Rando H, Anzalone AJ, et al. Characterizing long COVID: deep phenotype of a complex condition. EBioMedicine. 2021;74:103722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson KB, Rao M, Bonilla H, Subramanian A, Hack I, Madrigal M, et al. Patients with uncomplicated coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) have long-term persistent symptoms and functional impairment similar to patients with severe COVID-19: a cautionary tale during a global pandemic. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e826-e829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, Brown JS, Denneny EK, Hare SS, et al. &#x201c;Long-COVID&#x201d;: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76:396-398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Committee for the COMEBAC Study Group, Morin L, Savale L, Pham T, Colle R, Figueiredo S, et al. Four-month clinical status of a cohort of patients after hospitalization for COVID-19. JAMA. 2021;325:1525-1534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker TH, Migliavaca CB, Stein C, Colpani V, Falavigna M, Aromataris E, et al. Conducting proportional meta-analysis in different types of systematic reviews: a guide for synthesisers of evidence. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2021;21:189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ, Liu S. Proposed subtypes of post-COVID-19 syndrome (or long-COVID) and their respective potential therapies. Rev Med Virol. 2022;32:e2315.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>