<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37718186</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-2518</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>41</Volume><Issue>43</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Vaccine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Vaccine</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Protocol for a living evidence synthesis on variants of concern and COVID-19 vaccine effectiveness.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6411</StartPage><EndPage>6418</EndPage><MedlinePgn>6411-6418</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.vaccine.2023.09.012</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0264-410X(23)01065-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">It is evident that COVID-19 will remain a public health concern in the coming years, largely driven by variants of concern (VOC). It is critical to continuously monitor vaccine effectiveness as new variants emerge and new vaccines and/or boosters are developed. Systematic surveillance of the scientific evidence base is necessary to inform public health action and identify key uncertainties. Evidence syntheses may also be used to populate models to fill in research gaps and help to prepare for future public health crises. This protocol outlines the rationale and methods for a living evidence synthesis of the effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccines in reducing the morbidity and mortality associated with, and transmission of, VOC of SARS-CoV-2.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Living evidence syntheses of vaccine effectiveness will be carried out over one year for (1) a range of potential outcomes in the index individual associated with VOC (pathogenesis); and (2) transmission of VOC. The literature search will be conducted up to May 2023. Observational and database-linkage primary studies will be included, as well as RCTs. Information sources include electronic databases (MEDLINE; Embase; Cochrane, L*OVE; the CNKI and Wangfang platforms), pre-print servers (medRxiv, BiorXiv), and online repositories of grey literature. Title and abstract and full-text screening will be performed by two reviewers using a liberal accelerated method. Data extraction and risk of bias assessment will be completed by one reviewer with verification of the assessment by a second reviewer. Results from included studies will be pooled via random effects meta-analysis when appropriate, or otherwise summarized narratively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Evidence generated from our living evidence synthesis will be used to inform policy making, modelling, and prioritization of future research on the effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccines against VOC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaver</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Synthesis and Application Unit, School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: nicole.shaver@uottawa.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katz</LastName><ForeName>Melanie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health Agency of Canada, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: melanie.katz@phac-aspc.gc.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Darko Asamoah</LastName><ForeName>Gideon</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Synthesis and Application Unit, School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: gasamoah@uottawa.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Linkins</LastName><ForeName>Lori-Ann</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: linkinla@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdelkader</LastName><ForeName>Wael</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: abdelkaw@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beck</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Synthesis and Application Unit, School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: andrew.e.beck@outlook.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bennett</LastName><ForeName>Alexandria</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Synthesis and Application Unit, School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: d.bennett@uottawa.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hughes</LastName><ForeName>Sarah E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Patient Reported Outcome Research, Institute of Applied Health Research, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, United Kingdom. Electronic address: s.e.hughes@bham.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Maureen</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Cochrane Consumer Network, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: maureen_smith@rogers.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Begin</LastName><ForeName>Mpho</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cassidy e-Care Solutions Inc, Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada. Electronic address: mpho@cassidye-care.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coyle</LastName><ForeName>Doug</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: Doug.Coyle@uOttawa.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piggott</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Research Methods, Evidence and Impact, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; Peterborough Public Health, Peterborough, Ontario, Canada; Department of Family Medicine, Queens University, Kingston, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: piggott@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kagina</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccines for Africa Initiative; NITAGs Support Hub (NISH), Faculty of Health Sciences, School of Public Health, University of Cape Town, South Africa. Electronic address: benjamin.kagina@uct.ac.za.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Welch</LastName><ForeName>Vivian</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bruy&#xe8;re Research Institute, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada; School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: vwelch@campbellcollaboration.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colijn</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of mathematics, Faculty of Science, Simon Fraser University, Burnaby, British Columbia, Canada. Electronic address: ccolijn@sfu.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Earn</LastName><ForeName>David J D</ForeName><Initials>DJD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Statistics, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: earn@math.mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El Emam</LastName><ForeName>Khaled</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: kelemam@uottawa.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heffernan</LastName><ForeName>Jane</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Disease Modelling, Department of Mathematics &amp; Statistics, Faculty of Science, York University, Toronto, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: jmheffer@yorku.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Brien</LastName><ForeName>Sheila F</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epidemiology and Surveillance, Canadian Blood Services, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada; School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: sheila.obrien@blood.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilson</LastName><ForeName>Kumanan</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ontario, Canada; Bruy&#xe8;re Research Institute, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada; Ottawa Hospital Research Institute, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada; O'Neill Institute for National and Global Health Law, Georgetown University, Washington, DC, USA. Electronic address: kwilson@ohri.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Collins</LastName><ForeName>Erin</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health Agency of Canada, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: erin.collins@phac-aspc.gc.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Navarro</LastName><ForeName>Tamara</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: navarro@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beyene</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: beyene@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boutron</LastName><ForeName>Isabelle</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Inserm, INRAE, Centre for Research in Epidemiology and Statistics (CRESS), F75004 Paris, France. Electronic address: isabelle.boutron@aphp.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bowdish</LastName><ForeName>Dawn</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: bowdish@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooper</LastName><ForeName>Curtis</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: ccooper@toh.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costa</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: acosta@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Curran</LastName><ForeName>Janet</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Faculty of Health, Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada. Electronic address: jacurran@dal.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Griffith</LastName><ForeName>Lauren</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: griffith@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsu</LastName><ForeName>Amy</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: ahsu@ohri.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grimshaw</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ottawa Hospital Research Institute and Department of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada; Department of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: jgrimshaw@ohri.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Langlois</LastName><ForeName>Marc-Andr&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: langlois@uottawa.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoguang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200025, China; State Key Laboratory of Oncogenes and Related Genes, Center for Single-Cell Omics, School of Public Health, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200025, China. Electronic address: lixg@shsmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pham-Huy</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: aphamhuy@uottawa.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raina</LastName><ForeName>Parminder</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: praina@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rubini</LastName><ForeName>Michele</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Rehabilitation, University of Ferrara, Ferrara, Italy. Electronic address: rub@unife.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thabane</LastName><ForeName>Lehana</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Research Methods, Evidence, and Impact, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; St Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Johannesburg, Johannesburg, South Africa. Electronic address: thabanl@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200025, China; State Key Laboratory of Oncogenes and Related Genes, Center for Single-Cell Omics, School of Public Health, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200025, China. Electronic address: huiwang@shsmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Lan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200025, China. Electronic address: lan.xu@sjtu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brouwers</LastName><ForeName>Melissa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Synthesis and Application Unit, School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: melissa.brouwers@uottawa.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horsley</LastName><ForeName>Tanya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons of Canada, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: thorsley@royalcollege.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lavis</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Research Methods, Evidence and Impact, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; McMaster Health Forum, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: lavisj@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iorio</LastName><ForeName>Alfonso</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: iorioa@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Little</LastName><ForeName>Julian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Knowledge Synthesis and Application Unit, School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: jlittle@uottawa.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>EG9 179477</GrantID><Agency>CIHR</Agency><Country>Canada</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Vaccine</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8406899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0264-410X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000086663">COVID-19 Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086663" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000087507" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccine Efficacy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015982" MajorTopicYN="N">Bias</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015201" MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-Analysis as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hybrid immunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Living systematic review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Omicron</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2 variant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37718186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2023.09.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0264-410X(23)01065-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>