<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39423876</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-2742</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>89</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of infection</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Infect</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Trends of common laboratory biomarkers after SARS-CoV-2 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>106318</StartPage><MedlinePgn>106318</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jinf.2024.106318</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0163-4453(24)00252-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Most studies that explore the long-term effects of COVID-19 are based on subjectively reported symptoms, while laboratory-measured biomarkers are mainly examined in studies of relatively small cohorts. This study investigates the long-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on common laboratory biomarkers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We utilized a retrospective cohort of SARS-CoV-2 infected individuals and rigorously matched controls based on demographic and clinical characteristics, examining 63 common laboratory biomarkers. Additional lab-specific cohorts were matched with an additional criterion of baseline biomarker values. Differences in biomarkers over a 12-month follow-up were analyzed using standardized mean difference-in-differences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The general cohort included 361,061 matched pairs, with 26M laboratory results. The effects on most biomarkers lasted 1-4 months and were consistent with anticipated changes after acute viral infections. Some biomarkers presented prolonged effects, consistent across the general and lab-specific cohorts. One group of such findings included a 7-8 month decrease in WBC counts, mainly driven by decreased counts of neutrophils, monocytes, and basophils. Potassium levels were decreased for 3-5 months. Vaccinated individuals' data suggested potentially smaller effects on WBCs, but cohort sizes limited this analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study explores SARS-CoV-2 infection effects on common laboratory biomarkers, characterizing the direction and duration of these effects on the largest infected cohort to date. The effects of most biomarkers resolve in the first months following infection. The most notable longer-lasting effects involved the immune system. Further research is required to characterize the magnitude of these effects among specific individuals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024. Published by Elsevier Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meirman</LastName><ForeName>Tomer David</ForeName><Initials>TD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Israel. Electronic address: meirmant@post.bgu.ac.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shapira</LastName><ForeName>Bracha</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Israel. Electronic address: bshapira@bgu.ac.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balicer</LastName><ForeName>Ran D</ForeName><Initials>RD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Israel; Clalit Research Institute, Israel; The Ivan and Francesca Berkowitz Family Living Laboratory Collaboration at Harvard Medical School and Clalit Research Institute. Electronic address: rbalicer@clalit.org.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rokach</LastName><ForeName>Lior</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Israel. Electronic address: liorrk@post.bgu.ac.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dagan</LastName><ForeName>Noa</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Israel; Clalit Research Institute, Israel; The Ivan and Francesca Berkowitz Family Living Laboratory Collaboration at Harvard Medical School and Clalit Research Institute. Electronic address: noada@clalit.org.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Infect</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7908424</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0163-4453</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Laboratory biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective cohort study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2 infection effect</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships that may be considered as potential competing interests: Ran Balicer and Noa Dagan report institutional grants to the Clalit Research Institute from Regeneron, Astra-Zeneca, and Pfizer, all outside this submitted work (and the latter - unrelated to COVID-19), with no direct or indirect personal benefits. Other authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39423876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2024.106318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0163-4453(24)00252-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>