<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38401674</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1555-7162</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>137</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The American journal of medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association of Obstructive Sleep Apnea with Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>529</StartPage><EndPage>537.e3</EndPage><MedlinePgn>529-537.e3</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.amjmed.2024.02.023</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0002-9343(24)00109-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Obstructive sleep apnea is associated with COVID-19 infection. Less clear is whether obstructive sleep apnea is a risk factor for the development of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN">Cross-sectional survey of a general population of 24,803 US adults to determine the association of obstructive sleep apnea with PASC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">COVID-19 infection occurred in 10,324 (41.6%) participants. Prevalence of persistent (&gt;3 months post infection) putative PASC-related physical and mental health symptoms ranged from 6.5% (peripheral edema) to 19.6% (nervous/anxious). In logistic regression models, obstructive sleep apnea was associated with all putative PASC-related symptoms with the highest adjusted odds ratios being fever (2.053) and nervous/anxious (1.939). In 4 logistic regression models of overall PASC derived from elastic net regression, obstructive sleep apnea was associated with PASC (range of adjusted odds ratios: 1.934-2.071); this association was mitigated in those with treated obstructive sleep apnea. In the best fitting overall model requiring &#x2265;3 symptoms, PASC prevalence was 21.9%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">In a general population sample, obstructive sleep apnea is associated with the development of PASC-related symptoms and a global definition of PASC. Treated obstructive sleep apnea mitigates the latter risk. The presence of 3 or more PASC symptoms may be useful in identifying cases and for future research.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quan</LastName><ForeName>Stuart F</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Sleep and Circadian Disorders, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, Mass; Division of Sleep Medicine. Electronic address: Stuart_Quan@hms.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weaver</LastName><ForeName>Matthew D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Sleep and Circadian Disorders, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, Mass; Division of Sleep Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Czeisler</LastName><ForeName>Mark &#xc9;</ForeName><Initials>M&#xc9;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Francis Weld Peabody Society, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Mass; School of Psychological Sciences, Turner Institute for Brain and Mental Health, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia; Institute for Breathing and Sleep, Austin Health, Heidelberg, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barger</LastName><ForeName>Laura K</ForeName><Initials>LK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Sleep and Circadian Disorders, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, Mass; Division of Sleep Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Booker</LastName><ForeName>Lauren A</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Breathing and Sleep, Austin Health, Heidelberg, Victoria, Australia; University Department of Rural Health, La Trobe Rural Health School, La Trobe University, Bendigo, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Howard</LastName><ForeName>Mark E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Breathing and Sleep, Austin Health, Heidelberg, Victoria, Australia; Turner Institute for Brain and Mental Health, Monash University, Clayton, Victoria, Australia; Department of Medicine, The University of Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jackson</LastName><ForeName>Melinda L</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychological Sciences, Turner Institute for Brain and Mental Health, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia; Institute for Breathing and Sleep, Austin Health, Heidelberg, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lane</LastName><ForeName>Rashon I</ForeName><Initials>RI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Sleep and Circadian Disorders, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, Mass.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDonald</LastName><ForeName>Christine F</ForeName><Initials>CF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Breathing and Sleep, Austin Health, Heidelberg, Victoria, Australia; Department of Medicine, The University of Melbourne, Victoria, Australia; Department of Respiratory and Sleep Medicine, Austin Health, Heidelberg, Victoria, Australia; Faculty of Medicine, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ridgers</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Breathing and Sleep, Austin Health, Heidelberg, Victoria, Australia; Department of Medicine, The University of Melbourne, Victoria, Australia; Department of Respiratory and Sleep Medicine, Austin Health, Heidelberg, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robbins</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Sleep and Circadian Disorders, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, Mass; Division of Sleep Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varma</LastName><ForeName>Prerna</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychological Sciences, Turner Institute for Brain and Mental Health, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiley</LastName><ForeName>Joshua F</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychological Sciences, Turner Institute for Brain and Mental Health, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajaratnam</LastName><ForeName>Shantha M W</ForeName><Initials>SMW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Sleep and Circadian Disorders, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, Mass; Division of Sleep Medicine; School of Psychological Sciences, Turner Institute for Brain and Mental Health, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia; Institute for Breathing and Sleep, Austin Health, Heidelberg, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Czeisler</LastName><ForeName>Charles A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Sleep and Circadian Disorders, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, Mass; Division of Sleep Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K01 HL150339</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 OH011773</GrantID><Acronym>OH</Acronym><Agency>NIOSH CDC HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01OH011773</GrantID><Acronym>ACL</Acronym><Agency>ACL HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R56 HL151637</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0267200</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0002-9343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>medRxiv. 2023 Dec 31:2023.12.30.23300666. doi: 10.1101/2023.12.30.23300666</RefSource><PMID Version="1">38234859</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020181" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obstructive sleep apnea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>MDW reports institutional support from the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Institutes of Occupational Safety and Health, Delta Airlines, and the Puget Sound Pilots; as well as consulting fees from the Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center and the University of Pittsburgh. LKB reports institutional support from the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Institutes of Occupational Safety and Health, Delta Airlines, and the Puget Sound Pilots; as well as honorariums from the National Institutes of Occupational Safety and Health, University of Arizona and University of British Columbia. M&#xc9;C reported personal fees from Vanda Pharmaceuticals Inc., research grants or gifts to Monash University from WHOOP, Inc., Hopelab, Inc., CDC Foundation, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. SMWR reported receiving grants and personal fees from Cooperative Research Centre for Alertness, Safety, and Productivity, receiving grants and institutional consultancy fees from Teva Pharma Australia and institutional consultancy fees from Vanda Pharmaceuticals, Circadian Therapeutics, BHP Billiton, and Herbert Smith Freehills. SFQ has served as a consultant for Best Doctors, Bryte Foundation, Jazz Pharmaceuticals, Apnimed, and Whispersom. RR reports personal fees from SleepCycle AB; Rituals Cosmetics BV; Sonesta Hotels International, LLC; Ouraring Ltd; AdventHealth; and With Deep, LLC. CAC serves as the incumbent of an endowed professorship provided to Harvard Medical School by Cephalon, Inc. and reports institutional support for a Quality Improvement Initiative from Delta Airlines and Puget Sound Pilots; education support to Harvard Medical School Division of Sleep Medicine and support to Brigham and Women&#x2019;s Hospital from: Jazz Pharmaceuticals PLC, Inc, Philips Respironics, Inc., Optum, and ResMed, Inc.; research support to Brigham and Women&#x2019;s Hospital from Axome Therapeutics, Inc., Dayzz Ltd., Peter Brown and Margaret Hamburg, Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, Sanofi SA, Casey Feldman Foundation, Summus, Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., LTD, Abbaszadeh Foundation, CDC Foundation; educational funding to the Sleep and Health Education Program of the Harvard Medical School Division of Sleep Medicine from ResMed, Inc., Teva Pharmaceuticals Industries, Ltd., and Vanda Pharmaceuticals; personal royalty payments on sales of the Actiwatch-2 and Actiwatch-Spectrum devices from Philips Respironics, Inc; personal consulting fees from Axome, Inc., Bryte Foundation, With Deep, Inc. and Vanda Pharmaceuticals; honoraria from the Associated Professional Sleep Societies, LLC for the Thomas Roth Lecture of Excellence at SLEEP 2022, from the Massachusetts Medical Society for a New England Journal of Medicine Perspective article, from the National Council for Mental Wellbeing, from the National Sleep Foundation for serving as chair of the Sleep Timing and Variability Consensus Panel, for lecture fees from Teva Pharma Australia PTY Ltd. and Emory University, and for serving as an advisory board member for the Institute of Digital Media and Child Development, the Klarman Family Foundation, and the UK Biotechnology and Biological Sciences Research Council. CAC has received personal fees for serving as an expert witness on a number of civil matters, criminal matters, and arbitration cases, including those involving the following commercial and government entities: Amtrak; Bombardier, Inc.; C&amp;J Energy Services; Dallas Police Association; Delta Airlines/Comair; Enterprise Rent-A-Car; FedEx; Greyhound Lines, Inc./Motor Coach Industries/FirstGroup America; PAR Electrical Contractors, Inc.; Puget Sound Pilots; and the San Francisco Sheriff&#x2019;s Department; Schlumberger Technology Corp.; Union Pacific Railroad; United Parcel Service; Vanda Pharmaceuticals. CAC has received travel support from the Stanley Ho Medical Development Foundation for travel to Macao and Hong Kong; equity interest in Vanda Pharmaceuticals, With Deep, Inc, and Signos, Inc.; and institutional educational gifts to Brigham and Women&#x2019;s Hospital from Johnson &amp; Johnson, Mary Ann and Stanley Snider via Combined Jewish Philanthropies, Alexandra Drane, DR Capital, Harmony Biosciences, LLC, San Francisco Bar Pilots, Whoop, Inc., Harmony Biosciences LLC, Eisai Co., LTD, Idorsia Pharmaceuticals LTD, Sleep Number Corp., Apnimed, Inc., Avadel Pharmaceuticals, Bryte Foundation, f.lux Software, LLC, Stuart F. and Diana L. Quan Charitable Fund. Dr Czeisler&#x2019;s interests were reviewed and are managed by the Brigham and Women&#x2019;s Hospital and Mass General Brigham in accordance with their conflict-of interest policies. No other disclosures were reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38401674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1971309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11144080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2024.02.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0002-9343(24)00109-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Healey Q, Sheikh A, Daines L, Vasileiou E. Symptoms and signs of long COVID: A rapid review and meta-analysis. J Glob Health. 2022;12:05014. doi:10.7189/jogh.12.05014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7189/jogh.12.05014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9125197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35596571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall M The lasting misery of coronavirus long-haulers. Nature. 2020;585(7825):339&#x2013;341. doi:10.1038/d41586-020-02598-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/d41586-020-02598-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32929257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T, Hittle M, Goodman SN. Assessment of the Frequency and Variety of Persistent Symptoms Among Patients With COVID-19: A Systematic Review. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(5):e2111417. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.11417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.11417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8155823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34037731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond). 2021;53(10):737&#x2013;754. doi:10.1080/23744235.2021.1924397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23744235.2021.1924397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nittas V, Gao M, West EA, et al. Long COVID Through a Public Health Lens: An Umbrella Review. Public Health Rev. 2022;43:1604501. doi:10.3389/phrs.2022.1604501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/phrs.2022.1604501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8963488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35359614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampasian V, Elghazaly H, Chattopadhyay R, et al. Risk Factors Associated With Post&#x2212;COVID-19 Condition: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. JAMA Internal Medicine. 2023;183(6):566&#x2013;580. doi:10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.0750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.0750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10037203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cade BE, Dashti HS, Hassan SM, Redline S, Karlson EW. Sleep Apnea and COVID-19 Mortality and Hospitalization. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020;202(10):1462&#x2013;1464. doi:10.1164/rccm.202006-2252LE</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202006-2252LE</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7667903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32946275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung F, Waseem R, Pham C, et al. The association between high risk of sleep apnea, comorbidities, and risk of COVID-19: a population-based international harmonized study. Sleep Breath. 2021;25(2):849&#x2013;860. doi:10.1007/s11325-021-02373-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11325-021-02373-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8079162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33907966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hariyanto TI, Kurniawan A. Obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) and outcomes from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pneumonia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med. 2021;82:47&#x2013;53. doi:10.1016/j.sleep.2021.03.029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2021.03.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8012298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maas MB, Kim M, Malkani RG, Abbott SM, Zee PC. Obstructive Sleep Apnea and Risk of COVID-19 Infection, Hospitalization and Respiratory Failure. Sleep Breath. 2021;25(2):1155&#x2013;1157. doi:10.1007/s11325-020-02203-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11325-020-02203-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7521948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32989673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mashaqi S, Lee-Iannotti J, Rangan P, et al. Obstructive sleep apnea and COVID-19 clinical outcomes during hospitalization: a cohort study. J Clin Sleep Med. 2021;17(11):2197&#x2013;2204. doi:10.5664/jcsm.9424</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5664/jcsm.9424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8636359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34019476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan SF, Weaver MD, Czeisler M&#xc9;, et al. Associations between obstructive sleep apnea and COVID-19 infection and hospitalization among US adults. J Clin Sleep Med. 2023;19(7):1303&#x2013;1311. doi:10.5664/jcsm.10588</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5664/jcsm.10588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10315594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37279079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2013;146. doi:10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandel HL, Colleen G, Abedian S, et al. Risk of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection associated with pre-coronavirus disease obstructive sleep apnea diagnoses: an electronic health record-based analysis from the RECOVER initiative. Sleep. 2023;46(9):zsad126. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsad126</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/zsad126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10485569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37166330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989;28(2):193&#x2013;213. doi:10.1016/0165-1781(89)90047-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0165-1781(89)90047-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2748771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan SF, Weaver MD, Czeisler M&#xc9;, et al. Insomnia, Poor Sleep Quality and Sleep Duration, and Risk for COVID-19 Infection and Hospitalization. Am J Med. 2023;136(8):780&#x2013;788.e5. doi:10.1016/j.amjmed.2023.04.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2023.04.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10108572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37075878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi B, Sudry T, Flaks-Manov N, et al. Long covid outcomes at one year after mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: nationwide cohort study. BMJ. 2023;380:e072529. doi:10.1136/bmj-2022-072529</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2022-072529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9832503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36631153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malesevic S, Sievi NA, Baumgartner P, et al. Impaired health-related quality of life in long-COVID syndrome after mild to moderate COVID-19. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):7717. doi:10.1038/s41598-023-34678-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-34678-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10175927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37173355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley SE, Karlson EW, et al. Development of a Definition of Postacute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection. JAMA. 2023;329(22):1934&#x2013;1946. doi:10.1001/jama.2023.8823</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2023.8823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10214179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe A, Iwagami M, Yasuhara J, Takagi H, Kuno T. Protective effect of COVID-19 vaccination against long COVID syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Vaccine. 2023;41(11):1783&#x2013;1790. doi:10.1016/j.vaccine.2023.02.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2023.02.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9905096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36774332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kheirandish-Gozal L, Gozal D. Obstructive Sleep Apnea and Inflammation: Proof of Concept Based on Two Illustrative Cytokines. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20(3):459. doi:10.3390/ijms20030459</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms20030459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6387387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30678164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren H, Hu K. Inflammatory and oxidative stress-associated factors in chronic intermittent hypoxia in Chinese patients, rats, lymphocytes and endotheliocytes. Mol Med Rep. 2017;16(6):8092&#x2013;8102. doi:10.3892/mmr.2017.7632</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/mmr.2017.7632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5779894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28983603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bikov A, Meszaros M, Schwarz EI. Coagulation and Fibrinolysis in Obstructive Sleep Apnoea. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(6):2834. doi:10.3390/ijms22062834</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22062834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8000922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33799528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zolotoff C, Bertoletti L, Gozal D, et al. Obstructive Sleep Apnea, Hypercoagulability, and the Blood-Brain Barrier. J Clin Med. 2021;10(14):3099. doi:10.3390/jcm10143099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm10143099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8304023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34300265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner S, Khan MA, Putrino D, Woodcock A, Kell DB, Pretorius E. Long COVID: pathophysiological factors and abnormalities of coagulation. Trends Endocrinol Metab. 2023;34(6):321&#x2013;344. doi:10.1016/j.tem.2023.03.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tem.2023.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10113134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37080828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanek A, Bro&#x17c;yna-Tkaczyk K, My&#x15b;li&#x144;ski W. Oxidative Stress Markers among Obstructive Sleep Apnea Patients. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2021;2021:9681595. doi:10.1155/2021/9681595</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/9681595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8321764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34336121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludwig K, Huppertz T, Radsak M, Gouveris H. Cellular Immune Dysfunction in Obstructive Sleep Apnea. Front Surg. 2022;9:890377. doi:10.3389/fsurg.2022.890377</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsurg.2022.890377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9299259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35874140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Chen HJ. Use of Percentiles and Z-Scores in Anthropometry. In: Handbook of Anthropometry: Physical Measures of Human Form in Health and Disease. 1st ed. Springer; 2012:3107. Accessed December 3, 2023. 10.1007/978-1-4419-1788-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4419-1788-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>