<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37586104</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Physical Exercise-Based Rehabilitation on Long COVID: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>143</StartPage><EndPage>154</EndPage><MedlinePgn>143-154</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003280</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The number of persons living with post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) conditions or long COVID continues to rise worldwide; however, the etiology and the treatment of long COVID remain nebulous. Therefore, efficient, feasible, and cost-effective therapeutic strategies for a large population with long COVID remain warranted. Physical exercise-based rehabilitation is a promising strategy for long COVID, although its therapeutic effects remain to be determined. This systematic review and meta-analysis aimed to examine the effects of physical exercise-based rehabilitation on long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The electronic databases Medline, Embase, Global Health (Ovid), CINAHL (EBSCO), Web of Science, WHO Global Research Database on COVID-19, LitCovid, and Google Scholar were searched from their inception to November 2022. The identified articles were independently screened by three reviewers, and a random-effects model was used to determine the mean differences in the meta-analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-three studies involving 1579 individuals who had COVID-19 (752 women) were included. Physical exercise-based rehabilitation showed beneficial effects on long COVID-related symptoms characterized by dyspnea, fatigue, and depression, as well as on the 6-min walk test, forced expiratory volume in 1 s/forced vital capacity, and quality of life in people who had COVID-19.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Physical exercise-based rehabilitation is a potential therapeutic strategy against long COVID and can be applied as a routine clinical practice in people who have recovered from COVID-19. However, customized physical exercise-based rehabilitation programs and their effects on specific types of long COVID require future large-scale studies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xiang-Ke</ForeName><Initials>XK</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sit</LastName><ForeName>Cindy Hui-Ping</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Physical Education, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Sha Tin, Hong Kong SAR, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Xiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Physical Education, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Sha Tin, Hong Kong SAR, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ming-Hui</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Physical Education, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Sha Tin, Hong Kong SAR, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Alvin Chun-Hang</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Technology and Informatics, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hung Hom, Hong Kong SAR, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Stephen Heung-Sang</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Physical Education, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Sha Tin, Hong Kong SAR, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37586104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-990000000-00343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis . 2022;22(4):e102&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Burdens of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 by severity of acute infection, demographics and health status. Nat Commun . 2021;12(1):6571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global prevalence of post COVID-19 condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis . 2022;226(9):1593&#x2013;607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Coronavirus disease (COVID-19): post COVID-19 condition. 2023; [cited 2023 May 12 ] Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/questions-and-answers/item/coronavirus-disease-(covid-19)-post-covid-19-condition .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med . 2021;27(4):626&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson EJ, Williams DM, Walker AJ, et al. Long COVID burden and risk factors in 10 UK longitudinal studies and electronic health records. Nat Commun . 2022;13(1):3528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Acute and postacute sequelae associated with SARS-CoV-2 reinfection. Nat Med . 2022;28(11):2398&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet . 2022;399(10343):2263&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampasian V, Elghazaly H, Chattopadhyay R, et al. Risk factors associated with post&#x2212; COVID-19 condition: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Intern Med . 2023;183(6):566&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Bowe B, Xie Y. Long COVID after breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med . 2022;28(7):1461&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol . 2023;21(3):133&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deer RR, Rock MA, Vasilevsky N, et al. Characterizing long COVID: deep phenotype of a complex condition. EBioMedicine . 2021;74:103722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker-Davies RM, O&#x2019;Sullivan O, Senaratne KPP, et al. The Stanford Hall consensus statement for post-COVID-19 rehabilitation. Br J Sports Med . 2020;54(16):949&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ . 2021;374:n1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson PD, Buchner D, Pi&#xf1;a IL, et al. Exercise and physical activity in the prevention and treatment of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease: a statement from the Council on Clinical Cardiology (Subcommittee on Exercise, Rehabilitation, and Prevention) and the Council on Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Metabolism (Subcommittee on Physical Activity). Circulation . 2003;107(24):3109&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zschucke E, Gaudlitz K, Str&#xf6;hle A. Exercise and physical activity in mental disorders: clinical and experimental evidence. J Prev Med Public Heal . 2013;46(Suppl 1):S12&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakoski SG, Eves ND, Douglas PS, Jones LW. Exercise rehabilitation in patients with cancer. Nat Rev Clin Oncol . 2012;9(5):288&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiuza-Luces C, Garatachea N, Berger NA, Lucia A. Exercise is the real polypill. Physiology (Bethesda) . 2013;28(5):330&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daynes E, Gerlis C, Chaplin E, Gardiner N, Singh SJ. Early experiences of rehabilitation for individuals post-COVID to improve fatigue, breathlessness exercise capacity and cognition&#x2014;a cohort study. Chron Respir Dis . 2021;18:14799731211015692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nopp S, Moik F, Klok FA, et al. Outpatient pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with long COVID improves exercise capacity, functional status, dyspnea, fatigue, and quality of life. Respiration . 2022;101(6):593&#x2013;601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med . 2021;27(4):601&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright J, Astill SL, Sivan M. The relationship between physical activity and long COVID: a cross-sectional study. Int J Environ Res Public Health . 2022;19(9):5093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salman D, Vishnubala D, Le Feuvre P, et al. Returning to physical activity after COVID-19. BMJ . 2021;372:m4721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine . 2021;38:101019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denay KL, Breslow RG, Turner MN, Nieman DC, Roberts WO, Best TM. ACSM call to action statement: COVID-19 considerations for sports and physical activity. Curr Sports Med Rep . 2020;19(8):326&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, Hishmeh L. Managing the long term effects of covid-19: summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ . 2021;372:n136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceravolo M, Arienti C, De Sire A, et al. Rehabilitation and COVID-19: the Cochrane Rehabilitation 2020 rapid living systematic review. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med . 2020;56(5):642&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kambic T, Had&#x17e;i&#x107; V, Lainscak M. Optimizing cardiopulmonary rehabilitation of long COVID-19 syndrome: are we there yet? Eur J Prev Cardiol . 2022;29(8):e268&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soril LJJ, Damant RW, Lam GY, et al. The effectiveness of pulmonary rehabilitation for post-COVID symptoms: a rapid review of the literature. Respir Med . 2022;195:106782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fugazzaro S, Contri A, Esseroukh O, et al. Rehabilitation interventions for post-acute COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health . 2022;19(9):5185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Shi H, Liu X, Sun T, Wu J, Liu Z. Effect of pulmonary rehabilitation for patients with post-COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Med (Lausanne) . 2022;9:837420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ . 2021;372:n71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, et al. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Health . 2021;6(9):e005427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng C, Chen XK, Tian XY, Ma AC, Wong SH. Does the gut microbiota contribute to the antiobesity effect of exercise? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Obesity (Silver Spring) . 2022;30(2):407&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohatgi A. WebPlotDigitizer. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ . 2019;366:I4898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stang A. Critical evaluation of the Newcastle&#x2013;Ottawa scale for the assessment of the quality of nonrandomized studies in meta-analyses. Eur J Epidemiol . 2010;25(9):603&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ . 2003;327(7414):557&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nambi G, Abdelbasset WK, Alrawaili SM, et al. Comparative effectiveness study of low versus high-intensity aerobic training with resistance training in community-dwelling older men with post-COVID 19 sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil . 2022;36(1):59&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavrou VT, Tourlakopoulos KN, Vavougios GD, et al. Eight weeks unsupervised pulmonary rehabilitation in previously hospitalized of SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Pers Med . 2021;11(8):806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira DO Amaral V, Viana AA, Heubel AD, et al. Cardiovascular, respiratory, and functional effects of home-based exercise training after COVID-19 hospitalization. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2022;54(11):1795&#x2013;803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagherzadeh-Rahmani B, Kordi N, Haghighi AH, et al. Eight weeks of Pilates training improves respiratory measures in people with a history of COVID-19: a preliminary study. Sports Health . 2023;15(5):710&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhandari R. Online yoga and ayurveda intervention as tertiary prevention of psychological comorbidities in COVID-19 survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Ann Neurosci . 2022;29(4):233&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos MC, Nery T, Speck AE, et al. Rehabilitation in survivors of COVID-19 (RE2SCUE): a non-randomized, controlled and open study. medRxiv . 2022. doi:10.10.22280907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.10.22280907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capin JJ, Jolley SE, Morrow M, et al. Safety, feasibility and initial efficacy of an app-facilitated telerehabilitation (AFTER) programme for COVID-19 survivors: a pilot randomised study. BMJ Open . 2022;12(7):e061285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dellavechia de Carvalho C, Bertucci DR, Ribeiro FA, et al. Effects of moderate-intensity training under cyclic hypoxia on cardiorespiratory fitness and hematological parameters in people recovered from COVID-19: the AEROBICOVID study. Sports Health . 2023;15(4):558&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dun Y, Liu C, Ripley-Gonzalez JW, et al. Six-month outcomes and effect of pulmonary rehabilitation among patients hospitalized with COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study. Ann Med . 2021;53(1):2099&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n A, Franco-L&#xf3;pez F, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, et al. Rehabilitation for post-COVID-19 condition through a supervised exercise intervention: a randomized controlled trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2022;32(12):1791&#x2013;801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albu S, Rivas Zozaya N, Murillo N, Garc&#xed;a-Molina A, Figueroa Chac&#xf3;n CA, Kumru H. Multidisciplinary outpatient rehabilitation of physical and neurological sequelae and persistent symptoms of covid-19: a prospective, observational cohort study. Disabil Rehabil . 2022;44(22):6833&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King M, Byrne A, Denehy L, et al. Feasibility of a group-based telerehabilitation intervention for long COVID management. Res Sq . 2022. doi:10.21203/rs.3.rs1452186/v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.3.rs1452186/v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Xia W, Zhan C, et al. A telerehabilitation programme in post-discharge COVID-19 patients (TERECO): a randomised controlled trial. Thorax . 2022;77(7):697&#x2013;706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romanet C, Wormser J, Fels A, et al. Effectiveness of endurance training rehabilitation after hospitalisation in intensive care for COVID-19-related acute respiratory distress syndrome on dyspnoea (RECOVER): a randomised controlled, open-label multicentre trial. medRxiv . 2022. doi:2022.08.29.22279327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">2022.08.29.22279327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbara C, Clavario P, De Marzo V, et al. Effects of exercise rehabilitation in patients with long coronavirus disease 2019. Eur J Prev Cardiol . 2022;29(7):e258&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalbosco-Salas M, Torres-Castro R, Rojas Leyton A, et al. Effectiveness of a primary care telerehabilitation program for post-COVID-19 patients: a feasibility study. J Clin Med . 2021;10(19):4428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everaerts S, Heyns A, Langer D, et al. COVID-19 recovery: benefits of multidisciplinary respiratory rehabilitation. BMJ Open Respir Res . 2021;8(1):e000837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kortianou EA, Tsimouris D, Mavronasou A, et al. Application of a home-based exercise program combined with tele-rehabilitation in previously hospitalized patients with COVID-19: a feasibility, single-cohort interventional study. Pneumonologie . 2022;35(2):12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loboda D, Gibinski M, Wilczek J, et al. Effectiveness of cardiopulmonary rehabilitation after COVID-19 in Poland. Pol Arch Intern Med . 2023;133(1):16341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin I, Braem F, Baudet L, et al. Follow-up of functional exercise capacity in patients with COVID-19: it is improved by telerehabilitation. Respir Med . 2021;183:106438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer KP, Parry SM, Kalema AG, et al. Safety and feasibility of an interdisciplinary treatment approach to optimize recovery from critical coronavirus disease 2019. Crit Care Explor . 2021;3(8):e0516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Support for Rehabilitation: Self-management after COVID-19-Related Illness . World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Li Y, Yue Y, et al. Adherence to healthy lifestyle prior to infection and risk of post-COVID-19 condition. JAMA Intern Med . 2023;183(3):232&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wise J. Long covid: WHO calls on countries to offer patients more rehabilitation. BMJ . 2021;372:n405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahlgren C, Divanoglou A, Larsson M, et al. Rehabilitation needs following COVID-19: five-month post-discharge clinical follow-up of individuals with concerning self-reported symptoms. EClinicalMedicine . 2022;43:101219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n A, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, et al. Effects of a concurrent training, respiratory muscle exercise, and self-management recommendations on recovery from post-COVID-19 conditions: the RECOVE trial. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2023;134(1):95&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro JP, Kierkegaard M, Zeitelhofer M. A call to use the multicomponent exercise tai chi to improve recovery from COVID-19 and long COVID. Front Public Health . 2022;10:827645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physiotherapy W. World Physiotherapy Response to COVID-19 Briefing Paper 9. Safe rehabilitation approaches for people living with Long COVID: physical activity and exercise . 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Zhang W, Yang Y, Zhang J, Li Y, Chen Y. Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: a randomized controlled study. Complement Ther Clin Pract . 2020;39:101166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piquet V, Luczak C, Seiler F, et al. Do patients with COVID-19 benefit from rehabilitation? Functional outcomes of the first 100 patients in a COVID-19 rehabilitation unit. Arch Phys Med Rehabil . 2021;102(6):1067&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues M, Costa AJ, Santos R, et al. Inpatient rehabilitation can improve functional outcomes of post-intensive care unit COVID-19 patients&#x2014;a prospective study. Disabil Rehabil . 2023;45(2):266&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain E, Harmon EY, Sonagere MB. Functional outcomes and post-discharge care sought by patients with COVID-19 compared to matched controls after completing inpatient acute rehabilitation. PM R . 2021;13(6):618&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damanti S, Ramirez GA, Bozzolo EP, et al. Six-month respiratory outcomes and exercise capacity of COVID-19 acute respiratory failure patients treated with continuous positive airway pressure. Intern Med J . 2021;51(11):1810&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Ascanio L, Vitelli F, Cingolani C, Maranzano M, Brenner MJ, Di Stadio A. Randomized clinical trial &#x201c;olfactory dysfunction after COVID-19: olfactory rehabilitation therapy vs. intervention treatment with palmitoylethanolamide and luteolin&#x201d;: preliminary results. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci . 2021;25(11):4156&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avenali M, Martinelli D, Todisco M, et al. Clinical and electrophysiological outcome measures of patients with post-infectious neurological syndromes related to COVID-19 treated with intensive neurorehabilitation. Front Neurol . 2021;12:643713.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>