<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37564950</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2633-2892</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>QRB discovery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>QRB Discov</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pulmonary surfactant and COVID-19: A new synthesis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e6</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e6</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e6</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1017/qrd.2022.1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CHAPTER 1" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">COVID-19 pathogenesis poses paradoxes difficult to explain with traditional physiology. For instance, since type II pneumocytes are considered the primary cellular target of SARS-CoV-2; as these produce pulmonary surfactant (PS), the possibility that insufficient PS plays a role in COVID-19 pathogenesis has been raised. However, the opposite of predicted <i>high</i> alveolar surface tension is found in many <i>early</i> COVID-19 patients: paradoxically normal lung volumes and high compliance occur, with profound hypoxemia. That 'COVID anomaly' was quickly rationalised by invoking traditional vascular mechanisms-mainly because of surprisingly preserved alveolar surface in early hypoxemic cases. However, that quick rejection of alveolar damage only occurred because the actual mechanism of gas exchange has long been presumed to be non-problematic, due to diffusion through the alveolar surface. On the contrary, we provide physical chemical evidence that <i>gas exchange occurs by an process of expansion and contraction of the three-dimensional structures of PS and its associated proteins.</i> This view explains anomalous observations from the level of cryo-TEM to whole individuals. It encompasses results from premature infants to the deepest diving seals. Once understood, the COVID anomaly dissolves and is straightforwardly explained as covert viral damage to the 3D structure of PS, with direct treatment implications. As a natural experiment, the SARS-CoV-2 virus itself has helped us to simplify and clarify not only the nature of dyspnea and its relationship to pulmonary compliance, but also the fine detail of the PS including such features as water channels which had heretofore been entirely unexpected.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CHAPTER 2" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">For a long time, physical, colloid and surface chemistry have not intersected with physiology and cell biology as much as we might have hoped. The reasons are starting to become clear. The discipline of physical chemistry suffered from serious unrecognised omissions that rendered it ineffective. These foundational defects included omission of specific ion molecular forces and hydration effects. The discipline lacked a predictive theory of self-assembly of lipids and proteins. Worse, theory omitted any role for dissolved gases, O<sub>2</sub>, N<sub>2</sub>, CO<sub>2</sub>, and their existence as stable nanobubbles above physiological salt concentration. Recent developments have gone some way to explaining the foam-like lung surfactant structures and function. It delivers O<sub>2</sub>/N<sub>2</sub> as nanobubbles, and efflux of CO<sub>2</sub>, and H<sub>2</sub>O nanobubbles at the alveolar surface. Knowledge of pulmonary surfactant structure allows an explanation of the mechanism of corona virus entry, and differences in infectivity of different variants. CO<sub>2</sub> nanobubbles, resulting from metabolism passing through the molecular frit provided by the glycocalyx of venous tissue, forms the previously unexplained foam which is the endothelial surface layer. CO<sub>2</sub> nanobubbles turn out to be lethal to viruses, providing a plausible explanation for the origin of 'Long COVID'. Circulating nanobubbles, stable above physiological 0.17 M salt drive various enzyme-like activities and chemical reactions. Awareness of the microstructure of Pulmonary Surfactant and that nanobubbles of (O<sub>2</sub>/N<sub>2</sub>) and CO<sub>2</sub> are integral to respiratory and circulatory physiology provides new insights to the COVID-19 and other pathogen activity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2022.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ninham</LastName><ForeName>Barry</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5706-1988</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Physics (formerly Department of Applied Mathematics), Research School of Physics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Science, University of New South Wales, Northcott Drive, Campbell, Canberra, ACT 2612, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reines</LastName><ForeName>Brandon</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7523-5192</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Physics (formerly Department of Applied Mathematics), Research School of Physics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Informatics, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, 5607 Baum Blvd, Pittsburgh, PA 15206, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Battye</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3396-9753</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Breakthrough Technologies, Deakin, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3396-9753</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Physics (formerly Department of Applied Mathematics), Research School of Physics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>QRB Discov</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101772102</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2633-2892</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gas Exchange</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lung Surfactant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary Surfactant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nano-bubbles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical chemistry</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37564950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10411325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/qrd.2022.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2633289222000011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>Chapter 1</Title><Reference><Citation>Abbasi S, Bhutani VK and Gerdes JS (1993) Long-term pulmonary consequences of respiratory distress syndrome in preterm infants treated with exogenous surfactant. The Journal of Pediatrics 122, 446&#x2013;452. 10.1016/s0022-3476(05)83439-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0022-3476(05)83439-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8441104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya D, Liu G and Gack MU (2020) Dysregulation of type I interferon responses in COVID-19. Nature Reviews Immunology 20, 397&#x2013;398. 10.1038/s41577-020-0346-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-020-0346-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7249038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32457522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackermann M, Verleden SE, Kuehnel M, Haverich A, Welte T, Laenger F, Vanstapel A, Werlein C, Stark H, Tzankov A, Li WW, Li VW, Mentzer SJ and Jonigk D (2020) Pulmonary vascular endothelialitis, thrombosis, and angiogenesis in COVID-19. The New England Journal of Medicine 383, 120&#x2013;128. 10.1056/NEJMoa2015432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2015432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7412750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmetaj-Shala B, Peacock P, Baillon L, Swann OC, Gashaw H, Barclay WS and Mitchell JA (2021) Resistance of endothelial cells to SARS-CoV-2 infection in vitro. bioRxiv. 10.1101/2020.11.08.372581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.11.08.372581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander J and Milner AD (1995) Lung volume and pulmonary blood flow measurements following exogenous surfactant. European Journal of Pediatrics 154, 392&#x2013;397. 10.1007/BF02072113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02072113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7641774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alheshibri M, Qian J, Jehannin M and Craig VS (2016) A history of nanobubbles. Langmuir 32, 11086&#x2013;11100. 10.1021/acs.langmuir.6b02489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.6b02489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27594543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almsherqi ZA, Kohlwein SD and Deng Y (2006) Cubic membranes: A legend beyond the Flatland* of cell membrane organization. The Journal of Cell Biology 173, 839&#x2013;844. 10.1083/jcb.200603055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1083/jcb.200603055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2063909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16785319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson S, Larsson K, Larsson M and Jacob M (1999) The lung surface structure and respiration. In Andersson S (ed), Biomathematics: Mathematics of Biostructures and Biodynamics. Elsevier Science, Chap. 14, pp. 341&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansarin K, Tolouian R, Ardalan M, Taghizadieh A, Varshochi M, Teimouri S, Vaezi T, Valizadeh H, Saleh P, Safiri S and Chapman KR (2020) Effect of bromhexine on clinical outcomes and mortality in COVID-19 patients: A randomized clinical trial. BioImpacts: BI 10, 209&#x2013;215. 10.34172/bi.2020.27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34172/bi.2020.27</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7502909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32983936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashbaugh DG, Bigelow DB, Petty TL and Levine BE (1967) Acute respiratory distress in adults. Lancet 2, 319&#x2013;323. 10.1016/s0140-6736(67)90168-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(67)90168-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4143721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avery ME and Mead J (1959) Surface properties in relation to atelectasis and hyaline membrane disease. AMA Journal of Diseases of Children 97, 517&#x2013;523. 10.1001/archpedi.1959.02070010519001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpedi.1959.02070010519001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13649082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangham AD (1992) &#x201c;Surface tension&#x201d; in the lungs. Nature 359, 110. 10.1038/359110a0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/359110a0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1522897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beachey CW (2020) PulmCrit: Understanding Happy Hypoxemia Physiology: how COVID taught me to treat pneumococcus. Farkas J (ed) https://emcrit.org/pulmcrit/happy-hypoxemia-physiology/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beecher HK (1960) Disease and the Advancement of Basic Science. Harvard University Press. Cambridge</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhat R, Dziedzic K, Bhutani VK and Vidyasagar D (1990) Effect of single dose surfactant on pulmonary function. Critical Care Medicine 18, 590&#x2013;595. 10.1097/00003246-199006000-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00003246-199006000-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2111754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt RM, Clark HW, Girardis M and Busani S (2021) Exogenous pulmonary surfactant in COVID-19 ARDS. The similarities to neonatal RDS suggest a new scenario for an &#x2018;old&#x2019; strategy. BMJ Open Respiratory Research 8, e000867. 10.1136/bmjresp-2020-000867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjresp-2020-000867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8441217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34521648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boerema I, Meyne N, Brummelkamp W, Bouma S, Mensch MH, Kamermans F, Stern Hanf M and van Aalderen M (1959) Life without blood. Journal of Cardiothoracic Surgery 13, 133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13802034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostrom M, Williams DR and Ninham BW (2001) Specific ion effects: Why DLVO theory fails for biology and colloid systems. Physical Review Letters 87, 168103. 10.1103/PhysRevLett.87.168103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.87.168103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11690249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozzani A, Arici V, Tavazzi G, Boschini S, Mojoli F, Bruno R, Sterpetti AV and Ragni F (2021) Re: &#x201c;Endothelitis in COVID-19-positive patients after extremity amputation for acute thrombotic events&#x201d;. Annals of Vascular Surgery 73, e6&#x2013;e7. 10.1016/j.avsg.2021.01.067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.avsg.2021.01.067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33548400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunkin NF, Ninham BW, Ignatiev PS, Kozlov VA, Shkirin AV and Starosvetskij AV (2011) Long-living nanobubbles of dissolved gas in aqueous solutions of salts and erythrocyte suspensions. Journal of Biophotonics 4, 150&#x2013;164. 10.1002/jbio.201000093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jbio.201000093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21287687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busani S, Dall&#x2019;Ara L, Tonelli R, Clini E, Munari E, Venturelli S, Meschiari M, Guaraldi G, Cossarizza A, Ranieri VM and Girardis M (2020) Surfactant replacement might help recovery of low-compliance lung in severe COVID-19 pneumonia. Therapeutic Advances in Respiratory Disease 14, 1753466620951043. 10.1177/1753466620951043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1753466620951043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7466887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32865137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cevik M, Tate M, Lloyd O, Maraolo AE, Schafers J and Ho A (2021) SARS-CoV-2, SARS-CoV, and MERS-CoV viral load dynamics, duration of viral shedding, and infectiousness: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Microbe 2, e13&#x2013;e22. 10.1016/S2666-5247(20)30172-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2666-5247(20)30172-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33521734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherian R, Chandra B, Tung ML and Vuylsteke A (2020) COVID-19 conundrum: Clinical phenotyping based on pathophysiology as a promising approach to guide therapy in a novel illness. The European Respiratory Journal 56, 2002135. 10.1183/13993003.02135-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02135-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7366182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32675212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherian R, Chandra B, Tung ML and Vuylsteke A (2021) Positive bubble study in severe COVID-19 indicates the development of anatomical intrapulmonary shunts in response to microvascular occlusion. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine 203, 263&#x2013;265. 10.1164/rccm.202008-3186LE.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202008-3186LE</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7874427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32997512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiumello D, Busana M, Coppola S, Romitti F, Formenti P, Bonifazi M, Pozzi T, Palumbo, MM, Cressoni M, Herrmann P, Meissner K, Quintel M, Camporota L, Marini JJ and Gattinoni L (2020) Physiological and quantitative CT-scan characterization of COVID-19 and typical ARDS: A matched cohort study. Intensive Care Medicine 46, 2187&#x2013;2196. 10.1007/s00134-020-06281-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-020-06281-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7577365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33089348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong K and Deng Y (2012) The three dimensionality of cell membranes: Lamellar to cubic membrane transition as investigated by electron microscopy. Methods in Cell Biology 108, 319&#x2013;343. 10.1016/B978-0-12-386487-1.00015-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-12-386487-1.00015-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22325609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comroe JH (1977a) Premature science and immature lungs. Part I. Some premature discoveries. The American Review of Respiratory Disease 116, 127&#x2013;135. 10.1164/arrd.1977.116.1.127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/arrd.1977.116.1.127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">327881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comroe JH (1977b) Premature science and immature lungs. Part II: Chemical warfare and the newly born. The American Review of Respiratory Disease 116, 311&#x2013;323. 10.1164/arrd.1977.116.2.311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/arrd.1977.116.2.311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">329727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comroe JH (1977c) Premature science and immature lungs. Part III. The attack on immature lungs. The American Review of Respiratory Disease 116, 497&#x2013;518. 10.1164/arrd.1977.116.3.497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/arrd.1977.116.3.497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">332020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coppola S, Chiumello D, Busana M, Giola E, Palermo P, Pozzi T, Steinberg I, Roli S, Romitti F, Lazzari S, Gattarello S, Palumbo M, Herrmann P, Saager L, Quintel M, Meissner K, Camporota L, Marini JJ, Centanni S and Gattinoni L (2021) Role of total lung stress on the progression of early COVID-19 pneumonia. Intensive Care Medicine 47, 1130&#x2013;1139. 10.1007/s00134-021-06519-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-021-06519-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34529118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig V, Ninham B and Pashley R (1993a) Effect of electrolytes on bubble coalescence. Nature 364, 317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig VS, Ninham B and Pashley R (1993b) The effect of electrolytes on bubble coalescence in water. The Journal of Physical Chemistry 97, 10192&#x2013;10197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JM, Veness-Meehan K, Notter RH, Bhutani VK, Kendig JW and Shapiro DL (1988) Changes in pulmonary mechanics after the administration of surfactant to infants with respiratory distress syndrome. The New England Journal of Medicine 319, 476&#x2013;479. 10.1056/NEJM198808253190804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM198808253190804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3405254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Y and Angelova A (2021) Coronavirus-induced host cubic membranes and lipid-related antiviral therapies: A focus on bioactive Plasmalogens. Frontiers in Cell and Development Biology 9, 630242. 10.3389/fcell.2021.630242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcell.2021.630242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33791293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorrington KL and Young JD (2001) Development of the concept of a liquid pulmonary alveolar lining layer. British Journal of Anaesthesia 86, 614&#x2013;617. 10.1093/bja/86.5.614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bja/86.5.614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11575334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DuBrock HM and Krowka MJ (2020) Bubble trouble in COVID-19. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine 202, 926&#x2013;928. 10.1164/rccm.202008-3096ED.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202008-3096ED</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7528805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32822239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Q, Zheng X, Zhou Y, Tang L, Chen Z and Ni S (2021) Re-recognizing bromhexine hydrochloride: Pharmaceutical properties and its possible role in treating pediatric COVID-19. European Journal of Clinical Pharmacology 77, 261&#x2013;263. 10.1007/s00228-020-02971-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00228-020-02971-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7459257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32870380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuschillo S, Ambrosino P, Motta A and Maniscalco M (2021) COVID-19 and diffusing capacity of the lungs for carbon monoxide: A clinical biomarker in postacute care settings. Biomarkers in Medicine 15, 537&#x2013;539. 10.2217/bmm-2021-0134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/bmm-2021-0134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8120998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33988464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gattinoni L, Chlumello D, Caironi P, Busana M, Romitti F, Brazzi L and Camporota L (2020a) COVID-10 pneumonia: Different respiratory treatment for different phenotypes? Intensive Care Medicine 46, 1099&#x2013;1102. 10.1007/s00134-020-06033-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-020-06033-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7154064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32291463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gattinoni L, Coppola S, Cressoni M, Busana M, Rossi S and Chiumello D (2020b) COVID-19 does not Lead to a &#x201c;typical&#x201d; acute respiratory distress syndrome. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine 201, 1299&#x2013;1300. 10.1164/rccm.202003-0817LE.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202003-0817LE</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7233352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32228035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gattinoni L and Marini JJ (2021) Isn&#x2019;t it time to abandon ARDS? The COVID-19 lesson. Critical Care 25, 326. 10.1186/s13054-021-03748-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-021-03748-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8419818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34488807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh GK, Dunker AK, Foster JA and Uversky VN (2020) Shell disorder analysis predicts greater resilience of the SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19) outside the body and in body fluids. Microbial Pathogenesis 144, 104177. 10.1016/j.micpath.2020.104177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.micpath.2020.104177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32244041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh GK, Dunker AK, Foster JA and Uversky VNC (2022) Experimental, and clinical evidence of a specific but peculiar evolutionary nature of (COVID-19) SARS-CoV-2. Journal of Proteome Research 21, 874&#x2013;890. 10.1021/acs.jproteome.2c00001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jproteome.2c00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldsmith CS, Miller SE, Martines RB, Bullock HA and Zaki SR (2020) Electron microscopy of SARS-CoV-2: A challenging task. Lancet 395, e99. 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31188-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31188-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7237172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldsmith LS, Greenspan JS, Rubenstein SD, Wolfson MR and Shaffer TH (1991) Immediate improvement in lung volume after exogenous surfactant: Alveolar recruitment versus increased distention. The Journal of Pediatrics 119, 424&#x2013;428. 10.1016/s0022-3476(05)82057-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0022-3476(05)82057-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1880658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Good RA (1991) Experiments of nature in the development of modern immunology. Immunology Today 12, 283&#x2013;286. 10.1016/0167-5699(91)90127-F.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0167-5699(91)90127-F</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1910450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gribetz I, Frank NR and Avery ME (1959) Static volume-pressure relations of excised lungs of infants with hyaline membrane disease, newborn and stillborn infants. The Journal of Clinical Investigation 38, 2168&#x2013;2175. 10.1172/JCI103996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI103996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC293308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13829255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrmann J, Mori V, Bates JHT and Suki B (2020) Can Hyperperfusion of nonaerated lung explain COVID-19 hypoxia? 01 June 2020, PREPRINT (Version 1) available at Research Square. 10.21203/rs.3.rs-32949/v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.3.rs-32949/v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hills BA (1999) An alternative view of the role(s) of surfactant and the alveolar model. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, MD: 1985) 87, 1567&#x2013;1583. 10.1152/jappl.1999.87.5.1567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1999.87.5.1567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10562593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyde ST, Andersson S, Larsson K, Lidin S, Landh T, Blum Z and Ninham BW (1997) The Language of Shape: The Role of Curvature in Condensed Matter Physics, Chemistry and Biology. Elsevier Science.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph KS (2016) A consilience of inductions supports the extended Fetuses-at-risk model. Paediatric and Perinatal Epidemiology 30, 11&#x2013;17. 10.1111/ppe.12260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ppe.12260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4693682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26768055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jue T, Simond G, Wright TJ, Shih L, Chung Y, Sriram R, Kreutzer U and Davis RW (2016) Effect of fatty acid interaction on myoglobin oxygen affinity and triglyceride metabolism. Journal of Physiology and Biochemistry 73, 359&#x2013;370. 10.1007/s13105-017-0559-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13105-017-0559-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28357578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitaoka H, Kobayashi H, Takimoto T and Kijima T (2021) Proposal of selective wedge instillation of pulmonary surfactant for COVID-19 pneumonia based on computational fluid dynamics simulation. BMC Pulmonary Medicine 21, 62. 10.1186/s12890-021-01435-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-021-01435-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7897887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33618696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman HN and Westgate AJ (2012) Solubility of nitrogen in marine mammal blubber depends on its lipid composition. The Journal of Experimental Biology 215, 3856&#x2013;3863. 10.1242/jeb.074443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/jeb.074443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22811247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koumbourlis AC and Motoyama EK (2020) Lung mechanics in COVID-19 resemble respiratory distress syndrome, not acute respiratory distress syndrome: Could surfactant be a treatment? American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine 202, 624&#x2013;626. 10.1164/rccm.202004-1471LE</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202004-1471LE</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32579022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koumbourlis AC, Motoyama EK and Mutich RL (1990). Changes in lung function in premature infants with respiratory insufficiency during the first 4 weeks of life. The American Review of Respiratory Disease 141, Abstract 157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar P (2020) Co-aerosolized pulmonary surfactant and Ambroxol for COVID-19 ARDS intervention: What are we waiting for? Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology 8, 577172. 10.3389/fbioe.2020.577172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2020.577172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7546362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33102461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang M, Som A, Mendoza DP, Flores EJ, Reid N, Carey D, Li MD, Witkin A, Rodriguez-Lopez JM, Shepard J-AO and Little BP (2020) Hypoxaemia related to COVID-19: Vascular and perfusion abnormalities on dual-energy CT. The Lancet Infectious Diseases 20, 1365&#x2013;1366. 10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30367-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30367-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7252023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32359410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson M and Larsson K (2014) Periodic minimal surface organizations of the lipid bilayer at the lung surface and in cubic cytomembrane assemblies. Advances in Colloid and Interface Science 205, 68&#x2013;73. 10.1016/j.cis.2013.07.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cis.2013.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23910375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson M, Larsson K, Andersson S, Kakhar J, Nylander T, Ninham B and Wollmer P (1999) The alveolar surface structure: Transformation from a liposome-like dispersion into a tetragonal CLP bilayer phase. Journal of Dispersion Science and Technology 20, 1&#x2013;12. DOI: 10.1080/01932699908943775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01932699908943775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson M, Larsson K and Wollmer P (2002) The alveolar surface is lined by a coherent liquid-crystalline phase. Progress in Colloid and Polymer Science 120, 28&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei X, Dong X, Ma R, Wang W, Xiao X, Tian Z, Wang C, Wang Y, Li L, Ren L, Guo F, Zhao Z, Zhou Z, Xiang Z and Wang J (2020) Activation and evasion of type I interferon responses by SARS-CoV-2. Nature Communications 11, 3810. 10.1038/s41467-020-17665-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-17665-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32733001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Nostro P, Ninham BW, Lo Nostro A, Pesavento G, Fratoni L and Baglioni P (2005) Specific ion effects on the growth rates of Staphylococcus aureus and Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Physical Biology 2, 1&#x2013;7. 10.1088/1478-3967/2/1/001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1478-3967/2/1/001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16204851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez L, Sang PC, Tian Y and Sang Y (2020) Dysregulated interferon response underlying severe COVID-19. Viruses 12, 1433. 10.3390/v12121433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v12121433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7764122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33322160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markart P, Ruppert C, Wygrecka M, Colaris T, Dahal B, Walmrath D, Harbach H, Wilhelm J, Seeger W, Schmidt R and Guenther A (2007) Patients with ARDS show improvement but not normalisation of alveolar surface activity with surfactant treatment: Putative role of neutral lipids. Thorax 62, 588&#x2013;594. 10.1136/thx.2006.062398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thx.2006.062398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2117258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17287298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meir JU, Champagne CD, Costa DP, Williams CL and Ponganis PJ (2009) Extreme hypoxemic tolerance and blood oxygen depletion in diving elephant seals. American Journal of Physiology. Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology 297, R927&#x2013;R939. 10.1152/ajpregu.00247.2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00247.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19641132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller NJ, Daniels CB, Costa DP and Orgeig S (2004) Control of pulmonary surfactant secretion in adult California Sea lions. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications 313, 727&#x2013;732. 10.1016/j.bbrc.2003.12.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2003.12.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14697251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner AD (1993) How does exogenous surfactant work? Archives of Disease in Childhood 68, 253&#x2013;254. 10.1136/adc.68.3_spec_no.253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/adc.68.3_spec_no.253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1590391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8466258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner AD (1995) How does exogenous surfactant really work? European Journal of Pediatrics 154, S5&#x2013;S6. 10.1007/BF02155102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02155102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7588987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner AD (1996) Surfactant and respiratory distress syndrome. The Turkish Journal of Pediatrics 38, 37&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8819619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner AD, Vyas H and Hopkin IE (1983) Effects of artificial surfactant on lung function and blood gases in idiopathic respiratory distress syndrome. Archives of Disease in Childhood 58, 458&#x2013;460. 10.1136/adc.58.6.458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/adc.58.6.458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1627978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6407404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner AD, Vyas H and Hopkin IE (1984) Effect of exogenous surfactant on total respiratory system compliance. Archives of Disease in Childhood 59, 369&#x2013;371. 10.1136/adc.59.4.369</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/adc.59.4.369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1628669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6372707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirastschijski U, Dembinski R and Maedler K (2020) Lung surfactant for pulmonary barrier restoration in patients with COVID-19 pneumonia. Frontiers in Medicine 7, 254. 10.3389/fmed.2020.00254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2020.00254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7256165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32574339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirceta S, Signore AV, Burns JM, Cossins AR, Campbell KL and Berenbrink M (2013) Evolution of mammalian diving capacity traced by myoglobin net surface charge. Science 340, 1234192. 10.1126/science.1234192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1234192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23766330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morley CJ (1984) Effect of exogenous surfactant on total respiratory system compliance. Archives of Disease in Childhood 59, 798&#x2013;799. 10.1136/adc.59.8.798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/adc.59.8.798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1628643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6548106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen TL and Perlman CE (2018) Tracheal acid or surfactant instillation raises alveolar surface tension. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, MD: 1985) 125, 1357&#x2013;1367. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00397.2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00397.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6295485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29771610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW, Larsson K and Lo Nostro P (2017a) Two sides of the coin. Part 1. Lipid and surfactant self-assembly revisited. Colloids and Surfaces. B, Biointerfaces 152, 326&#x2013;338. 10.1016/j.colsurfb.2017.01.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfb.2017.01.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28131093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW, Larsson K and Lo Nostro P (2017b) Two sides of the coin. Part 2. Colloid and surface science meets real biointerfaces. Colloids and Surfaces. B, Biointerfaces 159, 394&#x2013;404. 10.1016/j.colsurfb.2017.07.090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfb.2017.07.090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28822288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW, Pashley R and Lo Nostro P (2016) Surface forces: Changing concepts and complexity with dissolved gas, bubbles, salt and heat. Current Opinion in Colloid and Interface Science 27, 25&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olmeda B, Villen L, Cruz A, Orellana G and Perez-Gil J (2010) Pulmonary surfactant layers accelerate O(2) diffusion through the air-water interface. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta 1798, 1281&#x2013;1284. 10.1016/j.bbamem.2010.03.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbamem.2010.03.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20227386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Gil J (2008) Structure of pulmonary surfactant membranes and films: The role of proteins and lipid-protein interactions. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta 1778, 1676&#x2013;1695. 10.1016/j.bbamem.2008.05.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbamem.2008.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18515069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlman CE, Lederer DJ and Bhattacharya J (2011) Micromechanics of alveolar edema. American Journal of Respiratory Cell and Molecular Biology 44, 34&#x2013;39. 10.1165/rcmb.2009-0005OC.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1165/rcmb.2009-0005OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3028256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20118224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfenninger J, Aebi C, Bachmann D and Wagner BP (1992) Lung mechanics and gas exchange in ventilated preterm infants during treatment of hyaline membrane disease with multiple doses of artificial surfactant (exosurf). Pediatric Pulmonology 14, 10&#x2013;15. 10.1002/ppul.1950140104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ppul.1950140104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1437337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reines BP (1991) On the locus of medical discovery. The Journal of Medicine and Philosophy 16, 183&#x2013;209. 10.1093/jmp/16.2.183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jmp/16.2.183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2061700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reines BP and Ninham BW (2019) Structure and function of the endothelial surface layer: Unraveling the nanoarchitecture of biological surfaces. Quarterly Reviews of Biophysics 52, e13. 10.1017/S0033583519000118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033583519000118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31771669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds AS, Lee AG, Renz J, DeSantis K, Liang J, Powell CA, Ventetuolo CE and Poor HD (2020) Pulmonary vascular dilatation detected by automated transcranial Doppler in COVID-19 pneumonia. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine 202, 1037&#x2013;1039. 10.1164/rccm.202006-2219LE.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202006-2219LE</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7528793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32757969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruetsch C, Brglez V, Cr&#xe9;moni M, Zorzi K, Fernandez C, Boyer-Suavet S, Benzaken S, Demonchy E, Risso K, Courjon J, Cua E, Ichai C, Dellamonica J, Passeron T and Seitz-Polski B (2020) Functional exhaustion of type I and II interferons production in severe COVID-19 patients. Frontiers in Medicine 7, 603961. 10.3389/fmed.2020.603961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2020.603961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33585507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchis A, Pashley R and Ninham B (2019) Virus and bacteria inactivation by C02 bubbles in solution. npj Clean Water 2, 4&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli EM and Hills BA (2000) Opposing views on the alveolar surface, alveolar models, and the role of surfactant. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, MD: 1985) 89, 408&#x2013;412. 10.1152/jappl.2000.89.2.408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.89.2.408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10926620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholkmann F and Nicholls J (2020) Pulmonary vascular pathology in COVID-19. The New England Journal of Medicine 383, 887&#x2013;888. 10.1056/NEJMc2022068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMc2022068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32678533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schousboe P, Wiese L, Heiring C, Verder H, Poorisrisak P, Verder P and Nielsen HB (2020) Assessment of pulmonary surfactant in COVID-19 patients. Critical Care 24, 552. 10.1186/s13054-020-03268-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-020-03268-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7475719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32894160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sender R, Bar-On YM, Gleizer S, Bernsthein B, Flamholz A, Phillips R and Milo R (2021) The total number and mass of SARS-CoV-2 virions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 118, e2024815118. 10.1073/pnas.2024815118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2024815118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8237675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34083352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solaimanzadeh I (2020) Heterogeneous perfusion in COVID-19 and high altitude pulmonary Edema: A review of 2 cases followed by implications for hypoxic pulmonary vasoconstriction, thrombosis development, ventilation perfusion mismatch and emergence of treatment approaches. Cureus 12, e10230. 10.7759/cureus.10230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.10230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7474561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32913696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spragg RG, Ponganis PJ, Marsh JJ, Rau GA and Bernhard W (2004) Surfactant from diving aquatic mammals. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, MD: 1985) 96, 1626&#x2013;1632. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00898.2003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00898.2003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14688033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sridhar S and Nicholls J (2021) Pathophysiology of infection with SARS-CoV-2-what is known and what remains a mystery. Respirology 26, 652&#x2013;665. 10.1111/resp.14091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.14091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34041821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobin MJ, Jubran A and Laghi F (2020) Misconceptions of pathophysiology of happy hypoxemia and implications for management of COVID-19. Respiratory Research 21, 249. 10.1186/s12931-020-01520-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-020-01520-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7512214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolouian R, Mulla ZD, Jamaati H, Babamahmoodi A, Marjani M, Eskandari R and Dastan F (2021) Effect of bromhexine in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Journal of Investigative Medicine. 10.1136/jim-2020-001747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jim-2020-001747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33722999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veldhuizen RAW, Zuo YY, Petersen NO, Lewis JF and Possmayer F (2021) The COVID-19 pandemic: A target for surfactant therapy? Expert Review of Respiratory Medicine 15, 597&#x2013;608. 10.1080/17476348.2021.1865809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17476348.2021.1865809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33331197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Zhang Y, Chen X, Xue K, Zhang T and Ren X (2020) Evaluating the efficacy and safety of bromhexine hydrochloride tablets in treating pediatric COVID-19: A protocol for meta-analysis and systematic review. Medicine (Baltimore) 99, e22114. 10.1097/MD.0000000000022114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000022114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7489657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32925756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yurchenko SO, Shkirin AV, Ninham BW, Sychev AA, Babenko VA, Penkov NV, Kryuchkov NP and Bunkin NF (2016) Ion-specific and thermal effects in the stabilization of the gas nanobubble phase in bulk aqueous electrolyte solutions. Langmuir 32, 11245&#x2013;11255. 10.1021/acs.langmuir.6b01644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.6b01644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27350310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Wang YE, Fan Q and Zuo YY (2011) On the low surface tension of lung surfactant. Langmuir 27, 8351&#x2013;8358. 10.1021/la201482n.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la201482n</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4849879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21650180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Bastard P, Bolze A, Jouanguy E, Zhang S-Y, COVID Human Genetic Effort; Cobat A, Notarangelo LD, Su HC, Abel L and Casanova J-L (2020) Life-threatening COVID-19: Defective interferons unleash excessive inflammation. Med (N Y) 1, 14&#x2013;20. 10.1016/j.medj.2020.12.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.medj.2020.12.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7748410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33363283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Chapter 2</Title><ReferenceList><Title>The Background</Title><Reference><Citation>Lo Nostro P and Ninham BW (2020) After DLVO: Hans Lyklema and the keepers of the faith. Advances in Colloid and Interface Science 276, 102082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31887575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW (2006) The present state of molecular forces. Progress in Colloid and Polymer Science 133, 65&#x2013;73. 10.1007/2882_051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/2882_051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW (2017) The biological/physical sciences divide and the age of unreason. Substantia 1(1), 7&#x2013;24. 10.13128/Substantia-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13128/Substantia-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW (2019) B. V. Derjaguin and J. Theo. G. Overbeek. Their times, and ours. Substantia 3(2), 65&#x2013;72. 10.13128/Substantia-637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13128/Substantia-637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW and Lo Nostro P (2010) Molecular Forces and Self-Assembly: In Colloid, Nano Sciences and Biology. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW and Lo Nostro P (2020) Unexpected properties of degassed solutions. The Journal of Physical Chemistry 124, 7872&#x2013;7878. 10.1021/acs.jpcb.0c05001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcb.0c05001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8010794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW and Yaminsky V (1997) Ion binding and ion specificity: The Hofmeister effect Onsager and Lifschitz theories. Langmuir 13(7), 2097&#x2013;2108. 10.1021/la960974y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la960974y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Bubble&#x2013;bubble fusion in electrolytes</Title><Reference><Citation>Craig V and Henry C (2010) Inhibition of bubble coalescence by salts and sugars. In XXV International Mineral Processing Congress: IMPC 2010 Proceedings, Brisbane, Australia, ed. Conference Program Committee, CSIRO Publishing pp. 1814&#x2013;1826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry CL and Craig VSG (2009) Inhibition of bubble coalescence by osmolytes: Sucrose, other sugars, and urea. Langmuir 25, 11406&#x2013;11412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19572516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe9;kicheff P and Ninham BW (1990) The double-layer interaction of asymmetric electrolytes. Europhysics Letters 12(5), 471&#x2013;477. 10.1209/0295-5075/12/5/016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1209/0295-5075/12/5/016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nylander T, K&#xe9;kicheff P and Ninham BW (1994) The effect of solution behavior of insulin on interactions between adsorbed layers of insulin. Journal of Colloid and Interface Science 164(1), 136&#x2013;150. 10.1006/jcis.1994.1152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jcis.1994.1152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Classical electrolyte theory and colloid science</Title><Reference><Citation>Bostr&#xf6;m M, Craig VJS, Albion R, Williams DRM and Ninham BW (2003) Hofmeister effects in pH measurements: Role of added salt and co-ions. The Journal of Physical Chemistry. B 107(13), 2875&#x2013;2878. 10.1021/jp026804d.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp026804d</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW, Kurihara K and Vinogradova OI (1997) Hydrophobicity, specific ion adsorption and reactivity. Colloids Surfaces A: Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects 123&#x2013;124, 7&#x2013;12. 10.1016/S0927-7757(96)03794-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0927-7757(96)03794-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salis A, Cappai L, Carucci C, Parsons DF and Monduzzi M (2020) Specific buffer effects on the intermolecular interactions among protein molecules at physiological pH. Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters 11, 6805&#x2013;6811. 10.1021/acs.jpclett.0c01900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.0c01900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32787211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salis A, Pinna MC, Bilani&#x109;ova D, Monduzzi M, Lo Nostro P and Ninham BW (2006) Specific anion effects on glass electrode pH measurements of buffer solutions: Bulk and surface phenomena. The Journal of Physical Chemistry. B 110(6), 2949&#x2013;2956. 10.1021/jp0546296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp0546296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16471906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Dissolved atmospheric gas</Title><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW and Pashley RM (2020) &#x2018;Outline&#x2019;, &#x2018;Postscript&#x2019;, &amp; &#x2018;cavitation&#x2019;, in &#x2018;about water: Novel technologies for the new millennium&#x2019;. special issue of Substantia 4(2 Suppl.), 5&#x2013;8. 10.36253/Substantia-1155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36253/Substantia-1155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taseidifar M, Antony J and Pashley RM (2020) Prevention of cavitation in propellers. Substantia 4(2 Suppl.), 109&#x2013;117. 10.36253/Substantia-821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36253/Substantia-821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Nanobubbles</Title><Reference><Citation>Alheshibri M and Craig VSJ (2018) Differentiating between nanoparticles and nanobubbles by evaluation of the compressibility and density of nanoparticles. The Journal of Physical Chemistry C 122, 21998&#x2013;22007. 10.1021/acs.jpcc.8b07174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.8b07174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alheshibri M and Craig VSJ (2019a) Armoured nanobubbles; ultrasound contrast agents under pressure. Journal of Colloid and Interface Science 537, 123&#x2013;131. 10.1016/j.jcis.2018.10.108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2018.10.108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30423486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alheshibri M and Craig VSJ (2019b) Generation of nanoparticles upon mixing ethanol and water: Nanobubbles or not? Journal of Colloid and Interface Science 542, 136&#x2013;143. 10.1016/j.jcis.2019.01.134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2019.01.134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30735888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alheshibri M, Jehannin M, Coleman VA and Craig VSJ (2019) Does gas supersaturation by a chemical reaction produce bulk nanobubbles? Journal of Colloid and Interface Science 554, 388&#x2013;395. 10.1016/j.jcis.2019.07.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2019.07.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31306949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunkin NF, Kiseleva OA, Lobeyev AV, Movchan TG, Ninham BW and Vinogradova OI (1997) Effect of salts and dissolved gas on optical cavitation near hydrophobic and hydrophilic surfaces. Langmuir 13(11), 3024&#x2013;3028. 10.1021/la960265k.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la960265k</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunkin NF, Kochergin AV, Lobeyev AV, Ninham BW and Vinogradova OI (1996) Existence of charged submicrobubble clusters in polar liquids as revealed by correlation between optical cavitation and electrical conductivity. Colloids and Surfaces A: Physicochemical &amp; Engineering Aspects 110(2), 207&#x2013;212. 10.1016/0927-7757(95)03422-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0927-7757(95)03422-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunkin NF, Lobeyev AV, Lyakhov GA and Ninham BW (1999) Mechanism of low-threshold hypersonic cavitation stimulated by broadband laser pump. Physical Review E 60(2), 1681&#x2013;1690. 10.1103/PhysRevE.60.1681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevE.60.1681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11969950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunkin NF, Ninham BW, Babenko VA, Suyazov NV and Sychev AA (2010) Role of dissolved gas in optical breakdown of water: Differences between effects due to helium and other gases. Journal of Physical Chemistry B 114(23), 7743&#x2013;7752. 10.1021/jp101657f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp101657f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20496876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunkin NF, Ninham BW, Ignatiev PS, Kozlov VA, Shkirin AV and Starosvetskiy AV (2011) Long-lived nanobubbles of dissolved gas in aqueous solutions of salts and eurythocyte suspensions. Journal of Biophotonics 4(3), 150&#x2013;164. 10.1002/jbio.201000093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jbio.201000093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21287687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper JS, Phuyal P and Shah N (2021) Oxygen Toxicity. [Updated 2021 July 18]. In: StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK430743/.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28613494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn RG, Del Castillo LA and Ohnishi S (2011) Coalescence map for bubbles in surfactant-free aqueous electrolyte solutions. Advances in Colloid and Interface Science 168(1&#x2013;2), 85&#x2013;92. 10.1016/j.cis.2011.05.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cis.2011.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21640320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao Y (2010) Nanofluids: Stability, phase diagram, rheology and applications. Particuology 8(6), 549&#x2013;555. 10.1016/j.partic.2010.08.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.partic.2010.08.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor MJ, Bailes JE, Elrifai AM, Shih SR, Teeple E, Leavitt ML, Baust JG and Maroon JC (1995) A new solution for life without blood. Asanguineous low-flow perfusion of a whole-body perfusate during 3 hours of cardiac arrest and profound hypothermia. Circulation 91(2), 431&#x2013;444. 10.1161/01.cir.91.2.431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.cir.91.2.431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7805248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinogradova OI, Bunkin NV, Churaev NV, Kiseleva OA, Lobeyev AV and Ninham BW (1995) Submicrocavity structure of water between hydrophobic and hydrophilic walls as revealed by optical cavitation. Journal of Colloid and Interface Science 173(2), 443&#x2013;447. 10.1006/jcis.1995.1345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jcis.1995.1345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Carbon dioxide bubbles destroy viruses and bacteria: CO2 a saint not sinner</Title><Reference><Citation>Adams MH (1948) Surface inactivation of bacterial viruses and of proteins. The Journal of General Physiology 31(5), 417&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2147118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18917025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arkill KP, Knupp C, Michel CC, Neal CR, Qvortrup K, Rostgaard J and Squire JM (2011) Similar endothelial glycocalyx structures in microvessels from a range of mammalian tissues: Evidence for a common filtering mechanism? Biophysical Journal 101(5), 1046&#x2013;1056. 10.1016/j.bpj.2011.07.036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpj.2011.07.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3164174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21889441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunkin NF, Shkirin AV, Ninham BW, Chirikov SN, Chaikov LL, Penkov NV, Kozlov VA and Gudkov SV (2020) Shaking-induced aggregation and flotation in immunoglobulin. Dispersions: Differences between water and water&#x2212;ethanol mixtures. ACS Omega 5, 14689&#x2013;14701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7315612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32596606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Betany AMM, Behiry E, Gumbleton M and Harding K (2020) Humidified warmed CO2 treatment therapy strategies can save lives with mitigation and suppression of SARS-CoV-2 infection: An evidence review. Frontiers in Medicine 7, 594295. 10.3389/fmed.2020.594295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2020.594295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7793941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33425942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Z, Wang X, Zhou L, Zhang L and Hu J (2020) Formation and stability of bulk nanobubbles by vibration. Langmuir 36, 2264&#x2013;2270. 10.1021/acs.langmuir.0c00036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.0c00036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32093475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrido A, Pashley RM and Ninham BW (2016) Low temperature MS2 (ATCC15597-B1) virus inactivation using a hot bubble column evaporator (HBCE). Colloids and Surfaces. B, Biointerfaces 151, 1&#x2013;10. 10.1016/j.colsurfb.2016.11.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfb.2016.11.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27930923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrido A, Pashley RM and Ninham BW (2018) Water sterilisation using different hot gases in a bubble column reactor. Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering 6, 2651&#x2013;2659. 10.1016/j.jece.2018.04.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2018.04.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrido AS and Jin L (2020) Evaluation of the new energy-efficient hot bubble pilot plant (HBPP) for water sterilization from the livestock farming industry. Water Resources and Industry 24, 100135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudkov SV, Lyakhov GA, Pustovoy VI and Shcherbakov IA (2019) Influence of mechanical effects on the hydrogen peroxide concentration in aqueous solutions. Physics of Wave Phenomenon 27, 141&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karaman ME, Ninham BW and Pashley RM (1996) Effects of dissolved gas on emulsions, emulsion polymerization, and surfactant aggregation. Journal of Physical Chemistry 100(38), 15503&#x2013;15507. 10.1021/jp960758y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp960758y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H-K, Tuite E, Nord&#xe9;n B and Ninham BW (2001) Co-ion dependence of DNA nuclease activity suggests hydrophobic cavitation as a potential source of activation energy. European Physical Journal E: Soft Matter 4(4), 411&#x2013;417. 10.1007/s101890170096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s101890170096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JK, Walker KL, Han HS, Kang J, Prinz FB, Waymouth RM, Nam HG and Zare RN (2019) Spontaneous generation of hydrogen peroxide from aqueous microdroplets. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 116, 19294&#x2013;19298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6765303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31451646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Queisser KA, Mellema RA, Middleton EA, Portier I, Manne BK, Denorme F, Beswick EJ, Rondina MT, Campbell RA and Petrey AC (2021) COVID-19 generates hyaluronan fragments that directly induce endothelial barrier dysfunction. JCI Insight 6, e147472. 10.1172/jci.insight.147472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci.insight.147472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8492325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34314391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Chemical reactions, enzyme action, nanobubbles</Title><Reference><Citation>Allen M, Evans DF, Mitchell DJ and Ninham BW (1987) Interfacial tension of ionic microemulsions. Journal of Physical Chemistry 91(9), 2320&#x2013;2324. 10.1021/j100293a022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/j100293a022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans DF, Mitchell DJ and Ninham BW (1986) Oil, water, and surfactant: Properties and conjectured structure of simple microemulsions. The Journal of Physical Chemistry 90(13), 2817&#x2013;2825. 10.1021/j100404a009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/j100404a009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng B, Sosa RP, M&#xe5;rtensson AKF, Jiang K, Tong A, Dorfman KD, Takahashi M, Lincoln P, Bustamante CJ, Westerlund F and Nord&#xe9;n B (2019) Hydrophobic catalysis and a potential biological role of DNA unstacking induced by environment effects. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 116, 17169&#x2013;17174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6717297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31413203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knackstedt MA and Ninham BW (1994) Model disorder media for ternary microemulsions. Physical Review E 50, 2839&#x2013;2843. 10.1103/PhysRevE.50.2839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevE.50.2839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9962323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knackstedt MA and Ninham BW (1995) Ternary microemulsions as model disordered media. AICHE Journal 41(5), 1295&#x2013;1305. 10.1002/aic.690410524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aic.690410524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell DJ and Ninham BW (1981) Micelles, vesicles and microemulsions. Journal of the Chemical Society, Faraday Transactions II 77(4), 601&#x2013;629. 10.1039/F29817700601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/F29817700601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW, Barnes IS, Hyde ST, Derian P-J and Zemb TN (1987) Random connected cylinders: A new structure in three component microemulsions. Europhysics Letters 4(5), 561&#x2013;568. 10.1209/0295-5075/4/5/009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1209/0295-5075/4/5/009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pingoud A and Jeltsch A (2001) Structure and function of type II restriction endonucleases. Nucleic Acids Research 29(18), 3705&#x2013;3727. 10.1093/nar/29.18.3705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/29.18.3705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC55916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11557805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zemb TN, Hyde ST, Derian P-J, Barnes IS and Ninham BW (1987) Microstructure from X-ray scattering: The disordered open connected model of microemulsions. Journal of Physical Chemistry 91(14), 3814&#x2013;3820. 10.1021/j100298a018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/j100298a018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Lung surfactant structure: Self-assembly of lipids</Title><Reference><Citation>Alfredsson V, Lo Nostro P, Ninham BW and Nylander T (2021) Morphologies and structure of brain lipid membrane dispersions. Frontiers in Cell and Developmental Biology 9, 675140. 10.3389/fcell.2021.675140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcell.2021.675140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8236638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34195192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangham AD (1995) Surface tension in the lungs. Biophysical Journal
68, 1630&#x2013;1633. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1282060/pdf/biophysj00063-0429.pdf.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1282059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7787049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangham D, Morley CJ and Phillips MC (1979) The physical properties of an effective lung surfactant. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta (BBA) 573(3), 552&#x2013;556. 10.1016/0005-2760(79)90229-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0005-2760(79)90229-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">582419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Follows D, Tiberg F, Thomas RK and Larsson M (2007) Multilayers at the surface of solutions of exogenous lung surfactant: Direct observation by neutron reflection. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta 1768, 228&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17156743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gershfeld NL (1989) The critical unilamellar lipid state: A perspective for membrane bilayer assembly. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta 988, 335. 10.1016/0304-4157(89)90009-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0304-4157(89)90009-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2686756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gershfeld NL (1989) Thermodynamics of phospholipid bilayer assembly. Biochemistry 28(10), 4229&#x2013;4232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2765483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene KE, King TE Jr, Kuroki Y, Bucher-Bartelson B, Hunninghake GW, Newman LS, Nagae H and Mason RJ Serum surfactant proteins-A and -D as biomarkers in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. European Respiratory Journal 19, 439&#x2013;446. 10.1183/09031936.02.00081102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.02.00081102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11936520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninham BW and Evans DF (1986) The Rideal lecture: Vesicles and molecular forces. Faraday Discussion Chemical Society 81(1), 1&#x2013;17. 10.1039/DC9868100001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/DC9868100001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorensen GL (2018) Surfactant protein D in respiratory and non-respiratory diseases. Frontiers in Medicine 5, 18. 10.3389/fmed.2018.00018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2018.00018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5809447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29473039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>The real lung surfactant &#x2013; Structure and machinery</Title><Reference><Citation>Almsherqi ZA (2021) Potential role of plasmalogens in the modulation of biomembrane morphology. Frontiers in Cell and Developmental Biology 9, 673917. 10.3389/fcell.2021.673917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcell.2021.673917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8335397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34368127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelova A, Angelov B, Drechsler M, Bizien T, Gorshkova YE and Deng Y (2021) Plasmalogen-based liquid crystalline multiphase structures involving Docosapentaenoyl derivatives inspired by biological cubic membranes. Frontiers in Cell and Developmental Biology 9, 617984. 10.3389/fcell.2021.617984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcell.2021.617984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7905036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33644054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashman RB, Blanden RV, Ninham BW and Evans DF (1986) Interaction of amphiphilic aggregates with cells of the immune system. Immunology Today 7(9), 278&#x2013;283. 10.1016/0167-5699(86)90010-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0167-5699(86)90010-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25290632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashman RB and Ninham BW (1985) Immunosuppressive effects of cationic vesicles. Molecular Immunology 22(5), 609&#x2013;612. 10.1016/0161-5890(85)90185-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0161-5890(85)90185-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3160932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball JM, Chen S and Li W (2022) Mitochondria in cone photoreceptors act as microlenses to enhance photon delivery and confer directional sensitivity to light. Science Advances 8(9), eabn2070. 10.1126/sciadv.abn2070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.abn2070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8890704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35235359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopfer H, Herzig MC, Gosert R, Menter T, Hench J, Tzankov A, Hirsch HH and Miller SE (2021) Hunting coronavirus by transmission electron microscopy&#x2014;A guide to SARS-CoV-2-associated ultrastructural pathology in COVID-19 tissues. Histopathology 78(3), 358&#x2013;370. 10.1111/his.14264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/his.14264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32981112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson BA, Xie X, Kalveram B, Lokugamage KG, Muruato A, Zou J, Zhang X, Juelich T, Smith JK, Zhang L, Bopp N, Schindewolf C, Vu M, Vanderheiden A, Swetnam D, Plante JA, Aguilar P, Plante KS, Lee B, Weaver SC and Menachery VD (2020). Furin cleavage site is key to SARS-CoV-2 pathogenesis. bioRxiv. 10.1101/2020.08.26.268854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.08.26.268854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8175039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33494095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leu A (2020) https://www.organicconsumers.org/blog/covid-19-spike-and-furin-cleavage.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker JL, Christenson HK and Ninham BW (1988) Forces between bilayers of a cationic surfactant with hydroxylated headgroups: Effects of interbilayer adhesion on the interactions. Journal of Physical Chemistry 92(14), 4155&#x2013;4159. 10.1021/j100325a032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/j100325a032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pashley RM, McGuiggan PM, Ninham BW, Brady J and Evans DF (1986) Direct measurements of surface forces between bilayers of double-chained quaternary ammonium acetate and bromide surfactants. Journal of Physical Chemistry 90(8), 1637&#x2013;1642. 10.1021/j100399a037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/j100399a037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peacock TP, Goldhill DH, Zhou J, Baillon L, Frise R, Swann OC, Kugathasan R, Penn R, Brown JC, Sanchez-David RY, Braga L, Williamson MK, Hassard JA, Staller E, Hanley B, Osborn M, Giacca M, Davidson AD, Matthews DA and Barclay WS (2021) The furin cleavage site in the SARS-CoV-2 spike protein is required for transmission in ferrets. Nature Microbiology 6, 899&#x2013;909. 10.1038/s41564-021-00908-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41564-021-00908-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33907312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuben AD and Harris AR (2004) Heliox for asthma in the emergency department: A review of the literature. Emergency Medicine Journal (EMJ) 21(2), 131&#x2013;135. 10.1136/emj.2002.003483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/emj.2002.003483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1726290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14988333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safaee Fakhr B, Di Fenza R, Gianni S, Wiegand SB, Miyazaki Y, Araujo Morais CC, Gibson LE, Chang MG, Mueller AL, Rodriguez-Lopez JM, Ackman JB, Arora P, Scott LK, Bloch DB, Zapol WM, Carroll RW, Ichinose F, Berra L and Investigators NOS (2021) Inhaled high dose nitric oxide is a safe and effective respiratory treatment in spontaneous breathing hospitalized patients with COVID-19 pneumonia. Nitric Oxide: Biology and Chemistry 116, 7&#x2013;13. 10.1016/j.niox.2021.08.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.niox.2021.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8361002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34400339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanderson RJ and Vatter AE (1977) A mode of formation of tubular myelin from lamellar bodies in the lung. The Journal of Cell Biology 74, 1027&#x2013;1031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2110109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">903368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli EM (1998) The alveolar surface network: A new anatomy and its physiological significance. The Anatomical Record 251(4), 491&#x2013;527. 10.1002/(SICI)1097-0185(199808)251:4&lt;491:AID-AR8&gt;3.0.CO;2-V.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1097-0185(199808)251:4&lt;491:AID-AR8&gt;3.0.CO;2-V</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9713987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei R, Pashley R and The M (2020) &#x201c;Molecule diode&#x201d; effect caused by adsorbed surfactant layers improves evaporation efficiency in the bubble column evaporator (BCE) for seawater desalination. Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering 8(5), 104303. 10.1016/j.jece.2020.104303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2020.104303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y and Zhao S (2021) Furin cleavage sites naturally occur in coronaviruses. Stem Cell Research 50, 102115. 10.1016/j.scr.2020.102115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scr.2020.102115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33340798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young SL, Fram EK and Larsson EW (1992) Three-dimensional reconstruction of tubular myelin. Experimental Lung Research 18, 497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1516569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuo R, Rong P, Wang J, Parvin R and Deng Y (2021) The potential role of bioactive plasmalogens in lung surfactant. Frontiers in Cell and Developmental Biology 9, 618102. 10.3389/fcell.2021.618102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcell.2021.618102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7928286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33681198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou W, Xiong M, Hao S, Zhang EY, Baumlin N, Kim MD, Salathe M, Yan Z and Qiu J (2021) The SARS-CoV-2 transcriptome and the dynamics of the S Gene Furin cleavage site in primary human airway epithelia. mBio 12(3), e01006&#x2013;e01021. 10.1128/mBio.01006-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/mBio.01006-21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8262919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33975939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>