<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39150062</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-7072</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in critical care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Crit Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Implications of frailty before and after intensive care unit admission.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>472</StartPage><EndPage>478</EndPage><MedlinePgn>472-478</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCC.0000000000001197</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">In the decade since the first publications related to frailty in those with critical illness, the study of frailty has rapidly increased. The purpose of this review is to update the reader on recent advances across several important areas of frailty research: how best to identify frailty in those with critical illness, studies describing the relationship between frailty and delirium, and how frailty affects outcomes for those with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), which, despite rates and severity of acute infection declining, still tremendously impacts patients long after the acute infection, resulting in symptoms of long COVID-19.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A number of frailty assessment tools exist, to date, the Clinical Frailty Scale based on the deficit accumulation approach to defining frailty, is the most commonly used in ICU studies. Several novel frailty instruments for the ICU are being developed. Because tools assessing frailty by the phenotypic and deficit accumulation approaches identify different populations, careful choice of a frailty assessment tool is warranted.Frailty and delirium are hypothesized to represent different clinical expressions of a similar underlying vulnerability, thus identifying frailty may be a useful means by which to identify patients at high risk of becoming delirious. Recent studies show that frailty at ICU admission is a predictor of the development of delirium.Finally, frailty and its outcomes were studied in patients with COVID-19. As with other causes of critical illness, frailty was highly prevalent in those admitted to the ICU and is associated with greater mortality. Frailty was also associated with increased decisions to limit life support treatments, but these decisions were not different among those admitted with COVID-19 or for other reasons.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Frailty in those with critical illness is an emerging field of study. Future work to define the optimal means by which to identify this syndrome and how best to manage critically ill patients with frailty are needed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gordon</LastName><ForeName>Joshua I</ForeName><Initials>JI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Pulmonary, Critical Care, and Sleep Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for the Advancement of Team Science, Analytics, and Systems Thinking in Health Services and Implementation Science Research (CATALYST).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brummel</LastName><ForeName>Nathan E</ForeName><Initials>NE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Pulmonary, Critical Care, and Sleep Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for the Advancement of Team Science, Analytics, and Systems Thinking in Health Services and Implementation Science Research (CATALYST).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Davis Heart and Lung Research Institute, College of Medicine, The Ohio State University College of Medicine, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Crit Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9504454</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1070-5295</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007362" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intensive Care Units</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073496" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frailty</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003693" MajorTopicYN="Y">Delirium</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016638" MajorTopicYN="Y">Critical Illness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016330" MajorTopicYN="N">Frail Elderly</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015577" MajorTopicYN="N">Geriatric Assessment</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39150062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCC.0000000000001197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00075198-990000000-00201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Brummel NE. Measuring outcomes after critical illness. Crit Care Clin 2018; 34:515&#x2013;526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morley JE, Vellas B, van Kan GA, et al. Frailty consensus: a call to action. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2013; 14:392&#x2013;397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walston J, Hadley EC, Ferrucci L, et al. Research agenda for frailty in older adults: toward a better understanding of physiology and etiology: summary from the American Geriatrics Society/National Institute on Aging Research Conference on Frailty in Older Adults. J Am Geriatr Soc 2006; 54:991&#x2013;1001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobert J, Jeon SY, Boscardin J, et al. Trends in geriatric conditions among older adults admitted to US ICUs between 1998 and. Chest 2022; 161:1555&#x2013;1565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscedere J, Waters B, Varambally A, et al. The impact of frailty on intensive care unit outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Intensive Care Med 2017; 43:1105&#x2013;1122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagshaw SM, Stelfox HT, McDermid RC, et al. Association between frailty and short- and long-term outcomes among critically ill patients: a multicentre prospective cohort study. CMAJ 2014; 186:E95&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrante LE, Pisani MA, Murphy TE, et al. The association of frailty with post-ICU disability, nursing home admission, and mortality: a longitudinal study. Chest 2018; 153:1378&#x2013;1386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brummel NE, Bell SP, Girard TD, et al. Frailty and subsequent disability and mortality among patients with critical illness. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2017; 196:64&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brummel NE, Girard TD, Pandharipande PP, et al. Prevalence and course of frailty in survivors of critical illness. Crit Care Med 2020; 48:1419&#x2013;1426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geense W, Zegers M, Dieperink P, et al. Changes in frailty among ICU survivors and associated factors: results of a one-year prospective cohort study using the Dutch Clinical Frailty Scale. J Crit Care 2020; 55:184&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson TN, Walston JD, Brummel NE, et al. Frailty for surgeons: review of a national institute on aging conference on frailty for specialists. J Am Coll Surg 2015; 221:1083&#x2013;1092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fried LP, Tangen CM, Walston J, et al. Frailty in older adults: evidence for a phenotype. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2001; 56:M146&#x2013;M156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rockwood K, Mitnitski A. Frailty in relation to the accumulation of deficits. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2007; 62:722&#x2013;727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitnitski AB, Mogilner AJ, Rockwood K. Accumulation of deficits as a proxy measure of aging. ScientificWorldJournal 2001; 1:323&#x2013;336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vries NM, Staal JB, van Ravensberg CD, et al. Outcome instruments to measure frailty: a systematic review. Ageing Res Rev 2011; 10:104&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clegg A, Young J, Iliffe S, et al. Frailty in elderly people. Lancet 2013; 381:752&#x2013;762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buta BJ, Walston JD, Godino JG, et al. Frailty assessment instruments: systematic characterization of the uses and contexts of highly-cited instruments. Ageing Res Rev 2016; 26:53&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertschi D, Waskowski J, Schilling M, et al. Methods of assessing frailty in the critically ill: a systematic review of the current literature. Gerontology 2022; 68:1321&#x2013;1349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee ZY, Hasan MS, Day AG, et al. Initial development and validation of a novel nutrition risk, sarcopenia, and frailty assessment tool in mechanically ventilated critically ill patients: the NUTRIC-SF score. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr 2022; 46:499&#x2013;507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Er B, Mizrak B, Aydemir A, et al. Association of nutritional status, frailty, and rectus femoris muscle thickness measured by ultrasound and weaning in critically ill elderly patients. Tuberk Toraks 2023; 71:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Detsky ME, Shin S, Fralick M, et al. Using the Hospital Frailty Risk Score to assess mortality risk in older medical patients admitted to the intensive care unit. CMAJ Open 2023; 11:E607&#x2013;E614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao B, Xu W, Gao W, et al. Association between frailty assessed using two electronic medical record-based frailty assessment tools and long-term adverse prognosis in older critically ill survivors. J Nutr Health Aging 2023; 27:649&#x2013;655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue QL, Tian J, Walston JD, et al. Discrepancy in frailty identification: move beyond predictive validity. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2020; 75:387&#x2013;393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinlan N, Marcantonio ER, Inouye SK, et al. Vulnerability: the crossroads of frailty and delirium. J Am Geriatr Soc 2011; 59: (Suppl 2): S262&#x2013;S268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persico I, Cesari M, Morandi A, et al. Frailty and delirium in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of the literature. J Am Geriatr Soc 2018; 66:2022&#x2013;2030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verloo H, Goulet C, Morin D, von Gunten A. Association between frailty and delirium in older adult patients discharged from hospital. Clin Interv Aging 2016; 11:55&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahle BW, Pilcher D, Litton E, et al. Association between frailty, delirium, and mortality in older critically ill patients: a binational registry study. Ann Intensive Care 2022; 12:108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell C, Verghese J, Gong MN, et al. Frailty, acute brain dysfunction, and posthospitalization disability outcomes in critically ill older adults. Am J Crit Care 2023; 32:256&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Heijden EFM, Kooken RWJ, Zegers M, et al. Differences in long-term outcomes between ICU patients with persistent delirium, nonpersistent delirium and no delirium: a longitudinal cohort study. J Crit Care 2023; 76:154277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandharipande PP, Girard TD, Jackson JC, et al. Long-term cognitive impairment after critical illness. N Engl J Med 2013; 369:1306&#x2013;1316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brummel NE, Jackson JC, Pandharipande PP, et al. Delirium in the ICU and subsequent long-term disability among survivors of mechanical ventilation. Crit Care Med 2014; 42:369&#x2013;377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo R, Zhang S, Yu S, et al. Inclusion of frailty improved performance of delirium prediction for elderly patients in the cardiac intensive care unit (D-FRAIL): a prospective derivation and external validation study. Int J Nurs Stud 2023; 147:104582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost SA, Brennan K, Sanchez D, et al. Frailty in the prediction of delirium in the intensive care unit: a secondary analysis of the Deli study. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand 2024; 68:214&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Boogaard M, Pickkers P, Slooter AJ, et al. Development and validation of PRE-DELIRIC (PREdiction of DELIRium in ICu patients) delirium prediction model for intensive care patients: observational multicentre study. BMJ 2012; 344:e420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobo-Valbuena B, Molina R, Castaneda-Vozmediano R, et al. Functional independence, frailty and perceived quality of life in patients who developed delirium during ICU stay: a prospective cohort study. Eur J Med Res 2023; 28:560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson DJC. Frailty triage: is rationing intensive medical treatment on the grounds of frailty ethical? Am J Bioeth 2021; 21:48&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lengele L, Locquet M, Moutschen M, et al. Frailty but not sarcopenia nor malnutrition increases the risk of developing COVID-19 in older community-dwelling adults. Aging Clin Exp Res 2022; 34:223&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammel IS, Tosi DM, Tang F, et al. Frailty as a risk factor for postacute sequelae of COVID-19 among US veterans during the Delta and Omicron waves. J Am Geriatr Soc 2023; 71:3826&#x2013;3835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattsson G, Gonzalez Lindh M, Razmi R, et al. Clinical frailty scale as a predictor of disease severity in patients hospitalised with COVID-19 &#x2013; an observational cohort study. Infect Dis (Lond) 2022; 54:583&#x2013;590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones MR, Subbe CP, Thorpe C, Pickwick C. Frailty status and outcomes of COVID-19 patients admitted to an intensive care unit. J Frailty Aging 2022; 11:242&#x2013;243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung C, Flaatten H, Fjolner J, et al. The impact of frailty on survival in elderly intensive care patients with COVID-19: the COVIP study. Crit Care 2021; 25:149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernly B, Flaatten H, Leaver S, et al. The clinical frailty scale, but not the FRAIL checklist is associated with mortality in old critically ill patients with COVID-19. Crit Care 2023; 27:101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramaniam A, Tiruvoipati R, Pilcher D, Bailey M. Treatment limitations and clinical outcomes in critically ill frail patients with and without COVID-19 pneumonitis. J Am Geriatr Soc 2023; 71:145&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taniguchi LU, Avelino-Silva TJ, Dias MB, et al. Patient-centered outcomes following COVID-19: frailty and disability transitions in critical care survivors. Crit Care Med 2022; 50:955&#x2013;963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taniguchi LU, Aliberti MJR, Dias MB, et al. Twelve months and counting: following clinical outcomes in critical COVID-19 survivors. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2023; 20:289&#x2013;295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley HJC, Evans RA, Bolton CE, et al. Prevalence of physical frailty, including risk factors, up to 1&#x200a;year after hospitalisation for COVID-19 in the UK: a multicentre, longitudinal cohort study. EClinicalMedicine 2023; 57:101896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adjaye-Gbewonyo D, Vahratian A, Perrine CG, Bertolli J. Long COVID in adults: United States, 2022. NCHS Data Brief No 480: US Department of Health and Human Services, National Center for Health Statistics, CDC; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastie CE, Lowe DJ, McAuley A, et al. True prevalence of long-COVID in a nationwide, population cohort study. Nat Commun 2023; 14:7892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddocks M, Brighton LJ, Alison JA, et al. Rehabilitation for people with respiratory disease and frailty: an official American Thoracic Society Workshop Report. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2023; 20:767&#x2013;780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscedere J, Bagshaw SM, Kho M, et al. Frailty, outcomes, recovery and care steps of critically ill patients (FORECAST): a prospective, multicentre, cohort study. Intensive Care Med 2024; 50:1064&#x2013;1074.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>