<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34918437</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Relationship between COVID-19 and movement disorders: A narrative review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1243</StartPage><EndPage>1253</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1243-1253</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15217</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">The scientific literature on COVID-19 is increasingly growing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this paper, we review the literature on movement disorders in the context of the COVID-19 pandemic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">First, there are a variety of transient movement disorders that may manifest in the acute phase of COVID-19, most often myoclonus, with more than 50 patients described in the literature. New onset parkinsonism, chorea, and tic-like behaviours have also been reported. Movement disorders as a side effect after COVID-19 vaccination are rare, occurring with a frequency of 0.00002-0.0002 depending on the product used, mostly manifesting with tremor. Current evidence for potential long-term manifestations, for example, long COVID parkinsonism, is separately discussed. Second, the pandemic has also had an impact on patients with pre-existing movement disorder syndromes, with negative effects on clinical status and overall well-being, and reduced access to medication and health care. In many parts, the pandemic has led to reorganization of the medical system, including the development of new digital solutions. The movement disorder-related evidence for this is reviewed and discussed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The pandemic and the associated preventive measures have had a negative impact on the clinical status, access to health care, and overall well-being of patients with pre-existing movement disorders.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schneider</LastName><ForeName>Susanne A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7283-1995</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ludwig Maximilian University, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hennig</LastName><ForeName>Anita</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ludwig Maximilian University, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martino</LastName><ForeName>Davide</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2217-0487</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Calgary and Hotchkiss Brain Institute, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000086663">COVID-19 Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086663" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009069" MajorTopicYN="Y">Movement Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sars-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spanish flu</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chorea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dystonia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myoclonus ataxia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">parkinsonism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postencephalitic parkinsonism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tic-like behaviour</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccine</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34918437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Karuppan MKM, Devadoss D, Nair M, Chand HS, Lakshmana MK. SARS-CoV-2 infection in the central and peripheral nervous system-associated morbidities and their potential mechanism. Mol Neurobiol. 2021;58(6):2465-2480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson RW, Brown RL, Benjamin L, et al. The emerging spectrum of COVID-19 neurology: clinical, radiological and laboratory findings. Brain. 2020;143:3104-3120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M, et al. Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:683-690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maury A, Lyoubi A, Peiffer-Smadja N, de Broucker T, Meppiel E. Neurological manifestations associated with SARS-CoV-2 and other coronaviruses: a narrative review for clinicians. Rev Neurol (Paris). 2021;177:51-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416-427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan JL, Murphy KA, Sarna JR. Myoclonus and cerebellar ataxia associated with COVID-19: a case report and systematic review. J Neurol. 2021;268(10):3517-3548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muccioli L, Rondelli F, Ferri L, Rossini G, Cortelli P, Guarino M. Subcortical myoclonus in COVID-19: comprehensive evaluation of a patient. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2020;7:971-973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabano-Suarez P, Bermejo-Guerrero L, Mendez-Guerrero A, et al. Generalized myoclonus in COVID-19. Neurology. 2020;95:e767-e772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borroni B, Gazzina S, Dono F, et al. Diaphragmatic myoclonus due to SARS-CoV-2 infection. Neurol Sci. 2020;41:3471-3474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schellekens MMI, Bleeker-Rovers CP, Keurlings PAJ, Mummery CJ, Bloem BR. Reversible Myoclonus-Ataxia as a postinfectious manifestation of COVID-19. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2020;7:977-979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendez-Guerrero A, Laespada-Garcia MI, Gomez-Grande A, et al. Acute hypokinetic-rigid syndrome following SARS-CoV-2 infection. Neurology. 2020;95:e2109-e2118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Otmani H, Moutaouakil F, Ouazzani M, Mjahed K. Isolated generalized myoclonus immune-mediated by SARS-CoV-2: an illustrative videotaped case. Neurol Sci. 2021;42(8):3411-3413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dijkstra F, Van den Bossche T, Willekens B, Cras P, Crosiers D. Myoclonus and cerebellar ataxia following Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2020;7:974-976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah PB, Desai SD. Opsoclonus myoclonus ataxia syndrome in the setting of COVID-19 infection. Neurology. 2021;96:33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaumont H, San-Galli A, Martino F, et al. Mixed central and peripheral nervous system disorders in severe SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Neurol. 2020;267:3121-3127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann KM, Harmel J, Wojtecki L. CORE-myoclonus syndrome: a proposed neurological initial manifestation of COVID-19. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2021;8:637-638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimaldi S, Lagarde S, Harle JR, Boucraut J, Guedj E. Autoimmune encephalitis concomitant with SARS-CoV-2 infection: insight from (18)F-FDG PET imaging and neuronal autoantibodies. J Nucl Med. 2020;61:1726-1729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuhna P, Herlin B, Vassilev K, et al. Movement disorders as a new neurological clinical picture in severe SARS-CoV-2 infection. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27:e88-e90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ros-Castello V, Quereda C, Lopez-Sendon J, Corral I. Post-hypoxic myoclonus after COVID-19 infection recovery. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2020;7:983-984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anand P, Zakaria A, Benameur K, et al. Myoclonus in patients with coronavirus disease 2019: a multicenter case series. Crit Care Med. 2020;48:1664-1669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han PK, Arnold R, Bond G, Janson D, Abu-Elmagd K. Myoclonus secondary to withdrawal from transdermal fentanyl: case report and literature review. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2002;23:66-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tam MK, Irwin MG, Tse ML, Lui YW, Law KI, Ng PW. Prolonged myoclonus after a single bolus dose of propofol. Anaesthesia. 2009;64:1254-1257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mas Serrano M, Perez-Sanchez JR, Portela Sanchez S, et al. Serotonin syndrome in two COVID-19 patients treated with lopinavir/ritonavir. J Neurol Sci. 2020;415:116944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latorre A, Rothwell JC. Myoclonus and COVID-19: a challenge for the present, a lesson for the future. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2020;7:888-890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Han Y, Nilsson-Payant BE, et al. A human pluripotent stem cell-based platform to study SARS-CoV-2 tropism and model virus infection in human cells and organoids. Cell Stem Cell. 2020;27:125-136 e127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brundin P, Nath A, Beckham JD. Is COVID-19 a perfect storm for Parkinson's disease? Trends Neurosci. 2020;43(12):931-933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Sarraj S, Troakes C, Hanley B, et al. Invited review: the spectrum of neuropathology in COVID-19. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol. 2021;47:3-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fishman PS, Gass JS, Swoveland PT, Lavi E, Highkin MK, Weiss SR. Infection of the basal ganglia by a murine coronavirus. Science. 1985;229:877-879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iadecola C, Anrather J, Kamel H. Effects of COVID-19 on the nervous system. Cell. 2020;183:16-27 e11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen ME, Eichel R, Steiner-Birmanns B, et al. A case of probable Parkinson's disease after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19:804-805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rass V, Beer R, Josef Schiefecker A, et al. Neurological outcome and quality of life three months after COVID-19: a prospective observational cohort study. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28:3348-3359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domingues R, Lippi A, Setz C, Outeiro TF, Krisko A. SARS-CoV-2, immunosenescence and inflammaging: partners in the COVID-19 crime. Aging (Albany NY). 2020;12:18778-18789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beauchamp LC, Finkelstein DI, Bush AI, Evans AH, Barnham KJ. Parkinsonism as a third wave of the COVID-19 pandemic? J Parkinsons Dis. 2020;10(4):1343-1353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbour N, Cote G, Lachance C, Tardieu M, Cashman NR, Talbot PJ. Acute and persistent infection of human neural cell lines by human coronavirus OC43. J Virol. 1999;73:3338-3350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boika AV. A post-COVID-19 Parkinsonism in the future? Mov Disord. 2020;35:1094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi A, Domingues R, Setz C, Outeiro TF, Krisko A. SARS-CoV-2: at the crossroad between aging and neurodegeneration. Mov Disord. 2020;35:716-720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carfi A, Bernabei R, Landi F, Gemelli Against C-P-ACSG. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603-605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philippens IB, B&#xf6;sz&#xf6;rm&#xe9;nyi KP, Wubben JA et al. SARS-CoV-2 causes brain inflammation 1 and induces Lewy body formation in macaques. bioRxiv Preprint. 2021. 10.1101/2021.02.23.432474</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid AH, McCall S, Henry JM, Taubenberger JK. Experimenting on the past: the enigma of von Economo's encephalitis lethargica. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2001;60:663-670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo KC, Geddes JF, Daniels RS, Oxford JS. Lack of detection of influenza genes in archived formalin-fixed, paraffin wax-embedded brain samples of encephalitis lethargica patients from 1916 to 1920. Virchows Arch. 2003;442:591-596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langston JW, Forno LS, Tetrud J, Reeves AG, Kaplan JA, Karluk D. Evidence of active nerve cell degeneration in the substantia nigra of humans years after 1-methyl-4-phenyl-1,2,3,6-tetrahydropyridine exposure. Ann Neurol. 1999;46:598-605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang H, Boltz DA, Webster RG, Smeyne RJ. Viral parkinsonism. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2009;1792:714-721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulop T, Witkowski JM, Olivieri F, Larbi A. The integration of inflammaging in age-related diseases. Semin Immunol. 2018;40:17-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surmeier DJ, Obeso JA, Halliday GM. Selective neuronal vulnerability in Parkinson disease. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2017;18:101-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woulfe J, Hoogendoorn H, Tarnopolsky M, Mu&#xf1;oz DG. Monoclonal antibodies against Epstein-Barr virus cross-react with &#x3b1;-synuclein in human brain. Neurology. 2000;55:1398-1440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wouk J, Rechenchoski DZ, Rodrigues BCD, Ribelato EV, Faccin-Galhardi LC. Viral infections and their relationship to neurological disorders. Arch Virol. 2021;166:733-753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butowt R, von Bartheld CS. Anosmia in COVID-19: underlying mechanisms and assessment of an olfactory route to brain infection. Neuroscientist. 2020;27:1073858420956905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa K, Carnauba ATL, Rocha KW, Andrade KCL, Ferreira SMS, Menezes PL. Olfactory and taste disorders in COVID-19: a systematic review. Braz J Otorhinolaryngol. 2020;86:781-792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechien JR, Chiesa-Estomba CM, De Siati DR, et al. Olfactory and gustatory dysfunctions as a clinical presentation of mild-to-moderate forms of the coronavirus disease (COVID-19): a multicenter European study. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2020;277:2251-2261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Politi LS, Salsano E, Grimaldi M. Magnetic resonance imaging alteration of the brain in a patient with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) and Anosmia. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:1028-1029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rethinavel HS, Ravichandran S, Radhakrishnan RK, Kandasamy M. COVID-19 and Parkinson's disease: defects in neurogenesis as the potential cause of olfactory system impairments and anosmia. J Chem Neuroanat. 2021;115:101965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JG, Cui HR, Tang HB, Deng XL. Gastrointestinal symptoms and fecal nucleic acid testing of children with 2019 coronavirus disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2020;10:17846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kariyawasam JC, Jayarajah U, Riza R, Abeysuriya V, Seneviratne SL. Gastrointestinal manifestations in COVID-19. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 2021;115:1362-1388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Z, Yang M, Lai CL. Long COVID-19 syndrome: a comprehensive review of its effect on various organ systems and recommendation on rehabilitation plans. Biomedicines. 2021;9:966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postuma RB, Gagnon JF, Pelletier A, Montplaisir J. Prodromal autonomic symptoms and signs in Parkinson's disease and dementia with Lewy bodies. Mov Disord. 2013;28:597-604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travagli RA, Browning KN, Camilleri M. Parkinson disease and the gut: new insights into pathogenesis and clinical relevance. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;17:673-685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo MS, Malsy J, P&#xf6;ttgen J, et al. Frequent neurocognitive deficits after recovery from mild COVID-19. Brain Commun. 2020;2:fcaa205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toniolo S, Di Lorenzo F, Scarioni M, Frederiksen KS, Nobili F. Is the frontal lobe the primary target of SARS-CoV-2? J Alzheimers Dis. 2021;81(1):75-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan M, Syed F, Ali L, et al. Chorea as a presentation of SARS-CoV-2 encephalitis: a clinical case report. J Mov Disord. 2021;14:245-247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray STJ, Abdel-Mannan O, Sa M, et al. Neurological manifestations of SARS-CoV-2 infection in hospitalised children and adolescents in the UK: a prospective national cohort study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2021;5:631-641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyman I, Liang H, Hedderly T. COVID-19 related increase in childhood tics and tic-like attacks. Arch Dis Child. 2021;106:420-421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hull M, Parnes M, Jankovic J. Increased incidence of functional (psychogenic) movement disorders in children and adults amidst the COVID-19 pandemic: a cross-sectional study. Neurol Clin Pract. 2021;11(5):e686-e690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pringsheim T, Ganos C, McGuire JF, et al. Rapid onset functional Tic-Like behaviors in young females during the COVID-19 pandemic. Mov Disord. 2021;36(12):2707-2713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hull M, Parnes M. Tics and TikTok: functional tics spread through social media. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2021;8:1248-1252 (published online).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pringsheim T, Martino D. Rapid onset of functional Tic-Like behaviours in young adults during the COVID-19 pandemic. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28:3805-3808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olvera C, Stebbins GT, Goetz CG, Kompoliti K. TikTok tics: a pandemic within a pandemic. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2021;8:1200-1205 (published online).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller-Vahl KR, Pisarenko A, Jakubovski E, Fremer C. Stop that! It's not Tourette's but a new type of mass sociogenic illness. Brain. 2021;awab316. 10.1093/brain/awab316</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire JF, Bennett SM, Conelea CA, et al. Distinguishing and managing acute-onset complex Tic-like behaviors in adolescence. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2021;60(12):1445-1447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piscitelli D, Perin C, Tremolizzo L, Peroni F, Cerri CG, Cornaggia CM. Functional movement disorders in a patient with COVID-19. Neurol Sci. 2020;41:2343-2344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad S, Holla VV, Neeraja K, et al. Parkinson's disease and COVID-19: perceptions and implications in patients and caregivers. Mov Disord. 2020;35:912-914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalash A, Roushdy T, Essam M, et al. Mental health, physical activity, and quality of life in Parkinson's disease during COVID-19 pandemic. Mov Disord. 2020;35:1097-1099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leavy B, Hagstromer M, Conradsson DM, Franzen E. Physical activity and perceived health in people with Parkinson disease during the first wave of Covid-19 pandemic: a cross-sectional study from Sweden. J Neurol Phys Ther. 2021;45(4):266-272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheong JL, Goh ZHK, Marras C, et al. The impact of COVID-19 on access to Parkinson's disease medication. Mov Disord. 2020;35:2129-2133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buccafusca M, Micali C, Autunno M, Versace AG, Nunnari G, Musumeci O. Favourable course in a cohort of Parkinson's disease patients infected by SARS-CoV-2: a single-centre experience. Neurol Sci. 2021;42:811-816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cilia R, Bonvegna S, Straccia G, et al. Effects of COVID-19 on Parkinson's disease clinical features: a community-based case-control study. Mov Disord. 2020;35:1287-1292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasano A, Elia AE, Dallocchio C, et al. Predictors of COVID-19 outcome in Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2020;78:134-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasano A, Cereda E, Barichella M, et al. COVID-19 in Parkinson's disease patients living in Lombardy, Italy. Mov Disord. 2020;35:1089-1093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonini A, Leta V, Teo J, Chaudhuri KR. Outcome of Parkinson's disease patients affected by COVID-19. Mov Disord. 2020;35:905-908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado C, Parees I, Kurtis MM. Patients' perspective of dystonia symptoms during the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. Mov Disord. 2021;36(7):1485-1486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erbguth F, Lange R. Sensory trick effect in craniofacial dystonia as one of the possible impacts of wearing face masks during the COVID-19 pandemic. Neurol Res Pract. 2021;3:24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conte G, Baglioni V, Valente F, Chiarotti F, Cardona F. Adverse mental health impact of the COVID-19 lockdown in individuals with Tourette syndrome in Italy: an online survey. Front Psychiatry. 2020;11:583744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mataix-Cols D, Ringberg H, Fernandez de la Cruz L. Perceived worsening of Tics in adult patients with Tourette syndrome after the COVID-19 outbreak. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2020;7:725-726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado C, Parees I, Jimenez-Huete A, Kurtis MM. Impact of the coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic on functional movement disorders: lessons from a specialized clinic. Mov Disord. 2020;35:1723-1724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbeddini A, To A, Tayefehchamani Y, Wen C. Potential impact and challenges associated with Parkinson's disease patient care amidst the COVID-19 global pandemic. J Clin Mov Disord. 2020;7:7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg D, Dhamija RK. The challenge of managing Parkinson's disease patients during the COVID-19 pandemic. Ann Indian Acad Neurol. 2020;23:S24-S27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen JJ. Pharmacologic safety concerns in Parkinson's disease: facts and insights. Int J Neurosci. 2011;121(Suppl 2):45-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao MM, Yang WL, Yang FY, et al. Cathepsin L plays a key role in SARS-CoV-2 infection in humans and humanized mice and is a promising target for new drug development. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6:134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieb P, Swiatkiewicz M, Prus K, Rejdak K. Amantadine for COVID-19. J Clin Pharmacol. 2021;61:412-413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artusi CA, Romagnolo A, Ledda C, et al. COVID-19 and Parkinson's disease: what do we know so far? J Parkinsons Dis. 2021;11(2):445-454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aranda-Abreu GE, Aranda-Martinez JD, Araujo R. Use of amantadine in a patient with SARS-CoV-2. J Med Virol. 2021;93:110-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink K, Nitsche A, Neumann M, Grossegesse M, Eisele KH, Danysz W. Amantadine inhibits SARS-CoV-2 in vitro. Viruses. 2021;13:539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Yang L. Underlying mechanisms and candidate drugs for COVID-19 based on the connectivity map database. Front Genet. 2020;11:558557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EudraVigilance European database of suspected adverse drug reactions. www.adrreports.eu [online]. Accessed December 1, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erro R, Buonomo AR, Barone P, Pellecchia MT. Severe dyskinesia after administration of SARS-CoV2 mRNA vaccine in Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord. 2021;36:2219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reijneveld JC, Taphoorn MJ, Hoogenraad TU, van Gijn J. Severe but transient Parkinsonism after tetanus vaccination. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1997;63:258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves RS, Barbosa ER, Scaff M. Postvaccinal Parkinsonism. Mov Disord. 1992;7:178-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenichel GM. Postvaccinal parkinsonism. Mov Disord. 1993;8:253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloem BR, Trenkwalder C, Sanchez-Ferro A, et al. COVID-19 vaccination for persons with Parkinson's disease: light at the end of the tunnel? J Parkinsons Dis. 2021;11:3-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Zhu K, Lin Z, et al. Utility of deep brain stimulation telemedicine for patients with movement disorders during the COVID-19 outbreak in China. Neuromodulation. 2021;24:337-342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfalzer AC, Hale LM, Huitz E, et al. Healthcare delivery and Huntington's disease during the time of COVID-19. J Huntingtons Dis. 2021;10:313-322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erro R, Scannapieco S, Russo M, Picillo M, Barone P. Impact of COVID-19 on neurological patients attending a botulinum toxin service. Neurol Sci. 2021;42:433-435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Hao H, Chen H, Li L. The study on a telemedicine interaction mode for deep brain stimulation postoperative follow-up. Annu Int Conf IEEE Eng Med Biol Soc. 2015;2015:186-189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miele G, Straccia G, Moccia M, et al. Telemedicine in Parkinson's disease: how to ensure patient needs and continuity of care at the time of COVID-19 pandemic. Telemed J E Health. 2020;26:1533-1536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group MTS Telemedicine in your movement disorders practice - a step-by-step guide. [online]. Accessed April 8, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulroy E, Menozzi E, Lees AJ, Lynch T, Lang AE, Bhatia KP. Reply to: "A new day: the role of telemedicine in reshaping care for persons with movement disorders". Mov Disord. 2020;35:1903-1904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li WS, Heng DL, Chia TH, Lim EC, Tan EK. High outpatient attendance during COVID-19 lockdown when patients were given the option to return. Mov Disord. 2020;35:2137-2138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisicaro F, Di Napoli M, Liberto A, et al. Neurological sequelae in patients with COVID-19: a histopathological perspective. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:1415.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>