<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37388279</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2572-9365</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Archives of microbiology &amp; immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arch Microbiol Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID: Complications, Underlying Mechanisms, and Treatment Strategies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>36</StartPage><EndPage>61</EndPage><MedlinePgn>36-61</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Long Covid is one of the most prevalent and puzzling conditions that arose with the Covid pandemic. Covid-19 infection generally resolves within several weeks but some experience new or lingering symptoms. Though there is no formal definition for such lingering symptoms the CDC boadly describes long Covid as persons having a wide range of new, recurring or sustained health issues four or more weeks after first being infected with SARS-CoV2. The WHO defines <i>long Covid</i> as the manifestation of symptoms from a "probable or confirmed" Covid-19 infection that start approximately 3 months after the onset of the acute infection and last for more than 2 months. Numerous studies have looked at the implications of long Covid on various organs. Many specific mechanisms have been proposed for such changes. In this article, we provide an overview of some of the main mechanisms by which long Covid induces end-organ damage proposed in recent research studies. We also review various treatment options, current clinical trials, and other potential therapeutic avenues to control long Covid followed by the information about the effect of vaccination on long Covid. Lastly, we discuss some of the questions and knowledge gaps in the present understanding of long Covid. We believe more studies of the effects long Covid has on quality of life, future health and life expectancy are required to better understand and eventually prevent or treat the disease. We acknowledge the effects of long Covid are not limited to those in this article but as it may affect the health of future offspring and therefore, we deem it important to identify more prognostic and therapeutic targets to control this condition.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zadeh</LastName><ForeName>Farigol Hakem</ForeName><Initials>FH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Research, College of Osteopathic Medicine of the Pacific Western University of Health Sciences, Pomona, California 91766, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilson</LastName><ForeName>Daniel R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Research, College of Osteopathic Medicine of the Pacific Western University of Health Sciences, Pomona, California 91766, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agrawal</LastName><ForeName>Devendra K</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Research, College of Osteopathic Medicine of the Pacific Western University of Health Sciences, Pomona, California 91766, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 HL144125</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 HL147662</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Arch Microbiol Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918451287306676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2572-9365</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain fog</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic fatigue syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long Covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post Covid-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post SARS-CoV2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary fibrosis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37388279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1901771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10310313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re'em Y, et al. Characterizing long Covid in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine 38 (2021): 101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logue JK, Franko NM, McCulloch DJ, McDonald D, Magedson A, Wolf CR, et al. Sequelae in Adults at 6 Months After Covid -19 Infection. JAMA Netw Open 4 (2021): e210830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33606031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callard F. Epidemic Time: Thinking from the Sickbed. Bull Hist Med 94 (2020): 727&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33775950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ, Liu S. Proposed subtypes of post-Covid-19 syndrome (or long- Covid) and their respective potential therapies. Rev Med Virol 32 (2022): e2315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34888989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong MC, Huang J, Wong YY, Wong GL, Yip TC, Chan RN, et al. Epidemiology, Symptomatology, and Risk Factors for Long Covid Symptoms: Population-Based, Multicenter Study. JMIR Public Health Surveill 9 (2023): e42315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9994465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36645453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis G, Li K, Thankam FG, Wilson DR, Agrawal DK: Ocular Transmissibility of COVID-19: Possibilities and Perspectives. Mol Cell Biochem 477 (2022): 849&#x2013;864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8783769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35066705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wais T, Hasan M, Rai V, Agrawal DK: Gut-brain communication in COVID-19: Potential biomarkers and interventional strategies. Expert Review of Clin Immunol 18 (2022): 947&#x2013;960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35868344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thankam FG, Agrawal DK: Molecular chronicles of cytokine burst in COVID-19 patients with cardiovascular diseases. J Thoracic Cardiovasc Surg 161 (2021): e217&#x2013;e226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32631657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdani AN, DeMarco N, Patel P, Abdi A, Velpuri P, Agrawal DK, Rai V: Adverse hematological effects of COVID-19 vaccination and pathomechanisms of low acquired immunity in patients with hematological malignancies. Vaccines 11 (2023): 662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10058097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36992246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasa S, Nora-Krukle Z, Henning N, Eliassen E, Shikova E, Harrer T, et al. Chronic viral infections in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). J Transl Med 16 (2018): 268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6167797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30285773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shukla AK, Atal S, Banerjee A, Jhaj R, Balakrishnan S, Chugh PK, et al. An observational multi-centric Covid-19 sequelae study among health care workers. Lancet Reg Health Southeast Asia 10 (2023): 100129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9744681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36531928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, Dunne J, Mooney A, Gaffney F, et al. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One 15 (2020): e0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nooti SK, Rai V, Singh H, Potluri V, Agrawal DK: Strokes, Neurological and Neuropsychiatric Disorders in COVID-19. In: Sobti RC, Dhalla NS, Watanabe M, Sobti A. (eds) Delineating Health and Health System: Mechanistic Insights into Covid 19 Complications, pp 2021. (209&#x2013;231).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margalit I, Yelin D, Sagi M, Rahat MM, Sheena L, Mizrahi N, et al. Risk Factors and Multidimensional Assessment of Long Coronavirus Disease Fatigue: A Nested Case-Control Study. Clin Infect Dis 75 (2022): 1688&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9383780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35403679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell A, Hepgul N, Nikkheslat N, Borsini A, Zajkowska Z, Moll N, et al. Persistent fatigue induced by interferon-alpha: a novel, inflammation-based, proxy model of chronic fatigue syndrome. Psychoneuroendocrinology 100 (2019): 276&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6350004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30567628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wostyn P. Covid-19 and chronic fatigue syndrome: Is the worst yet to come? Med Hypotheses. 146 (2021): 110469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33401106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas G, Medeiros Geraldo LH, Gedeao Salomao N, Viana Paes M, Regina Souza Lima F, Carvalho Alcantara Gomes F. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) and glial cells: Insights and perspectives. Brain Behav Immun Health 7 (2020): 100127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7423575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steenblock C, Todorov V, Kanczkowski W, Eisenhofer G, Schedl A, Wong ML, et al. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) and the neuroendocrine stress axis. Mol Psychiatry 25 (2020): 1611&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7204611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32382135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morbini P, Benazzo M, Verga L, Pagella FG, Mojoli F, Bruno R, et al. Ultrastructural Evidence of Direct Viral Damage to the Olfactory Complex in Patients Testing Positive for SARS-CoV-2. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 146 (2020): 972&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norwood JN, Zhang Q, Card D, Craine A, Ryan TM, Drew PJ. Anatomical basis and physiological role of cerebrospinal fluid transport through the murine cribriform plate. Elife 8 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6524970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31063132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalid MF, Micieli JA. Idiopathic Intracranial Hypertension Associated with SARS-CoV-2 B.1.1.7 Variant of Concern. Can J Neurol Sci 49 (2022): 472&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8314070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34121637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur S, Mahajan M, Azad RK, Thakur JS. Covid-19 Associated Idiopathic Intracranial Hypertension and Acute Vision loss. Indian J Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg (2022): 1&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9736703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36532229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller T, Riederer P, Kuhn W. Aminoadamantanes: from treatment of Parkinson's and Alzheimer's disease to symptom amelioration of long Covid-19 syndrome? Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol 16 (2023): 101&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36726198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A HH, Perrin R, Walther A, Stedman M, Hann M, Mukherjee A, et al. Reducing fatigue-related symptoms in Long Covid-19: a preliminary report of a lymphatic drainage intervention. Cardiovasc Endocrinol Metab 11 (2022): e0261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9010124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35441129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollbracht C, Kraft K. Feasibility of Vitamin C in the Treatment of Post Viral Fatigue with Focus on Long Covid, Based on a Systematic Review of IV Vitamin C on Fatigue. Nutrients 13 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8066596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santana K, Franca E, Sato J, Silva A, Queiroz M, de Farias J, et al. Non-invasive brain stimulation for fatigue in post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (PASC). Brain Stimul 16 (2023): 100&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9867562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36693536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khraisat B, Toubasi A, AlZoubi L, Al-Sayegh T, Mansour A. Meta-analysis of prevalence: the psychological sequelae among Covid-19 survivors. Int J Psychiatry Clin Pract 26 (2022): 234&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34709105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT, Hamilton FW, Milne A, Morley AJ, Viner J, Attwood M, et al. Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with Covid-19 and implications for follow-up: results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax 76 (2021): 399&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnefeesi Y, Siegel A, Lui LMW, Teopiz KM, Ho RCM, Lee Y, et al. Impact of SARS-CoV-2 Infection on Cognitive Function: A Systematic Review. Front Psychiatry 11 (2020): 621773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7902710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33643083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultheiss C, Willscher E, Paschold L, Gottschick C, Klee B, Henkes SS, et al. The IL-1beta, IL-6, and TNF cytokine triad is associated with post-acute sequelae of Covid-19. Cell Rep Med 3 (2022): 100663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35732153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanderVeen BN, Fix DK, Montalvo RN, Counts BR, Smuder AJ, Murphy EA, et al. The regulation of skeletal muscle fatigability and mitochondrial function by chronically elevated interleukin-6. Exp Physiol 104 (2019): 385&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6750733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30576589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motta-Santos D, Dos Santos RA, Oliveira M, Qadri F, Poglitsch M, Mosienko V, et al. Effects of ACE2 deficiency on physical performance and physiological adaptations of cardiac and skeletal muscle to exercise. Hypertens Res 39 (2016): 506&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27053009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin M, Tong Q. Rhabdomyolysis as Potential Late Complication Associated with Covid-19. Emerg Infect Dis 26 (2020): 1618&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32197060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renna ME, O'Toole MS, Spaeth PE, Lekander M, Mennin DS. The association between anxiety, traumatic stress, and obsessive-compulsive disorders and chronic inflammation: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Depress Anxiety 35 (2018): 1081&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30199144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller AH, Raison CL. The role of inflammation in depression: from evolutionary imperative to modern treatment target. Nat Rev Immunol 16 (2016): 22&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5542678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26711676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowlati Y, Herrmann N, Swardfager W, Liu H, Sham L, Reim EK, et al. A meta-analysis of cytokines in major depression. Biol Psychiatry 67 (2010): 446&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20015486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stetler C, Miller GE. Depression and hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal activation: a quantitative summary of four decades of research. Psychosom Med 73 (2011): 114&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21257974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantzer R. Cytokine-induced sickness behavior: mechanisms and implications. Ann N Y Acad Sci 933 (2001): 222&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12000023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Weyhern CH, Kaufmann I, Neff F, Kremer M. Early evidence of pronounced brain involvement in fatal Covid-19 outcomes. Lancet 395 (2020): e109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32505222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J, Radke J, Dittmayer C, Franz J, Thomas C, Mothes R, et al. Olfactory transmucosal SARS-CoV-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with Covid-19. Nat Neurosci 24 (2021): 168&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deigendesch N, Sironi L, Kutza M, Wischnewski S, Fuchs V, Hench J, et al. Correlates of critical illness-related encephalopathy predominate postmortem Covid-19 neuropathology. Acta Neuropathol 140 (2020): 583&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7449525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32851506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrin R, Riste L, Hann M, Walther A, Mukherjee A, Heald A. Into the looking glass: Post-viral syndrome post Covid-19. Med Hypotheses 144 (2020): 110055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7320866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32758891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parvizi J, Damasio AR. Neuroanatomical correlates of brainstem coma. Brain 126 (2003): 1524&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12805123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimniak M, Kirschner L, Hilpert H, Geiger N, Danov O, Oberwinkler H, et al. The serotonin reuptake inhibitor Fluoxetine inhibits SARS-CoV-2 in human lung tissue. Sci Rep 11 (2021): 5890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7961020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33723270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoertel N, Sanchez-Rico M, Vernet R, Beeker N, Jannot AS, Neuraz A, et al. Association between antidepressant use and reduced risk of intubation or death in hospitalized patients with Covid-19: results from an observational study. Mol Psychiatry 26 (2021): 5199&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33536545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ: Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nature Reviews Microbiology 21 (2023): 133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultebraucks K, Blekic W, Basaraba C, Corbeil T, Khan Z, Henry BF, Krawczyk N, Rivera BD, Allen B, Arout C, Pincus HA, Martinez DM, Levin FR: The impact of preexisting psychiatric disorders and antidepressant use on COVID-19 related outcomes: a multicenter study. Mol Psychiatry 17 (2023): 1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10107583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37069343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, Zanardi R, Palladini M, Rovere-Querini P, Benedetti F. Rapid response to selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors in post-Covid depression. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol 54 (2022): 1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34634679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takano A, Suhara T, Sudo Y, Inoue M, Hashimoto K, Zhang MR, et al. Comparative evaluation of two serotonin transporter ligands in the human brain: [(11) C] (+) McN5652 and [(11) C] cyanoimipramine. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging 29 (2002): 1289&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12271409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adnot S, Houssaini A, Abid S, Marcos E, Amsellem V. Serotonin transporter and serotonin receptors. Handb Exp Pharmacol 218 (2013): 365&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24092348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friesland M, Mingorance L, Chung J, Chisari FV, Gastaminza P. Sigma-1 receptor regulates early steps of viral RNA replication at the onset of hepatitis C virus infection. J Virol 87 (2013): 6377&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3648129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23536676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards MJ, Becker KA, Gripp B, Hoffmann M, Keitsch S, Wilker B, et al. Sphingosine prevents binding of SARS-CoV-2 spike to its cellular receptor ACE2. J Biol Chem 295 (2020): 15174&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7650243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32917722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoertel N, Sanchez-Rico M, Gulbins E, Kornhuber J, Carpinteiro A, Lenze EJ, et al. Association Between FIASMAs and Reduced Risk of Intubation or Death in Individuals Hospitalized for Severe Covid-19: An Observational Multicenter Study. Clin Pharmacol Ther 110 (2021): 1498&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34050932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seftel D, Boulware DR. Prospective Cohort of Fluvoxamine for Early Treatment of Coronavirus Disease 19. Open Forum Infect Dis 8 (2021): ofab050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7888564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33623808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarrott B, Head R, Pringle KG, Lumbers ER, Martin JH. "LONG Covid"-A hypothesis for understanding the biological basis and pharmacological treatment strategy. Pharmacol Res Perspect 10 (2022): e00911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8929332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35029046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskelund A, Li Y, Budac DP, Muller HK, Gulinello M, Sanchez C, et al. Drugs with antidepressant properties affect tryptophan metabolites differently in rodent models with depression-like behavior. J Neurochem 142 (2017): 118&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28407315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedetti F, Mazza M, Cavalli G, Ciceri F, Dagna L, Rovere-Querini P. Can Cytokine Blocking Prevent Depression in Covid-19 Survivors? J Neuroimmune Pharmacol 16 (2021): 1&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7587545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33107012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezzacappa A, Lasica PA, Gianfagna F, Cazas O, Hardy P, Falissard B, et al. Risk for Autism Spectrum Disorders According to Period of Prenatal Antidepressant Exposure: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. JAMA Pediatr 171 (2017): 555&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28418571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versace V, Ortelli P, Dezi S, Ferrazzoli D, Alibardi A, Bonini I, et al. Co-ultramicronized palmitoylethanolamide/luteolin normalizes GABA(B)-ergic activity and cortical plasticity in long Covid-19 syndrome. Clin Neurophysiol 145 (2023): 81&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9650483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36455453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortolato B, Carvalho AF, Soczynska JK, Perini GI, McIntyre RS. The Involvement of TNF-alpha in Cognitive Dysfunction Associated with Major Depressive Disorder: An Opportunity for Domain Specific Treatments. Curr Neuropharmacol 13 (2015): 558&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4761629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26467407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spuch C, Lopez-Garcia M, Rivera-Baltanas T, Rodrigues-Amorim D, Olivares JM. Does Lithium Deserve a Place in the Treatment Against Covid-19? A Preliminary Observational Study in Six Patients, Case Report. Front Pharmacol 11 (2020): 557629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7481472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32973537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez L, Vidal B, Cabrera Y, Hernandez L, Rondon Y. Successful Treatment of Post-Covid Symptoms with Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation. Prim Care Companion CNS Disord 23 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34861746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of Covid-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry 8 (2021): 416&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degen CV, Mikuteit M, Niewolik J, Schroder D, Vahldiek K, Mucke U, et al. Self-reported Tinnitus and Vertigo or Dizziness in a Cohort of Adult Long Covid Patients. Front Neurol 13 (2022): 884002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9082801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35547372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechien JR, Chiesa-Estomba CM, Beckers E, Mustin V, Ducarme M, Journe F, et al. Prevalence and 6-month recovery of olfactory dysfunction: a multicentre study of 1363 Covid-19 patients. J Intern Med 290 (2021): 451&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33403772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renaud M, Thibault C, Le Normand F, McDonald EG, Gallix B, Debry C, et al. Clinical Outcomes for Patients with Anosmia 1 Year After Covid-19 Diagnosis. JAMA Netw Open 4 (2021): e2115352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8226421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34165581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degen CV, Mikuteit M, Niewolik J, Joosten T, Schroder D, Vahldiek K, et al. Audiological profile of adult Long Covid patients. Am J Otolaryngol 43 (2022): 103579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9354445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35988361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saniasiaya J, Kulasegarah J. Auditory Cinchonism in Covid Era. Ear Nose Throat J 99 (2020): 597&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8263378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32744901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsowaida YS, Almulhim AS, Oh M, Erstad B, Abraham I. Sensorineural hearing loss with macrolide antibiotics exposure: a meta-analysis of the association. Int J Pharm Pract 29 (2021): 21&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32871046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degen C, Lenarz T, Willenborg K. Acute Profound Sensorineural Hearing Loss After Covid-19 Pneumonia. Mayo Clin Proc 95 (2020): 1801&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7275185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frazier KM, Hooper JE, Mostafa HH, Stewart CM. SARS-CoV-2 Virus Isolated from the Mastoid and Middle Ear: Implications for Covid-19 Precautions During Ear Surgery. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 146 (2020): 964&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7378866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32701126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes LA, Agrawal DK: Thromboembolism in the complications of long COVID-19. Cardiol Cardiovasc Med 7 (2023): 123&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10310316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37389402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iba T, Connors JM, Levy JH. The coagulopathy, endotheliopathy, and vasculitis of Covid-19. Inflamm Res 69 (2020): 1181&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32918567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koumpa FS, Forde CT, Manjaly JG. Sudden irreversible hearing loss post Covid-19. BMJ Case Rep 13 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7554505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33051251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Netland J, Meyerholz DK, Moore S, Cassell M, Perlman S. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus infection causes neuronal death in the absence of encephalitis in mice transgenic for human ACE2. J Virol 82 (2008): 7264&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2493326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18495771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giacomelli A, Pezzati L, Conti F, Bernacchia D, Siano M, Oreni L, et al. Self-reported Olfactory and Taste Disorders in Patients with Severe Acute Respiratory Coronavirus 2 Infection: A Cross-sectional Study. Clin Infect Dis 71 (2020): 889&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan CH, Faraji F, Prajapati DP, Boone CE, DeConde AS. Association of chemosensory dysfunction and Covid-19 in patients presenting with influenza-like symptoms. Int Forum Allergy Rhinol 10 (2020): 806&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32279441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franke C, Ferse C, Kreye J, Reincke SM, Sanchez-Sendin E, Rocco A, et al. High frequency of cerebrospinal fluid autoantibodies in Covid-19 patients with neurological symptoms. Brain Behav Immun 93 (2021): 415&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saniasiaya J, Narayanan P. Parosmia post Covid-19: an unpleasant manifestation of long Covidsyndrome. Postgrad Med J 98 (2022): e96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35232851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca P, Camaioni A, Marra P, Salzano G, Carriere G, Ricciardi L, et al. Effect of Ultra-Micronized Palmitoylethanolamide and Luteolin on Olfaction and Memory in Patients with Long Covid: Results of a Longitudinal Study. Cells 11 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9406356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36010630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bawazeer MA, Theoharides TC. IL-33 stimulates human mast cell release of CCL5 and CCL2 via MAPK and NF-kappaB, inhibited by methoxyluteolin. Eur J Pharmacol 865 (2019): 172760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31669588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitcroft KL, Hummel T. Clinical Diagnosis and Current Management Strategies for Olfactory Dysfunction: A Review. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 145 (2019): 846&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31318413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altundag A, Yildirim D, Tekcan Sanli DE, Cayonu M, Kandemirli SG, Sanli AN, et al. Olfactory Cleft Measurements and Covid-19-Related Anosmia. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 164 (2021): 1337&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7554408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33045908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casagrande M, Fitzek A, Puschel K, Aleshcheva G, Schultheiss HP, Berneking L, et al. Detection of SARS-CoV-2 in Human Retinal Biopsies of Deceased Covid-19 Patients. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 28 (2020): 721&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hepokur M, Gunes M, Durmus E, Aykut V, Esen F, Oguz H. Long-term follow-up of choroidal changes following Covid-19 infection: analysis of choroidal thickness and choroidal vascularity index. Can J Ophthalmol 58 (2023): 59&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8255099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34302757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karagoz IK, Munk MR, Kaya M, Ruckert R, Yildirim M, Karabas L. Using bioinformatic protein sequence similarity to investigate if SARS CoV-2 infection could cause an ocular autoimmune inflammatory reactions? Exp Eye Res 203 (2021): 108433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7831665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33400927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabel BA, Zhou W, Huber F, Schmidt F, Sabel K, Gonschorek A, et al. Non-invasive brain microcurrent stimulation therapy of long-Covid-19 reduces vascular dysregulation and improves visual and cognitive impairment. Restor Neurol Neurosci 39 (2021): 393&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8764598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34924406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H, Zhong L, Deng J, Peng J, Dan H, Zeng X, et al. High expression of ACE2 receptor of 2019-nCoV on the epithelial cells of oral mucosa. International Journal of Oral Science 12 (2020): 8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7039956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32094336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pushpass RG, Pellicciotta N, Kelly C, Proctor G, Carpenter GH. Reduced Salivary Mucin Binding and Glycosylation in Older Adults Influences Taste in an In Vitro Cell Model. Nutrients 11 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6835954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31554163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jothimani D, Kailasam E, Danielraj S, Nallathambi B, Ramachandran H, Sekar P, et al. Covid-19: Poor outcomes in patients with zinc deficiency. Int J Infect Dis 100 (2020): 343&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7482607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32920234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okada Y, Yoshimura K, Toya S, Tsuchimochi M. Pathogenesis of taste impairment and salivary dysfunction in Covid-19 patients. Jpn Dent Sci Rev 57 (2021): 111&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8266517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34257762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart MF, Ware LB. The long-lasting effects of the acute respiratory distress syndrome. Expert Rev Respir Med 14 (2020): 577&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32168460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motiejunaite J, Balagny P, Arnoult F, Mangin L, Bancal C, d'Ortho MP, et al. Hyperventilation: A Possible Explanation for Long-Lasting Exercise Intolerance in Mild Covid-19 Survivors? Front Physiol 11 (2020): 614590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7849606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33536937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carsana L, Sonzogni A, Nasr A, Rossi RS, Pellegrinelli A, Zerbi P, et al. Pulmonary post-mortem findings in a series of Covid-19 cases from northern Italy: a two-centre descriptive study. Lancet Infect Dis 20 (2020): 1135&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7279758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32526193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McElvaney OJ, McEvoy NL, McElvaney OF, Carroll TP, Murphy MP, Dunlea DM, et al. Characterization of the Inflammatory Response to Severe Covid-19 Illness. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 202 (2020): 812&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32584597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackermann M, Verleden SE, Kuehnel M, Haverich A, Welte T, Laenger F, et al. Pulmonary Vascular Endothelialitis, Thrombosis, and Angiogenesis in Covid-19. N Engl J Med 383 (2020): 120&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7412750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Fogarty H, Dyer A, Martin-Loeches I, Bannan C, Nadarajan P, et al. Prolonged elevation of D-dimer levels in convalescent Covid-19 patients is independent of the acute phase response. J Thromb Haemost 19 (2021): 1064&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33587810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy B, Casey D, Devane D, Murphy K, Murphy E, Lacasse Y. Pulmonary rehabilitation for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev (2015): CD003793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10008021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25705944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vancheri C, Kreuter M, Richeldi L, Ryerson CJ, Valeyre D, Grutters JC, et al. Nintedanib with Add-on Pirfenidone in Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis. Results of the INJOURNEY Trial. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 197 (2018): 356&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28889759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gigante A, Aquili A, Farinelli L, Caraffa A, Ronconi G, Enrica Gallenga C, et al. Sodium chromo-glycate and palmitoylethanolamide: A possible strategy to treat mast cell-induced lung inflammation in Covid-19. Med Hypotheses 143 (2020): 109856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32460208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limen RY, Sedono R, Sugiarto A, Hariyanto TI. Janus kinase (JAK)-inhibitors and coronavirus disease 2019 (Covid-19) outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther 20 (2022): 425&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34538216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjellberg A, Abdel-Halim L, Hassler A, El Gharbi S, Al-Ezerjawi S, Bostrom E, et al. Hyperbaric oxygen for treatment of long Covid-19 syndrome (HOT-LoCO): protocol for a randomised, placebo-controlled, double-blind, phase II clinical trial. BMJ Open 12 (2022): e061870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9638753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36323462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mera-Cordero F, Bonet-Monne S, Almeda-Ortega J, Garcia-Sangenis A, Cunillera-Puertolas O, Contreras-Martos S, et al. Double-blind placebo-controlled randomized clinical trial to assess the efficacy of montelukast in mild to moderate respiratory symptoms of patients with long Covid: E-SPERANZA Covid Project study protocol. Trials 23 (2022): 19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8733792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34991703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JA, Kitt MM, Morice AH, Birring SS, McGarvey LP, Sher MR, et al. Gefapixant, a P2X3 receptor antagonist, for the treatment of refractory or unexplained chronic cough: a randomised, double-blind, controlled, parallel-group, phase 2b trial. Lancet Respir Med 8 (2020): 775&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32109425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. 6-month consequences of Covid-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet 397 (2021): 220&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntmann VO, Carerj ML, Wieters I, Fahim M, Arendt C, Hoffmann J, et al. Outcomes of Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance Imaging in Patients Recently Recovered from Coronavirus Disease 2019 (Covid-19). JAMA Cardiol 5 (2020): 1265&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Bermejo JA, Kang S, Rockwood SJ, Simoneau CR, Joy DA, Silva AC, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection of human iPSC-derived cardiac cells reflects cytopathic features in hearts of patients with Covid-19. Sci Transl Med 13 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8128284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33723017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavazzi G, Pellegrini C, Maurelli M, Belliato M, Sciutti F, Bottazzi A, et al. Myocardial localization of coronavirus in Covid-19 cardiogenic shock. Eur J Heart Fail 22 (2020): 911&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajpal S, Tong MS, Borchers J, Zareba KM, Obarski TP, Simonetti OP, et al. Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance Findings in Competitive Athletes Recovering from Covid-19 Infection. JAMA Cardiol 6 (2021): 116&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7489396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32915194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Zhou L, Sun X, Yan Z, Hu C, Wu J, et al. Altered Lipid Metabolism in Recovered SARS Patients Twelve Years after Infection. Sci Rep 7 (2017): 9110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5567209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28831119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi S, Qin M, Shen B, Cai Y, Liu T, Yang F, et al. Association of Cardiac Injury with Mortality in Hospitalized Patients with Covid-19 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Cardiol 5 (2020): 802&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32211816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzik TJ, Mohiddin SA, Dimarco A, Patel V, Savvatis K, Marelli-Berg FM, et al. Covid-19 and the cardiovascular system: implications for risk assessment, diagnosis, and treatment options. Cardiovasc Res 116 (2020): 1666&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7197627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32352535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalil AC, Mehta AK, Patterson TF, Erdmann N, Gomez CA, Jain MK, et al. Efficacy of interferon beta-1a plus remdesivir compared with remdesivir alone in hospitalised adults with Covid-19: a double-bind, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Respir Med 9 (2021): 1365&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8523116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consortium WHOST, Pan H, Peto R, Henao-Restrepo AM, Preziosi MP, Sathiyamoorthy V, et al. Repurposed Antiviral Drugs for Covid-19 - Interim WHO Solidarity Trial Results. N Engl J Med 384 (2021): 497&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33264556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harzallah I, Debliquis A, Drenou B. Lupus anticoagulant is frequent in patients with Covid-19. J Thromb Haemost 18 (2020): 2064&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32324958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sollini M, Ciccarelli M, Cecconi M, Aghemo A, Morelli P, Gelardi F, et al. Vasculitis changes in Covid-19 survivors with persistent symptoms: an [(18)F]FDG-PET/CT study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging 48 (2021): 1460&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7595761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33123760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallukat G, Hohberger B, Wenzel K, Furst J, Schulze-Rothe S, Wallukat A, et al. Functional autoantibodies against G-protein coupled receptors in patients with persistent Long-Covid-19 symptoms. J Transl Autoimmun 4 (2021): 100100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8049853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33880442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinagra G, Anzini M, Pereira NL, Bussani R, Finocchiaro G, Bartunek J, et al. Myocarditis in Clinical Practice. Mayo Clin Proc 91 (2016): 1256&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27489051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw BH, Stiles LE, Bourne K, Green EA, Shibao CA, Okamoto LE, et al. The face of postural tachycardia syndrome - insights from a large cross-sectional online community-based survey. J Intern Med 286 (2019): 438&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6790699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30861229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P, Torocastro M, Panagopoulos D, Sutton R, et al. Autonomic dysfunction in 'long Covid': rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin Med (Lond) 21 (2021): e63&#x2013;e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmona-Torre F, Minguez-Olaondo A, Lopez-Bravo A, Tijero B, Grozeva V, Walcker M, et al. Dysautonomia in Covid-19 Patients: A Narrative Review on Clinical Course, Diagnostic and Therapeutic Strategies. Front Neurol 13 (2022): 886609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9198643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35720084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruzieh M, Batizy L, Dasa O, Oostra C, Grubb B. The role of autoantibodies in the syndromes of orthostatic intolerance: a systematic review. Scand Cardiovasc J 51 (2017): 243&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28738696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yachou Y, El Idrissi A, Belapasov V, Ait Benali S. Neuroinvasion, neurotropic, and neuroinflammatory events of SARS-CoV-2: understanding the neurological manifestations in Covid-19 patients. Neurol Sci 41 (2020): 2657&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varma-Doyle A, Villemarette-Pittman NR, Lelorier P, England J. Demonstrating new-onset or worsened sudomotor function post-Covid-19 on comparative analysis of autonomic function pre-and post-SARS-CoV-2 infection. eNeurologicalSci 30 (2023): 100445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9877150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36718227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller AJ, Raj SR. Pharmacotherapy for postural tachycardia syndrome. Auton Neurosci 215 (2018): 28&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29753556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu LD, Duricka DL. Stellate ganglion block reduces symptoms of Long Covid: A case series. J Neuroimmunol 362 (2022): 577784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8653406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34922127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, Bunker CB, Ciurtin C, Porter JC, Chambers RC, Papdopoulou C, et al. Chilblain-like acral lesions in long Covid-19: management and implications for understanding microangiopathy. Lancet Infect Dis 21 (2021): 912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33705725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga Z, Flammer AJ, Steiger P, Haberecker M, Andermatt R, Zinkernagel AS, et al. Endothelial cell infection and endotheliitis in Covid-19. Lancet 395 (2020): 1417&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colmenero I, Santonja C, Alonso-Riano M, Noguera-Morel L, Hernandez-Martin A, Andina D, et al. SARS-CoV-2 endothelial infection causes Covid-19 chilblains: histopathological, immunohistochemical and ultrastructural study of seven paediatric cases. Br J Dermatol 183 (2020): 729&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32562567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanshal M. Low- dose systemic steroids, an emerging therapeutic option for Covid-19 related urticaria. J Dermatolog Treat 33 (2022): 1140&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32649228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnaud S, Budowski C, Ng Wing Tin S, Degos B. Post SARS-CoV-2 Guillain-Barre syndrome. Clin Neurophysiol 131 (2020): 1652&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7212990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raahimi MM, Kane A, Moore CE, Alareed AW. Late onset of Guillain-Barre syndrome following SARS-CoV-2 infection: part of 'long Covid-19 syndrome'? BMJ Case Rep 14 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7813388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33462068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goudarzi S, Esmaeeli S, Valencia JD, Lu ME, Hales RR, Fehnel CR, et al. Treatment Options for Covid-19-Related Guillain-Barre Syndrome: A Systematic Review of Literature. Neurologist 26 (2021): 196&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8423032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34491938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones VG, Mills M, Suarez D, Hogan CA, Yeh D, Segal JB, et al. Covid-19 and Kawasaki Disease: Novel Virus and Novel Case. Hosp Pediatr 10 (2020): 537&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32265235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauf A, Vijayan A, John ST, Krishnan R, Latheef A. Multisystem Inflammatory Syndrome with Features of Atypical Kawasaki Disease during Covid-19 Pandemic. Indian J Pediatr 87 (2020): 745&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8823324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32462354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esper F, Shapiro ED, Weibel C, Ferguson D, Landry ML, Kahn JS. Association between a novel human coronavirus and Kawasaki disease. J Infect Dis 191 (2005): 499&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7199489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15655771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouletty M, Borocco C, Ouldali N, Caseris M, Basmaci R, Lachaume N, et al. Paediatric multisystem inflammatory syndrome temporally associated with SARS-CoV-2 mimicking Kawasaki disease (Kawa-Covid-19): a multicentre cohort. Ann Rheum Dis 79 (2020): 999&#x2013;1006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7299653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32527868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdoni L, Mazza A, Gervasoni A, Martelli L, Ruggeri M, Ciuffreda M, et al. An outbreak of severe Kawasaki-like disease at the Italian epicentre of the SARS-CoV-2 epidemic: an observational cohort study. Lancet 395 (2020): 1771&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7220177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32410760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belhadjer Z, Meot M, Bajolle F, Khraiche D, Legendre A, Abakka S, et al. Acute Heart Failure in Multisystem Inflammatory Syndrome in Children in the Context of Global SARS-CoV-2 Pandemic. Circulation 142 (2020): 429&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32418446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal S, Agrawal DK: Kawasaki disease: Etiopathogenesis and novel treatment strategies. Expert Rev Clin Immunol 13 (2017): 247&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5542821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27590181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toubiana J, Poirault C, Corsia A, Bajolle F, Fourgeaud J, Angoulvant F, et al. Kawasaki-like multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children during the Covid-19 pandemic in Paris, France: prospective observational study. BMJ 369 (2020): m2094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7500538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32493739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waltuch T, Gill P, Zinns LE, Whitney R, Tokarski J, Tsung JW, et al. Features of Covid-19 post-infectious cytokine release syndrome in children presenting to the emergency department. Am J Emerg Med 38 (2020): 2246 e3&#x2013;e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32471782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balasubramanian S, Nagendran TM, Ramachandran B, Ramanan AV. Hyper-inflammatory Syndrome in a Child with Covid-19 Treated Successfully with Intravenous Immunoglobulin and Tocilizumab. Indian Pediatr 57 (2020): 681&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7387261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32393681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrindle BW, Rowley AH, Newburger JW, Burns JC, Bolger AF, Gewitz M, et al. Diagnosis, Treatment, and Long-Term Management of Kawasaki Disease: A Scientific Statement for Health Professionals From the American Heart Association. Circulation 135 (2017): e927&#x2013;e99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28356445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng J, Li Y, Li J, Shen L, Zhu L, Liang Y, et al. Gastrointestinal sequelae 90 days after discharge for Covid-19. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol 6 (2021): 344&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7943402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33711290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long Covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ 374 (2021): n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmulson M, Davalos MF, Berumen J. Beware: Gastrointestinal symptoms can be a manifestation of Covid-19. Rev Gastroenterol Mex (Engl Ed) 85 (2020): 282&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32376072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Guo C, Tang L, Hong Z, Zhou J, Dong X, et al. Prolonged presence of SARS-CoV-2 viral RNA in faecal samples. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol 5 (2020): 434&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32199469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan KH, Poon LL, Cheng VC, Guan Y, Hung IF, Kong J, et al. Detection of SARS coronavirus in patients with suspected SARS. Emerg Infect Dis 10 (2004): 294&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3322905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15030700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deshmukh V, Motwani R, Kumar A, Kumari C, Raza K. Histopathological observations in Covid-19: a systematic review. J Clin Pathol 74 (2021): 76&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32817204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akiho H, Ihara E, Motomura Y, Nakamura K. Cytokine-induced alterations of gastrointestinal motility in gastrointestinal disorders. World J Gastrointest Pathophysiol 2 (2011): 72&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22013552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdo J, Rai V, Agrawal DK: Interplay of Immunity and Vitamin D: Interactions and Implications with Current IBD Therapy. Curr Med Chem 24 (2017): 852&#x2013;867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27784213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghoshal UC, Ranjan P. Post-infectious irritable bowel syndrome: the past, the present and the future. J Gastroenterol Hepatol 26 (2011): 94&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21443719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, Ng RH, Wang K, Choi J, et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute Covid-19 sequelae. Cell 185 (2022): 881&#x2013;95 e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo T, Liu Q, Zhang F, Yeoh YK, Wan Y, Zhan H, et al. Temporal landscape of human gut RNA and DNA virome in SARS-CoV-2 infection and severity. Microbiome 9 (2021): 91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8044506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33853691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo T, Zhan H, Zhang F, Liu Q, Tso EYK, Lui GCY, et al. Alterations in Fecal Fungal Microbiome of Patients with Covid-19 During Time of Hospitalization until Discharge. Gastroenterology 159 (2020): 1302&#x2013;10 e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7318920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32598884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu S, Chen Y, Wu Z, Chen Y, Gao H, Lv L, et al. Alterations of the Gut Microbiota in Patients with Coronavirus Disease 2019 or H1N1 Influenza. Clin Infect Dis 71 (2020): 2669&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7314193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32497191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Mak JWY, Su Q, Yeoh YK, Lui GC, Ng SSS, et al. Gut microbiota dynamics in a prospective cohort of patients with post-acute Covid-19 syndrome. Gut 71 (2022): 544&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing YH, Ni W, Wu Q, Li WJ, Li GJ, Wang WD, et al. Prolonged viral shedding in feces of pediatric patients with coronavirus disease 2019. J Microbiol Immunol Infect 53 (2020): 473&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7141453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32276848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaebler C, Wang Z, Lorenzi JCC, Muecksch F, Finkin S, Tokuyama M, et al. Evolution of antibody immunity to SARS-CoV-2. Nature 591 (2021): 639&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoang VT, Dao TL, Gautret P. Recurrence of positive SARS-CoV-2 in patients recovered from Covid-19. J Med Virol 92 (2020): 2366&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7280660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32449789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanner N, Andrieux G, Badia IMP, Edler C, Pfefferle S, Lindenmeyer MT, et al. Molecular consequences of SARS-CoV-2 liver tropism. Nat Metab 4 (2022): 310&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8964418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35347318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radwan MM, Radwan BM, Nandipati KC, Hunter WJ, Agrawal DK: Immunological and molecular basis of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis and nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Expert Rev Clin Immunol 9 (2013): 727&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23971751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Zhang L, Wang Y, Dai T, Qin Z, Zhou F, et al. Alterations in microbiota of patients with Covid-19: potential mechanisms and therapeutic interventions. Signal Transduct Target Ther 7 (2022): 143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9052735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35487886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Alberts J, Oben J, Cuthbertson DJ, Wootton D, et al. Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-Covid-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open 11 (2021): e048391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera-Valdes R, Almaguer-Lopez M, Lopez-Marin L, Bacallao-Mendez R, F J, Guerra-Bustillo G. Covid-19 and the Kidneys: Risk, Damage and Sequelae. MEDICC Rev 22 (2020): 87&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33295327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lui DTW, Tsoi KH, Lee CH, Cheung CYY, Fong CHY, Lee ACH, et al. A prospective follow-up on thyroid function, thyroid autoimmunity and long Covid among 250 Covid-19 survivors. Endocrine (2023): 1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9810240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36596904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feghali K, Atallah J, Norman C. Manifestations of thyroid disease post Covid-19 illness: Report of Hashimoto thyroiditis, Graves' disease, and subacute thyroiditis. J Clin Transl Endocrinol Case Rep 22 (2021): 100094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8387132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34462717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasconez-Gonzalez J, Fernandez-Naranjo R, Izquierdo-Condoy JS, Delgado-Moreira K, Cordovez S, Tello-De-la-Torre A, et al. Comparative analysis of long-term self-reported Covid-19 symptoms among pregnant women. J Infect Public Health 16 (2023): 430&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9851727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36736066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chourasia UH, Khormi AH, Jawkhab HA, Zoli SI, Assiri KA, Thurwi SA, et al. Determining the Effect of Covid-19 on the Menstrual Cycle Among Women of Reproductive Age Group in the Jazan Region: A Cross-Sectional Study. Cureus 14 (2022): e32431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9832938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36644095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Najjar MAA, Al-Alwany RR, Al-Rshoud FM, Abu-Farha RK, Zawiah M. Menstrual changes following Covid-19 infection: A cross-sectional study from Jordan and Iraq. PLoS One 17 (2022): e0270537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9242447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35767537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krystel-Whittemore M, Dileepan KN, Wood JG. Mast Cell: A Multi-Functional Master Cell. Front Immunol 6 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4701915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26779180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akin C, Valent P, Metcalfe DD. Mast cell activation syndrome: Proposed diagnostic criteria. J Allergy Clin Immunol 126 (2010): 1099&#x2013;104 e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3753019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21035176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoharides TC, Cholevas C, Polyzoidis K, Politis A. Long-Covid syndrome-associated brain fog and chemofog: Luteolin to the rescue. Biofactors 47 (2021): 232&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33847020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstock LB, Brook JB, Walters AS, Goris A, Afrin LB, Molderings GJ. Mast cell activation symptoms are prevalent in Long-Covid. Int J Infect Dis 11 (2021): 217&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34563706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoharides TC. Covid-19, pulmonary mast cells, cytokine storms, and beneficial actions of luteolin. Biofactors 46 (2020): 306&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32339387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munafo F, Donati E, Brindani N, Ottonello G, Armirotti A, De Vivo M. Quercetin and luteolin are single-digit micromolar inhibitors of the SARS-CoV-2 RNA-dependent RNA polymerase. Sci Rep 12 (2022): 10571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9216299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35732785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Z, Xu H, Qu ZY, Ma XY, Huang BX, Sun MS, et al. Active Ingredients of Reduning Injection Maintain High Potency against SARS-CoV-2 Variants. Chin J Integr Med 29 (2023): 205&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9661462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36374439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dissook S, Umsumarng S, Mapoung S, Semmarath W, Arjsri P, Srisawad K, et al. Luteolin-rich fraction from Perilla frutescens seed meal inhibits spike glycoprotein S1 of SARS-CoV-2-induced NLRP3 inflammasome lung cell inflammation via regulation of JAK1/STAT3 pathway: A potential anti-inflammatory compound against inflammation-induced long-Covid. Front Med (Lausanne) 9 (2022): 1072056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9870545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36698809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng Z, Patel AB, Panagiotidou S, Theoharides TC. The novel flavone tetramethoxyluteolin is a potent inhibitor of human mast cells. J Allergy Clin Immunol 135 (2015): 1044&#x2013;52 e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4388775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25498791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaylis NB, Ritter A, Kelly SA, Pourhassan NZ, Tiwary M, Sacha JB, et al. Reduced Cell Surface Levels of C-C Chemokine Receptor 5 and Immunosuppression in Long Coronavirus Disease 2019 Syndrome. Clin Infect Dis 75 (2022): 1232&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9383814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35452519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai C, Chotirmall SH, Rello J, Alba GA, Ginns LC, Krishnan JA, et al. Updated guidance on the management of Covid-19: from an American Thoracic Society/European Respiratory Society coordinated International Task Force (29 July 2020). Eur Respir Rev 29 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33020069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramlall V, Thangaraj PM, Meydan C, Foox J, Butler D, Kim J, et al. Immune complement and coagulation dysfunction in adverse outcomes of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med 26 (2020): 1609&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7809634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32747830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skendros P, Mitsios A, Chrysanthopoulou A, Mastellos DC, Metallidis S, Rafailidis P, et al. Complement and tissue factor-enriched neutrophil extracellular traps are key drivers in Covid-19 immunothrombosis. J Clin Invest 130 (2020): 6151&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7598040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao T, Zhu L, Liu H, Zhang X, Wang T, Fu Y, et al. Highly pathogenic coronavirus N protein aggravates inflammation by MASP-2-mediated lectin complement pathway overactivation. Signal Transduct Target Ther 7 (2022): 318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9470675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36100602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastaglio S, Ruggeri A, Risitano AM, Angelillo P, Yancopoulou D, Mastellos DC, et al. The first case of Covid-19 treated with the complement C3 inhibitor AMY-101. Clin Immunol 215 (2020): 108450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7189192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32360516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryce C, Grimes Z, Pujadas E, Ahuja S, Beasley MB, Albrecht R, et al. Pathophysiology of SARS-CoV-2: the Mount Sinai Covid-19 autopsy experience. Mod Pathol 34 (2021): 1456&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8015313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33795830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escher R, Breakey N, Lammle B. Severe Covid-19 infection associated with endothelial activation. Thromb Res 190 (2020): 62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32305740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manne BK, Denorme F, Middleton EA, Portier I, Rowley JW, Stubben C, et al. Platelet gene expression and function in patients with Covid-19. Blood 136 (2020): 1317&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32573711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldmann M, Maini RN, Woody JN, Holgate ST, Winter G, Rowland M, et al. Trials of anti-tumour necrosis factor therapy for Covid-19 are urgently needed. Lancet 395 (2020): 1407&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32278362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang EY, Mao T, Klein J, Dai Y, Huck JD, Jaycox JR, et al. Diverse functional autoantibodies in patients with Covid-19. Nature 595 (2021): 283&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34010947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acosta-Ampudia Y, Monsalve DM, Rojas M, Rodriguez Y, Zapata E, Ramirez-Santana C, et al. Persistent Autoimmune Activation and Proinflammatory State in Post-Coronavirus Disease 2019 Syndrome. J Infect Dis 225 (2022): 2155&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8903340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35079804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreye J, Reincke SM, Kornau HC, Sanchez-Sendin E, Corman VM, Liu H, et al. A Therapeutic Non-self-reactive SARS-CoV-2 Antibody Protects from Lung Pathology in a Covid-19 Hamster Model. Cell 183 (2020): 1058&#x2013;69 e19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7510528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33058755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiral J, Vissac AM, Seghatchian J. Covid-19, induced activation of hemostasis, and immune reactions: Can an auto-immune reaction contribute to the delayed severe complications observed in some patients? Transfus Apher Sci 59 (2020): 102804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7252011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur JM, Forrest JC, Boehme KW, Kennedy JL, Owens S, Herzog C, et al. Development of ACE2 autoantibodies after SARS-CoV-2 infection. PLoS One 16 (2021): e0257016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8415618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34478478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallmann E, Sikora D, Poniedzialek B, Szymanski K, Kondratiuk K, Zurawski J, et al. IgG autoantibodies against ACE2 in SARS-CoV-2 infected patients. J Med Virol 95 (2023): e28273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9877908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36324055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son K, Jamil R, Chowdhury A, Mukherjee M, Venegas C, Miyasaki K, et al. Circulating anti-nuclear autoantibodies in Covid-19 survivors predict long Covidsymptoms. Eur Respir J 61 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9515477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36137590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giszas B, Reuken PA, Katzer K, Kiehntopf M, Schmerler D, Rummler S, et al. Immunoadsorption to treat patients with severe post-Covid syndrome. Ther Apher Dial (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36719401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo P, Liu Y, Qiu L, Liu X, Liu D, Li J. Tocilizumab treatment in Covid-19: A single center experience. J Med Virol 92 (2020): 814&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32253759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantini F, Niccoli L, Matarrese D, Nicastri E, Stobbione P, Goletti D. Baricitinib therapy in Covid-19: A pilot study on safety and clinical impact. J Infect 81 (2020): 318&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7177073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32333918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darbeheshti F, Mahdiannasser M, Uhal BD, Ogino S, Gupta S, Rezaei N. Interindividual immunogenic variants: Susceptibility to coronavirus, respiratory syncytial virus and influenza virus. Rev Med Virol 31 (2021): e2234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33724604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Abellan J, Padilla S, Fernandez-Gonzalez M, Garcia JA, Agullo V, Andreo M, et al. Antibody Response to SARS-CoV-2 is Associated with Long-term Clinical Outcome in Patients with Covid-19: a Longitudinal Study. J Clin Immunol 41 (2021): 1490&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8285689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubchenko S, Kril I, Nadizhko O, Matsyura O, Chopyak V. Herpesvirus infections and post-Covid-19 manifestations: a pilot observational study. Rheumatol Int 42 (2022): 1523&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9159383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35650445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma D, Church TM, Swaminathan S. Epstein-Barr Virus Lytic Replication Induces ACE2 Expression and Enhances SARS-CoV-2 Pseudotyped Virus Entry in Epithelial Cells. J Virol 95 (2021): e0019221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8316011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33853968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, et al. Attributes and predictors of long Covid. Nat Med 27 (2021): 626&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-de-Las-Penas C, Martin-Guerrero JD, Pellicer-Valero OJ, Navarro-Pardo E, Gomez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, et al. Female Sex Is a Risk Factor Associated with Long-Term Post-Covid Related-Symptoms but Not with Covid-19 Symptoms: The LONG-Covid-EXP-CM Multicenter Study. J Clin Med 11 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8778106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35054108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Keefe JB, Tong EJ, O'Keefe GD, Tong DC. Description of symptom course in a telemedicine monitoring clinic for acute symptomatic Covid-19: a retrospective cohort study. BMJ Open 11 (2021): e044154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7938467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33674374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT MA, Samms E, Stadon L. Are vaccines safe in patients with Long Covid? A prospective observational study. Brit med j (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchida T, Hirose M, Inoue Y, Kunishima H, Otsubo T, Matsuda T. Relationship between changes in symptoms and antibody titers after a single vaccination in patients with Long Covid. J Med Virol 94 (2022): 3416&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9088489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35238053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mumtaz A, Sheikh AAE, Khan AM, Khalid SN, Khan J, Nasrullah A, et al. COVID-19 Vaccine and Long Covid: A Scoping Review. Life (Basel) 12 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9324565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35888154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Bermingham C, Pouwels KB, Glickman M, Nafilyan V, Zaccardi F, et al. Trajectory of long coCvid symptoms after Covid-19 vaccination: community based cohort study. BMJ 377 (2022): e069676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35584816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehme M, Braillard O, Salamun J, Jacquerioz F, Courvoisier DS, Spechbach H, et al. Symptoms After Covid-19 Vaccination in Patients with Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2. J Gen Intern Med 37 (2022): 1585&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8863092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35194744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edey M, Barraclough K, Johnson DW. Review article: Hepatitis B and dialysis. Nephrology (Carlton) 15 (2010): 137&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20470270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue P, Merikanto I, Chung F, Morin CM, Espie C, Bjorvatn B, et al. Persistent short nighttime sleep duration is associated with a greater post-Covid risk in fully mRNA-vaccinated individuals. Transl Psychiatry 13 (2023): 32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9890416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36726008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couzin-Frankel J, Vogel G. Vaccines may cause rare, Long Covid-like symptoms. Science 375 (2022): 364&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35084966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>