<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35787541</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6578</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The physical and mental health consequences of social isolation and loneliness in the context of COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>305</StartPage><EndPage>310</EndPage><MedlinePgn>305-310</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/YCO.0000000000000806</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Social isolation and loneliness are known contributors to all-cause mortality as well as a range of physical and mental health conditions. Therefore, this article reviews current literature pertaining to the effects of social isolation and loneliness on physical and mental health during the current COVID-19 pandemic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Social isolation and loneliness contribute to a myriad of physical and mental health conditions. Specifically social isolation and loneliness contribute to the development of cardiovascular disease, diabetes mellitus, and cancer. However, most research indicated that poor lifestyle factors explained most of the association. Social isolation and loneliness are also associated with cognitive problems including dementia, immune system problems, and mental health conditions. Further social isolation and loneliness also spur behavioral issues that significantly affect physical and mental health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Evidence suggests that social isolation and loneliness have significant consequences on the physical and mental health of the individual and that the move toward ending all protections against COVID-19 has significant implications for the vulnerable. Further the similarities between the effects of social isolation and loneliness are compared to some of the conditions evident in long-COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pai</LastName><ForeName>Nagesh</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Medicine, Faculty of Science, Medicine and Health, University of Wollongong.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Illawarra Health and Medical Research Institute.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Illawarra Shoalhaven Local Health District, Wollongong, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vella</LastName><ForeName>Shae-Leigh</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Medicine, Faculty of Science, Medicine and Health, University of Wollongong.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8809880</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0951-7367</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008132" MajorTopicYN="Y">Loneliness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008603" MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012934" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Isolation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35787541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/YCO.0000000000000806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001504-202209000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fakoya OA, McCorry N, Donnelly M. Loneliness and social isolation interventions for older adults: a scoping review of reviews. BMC Public Health 2020; 20:129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee D, Rai M. Social isolation in COVID-19: the impact of loneliness. Int J Soc Psychiatr 2020; 66:525&#x2013;527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escalante E, Mason DJ. Social isolation and loneliness: imperatives for healthcare in a post-COVID world. JAMA 2021; 325:520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pai N, Vella SC. COVID-19 and loneliness: a rapid systematic review. Aust N Z J Psychiatry 2021; 53:1144&#x2013;1156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worldometer.(2022). Worldometer coronoavirus. https://www.worldometers.info/coronavirus /: accessed on 4/03/22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, et al. Global prevalence of post-acute sequalae of COVID-19 (PASC) or long-COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. Journal of Infectious Diseases 2022; Online Ahead of Print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajek A, Konig HH. Do lonely and socially isolated individuals think they die earlier? The link between loneliness, social isolation and expectations of longevity based on a nationally representative sample. Psychogeriatrics 2021; 21:571&#x2013;576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang TJ, Rabheru K, Peisah C, et al. Loneliness and social isolation during the COVID-19 pandemic. Int Psychogeriatr 2020; 32:1217&#x2013;1220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lennartsson C, Rehnberg J, Dahlberg L. The association between loneliness, social isolation and all-cause mortality in a nationally representative sample of older women and men. Aging Ment Health 2021; XX:XX10.1080/13607863.2021.1976723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13607863.2021.1976723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraav SL, Awoyemi O, Junttila N, et al. The effects of loneliness and social isolation on all-cause, injury, cancer, and CVD mortality in a cohort of middle-aged Finnish men: A prospective study. Aging Mental Health 2021; 25:2219&#x2013;2228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bu F, Zaninotto P, Fancourt D. Longitudinal associations between loneliness, social isolation and cardiovascular events. Heart 2020; 106:1394&#x2013;1399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groneworld J, Engels M. The lonely brain &#x2013; associations between social isolation and (cerebro-) vascular disease from the perspective of social neuroscience. Front Integr Neurosci 2022; 16:729621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freak-Poli R, Ryan J, Neumann JT, et al. Social isolation, social support and loneliness as predictors of cardiovascular disease incidence and mortality. BMC Geriatr 2021; 21:711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christiansen J, Lund R, Qualter P, et al. Loneliness, social isolation, and chronic disease outcomes. Ann Behav Med 2021; 55:203&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang Y, Choi EY, Park NS, et al. Cognitive health risks posed by social isolation and loneliness in older Korean Americans. BMC Geriatr 2021; 21:123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinberg LJ, Steffen K. Social isolation and loneliness during the COVID-19 pandemic: impact on weight. Curr Obes Rep 2021; 10:365&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes TF, Fang F, Jacobsen EP, et al. Social isolation, loneliness, and cognitive impairment in late life: the MYHAT study. Alzheimers Dement 2020; 16:e047706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zilioli S, Jiang Y. Endocrine and immunomodulatory effects of social isolation and loneliness across adulthood. Psychoneuroendocrinology 2021; 128:105194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beam CR, Kim AJ. Psychological sequelae of social isolation and loneliness might be a larger problem in young adults than older adults. Psychol trauma 2020; 12:S58&#x2013;S60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaeta L, Brydges CR. Coronavirus-related anxiety, social isolation, and loneliness in older adults in Northern California during the stay-at-home order. J Aging Soc Policy 2021; 33:320&#x2013;331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holt-Lunstad J. A pandemic of social isolation? World Psychiatr 2021; 20:55&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng KS, Yu K, Lubben J. Effects of loneliness and social isolation on cognitive health: latest perspectives and future directions. Innov Aging 2021; 5:237&#x2013;238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu B, Steptoe A, Chen Y, Jia X. Social isolation, rather than loneliness, is associated with cognitive decline in older adults: the China Health and Retirement Longitudinal Study. Psychol Med 2021; 51:2414&#x2013;2421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutin AR, Stephan Y, Luchetti M, Terracciano A. Loneliness and risk of dementia. J Gerontol B Psychol Sci Soc Sci 2020; 75:1414&#x2013;1422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzola P. Depression and social isolation are associated with loneliness among seniors with mild-to-moderate dementia &#x2013; findings from the IDEAL cohort study. Evid Based Nurs 2022; 25:17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spreng RN, Dimas E, Mwilambwe-Tshilobo L, Dagher A, et al. The default network of the human brain is associated with perceived social isolation. Nat Commun 2020; 11:6393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieberz J, Shamay-Tsoory SG, Saporta N, et al. Loneliness and the social brain: how perceived social isolation impairs human interactions. Adv Sci 2021; 8:2102076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourriyahi H, Yazdanpanah N, Saghazadeh A, Rezaei N. Loneliness: an immunometabolic syndrome. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021; 18:12162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrabissa G, Simpson SG. Psychological consequences of social isolation during COVID-19 outbreak. Front Psychol 2020; 11:2201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkialis L, Rodrigues NB, Cha DS, et al. Social isolation, loneliness and generalized anxiety: implications and associations during the COVID-19 quarantine. Brain Sci 2021; 11:1620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loades ME, Chatburn E, Higson-Sweeney N, et al. Rapid systematic review: the impact of social isolation and loneliness on the mental health of children and adolescents in the context of COVID-19. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry 2020; 59:1218&#x2013;1239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tso IF, Park S. Alarming levels of psychiatric symptoms and the role of loneliness during the COVID-19 epidemic: a case study of Hong Kong. Psychiatry Res 2020; 293:113423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeigler Z. COVID-19 self-quarantine and weight gain risk factors in adults. Curr Obes Rep 2021; 10:423&#x2013;433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillip KEJ, Polkey MI, Hopkinson NS, et al. Social isolation, loneliness and physical performance in older adults: fixed effects analyses of a cohort study. Nat Sci Rep 2020; 10:13908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bu F, Abeil J, Zaninotto P, Fancourt D. A longitudinal analysis of loneliness, social isolation and falls amongst older people in England. Nat Sci Rep 2020; 10:20064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLay L, Jamieson HA, France KG, Schluter PJ. Loneliness and social isolation is associated with sleep problems among older community dwelling woman and men with complex needs. Nat Sci Rep 2021; 11:4877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman ES, Hoffman YSG, Palgi Y, Shrira A. COVID-19 related loneliness and sleep problems in older adults: worries and resilience as potential moderators. Pers Individ Dif 2021; 168:110371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emerson E, Fortune N, Llewellyn G, Stancliffe R. Loneliness, social support and wellbeing among working age adults with and without disability: cross-sectional study. Disabil Health J 2021; 14:100965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White A. Social isolation and loneliness: a hidden killer. Trends Urol Men's Health 2020; 11:31&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long COVID mechanisms, risk factors and management. BMJ 2021; 374:n1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strait, J. E. (2021). Among COVID-19 survivors, an increased risk of death and serious illness. Online: medicine.wustl.edu/news/among-covid-19-survivors-an-increased-risk-ofdeath-serious-illness.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accili D. Can COVID-19 cause diabetes? Nat Metab 2021; 3:123&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P, Tahmasebi N, Gant V, Gupta R. Long COVID following mild SARS-COV-2 infections: characteristic t cell alterations and response to antihistamines. J Investig Med 2022; 70:61&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>