<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37391116</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1555-7162</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The American journal of medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>High Incidence of Autonomic Dysfunction and Postural Orthostatic Tachycardia Syndrome in Patients with Long COVID: Implications for Management and Health Care Planning.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0002-9343(23)00402-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.amjmed.2023.06.010</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Autonomic dysfunction, including postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS), has been reported in individuals with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC). However, the degree of dysautonomia in PASC has not been compared to those with POTS and healthy controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">All participants were prospectively enrolled between August 5, 2021 and October 31, 2022. Autonomic testing included beat-to-beat hemodynamic monitoring to assess respiratory sinus arrhythmia, Valsalva ratio, and orthostatic changes during a 10-minute active standing test, as well as sudomotor assessment. The Composite Autonomic Symptom Score (COMPASS-31) was used to assess symptoms and the EuroQuol 5-Dimension survey (EQ-5D-5L) was used to assess health-related quality of life (HrQoL) measures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 99 participants (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;33 PASC, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;33 POTS, and n&#xa0;=&#xa0;33 healthy controls; median age 32 years, 85.9% females) were included. Compared with healthy controls, the PASC and POTS cohorts demonstrated significantly reduced respiratory sinus arrhythmia (P &lt; .001), greater heart rate increase during 10-minute active standing test (P &lt; .001), greater burden of autonomic dysfunction evidenced by higher COMPASS-31 scores across all subdomains (all P &lt; .001), and poor HrQoL across all EQ-5D-5L domains (all P &lt; .001), lower median EuroQol-visual analogue scale (P &lt; .001), and lower utility scores (P &lt; .001). The majority (79%) of those with PASC met the internationally established criteria for POTS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The prevalence of autonomic symptomology for POTS was high in those with PASC, leading to poor HrQoL and high health disutility. Autonomic testing should be routinely undertaken in those with PASC to aid diagnosis and direct appropriate management to improve health outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seeley</LastName><ForeName>Marie-Claire</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Dysautonomia and Arrhythmia Research Collaborative, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, The University of Adelaide, South Australia, Australia; South Australian Health and Medical Research Institute, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gallagher</LastName><ForeName>Celine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Dysautonomia and Arrhythmia Research Collaborative, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, The University of Adelaide, South Australia, Australia; South Australian Health and Medical Research Institute, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ong</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Dysautonomia and Arrhythmia Research Collaborative, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, The University of Adelaide, South Australia, Australia; College of Medicine and Public Health, Flinders University, Bedford Park, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Langdon</LastName><ForeName>Amy</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Dysautonomia and Arrhythmia Research Collaborative, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, The University of Adelaide, South Australia, Australia; College of Medicine and Public Health, Flinders University, Bedford Park, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chieng</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Dysautonomia and Arrhythmia Research Collaborative, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, The University of Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bailey</LastName><ForeName>Danielle</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Dysautonomia and Arrhythmia Research Collaborative, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, The University of Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Page</LastName><ForeName>Amanda</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lim</LastName><ForeName>Han S</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Austin and Northern Health, The University of Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lau</LastName><ForeName>Dennis H</ForeName><Initials>DH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Dysautonomia and Arrhythmia Research Collaborative, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, The University of Adelaide, South Australia, Australia; South Australian Health and Medical Research Institute, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia. Electronic address: dennis.h.lau@adelaide.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0267200</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0002-9343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dysautonomia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Orthostatic intolerance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37391116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10307671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2023.06.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0002-9343(23)00402-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Romieu AC, Carton TW, Saydah S, et al. Prevalence of Select New Symptoms and Conditions among Persons Aged Younger Than 20 Years and 20 Years or Older at 31 to 150 Days after Testing Positive or Negative for SARS-CoV-2. JAMA Netw. Open. 2022;5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8817203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35119459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesh R, Vanichkachorn GS, Munipalli B, et al. Postacute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection-Lessons Learned From a Coordinated Health System Response. Mayo Clinic proceedings. Innovations, quality &amp; outcomes. 2022;6:311&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9156955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35669936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younger DS. Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC): peripheral, autonomic, and central nervous system features in a child. Neurological Sciences. 2021;42:3959&#x2013;3963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8272686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34247285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hira R, Baker JR, Siddiqui T, et al. Objective Hemodynamic Cardiovascular Autonomic Abnormalities in Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19. Canadian Journal of Cardiology. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9733966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36509178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal SM, Landers DB, Hollenberg SM, et al. Prospective Evaluation of Autonomic Dysfunction in Post-Acute Sequela of COVID-19. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79:2325&#x2013;2330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8976261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35381331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheldon RS, Grubb BP, 2nd, Olshansky B, et al. 2015 heart rhythm society expert consensus statement on the diagnosis and treatment of postural tachycardia syndrome, inappropriate sinus tachycardia, and vasovagal syncope. Heart Rhythm. 2015;12:e41&#x2013;e63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5267948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25980576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells R, Spurrier AJ, Linz D, et al. Postural tachycardia syndrome: current perspectives. Vasc Health Risk Manag. 2018;14:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5749569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29343965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells R, Elliott AD, Mahajan R, et al. Efficacy of therapies for postural tachycardia syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Mayo Clinic Proceedings. 2018;93:1043&#x2013;1053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29937049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S. Autoimmune markers and autoimmune disorders in patients with postural tachycardia syndrome (POTS) Lupus. 2015;24:1364&#x2013;1369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26038344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schofield JR, Chemali KR. Intravenous Immunoglobulin Therapy in Refractory Autoimmune Dysautonomias: A Retrospective Analysis of 38 Patients. American journal of therapeutics. 2019;26:570&#x2013;582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29781817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021. In: Organization WH, ed. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheldon RS, Grubb BP, II, Olshansky B, et al. 2015 heart rhythm society expert consensus statement on the diagnosis and treatment of postural tachycardia syndrome, inappropriate sinus tachycardia, and vasovagal syncope. Heart Rhythm. 2015;12:e41&#x2013;e63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5267948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25980576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinduja A, Moutairou A, Calvet J-H. Sudomotor dysfunction in patients recovered from COVID-19. Neurophysiologie Clinique. 2021;51:193&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7835104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33551341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ru&#x161;ka B, Pavi&#x10d;i&#x107; T, Pavlovi&#x107; I, et al. Performance of the COMPASS-31 questionnaire with regard to autonomic nervous system testing results and medication use: a prospective study in a real-life setting. Neurological Sciences. 2018;39:2079&#x2013;2084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30140988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vold JH, Gjestad R, Aas CF, et al. Validation of a three-item Fatigue Severity Scale for patients with substance use disorder: a cohort study from Norway for the period 2016&#x2013;2020. Health and Quality of Life Outcomes. 2021;19:69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7923309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33653349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCaffrey N, Kaambwa B, Currow DC, Ratcliffe J. Health-related quality of life measured using the EQ-5D-5L: South Australian population norms. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2016;14:133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5028927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27644755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devlin NJ, Shah KK, Feng Y, Mulhern B, van Hout B. Valuing health-related quality of life: An EQ-5D-5L value set for England. Health Econ. 2018;27:7&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6680214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28833869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glans M, Humble MB, Elwin M, Bejerot S. Self-rated joint hypermobility: the five-part questionnaire evaluated in a Swedish non-clinical adult population. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2020;21:174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7079417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32183749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S, Whitelaw S. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) and other autonomic disorders after COVID-19 infection: a case series of 20 patients. Immunol Res. 2021;69:205&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8009458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33786700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman BP, Khoury JA, Blair JE, Grill MF. COVID-19 Dysautonomia. Frontiers in neurology. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8076737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33927679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson M, St&#xe5;hlberg M, Runold M, et al. Long-Haul Post-COVID-19 Symptoms Presenting as a Variant of Postural Orthostatic Tachycardia Syndrome: The Swedish Experience. JACC. Case reports. 2021;3:573&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7946344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33723532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buoite Stella A, Furlanis G, Frezza NA, Valentinotti R, Ajcevic M, Manganotti P. Autonomic dysfunction in post-COVID patients with and witfhout neurological symptoms: a prospective multidomain observational study. Journal of neurology. 2022;269:587&#x2013;596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8359764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34386903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Moloney D, Finucane C, et al. Fatigue following COVID-19 infection is not associated with autonomic dysfunction. PLoS One. 2021;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7906457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33630906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutt E, Vajapey R, Van Iterson EH, et al. Functional capacity and quality of life in the postural tachycardia syndrome: A retrospective cross-sectional study. Ann Med Surg (Lond) 2020;56:72&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7322180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32612820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon J, Kim DY, Byun JI, et al. Orthostatic intolerance symptoms are associated with depression and diminished quality of life in patients with postural tachycardia syndrome. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2016;14:144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5059908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27729043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benrud-Larson LM, Dewar MS, Sandroni P, Rummans TA, Haythornthwaite JA, Low PA. Quality of life in patients with postural tachycardia syndrome. Mayo Clin Proc. 2002;77:531&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12059122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou T, Guan H, Wang L, Zhang Y, Rui M, Ma A. Health-Related Quality of Life in Patients With Different Diseases Measured With the EQ-5D-5L: A Systematic Review. Front Public Health. 2021;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8275935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34268287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeley MC, Gallagher C, Ong E, et al. Poor health-related quality of life in postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome in comparison to a sex- and age-matched normative population. Clin Auton Res. Accepted for publication.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10439037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37338634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR, Arnold AC, Barboi A, et al. Long-COVID postural tachycardia syndrome: an American Autonomic Society statement. Clin Auton Res. 2021;31:365&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7976723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33740207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeley MC, Lau DH. Raising the bar in postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome research: Evidence and challenges. Auton Neurosci. 2021;233</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33714702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>