<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39352145</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cytokine Profile in Children Following SARS-CoV-2 Infection: Preliminary Findings.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000004558</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We provide preliminary evidence that, also in children, Long coronavirus disease (COVID) may be characterized by a proinflammatory signature. Ten Long COVID patients, 7 convalescent subjects after COVID infection and 4 healthy controls were enrolled. When adjusted for sex, children with long COVID had statistically significant differences in the levels of Flt3L, CD5, uPA, CCL23, CD40 and TGF&#x3b1;. When adjusted for age, CCL23 levels remained statistically significant.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buonsenso</LastName><ForeName>Danilo</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8567-2639</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Woman and Child Health and Public Health, Fondazione Policlinico Universitario A. Gemelli IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centers for Global Health Research Studies, Universit&#xe0; Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Area Pediatrica, Dipartimento di Scienze della Vita e di Sanit&#xe0; Pubblica, Universit&#xe0; Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Camporesi</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesia and Intensive Care Unit, "Vittore Buzzi" Children's Hospital, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Sante</LastName><ForeName>Gabriele</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Surgery, Section of Human, Clinical and Forensic Anatomy, University of Perugia, Perugia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sali</LastName><ForeName>Michela</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dipartimento di Scienze di Laboratorio e Infettivologiche, Fondazione Policlinico Universitario "A. Gemelli," IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dipartimento di Scienze biotecnologiche di base, Cliniche intensivologiche e perioperatorie-Sezione di Microbiologia, Universit&#xe0; Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boza</LastName><ForeName>Maria Del Carmen Pereyra</ForeName><Initials>MDCP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dipartimento di Scienze di Laboratorio e Infettivologiche, Fondazione Policlinico Universitario "A. Gemelli," IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morello</LastName><ForeName>Rosa</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Woman and Child Health and Public Health, Fondazione Policlinico Universitario A. Gemelli IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valentini</LastName><ForeName>Piero</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Woman and Child Health and Public Health, Fondazione Policlinico Universitario A. Gemelli IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raffaelli</LastName><ForeName>Francesca</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dipartimento di Scienze Mediche e Chirurgiche, UOC di Malattie infettive, Fondazione Policlinico Universitario A. Gemelli IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodriguez</LastName><ForeName>Lucie</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Women's and Children's Health, Karolinska Institutet, Solna, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Women's and Children's Health, Karolinska Institutet, Solna, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnsson</LastName><ForeName>Anette</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Women's and Children's Health, Karolinska Institutet, Solna, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mugabo</LastName><ForeName>Constantin Habimana</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Women's and Children's Health, Karolinska Institutet, Solna, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lakshmikanth</LastName><ForeName>Tadepally</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Women's and Children's Health, Karolinska Institutet, Solna, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brodin</LastName><ForeName>Petter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Women's and Children's Health, Karolinska Institutet, Solna, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Research Council Laboratory of Medical Sciences (LMS), Imperial College Hammersmith Campus, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39352145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000004558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-990000000-01036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, et al. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post-COVID-19-condition-CA-Clinical-case-definition-2023-1; Accessed May 1, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morello R, Mariani F, Mastrantoni L, et al. Risk factors for post-COVID-19 condition (Long Covid) in children: a prospective cohort study. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;59:101961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia-Hasler C, Br&#xfc;ningk SC, Hoch T, et al. Persistent complement dysregulation with signs of thromboinflammation in active Long COVID. Science. 2024;383:eadg7942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin K, Peluso MJ, Luo X, et al. Long COVID manifests with T cell dysregulation, inflammation and an uncoordinated adaptive immune response to SARS-CoV-2. Nat Immunol. 2024;25:218&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil BA, Elemam NM, Maghazachi AA. Chemokines and chemokine receptors during COVID-19 infection. Comput Struct Biotechnol J. 2021;19:976&#x2013;988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://www.epicentro.iss.it/coronavirus/pdf/sars-cov-2-monitoraggio-varianti-rapporti-periodici-27-maggio-2022.pdf. Accessed May 1, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youn BS, Zhang SM, Broxmeyer HE, et al. Characterization of CKbeta8 and CKbeta8-1: two alternatively spliced forms of human beta-chemokine, chemoattractants for neutrophils, monocytes, and lymphocytes, and potent agonists at CC chemokine receptor 1. Blood. 1998;91:3118&#x2013;3126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel VP, Kreider BL, Li Y, et al. Molecular and functional characterization of two novel human C-C chemokines as inhibitors of two distinct classes of myeloid progenitors. J Exp Med. 1997;185:1163&#x2013;1172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Kim YS, Ko J. CK beta 8/CCL23 induces cell migration via the Gi/Go protein/PLC/PKC delta/NF-kappa B and is involved in inflammatory responses. Life Sci. 2010;86:300&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim CS, Kang JH, Cho HR, et al. Potential involvement of CCL23 in atherosclerotic lesion formation/progression by the enhancement of chemotaxis, adhesion molecule expression, and MMP-2 release from monocytes. Inflamm Res. 2011;60:889&#x2013;895.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rioja I, Hughes FJ, Sharp CH, et al. Potential novel biomarkers of disease activity in rheumatoid arthritis patients: CXCL13, CCL23, transforming growth factor alpha, tumor necrosis factor receptor superfamily member 9, and macrophage colony-stimulating factor. Arthritis Rheum. 2008;58:2257&#x2013;2267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung JH, Kim MO, Koh PO. Proteomic identification of proteins differentially expressed by nicotinamide in focal cerebral ischemic injury. Neuroscience. 2011;174:171&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanaba K, Yoshizaki A, Muroi E, et al. Serum CCL23 levels are increased in patients with systemic sclerosis. Arch Dermatol Res. 2011;303:29&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poposki JA, Keswani A, Kim JK, et al. Tissue proteases convert CCL23 into potent monocyte chemoattractants in patients with chronic rhinosinusitis. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2016;137:1274&#x2013;1277.e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawlak K, My&#x15b;liwiec M, Pawlak D. Effect of diabetes and oxidative stress on plasma CCL23 levels in patients with severe chronic kidney disease. Pol Arch Med Wewn. 2014;124:459&#x2013;466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Martino L, Morello R, et al. Viral persistence in children infected with SARS-CoV-2: current evidence and future research strategies. Lancet Microbe. 2023;4:e745&#x2013;e756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son K-N, Hwang J, Kwon BS, et al. Human CC chemokine CCL23 enhances expression of matrix metalloproteinase-2 and invasion of vascular endothelial cells. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2006;340:498&#x2013;504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han KY, Kim CW, Lee TH, et al. CCL23 up-regulates expression of KDR/Flk-1 and potentiates VEGF-induced proliferation and migration of human endothelial cells. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2009;382:124&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simats A, Garc&#xed;a-Berrocoso T, Penalba A, et al. CCL23: a new CC chemokine involved in human brain damage. J Intern Med. 2018;283:461&#x2013;475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiting CC, Siebert J, Newman AM, et al. Large-scale and comprehensive immune profiling and functional analysis of normal human aging. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0133627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Hu XZ, Li X, et al.; Biomarker team. Potential chemokine biomarkers associated with PTSD onset, risk and resilience as well as stress responses in US military service members. Transl Psychiatry. 2020;10:31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijman RG. Along came COVID-19: The changing landscape of serious childhood infections. Glob Pediatr. 42024;7:100120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>den Hartog G, van Kasteren PB, Schepp RM, et al. Decline of RSV-specific antibodies during the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet Infect Dis. 2023;23:23&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Jacka B, Ballouz S, et al. Improvement of immune dysregulation in individuals with long COVID at 24-months following SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Commun. 2024;15:3315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Valentini P, De Rose C, Tredicine M, Pereyra Boza MDC, Camponeschi C, Morello R, Zampino G, Brooks AES, Rende M, Ria F, Sanguinetti M, Delogu G, Sali M, Di Sante G; On Behalf Of The Gemelli-Pediatric Covid-Team. Recovering or persisting: the immunopathological features of SARS-CoV-2 infection in children. J Clin Med. 2022;11:4363.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>