<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39429966</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-7762</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>44</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Lancet regional health. Europe</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Reg Health Eur</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19 and multiple sclerosis: challenges and lessons for patient care.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100979</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100979</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100979</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.lanepe.2024.100979</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>During the COVID-19 pandemic, people with multiple sclerosis (MS) and their healthcare providers have faced unique challenges related to the interaction between SARS-CoV-2, underlying neurological disease and the use of disease-modifying treatments (DMTs). Key concerns arose, primarily related to the possibility that SARS-CoV-2 infection could trigger the initial demyelinating event or exacerbate disease activity. Another major concern was the safety and efficacy of the COVID-19 vaccines, especially for patients undergoing specific treatments that could weaken their antibody responses. In the post-infection phase, identifying long COVID in patients with MS has been complicated due to the large overlap between post-infection sequelae and MS symptoms. In addition, disruptions in health and rehabilitation services have made it difficult for MS patients to access care. This Series article explores current evidence on the interaction between MS and SARS-CoV-2, identifies the challenges posed by the COVID-19 pandemic in the care of patients with MS, and discusses the significant adoption of digital health solutions, including telemedicine and new technology-based rehabilitation approaches. Based on lessons learned, recommendations and future directions are offered for managing patients with MS, rethinking healthcare systems and improving health outcomes in the post-COVID-19 pandemic era.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prosperini</LastName><ForeName>Luca</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MS Centre, Department of Neurosciences, S. Camillo-Forlanini Hospital, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arrambide</LastName><ForeName>Georgina</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology-Neuroimmunology Department Multiple Sclerosis Centre of Catalonia (Cemcat), Vall d'Hebron Barcelona Hospital Campus, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Celius</LastName><ForeName>Elisabeth G</ForeName><Initials>EG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goletti</LastName><ForeName>Delia</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Research Unit, National Institute for Infectious Diseases "Lazzaro Spallanzani", Istituto di Ricovero e Cura a Carattere Scientifico (IRCCS), Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Killestein</LastName><ForeName>Joep</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Amsterdam University Medical Centers, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kos</LastName><ForeName>Daphne</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Multiple Sclerosis Center, Melsbroek, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>KU Leuven, Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lavorgna</LastName><ForeName>Luigi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>DAI Internal Medicine, Geriatric and Neurology, University Hospital "Luigi Vanvitelli", Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Louapre</LastName><ForeName>Celine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, Paris Brain Institute-ICM, CIC Neurosciences, H&#xf4;pital de la Piti&#xe9; Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re, Assistance Publique H&#xf4;pitaux de Paris, INSERM, CNRS, FCRIN4MS, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sormani</LastName><ForeName>Maria Pia</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences (DISSAL), University of Genoa, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS Ospedale Policlinico San Martino, Genova, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stastna</LastName><ForeName>Dominika</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Centre of Clinical Neuroscience, First Faculty of Medicine, Charles University in Prague and General University Hospital, Prague, Czechia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ziemssen</LastName><ForeName>Tjalf</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Clinical Neuroscience, Department of Neurology, University Hospital Carl Gustav Carus, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Filippo</LastName><ForeName>Massimiliano</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Neurology, Department of Medicine and Surgery, University of Perugia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet Reg Health Eur</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101777707</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-7762</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multiple sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>LP has received personal fees and non-financial support from Biogen, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Merck, Novartis, Roche, Sanofi, Viatris. GA has received compensation for consulting services, speaking honoraria or participation in advisory boards from Merck, Roche, and Horizon Therapeutics; travel support for scientific meetings from Novartis, Roche, ECTRIMS and EAN. She serves as editor for Europe of the Multiple Sclerosis Journal&#x2014;Experimental, Translational and Clinical journal; and as a member of the editorial and scientific committee of Acta Neurol&#xf3;gica Colombiana. She is a member of the International Women in Multiple Sclerosis (iWiMS) network executive committee, of the European Biomarkers in Multiple Sclerosis (BioMS-eu) steering committee, and of the MOGAD Eugene Devic European Network (MEDEN) steering group. EGC has received educational and/or consultancy fees from Alexion, Almirall, Biogen, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Janssen, Sanofi, Merck, Novartis, Roche and Teva. DG has received educational and consultancy fees from Amgen, Almirall, Biogen, Biomerieux, Diasorin, Eli Lilly, Janssen, PDB Biotec, Qiagen, Quidel. She was partially supporedt by the Italian Ministry of Health, Ricerca Corrente, Linea 1. JK has received grants and consulting fees from F. Hoffmann-La Roche Ltd, Biogen, Teva, Merck, Novartis, Immunic, Celgene and Sanofi (payments to institution); reports speaker relationships with F. Hoffmann-La Roche Ltd, Biogen, Celgene, Teva, Merck, Novartis, Sanofi and Viatris (payments to institution). DK has received educational and consultancy fees from Biogen, Teva, Merck and Roche. LL has received educational and consultancy fees from Biogen, Teva, Merck, Roche, Novartis, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Almirall, Horizon, Alexion, Sanofi. CL has received consulting or travel fees from Biogen, Novartis, Roche, Sanofi, Teva and Merck, and research grant from Biogen. MPS has received consulting fees from Biogen, Novartis, Roche, Sanofi, Merck, Alexion, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Immunic. DS has received financial support for conference travel and/or speaker honoraria from. Novartis, Biogen, Merck, Teva, Janssen-Cilag, and Roche and is also supported by the Charles University: Cooperation Program in Neuroscience and by the National Institute for. Neurological Research project funded by the European Union&#x2013;Next Generation EU. (Programme EXCELES, ID Project No. LX22NPO5107). TZ has received consulting or serving on speaker bureaus for Alexion, Biogen, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Roche, Sandoz, Novartis, Merck, Teva and Sanofi, as well as research support from Biogen, Novartis, Merck, Roche and Sanofi. MDF participated on advisory boards and steering committees for and received speaker or writing honoraria, research support and funding for travelling from Alexion, BMS, Bayer, Biogen Idec, Genzyme, Horizon, Janssen, Merck, Mylan, Novartis, Roche, Siemens Healthineers, Teva and Viatris.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39429966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11486927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanepe.2024.100979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-7762(24)00146-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pugliatti M., Berger T., Hartung H.P., Oreja-Guevara C., Bar-Or A. Multiple sclerosis in the era of COVID-19: disease course, DMTs and SARS-CoV2 vaccinations. Curr Opin Neurol. 2022;35(3):319&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35674075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanou M.I., Palaiodimou L., Theodorou A., et al. Safety of COVID-19 vaccines in multiple sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Mult Scler. 2023;29(4-5):585&#x2013;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9895285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36722184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etemadifar M., Nouri H., Pitzalis M., et al. Multiple sclerosis disease-modifying therapy and COVID-19 vaccines: a practical review and meta-analysis. J&#xa0;Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2022;93(9):986&#x2013;994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35688629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhry F., Jageka C., Levy P.D., Cerghet M., Lisak R.P. Review of the COVID-19 risk in multiple sclerosis. J&#xa0;Cell Immunol. 2021;3(2):68&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8098748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33959727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louapre C., Collongues N., Stankoff B., et al. Clinical characteristics and outcomes in patients with coronavirus disease 2019 and multiple sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(9):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7320356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32589189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sormani M.P., Schiavetti I., Carmisciano L., et al. COVID-19 severity in multiple sclerosis: putting data into context. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflammation. 2022;9(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8579249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34753829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garjani A., Middleton R.M., Nicholas R., Evangelou N. Recovery from COVID-19 in multiple sclerosis: a prospective and longitudinal cohort study of the United Kingdom multiple sclerosis register. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflammation. 2022;9(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8631790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34848503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prosperini L., Tortorella C., Haggiag S., et al. Increased risk of death from COVID-19 in multiple sclerosis: a pooled analysis of observational studies. J&#xa0;Neurol. 2022;269(3):1114&#x2013;1120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8446478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34533590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiavetti I., Carmisciano L., Ponzano M., et al. Signs and symptoms of COVID-19 in patients with multiple sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2022;29(12):3728&#x2013;3736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36086905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prosperini L., Tortorella C., Haggiag S., et al. Determinants of COVID-19-related lethality in multiple sclerosis: a meta-regression of observational studies. J&#xa0;Neurol. 2022;269(5):2275&#x2013;2285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8726522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34984514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson-Yap S., Pirmani A., Kalincik T., et al. Updated results of the COVID-19 in MS global data sharing initiative: anti-CD20 and other risk factors associated with COVID-19 severity. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflammation. 2022;9(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9423711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36038263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barzegar M., Mirmosayyeb O., Gajarzadeh M., et al. COVID-19 among patients with multiple sclerosis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflammation. 2021;8(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8142838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34016734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oncel I., Alici N., Solmaz I., et al. The outcome of COVID-19 in pediatric-onset multiple sclerosis patients. Pediatr Neurol. 2022;134:7&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9186527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35772229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salter A., Cross A.H., Cutter G.R., et al. COVID-19 in the pregnant or postpartum MS patient: symptoms and outcomes. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2022;65</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9252864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35839562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvert C., Brockway M.M., Zoega H., et al. Changes in preterm birth and stillbirth during COVID-19 lockdowns in 26 countries. Nat Hum Behav. 2023;7(4):529&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10129868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36849590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sormani M.P., De Rossi N., Schiavetti I., et al. Disease-modifying therapies and coronavirus disease 2019 severity in multiple sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2021;89(4):780&#x2013;789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33480077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sormani M.P., Salvetti M., Labauge P., et al. DMTs and Covid-19 severity in MS: a pooled analysis from Italy and France. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2021;8(8):1738&#x2013;1744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8351392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34240579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salter A., Fox R.J., Newsome S.D., et al. Outcomes and risk factors associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection in a North American registry of patients with multiple sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78(6):699&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7980147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33739362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spelman T., Forsberg L., McKay K., Glaser A., Hillert J. Increased rate of hospitalisation for COVID-19 among rituximab-treated multiple sclerosis patients: a study of the Swedish multiple sclerosis registry. Mult Scler. 2022;28(7):1051&#x2013;1059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34212816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E., Bower H., McKay K.A., et al. COVID-19 clinical outcomes and DMT of MS patients and population-based controls. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2022;9(9):1449&#x2013;1458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9463950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35993445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastard P., Rosen L.B., Zhang Q., et al. Autoantibodies against type I IFNs in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science. 2020;370(6515)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Januel E., Hajage D., Labauge P., et al. Association between anti-CD20 therapies and COVID-19 severity among patients with relapsing-remitting and progressive multiple sclerosis. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10290250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37351881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiner T., Wilson-Murphy M., Mendelt-Tillema J., et al. Characteristics of pediatric patients with multiple sclerosis and related disorders infected with SARS-CoV-2. Mult Scler. 2023;29(4&#x2013;5):576&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10040482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36960480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng K., Li X., Yang D., et al.  Risk of autoimmune diseases following COVID-19 and the potential protective effect from vaccination: a population-based cohort study. eClinicalMedicine. 2023;63 https://www.thelancet.com/journals/eclinm/article/PIIS2589-5370(23)00331-0/fulltext Available at:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10458663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37637754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun D., Du Q., Wang R., et al. COVID-19 and the risk of neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: a Mendelian randomization study. Front Immunol. 2023;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10414539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37575255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellucci G., Rinaldi V., Buscarinu M.C., et al.  Multiple sclerosis and SARS-CoV-2: has the interplay started? Front Immunol. 2021;12 https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fimmu.2021.755333 Available at:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.755333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8503550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34646278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelena G., Casas M., Eizaguirre M.B., et al. Can COVID-19 exacerbate multiple sclerosis symptoms? A case series analysis. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2022;57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35158474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmani M., Moghadasi A.N., Shahi S., et al. COVID-19 and its implications on the clinico-radiological course of multiple sclerosis: a case&#x2013;control study. Med Clin. 2023;160(5):187&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9364744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36089420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeters G., Van Remoortel A., Nagels G., Van Schependom J., D&#x2019;haeseleer M. Occurrence and severity of coronavirus disease 2019 are associated with clinical disability worsening in patients with multiple sclerosis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflammation. 2023;10(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9942531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36807080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bsteh G., Assar H., Gradl C., et al. Long-term outcome after COVID-19 infection in multiple sclerosis: a nation-wide multicenter matched-control study. Eur J Neurol. 2022 doi: 10.1111/ene.15477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9350009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35751475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etemadifar M., Abhari A.P., Nouri H., et al. Does COVID-19 increase the long-term relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis clinical activity? A cohort study. BMC Neurol. 2022;22(1):64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8861623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35193507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghajanian S., Shafiee A., Akhondi A., et al. The effect of COVID-19 on Multiple Sclerosis relapse: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2023;81</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37979408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montini F., Nozzolillo A., Tedone N., et al. COVID-19 has no impact on disease activity, progression and cognitive performance in people with multiple sclerosis: a 2-year study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2023;95(4):342&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37857497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babtain F., Bajafar A., Nazmi O., et al. The disease course of multiple sclerosis before and during COVID-19 pandemic: a retrospective five-year study. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2022;65</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35759904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano J.B., Murthy S., Marshall J.C., et al. A&#xa0;clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(4):e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monje M., Iwasaki A. The neurobiology of long COVID. Neuron. 2022;110(21):3484&#x2013;3496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9537254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36288726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rousseau B.A., Bhaduri-McIntosh S. Inflammation and epstein-barr virus at the crossroads of multiple sclerosis and post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 infection. Viruses. 2023;15(4):949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10141000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37112929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H.E., McCorkell L., Vogel J.M., Topol E.J. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein S.R., Ramelli S.C., Grazioli A., et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence in the human body and brain at autopsy. Nature. 2022;612(7941):758&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9749650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36517603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verde F., Milone I., Bulgarelli I., et al. Serum neurofilament light chain levels in Covid-19 patients without major neurological manifestations. J&#xa0;Neurol. 2022;269(11):5691&#x2013;5701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9252542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35781535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai Y.-J., Liu S.-H., Manachevakul S., et al.  Biomarkers in long COVID-19: a systematic review. Front Med. 2023;10 https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fmed.2023.1085988 Available at:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2023.1085988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9895110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36744129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waltz E. Could long COVID be linked to herpes viruses? Early data offer a hint. Nature. 2022 https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-022-02296-5 Available at:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36008721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y., Yuan D., Chen D.G., et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185(5):881&#x2013;895.e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornevik K., M&#xfc;nz C., Cohen J.I., Ascherio A. Epstein-Barr virus as a leading cause of multiple sclerosis: mechanisms and implications. Nat Rev Neurol. 2023;19(3):160&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36759741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etter M.M., Martins T.A., Kulsvehagen L., et al. Severe Neuro-COVID is associated with peripheral immune signatures, autoimmunity and neurodegeneration: a prospective cross-sectional study. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):6777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9645766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36351919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia-Hasler C., Br&#xfc;ningk S.C., Hoch T., et al. Persistent complement dysregulation with signs of thromboinflammation in active long Covid. Science. 2024;383(6680)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38236961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi B., Sudry T., Flaks-Manov N., et al. Long covid outcomes at one year after mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: nationwide cohort study. BMJ. 2023;380</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9832503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36631153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramoff B.A., Hentschel C., Dillingham I.A., et al. The association of multiple sclerosis, traumatic brain injury, and spinal cord injury to acute and long COVID-19 outcomes. PM R. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11189756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38145343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayward W., Buch E.R., Norato G., et al. Procedural motor memory deficits in patients with long-COVID. Neurology. 2024;102(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11097756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38237090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Filippo M., Portaccio E., Mancini A., Calabresi P. Multiple sclerosis and cognition: synaptic failure and network dysfunction. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2018;19(10):599&#x2013;609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30158590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menculini G., Mancini A., Gaetani L., et al. Psychiatric symptoms in multiple sclerosis: a biological perspective on synaptic and network dysfunction. J&#xa0;Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2023;94(5):389&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36653171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zrzavy T., Kollaritsch H., Rommer P.S., et al. Vaccination in multiple sclerosis: friend or foe? Front Immunol. 2019;10:1883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6693409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31440255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail I.I., Salama S. A&#xa0;systematic review of cases of CNS demyelination following COVID-19 vaccination. J&#xa0;Neuroimmunol. 2022;362</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8577051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34839149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S., Muccilli A., Schneider R., Selchen D., Krysko K. Acute central nervous system demyelination following COVID-19 vaccination. Neurology. 2022;99(23_Supplement_2):S34&#x2013;S35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi V., Bellucci G., Buscarinu M.C., et al. CNS inflammatory demyelinating events after COVID-19 vaccines: a case series and systematic review. Front Neurol. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9752005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36530641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achiron A., Dolev M., Menascu S., et al. COVID-19 vaccination in patients with multiple sclerosis: what we have learnt by February 2021. Mult Scler. 2021;27(6):864&#x2013;870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8114441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33856242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Filippo M., Cordioli C., Malucchi S., et al. mRNA COVID-19 vaccines do not increase the short-term risk of clinical relapses in multiple sclerosis. J&#xa0;Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2022;93(4):448&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34408003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Filippo M., Ferraro D., Ragonese P., et al. SARS-CoV-2 vaccination and multiple sclerosis: a large multicentric study on relapse risk after the third booster dose. J&#xa0;Neurol. 2023;271(1):24&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10769943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37922069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boekel L., Steenhuis M., Hooijberg F., et al. Antibody development after COVID-19 vaccination in patients with autoimmune diseases in The Netherlands: a substudy of data from two prospective cohort studies. Lancet Rheumatol. 2021;3(11):e778&#x2013;e788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8346242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34396154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wieske L., Kummer L.Y.L., van Dam K.P.J., et al. Risk factors associated with short-term adverse events after SARS-CoV-2 vaccination in patients with immune-mediated inflammatory diseases. BMC Med. 2022;20(1):100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8889379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35236350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frahm N., Fneish F., Ellenberger D., et al. SARS-CoV-2 vaccination in patients with multiple sclerosis in Germany and the United Kingdom: gender-specific results from a longitudinal observational study. Lancet Reg Health Eur. 2022;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9438509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36090519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q., Dudley M.Z., Chen X., et al. Evaluation of the safety profile of COVID-19 vaccines: a rapid review. BMC Med. 2021;19(1):173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8315897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34315454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capone F., Rossi M., Cruciani A., et al. Safety, immunogenicity, efficacy, and acceptability of COVID-19 vaccination in people with multiple sclerosis: a narrative review. Neural Regen Res. 2023;18(2):284&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9396498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35900404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capuano R., Altieri M., Conte M., et al. Humoral response and safety of the third booster dose of BNT162b2 mRNA COVID-19 vaccine in patients with multiple sclerosis treated with ocrelizumab or fingolimod. J&#xa0;Neurol. 2022;269(12):6185&#x2013;6192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9314242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yap S.M., Al Hinai M., Gaughan M., et al. Vaccine hesitancy among people with multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2021;56</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8411656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34507240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalron A., Dolev M., Menascu S., et al. Overcoming COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy in people with multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler. 2021;27(Suppl 2):218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proietti F., Landi D., Ponzano M., et al. COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy among Italian people with multiple sclerosis. Neurol Sci. 2023;44(3):803&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9790761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36567409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suthar A.B., Wang J., Seffren V., et al. Public health impact of covid-19 vaccines in the US: observational study. BMJ. 2022;377</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9044401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35477670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sette A., Sidney J., Crotty S. T&#xa0;cell responses to SARS-CoV-2. Annu Rev Immunol. 2023;41:343&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36750314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoury D.S., Cromer D., Reynaldi A., et al. Neutralizing antibody levels are highly predictive of immune protection from symptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med. 2021;27(7):1205&#x2013;1211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34002089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarke A., Coelho C.H., Zhang Z., et al. SARS-CoV-2 vaccination induces immunological T cell memory able to cross-recognize variants from Alpha to Omicron. Cell. 2022;185(5):847&#x2013;859.e11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8784649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35139340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrone L., Picchianti-Diamanti A., Sebastiani G.D., et al. Humoral and cellular responses to spike of &#x3b4; SARS-CoV-2 variant in vaccinated patients with immune-mediated inflammatory diseases. Int J Infect Dis. 2022;121:24&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9023365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35462039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrone L., Tortorella C., Aiello A., et al. Humoral and cellular response to spike of delta SARS-CoV-2 variant in vaccinated patients with multiple sclerosis. Front Neurol. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9194677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35711277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tortorella C., Aiello A., Gasperini C., et al. Humoral- and T-cell-specific immune responses to SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccination in patients with MS using different disease-modifying therapies. Neurology. 2022;98(5):e541&#x2013;e554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8826460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34810244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gombolay G.Y., Dutt M., Tyor W. Immune responses to SARS-CoV-2 vaccination in multiple sclerosis: a systematic review/meta-analysis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2022;9(8):1321&#x2013;1331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9349877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35852423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conway S., Saxena S., Baecher-Allan C., et al. Preserved T cell but attenuated antibody response in MS patients on fingolimod and ocrelizumab following 2nd and 3rd SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccine. Mult Scler Exp Transl Clin. 2023;9(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10086198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37057191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proschmann U., Mueller-Enz M., Woopen C., et al. Differential effects of selective versus unselective sphingosine 1-phosphate receptor modulators on T- and B-cell response to SARS-CoV-2 vaccination. Mult Scler. 2023;29(14):1849&#x2013;1859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10687795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37776101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vita S., Rosati S., Ascoli Bartoli T., et al. Monoclonal antibodies for pre- and postexposure prophylaxis of COVID-19: review of the literature. Pathog Basel Switz. 2022;11(8):882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9412407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36015003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggieri S., Aiello A., Tortorella C., et al. Dynamic evolution of humoral and T-cell specific immune response to COVID-19 mRNA vaccine in patients with multiple sclerosis followed until the booster dose. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(10):8525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10218688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37239872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiavetti I., Cordioli C., Stromillo M.L., et al. Breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infections in MS patients on disease-modifying therapies. Mult Scler. 2022;28(13):2106&#x2013;2111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35735030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capuano R., Prosperini L., Altieri M., et al. Symptomatic COVID-19 course and outcomes after three mRNA vaccine doses in multiple sclerosis patients treated with high-efficacy DMTs. Mult Scler. 2023;29(7):856&#x2013;865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10183344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37165941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciccarelli O., Cohen J.A., Thompson A. Response of the multiple sclerosis community to COVID-19. Mult Scler. 2020;26(10):1134&#x2013;1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7720349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32924837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sastre-Garriga J., Tintor&#xe9; M., Montalban X. Keeping standards of multiple sclerosis care through the COVID-19 pandemic. Mult Scler. 2020;26(10):1153&#x2013;1156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32552382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manacorda T., Bandiera P., Terzuoli F., et al. Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on persons with multiple sclerosis: early findings from a survey on disruptions in care and self-reported outcomes. J&#xa0;Health Serv Res Policy. 2021;26(3):189&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8182334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33337256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss B.P., Mahajan K.R., Bermel R.A., et al. Multiple sclerosis management during the COVID-19 pandemic. Mult Scler. 2020;26(10):1163&#x2013;1171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7424611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32772807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baba C., Yigit P., Dastan S., et al. Challenges of persons with multiple sclerosis on ocrelizumab treatment during COVID-19 pandemic. Neurol Clin Neurosci. 2022;10(1):3&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34909197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghadasi A.N., Vaheb S., Hamtaei-Ghashti S., et al. Fear of re-infection, relapse, and anxiety during COVID-19 pandemic in patients with multiple sclerosis: a multi-center study. Curr J Neurol. 2023;22(2):82&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10460923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38011388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colais P., Cascini S., Balducci M., et al. Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on access to healthcare services amongst patients with multiple sclerosis in the Lazio region, Italy. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28(10):3403&#x2013;3410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33896086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownlee W., Bourdette D., Broadley S., Killestein J., Ciccarelli O. Treating multiple sclerosis and neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder during the COVID-19 pandemic. Neurology. 2020;94(22):949&#x2013;952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32241953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giovannoni G., Hawkes C., Lechner-Scott J., et al. The COVID-19 pandemic and the use of MS disease-modifying therapies. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2020;39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7138156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32334820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Lierop Z.Y., Toorop A.A., van Ballegoij W.J., et al. Personalized B-cell tailored dosing of ocrelizumab in patients with multiple sclerosis during the COVID-19 pandemic. Mult Scler. 2022;28(7):1121&#x2013;1125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9131403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34240631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolfes L., Pawlitzki M., Pfeuffer S., et al. Ocrelizumab extended interval dosing in multiple sclerosis in times of COVID-19. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflammation. 2021;8(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8362352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34261812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zangh&#xec; A., Avolio C., Signoriello E., et al. Is it time for ocrelizumab extended interval dosing in relapsing remitting MS? Evidence from an Italian multicenter experience during the COVID-19 pandemic. Neurotherapeutics. 2022;19(5):1535&#x2013;1545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9422942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36036858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerrieri S., Bucca C., Nozzolillo A., et al. Ocrelizumab extended-interval dosing in multiple sclerosis during SARS-CoV-2 pandemic: a real-world experience. Eur J Neurol. 2023;30(9):2859&#x2013;2864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37227923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otero-Romero S., Lebrun-Fr&#xe9;nay C., Reyes S., et al. European committee for treatment and research in multiple sclerosis and European academy of neurology consensus on vaccination in people with multiple sclerosis: improving immunization strategies in the era of highly active immunotherapeutic drugs. Eur J Neurol. 2023;30(8):2144&#x2013;2176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37293849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Affinito G., Trama U., Palumbo L., et al. Impact of COVID-19 and system recovery in delivering healthcare to people with multiple sclerosis: a population-based Study. Neurol Sci. 2023;44(11):3771&#x2013;3779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10570189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37672178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orschiedt J., Jacyshyn-Owen E., Kahn M., et al. The influence of the COVID-19 pandemic on the prescription of multiple sclerosis medication in Germany. Biomed Pharmacother. 2023;158</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9756211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36527843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedull&#xe0; L., Santoyo-Medina C., Novotna K., et al. Physical activity in multiple sclerosis: meeting the guidelines at the time of the COVID-19 pandemic. J Neurol Phys Ther. 2023;47(2):112&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36753458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalgas U, Langeskov-Christensen M, Stenager E, Riemenschneider M, Hvid LG. Exercise as medicine in multiple sclerosis-time for a paradigm shift: preventive, symptomatic, and disease-modifying aspects and perspectives. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2019;19(11):88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31720862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilutti L.A., Platta M.E., Motl R.W., Latimer-Cheung A.E. The safety of exercise training in multiple sclerosis: a systematic review. J Neurol Sci. 2014;343(1&#x2013;2):3&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24880538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsdottir J, Santoyo-Medina C, Kahraman T, et al. Changes in physiotherapy services and use of technology for people with multiple sclerosis during the COVID-19 pandemic. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2023;71:104520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36724646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strober L, Weber E, Lequerica A, Chiaravalloti N. Surviving a global pandemic: the experience of depression, anxiety, and loneliness among individuals with multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2022;58:103497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8742660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35066271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costabile T, Carotenuto A, Lavorgna L, et al. COVID-19 pandemic and mental distress in multiple sclerosis: implications for clinical management. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28(10):3375&#x2013;3383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33043560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altieri M., Capuano R., Bisecco A., et al. The psychological impact of Covid-19 pandemic on people with Multiple Sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2022;61:103774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8956358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35381533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novotn&#xe1; K., V&#x11b;trovsk&#xe1; R., Struskova E., et al. Despite the COVID-19 pandemic, people with chronic neurological disease (Multiple Sclerosis) are trying to maintain physical activity. Stud Sport. 2022;16(2):46&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brichetto G., Tacchino A., Leocani L., Kos D. Impact of Covid-19 emergency on rehabilitation services for Multiple Sclerosis: an international RIMS survey. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2022;67</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9474392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36130457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes S., Cunningham A.L., Kalincik T., et al. Update on the management of multiple sclerosis during the COVID-19 pandemic and post pandemic: an international consensus statement. J&#xa0;Neuroimmunol. 2021;357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8183006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34139567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieneck C., McLauchlan M., Phillips S. Healthcare cybersecurity ethical concerns during the COVID-19 global pandemic: a rapid review. Healthcare. 2023;11(22):2983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10671505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37998475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavorgna L., Brigo F., Moccia M., et al. e-Health and multiple sclerosis: an update. Mult Scler. 2018;24(13):1657&#x2013;1664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30231004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keszler P., Maloni H., Miles Z., Jin S., Wallin M. Telemedicine and multiple sclerosis: a survey of health care providers before and during the COVID-19 pandemic. Int J MS Care. 2022;24(6):266&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9749831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36545646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghi N., Eelen P., Nagels G., et al. Innovating care in multiple&#xa0;sclerosis: feasibility of synchronous internet-based teleconsultation for longitudinal clinical monitoring. J&#xa0;Pers Med. 2022;12(3):433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8948780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35330433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dillenseger A., Weidemann M.L., Trentzsch K., et al. Digital biomarkers in multiple sclerosis. Brain Sci. 2021;11(11):1519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8615428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34827518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voigt I., Inojosa H., Dillenseger A., et al. Digital twins for multiple sclerosis. Front Immunol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8128142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34012452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>d'Arma A., Rossi V., Pugnetti L., et al. Managing chronic disease in the COVID-19 pandemic: an e-learning application to promote a healthy lifestyle for persons with multiple sclerosis. Psychol Health Med. 2022;27(2):428&#x2013;435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34130565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riva A, Barcella V, Benatti SV, et al. Vaccinations in patients with multiple sclerosis: a Delphi consensus statement. Mult Scler. 2021;27(3):347&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32940128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>