<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37398206</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2693-5015</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Research square</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Res Sq</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proteomic landscape of astrocytes and pericytes infected with HIV/SARS-CoV-2 mono/co-infection, impacting on neurological complications.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">rs.3.rs-3031591</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.21203/rs.3.rs-3031591/v1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Although most individuals recover from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) within a few weeks, some people continue to experience a wide range of symptoms known as post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (PASC) or long COVID. Majority of patients with PASC develop neurological disorders like brain fog, fatigue, mood swings, sleep disorders, loss of smell and test among others collectively called neuro-PASC. While the people living with HIV (PWH) do not have a higher risk of developing severe disease and mortality/morbidity due to COVID-19. As a large section of PWH suffered from HIV-associated neurocognitive disorders (HAND), it is essential to understand the impact of neuro-PASC on people with HAND. In pursuit of this, we infected HIV/SARS-CoV-2 alone or together in primary human astrocytes and pericytes and performed proteomics to understand the impact of co-infection in the central nervous system.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Primary human astrocytes and pericytes were infected with SARS-CoV-2 or HIV or HIV + SARS-CoV-2. The concentration of HIV and SARS-CoV-2 genomic RNA in the culture supernatant was quantified using reverse transcriptase quantitative real time polymerase chain reaction (RT-qPCR). This was followed by a quantitative proteomics analysis of mock, HIV, SARS-CoV-2, and HIV + SARS-CoV-2 infected astrocytes and pericytes to understand the impact of the virus in CNS cell types.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Both healthy and HIV-infected astrocytes and pericytes support abortive/low level of SARS-CoV-2 replication. In both mono-infected and co-infected cells, we observe a modest increase in the expression of SARS-CoV-2 host cell entry factors (ACE2, TMPRSS2, NRP1, and TRIM28) and inflammatory mediators (IL-6, TNF-&#x3b1;, IL-1&#x3b2; and IL-18). Quantitative proteomic analysis has identified uniquely regulated pathways in mock vs SARS-CoV-2, mock vs HIV + SARS-CoV-2, and HIV vs HIV + SARS-CoV-2 infected astrocytes and pericytes. The gene set enrichment analysis revealed that the top ten enriched pathways are linked to several neurodegenerative disorders, including Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's disease, Huntington's disease, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Our study emphasizes the significance of long-term monitoring of patients co-infected with HIV and SARS-CoV-2 to detect and understand the development of neurological abnormalities. By unraveling the molecular mechanisms involved, we can identify potential targets for future therapeutic interventions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Acharya</LastName><ForeName>Arpan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Nebraska Medical Center.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ambikan</LastName><ForeName>Anoop T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Karolinska Institutet.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thurman</LastName><ForeName>Michellie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Nebraska Medical Center.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malik</LastName><ForeName>Mohid Reza</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Nebraska Medical Center.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dyavar</LastName><ForeName>Shetty Ravi</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Nebraska Medical Center.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>V&#xe9;gv&#xe1;ri</LastName><ForeName>&#xc1;kos</ForeName><Initials>&#xc1;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Karolinska Institutet.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neogi</LastName><ForeName>Ujjwal</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Karolinska Institutet.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Byrareddy</LastName><ForeName>Siddappa N</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Nebraska Medical Center.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 DA052845</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Res Sq</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101768035</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2693-5015</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACE-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Astrocytes and Pericytes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Co-infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HAND</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIV</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LONG-Covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37398206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10312942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.3.rs-3031591/v1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">rs.3.rs-3031591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hartley SL, Fleming V, Piro-Gambetti B, Cohen A, Ances BM, Yassa MA, Brickman AM, Handen BL, Head E, Mapstone M, et al.: Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on daily life, mood, and behavior of adults with Down syndrome. Disabil Health J 2022, 15:101278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8849846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35256308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massetti GM, Jackson BR, Brooks JT, Perrine CG, Reott E, Hall AJ, Lubar D, Williams IT, Ritchey MD, Patel P, et al.: Summary of Guidance for Minimizing the Impact of COVID-19 on Individual Persons, Communities, and Health Care Systems - United States, August 2022. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2022, 71:1057&#x2013;1064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9400529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35980866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singu S, Acharya A, Challagundla K, Byrareddy SN: Impact of Social Determinants of Health on the Emerging COVID-19 Pandemic in the United States. Front Public Health 2020, 8:406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32793544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqi HK, Libby P, Ridker PM: COVID-19 - A vascular disease. Trends Cardiovasc Med 2021, 31:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7556303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33068723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya A, Kevadiya BD, Gendelman HE, Byrareddy SN: SARS-CoV-2 Infection Leads to Neurological Dysfunction. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol 2020, 15:167&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7244399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32447746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algahtani H, Subahi A, Shirah B: Neurological Complications of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus: A Report of Two Cases and Review of the Literature. Case Rep Neurol Med 2016, 2016:3502683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4864560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27239356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, He L, Zhang Q, Huang Z, Che X, Hou J, Wang H, Shen H, Qiu L, Li Z, et al.: Organ distribution of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) associated coronavirus (SARS-CoV) in SARS patients: implications for pathogenesis and virus transmission pathways. J Pathol 2004, 203:622&#x2013;630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7167761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15141376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spudich S, Nath A: Nervous system consequences of COVID-19. Science 2022, 375:267&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35050660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balcom EF, Nath A, Power C: Acute and chronic neurological disorders in COVID-19: potential mechanisms of disease. Brain 2021, 144:3576&#x2013;3588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8719840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34398188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsivgoulis G, Palaiodimou L, Zand R, Lioutas VA, Krogias C, Katsanos AH, Shoamanesh A, Sharma VK, Shahjouei S, Baracchini C, et al.: COVID-19 and cerebrovascular diseases: a comprehensive overview. Ther Adv Neurol Disord 2020, 13:1756286420978004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33343709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term neurological sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med 2022, 28:2269&#x2013;2270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9528864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36192556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertagnolio S, Thwin SS, Silva R, Nagarajan S, Jassat W, Fowler R, Haniffa R, Reveiz L, Ford N, Doherty M, Diaz J: Clinical features of, and risk factors for, severe or fatal COVID-19 among people living with HIV admitted to hospital: analysis of data from the WHO Global Clinical Platform of COVID-19. Lancet HIV 2022, 9:e486&#x2013;e495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9090268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35561704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel RH, Acharya A, Chand HS, Mohan M, Byrareddy SN: Human Immunodeficiency Virus and Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 Coinfection: A Systematic Review of the Literature and Challenges. AIDS Res Hum Retroviruses 2021, 37:266&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8035919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33599163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varshney K, Ghosh P, Stiles H, Iriowen R: Risk Factors for COVID-19 Mortality Among People Living with HIV: A Scoping Review. AIDS Behav 2022, 26:2256&#x2013;2265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8756751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35024992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smail RC, Brew BJ: HIV-associated neurocognitive disorder. Handb Clin Neurol 2018, 152:75&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29604986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irollo E, Luchetta J, Ho C, Nash B, Meucci O: Mechanisms of neuronal dysfunction in HIV-associated neurocognitive disorders. Cell Mol Life Sci 2021, 78:4283&#x2013;4303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8164580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33585975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saylor D, Dickens AM, Sacktor N, Haughey N, Slusher B, Pletnikov M, Mankowski JL, Brown A, Volsky DJ, McArthur JC: HIV-associated neurocognitive disorder--pathogenesis and prospects for treatment. Nat Rev Neurol 2016, 12:234&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4937456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26965674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bocci M, Oudenaarden C, Saenz-Sarda X, Simren J, Eden A, Sjolund J, Moller C, Gisslen M, Zetterberg H, Englund E, Pietras K: Infection of Brain Pericytes Underlying Neuropathology of COVID-19 Patients. Int J Mol Sci 2021, 22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8583965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34769052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullard JF, Lee HC, Voloudakis G, Suo S, Javidfar B, Shao Z, Peter C, Zhang W, Jiang S, Corvelo A, et al.: Single-nucleus transcriptome analysis of human brain immune response in patients with severe COVID-19. Genome Med 2021, 13:118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8287557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34281603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira LG, de Souza Angelo Y, Yamamoto P, Carregari VC, Crunfli F, Reis-de-Oliveira G, Costa L, Vendramini PH, Duque EA, Dos Santos NB, et al.: SARS-CoV-2 infection impacts carbon metabolism and depends on glutamine for replication in Syrian hamster astrocytes. J Neurochem 2022, 163:113&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9350388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35880385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaddaj-Mallat R, Aldib N, Bernard M, Paquette AS, Ferreira A, Lecordier S, Saghatelyan A, Flamand L, ElAli A: SARS-CoV-2 deregulates the vascular and immune functions of brain pericytes via Spike protein. Neurobiol Dis 2021, 161:105561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8590447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34780863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crunfli F, Carregari VC, Veras FP, Silva LS, Nogueira MH, Antunes A, Vendramini PH, Valenca AGF, Brandao-Teles C, Zuccoli GDS, et al.: Morphological, cellular, and molecular basis of brain infection in COVID-19 patients. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2022, 119:e2200960119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9436354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35951647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Melo GD, Lazarini F, Levallois S, Hautefort C, Michel V, Larrous F, Verillaud B, Aparicio C, Wagner S, Gheusi G, et al.: COVID-19-related anosmia is associated with viral persistence and inflammation in human olfactory epithelium and brain infection in hamsters. Sci Transl Med 2021, 13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8158965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33941622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S, Fishell G: In SARS-CoV-2, astrocytes are in it for the long haul. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2022, 119:e2209130119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9335203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35858460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya A, Pathania AS, Pandey K, Thurman M, Vann KR, Kutateladze TG, Challagundala KB, Durden DL, Byrareddy SN : PI3K-alpha/mTOR/BRD4 inhibitor alone or in combination with other anti-virals blocks replication of SARS-CoV-2 and its variants of concern including Delta and Omicron. Clin Transl Med 2022, 12:e806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8989379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35390226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghorpade A, Nukuna A, Che M, Haggerty S, Persidsky Y, Carter E, Carhart L, Shafer L, Gendelman HE: Human immunodeficiency virus neurotropism: an analysis of viral replication and cytopathicity for divergent strains in monocytes and microglia. J Virol 1998, 72:3340&#x2013;3350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC109814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9525661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan L, Rabi SA, Laird GM, Eisele EE, Zhang H, Margolick JB, Siliciano RF: A novel PCR assay for quantification of HIV-1 RNA. J Virol 2013, 87:6521&#x2013;6525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3648108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23536672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devadoss D, Acharya A, Manevski M, Houserova D, Cioffi MD, Pandey K, Nair M, Chapagain P, Mirsaeidi M, Borchert GM, et al.: Immunomodulatory LncRNA on antisense strand of ICAM-1 augments SARS-CoV-2 infection-associated airway mucoinflammatory phenotype. iScience 2022, 25:104685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9242679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35789750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie ME, Phipson B, Wu D, Hu Y, Law CW, Shi W, Smyth GK: limma powers differential expression analyses for RNA-sequencing and microarray studies. Nucleic Acids Res 2015, 43:e47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4402510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25605792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varemo L, Nielsen J, Nookaew I: Enriching the gene set analysis of genome-wide data by incorporating directionality of gene expression and combining statistical hypotheses and methods. Nucleic Acids Res 2013, 41:4378&#x2013;4391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3632109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23444143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Z, Eils R, Schlesner M: Complex heatmaps reveal patterns and correlations in multidimensional genomic data. Bioinformatics 2016, 32:2847&#x2013;2849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27207943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heberle H, Meirelles GV, da Silva FR, Telles GP, Minghim R: InteractiVenn: a web-based tool for the analysis of sets through Venn diagrams. BMC Bioinformatics 2015, 16:169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4455604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25994840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya A, Olwenyi OA, Thurman M, Pandey K, Morsey BM, Lamberty B, Ferguson N, Callen S, Fang Q, Buch SJ, et al.: Chronic morphine administration differentially modulates viral reservoirs in SIVmac251 infected rhesus macaque model. J Virol 2020, 95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8092838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33328304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge SX, Jung D, Yao R: ShinyGO: a graphical gene-set enrichment tool for animals and plants. Bioinformatics 2020, 36:2628&#x2013;2629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7178415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31882993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramani A, Pranty AI, Gopalakrishnan J: Neurotropic Effects of SARS-CoV-2 Modeled by the Human Brain Organoids. Stem Cell Reports 2021, 16:373&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7879157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33631123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canet G, Dias C, Gabelle A, Simonin Y, Gosselet F, Marchi N, Makinson A, Tuaillon E, Van de Perre P, Givalois L, Salinas S: HIV Neuroinfection and Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease: Similarities and Potential Links? Front Cell Neurosci 2018, 12:307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6141679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30254568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#x2019;Kovski P, Kratzel A, Steiner S, Stalder H, Thiel V: Coronavirus biology and replication: implications for SARS-CoV-2. Nat Rev Microbiol 2021, 19:155&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7592455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33116300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik JR, Acharya A, Avedissian SN, Byrareddy SN, Fletcher CV, Podany AT, Dyavar SR: ACE-2, TMPRSS2, and Neuropilin-1 Receptor Expression on Human Brain Astrocytes and Pericytes and SARS-CoV-2 Infection Kinetics. Int J Mol Sci 2023, 24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10218482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37239978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews MG, Mukhtar T, Eze UC, Simoneau CR, Ross J, Parikshak N, Wang S, Zhou L, Koontz M, Velmeshev D, et al.: Tropism of SARS-CoV-2 for human cortical astrocytes. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2022, 119:e2122236119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9335272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35858406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong W, Montano M, Corley MJ, Helmy E, Kobayashi H, Kinisu M, Suryawanshi R, Luo X, Royer LA, Roan NR, et al.: Neuropilin-1 Mediates SARS-CoV-2 Infection of Astrocytes in Brain Organoids, Inducing Inflammation Leading to Dysfunction and Death of Neurons. mBio 2022:e0230822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9765283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36314791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon CL, Staples H, Gazi M, Carrion R, Hsieh J: SARS-CoV-2 targets glial cells in human cortical organoids. Stem Cell Reports 2021, 16:1156&#x2013;1164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8111796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33979600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Sievert D, Clark AE, Lee S, Federman H, Gastfriend BD, Shusta EV, Palecek SP, Carlin AF, Gleeson JG: A human three-dimensional neural-perivascular &#x2018;assembloid&#x2019; promotes astrocytic development and enables modeling of SARS-CoV-2 neuropathology. Nat Med 2021, 27:1600&#x2013;1606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8601037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34244682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelmoaty MM, Yeapuri P, Machhi J, Olson KE, Shahjin F, Kumar V, Zhou Y, Liang J, Pandey K, Acharya A, et al.: Defining the Innate Immune Responses for SARS-CoV-2-Human Macrophage Interactions. Front Immunol 2021, 12:741502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8521106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34671355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalloh S, Olejnik J, Berrigan J, Nisa A, Suder EL, Akiyama H, Lei M, Tyagi S, Bushkin Y, Muhlberger E, Gummuluru S: CD169-mediated restrictive SARS-CoV-2 infection of macrophages induces pro-inflammatory responses. bioRxiv 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9632919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36279285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F, Arthofer C, Wang C, McCarthy P, Lange F, Andersson JLR, Griffanti L, Duff E, et al.: SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature 2022, 604:697&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9046077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milad MR, Rauch SL: The role of the orbitofrontal cortex in anxiety disorders. Ann N Y Acad Sci 2007, 1121:546&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17698998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Hellmuth J, Chow FC: Central Nervous System Effects of COVID-19 in People with HIV Infection. Curr HIV/AIDS Rep 2021, 18:538&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8628487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34843065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramani A, Muller L, Ostermann PN, Gabriel E, Abida-Islam P, Muller-Schiffmann A, Mariappan A, Goureau O, Gruell H, Walker A, et al.: SARS-CoV-2 targets neurons of 3D human brain organoids. EMBO J 2020, 39:e106230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7560208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32876341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E, Zhang C, Israelow B, Lu-Culligan A, Prado AV, Skriabine S, Lu P, Weizman OE, Liu F, Dai Y, et al.: Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 in human and mouse brain. J Exp Med 2021, 218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang BZ, Chu H, Han S, Shuai H, Deng J, Hu YF, Gong HR, Lee AC, Zou Z, Yau T, et al.: SARS-CoV-2 infects human neural progenitor cells and brain organoids. Cell Res 2020, 30:928&#x2013;931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7399356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Zhou L, Bao L, Liu J, Zhu H, Lv Q, Liu R, Chen W, Tong W, Wei Q, et al.: SARS-CoV-2 crosses the blood-brain barrier accompanied with basement membrane disruption without tight junctions alteration. Signal Transduct Target Ther 2021, 6:337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8419672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34489403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidoryk-Wegrzynowicz M, Wegrzynowicz M, Lee E, Bowman AB, Aschner M: Role of astrocytes in brain function and disease. Toxicol Pathol 2011, 39:115&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6218934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21075920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Park J, Choi YK: The Role of Astrocytes in the Central Nervous System Focused on BK Channel and Heme Oxygenase Metabolites: A Review. Antioxidants (Basel) 2019, 8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6562853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31060341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD, Dykes-Hoberg M, Pardo CA, Bristol LA, Jin L, Kuncl RW, Kanai Y, Hediger MA, Wang Y, Schielke JP, Welty DF: Knockout of glutamate transporters reveals a major role for astroglial transport in excitotoxicity and clearance of glutamate. Neuron 1996, 16:675&#x2013;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8785064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acioglu C, Li L, Elkabes S: Contribution of astrocytes to neuropathology of neurodegenerative diseases. Brain Res 2021, 1758:147291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33516810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li GH, Maric D, Major EO, Nath A: Productive HIV infection in astrocytes can be established via a nonclassical mechanism. AIDS 2020, 34:963&#x2013;978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdebenito S, Castellano P, Ajasin D, Eugenin EA: Astrocytes are HIV reservoirs in the brain: A cell type with poor HIV infectivity and replication but efficient cell-to-cell viral transfer. J Neurochem 2021, 158:429&#x2013;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11102126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33655498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borrajo A, Spuch C, Penedo MA, Olivares JM, Agis-Balboa RC: Important role of microglia in HIV-1 associated neurocognitive disorders and the molecular pathways implicated in its pathogenesis. Ann Med 2021, 53:43&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7877929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32841065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo EH, Dalkara T, Moskowitz MA: Mechanisms, challenges and opportunities in stroke. Nat Rev Neurosci 2003, 4:399&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12728267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killingsworth J, Sawmiller D, Shytle RD: Propionate and Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease. Front Aging Neurosci 2020, 12:580001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7831739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33505301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Wei Q, Yang X, Wang X, Zhang J, Xu R, Zhang H, Wang S, Wan X, Jiang L, et al.: Lipidomics Reveals Dysregulated Glycerophospholipid Metabolism in the Corpus Striatum of Mice Treated with Cefepime. ACS Chem Neurosci 2021, 12:4449&#x2013;4464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34762393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alecu I, Bennett SAL: Dysregulated Lipid Metabolism and Its Role in alpha-Synucleinopathy in Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease. Front Neurosci 2019, 13:328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6470291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31031582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schousboe A, Scafidi S, Bak LK, Waagepetersen HS, McKenna MC: Glutamate metabolism in the brain focusing on astrocytes. Adv Neurobiol 2014, 11:13&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4667713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25236722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorska AM, Eugenin EA: The Glutamate System as a Crucial Regulator of CNS Toxicity and Survival of HIV Reservoirs. Front Cell Infect Microbiol 2020, 10:261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7326772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32670889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahajan UV, Varma VR, Griswold ME, Blackshear CT, An Y, Oommen AM, Varma S, Troncoso JC, Pletnikova O, O&#x2019;Brien R, et al.: Dysregulation of multiple metabolic networks related to brain transmethylation and polyamine pathways in Alzheimer disease: A targeted metabolomic and transcriptomic study. PLoS Med 2020, 17:e1003012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6980402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31978055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeney MD, Ayyadurai S, Zlokovic BV: Pericytes of the neurovascular unit: key functions and signaling pathways. Nat Neurosci 2016, 19:771&#x2013;783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5745011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27227366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarcon-Martinez L, Yemisci M, Dalkara T: Pericyte morphology and function. Histol Histopathol 2021, 36:633&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33595091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold TD, Niaudet C, Pang MF, Siegenthaler J, Gaengel K, Jung B, Ferrero GM, Mukouyama YS, Fuxe J, Akhurst R, et al.: Excessive vascular sprouting underlies cerebral hemorrhage in mice lacking alphaVbeta8-TGFbeta signaling in the brain. Development 2014, 141:4489&#x2013;4499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4302931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25406396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Lan Y, Wang Y, Wang J, Yang G, Meng F, Han H, Meng A, Wang Y, Yang X: Endothelial Smad4 maintains cerebrovascular integrity by activating N-cadherin through cooperation with Notch. Dev Cell 2011, 20:291&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21397841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagare AP, Bell RD, Zhao Z, Ma Q, Winkler EA, Ramanathan A, Zlokovic BV: Pericyte loss influences Alzheimer-like neurodegeneration in mice. Nat Commun 2013, 4:2932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3945879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24336108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler EA, Bell RD, Zlokovic BV: Central nervous system pericytes in health and disease. Nat Neurosci 2011, 14:1398&#x2013;1405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4020628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22030551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertrand L, Cho HJ, Toborek M: Blood-brain barrier pericytes as a target for HIV-1 infection. Brain 2019, 142:502&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6391611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30668645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naranjo O, Torices S, Clifford PR, Daftari MT, Osborne OM, Fattakhov N, Toborek M: Pericyte infection by HIV-1: a fatal attraction. Retrovirology 2022, 19:27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9730689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36476484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torices S, Roberts SA, Park M, Malhotra A, Toborek M: Occludin, caveolin-1, and Alix form a multi-protein complex and regulate HIV-1 infection of brain pericytes. FASEB J 2020, 34:16319&#x2013;16332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7686148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33058236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velazquez-Salinas L, Verdugo-Rodriguez A, Rodriguez LL, Borca MV: The Role of Interleukin 6 During Viral Infections. Front Microbiol 2019, 10:1057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6524401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31134045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akwa Y: Steroids and Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease: Changes Associated with Pathology and Therapeutic Potential. Int J Mol Sci 2020, 21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7370115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32646017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran LT, Park S, Kim SK, Lee JS, Kim KW, Kwon O: Hypothalamic control of energy expenditure and thermogenesis. Exp Mol Med 2022, 54:358&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9076616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35301430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang R, Cai H, Zhang L, Liang D, Lv C, Guo Y, Yang R, Zhu Y, Jiang P: Dysregulation of Neuregulin-1/ErbB signaling in the prefrontal cortex and hippocampus of rats exposed to chronic unpredictable mild stress. Physiol Behav 2016, 154:145&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26626816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>May D, Fullilove R: Depression, HIV, and COVID-19: A Deadly Trifecta. Public Health Rep 2022, 137:420&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9109531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35137644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Harthi L, Campbell E, Schneider JA, Bennett DA: What HIV in the Brain Can Teach Us About SARS-CoV- 2 Neurological Complications? AIDS Res Hum Retroviruses 2021, 37:255&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8035916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32683890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>