<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38690133</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2434-9194</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Global health &amp; medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Glob Health Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proposal to apply a "Positive Emotion, Engagement, Relationships, Meaning, and Accomplishment (PERMA)" based approach to manage the COVID-19-related mental health problems in the era of long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>160</StartPage><EndPage>163</EndPage><MedlinePgn>160-163</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.35772/ghm.2023.01102</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long COVID (LC)-related health problems are highly concerned. Many patients seem to have "recovered" from an acute SARS-CoV-2 infection, however, they might experience various symptoms, almost involving all organs and systems. Of those, neuropsychiatric symptoms like depression, anxiety, and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) are not rare. These problems significantly impact the quality of life (QOL) of patients, family, and caregivers, even lead a tragic suicide outcome. Other than the conventional psychological and medical approaches, here, we proposal a positive emotion, engagement, relationships, meaning, and accomplishment (PERMA)-based approach to fight against these COVID-19-related mental health problems (CRMHPs). This approach is characterized by positive psychological interventions and self-achievements, which has been proved to be a powerful tool against mood disorders in common people. Nowadays, abolishment of certain prophylactic measures (such as isolation, lockdown, compulsorily wearing a mask and maintaining social distance, measures to avoid crowding) enables us to have more opportunities to contact patients and implement the PERMA-based approach to the patients with CRMHPs. We believe that application of PERMA-based approach is conducive to alleviate the influence of the CRMHPs and improve their QOL.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>2024, National Center for Global Health and Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Rongfeng</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital administrative office, National Clinical Research Center for Infectious Diseases, the Third People's Hospital of Shenzhen, Shenzhen, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Fang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Social Sciences, University of Macau, Macao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Hongzhou</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, National Clinical Research Center for Infectious Diseases, the Third People's Hospital of Shenzhen, Shenzhen, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neurology, National Clinical Research Center for Infectious Diseases, the Third People's Hospital of Shenzhen, Shenzhen, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asakawa</LastName><ForeName>Tetsuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neurology, National Clinical Research Center for Infectious Diseases, the Third People's Hospital of Shenzhen, Shenzhen, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Glob Health Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101771579</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2434-9186</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19-related mental health problems</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PERMA model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">positive psychological intervention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38690133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11043128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35772/ghm.2023.01102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Asakawa T, Cai Q, Shen J, et al. . Sequelae of long COVID, known and unknown: A review of updated information. Biosci Trends. 2023; 17:85-116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36928222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballering AV, van Zon SKR, Olde Hartman TC, Rosmalen JGM; Lifelines Corona Research Initiative. Persistence of somatic symptoms after COVID-19 in the Netherlands: An observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022; 400:452-461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9352274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35934007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrman H, Patel V, Kieling C, et al. . Time for united action on depression: A Lancet-World Psychiatric Association Commission. Lancet. 2022; 399:957-1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35180424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. . Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021; 27:601-615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers JP, Chesney E, Oliver D, Pollak TA, McGuire P, Fusar-Poli P, Zandi MS, Lewis G, David AS. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: A systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020; 7:611-627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7234781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng B, Cheng SK, Lau KK, Li HL, Chan EL. The effects of disease severity, use of corticosteroids and social factors on neuropsychiatric complaints in severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) patients at acute and convalescent phases. Eur Psychiatry. 2005; 20:236-242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7135192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15935422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Qiao D, Xu Y, Zhao W, Yang Y, Wen D, Li X, Nie X, Dong Y, Tang S. The efficacy of computerized cognitive behavioral therapy for depressive and anxiety symptoms in patients with COVID-19: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2021; 23:e26883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8128049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33900931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si MY, Xiao WJ, Pan C, Wang H, Huang YM, Lian J, Mak WWS, Leng ZW, Su XY, Tang QP, Jiang Y, Feng LZ, Yang WZ, Wang C. Mindfulness-based online intervention on mental health and quality of life among COVID-19 patients in China: An intervention design. Infect Dis Poverty. 2021; 10:69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8127244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34001277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaygan M, Yazdani Z, Valibeygi A. The effect of online multimedia psychoeducational interventions on the resilience and perceived stress of hospitalized patients with COVID-19: A pilot cluster randomized parallel-controlled trial. BMC Psychiatry. 2021; 21:93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7877318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33573631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagadeesan T, Archana R, Kannan R, Jain T, Allu AR, Maveeran M, Kuppusamy M. Effect of Bhramari Pranayama intervention on stress, anxiety, depression and sleep quality among COVID 19 patients in home isolation. J Ayurveda Integr Med. 2022; 13:100596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9167919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35693195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma N, Sahni PS, Sharma US, Kumar J, Garg R. Effect of yoga on the stress, anxiety, and depression of COVID- 19-positive patients: A quasi-randomized controlled study. Int J Yoga Therap. 2022; 32:Article 8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35850136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Li W. Improvement effect of PERMA model-based nursing intervention plus music therapy on patients with acute liver failure undergoing plasma exchange therapy. Emerg Med Int. 2022; 2022:2485056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9259328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35811606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gander F, Proyer RT, Ruch W. Positive psychology interventions addressing pleasure, engagement, meaning, positive relationships, and accomplishment increase well-being and ameliorate depressive symptoms: A randomized, placebo-controlled online study. Front Psychol. 2016; 7:686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4873493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27242600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu T, Huang Y, Fang Y, Liu A, Luo X, Xu J. Effect of positive psychological intervention based on PERMA model on disability acceptance and self-care disability in stroke patients. Chinese Nursing Research. 2020; 34:965-970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu M, Wang F, Shen S, Wang H, Feng J. Influences of psychological intervention on negative emotion, cancer-related fatigue and level of hope in lung cancer chemotherapy patients based on the PERMA framework. Iran J Public Health. 2021; 50:728-736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8219625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34183922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang H, Zeng Y, Liu Y, Zhu C. The effect of the PERMA model-based positive psychological intervention on the quality of life of patients with breast cancer. Heliyon. 2023; 9:e17251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10320023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37416631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez R, Burrows B, Wilund K, Cohn M, Xu S, Moskowitz JT. Feasibility of an Internet-based positive psychological intervention for hemodialysis patients with symptoms of depression. Soc Work Health Care. 2018; 57:864-879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7282478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30277449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seligman M, Flourish P. A visionary new understanding of happiness and well-being. Atria; Reprint edition. 2012; 1-368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaw D, Kern ML. A cross-cultural comparison of the PERMA model of well-being. Undergraduate Journal of Psychology at Berkeley. 2014; 8:1-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Hernandez O, Barkavi-Shani M, Bermejo RM. Promotion of resilience and emotional self-care in families and health professionals in times of COVID-19. Front Psychol. 2022; 13:879846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9001946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35422740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi MY. Mental and physical factors influencing wellbeing among South Korean emergency workers. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020; 18:70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7795396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33374138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacIntyre PD, Gregersen T, Mercer S. Language teachers' coping strategies during the Covid-19 conversion to online teaching: Correlations with stress, wellbeing and negative emotions. System. 2020; 94:102352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Ginsborg J. The experiences of mid-career and seasoned orchestral musicians in the UK during the first COVID-19 lockdown. Front Psychol. 2021; 12:645967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8062715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33897549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasath PR, Mather PC, Bhat CS, James JK. University student well-being during COVID-19: The role of psychological capital and coping strategies. The Professional Counselor. 2021; 11:46-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkie L, Arroyo P, Conibeer H, Kemp AH, Fisher Z. The impact of psycho-social interventions on the wellbeing of individuals with acquired brain injury during the COVID-19 pandemic. Front Psychol. 2021; 12:648286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8027334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33841287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arslan G, Y&#x131;ld&#x131;r&#x131;m M, Karata&#x15f; Z, Kabasakal Z, K&#x131;l&#x131;n&#xe7; M. Meaningful living to promote complete mental health among university students in the context of the COVID-19 pandemic. Int J Ment Health Addict. 2022; 20:930-942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7609355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33169074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>