<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34506003</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2161-3311</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current nutrition reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Nutr Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lifestyle Adjustments in Long-COVID Management: Potential Benefits of Plant-Based Diets.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>352</StartPage><EndPage>363</EndPage><MedlinePgn>352-363</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13668-021-00369-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">The SARS-CoV-2-pandemic has caused mortality and morbidity at an unprecedented global scale. Many patients infected with SARS-CoV-2 continue to experience symptoms after the acute phase of infection and report fatigue, sleep difficulties, anxiety, and depression as well as arthralgia and muscle weakness. Summarized under the umbrella term "long-COVID," these symptoms may last weeks to months and impose a substantial burden on affected individuals. Dietary approaches to tackle these complications have received comparably little attention. Although plant-based diets in particular were shown to exert benefits on underlying conditions linked to poor COVID-19 outcomes, their role with regard to COVID-19 sequelae is yet largely unknown. Thus, this review sought to investigate whether a plant-based diet could reduce the burden of long-COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">The number of clinical trials investigating the role of plant-based nutrition in COVID-19 prevention and management is currently limited. Yet, there is evidence from pre-pandemic observational and clinical studies that a plant-based diet may be of general benefit with regard to several clinical conditions that can also be found in individuals with COVID-19. These include anxiety, depression, sleep disorders, and musculoskeletal pain. Adoption of a plant-based diet leads to a reduced intake in pro-inflammatory mediators and could be one accessible strategy to tackle long-COVID associated prolonged systemic inflammation. Plant-based diets may be of general benefit with regard to some of the most commonly found COVID-19 sequelae. Additional trials investigating which plant-based eating patterns confer the greatest benefit in the battle against long-COVID are urgently warranted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Storz</LastName><ForeName>Maximilian Andreas</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3277-0301</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Complementary Medicine, Institute for Infection Prevention and Hospital Epidemiology, Faculty of Medicine, University of Freiburg, Freiburg im Breisgau, Germany. maximilian.storz@uniklinik-freiburg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Nutr Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101587480</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2161-3311</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014676" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet, Vegetarian</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008019" MajorTopicYN="N">Life Style</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Economic burden</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Plant-based diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2; Long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vegan</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author declares that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34506003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8429479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13668-021-00369-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13668-021-00369-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. COVID-19 weekly epidemiological update; [cited 2021 May 30]. Available from: https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/situation-reports/20210601_weekly_epi_update_42.pdf?sfvrsn=5b0bbc7c_5&amp;download=true</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NIHR. Living with covid-19. A dynamic review of the evidence around ongoing covid-19 symptoms (often called long covid). October 2020; [cited 2021 May 30]. https://evidence.nihr.ac.uk/themedreview/living-with-covid19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwu CJ, Iwu CD, Wiysonge CS. The occurrence of long COVID: a rapid review. Pan Afr Med J. 2021;38:65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8028365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33889231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, et al. More than 50 Long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. medRxiv. 2021 Jan 30;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong TL, Weitzer DJ. Long COVID and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS)-a systemic review and comparison of clinical presentation and symptomatology. Medicina (Kaunas). 2021;57(5):418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8145228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33925784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Gemelli against COVID-19 post-acute care study group. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logue JK, Franko NM, McCulloch DJ, McDonald D, Magedson A, Wolf CR, et al. Sequelae in adults at 6 months after COVID-19 infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(2):e210830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33606031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osikomaiya B, Erinoso O, Wright KO, Odusola AO, Thomas B, Adeyemi O, et al. &#x2018;Long COVID&#x2019;: persistent COVID-19 symptoms in survivors managed in Lagos State, Nigeria. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7993075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33765941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marra A, Pandharipande PP, Girard TD, Patel MB, Hughes CG, Jackson JC, et al. Co-occurrence of post-intensive care syndrome problems among 406 survivors of critical illness. Crit Care Med. 2018;46(9):1393&#x2013;1401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6095801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29787415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal FM, Lam K, Sounderajah V, Elkin S, Ashrafian H, Darzi A. Understanding the survivorship burden of long COVID. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;33:100767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7904277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33649741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH, Crooks MG. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;199(2):113&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Rio C, Collins LF, Malani P. Long-term health consequences of COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(17):1723&#x2013;1724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8019677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization | 1. Introduction [Internet]. WHO. World Health Organization; [cited 2021 May 21]. Available from: https://www.who.int/nutrition/topics/1_introduction/en/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):601&#x2013;615. doi: 10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holdoway A. Addressing nutrition in the road map of recovery for those with long COVID-19. Br J Community Nurs. 2021;26(5):218&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33939462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physicians Committee for Responsible Medicine. Diet can fight diseases linked to poor COVID-19 outcomes [Internet]. Physicians Committee for Responsible Medicine; [cited 2021 May 21]. Available from: https://www.pcrm.org/news/blog/diet-can-fight-diseases-linked-poor-covid-19-outcomes</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benavides H, Meireles CL, Benavente V, Mays MH, Wang J. Decreasing older adult COVID-19 risk factors using digital technology to implement a plant-based-diet: an opinion paper. JMIR Aging. 2021 May 31;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8406109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34081595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostfeld RJ. Definition of a plant-based diet and overview of this special issue. J Geriatr Cardiol. 2017;14(5):315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5466934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28630607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craddock JC, Neale EP, Peoples GE, Probst YC. Plant-based eating patterns and endurance performance: a focus on inflammation, oxidative stress and immune responses. Nutr Bull. 2020;45(2):123&#x2013;132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satija A, Hu FB. Plant-based diets and cardiovascular health. Trends Cardiovasc Med. 2018;28(7):437&#x2013;441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6089671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29496410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storz MA. Is there a lack of support for whole-food, plant-based diets in the medical community? Perm J. 2018;23:18&#x2013;068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6307547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30589405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storz MA. Will the plant-based movement redefine physicians&#x2019; understanding of chronic disease? New Bioeth. 2020;26(2):141&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32594898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trautwein EA, McKay S. The role of specific components of a plant-based diet in management of dyslipidemia and the impact on cardiovascular risk. Nutrients. 2020 Sept 1;12(9).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7551487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32883047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grosse CSJ, Christophersen CT, Devine A, Lawrance IC. The role of a plant-based diet in the pathogenesis, etiology and management of the inflammatory bowel diseases. Expert Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;14(3):137&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32077339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medawar E, Huhn S, Villringer A, Veronica WA. The effects of plant-based diets on the body and the brain: a systematic review. Transl Psychiatry. 2019;9(1):226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6742661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31515473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022;&#x2022; Kim H, Rebholz CM, Hegde S, LaFiura C, Raghavan M, Lloyd JF, et al. Plant-based diets, pescatarian diets and COVID-19 severity: a population-based case&#x2013;control study in six countries. BMJ Nutrition, Prevention &amp; Health. 2021 May 18;bmjnph. This is the first high-quality case-control study that revealed that following plant-based diets is associated with 73% lower odds of moderate-to-severe COVID-19-like illness compared with individuals who did not follow these diets.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8219480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehman U, Shahnawaz MG, Khan NH, Kharshiing KD, Khursheed M, Gupta K, et al. Depression, anxiety and stress among Indians in times of covid-19 lockdown. Community Ment Health J. 2021;57(1):42&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7309680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32577997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J, Zheng P, Jia Y, Chen H, Mao Y, Chen S, et al. Mental health problems and social media exposure during COVID-19 outbreak. PLoS One. 2020;15(4):e0231924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7162477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi EPH, Hui BPH, Wan EYF. Depression and anxiety in Hong Kong during COVID-19. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(10):3740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7277420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32466251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CH, Zhang E, Wong GTF, Hyun S, Chris HH. Factors associated with depression, anxiety, and PTSD symptomatology during the COVID-19 pandemic: clinical implications for US young adult mental health. Psychiatry Research. 2020;290:113172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7263263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32512357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, De Lorenzo R, Conte C, Poletti S, Vai B, Bollettini I, et al. Anxiety and depression in COVID-19 survivors: role of inflammatory and clinical predictors. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;1(89):594&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7390748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilsher SH. The impact of emotional health on fruit and vegetable consumption in young men: a qualitative study. Proceedings of the Nutrition Society [Internet]. 2013 ed [cited 2021 May 24];72(OCE4). Available from: https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/proceedings-of-the-nutrition-society/article/impact-of-emotional-health-on-fruit-and-vegetable-consumption-in-young-men-a-qualitative-study/79ED3B2F9D71AC5C98AC58B62FA90D21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#x142;&#x105;bska D, Guzek D, Groele B, Gutkowska K. Fruit and vegetable intake and mental health in adults: a systematic review. Nutrients. 2020;12(1):E115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7019743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31906271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchflower DG, Oswald AJ, Stewart-Brown S. Is psychological well-being linked to the consumption of fruit and vegetables? Soc Indic Res. 2013;114(3):785&#x2013;801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boehm JK, Williams DR, Rimm EB, Ryff C, Kubzansky LD. Association between optimism and serum antioxidants in the midlife in the United States study. Psychosom Med. 2013;75(1):2&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3539819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23257932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelloniemi H, Ek E, Laitinen J. Optimism, dietary habits, body mass index and smoking among young Finnish adults. Appetite. 2005;45(2):169&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16009454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giltay EJ, Geleijnse JM, Zitman FG, Buijsse B, Kromhout D. Lifestyle and dietary correlates of dispositional optimism in men: The Zutphen Elderly Study. J Psychosom Res. 2007;63(5):483&#x2013;490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17980220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt T, Patel K. Carotenoids: potent to prevent diseases review. Nat Prod Bioprospect. 2020;10(3):109&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7253555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32405969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju S-Y, Park YK. Low fruit and vegetable intake is associated with depression among Korean adults in data from the 2014 Korea National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey. J Health Popul Nutr. 2019;38(1):39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6892133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31796113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang P, O&#x2019;Keeffe M, Elia C, Karamanos A, Goff LM, Maynard M, et al. Fruit and vegetable consumption and mental health across adolescence: evidence from a diverse urban British cohort study. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2019;16(1):19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6368762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30736801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmayani PNA, Juergens M, Allman-Farinelli M, Mihrshahi S. Association between fruit and vegetable consumption and depression symptoms in young people and adults aged 15&#x2013;45: a systematic review of cohort studies. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(2):E780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7831325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33477603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wattick RA, Hagedorn RL, Olfert MD. Relationship between diet and mental health in a young adult appalachian college population. Nutrients. 2018;10(8):957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6115820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30044399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbaraly TN, Brunner EJ, Ferrie JE, Marmot MG, Kivimaki M, Singh-Manoux A. Dietary pattern and depressive symptoms in middle age. Br J Psychiatry. 2009;195(5):408&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2801825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19880930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Yang Y, Xie M-S, Ding X, Li H, Liu Z-C, et al. Is meat consumption associated with depression? a meta-analysis of observational studies. BMC Psychiatry. 2017;17(1):409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5745880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29282023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beezhold BL, Johnston CS, Daigle DR. Vegetarian diets are associated with healthy mood states: a cross-sectional study in Seventh Day Adventist adults. Nutr J. 2010;1(9):26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2887769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20515497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y-C, Chang C-E, Lin M-N, Lin C-L. Vegetarian diet is associated with lower risk of depression in Taiwan. Nutrients. 2021;13(4):1059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8064096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33805124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal U, Mishra S, Xu J, Levin S, Gonzales J, Barnard ND. A multicenter randomized controlled trial of a nutrition intervention program in a multiethnic adult population in the corporate setting reduces depression and anxiety and improves quality of life: the GEICO study. Am J Health Promot. 2015;29(4):245&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24524383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahleova H, Hrachovinova T, Hill M, Pelikanova T. Vegetarian diet in type 2 diabetes&#x2013;improvement in quality of life, mood and eating behaviour. Diabet Med. 2013;30(1):127&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23050853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajaram S, Jones J, Lee GJ. Plant-based dietary patterns, plant foods, and age-related cognitive decline. Adv Nutr. 2019;10(Suppl_4):422&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6855948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31728502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Pinilla F, Nguyen TTJ. Natural mood foods: the actions of polyphenols against psychiatric and cognitive disorders. Nutr Neurosci. 2012;15(3):127&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3355196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22334236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouayed J. Polyphenols: a potential new strategy for the prevention and treatment of anxiety and depression. Curr Nutr Food Sci. 2010;6(1):13&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanagan E, M&#xfc;ller M, Hornberger M, Vauzour D. Impact of flavonoids on cellular and molecular mechanisms underlying age-related cognitive decline and neurodegeneration. Curr Nutr Rep. 2018;7(2):49&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5960493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29892788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joris PJ, Mensink RP, Adam TC, Liu TT. Cerebral blood flow measurements in adults: a review on the effects of dietary factors and exercise. Nutrients. 2018;10(5):E530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5986410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29693564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tungmunnithum D, Thongboonyou A, Pholboon A, Yangsabai A. Flavonoids and other phenolic compounds from medicinal plants for pharmaceutical and medical aspects: an overview. Medicines (Basel) [Internet]. 2018 Aug 25 [cited 2021 May 24];5(3). Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6165118/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6165118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30149600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anand David AV, Arulmoli R, Parasuraman S. Overviews of biological importance of quercetin: a bioactive flavonoid. Pharmacogn Rev. 2016;10(20):84&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5214562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28082789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon Clarke SE, Ramsay RR. Dietary inhibitors of monoamine oxidase A. J Neural Transm (Vienna) 2011;118(7):1031&#x2013;1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21190052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higuchi Y, Soga T, Parhar IS. Regulatory pathways of monoamine oxidase A during social stress. Front Neurosci. 2017;11:604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5671571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29163009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>aan het Rot M, Mathew SJ, Charney DS. Neurobiological mechanisms in major depressive disorder. CMAJ. 2009 Feb 3;180(3):305&#x2013;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2630359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19188629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail H, Amanat MA, Iqbal A, Mirza B. Medicinal plants: a complementary and alternative antidepressant therapy. Curr Pharm Des. 2018;24(22):2609&#x2013;2624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30051783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahramsoltani R, Farzaei MH, Farahani MS, Rahimi R. Phytochemical constituents as future antidepressants: a comprehensive review. Rev Neurosci. 2015;26(6):699&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26146123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhiman P, Malik N, Sobarzo-S&#xe1;nchez E, Uriarte E, Khatkar A. Quercetin and related chromenone derivatives as monoamine oxidase inhibitors: targeting neurological and mental disorders. Molecules [Internet]. 2019 Jan 24 [cited 2021 May 24];24(3). Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6385169/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6385169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30678358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal PK, Agrawal C, Blunden G. Quercetin: antiviral significance and possible COVID-19 integrative considerations. Nat Prod Commun. 2020;15(12):1934578X20976293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colunga Biancatelli RML, Berrill M, Catravas JD, Marik PE. Quercetin and vitamin C: an experimental, synergistic therapy for the prevention and treatment of SARS-CoV-2 related disease (COVID-19) Front Immunol. 2020;11:1451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7318306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32636851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grosso G, Galvano F, Marventano S, Malaguarnera M, Bucolo C, Drago F, et al. Omega-3 fatty acids and depression: scientific evidence and biological mechanisms. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2014;2014:313570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3976923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24757497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hathaway D, Pandav K, Patel M, Riva-Moscoso A, Singh BM, Patel A, et al. Omega 3 fatty acids and COVID-19: a comprehensive review. Infect Chemother. 2020;52(4):478&#x2013;495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7779984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33377319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez S, Svahn SL, Johansson ME. Effects of omega-3 fatty acids on immune cells. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20(20):5028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6834330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31614433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asher A, Tintle NL, Myers M, Lockshon L, Bacareza H, Harris WS. Blood omega-3 fatty acids and death from COVID-19: a pilot study. Prostaglandins Leukot Essent Fatty Acids. 2021;166:102250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7816864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33516093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doaei S, Gholami S, Rastgoo S, Gholamalizadeh M, Bourbour F, Bagheri SE, et al. The effect of omega-3 fatty acid supplementation on clinical and biochemical parameters of critically ill patients with COVID-19: a randomized clinical trial. J Transl Med. 2021;19(1):128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang JP-C, Pariante CM, Su K-P. Omega-3 fatty acids in the psychological and physiological resilience against COVID-19. Prostaglandins Leukot Essent Fatty Acids. 2020;161:102177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7516470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domingo JL. Omega-3 fatty acids and the benefits of fish consumption: is all that glitters gold? Environ Int. 2007;33(7):993&#x2013;998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17540446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physicians Committee for Responsible Medicine. Food and mood: eating plants to fight the blues [Internet] [cited 2021 May 24]. Available from: https://www.pcrm.org/good-nutrition/food-and-mood</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beezhold BL, Johnston CS. Restriction of meat, fish, and poultry in omnivores improves mood: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Nutr J. 2012;14(11):9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3293760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22333737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innes JK, Calder PC. Omega-6 fatty acids and inflammation. Prostaglandins Leukot Essent Fatty Acids. 2018;132:41&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29610056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson E, Wall R, Fitzgerald GF, Ross RP, Stanton C. Health implications of high dietary omega-6 polyunsaturated Fatty acids. J Nutr Metab. 2012;2012:539426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3335257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22570770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucas M, Chocano-Bedoya P, Schulze MB, Shulze MB, Mirzaei F, O&#x2019;Reilly &#xc9;J, et al. Inflammatory dietary pattern and risk of depression among women. Brain Behav Immun. 2014;36:46&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3947176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24095894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogelzangs N, Beekman ATF, de Jonge P, Penninx BWJH. Anxiety disorders and inflammation in a large adult cohort. Transl Psychiatry. 2013;3:e249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3641413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23612048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon SY, Massey K, Watson MA, Hussain T, Volpe G, Buckley CD, et al. Oxidised metabolites of the omega-6 fatty acid linoleic acid activate dFOXO. Life Sci Alliance. 2020;3(2):e201900356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6988086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31992650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burhani MD, Rasenick MM. Fish oil and depression: the skinny on fats. J Integr Neurosci. 2017;16(s1):S115&#x2013;S124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6087692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29254106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange KW. Omega-3 fatty acids and mental health. Global Health J. 2020;4(1):18&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange KW, Nakamura Y, Gosslau AM, Li S. Are there serious adverse effects of omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acid supplements? J Food Bioactives. 2019 doi: 10.31665/JFB.2019.7192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31665/JFB.2019.7192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storz MA. The role of vegan diets in lipotoxicity-induced beta-cell dysfunction in type-2-diabetes. J Popl Ther Clin Pharmacol. 2020;27(SP2):e22&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34032395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders TA, Roshanai F. Platelet phospholipid fatty acid composition and function in vegans compared with age- and sex-matched omnivore controls. Eur J Clin Nutr. 1992;46(11):823&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1425536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahleova H, Hlozkova A, Fleeman R, Fletcher K, Holubkov R, Barnard ND. Fat quantity and quality, as part of a low-fat, vegan diet, are associated with changes in body composition, insulin resistance, and insulin secretion. A 16-Week Randomized Controlled Trial. Nutrient. 2019;11(3):615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6472059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30871233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beezhold B, Radnitz C, Rinne A, DiMatteo J. Vegans report less stress and anxiety than omnivores. Nutr Neurosci. 2015;18(7):289&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25415255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherian L, Wang Y, Holland T, Agarwal P, Aggarwal N, Morris MC. DASH and Mediterranean-dash intervention for neurodegenerative delay (MIND) diets are associated with fewer depressive symptoms over time. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2021;76(1):151&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7973257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32080745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cong X, Tracy M, Edmunds LS, Hosler AS, Appleton AA. The relationship between inflammatory dietary pattern in childhood and depression in early adulthood. Brain Behav Immun Health. 2020;2:100017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7043331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32140686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farooqui AA, Farooqui T. Chapter 20 - Effects of Western, Mediterranean, vegetarian, and Okinawan diet patterns on human brain. In: Farooqui T, Farooqui AA, editors. Role of the Mediterranean diet in the brain and neurodegenerative diseases [Internet]. Academic Press; 2018 [cited 2021 Jul 4]. p. 317&#x2013;32. Available from: https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/B9780128119594000201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pistollato F, Battino M. Role of plant-based diets in the prevention and regression of metabolic syndrome and neurodegenerative diseases. Trends Food Sci Technol. 2014;40(1):62&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx W, Lane M, Hockey M, Aslam H, Berk M, Walder K, et al. Diet and depression: exploring the biological mechanisms of action. Mol Psychiatry. 2021;26(1):134&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33144709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Gostner JM, Fuchs D. Mood, food, and cognition: role of tryptophan and serotonin. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2016;19(1):55&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26560523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabbir F, Patel A, Mattison C, Bose S, Krishnamohan R, Sweeney E, et al. Effect of diet on serotonergic neurotransmission in depression. Neurochem Int. 2013;62(3):324&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23306210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindseth G, Helland B, Caspers J. The effects of dietary tryptophan on affective disorders. Arch Psychiatr Nurs. 2015;29(2):102&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4393508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25858202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuter M, Zamoscik V, Plieger T, Bravo R, Ugartemendia L, Rodriguez AB, et al. Tryptophan-rich diet is negatively associated with depression and positively linked to social cognition. Nutr Res. 2021;1(85):14&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33383299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chojnacki C, Pop&#x142;awski T, Chojnacki J, Fila M, Konrad P, Blasiak J. Tryptophan intake and metabolism in older adults with mood disorders. Nutrients. 2020;12(10):E3183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7603218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33081001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas T, Stefanoni D, Reisz JA, Nemkov T, Bertolone L, Francis RO, et al. COVID-19 infection alters kynurenine and fatty acid metabolism, correlating with IL-6 levels and renal status. JCI Insight. 2020;5(14):140327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7453907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32559180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansone L, Ustinova M, Terentjeva A, Perkons I, Birzniece L, Rovite V, et al. Tryptophan and arginine metabolism is significantly altered at the time of admission in hospital for severe COVID-19 patients: findings from longitudinal targeted metabolomics analysis. medRxiv. 2021;323:1239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8653833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34878333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ero&#x11f;lu &#x130;, Ero&#x11f;lu B&#xc7;, G&#xfc;ven GS. Altered tryptophan absorption and metabolism could underlie long-term symptoms in survivors of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Nutrition. 2021;90:111308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8087860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34111831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shader RI. COVID-19, interferons, and depression: a commentary. Psychiatr Res. 2020;291:113198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32535509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palego L, Betti L, Rossi A, Giannaccini G. Tryptophan biochemistry: structural, nutritional, metabolic, and medical aspects in humans. J Amino Acids. 2016;2016:8952520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4737446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26881063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone TW, Stoy N, Darlington LG. An expanding range of targets for kynurenine metabolites of tryptophan. Trends Pharmacol Sci. 2013;34(2):136&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23123095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wurtman RJ, Wurtman JJ, Regan MM, McDermott JM, Tsay RH, Breu JJ. Effects of normal meals rich in carbohydrates or proteins on plasma tryptophan and tyrosine ratios. Am J Clin Nutr. 2003;77(1):128&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12499331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lederer A-K, Maul-Pavicic A, Hannibal L, Hettich M, Steinborn C, Gr&#xfc;ndemann C, et al. Vegan diet reduces neutrophils, monocytes and platelets related to branched-chain amino acids - a randomized, controlled trial. Clin Nutr. 2020;39(11):3241&#x2013;3250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32147197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St-Onge M-P, Crawford A, Aggarwal B. Plant-based diets: reducing cardiovascular risk by improving sleep quality? Curr Sleep Med Rep. 2018;4(1):74&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5999325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscogiuri G, Barrea L, Savastano S, Colao A. Nutritional recommendations for CoVID-19 quarantine. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2020;74(6):850&#x2013;851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7155155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32286533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casagrande M, Favieri F, Tambelli R, Forte G. The enemy who sealed the world: effects quarantine due to the COVID-19 on sleep quality, anxiety, and psychological distress in the Italian population. Sleep Med. 2020;1(75):12&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta R, Grover S, Basu A, Krishnan V, Tripathi A, Subramanyam A, et al. Changes in sleep pattern and sleep quality during COVID-19 lockdown. Indian J Psychiatr. 2020;62(4):370&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7597722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33165382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coiro MJ, Asraf K, Tzischinsky O, Hadar-Shoval D, Tannous-Haddad L, Wolfson AR. Sleep quality and COVID-19-related stress in relation to mental health symptoms among Israeli and US adults. Sleep Health. 2021;7(2):127&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33691986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocevska D, Blanken TF, Van Someren EJW, R&#xf6;sler L. Sleep quality during the COVID-19 pandemic: not one size fits all. Sleep Med. 2020;76:86&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33126035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanlier N, Sabuncular G. Relationship between nutrition and sleep quality, focusing on the melatonin biosynthesis. Sleep Biol Rhythms. 2020;18(2):89&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pengpid S, Peltzer K. Fruit and vegetable consumption is protective from short sleep and poor sleep quality among university students from 28 countries. Nat Sci Sleep. 2020;12:627&#x2013;633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7467659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32943964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jyv&#xe4;korpi SK, Urtamo A, Kivim&#xe4;ki M, Strandberg TE. Associations of sleep quality, quantity and nutrition in oldest-old men The Helsinki Businessmen Study (HBS) Eur Geriatr Med. 2021;12(1):117&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7900075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33131032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St-Onge M-P, Roberts A, Shechter A, Choudhury AR. Fiber and saturated fat are associated with sleep arousals and slow wave sleep. J Clin Sleep Med. 2016;12(1):19&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4702189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26156950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato-Mito N, Sasaki S, Murakami K, Okubo H, Takahashi Y, Shibata S, et al. The midpoint of sleep is associated with dietary intake and dietary behavior among young Japanese women. Sleep Med. 2011;12(3):289&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan X, Al&#xe9;n M, Cheng SM, Mikkola TM, Tenhunen J, Lyytik&#xe4;inen A, et al. Associations of disordered sleep with body fat distribution, physical activity and diet among overweight middle-aged men. J Sleep Res. 2015;24(4):414&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25644747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensen NB, Madsen ML, Hansen TH, Allin KH, Hoppe C, Fagt S, et al. Intake of macro- and micronutrients in Danish vegans. Nutr J. 2015;14(1):115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4628270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26518233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi B, Kimiagar M, Sadeghniiat K, Shirazi MM, Hedayati M, Rashidkhani B. The effect of magnesium supplementation on primary insomnia in elderly: a double-blind placebo-controlled clinical trial. J Res Med Sci. 2012;17(12):1161&#x2013;1169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3703169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23853635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Chen C, Lu L, Knuston K, Carnethon M, Fly A, et al. Association of magnesium intake with sleep duration and sleep quality: findings from the CARDIA study. Curr Dev Nutr. 2021;5:1109&#x2013;1109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8996025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34883514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering G, Mazur A, Trousselard M, Bienkowski P, Yaltsewa N, Amessou M, et al. Magnesium status and stress: the vicious circle concept revisited. Nutrients. 2020;12(12):3672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7761127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33260549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wienecke E, Nolden C. Long-term HRV analysis shows stress reduction by magnesium intake. MMW Fortschr Med. 2016;158(Suppl 6):12&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27933574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Gemelli against COVID-19 post-acute care study group. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali AM, Kunugi H. Skeletal muscle damage in COVID-19: a call for action. Medicina (Kaunas) 2021;57(4):372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8069858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33921429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elma &#xd6;, Yilmaz ST, Deliens T, Coppieters I, Clarys P, Nijs J, et al. Do nutritional factors interact with chronic musculoskeletal pain? a systematic review. J Clin Med. 2020;9(3):702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7141322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32150934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi KW, Somers TJ, Babyak MA, Sikkema KJ, Blumenthal JA, Keefe FJ. The relationship between pain and eating among overweight and obese individuals with osteoarthritis: an ecological momentary study. Pain Res Manag. 2014;19(6):e159&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4273714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24911176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meleger AL, Froude CK, Walker J. Nutrition and eating behavior in patients with chronic pain receiving long-term opioid therapy. PM&amp;R. 2014;6(1):7&#x2013;12.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23973502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batista ED, Andretta A, de Miranda RC, Nehring J, Dos Santos PE, Schieferdecker MEM. Food intake assessment and quality of life in women with fibromyalgia. Rev Bras Reumatol Engl Ed. 2016;56(2):105&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27267522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarleton EK, Kennedy AG, Rose GL, Littenberg B. Relationship between magnesium intake and chronic pain in US adults. Nutrients. 2020;12(7):2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7400867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32708577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Towery P, Guffey JS, Doerflein C, Stroup K, Saucedo S, Taylor J. Chronic musculoskeletal pain and function improve with a plant-based diet. Complement Ther Med. 2018;40:64&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30219471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDougall J, Bruce B, Spiller G, Westerdahl J, McDougall M. Effects of a very low-fat, vegan diet in subjects with rheumatoid arthritis. J Altern Complement Med. 2002;8(1):71&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11890437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinton CM, O&#x2019;Brien S, Law J, Renier CM, Wendt MR. Whole-foods, plant-based diet alleviates the symptoms of osteoarthritis. Arthritis. 2015;2015:708152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4359818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25815212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solway J, McBride M, Haq F, Abdul W, Miller R. Diet and dermatology: the role of a whole-food, plant-based diet in preventing and reversing skin aging&#x2014;a review. J Clin Aesthet Dermatol. 2020;13(5):38&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7380694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32802255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner-McGrievy GM, Barnard ND, Scialli AR. A two-year randomized weight loss trial comparing a vegan diet to a more moderate low-fat diet. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2007;15(9):2276&#x2013;2281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17890496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najjar RS, Feresin RG. Plant-based diets in the reduction of body fat: physiological effects and biochemical insights. Nutrients. 2019;11(11):2712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6893503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31717463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Doykov I, H&#xe4;llqvist J, Gilmour KC, Grandjean L, Mills K, Heywood WE. &#x2018;The long tail of Covid-19&#x2019; - the detection of a prolonged inflammatory response after a SARS-CoV-2 infection in asymptomatic and mildly affected patients. F1000Res [Internet]. 2021 Jan 8 [cited 2021 May 25];9. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7745182/. The authors demonstrated that inflammatory pathways can remain perturbed up to 60 days after a SARS-CoV-2 infection in patients with long-COVID. Nutritional anti-inflammatory interventions are urgently warranted to reduce systemic inflammation in affected patients.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7745182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33391730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, Palladini M, De Lorenzo R, Magnaghi C, Poletti S, Furlan R, et al. Persistent psychopathology and neurocognitive impairment in COVID-19 survivors: effect of inflammatory biomarkers at three-month follow-up. Brain Behav Immun. 2021;94:138&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33639239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storz MA. How research on depression could now fundamentally change preventive cardiology. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2020;30:2047487320915804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33611430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner-McGrievy GM, Wirth MD, Shivappa N, Wingard EE, Fayad R, Wilcox S, et al. Randomization to plant-based dietary approaches leads to larger short-term improvements in Dietary Inflammatory Index scores and macronutrient intake compared with diets that contain meat. Nutr Res. 2015;35(2):97&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25532675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M-S, Hwang S-S, Park E-J, Bae J-W. Strict vegetarian diet improves the risk factors associated with metabolic diseases by modulating gut microbiota and reducing intestinal inflammation. Environ Microbiol Rep. 2013;5(5):765&#x2013;775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24115628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichelmann F, Schwingshackl L, Fedirko V, Aleksandrova K. Effect of plant-based diets on obesity-related inflammatory profiles: a systematic review and meta-analysis of intervention trials. Obes Rev. 2016;17(11):1067&#x2013;1079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27405372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco-de-Moraes AC, de Almeida-Pititto B, da Rocha FG, Gomes EP, da Costa PA, Ferreira SRG. Worse inflammatory profile in omnivores than in vegetarians associates with the gut microbiota composition. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2017;9:62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5557559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28814977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Shah B, Newman JD, Woolf K, Ganguzza L, Guo Y, Allen N, et al. Anti-inflammatory effects of a vegan diet versus the American Heart Association-recommended diet in coronary artery disease trial. J Am Heart Assoc. 2018 Dec 4;7(23):e011367. Shah et al. demonstrated that an 8-week vegan intervention can significantly reduce high-sensitivity C-reactive protein by 32%. This approach could be useful to reduce systemic inflammation in patients with long-COVID.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6405545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30571591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baden MY, Satija A, Hu FB, Huang T. Change in plant-based diet quality is associated with changes in plasma adiposity-associated biomarker concentrations in women. J Nutr. 2019;149(4):676&#x2013;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6461739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30927000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craddock JC, Neale EP, Peoples GE, Probst YC. Vegetarian-based dietary patterns and their relation with inflammatory and immune biomarkers: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Adv Nutr. 2019;10(3):433&#x2013;451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6520040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30947338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mainardi T, Kapoor S, Bielory L. Complementary and alternative medicine: herbs, phytochemicals and vitamins and their immunologic effects. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2009;123(2):283&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19203652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninfali P, Antonelli A, Magnani M, Scarpa ES. Antiviral properties of flavonoids and delivery strategies. Nutrients. 2020;12(9):E2534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7551920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32825564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zakaryan H, Arabyan E, Oo A, Zandi K. Flavonoids: promising natural compounds against viral infections. Arch Virol. 2017;162(9):2539&#x2013;2551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7087220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28547385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YS, Sayers TJ, Colburn NH, Milner JA, Young HA. Impact of dietary components on NK and Treg cell function for cancer prevention. Mol Carcinog. 2015;54(9):669&#x2013;678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4536099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25845339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malter M, Schriever G, Eilber U. Natural killer cells, vitamins, and other blood components of vegetarian and omnivorous men. Nutr Cancer. 1989;12(3):271&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2771803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad EH, Berk LS, Kettering JD, Hubbard RW, Peters WR. Dietary intake and biochemical, hematologic, and immune status of vegans compared with nonvegetarians. Am J Clin Nutr. 1999;70(3 Suppl):586S&#x2013;593S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10479236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong TYN, Key TJ, Gaitskell K, Green TJ, Guo W, Sanders TA, et al. Hematological parameters and prevalence of anemia in white and British Indian vegetarians and nonvegetarians in the UK Biobank. Am J Clin Nutr. 2019;110(2):461&#x2013;472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6669054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31190054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung C-H, Lee W-Y, Kim B-Y, Park SE, Rhee E-J, Park C-Y, et al. The risk of metabolic syndrome according to the white blood cell count in apparently healthy Korean adults. Yonsei Med J. 2013;54(3):615&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3635622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23549805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gkrania-Klotsas E, Ye Z, Cooper AJ, Sharp SJ, Luben R, Biggs ML, et al. Differential white blood cell count and type 2 diabetes: systematic review and meta-analysis of cross-sectional and prospective studies. PLoS One. 2010;5(10):e13405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2956635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20976133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth A, Reed AB, Ponzo S, Yassaee A, Aral M, Plans D, et al. Population risk factors for severe disease and mortality in COVID-19: a global systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2021;16(3):e0247461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7932512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33661992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farmer B, Larson BT, Fulgoni VL, Rainville AJ, Liepa GU. A vegetarian dietary pattern as a nutrient-dense approach to weight management: an analysis of the national health and nutrition examination survey 1999&#x2013;2004. J Am Diet Assoc. 2011;111(6):819&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21616194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fres&#xe1;n U, Errendal S, Craig WJ. Influence of the socio-cultural environment and external factors in following plant-based diets. Sustainability. 2020;12(21):9093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mensink GBM, Lage Barbosa C, Brettschneider AK. Prevalence of persons following a vegetarian diet in Germany. J Health Monitor. 2016;1(2):2&#x2013;14. doi: 10.17886/RKI-GBE-2016-039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17886/RKI-GBE-2016-039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9838578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36654829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paslakis G, Richardson C, N&#xf6;hre M, Br&#xe4;hler E, Holzapfel C, Hilbert A, et al. Prevalence and psychopathology of vegetarians and vegans &#x2013; results from a representative survey in Germany. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):6840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7176641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32321977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davey GK, Spencer EA, Appleby PN, Allen NE, Knox KH, Key TJ. EPIC-Oxford: lifestyle characteristics and nutrient intakes in a cohort of 33 883 meat-eaters and 31 546 non meat-eaters in the UK. Public Health Nutr. 2003;6(3):259&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12740075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>