<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37688764</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1534-3170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current cardiology reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Cardiol Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID Vaccination as a Strategy for Cardiovascular Disease Prevention.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1327</StartPage><EndPage>1335</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1327-1335</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11886-023-01950-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Cardiovascular (CV) disease is a known complication of SARS-CoV-2 infection. A clear benefit of COVID-19 vaccination is a reduction mortality; however, COVID-19 vaccination may also prevent cardiovascular disease (CVD). We aim to describe CV pathology associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection and describe how COVID-19 vaccination is a strategy for CVD prevention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">The risks and benefits of COVID-19 vaccination have been widely studied. Analysis of individuals with and without pre-existing CVD has shown that COVID-19 vaccination can prevent morbidity associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection and reduce mortality. COVID-19 vaccination is effective in preventing myocardial infarction, cerebrovascular events, myopericarditis, and long COVID, all associated with CVD risk factors. Vaccination reduces mortality in patients with pre-existing CVD. Further study investigating ideal vaccination schedules for individuals with CVD should be undertaken to protect this vulnerable group and address new risks from variants of concern.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fundora</LastName><ForeName>Michael P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's Healthcare of Atlanta Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, Emory University, 1405 Clifton Rd NE, Atlanta, GA, 30322, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamidani</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Center for Childhood Infections and Vaccines of Children's Healthcare of Atlanta and the Department of Pediatrics, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oster</LastName><ForeName>Matthew E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2243-8367</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's Healthcare of Atlanta Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, Emory University, 1405 Clifton Rd NE, Atlanta, GA, 30322, USA. OsterM@kidsheart.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Cardiol Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100888969</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1523-3782</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000086663">COVID-19 Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086663" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002318" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiovascular Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014611" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccination</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiovascular disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccination</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37688764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11886-023-01950-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11886-023-01950-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Papers of particular interest, published recently, have been highlighted as: &#x2022;&#xa0; Of importance &#x2022;&#x2022; Of major importance</Title><Reference><Citation>Guo T, Fan Y, Chen M, Wu X, Zhang L, He T, et al. Cardiovascular implications of fatal outcomes of patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5(7):811&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32219356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2020.1017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall EJ, Das SR, Ayers C, Bradley SM, Elkind M, Hall JL, et al. Longitudinal trends in cardiovascular complications among patients hospitalized for Covid-19 infection: a national multi-center analysis. Circulation. 2022;146(Suppl_1):A10406-A.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28(3):583&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-01689-3 .&#xa0;Findings from this study demonstrated the increased risks of a multitude of adverse cardiovascular outcomes associated with COVID-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustino G, Pinney SP, Lala A, Reddy VY, Johnston-Cox HA, Mechanick JI, et al. Coronavirus and cardiovascular disease, myocardial injury, and arrhythmia: JACC focus seminar. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76(17):2011&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33092737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7572122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2020.08.059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsoularis I, Fonseca-Rodr&#xed;guez O, Farrington P, Jerndal H, Lundevaller EH, Sund M, et al. Risks of deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, and bleeding after covid-19: nationwide self-controlled cases series and matched cohort study. BMJ. 2022;377:e069590. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj-2021-069590 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsoularis I, Fonseca-Rodr&#xed;guez O, Farrington P, Lindmark K, Connolly AMF. Risk of acute myocardial infarction and ischaemic stroke following COVID-19 in Sweden: a self-controlled case series and matched cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398(10300):599&#x2013;607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YE, Huh K, Park YJ, Peck KR, Jung J. Association between vaccination and acute myocardial infarction and ischemic stroke after COVID-19 infection. JAMA. 2022;328(9):887&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35867050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9449799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.12992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lala A, Johnson KW, Januzzi JL, Russak AJ, Paranjpe I, Richter F, et al. Prevalence and impact of myocardial injury in patients hospitalized with COVID-19 infection. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76(5):533&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32517963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7279721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2020.06.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luetkens JA, Isaak A, Zimmer S, Nattermann J, Sprinkart AM, Boesecke C, et al. Diffuse myocardial inflammation in COVID-19 associated myocarditis detected by multiparametric cardiac magnetic resonance imaging. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging. 2020;13(5):e010897.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modin D, Claggett B, Sindet-Pedersen C, Lassen MCH, Skaarup KG, Jensen JUS, et al. Acute COVID-19 and the incidence of ischemic stroke and acute myocardial infarction. Circulation. 2020;142(21):2080&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33054349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7682795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.050809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahra RE, Jackie C, Ahmed S, Betty R, Aaron Mark L, Stefan N, et al. Cardiovascular disease and mortality sequelae of COVID-19 in the UK Biobank. Heart. 2023;109(2):119. https://doi.org/10.1136/heartjnl-2022-321492 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/heartjnl-2022-321492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasudeva R, Challa A, Al Rifai M, Polana T, Duran B, Vindhyal M, et al. Prevalence of cardiovascular diseases in COVID-19 related mortality in the United States. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Sole F, Farcomeni A, Loffredo L, Carnevale R, Menichelli D, Vicario T, et al. Features of severe COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Clin Invest. 2020;50(10):e13378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figliozzi S, Masci PG, Ahmadi N, Tondi L, Koutli E, Aimo A, et al. Predictors of adverse prognosis in COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Clin Invest. 2020;50(10):e13362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ssentongo P, Ssentongo AE, Heilbrunn ES, Ba DM, Chinchilli VM. Association of cardiovascular disease and 10 other pre-existing comorbidities with COVID-19 mortality: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2020;15(8):e0238215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barron E, Bakhai C, Kar P, Weaver A, Bradley D, Ismail H, et al. Associations of type 1 and type 2 diabetes with COVID-19-related mortality in England: a whole-population study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2020;8(10):813&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32798472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7426088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(20)30272-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu E, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Risks and burdens of incident dyslipidaemia in long COVID: a cohort study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes LD, Ingram J, Sculthorpe NF. More than 100 persistent symptoms of SARS-CoV-2 (long COVID): a scoping review. Front Med. 2021;8: 750378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.750378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simone A, Herald J, Chen A, Nayak R, Shen AYJ, Lee MS. Exacerbation of pre-existing cardiovascular disease following COVID-19 mRNA vaccination. Circulation. 2022;146(Suppl_1):A11371-A.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peiris S, Ordunez P, DiPette D, Padwal R, Ambrosi P, Toledo J, et al. Cardiac manifestations in patients with COVID-19: a scoping review. Global Heart. 2022;17(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polito MV, Silverio A, Bellino M, Iuliano G, Di Maio M, Alfano C, et al. Cardiovascular involvement in COVID-19: what sequelae should we expect? Cardiol Ther. 2021;10(2):377&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34191268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8243311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40119-021-00232-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Wang C-Y, Wang SI, Wei JCC. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes in COVID-19 survivors among non-vaccinated population: a retrospective cohort study from the TriNetX US collaborative networks. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;53:101619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson S, Hirsch JS, Narasimhan M, Crawford JM, McGinn T, Davidson KW, et al. Presenting characteristics, comorbidities, and outcomes among 5700 patients hospitalized with COVID-19 in the New York City area. JAMA. 2020;323(20):2052&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.6775 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.6775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32320003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7177629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodruff RC, Garg S, George MG, Patel K, Jackson SL, Loustalot F, et al. Acute cardiac events during COVID-19-associated hospitalizations. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023;81(6):557&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36754516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9901494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2022.11.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardi CM, Carubelli V, Iorio A, Inciardi RM, Bellasi A, Canale C, et al. Association of troponin levels with mortality in Italian patients hospitalized with coronavirus disease 2019: results of a multicenter study. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5(11):1274&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32845276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2020.3538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandoval Y, Januzzi JL Jr, Jaffe AS. Cardiac troponin for assessment of myocardial injury in COVID-19: JACC review topic of the week. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76(10):1244&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32652195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7833921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2020.06.068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594(7862):259&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-021-03553-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall EJ, Ayers CR, Kolkailah AA, Rutan C, Walchok J, Williams IV JH, et al. Longitudinal trends in cardiovascular risk factor profiles and complications among patients hospitalized for COVID-19 infection: results from the American Heart Association COVID-19 Cardiovascular Disease Registry. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2023:e009652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Li M, Wang M, Zhou Y, Chang J, Xian Y, et al. Acute cerebrovascular disease following COVID-19: a single center, retrospective, observational study. Stroke Vasc Neurol. 2020;5(3).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilaloglu S, Aphinyanaphongs Y, Jones S, Iturrate E, Hochman J, Berger JS. Thrombosis in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 in a New York City health system. JAMA. 2020;324(8):799&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32702090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7372509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.13372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewek J, Jatczak-Pawlik I, Maciejewski M, Jankowski P, Banach M. COVID-19 and cardiovascular complications&#x2013;preliminary results of the LATE-COVID study. Arch Med Sci. 2021;17(3):818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34025853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8130484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/aoms/134211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perego E, Callard F, Stras L, Melville-Johannesson B, Pope R, Alwan N. Why we need to keep using the patient made term &#x201c;Long Covid. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendelson M, Nel J, Blumberg L, Madhi S, Dryden M, Stevens W, et al. Long-COVID: an evolving problem with an extensive impact. S Afr Med J. 2021;111(1):10&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorokin AV, Karathanasis SK, Yang ZH, Freeman L, Kotani K, Remaley AT. COVID-19&#x2014;associated dyslipidemia: implications for mechanism of impaired resolution and novel therapeutic approaches. FASEB J. 2020;34(8):9843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32588493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202001451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roccaforte V, Daves M, Lippi G, Spreafico M, Bonato C. Altered lipid profile in patients with COVID-19 infection. J Lab Precis Med. 2021;6:2-.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Yao H, Zhang N, Wu J, Gao S, Guo J, et al. Proteomic analysis identifies prolonged disturbances in pathways related to cholesterol metabolism and myocardium function in the COVID-19 recovery stage. J Proteome Res. 2021;20(7):3463&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34080435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jproteome.1c00054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jone PN, John A, Oster ME, Allen K, Tremoulet AH, Saarel EV, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection and associated cardiovascular manifestations and complications in children and young adults: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2022;145(19):e1037&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35400169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000001064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasa JJ, Alali A, Anders M, Tume SC, Muscal E, Tejtel SKS, et al. Cardiovascular sequelae from COVID-19: perspectives from a paediatric cardiac ICU. Cardiol Young. 2023;33(1):52&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1047951122000130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams N, Radia T, Harman K, Agrawal P, Cook J, Gupta A. COVID-19 Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection in children and adolescents: a systematic review of critically unwell children and the association with underlying comorbidities. Eur J Pediatr. 2021;180:689&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32914200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-020-03801-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fremed MA, Healy EW, Choi NH, Cheung EW, Choudhury TA, Jiang P, et al. Elevated cardiac biomarkers and outcomes in children and adolescents with acute COVID-19. Cardiol Young. 2023;33(2):183&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35086607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1047951122000397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guner Ozenen G, Akaslan Kara A, Kiymet E, Boncuoglu E, Sahinkaya S, Cem E, et al. The evaluation of troponin I levels and myocarditis in children with COVID-19: a pediatric single-center experience. Pediatr Cardiol. 2023;44(4):873&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36210385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00246-022-03017-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels CJ, Rajpal S, Greenshields JT, Rosenthal GL, Chung EH, Terrin M, et al. Prevalence of clinical and subclinical myocarditis in competitive athletes with recent SARS-CoV-2 infection: results from the big ten COVID-19 cardiac registry. JAMA Cardiol. 2021;6(9):1078&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34042947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8160916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2021.2065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark DE, Parikh A, Dendy JM, Diamond AB, George-Durrett K, Fish FA, et al. COVID-19 myocardial pathology evaluation in athletes with cardiac magnetic resonance (COMPETE CMR). Circulation. 2021;143(6):609&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33332151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.052573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldstein LR, Rose EB, Horwitz SM, Collins JP, Newhams MM, Son MBF, et al. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in US children and adolescents. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(4):334&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32598831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2021680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dufort EM, Koumans EH, Chow EJ, Rosenthal EM, Muse A, Rowlands J, et al. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children in New York State. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(4):347&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32598830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2021756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belay ED, Abrams J, Oster ME, Giovanni J, Pierce T, Meng L, et al. Trends in geographic and temporal distribution of US children with multisystem inflammatory syndrome during the COVID-19 pandemic. JAMA Pediatr. 2021;175(8):837&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33821923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2021.0630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilboa SM, Devine OJ, Kucik JE, Oster ME, Riehle-Colarusso T, Nembhard WN, et al. Congenital heart defects in the United States: estimating the magnitude of the affected population in 2010. Circulation. 2016;134(2):101&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27382105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4942347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.115.019307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehwerhemuepha L, Roth B, Patel AK, Heutlinger O, Heffernan C, Arrieta AC, et al. Association of congenital and acquired cardiovascular conditions with COVID-19 severity among pediatric patients in the US. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(5):e2211967-e.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnesi M, Baldetti L, Beneduce A, Calvo F, Gramegna M, Pazzanese V, et al. Pulmonary hypertension and right ventricular involvement in hospitalised patients with COVID-19. Heart. 2020;106(17):1324&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32675217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/heartjnl-2020-317355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broberg CS, Kovacs AH, Sadeghi S, Rosenbaum MS, Lewis MJ, Carazo MR, et al. COVID-19 in adults with congenital heart disease. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;77(13):1644&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33795039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8006800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2021.02.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis MJ, Anderson BR, Fremed M, Argenio M, Krishnan U, Weller R, et al. Impact of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) on patients with congenital heart disease across the lifespan: the experience of an academic congenital heart disease center in New York City. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020;9(23):e017580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrero P, Piazza I, Ciuffreda M. COVID-19 in adult patients with CHD: a matter of anatomy or comorbidities? Cardiol Young. 2020;30(8):1196&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32522306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1047951120001638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Liu A, Brophy JM, Cohen S, Abrahamowicz M, Paradis G, et al. Determinants of survival in older adults with congenital heart disease newly hospitalized for heart failure. Circ Heart Fail. 2020;13(8):e006490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downing KF, Simeone RM, Oster ME, Farr SL. Critical illness among patients hospitalized with acute COVID-19 with and without congenital heart defects. Circulation. 2022;145(15):1182&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35249378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8989604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.121.057833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baden LR, El Sahly HM, Essink B, Kotloff K, Frey S, Novak R, et al. Efficacy and safety of the mRNA-1273 SARS-CoV-2 vaccine. N Engl J Med. 2021;384(5):403&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2035389 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2035389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33378609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polack FP, Thomas SJ, Kitchin N, Absalon J, Gurtman A, Lockhart S, et al. Safety and efficacy of the BNT162b2 mRNA Covid-19 vaccine. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(27):2603&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2034577 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2034577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33301246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadoff J, Gray G, Vandebosch A, C&#xe1;rdenas V, Shukarev G, Grinsztejn B, et al. Safety and efficacy of single-dose Ad26.COV2.S vaccine against Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2021;384(23):2187&#x2013;201. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2101544 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heath PT, Galiza EP, Baxter DN, Boffito M, Browne D, Burns F, et al. Safety and efficacy of NVX-CoV2373 Covid-19 vaccine. N Engl J Med. 2021;385(13):1172&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2107659 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2107659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34192426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madewell ZJ, Yang Y, Longini IM, Halloran ME, Dean NE. Factors associated with household transmission of SARS-CoV-2: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(8):e2122240-e.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riemersma KK, Haddock LA, 3rd, Wilson NA, Minor N, Eickhoff J, Grogan BE, et al. Shedding of infectious SARS-CoV-2 despite vaccination. PLoS Pathog. 2022;18(9):e1010876. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.ppat.1010876 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah AS, Gribben C, Bishop J, Hanlon P, Caldwell D, Wood R, et al. Effect of vaccination on transmission of SARS-CoV-2. N Engl J Med. 2021;385(18):1718&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34496200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMc2106757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RJ, Hall JA, Zaidi A, Andrews NJ, Dunbar JK, Dabrera G. Effect of vaccination on household transmission of SARS-CoV-2 in England. N Engl J Med. 2021;385(8):759&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34161702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMc2107717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madewell ZJ, Yang Y, Longini IM, Jr, Halloran ME, Dean NE. Household secondary attack rates of SARS-CoV-2 by variant and vaccination status: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(4):e229317-e. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.9317 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyre DW, Taylor D, Purver M, Chapman D, Fowler T, Pouwels KB, et al. Effect of Covid-19 vaccination on transmission of alpha and delta variants. N Engl J Med. 2022;386(8):744&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2116597 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2116597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34986294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez-Gil IJ, Feltes G, Viana-Llamas MC, Raposeiras-Roubin S, Romero R, Alfonso-Rodr&#xed;guez E, et al. Post-COVID-19 symptoms and heart disease: incidence, prognostic factors, outcomes and vaccination: results from a multi-center international prospective registry (HOPE 2). J Clin Med. 2023;12(2):706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36675633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9863454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12020706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhtar Z, Trent M, Moa A, Tan TC, Fr&#xf6;bert O, MacIntyre CR. The impact of COVID-19 and COVID vaccination on cardiovascular outcomes. Eur Heart J Suppl. 2023;25(Supplement_A):A42-A9. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartjsupp/suac123 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parodi JB, Indavere A, Jacob PB, Toledo GC, Micali RG, Waisman G, et al. Impact of COVID-19 vaccination in post-COVID cardiac complications. Vaccine. 2023;41(8):1524&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36725436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9885297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2023.01.052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022;&#x2022; Jiang J, Chan L, Kauffman J, Narula J, Charney AW, Oh W, et al. Impact of vaccination on major adverse cardiovascular events in patients with COVID-19 infection. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023;81(9):928&#x2013;30. This article demonstrates that COVID-19 vaccination not only protects individuals from contracting COVID-19, but in instances where an individual does contract COVID-19 the likelihood of major adverse cardiovascular events is reduced.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye X, Yan VK, Yiu HHE, Shami JJ, Kang W, Ma T, et al. BNT162b2 or CoronaVac vaccinations are associated with a lower risk of myocardial infarction and stroke after SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection among patients with cardiovascular disease. J Am Heart Assoc. 2022:e029291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteley WN, Ip S, Cooper JA, Bolton T, Keene S, Walker V, et al. Association of COVID-19 vaccines ChAdOx1 and BNT162b2 with major venous, arterial, or thrombocytopenic events: a population-based cohort study of 46 million adults in England. PLoS Med. 2022;19(2):e1003926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patone M, Mei XW, Handunnetthi L, Dixon S, Zaccardi F, Shankar-Hari M, et al. Risks of myocarditis, pericarditis, and cardiac arrhythmias associated with COVID-19 vaccination or SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med. 2022;28(2):410&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34907393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01630-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zambrano LD, Newhams MM, Olson SM, Halasa NB, Price AM, Boom JA, et al. Effectiveness of BNT162b2 (Pfizer-BioNTech) mRNA vaccination against multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children among persons aged 12&#x2013;18 years&#x2014;United States, July&#x2013;December 2021. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71(2):52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm7102e1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Oster ME, Shay DK, Su JR, Gee J, Creech CB, Broder KR, et al. Myocarditis cases reported after mRNA-based COVID-19 vaccination in the US from December 2020 to August 2021. Jama. 2022;327(4):331&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2021.24110 . This manuscript details the incidence and clinical findings of acute myocarditis associated with COVID-19 vaccination from cases reported to the US Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin SE, Bhavsar SM, Corson A, Ghersin ZJ, Kim HS. Cardiac complications associated with COVID-19, MIS-C, and mRNA COVID-19 vaccination. Pediatr Cardiol. 2022;43(3):483&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35258639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8902276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00246-022-02851-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block JP, Boehmer TK, Forrest CB, Carton TW, Lee GM, Ajani UA, et al. Cardiac complications after SARS-CoV-2 infection and mRNA COVID-19 vaccination&#x2014;PCORnet, United States, january 2021&#x2013;January 2022. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71(14):517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm7114e1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goddard K, Donahue JG, Lewis N, Hanson KE, Weintraub ES, Fireman B, et al. Safety of COVID-19 mRNA vaccination among young children in the vaccine safety datalink. Pediatrics. 2023;152(1). https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2023-061894 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hause AM, Marquez P, Zhang B, Myers TR, Gee J, Su JR, et al. COVID-19 mRNA vaccine safety among children aged 6 months&#x2013;5 years&#x2014;United States, June 18, 2022&#x2013;August 21, 2022. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71(35):1115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm7135a3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis C, Logan N, Tyson G, Orton R, Harvey WT, Perkins JS, et al. Reduced neutralisation of the Delta (B.1.617.2) SARS-CoV-2 variant of concern following vaccination. PLOS Pathogens. 2021;17(12):e1010022. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.ppat.1010022 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouwels KB, Pritchard E, Matthews PC, Stoesser N, Eyre DW, Vihta KD, et al. Effect of Delta variant on viral burden and vaccine effectiveness against new SARS-CoV-2 infections in the UK. Nat Med. 2021;27(12):2127&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-021-01548-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01548-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34650248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8674129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noori M, Nejadghaderi SA, Arshi S, Carson-Chahhoud K, Ansarin K, Kolahi AA, et al. Potency of BNT162b2 and mRNA-1273 vaccine-induced neutralizing antibodies against severe acute respiratory syndrome-CoV-2 variants of concern: A systematic review of in vitro studies. Rev Med Vir. 2022;32(2):e2277. https://doi.org/10.1002/rmv.2277 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayart JL, Douxfils J, Gillot C, David C, Mullier F, Elsen M, et al. Waning of IgG, total and neutralizing antibodies 6 months post-vaccination with BNT162b2 in healthcare workers. Vaccines. 2021;9(10):1092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34696200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8540417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vaccines9101092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israel A, Merzon E, Sch&#xe4;ffer AA, Shenhar Y, Green I, Golan-Cohen A, et al. Elapsed time since BNT162b2 vaccine and risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection: test negative design study. BMJ. 2021;375:e067873. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj-2021-067873 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menegale F, Manica M, Zardini A, Guzzetta G, Marziano V, d'Andrea V, et al. Evaluation of waning of SARS-CoV-2 vaccine&#x2013;induced immunity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6(5):e2310650-e. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.10650 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferdinands JM, Rao S, Dixon BE, Mitchell PK, DeSilva MB, Irving SA, et al. Waning of vaccine effectiveness against moderate and severe covid-19 among adults in the US from the VISION network: test negative, case-control study. BMJ. 2022;379:e072141. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj-2022-072141 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan WC, Tan JYJ, Lim JSJ, Tan RYC, Lee ARYB, Leong FL, et al. COVID-19 severity and waning immunity after up to 4 mRNA vaccine doses in 73 608 patients with cancer and 621 475 matched controls in Singapore: a nationwide cohort study. JAMA Oncol. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaoncol.2023.2271 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoncol.2023.2271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37856106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10485745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases. https://www.niaid.nih.gov/diseases-conditions/next-generation-covid-19-vaccines . Accessed 7 Aug 2023.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>