<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38865213</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-5022</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2024 Nov-Dec 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of public health management and practice : JPHMP</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Public Health Manag Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Maintaining and Improving Virtual Call Centers for Public Health: The CUNY Recovery Corps Experience.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>869</StartPage><EndPage>878</EndPage><MedlinePgn>869-878</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PHH.0000000000001959</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CONTEXT" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In the early stages of the COVID-19 pandemic in New York City, individuals who tested positive, exposed contacts, and their families faced significant challenges in accessing essential resources for successful quarantine and isolation. These resources included alternative housing, food access, grocery delivery, missed wage assistance, transportation for household members, medical care, and more.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PROGRAM" NlmCategory="METHODS">The City University of New York (CUNY) Recovery Corps emerged as an innovative virtual resource navigation service to connect New Yorkers to essential resources and later to vaccinations, treatment, and services for Long COVID. The program prioritized reaching people living in underserved and under-resourced neighborhoods. Over 3&#xa0;years, it made a substantial impact, reaching 374&#xa0;728 New Yorkers and connecting 135&#xa0;147 to crucial resources.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="IMPLEMENTATION" NlmCategory="METHODS">Implementing a successful virtual navigation center amidst a global pandemic posed unique challenges. It required well-established systems to provide services, manage staff, build community, and both assure and improve service quality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="EVALUATION" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Continuous quality assurance and process improvement efforts resulted in a nearly 10-point increase in successful client-resource connections program-wide, with individual navigators showing improvements of up to 20%. Staff-led initiatives, such as population-specific resource guides and incentive awards, boosted morale and cohesion. Providing continuous professional development opportunities and requested training including trauma-informed care, self-care, and strategies for managing grief contributed to staff retention and improved client interactions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The CUNY Recovery Corps provides a blueprint for setting up navigation services for emergency response and supporting health and social services. The current paper delves into the intensive quality improvement efforts, program management infrastructure, and staff support that made this program a success. By applying these lessons on establishing and maintaining a virtual call center prioritizing the client's well-being and staff strengths, policymakers and social service leaders can effectively address various health and social service needs proactively rather than rebuilding after each disaster.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Srividhya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Innovation in Mental Health (Dr Sharma); City University of New York Graduate School of Public Health and Health Policy, New York, New York (Ms El-Alfi and Dr Greene).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Alfi</LastName><ForeName>Valerie</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greene</LastName><ForeName>Danielle</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Public Health Manag Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9505213</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1078-4659</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009519" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">New York City</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011634" MajorTopicYN="Y">Public Health</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38865213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHH.0000000000001959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124784-990000000-00266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Binns C, Low WY, Kyung LM. The COVID-19 pandemic: public health and epidemiology. Asia Pacific J Public Health. 2020;32(4):140-144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenthal A, Waitzberg R. The challenges brought by the COVID-19 pandemic to health systems exposed pre-existing gaps. Health Policy Open. 2023;4:100088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen GD, Jacobsen KH. Statewide COVID-19 stay-at-home orders and population mobility in the United States. World Med Health Policy. 2020;12(4):347-356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedson A, McNichols D, Sabia J, Dave D (2020). Did California&#x2019;s shelter&#x2010;in&#x2010;place order work? Early coronavirus&#x2010;related public health effects. NBER Working Paper No. w26992. Cambridge, MA: National Bureau of Economic Research.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson CN, Baumgartner J, Pichardo C, et al. COVID-19 outbreak &#x2014; New York City, February 29&#x2013;June 1, 2020. MMWR Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report. 2020;69(46):1725-1729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matias T, Dominski FH, Marks DF. Human needs in COVID-19 isolation. J Health Psychol. 2020;25(7):871-882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resolve to Save Lives. Services to Support People in Isolation and Quarantine. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa-Leiker C, Smith CL, Crespi EJ, et al. Stressors, coping, and resources needed during the COVID-19 pandemic in a sample of perinatal women. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2021;21(1):171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eraso Y, Hills S. Self-isolation and quarantine during the UK&#x2019;s first wave of COVID-19: a mixed-methods study of non-adherence. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(13):7015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantamneni N. The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on marginalized populations in the United States: a research agenda. J Vocational Behav. 2020;119:103439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estrada LV, Levasseur JL, Maxim A, Benavidez GA, Pollack Porter KM. Structural racism, place, and COVID-19: a narrative review describing how we prepare for an endemic COVID-19 future. Health Equity. 2022;6(1):356-366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey K, Ayers CK, Kondo KK, et al. Racial and ethnic disparities in COVID-19-related infections, hospitalizations, and deaths: a systematic review. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174(3):362&#x2013;373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairchild A, Gostin L, Bayer R. Vexing, veiled, and inequitable: social distancing and the &#x201c;rights&#x201d; divide in the age of COVID-19. Am J Bioeth. 2020;20(7):55-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NYC Department of Health and Mental Hygiene. (n.d.). Neighborhoods. https://www.nyc.gov/site/trie/about/neighborhoods.page . Accessed February 23, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NYC Health + Hospitals. (2022, April 07). Test &amp; Trace canvassers engage New Yorkers in over 10 million conversations [press release]. https://www.nychealthandhospitals.org/pressrelease/test-trace-canvassers-engage-new-yorkers-in-over-10-million-conversations/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas HM, Settles IH, Cech EA, et al. Disproportionate impacts of COVID-19 on marginalized and minoritized early-career academic scientists. PLoS One. 2022;17(9):e0274278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tai DBG, Shah A, Doubeni CA, Sia IG, Wieland ML. The disproportionate impact of COVID-19 on racial and ethnic minorities in the United States. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;72(4):703-706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanijahani A, Iezadi S, Gholipour K, Azami-Aghdash S, Naghibi D. A systematic review of racial/ethnic and socioeconomic disparities in COVID-19. Int J Equity Health. 2021;20(1):248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenleaf AR, Millington M, Chan K, et al. Effect of COVID-19 pandemic on older New York City residents living at home. J Community Health. 2022;47(2):361-370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns A (2023). Long COVID: what do the latest data show? https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/long-covid-what-do-latest-data-show/ . Accessed February 23, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luft S (2022). Long COVID symptoms most common among Latinos and residents of the Bronx.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glassman B (2023). Household pulse survey shows 31.1% reported symptoms three months or longer after they had COVID-19. https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2023/05/long-covid-19-symptoms-reported.html . Accessed February 23, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. (2021). COVID-19 Long COVID or post-COVID conditions. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html . Accessed February 23, 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>