<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">37934848</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK596746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>Canadian Agency for Drugs and Technologies in Health</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Ottawa (ON)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="op72831011100050">Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy: An Emerging Therapy for Post&#x2013;COVID-19 Condition: CADTH Horizon Scan</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month></PubDate><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Authors</CollectiveName></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Basharat</LastName><ForeName>Sinwan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spry</LastName><ForeName>Carolyn</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author></AuthorList><CollectionTitle book="cadthhorizoncollect">CADTH Horizon Scans</CollectionTitle><Medium>Internet</Medium><ReportNumber>Report No.: EN0050</ReportNumber></Book><Language>eng</Language><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText Label="WHAT IS THE ISSUE?">Post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition presents an important challenge to health care decision-makers in Canada and across the world due to the high volume of potential patients, diverse presentations of symptoms, few clinical guidelines and treatments, and unknown pathophysiology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="WHAT IS THE TECHNOLOGY?">Hyperbaric oxygen therapy (HBOT) is an established treatment for certain wound injuries, vascular conditions, and in specific medical emergencies. It is now being tested for post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition, also known as long COVID. The therapy delivers a high concentration of oxygen inside specialized pressure chambers. HBOT has been proposed as a treatment to help resolve prominent symptoms of post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition, such as fatigue and brain fog. The therapy may induce physiological changes that aid in recovering from the long-term effects and tissue damage due to severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-COV-2) infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="WHAT IS THE POTENTIAL IMPACT?">Results from early studies indicate that HBOT could improve a range of post&#x2013;COVID-19 symptoms and its use is generally safe with few adverse effects. These results are based on 2 randomized control trials and small nonrandomized studies and case reports. However, published results have been based on studies with limited sample sizes and limited long-term follow-up. HBOT could offer a therapy option that could support millions of people around the world with post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition if the ongoing and subsequent studies show efficacy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="WHAT ELSE DO WE NEED TO KNOW?">As of now, there are uncertainties about how to effectively deliver and dose the therapy and the potential safety implications for people with post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition. Implementation considerations, such as the number and location of hyperbaric oxygen chambers, will be important if HBOT is appropriate for a large number of people. As the evidence base develops, the potential role of HBOT in therapy for people with post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition will become clearer and will provide an indication of what kind of health system planning may be needed to provide HBOT for those who can benefit.</AbstractText></Abstract></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37934848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>