<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34386785</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-7762</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Lancet regional health. Europe</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Reg Health Eur</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long Covid in adults discharged from UK hospitals after Covid-19: A prospective, multicentre cohort study using the ISARIC WHO Clinical Characterisation Protocol.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100186</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100186</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100186</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100186</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study sought to establish the long-term effects of Covid-19 following hospitalisation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">327 hospitalised participants, with SARS-CoV-2 infection were recruited into a prospective multicentre cohort study at least 3 months post-discharge. The primary outcome was self-reported recovery at least ninety days after initial Covid-19 symptom onset. Secondary outcomes included new symptoms, disability (Washington group short scale), breathlessness (MRC Dyspnoea scale) and quality of life (EQ5D-5L).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">55% of participants reported not feeling fully recovered. 93% reported persistent symptoms, with fatigue the most common (83%), followed by breathlessness (54%). 47% reported an increase in MRC dyspnoea scale of at least one grade. New or worse disability was reported by 24% of participants. The EQ5D-5L summary index was significantly worse following acute illness (median difference 0.1 points on a scale of 0 to 1, IQR: -0.2 to 0.0). Females under the age of 50 years were five times less likely to report feeling recovered (adjusted OR 5.09, 95% CI 1.64 to 15.74), were more likely to have greater disability (adjusted OR 4.22, 95% CI 1.12 to 15.94), twice as likely to report worse fatigue (adjusted OR 2.06, 95% CI 0.81 to 3.31) and seven times more likely to become more breathless (adjusted OR 7.15, 95% CI 2.24 to 22.83) than men of the same age.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Survivors of Covid-19 experienced long-term symptoms, new disability, increased breathlessness, and reduced quality of life. These findings were present in young, previously healthy working age adults, and were most common in younger females.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">National Institute for Health Research, UK Medical Research Council,&#xa0;Wellcome&#xa0;Trust, Department for International Development and the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sigfrid</LastName><ForeName>Louise</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Fellow, Public Health Specialist, ISARIC Global Support Centre, Centre for Tropical Medicine and Global Health, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drake</LastName><ForeName>Thomas M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Fellow, Centre for Medical Informatics, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pauley</LastName><ForeName>Ellen</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Student, University of Edinburgh Medical School, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jesudason</LastName><ForeName>Edwin C</ForeName><Initials>EC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Consultant in Rehabilitation Medicine, NHS Lothian, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olliaro</LastName><ForeName>Piero</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Professor of Poverty Related Infectious Diseases, ISARIC Global Support Centre, Centre for Tropical Medicine and Global Health, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lim</LastName><ForeName>Wei Shen</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Honorary Professor of Respiratory Medicine, Department of Respiratory Medicine, Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust and University of Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gillesen</LastName><ForeName>Annelies</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Senior Clinical Trial Nurse, ISARIC Global Support Centre, Centre for Tropical Medicine and Global Health, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berry</LastName><ForeName>Colin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Professor of Cardiology and Imaging, Institute of Cardiovascular and Medical Sciences, University of Glasgow.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lowe</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Consultant in Emergency Medicine, NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde, Emergency Department, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McPeake</LastName><ForeName>Joanne</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nurse Consultant in Clinical Research, School of Medicine, Dentistry and Nursing, University of Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lone</LastName><ForeName>Nazir</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Senior Clinical Lecturer in Critical Care, Usher Institute, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Munblit</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Professor of Paediatrics, Department of Paediatrics and Paediatric Infectious Diseases, Institute of Child's Health, Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University (Sechenov University), Moscow, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Senior Lecturer, Inflammation, Repair and Development Section, National Heart and Lung Institute, Faculty of Medicine, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cevik</LastName><ForeName>Muge</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Lecturer, Division of Infection and Global Health Research, University of St Andrews.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Casey</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Student, Brighton and Sussex Medical School, Brighton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bannister</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Student, Brighton and Sussex Medical School, Brighton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Russell</LastName><ForeName>Clark D</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Lecturer in Infectious Diseases, Centre for Inflammation Research, University of Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goodwin</LastName><ForeName>Lynsey</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Specialist Registrar in Infectious Diseases and General Internal Medicine, Tropical and Infectious Diseases Unit, North Manchester General Hospital, Delaunays Rd, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Fellow, National Institute of Health Research (NIHR) Health Protection Research Unit in emerging and zoonotic infections, Institute of Infection, Veterinary and Ecological Sciences, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ho</LastName><ForeName>Antonia</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Senior Lecturer/Consultant in Infectious Diseases, MRC-University of Glasgow Centre for Virus Research, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turtle</LastName><ForeName>Lance</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Senior Clinical Lecturer, NIHR Health Protection Research Unit in emerging and zoonotic infections, Institute of Infection, Veterinary and Ecological Sciences, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Consultant in Infectious Disease, Tropical and Infectious Disease Unit, Liverpool University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Hara</LastName><ForeName>Margaret E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Patient-advocate, Long COVID Support, Birmingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hastie</LastName><ForeName>Claire</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Patient-advocate, Long COVID Support, Birmingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donohue</LastName><ForeName>Chloe</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trials Coordinator, Liverpool Clinical Trials Centre, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spencer</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca G</ForeName><Initials>RG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Project Administrator, Institute of Infection, Veterinary and Ecological Sciences (IVES), University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donegan</LastName><ForeName>Cara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Project Administrator, Institute of Infection, Veterinary and Ecological Sciences (IVES), University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gummery</LastName><ForeName>Alison</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Project Administrator, Institute of Infection, Veterinary and Ecological Sciences (IVES), University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harrison</LastName><ForeName>Janet</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Data Base Developer, National Institute of Health Research (NIHR) Health Protection research Unit in Emerging and Zoonotic Infections, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Infection and Global Health, Faculty of Health and Life Sciences, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hardwick</LastName><ForeName>Hayley E</ForeName><Initials>HE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Infection and Global Health, Faculty of Health and Life Sciences, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Project Manager, National Institute of Health Research (NIHR) Health Protection research Unit in Emerging and Zoonotic Infections, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hastie</LastName><ForeName>Claire E</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lecturer in Public Health, Institute of Health and Wellbeing, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carson</LastName><ForeName>Gail</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Head, ISARIC Global Support Centre, Centre for Tropical Medicine and Global Health, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merson</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Head of Data, ISARIC Global Support Centre, Centre for Tropical Medicine and Global Health, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baillie</LastName><ForeName>J Kenneth</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Senior Clinical Research Fellow, Roslin Institute, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Openshaw</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prof. of Experimental Medicine, National Heart and Lung Institute, Imperial College, London UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harrison</LastName><ForeName>Ewen M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Director Centre for Medical Informatics, Usher Institute, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Docherty</LastName><ForeName>Annemarie B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wellcome Clinical Research Career Development Fellow, Centre for Medical Informatics, Usher Institute, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Consultant in Intesnive Care Medicine, Intensive Care Unit, Royal Infirmary Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Semple</LastName><ForeName>Malcolm G</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Professor of Child Health and Outbreak Medicine, Health Protection Research Unit In Emerging and Zoonotic Infections, Institute of Infection, Veterinary and Ecological Sciences, University of Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Consultant in Respiratory Medicine, Alder Hey Children's NHS Foundation Trust, Eaton Road, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scott</LastName><ForeName>Janet T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Lecturer in Infectious Disease, MRC-University of Glasgow Centre for Virus Research, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>ISARIC4C investigators</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MC_PC_19059</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MC_UU_12014/9</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MC_UU_12014/8</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MC_PC_19025</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><Acronym>WT_</Acronym><Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MC_PC_15001</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MC_PC_19026</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MR/N003403/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet Reg Health Eur</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101777707</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-7762</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-Covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-term outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-Covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute Covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sequelae</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>CRD declares funding from the Medical Research Council, UK. JM reports a University of Cambridge Research Fellowship.&#xa0;WSL reports unrestricted investigator-initiated research funding from Pfizer for an unrelated multi-centre study in pneumonia, in which WSL is the CI and UK NIHR research funding for unrelated clinical trials in the fields of COVID-19, tuberculosis and community-acquired pneumonia. WSL's role on the Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunisation (JCVI), UK and chair of COVID-19 Immunisation and as National Lead on British Thoracic Society community acquired pneumonia audit programme is unpaid and unrelated to this work. CB declares a British Heart Foundation Centre award, and a project grants from the Chief Scientist Office, Scottish Government CSO Long Term Effects and from Heart Research UK unrelated to this work. LG declares support from Pfizer &amp; Gilead for attendance at an educational meeting in Nov 2018 and April 2019, for cost of conference registration fee, accommodation and flights unrelated to this work. PJMO reports personal fees from consultancy, grants from MRC, EU, NIHR Biomedical Research Centres, MRC/GSK, Wellcome Trust, NIHR (HPRU) and NIHR Senior Investigator Award. Personal fees from European Respiratory Society, grants from MRC Global Challenge Research fund, other from Nestle Discussion Forum (unpaid), Pfizer antivirals advisory board (unpaid) outside of the submitted work and the role of President of the British Society for Immunology was an unpaid appointment but PJMO's travel and accommodation at some meetings is provided by the Society. MGS reports grants from the National Institute for Health Research (NIHR), Medical Research Council. NIHR Health Protection Research Unit (HPRU) in Emerging and Zoonotic Infections at University of Liverpool in partnership with Public Health England (PHE), in collaboration with Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine and the University of Oxford. All other authors have no interests to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34386785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8343377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-7762(21)00163-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F, Group for the GAC-19 P-ACS Persistent Symptoms in Patients After Acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021 doi: 10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi S, Reddy S, Gholamrezanezhad A. Long-term Pulmonary Consequences of Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19): What We Know and What to Expect. J Thorac Imaging. 2020;35:W87&#x2013;w89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32404798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, Bobkova P, Spiridonova E. Risk factors for long-term consequences of COVID-19 in hospitalised adults in Moscow using the ISARIC Global follow-up protocol: StopCOVID cohort study. medRxiv. 2021 2021.02.17.21251895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burki TK. Post-Ebola syndrome. Lancet Infect Dis. 2016;16:780&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27352759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott JT, Sesay FR, Massaquoi TA, Idriss BR, Sahr F, Semple MG. Post-Ebola Syndrome, Sierra Leone. Emerg Infect Dis. 2016;22:641&#x2013;646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4806950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26983037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung TM, Wills B, Clapham HE, Yacoub S, Turner HC. The Uncertainty Surrounding the Burden of Post-acute Consequences of Dengue Infection. Trends Parasitol. 2019;35:673&#x2013;676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31279656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blettery M, Brunier L, Polomat K. Brief Report: Management of Chronic Post-Chikungunya Rheumatic Disease: The Martinican Experience. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2016;68:2817&#x2013;2824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27273928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawal G, Yadav S, Kumar R. Post-intensive care syndrome: An overview. J Transl Intern Med. 2017;5:90&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5506407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28721340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE  . NICE Guidel. [NG188]; 2020. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19.https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188 accessed March 10, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Yu T, Du R. Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet. 2020;395:1054&#x2013;1062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32171076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verity R, Okell LC, Dorigatti I. Estimates of the severity of coronavirus disease 2019: a model-based analysis. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20:669&#x2013;677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32240634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark A, Jit M, Warren-Gash C. Global, regional, and national estimates of the population at increased risk of severe COVID-19 due to underlying health conditions in 2020: a modelling study. Lancet Glob Heal. 2020;8:E1003&#x2013;E1017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7295519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32553130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Demographic Studies. Demographics of COVID-19 deaths: data and metadata. Covid-19 INED. https://dc-covid.site.ined.fr/en/data/. (accessed March 10, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Health 50/50. COVID-19: data disaggregated by age and sex. https://globalhealth5050.org/covid19/age-and-sex-data/. (accessed March 12, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight SR, Ho A, Pius R. Risk stratification of patients admitted to hospital with covid-19 using the ISARIC WHO Clinical Characterisation Protocol: development and validation of the 4C Mortality Score. BMJ. 2020;370:m3339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7116472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32907855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latronico N, Peli E, Rodella F, Novelli MP, Rasulo FA, Piva S. Three-Month Outcome in Survivors of COVID-19 Associated Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome. Prepr with Lancet. 2021 doi: 10.2139/ssrn.3749226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.3749226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Lancet Facing up to long COVID. Lancet. 2020;396:1861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33308453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ISARIC  . 2020. ISARIC Clinical Characterisation Protocol (CCP): UK version.https://isaric4c.net/protocols/ accessed Feb 1, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ISARIC. WHO  . 2020. ISARIC-4C Global.https://isaric.org/research/covid-19-clinical-research-resources/clinical-characterisation-protocol-ccp/ accessed Feb 1, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M. The Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) Statement: Guidelines for Reporting Observational Studies. J Clin Epidemiol. 2008;61:344&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18313558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall JC, Murthy S, Diaz J. A minimal common outcome measure set for COVID-19 clinical research. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20:e192&#x2013;e197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7292605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32539990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta RK, Harrison EM, Ho A. Development and validation of the ISARIC 4C Deterioration model for adults hospitalised with COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;0 doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30559-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30559-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33444539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washington Group on Disability Statistics. The Washington Group Short Set on Functioning (WG-SS). WG-SS. https://www.washingtongroup-disability.com/question-sets/wg-short-set-on-functioning-wg-ss/(accessed Feb 1, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medical Research Council. 1952 MRC Breathlessness Scale. https://mrc.ukri.org/research/facilities-and-resources-for-researchers/mrc-scales/mrc-dyspnoea-scale-mrc-breathlessness-scale/(accessed Feb 1, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EuroQol Research Foundation  . 2018. EQ-5D-3L User Guide.https://euroqol.org/publications/user-guides accessed Feb 1, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devlin N, Parkin D, Browne J. Using the EQ-5D as a performance measurement tool in the NHS. Health Econ. 2010;19:886&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20623685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkin D, Devlin N, Rice N. Statistical analysis of EQ-5D profiles: does the use of value sets bias inference? Med Decis Making. 2010;30:556&#x2013;565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20228285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Docherty AB, Harrison EM, Green CA. Features of 20&#x2009;133 UK patients in hospital with covid-19 using the ISARIC WHO Clinical Characterisation Protocol: prospective observational cohort study. BMJ. 2020;369:m1985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32444460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abate S, Ahmed AS, Mantfardo B, Basu B. Rate of Intensive Care Unit admission and outcomes among patients with coronavirus: A systematic review and Meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2020;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7351172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32649661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karagiannidis C, Mostert C, Hentschker C. Case characteristics, resource use, and outcomes of 10 021 patients with COVID-19 admitted to 920 German hospitals: an observational study. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8:853&#x2013;862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7386882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32735842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escher M, Hall M, Baillie JK. ISARIC Clinical Data Report 10 February 2021. medRxiv. 2021 2020.07.17.20155218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics  . 2020. Which occupations have the highest potential exposure to the coronavirus (COVID-19)?https://www.ons.gov.uk/employmentandlabourmarket/peopleinwork/employmentandemployeetypes/articles/whichoccupationshavethehighestpotentialexposuretothecoronaviruscovid19/2020-05-11 accessed March 12, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi T, Ellingson MK, Wong P. Sex differences in immune responses that underlie COVID-19 disease outcomes. Nature. 2020;588:315&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7725931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32846427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics  . 2021. COVID-19 Schools Infection Survey Round 2, England: December 2020.https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/covid19schoolsinfectionsurveyround2england/december2020 accessed March 12, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fincham Jack E. Response rates and responsiveness for surveys, standards, and the Journal. Am. J. Pharm. Educ. 2008;72:43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2384218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18483608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barsky A, Peekna H, Borus J. Somatic symptom reporting in women and men. J. Gen. Intern. Med. 2001;16:266&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1495200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11318929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PHOSP Covid . 2020. Long-term follow up of adults hospitalised with COVID-19. Prospectively registered. ISRCTN Regist 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>