<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39389388</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1090-2139</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>123</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Brain, behavior, and immunity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Brain Behav Immun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A review of intravenous immunoglobulin in the treatment of neuroimmune conditions, acute COVID-19 infection, and post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 Syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>725</StartPage><EndPage>738</EndPage><MedlinePgn>725-738</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bbi.2024.10.006</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0889-1591(24)00648-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG) is an immunomodulatory therapy that has been studied in several neuroimmune conditions, such as Guillain-Barr&#xe9; Syndrome, chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy, multifocal motor neuropathy, and multiple sclerosis. It has also been proposed as a potential treatment option for acute COVID-19 infection and post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC). IVIG is thought to function by providing the recipient with a pool of antibodies, which can, in turn, modulate immune responses through multiple mechanisms including neutralization of cytokines and autoantibodies, saturation of neonatal fragment crystallizable receptors, inhibition of complement activation, and regulation of T and B cell mediated inflammation. In acute COVID-19, studies have shown that early administration of IVIG and plasmapheresis in severe cases can reduce the need for mechanical ventilation, shorten ICU and hospital stays, and lower mortality. Similarly, in PASC, while research is still in early stages, IVIG has been shown to alleviate persistent symptoms in small patient cohorts. Furthermore, IVIG has shown benefits in another condition which has symptomatic overlap with PASC, myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS), though studies have yielded mixed results. It is important to note that IVIG can be associated with several potential adverse effects, such as anaphylaxis, headaches, thrombosis, liver enzyme elevations and renal complications. In addition, the high cost of IVIG can be a deterrent for payers and patients. This review provides a comprehensive update on the use of IVIG in multiple neuroimmune conditions, ME/CFS, acute COVID-19, and PASC, as well as covers its history, production, pricing, and mechanisms of action. We also identify key areas of future research, including the need to optimize the use of Ig product dosing, timing, and patient selection across conditions, particularly in the context of COVID-19 and PASC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morse</LastName><ForeName>Brinkley A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Dell Medical School at the University of Texas, Austin, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Motovilov</LastName><ForeName>Katherine</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Dell Medical School at the University of Texas, Austin, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michael Brode</LastName><ForeName>W</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Dell Medical School at the University of Texas, Austin, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michael Tee</LastName><ForeName>Francis</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Dell Medical School at the University of Texas, Austin, USA. Electronic address: fmtee@utexas.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Melamed</LastName><ForeName>Esther</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Dell Medical School at the University of Texas, Austin, USA. Electronic address: emelamed@austin.utexas.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Brain Behav Immun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8800478</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0889-1591</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmune</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intravenous immunoglobulin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroimmune</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: E. Melamed: has received NIH funding for Multiple Sclerosis and COVID-19 research, and honorarium from Multiple Sclerosis Association of America, National Center for Health Research, and has served on advisory boards of Genentech, Horizon, Teva, and Viela Bio. B. Morse, K. Motovilov, F. M. Tee, and W.M. Brode have no competing interests to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39389388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2024.10.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0889-1591(24)00648-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>