<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33796241</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2040-6223</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Therapeutic advances in chronic disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ther Adv Chronic Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The neurological symptoms of COVID-19: a systematic overview of systematic reviews, comparison with other neurological conditions and implications for healthcare services.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2040622320976979</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2040622320976979</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2040622320976979</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/2040622320976979</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">In response to the rapid spread of COVID-19, this paper provides health professionals with better accessibility to available evidence, summarising findings from a systematic overview of systematic reviews of the neurological symptoms seen in patients with COVID-19. Implications of so-called 'Long Covid' on neurological services and primary care and similarities with other neurological disorders are discussed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Firstly, a systematic overview of current reviews of neurological symptoms of COVID-19 was conducted. Secondly, the implications of these findings are discussed in relation to the potential effect on neurological services and the similarities in the experience of patients with COVID-19 and those with other neurological disorders. A total of 45 systematic reviews were identified within seven databases, published between 11 April 2020 and 15 October 2020, following a search in June 2020, updated on 20 October 2020.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The results indicated that COVID-19 exhibits two types of neurological symptoms; life-threatening symptoms such as Guillain-Barre Syndrome (GBS) and encephalitis, and less devastating symptoms such as fatigue and myalgia. Many of these so-called lesser symptoms appear to be emerging as longer-term for some sufferers and have been recently labelled Long Covid. When compared, these less devastating symptoms are very similar to other neurological conditions such as chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS) and functional neurological disorder (FND).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Implications for neurological healthcare services in the United Kingdom (UK) may include longer waiting times and a need for more resources (including more qualified health professionals). There is also a possible change-effect on health professionals' perceptions of other neurological conditions such as CFS and FND. Future research is recommended to explore changes in health professionals' perceptions of neurological symptoms because of COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), 2021.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wildwing</LastName><ForeName>Tamar</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3685-701X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Wellbeing, Canterbury Christ Church University Ringgold Standard Institution, North Holmes Road, Canterbury, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holt</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Wellbeing, Canterbury Christ Church University Ringgold Standard Institution, Canterbury, Kent, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ther Adv Chronic Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101532140</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2040-6223</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long Covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic fatigue syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional neurological disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurological services</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest statement: The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33796241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7970685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2040622320976979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_2040622320976979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>
John Hopkins University &amp; Medicine and Coronavirus Resource Centre. COVID-19 data in motion, https://coronavirus.jhu.edu/ (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Stevens R.
How does coronavirus affect the brain?
https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/conditions-and-diseases/coronavirus/how-does-coronavirus-affect-the-brain (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A&#x2019;Court C, et al.. Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ 2020; 370: m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi N. Long covid: how to define it and how to manage it. BMJ 2020; 370: m3489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32895219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Garner P.
Covid-19 at 14 weeks&#x2014;phantom speed cameras, unknown limits, and harsh penalties, https://blogs.bmj.com/bmj/2020/06/23/paul-garner-covid-19-at-14-weeks-phantom-speed-cameras-unknown-limits-and-harsh-penalties/2020 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahase E. Covid-19: what do we know about &#x201c;long covid&#x201d;? BMJ 2020; 370: m2815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32665317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimmer A. Covid-19: impact of long-term symptoms will be profound, warns BMA. BMJ 2020; 370: m3218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32816748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Guys and St Thomas National Health Service (NHS) Foundation Trust. Neurological services, https://www.guysandstthomas.nhs.uk/our-services/neurology/overview (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al.. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Ann Intern Med 2009; 151: 264&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Critical Appraisal Skills Programme. CASP checklist for systematic reviews, https://casp-uk.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/CASP-Systematic-Review-Checklist_2018.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelaziz O, Waffa Z. Neuropathogenic human coronaviruses: a review. Rev Med Virol 2020; 30: e2118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7404592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32687681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullahi A, Candan S, Abba M, et al.. Neurological and musculoskeletal features of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Neurol 2020; 11: 687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7333777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32676052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Rumeileh S, Abdelhak A, Foschi M, et al.. Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome spectrum associated with COVID-19: an up-to-date systematic review of 73 cases. Neurol. Epub ahead of print 25 August 2020. DOI: 10.1007/s00415-020-10124-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-020-10124-x.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32840686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agyeman AA, Chin KL, Landersdorfer CB, et al.. Smell and taste dysfunction in patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Mayo Clin Proc 2020; 95: 1621&#x2013;1631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7275152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almqvist J, Granberg T, Tzortzakakis A, et al.. Neurological manifestations of coronavirus infections - a systematic review. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. Epub ahead of print 27 August 2020. DOI: 10.1002/acn3.51166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.51166.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA, Simani L. Central nervous system manifestations of COVID-19: a systematic review. J Neurol Sci 2020; 413: 116832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7151535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32299017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatia R, Pedapati R, Komakula S, et al.. Stroke in coronavirus disease 2019: a systematic review. J Stroke 2020; 22: 324&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7568983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33053948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrillo-Larco RM, Altez-Fernandez C, Ravaglia S, et al.. COVID-19 and Guillain-Barre syndrome: a systematic review of case reports. Wellcome Open Res 2020; 5: 107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7509591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32995555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceravolo MG, Arienti C, De Sire A, et al..; International Multi-professional Steering Committee of Cochrane Rehabilitation REH-COVER action. Rehabilitation and Covid-19: the cochrane rehabilitation 2020 rapid living systematic review. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. Epub ahead of print 24 July 2020. DOI: 10.23736/S1973-9087.20.06501-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.20.06501-6.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collantes MEV, Espiritu AI, Sy MCC, et al. Neurological manifestations in COVID-19 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Can J Neurol Sci. Epub ahead of print 15 July 2020. DOI: 10.1017/cjn.2020.146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/cjn.2020.146.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7492583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32665054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correia A, Feitosa P, de Sousa Moreira J, et al.. Neurological manifestations of COVID-19 and other coronaviruses: a systematic review. Neurol Psychiat Br 2020; 37: 27&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7261450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32834527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Carlo DT, Montemurro N, Petrella G, et al.. Exploring the clinical association between neurological symptoms and COVID-19 pandemic outbreak: a systematic review of current literature. J Neurol. Epub ahead of print 1 August 2020. DOI: 10.1007/s00415-020-09978-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-020-09978-y.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7395578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32740766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinakaran D, Manjunatha N, Naveen Kumar C, et al.. Neuropsychiatric aspects of COVID-19 pandemic: a selective review. Asian J Psychiatr 2020; 53: 102188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7261092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32512530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatima N, Saqqur M, Qamar F, et al.. Impact of COVID-19 on neurological manifestations: an overview of stroke presentation in pandemic. Neurol Sci 2020; 41: 2675&#x2013;2679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7406873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32761396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghannam M, Alshaer Q, Al-Chalabi M, et al.. Neurological involvement of coronavirus disease 2019: a systematic review. J Neurol. Epub ahead of print 19 June 2020. DOI: 10.1007/s00415-020-09990-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-020-09990-2.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7304377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32561990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trujillo Gittermann LM, Valenzuela Feris SN, von Oetinger Giacomanc A. Relation between COVID-19 and Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome in adults: a systematic review. Neurolgia. Epub ahead of print 24 July 2020. DOI: 10.1016/j.nrl.2020.07.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nrl.2020.07.004.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32896460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katal S, Balakrishnan S, Gholamrezanezhad A. Neuroimaging and neurologic findings in COVID-19 and other coronavirus infections: a systematic review in 116 patients. Neuroradiol. Epub ahead of print 27 June 2020. DOI: 10.1016/j.neurad.2020.06.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurad.2020.06.007.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7320684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32603770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katyal N, Narula N, Acharya S, et al.. Neuromuscular complications with SARS-COV-2 infection: a review. Front Neurol 2020; 11: 1052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7527465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33041989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonardi M, Padovani A, McArthur JC. Neurological manifestations associated with COVID-19: a review and a call for action. J Neurol 2020; 267: 1573&#x2013;1576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7238392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32436101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liguoro I, Pilotto C, Bonanni M, et al.. SARS-COV-2 infection in children and newborns: a systematic review. Eur J Pediatr 2020; 79: 1029&#x2013;1046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7234446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32424745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montalvan V, Lee J, Bueso T, et al.. Neurological manifestations of COVID-19 and other coronavirus infections: a systematic review. Clin Neurol Neurosurg 2020; 194: 105921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7227498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narula N, Joseph R, Katyal N, et al.. Seizure and COVID-19: association and review of potential mechanism. Neurol Psychiatry Brain Res 2020; 38: 49&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7553058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33071468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nepal G, Rehrig JH, Shrestha GS, et al.. Neurological manifestations of COVID-19: a systematic review. Crit Care 2020; 24: 421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7356133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32660520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr&#xf9; G, Conversano C, Malloggi E, et al.. Neurological complications of COVID-19 and possible neuroinvasion pathways: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2020; 17: 6688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7558767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32937949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paliwali V, Garg R, Gupta A, et al.. Neuromuscular presentations in patients with COVID-19. Neurol Sci 2020; 41: 3039&#x2013;3056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32935156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda PK, Sharawat IK, Panda P, et al.. Neurological complications of SARS-CoV-2 infection in children: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Trop Pediatr. Epub ahead of print 10 September 2020. DOI: 10.1093/tropej/fmaa070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tropej/fmaa070.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7499728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32910826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinzon R, Wijaya V, Buana R. Neurologic characteristics in coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Neurol 2020; 11: 565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7273516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32574250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pousa P, Mendon&#xe7;a T, Oliveira E, et al.. Extrapulmonary manifestations of COVID-19 in children: a comprehensive review and pathophysiological considerations. J Pediatr (Rio J). Epub ahead of print 22 September 2020. DOI: 10.1016/j.jped.2020.08.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jped.2020.08.007.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32980319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raschetti R, Vivanti A, Vauloup-Fellous C, et al.. Synthesis and systematic review of reported neonatal SARS-CoV-2 infections. Nat Commun 2020; 11: 5164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7566441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33060565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers JP, Chesney E, Oliver D, et al.. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: a systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet Psychiatry 2020; 7: 611&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7234781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scoppettuolo P, Borrelli S, Naeije G. Neurological involvement in SARS-CoV-2 infection: a clinical systematic review. Brain Behav Immun Health 2020; 6: 100094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33521692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifian-Dorchea M, Huota P, Osherova M, et al.. Neurological complications of coronavirus infection; a comparative review and lessons learned during the COVID-19 pandemic. J Neurol Sci 2020; 417: 117085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7413162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32871412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taherifard E, Taherifard E. Neurological complications of COVID-19: a systematic review. Neurol Res. Epub ahead of print 23 July 2020. DOI: 10.1080/01616412.2020.1796405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01616412.2020.1796405.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32698732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Y-K, Goh C, Leow AST, et al. COVID-19 and ischemic stroke: a systematic review and meta-summary of the literature. J Thromb Thrombolysis 2020; 50: 587&#x2013;595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7358286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevisanuto D, Cavallin F, Cavicchiolo ME, et al.. Coronavirus infection in neonates: a systematic review. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. Epub ahead of print 17 September 2020. DOI: 10.1136/archdischild-2020-319837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/archdischild-2020-319837.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32943533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai S, Lu M, San S, et al.. The neurologic manifestations of coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic: a systemic review. Front Neurol 2020; 19: 498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7248254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32574246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsivgoulis G, Palaiodimou L, Katsanos A, et al.. Neurological manifestations and implications of COVID-1 9 pandemic. Ther Adv Neurol Diso 2020; 13: 1756286420932036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7284455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32565914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uncini A, Vallat J, Jacobs B. Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome in SARS-CoV-2 infection: an instant systematic review of the first six months of pandemic. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. Epub ahead of print 27 August 2020. DOI: 10.1136/jnnp-2020-324491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2020-324491.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32855289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valiuddun H, Kalajdzic A, Rosati J, et al.. Update on neurological manifestations of SARS-CoV-2. West J Emerg Med. Epub ahead of print 6 October 2020. DOI: 10.5811/westjem.2020.8.48839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5811/westjem.2020.8.48839.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7673884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33052822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vonck K, Garrez I, De Herdt V, et al.. Neurological manifestations and neuro-invasive mechanisms of the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus type 2. Eur J Neurol 2020; 27: 1578&#x2013;1587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7276727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32416028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Shen Y, Li M, et al.. Clinical manifestations and evidence of neurological involvement in 2019 novel coronavirus SARS-CoV-2: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol. Epub ahead of print 11 June 2020. DOI: 10.1007/s00415-020-09974-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-020-09974-2.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7288253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32529575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werner C, Scullen T, Mathkour M, et al.. Neurological impact of coronavirus disease (COVID-19): practical considerations for the neuroscience community. World Neurosurg 2020; 139: 344&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7202815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittaker A, Anson M, Harky A. Neurological manifestations of COVID-19: a systematic review and current update. Acta Neurol Scand 2020; 142: 14&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7273036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32412088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson MP, Jack AS. Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) in neurology and neurosurgery: a scoping review of the early literature. Clin Neurol Neurosurg 2020; 193: 105866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7179494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32389893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahra SA, Iddawela S, Pillai K, et al.. Can symptoms of anosmia and dysgeusia be diagnostic for COVID-19? Brain Behav. Epub ahead of print 16 September 2020. DOI: 10.1002/brb3.1839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/brb3.1839.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7667367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32935915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M, et al.. Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol 2020; 77: 683&#x2013;690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7149362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Patient Info. Functional Neurological Disorder (FND), https://patient.info/brain-nerves/functional-neurological-disorder (acessed 13 September 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
National Health Service (NHS). Medically unexplained symptoms, https://www.nhs.uk/conditions/medically-unexplained-symptoms/ (accessed 13 September 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Neurosymptoms.org. Functional Neurological Disorder (FND): a patient&#x2019;s guide, https://www.neurosymptoms.org/ (accessed 13 September 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black D, Grant J. DSM-5&#xae; guidebook: the essential companion to the diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders. 5th ed. Arlington, VA: American Psychiatric Association Publishing, 2014, pp.201&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton J. Covid-19: the challenge of patient rehabilitation after intensive care. BMJ 2020; 369: m1787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32376670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
National Health Service (NHS) England. Transforming elective care services neurology: learning from the elective care development collaborative, https://www.england.nhs.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/neurology-elective-care-handbook.pdf (accessed 1 June 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
The Kings Fund. Restarting health and care services will take months, www.kingsfund.org.uk/press/press-releases/restarting-health-and-care-services-will-take-many-months (accessed 1 June 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Vaughan L. Where are the patients? The factors affecting the use of emergency care during COVID-19; Nuffield Trust. www.nuffieldtrust.org.uk/news-item/where-are-the-patients-the-factors-affecting-the-use-of-emergency-care-during-covid-19 (accessed 5 July 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canna M, Seligman R. Dealing with the unknown. Functional neurological disorder (FND) and the conversion of cultural meaning. Soc Sci Med 2020; 246: 112725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31911360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robson CM, Lian OS. &#x201c;Are you saying she&#x2019;s mentally ill then?&#x201d; Explaining medically unexplained seizures in clinical encounters. In: Forum Qualitative Sozial for schung/Forum: Qualitative Social Research 2015; 17: 1. (accessed 1 September 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall M. Redefining quality: valuing the role of the GP in managing uncertainty. Br J Gen Pract 2016; 66: e146&#x2013;e148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4723214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26823265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Album D, Westin S. Do diseases have a prestige hierarchy? A survey among physicians and medical students. Soc Sci Med 2008; 66: 182&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17850944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
National Institute of Health Research (NIHR). Major study into long term health effects of Covid-19 launch in the UK, https://www.nihr.ac.uk/news/major-study-into-long-term-health-effects-of-covid-19-launched-in-the-uk/25200 (accessed 1 September 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Alwen NA.
What exactly is mild covid-19? BMJ opinion, https://blogs.bmj.com/bmj/2020/07/28/nisreen-a-alwan-what-exactly-is-mild-covid-19/ (2020) (accessed 1 September 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Nitkunan A, Lawrence J, Reilly MM.
Neurology workforce survey conducted by the association of British neurologists. 2020; pp. 1&#x2013;19. https://cdn.ymaws.com/www.theabn.org/resource/collection/219B4A48-4D25-4726-97AA-0EB6090769BE/2020_ABN_Neurology_Workforce_Survey_2018-19_28_Jan_2020.pdf (accessed 1 September 2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>