<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37974389</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1748-0361</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of rural health : official journal of the American Rural Health Association and the National Rural Health Care Association</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Rural Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cross-sectional population-based estimates of a rural-urban disparity in prevalence of long COVID among Michigan adults with polymerase chain reaction-confirmed COVID-19, 2020-2022.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>303</StartPage><EndPage>313</EndPage><MedlinePgn>303-313</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jrh.12807</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">To (1) assess whether residential rurality/urbanicity was associated with the prevalence of 30- or 90-day long COVID, and (2) evaluate whether differences in long COVID risk factors might explain this potential disparity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We used data from the Michigan COVID-19 Recovery Surveillance Study, a population-based probability sample of adults with COVID-19 (n = 4,937). We measured residential rurality/urbanicity using dichotomized Rural-Urban Commuting Area codes (metropolitan, nonmetropolitan). We considered outcomes of 30-day long COVID (illness duration &#x2265;30 days) and 90-day long COVID (illness duration &#x2265;90 days). Using Poisson regression, we estimated unadjusted prevalence ratios (PRs) to compare 30- and 90-day long COVID between metropolitan and nonmetropolitan respondents. Then, we adjusted our model to account for differences between groups in long COVID risk factors (age, sex, acute COVID-19 severity, vaccination status, race and ethnicity, socioeconomic status, health care access, SARS-CoV-2 variant, and pre-existing conditions). We estimated associations for the full study period (Jan 1, 2020-May 31, 2022), the pre-vaccine era (before April 5, 2021), and the vaccine era (after April 5, 2021).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS">Compared to metropolitan adults, the prevalence of 30-day long COVID was 15% higher (PR = 1.15 [95% CI: 1.03, 1.29]), and the prevalence of 90-day long COVID was 27% higher (PR = 1.27 [95% CI: 1.09, 1.49]) among nonmetropolitan adults. Adjusting for long COVID risk factors did not reduce disparity estimates in the pre-vaccine era but halved estimates in the vaccine era.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings provide evidence of a rural-urban disparity in long COVID and suggest that the factors contributing to this disparity changed over time as the sociopolitical context of the pandemic evolved and COVID-19 vaccines were introduced.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. The Journal of Rural Health published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of National Rural Health Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>MacCallum-Bridges</LastName><ForeName>Colleen L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8642-1858</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hirschtick</LastName><ForeName>Jana L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allgood</LastName><ForeName>Kristi L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Texas A&amp;M University, College Station, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ryu</LastName><ForeName>Soomin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orellana</LastName><ForeName>Robert C</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CDC Foundation, Atlanta, Georgia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Michigan Department of Health and Human Services, Lansing, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fleischer</LastName><ForeName>Nancy L</ForeName><Initials>NL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>6 NU50CK000510-02-04</GrantID><Acronym>CC</Acronym><Agency>CDC HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>1 NH75OT000078-01-00</GrantID><Acronym>CC</Acronym><Agency>CDC HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>6 NU50CK000510-02-04</GrantID><Acronym>CC</Acronym><Agency>CDC HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>1 NH75OT000078-01-00</GrantID><Acronym>CC</Acronym><Agency>CDC HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013487">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Rural Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8508122</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0890-765X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000086663">COVID-19 Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000711908">SARS-CoV-2 variants</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008824" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Michigan</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086663" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014505" MajorTopicYN="N">Urban Population</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016133" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086742" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Testing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health disparities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID-19 condition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rural health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urban health</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37974389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jrh.12807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Long COVID: Household Pulse Survey. Published 2023. Accessed May 2, 2023. https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/covid19/pulse/long-covid.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Long COVID or Post COVID Conditions. Published 2022. Accessed February 7, 2023. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(April):e102-e107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik P, Patel K, Pinto C, et&#xa0;al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PCS) and health-related quality of life (HRQoL)-a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2022;94(1):253-262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano MR, Rossi MF, Borrelli I, et&#xa0;al. Returning to work and the impact of post COVID-19 condition: a systematic review. Work. 2022;73:1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spence NJ, Russell D, Bouldin ED, Tumminello CM, Schwartz T. Getting back to normal? Identity and role disruptions among adults with long COVID. Sociol Health Illness. 2023;45(4):914-934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ireson J, Taylor A, Richardson E, Greenfield B, Jones G. Exploring invisibility and epistemic injustice in long covid-a citizen science qualitative analysis of patient stories from an online covid community. Health Expect. 2022;25(4):1753-1765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, et&#xa0;al. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J Roy Soc Med. 2021;114(9):428-442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastie CE, Lowe DJ, McAuley A, et&#xa0;al. Outcomes among confirmed cases and a matched comparison group in the long-COVID in Scotland study. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):5663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschtick JL, Titus AR, Slocum E, et&#xa0;al. Population-based estimates of post-acute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection (PASC) prevalence and characteristics. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73(11):2055-2064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarte KI, de Oliveira MHS, Peligro PJ, et&#xa0;al. Age, sex and previous comorbidities as risk factors not associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection for long COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Med. 2022;11(24):7314-7337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlis RH, Santillana M, Ognyanova K, et&#xa0;al. Prevalence and correlates of long COVID symptoms among US adults. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(10):e2238804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson EJ, Williams DM, Walker AJ, et&#xa0;al. Long COVID burden and risk factors in 10 UK longitudinal studies and electronic health records. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Bowe B, Xie Y. Long COVID after breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med. 2022;28(July):1461-1467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Penfold RS, Merino J, et&#xa0;al. Risk factors and disease profile of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection in UK users of the COVID Symptom Study app: a prospective, community-based, nested, case-control study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(1):43-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Bosworth ML, King S, et&#xa0;al. Risk of long COVID in people infected with SARS-CoV-2 after two doses of a COVID-19 vaccine: a community-based, matched cohort study. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2022;9(9):1-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azzolini E, Levi R, Sarti R, et&#xa0;al. Association between BNT162b2 vaccination and long COVID after infections not requiring hospitalization in health care workers. JAMA. 2022;328(7):676-678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell J, et&#xa0;al. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network - United States, March-June 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69(30):993-998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zisis SN, Durieux JC, Mouchati C, Perez JA, McComsey GA. The protective effect of covid-19 vaccination on post-acute sequelae of covid-19 (PASC): a multicenter study from a large national health research network. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2022;2019:1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khullar D, Zhang Y, Zang C, et&#xa0;al. Racial/ethnic disparities in post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection in New York: an EHR-based cohort study from the RECOVER Program. J Gen Intern Med. 2023;38(5):1127-1136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs MM, Evans E, Ellis C. Racial, ethnic, and sex disparities in the incidence and cognitive symptomology of long COVID-19. J Natl Med Assoc. 2023;115(2):233-243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabnam S, Razieh C, Dambha-Miller H, et&#xa0;al. Socioeconomic inequalities of long COVID: findings from a population-based survey in the United Kingdom. J Roy Soc Med. 2023;116(8):263-273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet. 2022;399(10343):2263-2264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Citizens Research Council of Michigan. Exploring Michigan's Urban/Rural Divide. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Census Bureau. New Census Data Show Differences Between Urban and Rural Populations. 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobis EA, Krumel TP Jr, Cromartie J, Conley KL, Sanders A, Ortiz R. Rural America at a Glance. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saelee R, Zell E, Patel Murthy B, et&#xa0;al. Disparities in COVID-19 Vaccination Coverage Between Urban and Rural Counties-United States, December 14, 2020-January 31, 2022. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullrich F, Mueller K. COVID-19 Cases and Deaths, Metropolitan and Non-Metropolitan Counties over Time (Updated). 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hale N, Ms AW, Ma MM, Loos M, Drph SP. The implications of long COVID for rural communities. J Rural Health. 2022;38(4):17-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. About Rural Health. Published 2017. Accessed April 10, 2023. https://www.cdc.gov/ruralhealth/about.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The American Association for Public Opinion Research. Standard Definitions: Final Dispositions of Case Codes and Outcome Rates for Surveys. 9th Edition. 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Agriculture. Rural Urban Commuting Area Codes. Published 2020. Accessed November 14, 2022. https://www.ers.usda.gov/data-products/rural-urban-commuting-area-codes/documentation/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washington State Department of Health. Guidelines for Using Rural-Urban Classification Systems for Community Health Assessment. 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence, Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network, Royal College of General Practitioners. COVID-19 Rapid Guideline: Managing the Long-Term Effects of COVID-19. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corum J, Zimmer C. Tracking Omicron and Other Coronavirus Variants. New York Times. Published 2022. Accessed February 7, 2023. https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/health/coronavirus-variant-tracker.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michigan Department of Health and Human Services. Rescission of Emergency Orders. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Census Bureau GPB. Census Tracts. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phelan JC, Link BG. Is racism a fundamental cause of inequalities in health? Annu Rev Sociol. 2015;41:311-330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Link BG, Phelan J. Social conditions as fundamental causes of disease. J Health Soc Behav. 1995;35:80-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger N, Chen JT, Waterman PD, et&#xa0;al. The inverse hazard law: blood pressure, sexual harassment, racial discrimination, workplace abuse and occupational exposures in US low-income black, white and Latino workers. Soc Sci Med. 2008;67(12):1970-1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClure ES, Vasudevan P, Bailey Z, Patel S, Robinson WR. Racial capitalism within public health-how occupational settings drive covid-19 disparities. Am J Epidemiol. 2020;189(11):1244-1253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michigan Department of Health and Human Services. Executive Order No. 2020-110. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michigan Department of Health and Human Services. Feb. 1: Gathering Guidelines. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pro G, Hubach R, Wheeler D, et&#xa0;al. Differences in US COVID-19 case rates and case fatality rates across the urban-rural continuum. Rural Remote Health. 2020;20(3):6074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan MN, Haider N, Stigler FL, et&#xa0;al. The global case-fatality rate of COVID-19 has been declining since May 2020. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2021;104(6):2176-2184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman N. People with &#x201c;Medium COVID&#x201d; are Caught in a Gray Area of Recovery with Little Support. Shots: Health News from NPR. March 17, 2022. https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2022/03/17/1083040162/long-covid-symptoms</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>