<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37274795</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2219-2840</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>19</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of gastroenterology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Gastrointestinal manifestations of long-term effects after COVID-19 infection in patients with dialysis or kidney transplantation: An observational cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3013</StartPage><EndPage>3026</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3013-3026</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3748/wjg.v29.i19.3013</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Prolonged symptoms after corona virus disease 2019 (Long-COVID) in dialysis-dependent patients and kidney transplant (KT) recipients are important as a possible risk factor for organ dysfunctions, especially gastrointestinal (GI) problems, during immunosuppressive therapy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To identify the characteristics of GI manifestations of Long-COVID in patients with dialysis-dependent or KT status.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This observational, prospective study included patients with COVID-19 infection, confirmed by reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction, with the onset of symptoms between 1 January 2022 and 31 July 2022 which was explored at 3 mo after the onset, either through the out-patient follow-up or by telephone interviews.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The 645 eligible participants consisted of 588 cases with hemodialysis (HD), 38 patients with peritoneal dialysis (PD), and 19 KT recipients who were hospitalized with COVID-19 infection during the observation. Of these, 577 (89.5%) cases agreed to the interviews, while 64 (10.9%) patients with HD and 4 (10.5%) cases of PD were excluded. The mean age was 52 &#xb1; 11 years with 52% women. The median dialysis duration was 7 &#xb1; 3 and 5 &#xb1; 1 years for HD and PD groups, respectively, and the median time post-transplantation was 6 &#xb1; 2 years. Long-COVID was identified in 293/524 (56%) and 21/34 (62%) in HD and PD, respectively, and 7/19 (37%) KT recipients. Fatigue was the most prevalent (96%) of the non-GI tract symptoms, whereas anorexia (90.9%), loss of taste (64.4%), and abdominal pain (62.5%) were the first three common GI manifestations of Long-COVID. Notably, there were 6 cases of mesenteric panniculitis from 19 patients with GI symptoms in the KT group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Different from patients with non-chronic kidney disease, there was a high prevalence of GI manifestations of Long-COVID in dialysis-dependent patients and KT recipients. An appropriate long-term follow-up in these vulnerable populations after COVID-19 infection is possibly necessary.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2023. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chancharoenthana</LastName><ForeName>Wiwat</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Tropical Medicine, Faculty of Tropical Medicine, Mahidol University, Bangkok 10400, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamolratanakul</LastName><ForeName>Supitcha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Tropical Medicine, Faculty of Tropical Medicine, Mahidol University, Bangkok 10400, Thailand. supitcha.kam@mahidol.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leelahavanichkul</LastName><ForeName>Asada</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Medicine, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok 10330, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ariyanon</LastName><ForeName>Wassawon</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiometabolic Centre, Department of Medicine, Bangkok Nursing Hospital, Bangkok 10500, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chinpraditsuk</LastName><ForeName>Sutatip</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dialysis Center, Hospital for Tropical Diseases, Faculty of Tropical Medicine, Mahidol University, Bangkok 10400, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saelim</LastName><ForeName>Rattanaporn</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dialysis Center, Hospital for Tropical Diseases, Faculty of Tropical Medicine, Mahidol University, Bangkok 10400, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vadcharavivad</LastName><ForeName>Somratai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy Practice, Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok 10330, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phumratanaprapin</LastName><ForeName>Weerapong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Tropical Medicine, Faculty of Tropical Medicine, Mahidol University, Bangkok 10400, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilairatana</LastName><ForeName>Polrat</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Tropical Medicine, Faculty of Tropical Medicine, Mahidol University, Bangkok 10400, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Gastroenterol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1007-9327</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006435" MajorTopicYN="N">Renal Dialysis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016030" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Transplantation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007676" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Failure, Chronic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005767" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrointestinal Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney transplant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: There are no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37274795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10237091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v29.i19.3013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Marshall M. The lasting misery of coronavirus long-haulers. Nature. 2020;585:339&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32929257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, Cook JR, Nordvig AS, Shalev D, Sehrawat TS, Ahluwalia N, Bikdeli B, Dietz D, Der-Nigoghossian C, Liyanage-Don N, Rosner GF, Bernstein EJ, Mohan S, Beckley AA, Seres DS, Choueiri TK, Uriel N, Ausiello JC, Accili D, Freedberg DE, Baldwin M, Schwartz A, Brodie D, Garcia CK, Elkind MSV, Connors JM, Bilezikian JP, Landry DW, Wan EY. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV, Jayadevan R, Sashidharan S. Long COVID: An overview. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15:869&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltezou HC, Pavli A, Tsakris A. Post-COVID Syndrome: An Insight on Its Pathogenesis. Vaccines (Basel) 2021;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8151752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34066007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visco V, Vitale C, Rispoli A, Izzo C, Virtuoso N, Ferruzzi GJ, Santopietro M, Melfi A, Rusciano MR, Maglio A, Di Pietro P, Carrizzo A, Galasso G, Vatrella A, Vecchione C, Ciccarelli M. Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: Involvement and Interactions between Respiratory, Cardiovascular and Nervous Systems. J Clin Med. 2022;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8836767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35159974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence: Clinical Guidelines. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE), 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modelli de Andrade LG, de Sandes-Freitas TV, Requi&#xe3;o-Moura LR, Viana LA, Cristelli MP, Garcia VD, Alc&#xe2;ntara ALC, Esmeraldo RM, Abbud Filho M, Pacheco-Silva A, de Lima Carneiro ECR, Manfro RC, Costa KMAH, Sim&#xe3;o DR, de Sousa MV, Santana VBBM, Noronha IL, Rom&#xe3;o EA, Zanocco JA, Arimatea GGQ, De Boni Monteiro de Carvalho D, Tedesco-Silva H, Medina-Pestana J COVID-19-KT Brazil. Development and validation of a simple web-based tool for early prediction of COVID-19-associated death in kidney transplant recipients. Am J Transplant. 2022;22:610&#x2013;625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8441938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34416075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basic-Jukic N, Juric I, Furic-Cunko V, Katalinic L, Radic J, Bosnjak Z, Jelakovic B, Kastelan Z. Follow-up of renal transplant recipients after acute COVID-19-A prospective cohort single-center study. Immun Inflamm Dis. 2021;9:1563&#x2013;1572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8426882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34414665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malinowska A, Muchlado M, &#x15a;lizie&#x144; Z, Biedunkiewicz B, Heleniak Z, D&#x119;bska-&#x15a;lizie&#x144; A, Tylicki L. Post-COVID-19 Sydrome and Decrease in Health-Related Quality of Life in Kidney Transplant Recipients after SARS-COV-2 Infection-A Cohort Longitudinal Study from the North of Poland. J Clin Med. 2021;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8584685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34768725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chauhan S, Meshram HS, Kute V, Patel H, Desai S, Dave R. Long-term follow-up of SARS-CoV-2 recovered renal transplant recipients: A single-center experience from India. Transpl Infect Dis. 2021;23:e13735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8646905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34547156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amorim CEN, Gomes VLT, Cristelli MP, Viana LA, de Luca Correa H, Lima GBB, de Sousa Silva FS, de Castro Lima GS, Rosa TDS, Nakamura MR, Quintino PM, Tedesco-Silva H, Medina-Pestana J. High Prevalence of Long-COVID Among Kidney Transplant Recipients: A Longitudinal Cohort Study. Transplantation. 2022;106:2408&#x2013;2415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9696768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36228200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Och A, Tylicki P, Polewska K, Puchalska-Regli&#x144;ska E, Parczewska A, Szabat K, Biedunkiewicz B, D&#x119;bska-&#x15a;lizie&#x144; A, Tylicki L. Persistent Post-COVID-19 Syndrome in Hemodialyzed Patients-A Longitudinal Cohort Study from the North of Poland. J Clin Med. 2021;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8509624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34640471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demiray A, Kanbay A, Kanbay M. Long-term effect of COVID-19 infection on hemodialysis patients: Should we follow hemodialysis patients more closely? Clin Kidney J. 2022;15:369&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8689791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35198153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo T, Liu Q, Zhang F, Lui GC, Tso EY, Yeoh YK, Chen Z, Boon SS, Chan FK, Chan PK, Ng SC. Depicting SARS-CoV-2 faecal viral activity in association with gut microbiota composition in patients with COVID-19. Gut. 2021;70:276&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32690600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saithong S, Worasilchai N, Saisorn W, Udompornpitak K, Bhunyakarnjanarat T, Chindamporn A, Tovichayathamrong P, Torvorapanit P, Chiewchengchol D, Chancharoenthana W, Leelahavanichkul A. Neutrophil Extracellular Traps in Severe SARS-CoV-2 Infection: A Possible Impact of LPS and (1&#x2192;3)-&#x3b2;-D-glucan in Blood from Gut Translocation. Cells. 2022;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8997739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35406667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M, Kleine-Weber H, Schroeder S, Kr&#xfc;ger N, Herrler T, Erichsen S, Schiergens TS, Herrler G, Wu NH, Nitsche A, M&#xfc;ller MA, Drosten C, P&#xf6;hlmann S. SARS-CoV-2 Cell Entry Depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and Is Blocked by a Clinically Proven Protease Inhibitor. Cell. 2020;181:271&#x2013;280.e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Docherty AB, Harrison EM, Green CA, Hardwick HE, Pius R, Norman L, Holden KA, Read JM, Dondelinger F, Carson G, Merson L, Lee J, Plotkin D, Sigfrid L, Halpin S, Jackson C, Gamble C, Horby PW, Nguyen-Van-Tam JS, Ho A, Russell CD, Dunning J, Openshaw PJ, Baillie JK, Semple MG ISARIC4C investigators. Features of 20 133 UK patients in hospital with covid-19 using the ISARIC WHO Clinical Characterisation Protocol: prospective observational cohort study. BMJ. 2020;369:m1985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32444460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Zang C, Xu Z, Zhang Y, Xu J, Bian J, Morozyuk D, Khullar D, Nordvig AS, Schenck EJ, Shenkman EA, Rothman RL, Block JP, Lyman K, Weiner MG, Carton TW, Wang F, Kaushal R. Data-driven identification of post-acute SARS-CoV-2 infection subphenotypes. Nat Med. 2023;29:226&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9873564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36456834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meringer H, Mehandru S. Gastrointestinal post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;19:345&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8981882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35383321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594:259&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke MJ, Del Rio C. Long COVID has exposed medicine's blind-spot. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21:1062&#x2013;1064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8213360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34153235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Requi&#xe3;o-Moura LR, Sandes-Freitas TV, Viana LA, Cristelli MP, Andrade LGM, Garcia VD, Oliveira CMC, Esmeraldo RM, Abbud Filho M, Pacheco-Silva A, Sousa KC, Vicari AR, Costa KMAH, Sim&#xe3;o DR, Sousa MV, Campos JB, Almeida RAMB, Deboni LM, Neto MM, Zanocco JA, Tedesco-Silva H, Medina-Pestana J COVID-19-KT Brazil. High mortality among kidney transplant recipients diagnosed with coronavirus disease 2019: Results from the Brazilian multicenter cohort study. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0254822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8318290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34320005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina-Pestana J, Cristelli MP, Foresto RD, Tedesco-Silva H, Requi&#xe3;o-Moura LR. The Higher COVID-19 Fatality Rate Among Kidney Transplant Recipients Calls for Further Action. Transplantation. 2022;106:908&#x2013;910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9038247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35250005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin-Chowdhury Z, Ladhani SN. Causation or confounding: why controls are critical for characterizing long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27:1129&#x2013;1130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34140704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Duarte &#xc1;, Rivera-Izquierdo M, Guerrero-Fern&#xe1;ndez de Alba I, P&#xe9;rez-Contreras M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Mart&#xed;nez NF, Ruiz-Montero R, Serrano-Ortiz &#xc1;, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Serna RO, Salcedo-Leal I, Jim&#xe9;nez-Mej&#xed;as E, C&#xe1;rdenas-Cruz A. Sequelae, persistent symptomatology and outcomes after COVID-19 hospitalization: the ANCOHVID multicentre 6-month follow-up study. BMC Med. 2021;19:129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8134820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Alberts J, Oben J, Cuthbertson DJ, Wootton D, Crooks M, Gabbay M, Brady M, Hishmeh L, Attree E, Heightman M, Banerjee R, Banerjee A COVERSCAN study investigators. Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e048391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackett JW, Wainberg M, Elkind MSV, Freedberg DE. Potential Long Coronavirus Disease 2019 Gastrointestinal Symptoms 6 Months After Coronavirus Infection Are Associated With Mental Health Symptoms. Gastroenterology. 2022;162:648&#x2013;650.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8556689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34728186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Persistent Symptoms in Patients After Acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez O, Merino E, Leon-Ramirez JM, Andres M, Ramos JM, Arenas-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Asensio S, Sanchez R, Ruiz-Torregrosa P, Galan I, Scholz A, Amo A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-delaAleja P, Boix V, Gil J COVID19-ALC research group. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: A Mediterranean cohort study. J Infect. 2021;82:378&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7802523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Schneider C, Laurent E, Lemaignen A, Beaufils E, Bourbao-Tournois C, Laribi S, Flament T, Ferreira-Maldent N, Bruy&#xe8;re F, Stefic K, Gaudy-Graffin C, Grammatico-Guillon L, Bernard L. Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:258&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caso JR, MacDowell KS, Soto M, Ruiz-Guerrero F, Carrasco-D&#xed;az &#xc1;, Leza JC, Carrasco JL, D&#xed;az-Mars&#xe1; M. Dysfunction of Inflammatory Pathways and Their Relationship With Psychological Factors in Adult Female Patients With Eating Disorders. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:846172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9062031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35517819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chancharoenthana W, Udompronpitak K, Manochantr Y, Kantagowit P, Kaewkanha P, Issara-Amphorn J, Leelahavanichkul A. Repurposing of High-Dose Erythropoietin as a Potential Drug Attenuates Sepsis in Preconditioning Renal Injury. Cells. 2021;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8617638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34831360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meijers RW, Litjens NH, de Wit EA, Langerak AW, Baan CC, Betjes MG. Uremia-associated immunological aging is stably imprinted in the T-cell system and not reversed by kidney transplantation. Transpl Int. 2014;27:1272&#x2013;1284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25082296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betjes MG. Immune cell dysfunction and inflammation in end-stage renal disease. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2013;9:255&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23507826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, Pujol JC, Klaser K, Antonelli M, Canas LS, Molteni E, Modat M, Jorge Cardoso M, May A, Ganesh S, Davies R, Nguyen LH, Drew DA, Astley CM, Joshi AD, Merino J, Tsereteli N, Fall T, Gomez MF, Duncan EL, Menni C, Williams FMK, Franks PW, Chan AT, Wolf J, Ourselin S, Spector T, Steves CJ. Author Correction: Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27:1116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vibholm LK, Nielsen SSF, Pahus MH, Frattari GS, Olesen R, Andersen R, Monrad I, Andersen AHF, Thomsen MM, Konrad CV, Andersen SD, H&#xf8;jen JF, Gunst JD, &#xd8;stergaard L, S&#xf8;gaard OS, Schleimann MH, Tolstrup M. SARS-CoV-2 persistence is associated with antigen-specific CD8 T-cell responses. EBioMedicine. 2021;64:103230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7847186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33530000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang EY, Mao T, Klein J, Dai Y, Huck JD, Liu F, Zheng NS, Zhou T, Israelow B, Wong P, Lucas C, Silva J, Oh JE, Song E, Perotti ES, Fischer S, Campbell M, Fournier JB, Wyllie AL, Vogels CBF, Ott IM, Kalinich CC, Petrone ME, Watkins AE Yale IMPACT Team, Cruz CD, Farhadian SF, Schulz WL, Grubaugh ND, Ko AI, Iwasaki A, Ring AM. Diverse Functional Autoantibodies in Patients with COVID-19. medRxiv. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34010947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas RM, Jobin C. Microbiota in pancreatic health and disease: the next frontier in microbiome research. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;17:53&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31811279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astin R, Banerjee A, Baker MR, Dani M, Ford E, Hull JH, Lim PB, McNarry M, Morten K, O'Sullivan O, Pretorius E, Raman B, Soteropoulos DS, Taquet M, Hall CN. Long COVID: mechanisms, risk factors and recovery. Exp Physiol. 2023;108:12&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10103775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36412084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enaud R, Prevel R, Ciarlo E, Beaufils F, Wie&#xeb;rs G, Guery B, Delhaes L. The Gut-Lung Axis in Health and Respiratory Diseases: A Place for Inter-Organ and Inter-Kingdom Crosstalks. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2020;10:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32140452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirivongrangson P, Kulvichit W, Payungporn S, Pisitkun T, Chindamporn A, Peerapornratana S, Pisitkun P, Chitcharoen S, Sawaswong V, Worasilchai N, Kampunya S, Putcharoen O, Thawitsri T, Leelayuwatanakul N, Kongpolprom N, Phoophiboon V, Sriprasart T, Samransamruajkit R, Tungsanga S, Tiankanon K, Lumlertgul N, Leelahavanichkul A, Sriphojanart T, Tantawichien T, Thisyakorn U, Chirathaworn C, Praditpornsilpa K, Tungsanga K, Eiam-Ong S, Sitprija V, Kellum JA, Srisawat N. Endotoxemia and circulating bacteriome in severe COVID-19 patients. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2020;8:72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33284413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cicho&#x17c;-Lach H, Michalak A. Liver injury in the era of COVID-19. World J Gastroenterol. 2021;27:377&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7856845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33584070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, Brown JS, Denneny EK, Hare SS, Heightman M, Hillman TE, Jacob J, Jarvis HC, Lipman MCI, Naidu SB, Nair A, Porter JC, Tomlinson GS, Hurst JR ARC Study Group. 'Long-COVID': a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghonimi TAL, Alkad MM, Abuhelaiqa EA, Othman MM, Elgaali MA, Ibrahim RAM, Joseph SM, Al-Malki HA, Hamad AI. Mortality and associated risk factors of COVID-19 infection in dialysis patients in Qatar: A nationwide cohort study. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0254246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8297751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34293004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robineau O, Zins M, Touvier M, Wiernik E, Lemogne C, de Lamballerie X, Blanch&#xe9; H, Deleuze JF, Saba Villarroel PM, Dorival C, Nicol J, Gomes-Rima R, Correia E, Coeuret-Pellicer M, Druesne-Pecollo N, Esseddik Y, Ribet C, Goldberg M, Severi G, Carrat F Sant&#xe9;, Pratiques, Relations et In&#xe9;galit&#xe9;s Sociales en Population G&#xe9;n&#xe9;rale Pendant la Crise COVID-19&#x2013;S&#xe9;rologie (SAPRIS-SERO) Study Group. Long-lasting Symptoms After an Acute COVID-19 Infection and Factors Associated With Their Resolution. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:e2240985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9647489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36350653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drossman DA, Hasler WL. Rome IV-Functional GI Disorders: Disorders of Gut-Brain Interaction. Gastroenterology. 2016;150:1257&#x2013;1261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27147121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Settanni CR, Ianiro G, Ponziani FR, Bibb&#xf2; S, Segal JP, Cammarota G, Gasbarrini A. COVID-19 as a trigger of irritable bowel syndrome: A review of potential mechanisms. World J Gastroenterol. 2021;27:7433&#x2013;7445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8613742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34887641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Mak JWY, Su Q, Yeoh YK, Lui GC, Ng SSS, Zhang F, Li AYL, Lu W, Hui DS, Chan PK, Chan FKL, Ng SC. Gut microbiota dynamics in a prospective cohort of patients with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Gut. 2022;71:544&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tungsanga S, Panpetch W, Bhunyakarnjanarat T, Udompornpitak K, Katavetin P, Chancharoenthana W, Chatthanathon P, Somboonna N, Tungsanga K, Tumwasorn S, Leelahavanichkul A. Uremia-Induced Gut Barrier Defect in 5/6 Nephrectomized Mice Is Worsened by Candida Administration through a Synergy of Uremic Toxin, Lipopolysaccharide, and (1&#x2192;3)-&#x3b2;-D-Glucan, but Is Attenuated by Lacticaseibacillus rhamnosus L34. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8910559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35269654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Guo C, Tang L, Hong Z, Zhou J, Dong X, Yin H, Xiao Q, Tang Y, Qu X, Kuang L, Fang X, Mishra N, Lu J, Shan H, Jiang G, Huang X. Prolonged presence of SARS-CoV-2 viral RNA in faecal samples. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;5:434&#x2013;435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32199469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandala S, Kodati R, Tadepalli A, Reddy C, Kalyan S. An Unusual Cause of Acute Abdominal Pain in Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19): Report of Two Cases. Indian J Crit Care Med. 2022;26:1045&#x2013;1048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9492738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36213717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alyousef IA, Alsaileek ZA, Alabdulsalam MA, Almohanna MA, Alshaqhaa NA, Alqahtani MM, Al Alyany AA, Alzahrani MA, Fallatah HA, Alqadhib JI, Alhawsawi AM, Alsuhaymi AD, Alasmari AM, Alshareef AJ, Al-Hawaj F. Mesenteric Panniculitis and COVID-19: A Rare Association. Cureus. 2022;14:e21314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8849467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35186573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang QW, Wang FD, Wang WZ, Wu X, Shu HJ, Li JN, Yang AM, Qian JM, Wu D. [An analysis of clinical characteristics of twelve cases of mesenteric panniculitis] Zhonghua Nei Ke Za Zhi. 2017;56:112&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28162180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cravedi P, Mothi SS, Azzi Y, Haverly M, Farouk SS, P&#xe9;rez-S&#xe1;ez MJ, Redondo-Pach&#xf3;n MD, Murphy B, Florman S, Cyrino LG, Grafals M, Venkataraman S, Cheng XS, Wang AX, Zaza G, Ranghino A, Furian L, Manrique J, Maggiore U, Gandolfini I, Agrawal N, Patel H, Akalin E, Riella LV. COVID-19 and kidney transplantation: Results from the TANGO International Transplant Consortium. Am J Transplant. 2020;20:3140&#x2013;3148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7405285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32649791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed IH, Chowdary PB, Shetty S, Sammartino C, Sivaprakasam R, Lindsey B, Thuraisingham R, Yaqoob MM, Khurram MA. Outcomes of Renal Transplant Recipients With SARS-CoV-2 Infection in the Eye of the Storm: A Comparative Study With Waitlisted Patients. Transplantation. 2021;105:115&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33350626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadi YB, Naqvi SFZ, Kupec JT, Sofka S, Sarwari A. Outcomes of COVID-19 in Solid Organ Transplant Recipients: A Propensity-matched Analysis of a Large Research Network. Transplantation. 2021;105:1365&#x2013;1371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8414593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33988341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beran TN, Violato C. Structural equation modeling in medical research: a primer. BMC Res Notes. 2010;3:267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2987867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20969789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chantasrisawad N, Puthanakit T, Kornsitthikul K, Jaru-Ampornpan P, Tawan M, Matapituk P, Sophonphan J, Anugulruengkitt S, Tangsathapornpong A, Katanyutanon A KIDSBOOST study team. Immunogenicity to SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variant among school-aged children with 2-dose of inactivated SARS-CoV-2 vaccines followed by BNT162b2 booster. Vaccine X. 2022;12:100221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9531410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36213592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chancharoenthana W, Leelahavanichkul A, Chinpraditsuk S, Pongpirul K, Kamolratanakul S, Phumratanaprapin W, Wilairatana P, Pitisuttithum P. Social restriction versus herd immunity policies in the early phase of the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic: A mathematical modelling study. Asian Pac J Allergy Immunol. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33386788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nooripour R, Ghanbari N, Radwin LE, Hosseinian S, Hassani-Abharian P. Development and validation of COVID-19 Stress Scale (CSS) in an Iranian non-clinical population. Zahedan J Res Med Sci. 2022;24:e118719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nooripour R, Hosseinian S, Farmani F, Abtahi Foroshani N, Ghanbari N, Farkhojasteh VS. Relationship Between Hardiness and Stress of COVID-19 Through the Mediating Role of Mindfulness in Iranian Students. PCP. 2022;10:193&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nooripour R, Hosseinian S, Hussain AJ, Annabestani M, Maadal A, Radwin LE, Hassani-Abharian P, Pirkashani NG, Khoshkonesh A. How Resiliency and Hope Can Predict Stress of Covid-19 by Mediating Role of Spiritual Well-being Based on Machine Learning. J Relig Health. 2021;60:2306&#x2013;2321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7780917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33398655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Vitetta L. Gut-brain axis in the neurological comorbidity of COVID-19. Brain Commun. 2021;3:fcab118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8195160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34169281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elseidy SA, Awad AK, Vorla M, Fatima A, Elbadawy MA, Mandal D, Mohamad T. Cardiovascular complications in the Post-Acute COVID-19 syndrome (PACS) Int J Cardiol Heart Vasc. 2022;40:101012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8958273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35355927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carriazo S, Mas-Fontao S, Seghers C, Cano J, Goma E, Avello A, Ortiz A, Gonzalez-Parra E. Increased 1-year mortality in haemodialysis patients with COVID-19: a prospective, observational study. Clin Kidney J. 2022;15:432&#x2013;441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8755355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35198156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilpatrick RD, McAllister CJ, Kovesdy CP, Derose SF, Kopple JD, Kalantar-Zadeh K. Association between serum lipids and survival in hemodialysis patients and impact of race. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2007;18:293&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barazzoni R, Breda J, Cuerda C, Schneider S, Deutz NE, Wickramasinghe K COVID-19 Call Editorial Board. COVID-19: Lessons on malnutrition, nutritional care and public health from the ESPEN-WHO Europe call for papers. Clin Nutr. 2022;41:2858&#x2013;2868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9365508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36075815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>