<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37350170</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2713-4148</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical and experimental pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Exp Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID in children and adolescents: prevalence, clinical manifestations, and management strategies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>465</StartPage><EndPage>474</EndPage><MedlinePgn>465-474</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3345/cep.2023.00472</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long coronavirus disease (COVID), also known as postacute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection, has been defined as signs and symptoms which persist for 4 weeks or even lasting for 6 months after the initial infection. Although the prevalence of long COVID in children is currently unknown, epidemiological investigations have reported cases in pediatric populations. Clinical manifestations of long COVID in children include respiratory symptoms, such as cough and dyspnea, as well as neuropsychiatric and general conditions, including fatigue, headache, and muscle weakness. The pathophysiology of long COVID in children is still being investigated, but potential mechanisms include viral persistence, autoimmunity, and neuroinflammation. Risk factors for long COVID in children are not yet well understood, but studies have suggested that children with a history of severe acute COVID-19 infection or comorbidities may be at increased risk. Evaluation for respiratory symptoms of long COVID in children is essential, including spirometry and imaging studies to assess lung function and any potential damage. Furthermore, long COVID in children has been associated with a higher prevalence of mental health problems than in adults, emphasizing the importance of monitoring and addressing these aspects in pediatric patients. Although our understanding of long COVID in children and adolescents is still evolving, it is clear that the condition can have significant impacts on their health and well-being. The aim of this review is to synthesize the current knowledge on the prevalence, risk factors, and pathophysiology of long COVID in children and adolescents, and to discuss potential management strategies based on existing evidence.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ha</LastName><ForeName>Eun Kyo</ForeName><Initials>EK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Hallym University Kangnam Sacred Heart Hospital, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Ju Hee</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Kyung Hee University Medical Center, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Man Yong</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, CHA Bundang Medical Center, CHA University School of Medicine, Seongnam, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Exp Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101761234</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2713-4148</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post COVID syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>Conflicts of interest</b>
. No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37350170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10626026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3345/cep.2023.00472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">cep.2023.00472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  . Geneva (Switzerland): World Health Organization; Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) pandemic [Internet] c2023 [cited 2023 Feb 7]. Available from:  https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SH, Choi JH, Yun KW. Therapeutics for the treatment of coronavirus disease 2019 in children and adolescents. Clin Exp Pediatr. 2022;65:377&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9348956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35760410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YH, Kim HH, Choe YJ. Predicting COVID-19 transmission in a student population in Seoul, South Korea, 2020-2021. Clin Exp Pediatr. 2023;66:173&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10080384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36550774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito S, Principi N, Azzari C, Cardinale F, Di Mauro G, Galli L, et al. Italian intersociety consensus on management of long covid in children. Ital J Pediatr. 2022;48:42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8905554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35264214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Allin B, Nugawela MD, Rojas N, Dalrymple E, Pinto Pereira S, et al. Long COVID (post-COVID-19 condition) in children: a modified Delphi process. Arch Dis Child. 2022;107:674&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8983414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35365499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics.  Office for National Statistics; 2021. CENSUS 2021. Technical article: Updated estimates of the prevalence of postacute symptoms among people with coronavirus (COVID-19) in the UK Articles [Internet] [cited 2023 Feb 7]. Available from:  https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsand diseases/articles/technicalarticleupdatedestimatesoftheprevalenceofpostacutesymptomsamongpeoplewithcoronaviruscovid19intheuk/previousReleases.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layton BA, Kaya D, Kelly C, Williamson KJ, Alegre D, Bachhuber SM, et al. Evaluation of a wastewater-based epidemiological approach to estimate the prevalence of SARS-CoV-2 infections and the detection of viral variants in disparate Oregon communities at city and neighborhood scales. Environ Health Perspect. 2022;130:67010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9241984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35767012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Say D, Crawford N, McNab S, Wurzel D, Steer A, Tosif S. Postacute COVID-19 outcomes in children with mild and asymptomatic disease. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2021;5:e22&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8057863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33891880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Munblit D, De Rose C, Sinatti D, Ricchiuto A, Carfi A, et al. Preliminary evidence on long COVID in children. Acta Paediatr. 2021;110:2208&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33835507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beharry M. Pediatric anxiety and depression in the time of COVID-19. Pediatr Ann. 2022;51:e154&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35417314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta M, Gupta N, Esang M. Long COVID in children and adolescents. Prim Care Companion CNS Disord. 2022;24:21r03218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35486940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> Long COVID or Post-COVID Conditions: National Center for Immunization and Respiratory Diseases (NCIRD) of Viral Diseases, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention [Internet]. Atlanta (GA): Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; [cited 2023 Feb 7]. Available from:  https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  . Geneva (Switzerland): World Health Organization; 2022. Post COVID-19 condition (long COVID) [Internet] [cited 2023 Feb 7]. Available from:  https://www.who.int/europe/newsroom/fact-sheets/item/post-covid-19-condition.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikkenborg Berg S, Dam Nielsen S, Nygaard U, Bundgaard H, Palm P, Rotvig C, et al. Long COVID symptoms in SARS-CoV-2-positive adolescents and matched controls (LongCOVIDKidsDK): a national, cross-sectional study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2022;6:240&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8820960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  . World Health Organization; 2021. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus [Internet] [cited 2023 Feb 7]. Available from:  https://www.who.int/publicationsi/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin B, Lee S, Chung US. Jeopardized mental health of children and adolescents in coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic. Clin Exp Pediatr. 2022;65:322&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9263423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35681248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashkenazi-Hoffnung L, Shmueli E, Ehrlich S, Ziv A, Bar-On O, Birk E, et al. Long COVID in Children: Observations From a Designated Pediatric Clinic. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:e509&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34371507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brackel CLH, Lap CR, Buddingh EP, van Houten MA, van der Sande L, Langereis EJ, et al. Pediatric long COVID: an overlooked phenomenon? Pediatr Pulmonol. 2021;56:2495&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34102037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludvigsson JF. Case report and systematic review suggest that children may experience similar long-term effects to adults after clinical COVID-19. Acta Paediatr. 2021;110:914&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33205450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Pittet LF, Curtis N. How common is long COVID in children and adolescents? Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:e482&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34870392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radtke T, Ulyte A, Puhan MA, Kriemler S. Long-term symptoms after SARS-CoV-2 infection in children and adolescents. JAMA. 2021;326:869&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8283661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34264266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics  . Office for National Statistics; 2021. CENSUS 2021. Updated estimates of the prevalence of long COVID symptoms [Internet] [cited 2023 Feb 7]. Available from:  https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/healthandlifeexpectancies/adhocs/12788updatedestimatesoftheprevalenceoflongcovidsymptoms.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller F, Nguyen DV, Navaratnam AM, Shrotri M, Kovar J, Hayward AC, et al. Prevalence and characteristics of persistent symptoms in children during the COVID-19 pandemic: evidence from a household cohort study in england and wales. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2022;41:979&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9645448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36375098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molteni E, Sudre CH, Canas LS, Bhopal SS, Hughes RC, Antonelli M, et al. Illness duration and symptom profile in symptomatic UK school-aged children tested for SARS-CoV-2. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2021;5:708&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8443448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34358472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smane L, Stars I, Pucuka Z, Roge I, Pavare J. Persistent clinical features in paediatric patients after SARS-CoV-2 virological recovery: a retrospective population-based cohort study from a single centre in Latvia. BMJ Paediatr Open. 2020;4:e000905</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7778738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34192185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osmanov IM, Spiridonova E, Bobkova P, Gamirova A, Shikhaleva A, Andreeva M, et al. Risk factors for post-COVID-19 condition in previously hospitalised children using the ISARIC Global follow-up protocol: a prospective cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2022;59:2101341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8576804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34210789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Shafran R, De Stavola B, Rojas N, Aiano F, AminChowdhury Z, et al. Long COVID and the mental and physical health of children and young people: national matched cohort study protocol (the CLoCk study) BMJ Open. 2021;11:e052838</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8392739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34446502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikkenborg Berg S, Palm P, Nygaard U, Bundgaard H, Petersen MNS, Rosenkilde S, et al. Long COVID symptoms in SARS-CoV-2-positive children aged 0-14 years and matched controls in Denmark (Long COVIDKidsDK): a national, cross-sectional study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2022;6:614&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9221683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35752194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roessler M, Tesch F, Batram M, Jacob J, Loser F, Weidinger O, et al. Post-COVID-19-associated morbidity in children, adolescents, and adults: a matched cohort study including more than 157,000 individuals with COVID-19 in Germany. PLoS Med. 2022;19:e1004122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9648706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36355754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson K, Skyrud KD, Suren P, Greve-Isdahl M, Stordal K, Kristoffersen DT, et al. Healthcare use in 700 000 children and adolescents for six months after covid-19: before and after register based cohort study. BMJ. 2022;376:e066809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8762452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35039315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuta T, Aizawa Y, Shoji K, Shimizu N, Okada K, Nakano T, et al. Acute and postacute clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in children in Japan. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2023;42:240&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9935236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36730047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behnood SA, Shafran R, Bennett SD, Zhang AXD, O'Mahoney LL, Stephenson TJ, et al. Persistent symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection amongst children and young people: a meta-analysis of controlled and uncontrolled studies. J Infect. 2022;84:158&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8604800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34813820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Di Gennaro L, De Rose C, Morello R, D'Ilario F, Zampino G, et al. Long-term outcomes of pediatric infections: from traditional infectious diseases to long Covid. Future Microbiol. 2022;17:551&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8910780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35264003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Pinto Pereira SM, Shafran R, de Stavola BL, Rojas N, McOwat K, et al. Physical and mental health 3 months after SARS-CoV-2 infection (long COVID) among adolescents in England (CLoCk): a national matched cohort study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2022;6:230&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8820961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funk AL, Kuppermann N, Florin TA, Tancredi DJ, Xie J, Kim K, et al. Post-COVID-19 conditions among children 90 days after SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:e2223253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9308058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35867061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Pujol FE, Munblit D, Pata D, McFarland S, Simpson FK. Clinical characteristics, activity levels and mental health problems in children with long coronavirus disease: a survey of 510 children. Future Microbiol. 2022;17:577&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9248023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35360923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA, Nemati H, Shahisavandi M, Akbari A, Emami A, Lotfi M, et al. Long COVID in children and adolescents. World J Pediatr. 2021;17:495&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8414448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34478045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roge I, Smane L, Kivite-Urtane A, Pucuka Z, Racko I, Klavina L, et al. Comparison of persistent symptoms after COVID-19 and other non-SARS-CoV-2 infections in children. Front Pediatr. 2021;9:752385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8586002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34778143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fainardi V, Meoli A, Chiopris G, Motta M, Skenderaj K, Grandinetti R, et al. Long COVID in children and adolescents. Life (Basel) 2022;12:285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8876679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35207572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterky E, Olsson-Akefeldt S, Hertting O, Herlenius E, Alfven T, Ryd Rinder M, et al. Persistent symptoms in Swedish children after hospitalisation due to COVID-19. Acta Paediatr. 2021;110:2578&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34157167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borch L, Holm M, Knudsen M, Ellermann-Eriksen S, Hagstroem S. Long COVID symptoms and duration in SARS-CoV-2 positive children - a nationwide cohort study. Eur J Pediatr. 2022;181:1597&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8742700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35000003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zavala M, Ireland G, Amin-Chowdhury Z, Ramsay ME, Ladhani SN. Acute and persistent symptoms in children with polymerase chain reaction (PCR)-confirmed severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection compared with test-negative children in England: active, prospective, national surveillance. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;75:e191&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8767867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34849658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV, Jayadevan R, Sashidharan S. Long COVID: an overview. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15:869&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaebler C, Wang Z, Lorenzi JCC, Muecksch F, Finkin S, Tokuyama M, et al. Evolution of antibody immunity to SARS-CoV-2. Nature. 2021;591:639&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodda LB, Netland J, Shehata L, Pruner KB, Morawski PA, Thouvenel CD, et al. Functional SARS-CoV-2-specific immune memory persists after mild COVID-19. Cell. 2021;184:169&#x2013;83.e17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7682481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33296701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danzetta ML, Amato L, Cito F, Di Giuseppe A, Morelli D, Savini G, et al. SARS-CoV-2 RNA persistence in naso-pharyngeal Swabs. Microorganisms. 2020;8:1124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7466010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32722621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu CLH, Raval M, Schnall JA, Kwong JC, Holmes NE. Duration of respiratory and gastrointestinal viral shedding in children with SARS-CoV-2: a systematic review and synthesis of data. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2020;39:e249&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32618932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing YH, Ni W, Wu Q, Li WJ, Li GJ, Wang WD, et al. Prolonged viral shedding in feces of pediatric patients with coronavirus disease 2019. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2020;53:473&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7141453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32276848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqui R, Mungroo MR, Khan NA. SARS-CoV-2 invasion of the central nervous: a brief review. Hosp Pract (1995) 2021;49:157&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7938650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33554684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Piazza M, Boner AL, Bellanti JA. Long COVID: a proposed hypothesis-driven model of viral persistence for the pathophysiology of the syndrome. Allergy Asthma Proc. 2022;43:187&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9106095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35524358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yonker LM, Neilan AM, Bartsch Y, Patel AB, Regan J, Arya P, et al. Pediatric severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2): clinical presentation, infectivity, and immune responses. J Pediatr. 2020;227:45&#x2013;52.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7438214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32827525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or postacute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): an overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front Microbiol. 2021;12:698169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond) 2021;53:737&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaffal SM, Abbas MA. TRP channels in COVID-19 disease: potential targets for prevention and treatment. Chem Biol Interact. 2021;345:109567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8217345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34166652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bousquet J, Czarlewski W, Zuberbier T, Mullol J, Blain H, Cristol JP, et al. Potential interplay between Nrf2, TRPA1, and TRPV1 in nutrients for the control of COVID-19. Int Arch Allergy Immunol. 2021;182:324&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8018185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33567446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng W, Zheng J. Distribution and assembly of TRP ion channels. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2021;1349:111&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35138613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liviero F, Campisi M, Mason P, Pavanello S. Transient receptor potential vanilloid subtype 1: potential role in infection, susceptibility, symptoms and treatment of COVID-19. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021;8:753819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8599155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34805220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy CG, Wilczynski S, Wenceslau CF, Webb RC. A new storm on the horizon in COVID-19: Bradykinin-induced vascular complications. Vascul Pharmacol. 2021;137:106826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33358968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvin MR, Alvarez C, Miller JI, Prates ET, Walker AM, Amos BK, et al. A mechanistic model and therapeutic interventions for COVID-19 involving a RAS-mediated bradykinin storm. Elife. 2020;9:e59177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7410499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32633718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabassum A, Iqbal MS, Sultan S, Alhuthali RA, Alshubaili DI, Sayyam RS, et al. Dysregulated bradykinin: mystery in the pathogenesis of COVID-19. Mediators Inflamm. 2022;2022:7423537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8826266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35153624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey J, Alam MT, Chandra S, Gupta J, Ray U, Srivastava AK, et al. Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 may play a role in the breakdown of the respiratory center of the brain. J Med Virol. 2021;93:1296&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32964419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon IH, Normandin E, Bhattacharyya S, Mukerji SS, Keller K, Ali AS, et al. Neuropathological features of Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:989&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7304421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Weyhern CH, Kaufmann I, Neff F, Kremer M. Early evidence of pronounced brain involvement in fatal COVID-19 outcomes. Lancet. 2020;395:e109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32505222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Persistent brainstem dysfunction in long COVID: a hypothesis. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2021;12:573&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, Brown JS, Denneny EK, Hare SS, et al. 'Long COVID': a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodin P, Casari G, Townsend L, O'Farrelly C, Tancevski I, Loffler-Ragg J, et al. Studying severe long COVID to understand post-infectious disorders beyond COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28:879&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35383311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guimaraes D, Pissarra R, Reis-Melo A, Guimaraes H. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MISC): a systematic review. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:e14450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34105843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, et al. Postacute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozturk GK, Beken B, Dogan S, Akar HH. Pulmonary function tests in the follow-up of children with COVID-19. Eur J Pediatr. 2022;181:2839&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9072762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35522314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daines L, Zheng B, Pfeffer P, Hurst JR, Sheikh A. A clinical review of long COVID with a focus on the respiratory system. Curr Opin Pulm Med. 2022;28:174&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7612723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35131989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> RCPCH responds to new study on long lasting symptoms in children with COVID-19 [Intetnet]. London: Royal College of Paediatrics and Child Health; 2021 [cited 2023 Feb 7]. Available from:  https://www.rcpch.ac.uk/news-events/news/rcpch-responds-new-study-long-lastingsymptoms-children-covid-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eitner L, Maier C, Brinkmann F, Schlegtendal A, Knoke L, EnaxKrumova E, et al. Somatosensory abnormalities after infection with SARS-CoV-2 - A prospective case-control study in children and adolescents. Front Pediatr. 2022;10:977827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9574195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36263148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi B, Sudry T, Flaks-Manov N, Yehezkelli Y, Kalkstein N, Akiva P, et al. Long covid outcomes at one year after mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: nationwide cohort study. BMJ. 2023;380:e072529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9832503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36631153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen MS, Kristiansen MF, Hanusson KD, Foldbo BM, Danielsen ME, &#xc1; Steig B, et al. Prevalence of long COVID in a national cohort: longitudinal measures from disease onset until 8 months' follow-up. Int J Infect Dis. 2022;122:437&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9222150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35753603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>