<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39159474</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-6623</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>165</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pain</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pain</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Increasing associations of long-COVID with small-fiber neuropathy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e93</StartPage><EndPage>e95</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e93-e95</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000003260</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oaklander</LastName><ForeName>Anne Louise</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9578-1596</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Massachusetts General Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology (Neuropathology), Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS093653</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01 FD007769</GrantID><Acronym>FD</Acronym><Agency>FDA HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013487">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pain</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7508686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0304-3959</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071075" MajorTopicYN="Y">Small Fiber Neuropathy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The author reports no Conflicts of Interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39159474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1979357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11343176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000003260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006396-202409000-00029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abrams RMC, Simpson DM, Navis A, Jette N, Zhou L, Shin SC. Small fiber neuropathy associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Muscle Nerve 2022;65:440&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34766365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albrecht PJ, Hou Q, Argoff CE, Storey JR, Wymer JP, Rice FL. Excessive peptidergic sensory innervation of cutaneous arteriole-venule shunts (AVS) in the palmar glabrous skin of fibromyalgia patients: implications for widespread deep tissue pain and fatigue. Pain Med 2013;14:895&#x2013;915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23691965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boneparth A, Chen S, Horton DB, Moorthy LN, Farquhar I, Downs HM, Lee H, Oaklander AL. Epidermal neurite density in skin biopsies from patients with juvenile fibromyalgia. J Rheumatol 2021;48:575&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7882634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32801135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan ACY, Wong HY, Chong YF, Lai PS, Teoh HL, Ng AYY, Hung JHM, Chan YC, Ng KWP, Vijayan J, Ong JJY, Chandra B, Tan CH, Rutt NH, Tan TM, Ismail NH, Wilder-Smith E, Schwarz H, Choi H, Sharma VK, Mak A Novel autoantibodies in idiopathic small fiber neuropathy. Ann Neurol 2022;91:66&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9300200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34761434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu IM, Heesters BA, Ghasemlou N, Von Hehn CA, Zhao F, Tran J, Wainger B, Strominger A, Muralidharan S, Horswill AR, Bubeck WJ, Hwang SW, Carroll MC, Woolf CJ. Bacteria activate sensory neurons that modulate pain and inflammation. Nature 2013;501:52&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3773968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23965627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabby R, Gilad R, Sadeh M, Lampl Y, Watemberg N Acute steroid responsive small-fiber sensory neuropathy: a new entity? J Peripher Nerv Syst 2006;11:47&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16519781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daifallah O, Farah A, Dawes JM. A role for pathogenic autoantibodies in small fiber neuropathy? Front Mol Neurosci 2023;16:1254854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10547903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37799730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Stefano G, Falco P, Galosi E, Di Pietro G, Leone C, Truini A A systematic review and meta-analysis of neuropathic pain associated with coronavirus disease 2019. Eur J Pain 2023;27:44&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9877974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36367322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evdokimov D, Frank J, Klitsch A, Unterecker S, Warrings B, Serra J, Papagianni A, Saffer N, Meyer Zu Altenschildesche C, Kampik D, Malik RA, Sommer C, Uceyler N Reduction of skin innervation is associated with a severe fibromyalgia phenotype. Ann Neurol 2019;86:504&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31376174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falco P, Litewczuk D, Di Stefano G, Galosi E, Leone C, De Stefano G, Di Pietro G, Tramontana L, Ciardi MR, Pasculli P, Zingaropoli MA, Arendt-Nielsen L, Truini A Small fibre neuropathy frequently underlies the painful long-COVID syndrome. PAIN 2024;in press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38723183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman R, Gewandter JS, Faber CG, Gibbons C, Haroutounian S, Lauria G, Levine T, Malik RA, Singleton JR, Smith AG, Bell J, Dworkin RH, Feldman E, Herrmann DN, Hoke A, Kolb N, Mansikka H, Oaklander AL, Peltier A, Polydefkis M, Ritt E, Russell JW, Sainati S, Steiner D, Treister R, Uceyler N Idiopathic distal sensory polyneuropathy: ACTTION diagnostic criteria. Neurology 2020;95:1005&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33055271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujii T, Lee EJ, Miyachi Y, Yamasaki R, Lim YM, Iinuma K, Sakoda A, Kim KK, Kira JI. Antiplexin D1 antibodies relate to small fiber neuropathy and induce neuropathic pain in animals. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2021;8:e1028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8185707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34099459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geerts M, de Greef BTA, Sopacua M, van Kuijk SMJ, Hoeijmakers JGJ, Faber CG, Merkies ISJ. Intravenous immunoglobulin therapy in patients with painful idiopathic small fiber neuropathy. Neurology 2021;96:e2534&#x2013;e45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8205474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33766992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendre T, Lefaucheur JP, Nordine T, Baba-Amer Y, Authier FJ, Devaux J, Creange A Characterizing acute-onset small fiber neuropathy. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2024;11:e200195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10766082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38170952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grayston R, Czanner G, Elhadd K, Goebel A, Frank B, Uceyler N, Malik RA, Alam U A systematic review and meta-analysis of the prevalence of small fiber pathology in fibromyalgia: Implications for a new paradigm in fibromyalgia etiopathogenesis. Semin Arthritis Rheum 2019;48:933&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30314675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh PC, Tseng MT, Chao CC, Lin YH, Tseng WY, Liu KH, Chiang MC, Hsieh ST. Imaging signatures of altered brain responses in small-fiber neuropathy: reduced functional connectivity of the limbic system after peripheral nerve degeneration. Pain 2015;156:904&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25734991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph P, Arevalo C, Oliveira RKF, Faria-Urbina M, Felsenstein D, Oaklander AL, Systrom DM. Insights from invasive cardiopulmonary exercise testing of patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Chest 2021;160:642&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph P, Pari R, Miller S, Warren A, Stovall MC, Squires J, Chang CJ, Xiao W, Waxman AB, Systrom DM. Neurovascular dysregulation and acute exercise intolerance in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: A randomized, placebo-controlled trial of pyridostigmine. Chest 2022;162:1116&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35526605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang M, Treister R, Oaklander AL. Diagnostic value of blood tests for occult causes of initially idiopathic small-fiber polyneuropathy. J Neurol 2016;263:2515&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5845263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27730378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Treister R, Lang M, Oaklander AL. IVIg for apparently autoimmune small-fiber polyneuropathy: First analysis of efficacy and safety. Ther Adv Neurol Disord 2018;11:1756285617744484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5791555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29403541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Magro C, Loewenstein JI, Makar RS, Stowell CP, Dzik WH, Hochberg EP, Oaklander AL, Sobrin L A man with paraneoplastic retinopathy plus small fiber polyneuropathy associated with Waldenstr&#xf6;m macroglobulinemia (lymphoplasmacytic lymphoma): Insights into mechanisms. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2015;23:405&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24654565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manganotti P, Garascia G, Furlanis G, Buoite Stella A Efficacy of intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIg) on COVID-19-related neurological disorders over the last 2 years: an up-to-date narrative review. Front Neurosci 2023;17:1159929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10166837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37179564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marjenberg Z, Leng S, Tascini C, Garg M, Misso K, El Guerche Seblain C, Shaikh N Risk of long COVID main symptoms after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep 2023;13:15332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10504382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37714919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak P Post COVID-19 syndrome associated with orthostatic cerebral hypoperfusion syndrome, small fiber neuropathy and benefit of immunotherapy: a case report. eNeurologicalSci 2020;21:100276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7502253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32984564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak P, Mukerji SS, Alabsi HS, Systrom D, Marciano SP, Felsenstein D, Mullally WJ, Pilgrim DM. Multisystem Involvement in Post-Acute Sequelae of Coronavirus Disease 19. Ann Neurol 2022;91:367&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9011495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34952975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oaklander AL, Herzog ZD, Downs HM, Klein MM. Objective evidence that small-fiber polyneuropathy underlies some illnesses currently labeled as fibromyalgia. Pain 2013;154:2310&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3845002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23748113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oaklander AL, Klein MM. Evidence of small-fiber polyneuropathy in unexplained, juvenile-onset, widespread pain syndromes. Pediatrics 2013;131:e1091&#x2013;e100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4074641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23478869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oaklander AL, Mills AJ, Kelley M, Toran LS, Smith B, Dalakas MC, Nath A Peripheral neuropathy evaluations of patients with prolonged Long COVID. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2022;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8889896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35232750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oaklander AL, Nolano M Scientific advances in and clinical approaches to small-fiber polyneuropathy: A review. JAMA Neurol 2019;76:1240&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10021074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31498378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paticoff J, Valovska A, Nedeljkovic SS, Oaklander AL. Defining a treatable cause of erythromelalgia: acute adolescent autoimmune small-fiber axonopathy. Anesth Analg 2007;104:438&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17242106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pindi Sala T, Villedieu M, Damian L, Crave JC, Pautot V, Stojanovich L, Tervaert JWC, Cherin P, Belizna C Long-term efficacy of immunoglobulins in small fiber neuropathy related to Sj&#xf6;gren&#x2019;s syndrome. J Neurol 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiers S, Ray PR, Wangzhou A, Sankaranarayanan I, Tatsui CE, Rhines LD, Li Y, Uhelski ML, Dougherty PM, Price TJ. ACE2 and SCARF expression in human dorsal root ganglion nociceptors: implications for SARS-CoV-2 virus neurological effects. Pain 2020;161:2494&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7572821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suh J, Mukerji SS, Collens SI, Padera RF Jr., Pinkus GS, Amato AA, Solomon IH. Skeletal muscle and peripheral nerve histopathology in COVID-19. Neurology 2021;97:e849&#x2013;e58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34099523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treister R, Lodahl M, Lang M, Tworoger SS, Sawilowsky S, Oaklander AL. Initial development and validation of a patient-reported symptom survey for small-fiber polyneuropathy. J Pain 2017;18:556&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5947871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28063957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuki N, Chan AC, Wong AHY, Inoue T, Yokai M, Kurihara T, Devaux JJ, Wilder-Smith E Acute painful autoimmune neuropathy: A variant of Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome. Muscle Nerve 2018;57:320&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28667708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubair AS, Rethana M, Ma A, McAlpine LS, Abulaban A, Munro BS, Patwa HS, Nowak RJ, Roy B Plasmapheresis versus intravenous immunoglobulin in patients with autoimmune neuromuscular and neuro-immunological conditions. Journal of clinical neuromuscular disease 2023;25:11&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37611265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>