<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37130538</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1438-8685</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Laryngo- rhino- otologie</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Laryngorhinootologie</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Outpatient rehabilitative care for patients with Long-COVID - a guideline-based clinical practice guideline].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>521</StartPage><EndPage>532</EndPage><MedlinePgn>521-532</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/a-1985-0450</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Even after weeks and months, persisting and also newly occurring symptoms after SARS-CoV-2 infection are common and lead in many cases to a broad spectrum of impairments and participation restrictions in all areas of daily life. Scientific evidence on therapeutic options still is limited. The aim of this work is therefore to provide pragmatic treatment recommendations analogous to the current therapeutic appliances guideline.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">In addition to a search in six electronic databases, the experiences from the treatment of more than hundred affected persons from the post-COVID outpatient rehabilitation service were used. Additionally, experiences with patients with similar symptoms from other diseases were included. All authors worked together to develop the pragmatic recommendations for the treatment of the main symptoms within the framework of outpatient therapy measures. A list of recommended diagnostics and functional assessments prior to therapy was also developed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">For the main symptoms fatigue, dyspnoea and cognitive impairment, the catalog of therapeutic products offers a wide range of therapeutic options under the diagnosis U09.9. The therapy packages should be composed individually and adapted to the patient's performance level that regularly should be (re-)assessed. Informing the patient about possible relapses and deteriorations and how to deal with them should be also part of the treatment regimen.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Physical modalities and rehabilitation interventions should be used in out-patient rehabilitation setting for the treatment of Long-COVID. In this regard, it is also important to take into account and treat serious complications after the disease, such as post-intensive care syndrome. Due to the rapid evolution of the knowledge a frequent review of scientific papers and recommendations should be conducted. High-quality intervention studies are necessary to achieve greater evidence in this field.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teixido</LastName><ForeName>Lidia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Klinik f&#xfc;r Rehabilitationsmedizin, Medizinische Hochschule Hannover, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andreeva</LastName><ForeName>Elena</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Klinik f&#xfc;r Rehabilitationsmedizin, Medizinische Hochschule Hannover, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gartmann</LastName><ForeName>Judith</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Klinik f&#xfc;r Rehabilitationsmedizin, Medizinische Hochschule Hannover, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lemh&#xf6;fer</LastName><ForeName>Christina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6206-4064</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Physiotherapie, Universit&#xe4;tsklinikum Jena, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sturm</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Klinik f&#xfc;r Rehabilitationsmedizin, Medizinische Hochschule Hannover, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gutenbrunner</LastName><ForeName>Christoph</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabitation Medicine, Hannover medical School, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>ger</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017065">Practice Guideline</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><VernacularTitle>Ambulante rehabilitative Versorgung von Patienten mit Long-COVID &#x2013; eine leitlinienorientierte klinisch-praktische Handlungsempfehlung.</VernacularTitle><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Laryngorhinootologie</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8912371</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0935-8943</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010045" MajorTopicYN="N">Outpatients</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger"><AbstractText Label="HINTERGRUND">Auch &#xfc;ber Wochen und Monate anhaltende und neu auftretende Symptome nach einer SARS-CoV-2 Infektion sind verbreitet und f&#xfc;hren teilweise zu einem bunten Bild an Einschr&#xe4;nkungen und Defiziten. Wissenschaftliche Evidenz zu einzelnen therapeutischen M&#xf6;glichkeiten ist nur begrenzt verf&#xfc;gbar. Das Ziel dieser Arbeit ist es daher, pragmatische Behandlungsempfehlungen analog der aktuellen Heilmittelrichtlinie aufzustellen.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODE">Neben einer Suche in sechs elektronischen Datenbanken wurden auch die Erfahrungen aus der Behandlung von hunderten Betroffenen aus der Post-COVID-Sprechstunde sowie Patienten mit &#xe4;hnlichen Symptomen bei anderen Erkrankungen herangezogen. Unter Einbeziehung aller Autoren erfolgte dann die Entwicklung der pragmatischen Handlungsempfehlungen f&#xfc;r die Hauptsymptome im Rahmen ambulanter Therapiema&#xdf;nahmen. Eine Aufstellung von m&#xf6;glicher Diagnostik und funktionellen Assessments vor der Therapie wurde abschlie&#xdf;end entwickelt.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ERGEBNISSE">F&#xfc;r die Hauptsymptome Fatigue, Dyspnoe und kognitive Einschr&#xe4;nkungen bietet der Heilmittelkatalog unter der Diagnose U09.9 weitreichende therapeutische M&#xf6;glichkeiten. Die Zusammenstellung der Therapiepakete sollte individuell erfolgen und durch Reassesments an das Leistungsniveau angepasst werden. Eine Aufkl&#xe4;rung des Patienten &#xfc;ber m&#xf6;gliche R&#xfc;ckf&#xe4;lle und Verschlechterungen sowie Umgang mit diesen sollte Teil der Therapie sein.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISKUSSION">Ambulante Heilmittel sollten im Rahmen des besonderen Verordnungsbedarfes zur Behandlung von Long-COVID eingesetzt werden. Hierbei ist es wichtig, auch schwerwiegende Komplikationen nach der Erkrankung, wie beispielsweise das Post-intensive-Care-Syndrom, zu erfassen und speziell zu behandeln. Eine regelm&#xe4;&#xdf;ige &#xdc;berpr&#xfc;fung wissenschaftlicher Arbeiten und Empfehlungen sollte auf Grund der schnellen Weiterentwicklung der Erkenntnisse erfolgen. Qualitativ hochwertige Interventionsstudien sind notwendig, um eine gr&#xf6;&#xdf;ere Evidenz auf diesem Gebiet zu erreichen.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><CoiStatement>Die Autorinnen/Autoren geben an, dass kein Interessenkonflikt besteht.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37130538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1985-0450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>