<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39103645</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2000</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecular diagnosis &amp; therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mol Diagn Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Blood Biomarkers of Long COVID: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>537</StartPage><EndPage>574</EndPage><MedlinePgn>537-574</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40291-024-00731-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Long coronavirus disease (COVID; LC) affects millions of people worldwide. The exact mechanisms which result in a broad, undulating and detrimental symptom profile remain unknown. Blood biomarkers associated with LC have been described; however, consensus on these remains elusive, in part due to a lack of continuity between studies on a universally accepted definition of LC. This systematic review aimed to consolidate current knowledge of blood biomarkers associated with the prevalence of LC on the basis of the World Health Organisation (WHO) clinical definition of this condition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA FOR SELECTING STUDIES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Observational, cross-sectional, and randomised control studies published in the English language that studied blood biomarkers associated with the WHO definition of LC. All studies included participants who were &#x2265; 18 years old and group sizes &#x2265; 10 participants, and were compared against a control group without any known co-morbidities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic literature search was conducted according to Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines and prospectively registered on Prospero (ID: CRD42022373121). The Cochrane, Embase, PubMed and Web of Science databases were searched from inception to January 2024. Search results were gathered using Rayyan software and data extracted using Microsoft Excel. The reporting recommendations for tumour markers prognostic studies (REMARK) questionnaire was used to assess the quality of the included studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 45 observational and one interventional study comprising 4415 participants were included in this review which identified 525 blood biomarkers thought to be associated with LC. Three blood biomarker subtypes were associated with the development of LC: (1) immunological and inflammatory dysfunction, (2) endothelial/vascular dysfunction and (3) metabolic and clotting abnormalities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION AND CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our data are consistent with previous findings; however, no single biomarker was sufficiently associated with LC prevalence and instead a profile of biomarkers across various physiological systems may be more clinically useful. In all, 196 studies were excluded due to a lack of an adequately healthy comparator group and/or failure to meet the WHO LC definition. This demonstrates a need for further research incorporating a universal LC definition across all disease severity groups and symptom profiles, and longitudinal data reflecting the relapsing and remitting nature of this condition. Further investigation into blood biomarkers of LC, including clear reporting of healthy comparator groups and the investigation of acute and chronic biomarker changes, within the context of medical practice, may support the development of curative/restorative approaches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>Callum</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8608-8231</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical and Clinical Science Research Theme, School of Human Sciences, University of Derby, Derby, UK. C.Thomas@derby.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healthy Living for Pandemic Event Protection (HL-PIVOT) Network, Chicago, IL, USA. C.Thomas@derby.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faghy</LastName><ForeName>Mark A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical and Clinical Science Research Theme, School of Human Sciences, University of Derby, Derby, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healthy Living for Pandemic Event Protection (HL-PIVOT) Network, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, College of Applied Sciences, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chidley</LastName><ForeName>Corinna</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical and Clinical Science Research Theme, School of Human Sciences, University of Derby, Derby, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phillips</LastName><ForeName>Bethan E</ForeName><Initials>BE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC-Versus Arthritis Centre for Musculoskeletal Ageing Research and NIHR Nottingham Biomedical Research Centre, School of Medicine, University of Nottingham, Derby, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bewick</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, University Hospitals of Derby and Burton NHS Foundation Trust, Derby, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashton</LastName><ForeName>Ruth E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical and Clinical Science Research Theme, School of Human Sciences, University of Derby, Derby, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healthy Living for Pandemic Event Protection (HL-PIVOT) Network, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Centre for Physical Activity, Sport and Exercise Sciences, Coventry University, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Mol Diagn Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101264260</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1177-1062</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="Y">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39103645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40291-024-00731-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40291-024-00731-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Perego E, et al. Why the patient-made term &#x201c;long covid&#x201d; is needed. Wellcome Open Res. 2020;5:224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/wellcomeopenres.16307.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38: 101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghy MA, et al. COVID-19 patients require multi-disciplinary rehabilitation approaches to address persisting symptom profiles and restore pre-COVID quality of life. Expert Rev Respir Med. 2022;16(5):595&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35385677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17476348.2022.2063843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes LD, Ingram J, Sculthorpe NF. More than 100 persistent symptoms of SARS-CoV-2 (long COVID): a scoping review. Front Med (Lausanne). 2021;8: 750378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34790680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.750378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas C, et al. Lived experience of patients with Long COVID: a qualitative study in the UK. BMJ Open. 2023;13(4): e068481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37185640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-068481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wulf Hanson S et al. A global systematic analysis of the occurrence, severity, and recovery pattern of long COVID in 2020 and 2021. medRxiv. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton C, et al. Within and between-day variation and associations of symptoms in long Covid: Intensive longitudinal study. PLoS ONE. 2023;18(1): e0280343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36656830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9851560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0280343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghy MAO, Thomas R, Yates C, Ferraro J, Skipper FV, Barley McMullen L, Brown S, Arena DA, Ashton R, Ruth EM. Is long COVID the next global health crisis? J Glob Health. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acosta-Ampudia Y, et al. Persistent autoimmune activation and proinflammatory state in post-coronavirus disease 2019 syndrome. J Infect Dis. 2022;225(12):2155&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35079804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiac017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, et al. Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open. 2021;11(3): e048391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-048391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BK, et al. Persistence of SARS CoV-2 S1 protein in CD16+ monocytes in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) up to 15 months post-infection. Front Immunol. 2022;12: 746021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8784688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.746021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, et al. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs LMC, et al. Biomarkers of sustained systemic inflammation and microvascular dysfunction associated with post-COVID-19 condition symptoms at 24 months after SARS-CoV-2-infection. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1182182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37868959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10586198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1182182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medori MCDK, Tezzele S, Micheletti C, Maltese PE, Cecchin S, Bonetti G, Fioretti F, Calzoni A, Praderio A, de Angelis MG, Arabia G, Donato K, Lorusso L, Manganotti P, Capelli E, Cristoni S, Nodari S, Bertelli M. Serum proteomic profiling reveals potential inflammatory biomarkers in long-COVID patients: a comparative analysis with healthy controls. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2023;27(6).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Togt V, Rossman JS. Hypothesis: inflammatory acid-base disruption underpins long Covid. Front Immunol. 2023;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swank Z et al. Persistent circulating SARS-CoV-2 spike is associated with post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Clin Infect Dis. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. J Clin Epidemiol. 2021;134:178&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2021.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021. 2021 22/07/2022]; https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1 . Accessed 15 May 2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouzzani M et al. Rayyan&#x2014;a web and mobile app for systematic reviews. Syst Rev. 2016;5(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai YJ, et al. Biomarkers in long COVID-19: a systematic review. Front Med (Lausanne). 2023;10:1085988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36744129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9895110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2023.1085988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McShane LM, et al. Reporting recommendations for tumor marker prognostic studies (REMARK). J Natl Cancer Inst. 2005;97(16):1180&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16106022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnci/dji237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauerbrei W, et al. Reporting recommendations for tumor marker prognostic studies (REMARK): an abridged explanation and elaboration. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2018;110(8):803&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29873743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6093349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnci/djy088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott NA, et al. Monocyte migration profiles define disease severity in acute COVID-19 and unique features of long COVID. Eur Respir J. 2023;61:2202226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36922030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10040898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02226-2022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BK, et al. Immune-based prediction of COVID-19 severity and chronicity decoded using machine learning. Front Immunol. 2021;12: 700782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34262570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8273732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.700782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salmasi JM et al. Neutrophil and monocyte extracellular traps in the diagnosis of post-COVID syndrome. Bull Russ State Med Univ. 2022;2022(6).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, et al. Longitudinal analysis of COVID-19 patients shows age-associated T cell changes independent of ongoing ill-health. Front Immunol. 2021;12: 676932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34025675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8138306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.676932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright TJ, et al. Low growth hormone secretion associated with post-acute sequelae SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) neurologic symptoms: a case-control pilot study. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2024;579: 112071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37816478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mce.2023.112071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iosef C, et al. Plasma proteome of long-COVID patients indicates HIF-mediated vasculo-proliferative disease with impact on brain and heart function. J Transl Med. 2023;21(1):377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37301958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10257382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-023-04149-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kravchenko D, et al. Cardiac MRI in patients with prolonged cardiorespiratory symptoms after mild to moderate COVID-19. Radiology. 2021;301(3):E419&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34374593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2021211162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altmann DM, et al. Persistent symptoms after COVID-19 are not associated with differential SARS-CoV-2 antibody or T cell immunity. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):5139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37612310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10447583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-40460-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin M, et al. Immunological fingerprint in coronavirus disease-19 convalescents with and without post-COVID syndrome. Front Med (Lausanne). 2023;10:1129288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37168268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2023.1129288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berentschot JC, et al. Immunological profiling in long COVID: overall low grade inflammation and T-lymphocyte senescence and increased monocyte activation correlating with increasing fatigue severity. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1254899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37881427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10597688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1254899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong SW, et al. Prolonged inflammation in patients hospitalized for coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) resolves 2 years after infection. J Med Virol. 2023;95(5): e28774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37212320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P, et al. Long COVID following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: characteristic T cell alterations and response to antihistamines. J Investig Med. 2022;70(1):61&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jim-2021-002051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paniskaki K, et al. Low avidity circulating SARS-CoV-2 reactive CD8+ T cells with proinflammatory TEMRA phenotype are associated with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Front Microbiol. 2023;14:1196721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37333646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10272838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2023.1196721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodruff MC, et al. Chronic inflammation, neutrophil activity, and autoreactivity splits long COVID. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):4201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37452024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10349085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-40012-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdi A, et al. Dysregulations in hemostasis, metabolism, immune response, and angiogenesis in post-acute COVID-19 syndrome with and without postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome: a multi-omic profiling study. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):20230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37981644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10658082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-47539-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso-Dominguez J, et al. High levels of IL-1beta, TNF-alpha and MIP-1alpha one month after the onset of the acute SARS-CoV-2 infection, predictors of post COVID-19 in hospitalized patients. Microorganisms. 2023;11(10):2396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37894054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10609568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms11102396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel MA et al. Elevated vascular transformation blood biomarkers in long-COVID indicate angiogenesis as a key pathophysiological mechanism. Mol Med. 2022;28(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Larragoiti N, et al. Inflammatory and Prothrombotic biomarkers contribute to the persistence of sequelae in recovered COVID-19 patients. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(24):17468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38139298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10744310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms242417468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanberg N, et al. COVID-19 recovery: consistent absence of cerebrospinal fluid biomarker abnormalities in patients with neurocognitive post-COVID complications. J Infect Dis. 2024;229(2):493&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37874918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiad395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neves P, et al. Imbalance of peripheral temperature, sympathovagal, and cytokine profile in long COVID. Biology (Basel). 2023;12(5):749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37237560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besteher B, et al. Cortical thickness alterations and systemic inflammation define long-COVID patients with cognitive impairment. Brain Behav Immun. 2024;116:175&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38036270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2023.11.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son K et al. Circulating anti-nuclear autoantibodies in COVID-19 survivors predict long-COVID symptoms. Eur Respir J. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes E, et al. Incomplete systemic recovery and metabolic phenoreversion in post-acute-phase nonhospitalized COVID-19 patients: implications for assessment of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. J Proteome Res. 2021;20(6):3315&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34009992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jproteome.1c00224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berezhnoy G, et al. Maintained imbalance of triglycerides, apolipoproteins, energy metabolites and cytokines in long-term COVID-19 syndrome patients. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1144224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37228606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10203989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1144224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sotzny FF, Salerno I, Kedor C, Freitag H, Wittke K, Bauer S, Sepulveda N, da Fonseca DLM, Baiocchi GC, Marques AHC, Kim M, Lange T, Placa DR, Luebber F, Paulus FM, De Vito R, Igor J, Schulze-Forster K, Paul F, Bellmann-Strobl J, Rust R, Hoppmann U, Shoenfeld Y, Riemekasten G, Heidecke H, Cabral-Marques O, Scheibenbogen C. Dysregulated autoantibodies targeting vaso- and immunoregulatory receptors in post COVID syndrome correlate with symptom severity. Front Immunol. 2022;13:5182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.981532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gimenez-Orenga K, et al. HERV-W ENV antigenemia and correlation of increased anti-SARS-CoV-2 immunoglobulin levels with post-COVID-19 symptoms. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1020064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36389746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9647063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.1020064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Ahearn JM. Acute-phase proteins and inflammation: immunological and clinical implications. In: Measuring immunity. New York: Academic Press; 2005. p. 131&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-012455900-4/50272-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Captur G, et al. Plasma proteomic signature predicts who will get persistent symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection. EBioMedicine. 2022;85:104293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36182629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9515404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2022.104293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, et al. Sequential multi-omics analysis identifies clinical phenotypes and predictive biomarkers for long COVID. Cell Rep Med. 2023;4(11): 101254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37890487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10694626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xcrm.2023.101254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philippe A, et al. VEGF-A plasma levels are associated with impaired DLCO and radiological sequelae in long COVID patients. Angiogenesis. 2024;27(1):51&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37526809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10456-023-09890-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espin E, et al. Cellular and molecular biomarkers of long COVID: a scoping review. EBioMedicine. 2023;91: 104552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37037165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10082390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2023.104552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montazersaheb S et al. COVID-19 infection: an overview on cytokine storm and related interventions. Virol J. 2022;19(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen R, et al. Long COVID quality of life and healthcare experiences in the UK: a mixed method online survey. Qual Life Res. 2024;33(1):133&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37740144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-023-03513-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kucharska J, et al. Benefit of mountain spa rehabilitation and ubiquinol treatment in patients with post-COVID-19 syndrome. Bratisl Lek Listy. 2023;124(2):89&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36598293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV, Jayadevan R, Sashidharan S. Long COVID: an overview. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15(3):869&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8056514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsx.2021.04.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel MA et al. Organ and cell-specific biomarkers of long-COVID identified with targeted proteomics and machine learning. Mol Med. 2023;29(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, et al. Plasma-based antigen persistence in the post-acute phase of COVID-19. Lancet Infect Dis. 2024;24(6):e345&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38604216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(24)00211-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M, et al. SARS-CoV-2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and is blocked by a clinically proven protease inhibitor. Cell. 2020;181(2):271-280.e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7102627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, et al. COVID-19 mechanisms in the human body&#x2014;what we know so far. Front Immunol. 2021;12: 693938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34790191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8592035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.693938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): an overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front Microbiol. 2021;12: 698169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2021.698169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rochette L, Ghibu S. Mechanics insights of alpha-lipoic acid against cardiovascular diseases during COVID-19 infection. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(15):7979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34360751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8348748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22157979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultheiss C, et al. Liquid biomarkers of macrophage dysregulation and circulating spike protein illustrate the biological heterogeneity in patients with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. J Med Virol. 2023;95(1): e28364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36458566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold JE, et al. Investigation of long COVID prevalence and its relationship to Epstein-Barr virus reactivation. Pathogens. 2021;10(6):763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34204243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8233978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pathogens10060763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kervevan J, et al. Divergent adaptive immune responses define two types of long COVID. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1221961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37559726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10408302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1221961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDaid KM, Chopra M. A pilot study to examine if dietary habits can affect symptomology in mild pre-vaccination COVID-19 cases. Biology. 2022;11(9):1274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36138753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9495586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biology11091274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin M, et al. Post-COVID syndrome in non-hospitalised patients with COVID-19: a longitudinal prospective cohort study. Lancet Regn Health Europe. 2021;6: 100122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Abell&#xe1;n J, et al. Antibody response to SARS-CoV-2 is associated with long-term clinical outcome in patients with COVID-19: a longitudinal study. J Clin Immunol. 2021;41(7):1490&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8285689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10875-021-01083-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asimakos AT, et al. Persistent endothelial lung damage and impaired diffusion capacity in long COVID. J Pers Med. 2023;13(9):1351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37763119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10533128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jpm13091351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson BA, et al. Plasma proteomics show altered inflammatory and mitochondrial proteins in patients with neurologic symptoms of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Brain Behav Immun. 2023;114:462&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37704012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2023.08.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haffke M et al. Endothelial dysfunction and altered endothelial biomarkers in patients with post-COVID-19 syndrome and chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). J Transl Med. 2022;20(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, et al. Plasma biomarkers for systemic inflammation in COVID-19 survivors. Proteom Clin Appl. 2022;16(5):2200031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/prca.202200031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kell DB, Laubscher GJ, Pretorius E. A central role for amyloid fibrin microclots in long COVID/PASC: origins and therapeutic implications. Biochem J. 2022;479(4):537&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35195253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/BCJ20220016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruger A et al. Proteomics of fibrin amyloid microclots in long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) shows many entrapped pro-inflammatory molecules that may also contribute to a failed fibrinolytic system. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E, et al. Persistent clotting protein pathology in long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) is accompanied by increased levels of antiplasmin. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2021;20(1):172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34425843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8381139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-021-01359-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Las Heras N, et al. Implications of oxidative stress and potential role of mitochondrial dysfunction in COVID-19: therapeutic effects of vitamin D. Antioxidants. 2020;9(9):897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox9090897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guntur VP, et al. Signatures of mitochondrial dysfunction and impaired fatty acid metabolism in plasma of patients with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC). Metabolites. 2022;12(11):1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36355108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9699059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/metabo12111026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haran JP et al. Inflammation-type dysbiosis of the oral microbiome associates with the duration of COVID-19 symptoms and long COVID. JCI Insight. 2021;6(20).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross SM. Long COVID and mitochondrial dysfunction. Holist Nurs Pract. 2023;37(1):51&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36378091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HNP.0000000000000566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossini V, et al. Gut microbiome and anti-viral immunity in COVID-19. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2022;64:1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayakumar B, et al. Immuno-proteomic profiling reveals aberrant immune cell regulation in the airways of individuals with ongoing post-COVID-19 respiratory disease. Immunity. 2022;55(3):542-556.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35151371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8789571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2022.01.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>