<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39328557</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2405-8440</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>18</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Heliyon</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Heliyon</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Herbal medicines for long COVID: A phase 2 pilot clinical study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e37920</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e37920</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e37920</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e37920</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Infections of Coronavirus Disease-2019 (COVID-19) can cause long-term effects known as long COVID. This pilot study aimed to evaluate the feasibility of a clinical study as well as the efficacy and safety of traditional East Asian herbal medicines in alleviating fatigue and cognitive dysfunction in patients with long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This prospective pilot study investigated the use of three types of herbal medicines, Bojungikgi-tang (BIT), Kyungok-go (KOG), and Cheonwangbosim-dan (CBD), for a 12-week period as potential treatments for fatigue and cognitive dysfunction in patients with long COVID. Forty-five patients with long COVID were recruited, and one of three drugs was given based on the patient's symptoms and pattern identification. The effect of herbal medications on fatigue and cognitive function outcomes was assessed over a 36-week period, with patient adherence closely monitored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">After 12 weeks of herbal drug administration, fatigue symptoms improved significantly across all groups, with treatment success rates of 80&#xa0;%, 53.33&#xa0;%, and 46.67&#xa0;% in the BIT, KOG, and CBD groups, respectively. However, cognitive dysfunction symptoms showed less improvement, with treatment success rates of 40&#xa0;%, 46.67&#xa0;%, and 13.33&#xa0;% in the BIT, KOG, and CBD groups, respectively. All adverse events reported were mild and unrelated to the medication. The study design was found to be feasible with high medication adherence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study demonstrated the feasibility of conducting a clinical trial with three herbal medicines to treat long COVID symptoms like fatigue and cognitive dysfunction.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Tae-Hun</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Korean Medicine Clinical Trial Center, Korean Medicine Hospital, Kyung Hee University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoon</LastName><ForeName>Jiwon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Korean Medicine Data Division, Korea Institute of Oriental Medicine, Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Sanghyun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Classics, College of Korean Medicine, Daejeon University, Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Byoung-Kab</ForeName><Initials>BK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Korean Medicine Research Division, Korea Institute of Oriental Medicine, Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Jung Won</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture &amp; Moxibustion, College of Korean Medicine, Kyung Hee University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwon</LastName><ForeName>Sunoh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Korean Medicine Convergence Research Division, Korea Institute of Oriental Medicine, Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Heliyon</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101672560</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2405-8440</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Herbal medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot clinical trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39328557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11425099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e37920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2405-8440(24)13951-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Soriano J.B., Murthy S., Marshall J.C., Relan P., Diaz J.V. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect. Dis. 2022;22(4):e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y., Kim S.E., Kim T., Yun K.W., Lee S.H., Lee E., et al. Preliminary guidelines for the clinical evaluation and management of long COVID. Infection &amp; chemotherapy. 2022;54(3):566&#x2013;597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9533168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36196612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C., Haupert S.R., Zimmermann L., Shi X., Fritsche L.G., Mukherjee B. Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J. Infect. Dis. 2022;226(9):1593&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall M. The lasting misery of coronavirus long-haulers. Nature. 2020;585(7825):339&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32929257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H.E., Assaf G.S., McCorkell L., Wei H., Low R.J., Re'em Y., et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F., Ling S., Lui L.M., Lee Y., Gill H., Teopiz K.M., et al. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav. Immun. 2022;101:93&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A., Nirantharakumar K., Hughes S., Myles P., Williams T., Gokhale K.M., et al. Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat. Med. 2022;28(8):1706&#x2013;1714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D. Who gets long COVID and suffers its mental health and socioeconomic consequences in the United States? Preliminary findings from a large nationwide study. medRxiv. 2023;2023 01. 06.23284199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler-Davis S., Platts K., Thelwell M., Woodward A., Harrop D. A mixed-methods systematic review of post-viral fatigue interventions: are there lessons for long Covid? PLoS One. 2021;16(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8577752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34752489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya M., Chatterjee S., Saxena S., Nandi S.S., Lee S.-S., Chakraborty C. Current landscape of long COVID clinical trials. Int. Immunopharm. 2024;132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38537538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonilla H., Peluso M.J., Rodgers K., Aberg J.A., Patterson T.F., Tamburro R., et al. Therapeutic trials for long COVID-19: a call to action from the interventions taskforce of the RECOVER initiative. Front. Immunol. 2023;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10034329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36969241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L., An X., Duan Y., Lian F., Jin D., Zhang Y., et al. The pathological mechanism of the COVID-19 convalescence and its treatment with traditional Chinese medicine. Front. Pharmacol. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9872123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36703736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong L.L.-D., Wong Y.-P., Leung C.-Y., Peng B., Lin Z.-X., Wong Taam V.C.-W., et al. Effects of Chinese medicine for COVID-19 rehabilitation: a multicenter observational study. Chin. Med. 2022;17(1):99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9395813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35996191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang W., Yang F., Zhao Y., Dai E., Feng J., Huang Y., et al. Qingjin Yiqi granules for post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 condition: a randomized clinical trial. J. Evid. Base Med. 2022;15(1):30&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9114922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35416437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim T.-H., Jeon S.-R., Kang J.W., Kwon S. Complementary and alternative medicine for long COVID: scoping review and bibliometric analysis. Evid. base Compl. Alternative Med. 2022;2022(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9371860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35966751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J.W., Kim H.J., Jang E.S., Jung H.J., Hwang M.W., Nam D.H. Survey on pattern identification and treatment of chronic fatigue in Korea medicine. Journal of Physiology &amp; Pathology in Korean Medicine. 2018;32(2):126&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokumasu K., Ueda K., Honda H., Sunada N., Sakurada Y., Matsuda Y., et al. Application of Kampo medicines for treatment of general fatigue due to long COVID. Medicina. 2022;58(6):730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9227280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35743993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang S., Kim D., Yi E., Choi G., Song M., Lee E.-K. Telemedicine and the use of Korean medicine for patients with COVID-19 in South Korea: observational study. JMIR Public Health and Surveillance. 2021;7(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7817255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33342765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon W.-Y., Jin S.E., Sohn E., Jo K., Ha H., Shin H.-K., Lee M.-Y. Anti-inflammatory and anti-allergic effects of Cheonwangbosim-dan water extract: an in vitro and in vivo study. Heliyon. 2023;9(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10199208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37215857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jegal K.H., Yoon J., Kim S., Jang S., Jin Y.-H., Lee J.-H., et al., editors. Herbal medicines for post-acute sequelae (fatigue or cognitive dysfunction) of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a phase 2 pilot clinical study protocolHealthcare. 2022;10(10):1839. MDPI)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9601660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36292286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercoulen J.H., Swanink C.M., Fennis J.F., Galama J.M., van der Meer J.W., Bleijenberg G. Dimensional assessment of chronic fatigue syndrome. J. Psychosom. Res. 1994;38(5):383&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7965927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha H., Jeong D., Hahm B.-J., Shim E.-J. Cross-cultural validation of the Korean version of the chalder fatigue scale. Int. J. Behav. Med. 2018;25:351&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29181801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung Y.I., Jeong E.H., Lee H., Seo J., Yu H.-J., Hong J.Y., Sunwoo M.K. Validation of MoCA-MMSE conversion scales in Korean patients with cognitive impairments. Dementia and Neurocognitive Disorders. 2018;17(4):148&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6425884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30906404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broadbent D.E., Cooper P.F., FitzGerald P., Parkes K.R. The cognitive failures questionnaire (CFQ) and its correlates. Br. J. Clin. Psychol. 1982;21(1):1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7126941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H., Park T. Korean norm for the difference between digits forward and digits backward. Kor. J. Clin. Psychol. 2003;22(3):599&#x2013;613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S.-H., Ahn J., Ock M., Shin S., Park J., Luo N., Jo M.-W. The EQ-5D-5L valuation study in Korea. Qual. Life Res. 2016;25:1845&#x2013;1852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26961008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohn S.I., Kim D.H., Lee M.Y., Cho Y.W. The reliability and validity of the Korean version of the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index. Sleep Breath. 2012;16:803&#x2013;812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21901299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck A.T., Ward C.H., Mendelson M., Mock J., Erbaugh J. An inventory for measuring depression. Arch. Gen. Psychiatr. 1961;4(6):561&#x2013;571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13688369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H., Kim S.R. Development of short form of the Korean version-the Boston Naming Test (K-BNT-15) based on item response theory. The Journal of the Korea Contents Association. 2013;13(12):321&#x2013;327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J.-H., Lee J.-K., Shin H.-K. Analysis of studies on bojungikgi-tang (Buzhongyiqi-tang) to establish the fundament for evidence based medicine (EBM) Korean Journal of Oriental Medicine. 2011;17(2):135&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam D. The effectiveness of Bojungikgi-tang and its modifications on chronic fatigue syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. The Journal of Korean Medicine. 2020;41(1):93&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satoh N., Sakai S., Kogure T., Tahara E., Origasa H., Shimada Y., et al. A randomized double blind placebo-controlled clinical trial of Hochuekkito, a traditional herbal medicine, in the treatment of elderly patients with weakness N of one and responder restricted design. Phytomedicine. 2005;12(8):549&#x2013;554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16121514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oka T. A patient who recovered from post-COVID myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a case report. Biopsychosoc. Med. 2023;17(1):8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9971667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36855180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee E.-S., Seo B.-I., Lee J.-U., Bae J.-S. The immunological activities of kyungohkgo and prescription of modified kyungohkgo. The Korea Journal of Herbology. 2002;17(2):95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y.A., Jin S.W., Kim S.M., Lee G.H., Kim S.J., Lee W.L., et al. Anti-fatigue effect of kyung-ok-ko. Korean J. Pharmacogn. 2016;47(3):258&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D.-G., Park W.-H., Cha Y.-Y. Effect of Kyungohkgo on aerobic capacity and anti-fatigue in high school soccer players. Journal of Physiology &amp; Pathology in Korean Medicine. 2011;25(5):934&#x2013;944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin B.Y., Lee Y.H., Kim D-h, Park C.S., Cho H.-J., Kim D.H., et al. Ameliorating effect of a herbal medicinal prescription, Kyung-Ok-Ko, on scopolamine-induced memory impairment in mice. J. Tradit. Med. 2009;26(1):35&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park M., Kim J.-S., Lee A., Roh S.-S., Kwon O., Seo Y.-B. Inhibition of inflammation by kyeongok-go with black ginseng in LPS-induced RAW 264.7 macrophages. The Korea Journal of Herbology. 2017;32(3):19&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K.-S., Kim G.-H., Kim H.-H., Seong B.-J., Kim S.-I., Han S.-H., et al. Qualities and anti-inflammatory activity of Kyungokgos sold in local markets. Journal of the Korean Society of Food Science and Nutrition. 2013;42(3):335&#x2013;341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang M., Lee M.J., Lee J.M., Bae C.-S., Kim S.-H., Ryu J.H., Cho I.-H. Oriental medicine Kyung-Ok-Ko prevents and alleviates dehydroepiandrosterone-induced polycystic ovarian syndrome in rats. PLoS One. 2014;9(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3919730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24520334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung I.-C., Lee S.-R., Lee J.-Y. Effects of ChenWhangBosimDan (CWBD) on inhibition of impairment of learning and memory, and acetylcholinesterase in amnesia mice. Journal of Oriental Neuropsychiatry. 2002;13(2):149&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim O.-S., Kim Y., Yoo S.-R., Lee M.-Y., Shin H.-K., Cheonwangbosimdan Jeong S-J. A traditional herbal formula, inhibits inflammatory responses through inactivation of NF-&#x3ba;B and induction of heme oxygenase-1 in raw264. 7 murine macrophages. Int. J. Clin. Exp. Med. 2016;9(2):1692&#x2013;1699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M.-J., Bose S., Shin N.-R., Park S., Kwon O., Song E.-J., et al. The herbal formula CWBSD improves sleep quality dependent on oral microbial type and tongue diagnostic features in insomnia. J. Personalized Med. 2021;11(5):325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8143156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S.-H., Kim J.-W., Kang C.-H., Whang W.-W. The effects of Chenwangbosim-dan and herbs on mouse neuroblastoma 2a cells damaged by hypoxia-reoxygenation. Journal of Oriental Neuropsychiatry. 2006;17(2):15&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim B., Jo C., Choi H.-Y., Lee K. Vasorelaxant and hypotensive effects of Cheonwangbosimdan in SD and SHR rats. Evid. base Compl. Alternative Med. 2018;2018(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6077565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30108659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi K.-W., Jung I.-C. The effects of Chenwhangbosindan (CBD) hot water extract &amp; ultra-fine powder on the Alzheimer's disease model. Journal of Oriental Neuropsychiatry. 2008;19(2):77&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung I.-C. Effects of Chenwhangbosim-dan and Sungsimjihwang-tang on protecting microglia and inhibiting acetylcholinesterase and oxidants. Journal of Physiology &amp; Pathology in Korean Medicine. 2008;22(1):120&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin S.-K., Yan S.-H., Lai J.-N., Tsai T.-H. Patterns of Chinese medicine use in prescriptions for treating Alzheimer's disease in Taiwan. Chin. Med. 2016;11:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4810525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27028311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>