<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39381125</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2233-7385</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Chonnam medical journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Chonnam Med J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigating the Role of Serotonin Levels in Cognitive Impairments Associated with Long COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>141</StartPage><EndPage>146</EndPage><MedlinePgn>141-146</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4068/cmj.2024.60.3.141</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to investigate the activation of the inflammation process, triggered as an immune response to combat the invasion by the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2). SARS-CoV-2 is a highly transmissible and pathogenic coronavirus that emerged in late 2019 and has caused a pandemic of acute respiratory disease, named 'coronavirus disease 2019' (COVID-19). Several mechanisms contribute to the reduction in serotonin levels, such as the impaired absorption of dietary tryptophan, hindered serotonin transport via platelets, and increased activity of an enzyme responsible for breaking down serotonin. Individuals seeking treatment for long COVID-19 had lower serotonin levels in their blood than those who had fully recovered from the infection. Furthermore, patients with long COVID-19 also had reduced tryptophan levels. The potential benefits of dietary supplementation with tryptophan or the use of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) to improve cognitive impairments and depressive and anxiety disorders in long-term COVID-19 patients. The findings support the immune response's pivotal role in modulating serotonin levels and further highlight the intricate connection between the immune system and neurotransmitter regulation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; Chonnam Medical Journal, 2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eslami</LastName><ForeName>Zahra</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Hamadan University of Medical Science, Hamadan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joshaghani</LastName><ForeName>Hamidreza</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory Sciences Research Center, Golestan University of Medical Sciences, Golestan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Chonnam Med J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101564659</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2233-7393</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immune System</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nervous System</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Serotonin</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>CONFLICT OF INTEREST STATEMENT: None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39381125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11458317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4068/cmj.2024.60.3.141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Coronaviridae Study Group of the International Committee on Taxonomy of Viruses. The species Severe acute respiratory syndrome-related coronavirus: classifying 2019-nCoV and naming it SARS-CoV-2. Nat Microbiol. 2020;5:536&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32123347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B, Guo H, Zhou P, Shi ZL. Characteristics of SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2021;19:141&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doernberg SB, Holubar M, Jain V, Weng Y, Lu D, Bollyky JB, et al. Incidence and prevalence of coronavirus disease 2019 within a healthcare worker cohort during the first year of the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 pandemic. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;75:1573&#x2013;1584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8992269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35279023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, Brown JS, Denneny EK, Hare SS, et al. &#x2018;Long-COVID&#x2019;: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang Y, Chen T, Mui D, Ferrari V, Jagasia D, Scherrer-Crosbie M, et al. Cardiovascular manifestations and treatment considerations in COVID-19. Heart. 2020;106:1132&#x2013;1141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32354800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salisbury R, Iotchkova V, Jaafar S, Morton J, Sangha G, Shah A, et al. Incidence of symptomatic, image-confirmed venous thromboembolism following hospitalization for COVID-19 with 90-day follow-up. Blood Adv. 2020;4:6230&#x2013;6239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7757009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33351117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sachdeva M, Gianotti R, Shah M, Bradanini L, Tosi D, Veraldi S, et al. Cutaneous manifestations of COVID-19: report of three cases and a review of literature. J Dermatol Sci. 2020;98:75&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7189855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32381430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacobellis G. COVID-19 and diabetes: can DPP4 inhibition play a role? Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2020;162:108125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32224164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins-Juarez SY, Qian L, King KL, Stevens JS, Husain SA, Radhakrishnan J, et al. Outcomes for patients with COVID-19 and acute kidney injury: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Kidney Int Rep. 2020;5:1149&#x2013;1160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7314696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32775814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, Rivera SC, McMullan C, Chandan JS, et al. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med. 2021;114:428&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullahi A, Candan SA, Abba MA, Bello AH, Alshehri MA, Afamefuna Victor E, et al. Neurological and musculoskeletal features of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Neurol. 2020;11:687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7333777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32676052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosleh H, Moradi F, Mehdizadeh M, Ajdary M, Moeinzadeh A, Shabani R. Health concerns regarding the effect of the COVID-19 pandemic on male fertility. Clin Exp Reprod Med. 2021;48:189&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8421655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34352169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodo TW, de Aquino MTP, Shimamoto A, Shanker A. Critical Neurotransmitters in the Neuroimmune Network. Front Immunol. 2020;11:1869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7472989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32973771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller SN, Sloan EK. Neuroimmune interactions at the crossroads of health and disease. Immunol Cell Biol. 2021;99:922&#x2013;923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34606127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider EM, Ma X, Stratz T, M&#xfc;ller W, Lorenz I, Seeling WD. Immunomodulatory function of the 5-HT3 receptor antagonist tropisetron. Scand J Rheumatol Suppl. 2004;119:34&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15515411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yassin A, Nawaiseh M, Shaban A, Alsherbini K, El-Salem K, Soudah O, et al. Neurological manifestations and complications of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Neurol. 2021;21:138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8007661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33784985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attademo L, Bernardini F. Are dopamine and serotonin involved in COVID-19 pathophysiology? Eur J Psychiatry. 2021;35:62&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7598536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33162632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian H, Hu Z, Xu J, Wang C. The molecular pathophysiology of depression and the new therapeutics. MedComm (2020) 2022;3:e156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9301929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35875370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen van Vuren E, Steyn SF, Brink CB, M&#xf6;ller M, Viljoen FP, Harvey BH. The neuropsychiatric manifestations of COVID-19: interactions with psychiatric illness and pharmacological treatment. Biomed Pharmacother. 2021;135:111200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33421734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothan HA, Stone S, Natekar J, Kumari P, Arora K, Kumar M. The FDA-approved gold drug auranofin inhibits novel coronavirus (SARS-COV-2) replication and attenuates inflammation in human cells. Virology. 2020;547:7&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choutka J, Jansari V, Hornig M, Iwasaki A. Unexplained postacute infection syndromes. Nat Med. 2022;28:911&#x2013;923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35585196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrottelli A, Sansone N, Giordano GM, Caporusso E, Giuliani L, Melillo A, et al. Cognitive impairment after post-acute COVID-19 infection: a systematic review of the literature. J Pers Med. 2022;12:2070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9781311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36556290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soria-Castro R, Meneses-Preza YG, Rodr&#xed;guez-L&#xf3;pez GM, Romero-Ram&#xed;rez S, Sosa-Hern&#xe1;ndez VA, Cervantes-D&#xed;az R, et al. Severe COVID-19 is marked by dysregulated serum levels of carboxypeptidase A3 and serotonin. J Leukoc Biol. 2021;110:425&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34057753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Zhang Z, Zhang Z, Wang Z, Li H. Cognitive impairment after long COVID-19: current evidence and perspectives. Front Neurol. 2023;14:1239182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10423939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37583958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakshi A, Tadi P. In: StatPearls. Ackley WB, Adolphe TS, Aeby TC, Aeddula NR, Agadi S, Agasthi P, et al., editors. Treasure Island: StatPearls Publishing; 2024. Biochemistry, serotonin.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32809691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong AC, Devason AS, Umana IC, Cox TO, Dohnalov&#xe1; L, Litichevskiy L, et al. Serotonin reduction in post-acute sequelae of viral infection. Cell. 2023;186:4851&#x2013;4867.e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11227373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37848036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer D, Camargo SM, Ramadan T, Sch&#xe4;fer M, Mariotta L, Herzog B, et al. Defective intestinal amino acid absorption in Ace2 null mice. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2012;303:G686&#x2013;G695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22790597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao K, Mu CL, Farzi A, Zhu WY. Tryptophan metabolism: a link between the gut microbiota and brain. Adv Nutr. 2020;11:709&#x2013;723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7231603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31825083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Mahony SM, Clarke G, Borre YE, Dinan TG, Cryan JF. Serotonin, tryptophan metabolism and the brain-gut-microbiome axis. Behav Brain Res. 2015;277:32&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25078296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nataf S. An alteration of the dopamine synthetic pathway is possibly involved in the pathophysiology of COVID-19. J Med Virol. 2020;92:1743&#x2013;1744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32246784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonini A, Leta V, Teo J, Chaudhuri KR. Outcome of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients affected by COVID-19. Mov Disord. 2020;35:905&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32347572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalefah MM, Khalifah AM. Determining the relationship between SARS-CoV-2 infection, dopamine, and COVID-19 complications. J Taibah Univ Med Sci. 2020;15:550&#x2013;553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7646371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33173452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson G, Reiter RJ. Melatonin: roles in influenza, COVID-19, and other viral infections. Rev Med Virol. 2020;30:e2109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7235470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32314850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sette A, Crotty S. Adaptive immunity to SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19. Cell. 2021;184:861&#x2013;880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7803150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultze JL, Aschenbrenner AC. COVID-19 and the human innate immune system. Cell. 2021;184:1671&#x2013;1692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7885626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33743212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clo&#xeb;z-Tayarani I, Petit-Bertron AF, Venters HD, Cavaillon JM. Differential effect of serotonin on cytokine production in lipopolysaccharide-stimulated human peripheral blood mononuclear cells: involvement of 5-hydroxytryptamine2A receptors. Int Immunol. 2003;15:233&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12578853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller AH, Raison CL. The role of inflammation in depression: from evolutionary imperative to modern treatment target. Nat Rev Immunol. 2016;16:22&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5542678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26711676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musselman DL, Lawson DH, Gumnick JF, Manatunga AK, Penna S, Goodkin RS, et al. Paroxetine for the prevention of depression induced by high-dose interferon alfa. N Engl J Med. 2001;344:961&#x2013;966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11274622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller AH, Haroon E, Raison CL, Felger JC. Cytokine targets in the brain: impact on neurotransmitters and neurocircuits. Depress Anxiety. 2013;30:297&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4141874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23468190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanova M, Kohout P. Serotonin-its synthesis and roles in the healthy and the critically Ill. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:4837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8124334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34063611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orrico-Sanchez A, Guiard BP, Manta S, Callebert J, Launay JM, Louis F, et al. Organic cation transporter 2 contributes to SSRI antidepressant efficacy by controlling tryptophan availability in the brain. Transl Psychiatry. 2023;13:302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10542329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37775532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Ho CS, McIntyre RS, Wang W, Ho RC. Effects of vortioxetine and fluoxetine on the level of Brain Derived Neurotrophic Factors (BDNF) in the hippocampus of chronic unpredictable mild stress-induced depressive rats. Brain Res Bull. 2018;142:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29933036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xfc;fner K, Vedova S, Tymoszuk P, Nelles P, Bruckner T, Deisenhammer EA, et al. The effect of inflammation, SARS-CoV-2 infection, age and mental health on serotonin, and kynurenine and catecholamine pathway metabolites. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2023;156:106334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37481962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badawy AA. Kynurenine pathway of tryptophan metabolism: regulatory and functional aspects. Int J Tryptophan Res. 2017;10:1178646917691938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5398323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28469468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas T, Stefanoni D, Reisz JA, Nemkov T, Bertolone L, Francis RO, et al. COVID-19 infection alters kynurenine and fatty acid metabolism, correlating with IL-6 levels and renal status. JCI Insight. 2020;5:e140327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7453907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32559180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Wu Z, Lu Y, Lu W, Su G, Zhou Z. Effects of phototherapy on biopterin, neopterin, tryptophan, and behavioral neuroinflammatory reaction in patients with post-stroke depression. Sci Rep. 2024;14:18368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11306333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39112627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebbrecht K, Skorobogatov K, Giltay EJ, Coppens V, De Picker L, Morrens M. Tryptophan catabolites in bipolar disorder: a meta-analysis. Front Immunol. 2021;12:667179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8170319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34093561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nettis MA, Lombardo G, Hastings C, Zajkowska Z, Mariani N, Nikkheslat N, et al. The interaction between kynurenine pathway, suicidal ideation and augmentation therapy with minocycline in patients with treatment-resistant depression. J Psychopharmacol. 2023;37:531&#x2013;538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10291376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37183855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramkissoon R, Wang XJ. The impact of COVID-19 in gastroenterology and hepatology. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2021;55:757&#x2013;765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34420001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eteraf-Oskouei T, Najafi M. The relationship between the serotonergic system and COVID-19 disease: a review. Heliyon. 2022;8:e09544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35652122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>