<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37646620</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-751X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cardiopulmonary rehabilitation and prevention</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Characteristics and Treatment of Exercise Intolerance in Patients With Long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>400</StartPage><EndPage>406</EndPage><MedlinePgn>400-406</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HCR.0000000000000821</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The post-acute sequalae of SARS-CoV-2, also known as "Long COVID," is characterized by profound fatigue, impaired functional capacity with post-exertional malaise, orthostatic intolerance, and tachycardia. At least 25-30% of individuals impacted by SARS-CoV-2 will go on to experience the Long COVID syndrome, underscoring the detrimental impact this condition has on society. Although efforts are underway to further understand risk factors for Long COVID and identify strategies to prevent disease development entirely, implementation of treatment strategies is warranted to alleviate symptom burden among those affected. This review provides a rationale for exercise prescriptions tailored to the Long COVID patient based on the pathophysiology underlying this syndrome, as well as the previously demonstrated benefits of exercise training in other similar populations whose clinical manifestations result from cardiac deconditioning. Herein, we discuss methods to tailor exercise protocols, accommodating exercise intolerance and post-exertional malaise that may otherwise limit the ability to participate in a training protocol, as well as data demonstrating that a focused exercise prescription may effectively alleviate symptom burden in these patients. Long COVID results, in large part, from deconditioning, which may result from as little as 20 hr of inactivity. Exercise prescriptions tailored to patients with Long COVID may effectively alleviate symptom burden associated with this condition and in the absence of overt contraindications should be considered in management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Edward</LastName><ForeName>Justin A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine-Cardiology (Drs Edward, Rudofker, Shamapant, Parker, Cotter, and Cornwell and Ms Sabin) and Clinical Translational Research Center (Dr Cornwell), University of Colorado Anschutz Medical Campus, Aurora; Department of Medicine, Division of Cardiology, Parkview Medical Center, Pueblo, Colorado (Dr Peruri); and Department of Sport Science, Division of Physiology, University of Innsbruck, Innsbruck, Austria (Dr Lawley).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peruri</LastName><ForeName>Adithya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rudofker</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shamapant</LastName><ForeName>Nikhil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parker</LastName><ForeName>Hugh</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cotter</LastName><ForeName>Ryan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sabin</LastName><ForeName>Katherine</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lawley</LastName><ForeName>Justin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cornwell</LastName><ForeName>William K</ForeName><Initials>WK</Initials><Suffix>3rd</Suffix></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K23 HL132048</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101291247</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-7501</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37646620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HCR.0000000000000821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01273116-990000000-00109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard. https://covid19.who.int/ . Accessed January 3 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smer A, Squires RW, Bonikowske AR, Allison TG, Mainville RN, Williams MA. Cardiac complications of COVID-19 infection and the role of physical activity. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2023;43(1):8&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logue JK, Franko NM, McCulloch DJ, et al. Sequelae in adults at 6 months after COVID-19 infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(2):e210830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Long COVID or post-COVID conditions. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html . Accessed Jan 3 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gluckman TJ, Bhave NM, Allen LA, et al. 2022 ACC expert consensus decision pathway on cardiovascular sequelae of COVID-19 in adults: myocarditis and other myocardial involvement, post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection, and return to play. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79(17):1717&#x2013;1756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal SM, Landers DB, Hollenberg SM, et al. Prospective evaluation of autonomic dysfunction in post-acute sequela of COVID-19. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79(23):2325&#x2013;2330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaffney FA, Nixon JV, Karlsson ES, Campbell W, Dowdey ABC, Blomqvist CG. Cardiovascular deconditioning produced by 20 hours of bedrest with head-down tilt (-5 degrees) in middle-aged healthy men. Am J Cardiol. 1985;56:634&#x2013;638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nixon JV, Murray G, Bryant C, et al. Early cardiovascular adaptation to simulated zero gravity. J Appl Physiol. 1979;46(3):541&#x2013;548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomqvist CG, Nixon JV, Johnson RL, MItchell JH. Early cardiovascular adaptation to zero gravity simulated by head-down tilt. Acta Astronaut. 1980;7:543&#x2013;553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saltin B, Blomqvist G, Mitchell JH, Johnson RL, Wildenthal K, Chapman CB. Response to exercise after bed rest and after training. Circulation. 1968;38(suppl 5):VII1&#x2013;VII78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire DK, Levine BD, Williamson JW, et al. A 30-year follow-up of the Dallas Bed Rest and Training Study: I. Effect of age on the cardiovascular response to exercise. Circulation. 2001;104(2):1350&#x2013;1357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire DK, Levine BD, Williamson JW, et al. A 30-year follow-up of the Dallas Bed Rest and Training Study II. Effect of age on cardiovascular adaptation to exercise training. Circulation. 2001;104(12):1358&#x2013;1366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JH, Levine BD, McGuire DK. The Dallas Bed Rest and Training Study: revisited after 50 years. Circulation. 2019;140(16):1293&#x2013;1295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ormiston CK, Swiatkiewicz I, Taub PR. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome as a sequela of COVID-19. Heart Rhythm. 2022;19(11):1880&#x2013;1889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine BD, Pawelczyk JA, Ertl AC, et al. Human muscle sympathetic neural and haemodynamic responses to tilt following spaceflight. J Physiol. 2002;538(pt 1):331&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo C, Ridolfi L, Scarsoglio S. Cardiovascular deconditioning during long-term spaceflight through multiscale modeling. NPJ Microgravity. 2020;6:27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen NW, Stiles LE, Miglis MG. Preparing for the long-haul: autonomic complications of COVID-19. Auton Neurosci. 2021;235:102841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benarroch EE. &#x201c;Dysautonomia&#x201d;: a plea for precision. Clin Auton Res. 2021;31(1):27&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudofker E, Parker H, Cornwell WK III. An exercise prescription as a novel management strategy for treatment of Long COVID. JACC Case Rep. 2022;4(20):1344&#x2013;1347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao P, Peritz DC, Systrom D, Lewine K, Cornwell WK III, Hsu JJ. Orthostatic and exercise intolerance in recreational and competitive athletes with Long COVID. JACC Case Rep. 2022;4(17):1119&#x2013;1123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryarly M, Phillips LT, Fu Q, Vernino S, Levine BD. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome: JACC focus seminar. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;73(10):1207&#x2013;1228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Q, Vangundy TB, Shibata S, Auchus RJ, Williams GH, Levine BD. Exercise training versus propranolol in the treatment of the postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. Hypertension. 2011;58(2):167&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckey JC Jr, Lane LD, Levine BD, et al. Orthostatic intolerance after spaceflight. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1996;81(1):7&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes DC, Orchard JW, Partridge EM, La Gerche A, Broderick C. Return to exercise post-COVID-19 infection: a pragmatic approach in mid-2022. J Sci Med Sport. 2022;25(7):544&#x2013;547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salman D, Vishnubala D, Le Feuvre P, et al. Returning to physical activity after Covid-19. BMJ. 2021;372:m4721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teo WP, Goodwill AM. Can exercise attenuate the negative effects of long COVID syndrome on brain health? Front Immunol. 2022;13:986950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapleau MW, Heesch CM, Abboud FM. Prevention or attenuation of baroreceptor resetting by pulsatility during elevated pressure. Hypertension. 1987;9(6, pt 2):III137&#x2013;III141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapleau MW, Abboud FM. Contrasting effects of static and pulsatile pressure on carotid baroreceptor activity in dogs [published erratum appears in Circ Res . 1988;63(1):272]. Circ Res. 1987;61(5):648&#x2013;658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajduczok G, Chapleau MW, Abboud FM. Rheoreceptors in the carotid sinus of dog. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1988;85(19):7399&#x2013;7403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapleau MW, Hajduczok G, Abboud FM. Pulsatile activation of baroreceptors causes central facilitation of baroreflex. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 1989;256(6, pt 2):H1735&#x2013;H1741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapleau MW, Abboud FM. Determinants of sensitization of carotid baroreceptors by pulsatile pressure in dogs. Circ Res. 1989;65(3):566&#x2013;577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamotte G, Coon EA, Suarez MD, et al. Standardized autonomic testing in patients with probable radiation-induced afferent baroreflex failure. Hypertension. 2022;79(1):50&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sailer C, Edelmann H, Buchanan C, et al. Impairments in blood pressure regulation and cardiac baroreceptor sensitivity among patients with heart failure supported with continuous-flow left ventricular assist devices. Circ Heart Fail. 2021;14(1):e007448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheshire WP, Freeman R, Gibbons CH, et al. Electrodiagnostic assessment of the autonomic nervous system: a consensus statement endorsed by the American Autonomic Society, American Academy of Neurology, and the International Federation of Clinical Neurophysiology. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132(2):666&#x2013;682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Q, Vangundy TB, Galbreath MM, et al. Cardiac origins of the postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2010;55(25):2858&#x2013;2868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes LD, Ingram J, Sculthorpe NF. More than 100 persistent symptoms of SARS-CoV-2 (Long COVID): a scoping review. Front Med (Lausanne). 2021;8:750378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naeije R, Caravita S. Phenotyping long COVID. Eur Respir J. 2021;58(2):2101763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durstenfeld MS, Sun K, Tahir P, et al. Use of cardiopulmonary exercise testing to evaluate Long COVID-19 symptoms in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(10):e2236057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancini DM, Brunjes DL, Lala A, Trivieri MG, Contreras JP, Natelson BH. Use of cardiopulmonary stress testing for patients with unexplained dyspnea post&#x2013;coronavirus disease. JACC Heart Fail. 2021;9(12):927&#x2013;937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arena R, Myers J, Harber M, et al. The V&#x2d9;E/V&#x2d9;CO 2 slope during maximal treadmill cardiopulmonary exercise testing: reference standards from friend (fitness registry and the importance of exercise: a national database). J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2021;41(3):194&#x2013;198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldo RF, Mondoni M, Parazzini EM, et al. Deconditioning as main mechanism of impaired exercise response in COVID-19 survivors. Eur Respir J. 2021;58(2):2100870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skjorten I, Ankerstjerne OAW, Trebinjac D, et al. Cardiopulmonary exercise capacity and limitations 3 months after COVID-19 hospitalisation. Eur Resp J. 2021;58(2):2100996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aparisi A, Ybarra-Falcon C, Garcia-Gomez M, et al. Exercise ventilatory inefficiency in post-COVID-19 syndrome: insights from a prospective evaluation. J Clin Med. 2021;10(12):2591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guntur VP, Nemkov T, de Boer E, et al. Signatures of mitochondrial dysfunction and impaired fatty acid metabolism in plasma of patients with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC). Metabolites. 2022;12(11):1026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aschman T, Wyler E, Baum O, et al. Post-COVID syndrome is associated with capillary alterations, macrophage infiltration and distinct transcriptomic signatures in skeletal muscles. MedRxiv. 2023. doi:10.1101/2023.02.15.23285584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine BD, Zuckerman JH, Pawelczyk JA. Cardiac atrophy after bed-rest deconditioing. A Nonneural mechanism for orthostatic intolerance. Circulation. 1997;96(2):517&#x2013;525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P, et al. Autonomic dysfunction in &#x201c;long COVID&#x201d;: rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin Med (Lond). 2021;21(1):e63&#x2013;e67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maggioni MA, Castiglioni P, Merati G, et al. High-intensity exercise mitigates cardiovascular deconditioning during long-duration bed rest. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastings JL, Krainski F, Snell PG, et al. Effect of rowing ergometry and oral volume loading on cardiovascular structure and function during bed rest. J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(10):1735&#x2013;1743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murthy G, Watenpaugh DE, Ballard RE, Hargens AR. Exercise against lower body negative pressure as a countermeasure for cardiovascular and musculoskeletal deconditioning. Acta Astronaut. 1994;33:89&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadegiani FA, Kater CE. Enhancement of hypothalamic-pituitary activity in male athletes: evidence of a novel hormonal mechanism of physical conditioning. BMC Endocr Disord. 2019;19(1):117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mtinangi BL, Hainsworth R. Effects of moderate exercise training on plasma volume, baroreceptor sensitivity and orthostatic tolerance in healthy subjects. Exp Physiol. 1999;84(1):121&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairbank R. Proposed Long COVID exercise trials raise alarm. Nature. 2023;616(7956):228&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine BD, Baggish AL, Kovacs RJ, et al. Eligibility and disqualification recommendations for competitive athletes with cardiovascular abnormalities: task force 1: classification of sports: dynamic, static, and impact: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association and American College of Cardiology. Circulation. 2015;132(22):e262&#x2013;e266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JH, Haskell W, Snell P, Van Camp SP. Task force 8: classification of sports. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005;45(8):1364&#x2013;1367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelliccia A, Maron BJ, Spataro A, Proschan MA, Spirito P. The upper limit of physiologic cardiac hypertrophy in highly trained elite athletes. New Engl J Med. 1991;324(5):295&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelliccia A, Culasso F, Di Paolo FM, Maron BJ. Physiologic left ventricular cavity dilatation in elite athletes. Ann Intern Med. 1999;130(1):23&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volianitis S, Yoshiga CC, Nissen P, Secher NH. Effect of fitness on arm vascular and metabolic responses to upper body exercise. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2004;286(5):H1736&#x2013;H1741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walther G, Nottin S, Karpoff L, Perez-Martin A, Dauzat M, Obert P. Flow-mediated dilation and exercise-induced hyperaemia in highly trained athletes: comparison of the upper and lower limb vasculature. Acta Physiol (Oxf). 2008;193(2):139&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maron BJ, Pelliccia A. The heart of trained athletes: cardiac remodeling and the risks of sports, including sudden death. Circulation. 2006;114(15):1633&#x2013;1644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JH, Haskell WL, Raven PB. Classification of sports. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1994;24(4):864&#x2013;866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edward JA, Cornwell WK III. Impact of exercise on cerebrovascular physiology and risk of stroke. Stroke. 2022;53(7):2404&#x2013;2410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krainski F, Hastings JL, Heinicke K, et al. The effect of rowing ergometry and resistive exercise on skeletal muscle structure and function during bed rest. J Appl Physiol. 2014;116(12):1569&#x2013;1581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nopp S, Moik F, Klok FA, et al. Outpatient pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with Long COVID improves exercise capacity, functional status, dyspnea, fatigue, and quality of life. Respiration. 2022;101(6):593&#x2013;601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almazan A, Franco-Lopez F, Buendia-Romero A, et al. Rehabilitation for post-COVID-19 condition through a supervised exercise intervention: A randomized controlled trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32(12):1791&#x2013;1801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almazan A, Buendia-Romero A, Martinez-Cava A, et al. Effects of a concurrent training, respiratory muscle exercise, and self-management recommendations on recovery from post-COVID-19 conditions: the RECOVE trial. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2023;134(1):95&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araujo BTS, Barros A, Nunes DTX, et al. Effects of continuous aerobic training associated with resistance training on maximal and submaximal exercise tolerance, fatigue, and quality of life of patients post-COVID-19. Physiother Res Int. 2023;28(1):e1972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krainski F, Hastings JL, Heinicke K, et al. The effect of rowing ergometry and resistive exercise on skeletal muscle structure and function during bed rest. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2014;116(12):1569&#x2013;1581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Are EB, Song Y, Stockdale JE, Tupper P, Colijn C. COVID-19 endgame: From pandemic to endemic? Vaccination, reopening and evolution in low- and high-vaccinated populations. J Theor Biol. 2023;559:111368.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>