<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39240511</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-7403</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pituitary</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pituitary</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID and pituitary dysfunctions: a bidirectional relationship?</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11102-024-01442-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long COVID is a novel emerging syndrome known to affect multiple health areas in patients previously infected by SARS-CoV-2 markedly impairing their quality of life. The pathophysiology of Long COVID is still largely poorly understood and multiple mechanisms were proposed to underlie its occurrence, including alterations in the hormonal hypothalamic-pituitary axes. Aim of this review is to present and discuss the potential negative implications of these hormonal dysfunctions in promoting and influencing the Long COVID syndrome. To date, the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis is the mostly investigated and several studies have reported a prolonged impairment leading to mild and subclinical forms of central adrenal insufficiency. Few data are also available regarding central hypogonadism, central hypothyroidism and growth hormone&#xa0;(GH) deficiency. A high prevalence of central hypogonadism in COVID-19 survivors several months after recovery was consistently reported in different cohorts. Conversely, very few data are available on the hypothalamic-pituitary-thyroid axis function that was mainly shown to be preserved in COVID-19 survivors. Finally, a potential impairment of the hypothalamic-GH axis in Long COVID has also been reported. These data altogether may suggest a novel possible pituitary-centred pathophysiological view of Long COVID syndrome which if confirmed by large clinical studies may have relevant implication for the diagnostic and therapeutic approach at least in a subset of patients with the syndrome.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>di Filippo</LastName><ForeName>Luigi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-6117-0081</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Endocrine and Metabolic Sciences, San Raffaele Vita-Salute University and IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Via Olgettina 60, Milan, 20132, Italy. difilippo.luigi@hsr.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Franzese</LastName><ForeName>Vincenzo</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Endocrine and Metabolic Sciences, San Raffaele Vita-Salute University and IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Via Olgettina 60, Milan, 20132, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santoro</LastName><ForeName>Simona</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Endocrine and Metabolic Sciences, San Raffaele Vita-Salute University and IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Via Olgettina 60, Milan, 20132, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Doga</LastName><ForeName>Mauro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Endocrine and Metabolic Sciences, San Raffaele Vita-Salute University and IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Via Olgettina 60, Milan, 20132, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giustina</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Endocrine and Metabolic Sciences, San Raffaele Vita-Salute University and IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Via Olgettina 60, Milan, 20132, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pituitary</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9814578</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1386-341X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adrenal insufficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Growth hormone deficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypogonadism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypopituitarism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pituitary</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39240511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11102-024-01442-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11102-024-01442-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 cases | WHO COVID-19 dashboard Accessed: Jul. 09, 2024. [Online]. Available: https://data.who.int/dashboards/covid19/cases?n=c</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A et al (2020) Extrapulmonary manifestations of COVID-19. Nat Med 26(7):1017&#x2013;1032. https://doi.org/10.1038/S41591-020-0968-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustina A, Bilezikian JP (2022) Revisiting the endocrine and metabolic manifestations of COVID-19 two years into the pandemic. Rev Endocr Metab Disord 23(2):133&#x2013;136. https://doi.org/10.1007/S11154-022-09716-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puig-Domingo M, Marazuela M, Yildiz BO, Giustina A (2021) COVID-19 and endocrine and metabolic diseases. An updated statement from the European Society of Endocrinology. Endocrine 72(2):301&#x2013;316. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-021-02734-W</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marazuela M, Giustina A, Puig-Domingo M (2020) Endocrine and metabolic aspects of the COVID-19 pandemic. Rev Endocr Metab Disord 21(4):495&#x2013;507. https://doi.org/10.1007/S11154-020-09569-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puig-Domingo M, Marazuela M, Giustina A (2020) COVID-19 and endocrine diseases. A statement from the European Society of Endocrinology. Endocrine 68(1):2&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-020-02294-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lorenzo R et al (2023) Longitudinal changes in physical function and their impact on Health outcomes in COVID-19 patients. Nutrients 15(20). https://doi.org/10.3390/NU15204474</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L, Frara S, Doga M, Giustina A (2022) The osteo-metabolic phenotype of COVID-19: an update. Endocrine 78(2):247&#x2013;254. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-022-03135-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L et al (2022) Vertebral fractures at hospitalization predict impaired respiratory function during follow-up of COVID-19 survivors. Endocrine 77(2):392&#x2013;400. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-022-03096-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L et al (2021) Hypocalcemia in COVID-19 is associated with low vitamin D levels and impaired compensatory PTH response. Endocrine 74(2):219&#x2013;225. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-021-02882-Z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L, Frara S, Giustina A (2021) The emerging osteo-metabolic phenotype of COVID-19: clinical and pathophysiological aspects. Nat Rev Endocrinol 17(8):445&#x2013;446. https://doi.org/10.1038/S41574-021-00516-Y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L, Doga M, Frara S, Giustina A (2022) Hypocalcemia in COVID-19: prevalence, clinical significance and therapeutic implications. Rev Endocr Metab Disord 23(2):299&#x2013;308. https://doi.org/10.1007/S11154-021-09655-Z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L et al (2021) Hypocalcemia is a distinctive biochemical feature of hospitalized COVID-19 patients. Endocrine 71(1):9&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-020-02541-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Filippo L, Formenti AM, Doga M, Pedone E, Rovere-Querini P, Giustina A (2021) Radiological thoracic vertebral fractures are highly prevalent in COVID-19 and predict Disease outcomes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 106(2):E602&#x2013;E614. https://doi.org/10.1210/CLINEM/DGAA738</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L, Formenti AM, Giustina A (2020) Hypocalcemia: the quest for the cause of a major biochemical feature of COVID-19. Endocrine 70(3):463&#x2013;464. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-020-02525-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Filippo L et al (2020) Hypocalcemia is highly prevalent and predicts hospitalization in patients with COVID-19. Endocrine 68(3):475&#x2013;478. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-020-02383-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frara S, Allora A, Castellino L, di Filippo L, Loli P, Giustina A (2021) COVID-19 and the pituitary. Pituitary 24(3):465&#x2013;481. https://doi.org/10.1007/S11102-021-01148-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frara S et al (2022) COVID-19 and hypopituitarism. Rev Endocr Metab Disord 23(2):215&#x2013;231. https://doi.org/10.1007/S11154-021-09672-Y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustina A, Legg E, Cesana BM, Frara S, Mortini P, Fleseriu M (2021) Results from ACROCOVID: an international survey on the care of acromegaly during the COVID-19 era. Endocrine 71(2):273&#x2013;280. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-020-02565-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capatina C, Poiana C, Fleseriu M (2023) Pituitary and SARS CoV-2: an unremitting conundrum. Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab 37(4). https://doi.org/10.1016/J.BEEM.2023.101752</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han T, Kang J, Li G, Ge J, Gu J (2020) Analysis of 2019-nCoV receptor ACE2 expression in different tissues and its significance study. Ann Transl Med 8(17):1077. https://doi.org/10.21037/ATM-20-4281</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y et al (2004) Organ distribution of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) associated coronavirus (SARS-CoV) in SARS patients: implications for pathogenesis and virus transmission pathways. J Pathol 203(2):622&#x2013;630. https://doi.org/10.1002/PATH.1560</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khadke S et al (2020) Harnessing the immune system to overcome cytokine storm and reduce viral load in COVID-19: a review of the phases of illness and therapeutic agents. Virol J 17(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/S12985-020-01415-W</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azkur AK et al (2020) Immune response to SARS-CoV-2 and mechanisms of immunopathological changes in COVID-19. Allergy 75(7):1564&#x2013;1581. https://doi.org/10.1111/ALL.14364</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troshina E, Melnichenko G, Senyushkina E, Mokrysheva N (2020) Adaptation of the hypothalamo-pituitary-thyroid and hypothalamo-pituitary-adrenal systems to a new infectious disease - COVID-19 in the development of COVID-19 pneumonia and/or cytokine storm. Clin Exp Thyroidol 16(1):21&#x2013;27. https://doi.org/10.14341/KET12461</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonetto V et al (2022) Markers of blood-brain barrier disruption increase early and persistently in COVID-19 patients with neurological manifestations. Front Immunol 13. https://doi.org/10.3389/FIMMU.2022.1070379</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-De-las-pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Florencio LL (2021) Defining post-COVID symptoms (post-, acute COVID, long COVID Persistent Post-COVID): an integrative classification. Int J Environ Res Public Health 18(5):1&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.3390/IJERPH18052621</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Taylor S (2020) NICE guideline on long covid. BMJ 371. https://doi.org/10.1136/BMJ.M4938</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overview | COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19 | Guidance | NICE [Online]. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188 . Accessed 09 Jul 2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarte KI et al (2022) Age, sex and previous comorbidities as risk factors not Associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection for long COVID-19: a systematic review and Meta-analysis. J Clin Med 11(24). https://doi.org/10.3390/JCM11247314</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maglietta G et al (2022) Prognostic factors for Post-COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review and Meta-analysis. J Clin Med 11(6). https://doi.org/10.3390/JCM11061541/S1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pintos-Pascual I et al (2022) Is SARS-CoV-2 the only cause of long-COVID? AIDS Rev 24(4):183&#x2013;196. https://doi.org/10.24875/AIDSREV.22000025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24875/AIDSREV.22000025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36427058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boaventura P, Macedo S, Ribeiro F, Jaconiano S, Soares P (2022) Post-COVID-19 condition: where are we now? Life (Basel) 12(4). https://doi.org/10.3390/LIFE12040517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustina A (2021) Hypovitaminosis D and the endocrine phenotype of COVID-19. Endocrine 72(1). https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-021-02671-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilezikian JP et al (2020) Mechanisms in endocrinology: vitamin D and COVID-19. Eur J Endocrinol 183(5):R133&#x2013;R147. https://doi.org/10.1530/EJE-20-0665</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustina A et al (2024) Consensus statement on vitamin D status assessment and supplementation: whys, whens, and hows. Endocr Rev. https://doi.org/10.1210/ENDREV/BNAE009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/ENDREV/BNAE009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Filippo L et al (2022) Vitamin D levels are associated with blood glucose and BMI in COVID-19 patients, predicting disease severity. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 107(1):E348&#x2013;E360. https://doi.org/10.1210/CLINEM/DGAB599</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L, Uygur M, Locatelli M, Nannipieri F, Frara S, Giustina A (2023) Low vitamin D levels predict outcomes of COVID-19 in patients with both severe and non-severe disease at hospitalization. Endocrine 80(3):669&#x2013;683. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-023-03331-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilezikian JP et al (2023) Consensus and controversial aspects of vitamin D and COVID-19. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 108(5):1034&#x2013;1042. https://doi.org/10.1210/CLINEM/DGAC719</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L (2023) Lack of vitamin D predicts impaired long-term immune response to COVID-19 vaccination. Endocrine 82(3):536&#x2013;541. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-023-03481-W</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L et al (2023) Low vitamin D levels are associated with long COVID syndrome in COVID-19 survivors. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 108(10):e1106&#x2013;e1116. https://doi.org/10.1210/CLINEM/DGAD207</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L, Frara S, Giustina A (2023) Response to the letter to the editor from Min et al: low vitamin D levels are associated with long COVID syndrome in COVID-19 survivors. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 109(1):E438&#x2013;E439. https://doi.org/10.1210/CLINEM/DGAD327</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L et al (2020) Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS ONE 15(11). https://doi.org/10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0240784</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isidori AM, Minnetti M, Sbardella E, Graziadio C, Grossman AB (2015) Mechanisms in endocrinology: the spectrum of haemostatic abnormalities in glucocorticoid excess and defect. Eur J Endocrinol 173(3):R101&#x2013;R113. https://doi.org/10.1530/EJE-15-0308</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiovato L, Magri F, Carl&#xe9; A (2019) Hypothyroidism in context: where we&#x2019;ve been and where we&#x2019;re going. Adv Ther 36(Suppl 2):47&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12325-019-01080-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doga M, Bonadonna S, Gola M, Mazziotti G, Giustina A (2006) Growth hormone deficiency in the adult. Pituitary 9(4):305&#x2013;311. https://doi.org/10.1007/S11102-006-0410-Y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampshire A et al (2021) Cognitive deficits in people who have recovered from COVID-19. EClinicalMedicine 39. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.ECLINM.2021.101044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y et al (2022) Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell 185(5):881&#x2013;895. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.CELL.2022.01.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ (2021) 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry 8(5):416&#x2013;427. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00084-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Perez O et al (2022) Male pituitary-gonadal axis dysfunction in post-acute COVID-19 syndrome-Prevalence and associated factors: a mediterranean case series. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 96(3):353&#x2013;362. https://doi.org/10.1111/CEN.14537</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salonia A et al (2022) Testosterone in males with COVID-19: a 7-month cohort study. Andrology 10(1):34&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1111/ANDR.13097</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiloiro S et al (2019) The changing clinical spectrum of Hypophysitis. Trends Endocrinol Metab 30(9):590&#x2013;602. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.TEM.2019.06.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazziotti G, et al (2017) Management of endocrine disease: risk of overtreatment in patients with adrenal insufficiency: current and emerging aspects. Eur J Endocrinol 177(5):R231&#x2013;R248. https://doi.org/10.1530/EJE-17-0154</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leow MKS, Kwek DSK, Ng AWK, Ong KC, Kaw GJL, Lee LSU (2005) Hypocortisolism in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS). Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 63(2):197&#x2013;202. https://doi.org/10.1111/J.1365-2265.2005.02325.X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheatland R (2004) Molecular mimicry of ACTH in SARS - implications for corticosteroid treatment and prophylaxis. Med Hypotheses 63(5):855&#x2013;862. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mehy.2004.04.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mehy.2004.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15488660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7126000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei L et al (2010) Endocrine cells of the adenohypophysis in severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS). Biochem Cell Biol 88(4):723&#x2013;730. https://doi.org/10.1139/O10-022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/O10-022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20651845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Torres D, D&#xed;az-Rodr&#xed;guez C, Armentia-Medina A (2022) Anti-ACTH antibodies in critically ill Covid-19 patients: a potential immune evasion mechanism of SARS-CoV-2. Med Intensiva 46(8):472&#x2013;474. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.MEDINE.2021.09.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonen MS et al (2022) Assessment of neuroendocrine changes and hypothalamo-pituitary autoimmunity in patients with COVID-19. Horm Metab Res 54(3):153&#x2013;161. https://doi.org/10.1055/A-1764-1260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taieb A, Nassim BHS, Asma G, Jabeur M, Ghada S, Asma BA (2024) The Growing understanding of the pituitary implication in the pathogenesis of long COVID-19 syndrome: a narrative review. Adv Respir Med 92(1):96&#x2013;109. https://doi.org/10.3390/ARM92010013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke SA et al (2021) Normal adrenal and thyroid function in patients who survive COVID-19 infection. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 106(8):2208&#x2013;2220. https://doi.org/10.1210/CLINEM/DGAB349</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urhan E, Karaca Z, Unuvar GK, Gundogan K, Unluhizarci K (2022) Investigation of pituitary functions after acute coronavirus disease 2019. Endocr J 69(6):649&#x2013;658. https://doi.org/10.1507/ENDOCRJ.EJ21-0531</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1507/ENDOCRJ.EJ21-0531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34987144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramesh J (2023) Evaluation of the hypothalamo-pituitary-adrenal axis during the post-COVID-19 period in patients treated with steroids during the illness. Arch Endocrinol Metab 68:e220207. https://doi.org/10.20945/2359-4292-2022-0207</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashmi KG et al (2023) Hypothalamic-pituitary adrenal Axis Status 3 months after recovery from COVID-19 infection. Endocr Res 48(4):85&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1080/07435800.2023.2245907</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07435800.2023.2245907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J et al (2023) Distinguishing features of long COVID identified through immune profiling. Nature 623(7985):139&#x2013;148. https://doi.org/10.1038/S41586-023-06651-Y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ach T et al (2024) Explaining long COVID: a pioneer cross-sectional study supporting the endocrine hypothesis. J Endocr Soc 8(3). https://doi.org/10.1210/JENDSO/BVAE003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller-Wood ME, Dallman MF (1984) Corticosteroid inhibition of ACTH secretion. Endocr Rev 5(1):1&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1210/EDRV-5-1-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/EDRV-5-1-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6323158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shipston MJ (2022) Glucocorticoid action in the anterior pituitary gland: insights from corticotroph physiology. Curr Opin Endocr Metab Res 25. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.COEMR.2022.100358</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaranta VN et al (2023) The predictors of long COVID in Southeastern Italy. J Clin Med 12(19). https://doi.org/10.3390/JCM12196303</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davelaar J, Jessurun N, Schaap G, Bode C, Vonkeman H (2023) The effect of corticosteroids, antibiotics, and anticoagulants on the development of post-COVID-19 syndrome in COVID-19 hospitalized patients 6 months after discharge: a retrospective follow up study, Clin Exp Med 23(8):4881&#x2013;4888. https://doi.org/10.1007/S10238-023-01153-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beuschlein F (2024) European Society of Endocrinology and Endocrine Society Joint Clinical guideline: diagnosis and therapy of glucocorticoid-induced adrenal insufficiency. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 109(7):1657&#x2013;1683. https://doi.org/10.1210/CLINEM/DGAE250</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou R et al (2020) Euthyroid sick syndrome in patients with COVID-19. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 11. https://doi.org/10.3389/FENDO.2020.566439</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brancatella A, Viola N, Santini F, Latrofa F (2023) COVID-induced thyroid autoimmunity. Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab 37(2). https://doi.org/10.1016/J.BEEM.2023.101742</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meftah E et al (2023) Subacute thyroiditis following COVID-19: a systematic review. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 14. https://doi.org/10.3389/FENDO.2023.1126637</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldelli R et al (2021) Thyroid dysfunction in COVID-19 patients. J Endocrinol Invest 44(12):2735&#x2013;2739. https://doi.org/10.1007/S40618-021-01599-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoo B, et al (2021) Thyroid function before, during, and, after COVID-19. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 106(2):E803&#x2013;E811. https://doi.org/10.1210/CLINEM/DGAA830</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lui DTW et al (2021) Long COVID in patients with mild to moderate disease: do thyroid function and autoimmunity play a role? Endocr Pract 27(9):894&#x2013;902. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.EPRAC.2021.06.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lui DTW et al (2023) A prospective follow-up on thyroid function, thyroid autoimmunity and long COVID among 250 COVID-19 survivors. Endocrine 80(2):380&#x2013;391. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-022-03281-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facondo P et al (2022) Case report: hypothalamic amenorrhea following COVID-19 infection and review of literatures. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 13. https://doi.org/10.3389/FENDO.2022.840749</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brabant G, Ocran K, Ranft U, Von Zur A, M&#xfc;hlen, Hesch RD (1989) Physiological regulation of thyrotropin. Biochimie 71(2):293&#x2013;301. https://doi.org/10.1016/0300-9084(89)90066-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0300-9084(89)90066-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2495828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu P, Yuan H, Chen H, Li X (2024) Thyroid function spectrum in Cushing&#x2019;s syndrome. BMC Endocr Disord 24(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/S12902-024-01614-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandi ML, Giustina A (2020) Sexual dimorphism of coronavirus 19 morbidity and lethality. Trends Endocrinol Metab 31(12):918&#x2013;927. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.TEM.2020.09.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groti Antonic K, Antonic B, Caliber M, Dhindsa S (2024) Men, testosterone and Covid-19. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 100(1):56&#x2013;65. https://doi.org/10.1111/CEN.14952</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-kuraishy HM et al (2023) Long COVID and risk of erectile dysfunction in recovered patients from mild to moderate COVID-19. Sci Rep 13(1):1. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-32211-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salonia A et al (2023) Testosterone in males with COVID-19: a 12-month cohort study. Andrology 11(1):17&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1111/ANDR.13322</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhasin S et al (2018) Testosterone therapy in men with hypogonadism: an endocrine Society Clinical Practice guideline. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 103(5):1715&#x2013;1744. https://doi.org/10.1210/JC.2018-00229</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustina A et al (2008) Guidelines for the treatment of growth hormone excess and growth hormone deficiency in adults. J Endocrinol Invest 31(9):820&#x2013;838. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF03349263</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03349263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18997495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gazzaruso C, Gola M, Karamouzis I, Giubbini R, Giustina A (2014) Cardiovascular risk in adult patients with growth hormone (GH) deficiency and following substitution with GH&#x2013;an update. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 99(1):18&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.1210/JC.2013-2394</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gola M, Bonadonna S, Doga M, Giustina A (2005) Clinical review: growth hormone and cardiovascular risk factors. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 90(3):1864&#x2013;1870. https://doi.org/10.1210/JC.2004-0545</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunada N et al (2022) Hormonal trends in patients suffering from long COVID symptoms. Endocr J 69(10):1173&#x2013;1181. https://doi.org/10.1507/ENDOCRJ.EJ22-0093</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1507/ENDOCRJ.EJ22-0093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35491089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Study details | brain and gut plasticity in mild TBI or post-acute COVID syndrome following growth hormone therapy | ClinicalTrials.gov. [Online]. https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT03554265 . Accessed 10 Jul 2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazziotti G, Giustina A (2013) Glucocorticoids and the regulation of growth hormone secretion. Nat Rev Endocrinol 9(5):265&#x2013;276. https://doi.org/10.1038/NRENDO.2013.5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustina A, Mazziotti G (2014) Impaired growth hormone secretion associated with low glucocorticoid levels: an experimental model for the Giustina effect. Endocrine 47(2):354&#x2013;356. https://doi.org/10.1007/S12020-014-0278-Y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustina A, Wehrenberg WB (1992) The role of glucocorticoids in the regulation of growth hormone secretion: mechanisms and clinical significance. Trends Endocrinol Metab 3:306&#x2013;311. https://doi.org/10.1016/1043-2760(92)90142-N</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/1043-2760(92)90142-N</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18407116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustina A, Romanelli G, Candrina R, Giustina G (1989) Growth hormone deficiency in patients with idiopathic adrenocorticotropin deficiency resolves during glucocorticoid replacement. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 68(1):120&#x2013;124. https://doi.org/10.1210/JCEM-68-1-120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/JCEM-68-1-120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2535850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verrienti M, Marino Picciola V, Ambrosio MR, Zatelli MC (2024) Pituitary and COVID-19 vaccination: a systematic review. Pituitary. https://doi.org/10.1007/S11102-024-01402-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/S11102-024-01402-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38761322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varlamov EV, Fleseriu M (2024) Acromegaly and COVID-19, lessons, and new opportunities. Pituitary. https://doi.org/10.1007/S11102-024-01404-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/S11102-024-01404-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38888685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>