<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39316344</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2196-8837</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of racial and ethnic health disparities</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Racial Ethn Health Disparities</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Mixed Methods Analysis of Long COVID Symptoms in Black Americans: Examining Physical and Mental Health Outcomes.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40615-024-02170-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">While several reports confirm that long COVID is associated with poorer health, few studies explore how long COVID directly impacts the lives of Black Americans who experienced higher mortality rates early in the pandemic. Even fewer studies utilize both quantitative and qualitative methods to identify pertinent long COVID symptoms. The current study, therefore, sought to identify points of overlap and divergence when comparing qualitative vs. quantitative descriptions of long COVID experiences among Black adults in the United States.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We analyzed&#xa0;cross-sectional surveys collected from the AmeriSpeak panel through the National Opinion Research Center (NORC) at the University of Chicago. This panel includes a probability-based sample of adults across the United&#xa0;States. Respondents completed online surveys between April and June 2022. We compared outcomes among participants who reported experiencing post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (i.e., long COVID) to those who reported experiencing SARS-CoV-2 without long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Nearly all qualitative responses focused on matters of physical health like prolonged coughing, cardiovascular concerns, troubled breathing, fatigue, headaches, memory loss, and bodily pains. Quantitative results, however, showed that Black adults living with long COVID reported significantly more anxiety, depressive symptoms, and hopelessness. Persons with long COVID were also significantly more likely to report experiencing psychosis, suicidal ideation, suicide plans, and suicide attempts within the last year.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Black adults with long COVID experienced worse outcomes across all mental health measures. Despite the COVID-19 Public Health Emergency expiration in May 2023, urgent efforts are still required to not only treat both the physical and mental health needs of persons living with long COVID, but to effectively prevent the spread and transmission of COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. W. Montague Cobb-NMA Health Institute.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goodwill</LastName><ForeName>Janelle R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9887-837X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Crown Family School of Social Work, Policy, and Practice, University of Chicago, Edith Abbott Hall, 969 E. 60th Street, Chicago, IL, 60637, USA. jgoodwill@uchicago.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ajibewa</LastName><ForeName>Tiwaloluwa A</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Preventive Medicine, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Racial Ethn Health Disparities</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101628476</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2196-8837</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Black/African Americans</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute Sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Suicidal Ideaiton</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Suicide</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39316344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40615-024-02170-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40615-024-02170-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References&#xa0;&#xa0;</Title><Reference><Citation>Parums DV. Long COVID, or post-COVID syndrome, and the global impact on health care. Med Sci Monit. 2021;27:e933446-1-e933446-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28(3):583&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01689-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35132265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8938267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu E, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Risks and burdens of incident dyslipidaemia in long COVID: a cohort study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2023;11(2):120&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00355-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36623520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9873268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Risks and burdens of incident diabetes in long COVID: a cohort study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2022;10(5):311&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00044-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35325624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8937253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu E, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Long-term neurologic outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28(11):2406&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-02001-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36138154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9671811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. The Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8(5):416&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00084-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8023694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9839201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, Rivera SC, McMullan C, Chandan JS, et al. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med. 2021;114(9):428&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/01410768211032850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8450986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman ML, Molldrem S, Elliott A, Robertson D, Keiser P. Long COVID and mental health correlates: a new chronic condition fits existing patterns. Health Psychol Behav Med. 2023;11(1):2164498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21642850.2022.2164498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36643576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9833408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Foer D, MacPhaul E, Lo YC, Bates DW, Zhou L. PASCLex: A comprehensive post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) symptom lexicon derived from electronic health record clinical notes. J Biomed Inform. 2022;125:103951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbi.2021.103951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34785382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasnier M, Choucha W, Radiguer F, Faulet T, Chappell K, Bougarel A, et al. Comorbidity of long COVID and psychiatric disorders after a hospitalisation for COVID-19: a cross-sectional study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2022;93(10):1091&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2021-328516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel UK, Mehta N, Patel A, Patel N, Ortiz JF, Khurana M, Urhoghide E, Parulekar A, Bhriguvanshi A, Patel N, Mistry AM. Long-term neurological sequelae among severe COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cureus. 2022;14(9).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey K, Ayers CK, Kondo KK, Saha S, Advani SM, Young S, Spencer H, Rusek M, Anderson J, Veazie S, Smith M. Racial and ethnic disparities in COVID-19&#x2013;related infections, hospitalizations, and deaths: a systematic review. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174(3):362&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs MM, Evans E, Ellis C. Racial, ethnic, and sex disparities in the incidence and cognitive symptomology of long COVID-19. J Natl Med Assoc. 2023;115(2):233&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36792456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A. Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat Med. 2022;28:1706&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01909-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9388369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re&#x2019;em Y, Redfield S, Austin JP, Akrami A. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmans RS, Chambers-Peeple K, Yu C, Xiao LZ, Wegryn-Jones R, Martin A, et al. &#x2018;I&#x2019;m still here, I&#x2019;m alive and breathing&#x2019;: the experience of Black Americans with long COVID. Journal of Clin Nurs. 2023;33(1):162&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.16733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smyth N, Alwan NA, Band R, Chaudhry A, Chew-Graham CA, Gopal D, et al. Exploring the lived experience of Long Covid in black and minority ethnic groups in the UK: Protocol for qualitative interviews and art-based methods. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(10):e0275166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0275166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36191007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9529129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell JW, Clark VLP. Designing and conducting mixed methods research. Thousand Oaks, CA: SagePublications; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onwuegbuzie AJ, Collins KM. A typology of mixed methods sampling designs in social science research. Qualitative report. 2007;12(2):281&#x2013;316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watkins D, Gioia D. Mixed methods research. Oxford University Press, USA; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JBW, L&#xf6;we B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166(10):1092&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16717171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL. The PHQ-9: a new depression diagnostic and severity measure. Psychiatr Ann. 2002;32(9):509&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/0048-5713-20020901-06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahorsu DK, Lin CY, Imani V, Saffari M, Griffiths MD, Pakpour AH. The fear of COVID-19 Scale: development and initial validation. Int J Ment Health Addict. 2022;20(3):1537&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11469-020-00270-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32226353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn SL, Olamijulo GB, Fuglseth HL, Holden TP, Swieringa LL, Sit MJ, et al. The state&#x2013;trait hopelessness scale: development and testing. West J Nurs Res. 2014;36(4):552&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0193945913507634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24122739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol. 2006;3(2):77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Novel insights into patients&#x2019; life-worlds: the value of qualitative research. Lancet Psychiatry. 2019;6(9):720&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(19)30296-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31350207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolley EE, Ulin PR, Mack N, Robinson ET, Succop SM. Qualitative methods in public health: a field guide for applied research. Wiley; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watkins DC. Qualitative research: the importance of conducting research that doesn&#x2019;t &#x201c;count.&#x201d; Health Promot Pract. 2012;13(2):153&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1524839912437370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22382490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salda&#xf1;a J. The coding manual for qualitative researchers. Sage; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watkins DC. Rapid and rigorous qualitative data analysis: the &#x201c;RADaR&#x201d; technique for applied research. Int J Qual Methods. 2017;16(1):1609406917712131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1609406917712131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staller KM. Qualitative analysis: the art of building bridging relationships. Qual Soc Work. 2015;14(2):145&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1473325015571210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieber E, Salmona M, Kaczynski D. Introduction to dedoose for mixed analysis. In: The Routledge reviewer&#x2019;s guide to mixed methods analysis. Routledge; 2021. p. 319&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9780203729434-27</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>StataCorp L. Stata statistical software: release 16 College Station. TX: StataCorp LLC; 2019. p. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onwuegbuzie AJ, Teddlie C. A framework for analyzing data in mixed methods research. Handb Mixed Methods Soc Behav Res. 2003;2(1):397&#x2013;430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorente-Ros M, Das S, Elias J, Frishman WH, Aronow WS. Cardiovascular manifestations of the long COVID syndrome. Cardiol Rev. 2023;:10&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sideratou CM, Papaneophytou C. Persisting shadows: unraveling the impact of long COVID-19 on respiratory, cardiovascular, and nervous systems. Infect Dis Rep. 2023;15(6):806&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/idr15060072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38131885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10742861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogungbe O, Slone S, Alharthi A, Tomiwa T, Kumbe B, Bergman A, et al. &#x201c;Living like an empty gas tank with a leak&#x201d;: mixed methods study on post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(12):e0279684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0279684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36584125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9803174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backmann T, Maribo T, Zwisler AD, Davidsen JR, Rottmann N. A Mixed Methods Study of Functioning and Rehabilitation Needs Following COVID-19. Front Rehabil Sci. 2021;2:710410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PAR-22&#x2013;113: Urgent award: COVID-19 Mental health research (R01 Clinical Trial Optional) [Internet]. Available from: https://grants.nih.gov/grants/guide/pa-files/PAR-22-113.html .&#xa0;Accessed 15 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Shin EC. The type I interferon response in COVID-19: implications for treatment. Nat Rev Immunol. 2020;20(10):585&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-020-00429-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8824445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNabb KC, Bergman AJ, Smith-Wright R, Seltzer J, Slone SE, Tomiwa T, et al. &#x201c;It was almost like it&#x2019;s set up for people to fail&#x201d; A qualitative analysis of experiences and unmet supportive needs of people with Long COVID. BMC Public Health. 2023;23(1):2131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-023-17033-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37904110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10617090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>