<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37116351</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1950-6007</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>163</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biomedicine &amp; pharmacotherapy = Biomedecine &amp; pharmacotherapie</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biomed Pharmacother</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Recuperative herbal formula Jing Si maintains vasculature permeability balance, regulates inflammation and assuages concomitants of "Long-Covid".</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>114752</StartPage><MedlinePgn>114752</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.biopha.2023.114752</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0753-3322(23)00541-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) is a worldwide health threat that has long-term effects on the patients and there is currently no efficient cure prescribed for the treatment and the prolonging effects. Traditional Chinese medicines (TCMs) have been reported to exert therapeutic effect against COVID-19. In this study, the therapeutic effects of Jing Si herbal tea (JSHT) against COVID-19 infection and associated long-term effects were evaluated in different in vitro and in vivo models. The anti-inflammatory effects of JSHT were studied in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-stimulated RAW 264.7 cells and in Omicron pseudotyped virus-induced acute lung injury model. The effect of JSHT on cellular stress was determined in HK-2 proximal tubular cells and H9c2 cardiomyoblasts. The therapeutic benefits of JSHT on anhedonia and depression symptoms associated with long COVID were evaluated in mice models for unpredictable chronic mild stress (UCMS). JSHT inhibited the NF-&#x199;B activities, and significantly reduced LPS-induced expression of TNF&#x3b1;, COX-2, NLRP3 inflammasome, and HMGB1. JSHT was also found to significantly suppress the production of NO by reducing iNOS expression in LPS-stimulated RAW 264.7 cells. Further, the protective effects of JSHT on lung tissue were confirmed based on mitigation of lung injury, repression in TMRRSS2 and HMGB-1 expression and reduction of cytokine storm in the Omicron pseudotyped virus-induced acute lung injury model. JSHT treatment in UCMS models also relieved chronic stress and combated depression symptoms. The results therefore show that JSHT attenuates the cytokine storm by repressing NF-&#x3ba;B cascades and provides the protective functions against symptoms associated with long COVID-19 infection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023. Published by Elsevier Masson SAS.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiang</LastName><ForeName>Chien-Yi</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular and Mitochondrial Related Disease Research Center, Hualien Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Hualien 970, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Jung</ForeName><Initials>YJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular and Mitochondrial Related Disease Research Center, Hualien Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Hualien 970, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weng</LastName><ForeName>Wen-Tsan</ForeName><Initials>WT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular and Mitochondrial Related Disease Research Center, Hualien Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Hualien 970, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Heng-Dao</ForeName><Initials>HD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular and Mitochondrial Related Disease Research Center, Hualien Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Hualien 970, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Cheng-You</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular and Mitochondrial Related Disease Research Center, Hualien Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Hualien 970, Taiwan; Department of Post Baccalaureate Medicine, College of Medicine, National Chung Hsing University, Taichung 40227, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Wan-Jing</ForeName><Initials>WJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular and Mitochondrial Related Disease Research Center, Hualien Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Hualien 970, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shih</LastName><ForeName>Cheng Yen</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Buddhist Compassion Relief Tzu Chi Foundation, Hualien 970, Taiwan; Buddhist Tzu Chi Foundation Hospital, Hualien 97002, Tawian.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Pi-Yu</ForeName><Initials>PY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Buddhist Compassion Relief Tzu Chi Foundation, Hualien 970, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Shinn-Zong</ForeName><Initials>SZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Buddhist Tzu Chi Foundation Hospital, Hualien 97002, Tawian; Bioinnovation Center, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Hualien 970, Taiwan; Department of Neurosurgery, Hualien Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Hualien 970, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ho</LastName><ForeName>Tsung-Jung</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chinese Medicine, Hualien Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Tzu Chi University, Hualien, Taiwan; School of Post-Baccalaure-ate Chinese Medicine, College of Medicine, Tzu Chi University, Hualien 97004,Taiwan; Integration Center of Traditional Chinese and Modern Medicine, HualienTzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Hualien 97002, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shibu</LastName><ForeName>Marthandam Asokan</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, Bharathiar University, Coimbatore 641046, India. Electronic address: shibu.m.a@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Chih-Yang</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular and Mitochondrial Related Disease Research Center, Hualien Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Hualien 970, Taiwan; Graduate Institute of Biomedical Sciences, China Medical University, Taichung 404, Taiwan; Department of Biological Science and Technology, Asia University, Taichung 413, Taiwan; Center of General Education, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Tzu Chi University of Science and Technology, Hualien 970, Taiwan; Department of Medical Research, China Medical University Hospital, China Medical University, Taichung 404, Taiwan. Electronic address: cyhuang@mail.cmu.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>France</Country><MedlineTA>Biomed Pharmacother</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8213295</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0753-3322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008070">Lipopolysaccharides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016207">Cytokines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016328">NF-kappa B</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008070" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipopolysaccharides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000080424" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokine Release Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016207" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055371" MajorTopicYN="Y">Acute Lung Injury</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016328" MajorTopicYN="N">NF-kappa B</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute lung injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokine storm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Decoction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NF-&#x199;B</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Severe COVID</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest exists.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37116351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10130602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2023.114752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0753-3322(23)00541-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Prampart S., Le Gentil S., Bureau M.L., Macchi C., Leroux C., Chapelet G., de Decker L., Rouaud A., Boureau A.S. Functional decline long term symptoms and course of frailty at 3-months follow-up in COVID-19 older survivors a prospective observational cohort study. BMC Geriatr. 2022;22(1):542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9244035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35768781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S., Williams M.A. Confronting our next national health disaster - long-haul covid. New Engl. J. Med. 2021;385(7):577&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34192429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustine J.N., Jones D. Immunopathology of hyperinflammation in COVID-19. Am. J. Pathol. 2021;191(1):4&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7484812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32919977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Xie X., Tu Z., Fu J., Xu D., Zhou Y. The signal pathways and treatment of cytokine storm in COVID-19. Signal Transduct. Target. Ther. 2021;6(1):255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8261820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34234112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadjadj J., Yatim N., Barnabei L., Corneau A., Boussier J., Smith N., P&#xe9;r&#xe9; H., Charbit B., Bondet V., Chenevier-Gobeaux C., Breillat P., Carlier N., Gauzit R., Morbieu C., P&#xe8;ne F., Marin N., Roche N., Szwebel T.A., Merkling S.H., Treluyer J.M., Veyer D., Mouthon L., Blanc C., Tharaux P.L., Rozenberg F., Fischer A., Duffy D., Rieux-Laucat F., Kern&#xe9;is S., Terrier B. Impaired type I interferon activity and inflammatory responses in severe COVID-19 patients. Science. 2020;369(6504):718&#x2013;724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7402632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diao B., Wang C., Tan Y., Chen X., Liu Y., Ning L., Chen L., Li M., Liu Y., Wang G., Yuan Z., Feng Z., Zhang Y., Wu Y., Chen Y. Reduction and functional exhaustion of t cells in patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Front. Immunol. 2020;11:827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7205903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32425950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragab D., Salah Eldin H., Taeimah M., Khattab R., Salem R. The COVID-19 cytokine storm; what we know so far. Front. Immunol. 2020;11:1446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7308649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32612617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y., Liu J., Zhang D., Xu Z., Ji J., Wen C. Cytokine storm in COVID-19: the current evidence and treatment strategies. Front. Immunol. 2020;11:1708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7365923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32754163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulthei&#xdf; C., Willscher E., Paschold L., Gottschick C., Klee B., Henkes S.-S., Bosurgi L., Dutzmann J., Sedding D., Frese T., Girndt M., H&#xf6;ll J.I., Gekle M., Mikolajczyk R., Binder M. The IL-1&#x3b2;, IL-6, and TNF cytokine triad is associated with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Cell Rep. Med. 2022;3(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35732153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo M., Liu J., Jiang W., Yue S., Liu H., Wei S. IL-6 and CD8+ T cell counts combined are an early predictor of in-hospital mortality of patients with COVID-19. JCI Insight. 2020;5(13)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7406244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32544099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Li S., Liu J., Liang B., Wang X., Wang H., Li W., Tong Q., Yi J., Zhao L., Xiong L., Guo C., Tian J., Luo J., Yao J., Pang R., Shen H., Peng C., Liu T., Zhang Q., Wu J., Xu L., Lu S., Wang B., Weng Z., Han C., Zhu H., Zhou R., Zhou H., Chen X., Ye P., Zhu B., Wang L., Zhou W., He S., He Y., Jie S., Wei P., Zhang J., Lu Y., Wang W., Zhang L., Li L., Zhou F., Wang J., Dittmer U., Lu M., Hu Y., Yang D., Zheng X. Longitudinal characteristics of lymphocyte responses and cytokine profiles in the peripheral blood of SARS-CoV-2 infected patients. EBioMedicine. 2020;55</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7165294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32361250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F., Nie J., Wang H., Zhao Q., Xiong Y., Deng L., Song S., Ma Z., Mo P., Zhang Y. Characteristics of peripheral lymphocyte subset alteration in COVID-19 Pneumonia, the. J. Infect. Dis. 2020;221(11):1762&#x2013;1769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32227123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C., Huang L., Wang Y., Li X., Ren L., Gu X., Kang L., Guo L., Liu M., Zhou X., Luo J., Huang Z., Tu S., Zhao Y., Chen L., Xu D., Li Y., Li C., Peng L., Li Y., Xie W., Cui D., Shang L., Fan G., Xu J., Wang G., Wang Y., Zhong J., Wang C., Wang J., Zhang D., Cao B. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y., Ling Q., Manyande A., Wu D., Xiang B. Brain imaging changes in patients recovered from COVID-19: a narrative review. Front. Neurosci. 2022;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9072792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35527821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wurz A., Culos-Reed S.N., Franklin K., DeMars J., Wrightson J.G., Twomey R. "I feel like my body is broken": exploring the experiences of people living with long COVID quality of life research. Int. J. Qual. life Asp. Treat. care Rehabil. 2022:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9272651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35816258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Sayed S., Shokry D., Gomaa S.M. Post-COVID-19 fatigue and anhedonia: a cross-sectional study and their correlation to post-recovery period. Neuropsychopharmacol. Rep. 2021;41(1):50&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8182964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33332756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wieman S.T., Fields J.S., Arditte Hall K.A., MacDonald H.Z., Liverant G.I. Effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on anhedonia reward exposure and responsiveness and sleep in college students. J. Am. Coll. Health. J. ACH. 2022:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35298368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodeir M.M., Shabana H.A., Rasheed Z., Alkhamiss A.S., Khodeir M., Alkhowailed M.S., Alharbi S., Alsoghair M., Alsagaby S.A., Al Abdulmonem W. COVID-19: post-recovery long-term symptoms among patients in Saudi Arabia. PLoS One. 2021;16(12)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8654233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34879074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M., Dercon Q., Luciano S., Geddes J.R., Husain M., Harrison P.J. Incidence co-occurrence and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 2021;18(9)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M.H., Perl D.P., Steiner J., Pasternack N., Li W., Maric D., Safavi F., Horkayne-Szakaly I., Jones R., Stram M.N., Moncur J.T., Hefti M., Folkerth R.D., Nath A. Neurovascular injury with complement activation and inflammation in COVID-19. Brain. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9278212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35788639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenzel J., Schwaninger M. How COVID-19 affects microvessels in the brain. Brain. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9337801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35848856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Zhou L., Bao L., Liu J., Zhu H., Lv Q., Liu R., Chen W., Tong W., Wei Q., Xu Y., Deng W., Gao H., Xue J., Song Z., Yu P., Han Y., Zhang Y., Sun X., Yu X., Qin C. SARS-CoV-2 crosses the blood&#x2013;brain barrier accompanied with basement membrane disruption without tight junctions alteration. Signal Transduct. Target. Ther. 2021;6(1):337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8419672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34489403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balcom E.F., Nath A., Power C. Acute and chronic neurological disorders in COVID-19: potential mechanisms of disease. Brain. 2021;144(12):3576&#x2013;3588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8719840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34398188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penninx B. Psychiatric symptoms and cognitive impairment in "Long COVID": the relevance of immunopsychiatry. World Psychiatry. 2021;20(3):357&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8429338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34505378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore J.B., June C.H. Cytokine release syndrome in severe COVID-19. Science. 2020;368(6490):473&#x2013;474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32303591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S.W. Tang, B.E. Leonard, D.M. Helmeste, Long COVID, neuropsychiatric disorders, psychotropics, present and future, Acta Neuropsychiatr 34(3) (2022) 109&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35144718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Huang B., Zhang Y.W. Chinese herbal medicine for the treatment of depression: effects on the neuroendocrine-immune network. Pharmaceuticals. 2021;14(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7830381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33466877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Xu B., Zhang Y., Duan Y., Gao R., He H., Li X., Li J. Efficacy and safety of traditional Chinese medicine in coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front. Pharmacol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8379002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34421581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Islam M.S., Wang J., Li Y., Chen X. Traditional Chinese medicine in the treatment of patients infected with 2019-new coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2): a review and perspective. Int. J. Biol. Sci. 2020;16(10):1708&#x2013;1717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7098036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32226288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Xiao P., Liu N., Zhang Z. Efficacy and safety of Chinese medicine lianhua qingwen for treating COVID-19: an updated meta-analysis. Front. Pharmacol. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9204491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35721166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh P.-C., Chao Y.-C., Tsai K.-W., Li C.-H., Tzeng I.-S., Wu Y.-K., Shih C.Y. Efficacy and safety of complementary therapy With Jing Si herbal tea in patients with mild-to-moderate COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Front. Nutr. 2022;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8967163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35369061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang C.-Y., Kuo W.-W., Lin Y.-J., Kuo C.-H., Shih C.-Y., Lin P.-Y., Lin S.-Z., Ho T.-J., Huang C.-Y., Shibu M.A. Combined effect of traditional Chinese herbal-based formulations Jing Si herbal tea and Jing Si nasal drop inhibits adhesion and transmission of SARS-CoV2 in diabetic SKH-1 mice. Front. Pharmacol. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9681529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36425575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal P.K., Agrawal C., Blunden G. Artemisia extracts and artemisinin-based antimalarials for COVID-19 management: could these be effective antivirals for COVID-19 treatment? Molecules. 2022;27(12)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9231170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35744958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuzimoto A.D. An overview of the anti-SARS-CoV-2 properties of Artemisia annua its antiviral action protein-associated mechanisms and repurposing for COVID-19 treatment. J. Integr. Med. 2021;19(5):375&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8378675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34479848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orege J.I., Adeyemi S.B., Tiamiyu B.B., Akinyemi T.O., Ibrahim Y.A., Orege O.B. Artemisia and Artemisia-based products for COVID-19 management: current state and future perspective advances in traditional. Medicine. 2021:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P.-C., Wang H.-S., Shibu M.A., Wang J., Huang S.-H., Wang J.-H., Wang J.-H., Huang C.-Y., Chiang C.-Y., Lin Y.-J., Ho T.-J., Lin S.-Z., Chung H.-C., Yu H.-Y., Su S.-H., Chou Y.-F., Tai C.-H., Ding D.-C., Shih C.Y. Clinical course of patients with severe SARS-CoV-2 infection co-treatment with Jin Si herbal tea in Eastern Taiwan: a retrospective cohort study. J. Herb. Med. 2022;36</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9616512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36341465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost T.S., Jiang L., Lynch R.M., Zohar Y. Permeability of Epithelial/Endothelial barriers in transwells and microfluidic bilayer devices. Micromachines. 2019;10(8)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6722679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31412604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaffer B.S., Grayson M.H., Wortham J.M., Kubicek C.B., McCleish A.T., Prajapati S.I., Nelon L.D., Brady M.M., Jung I., Hosoyama T., Sarro L.M., Hanes M.A., Rubin B.P., Michalek J.E., Clifford C.B., Infante A.J., Keller C. Immune competency of a hairless mouse strain for improved preclinical studies in genetically engineered mice. Mol. Cancer Ther. 2010;9(8):2354&#x2013;2364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2921575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20663932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kou J., Yu B., Xu Q. Inhibitory effects of ethanol extract from radix ophiopogon japonicus on venous thrombosis linked with its endothelium-protective and anti-adhesive activities. Vasc. Pharmacol. 2005;43(3):157&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16054441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen P.H., Zhao B.T., Lee J.H., Kim Y.H., Min B.S., Woo M.H. Isolation of benzoic and cinnamic acid derivatives from the grains of sorghum bicolor and their inhibition of lipopolysaccharide-induced nitric oxide production in RAW 264.7 cells. Food Chem. 2015;168:512&#x2013;519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25172742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Ge Q., Du H., Lin S. Tricholoma matsutake-derived peptides ameliorate inflammation and mitochondrial dysfunction in RAW264.7 macrophages by modulating the NF-&#x3ba;B/COX-2 pathway. Foods. 2021;10(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8621704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34828964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang G., Jin S., Huang W., Li Y., Wang J., Ling X., Huang Y., Hu Y., Li C., Meng Y., Li X. LPS-induced macrophage HMGB1-loaded extracellular vesicles trigger hepatocyte pyroptosis by activating the NLRP3 inflammasome. Cell death Discov. 2021;7(1):337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8572226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34743181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aljabr W., Al-Amari A., Abbas B., Karkashan A., Alamri S., Alnamnakani M., Al-Qahtani A. Evaluation of the levels of peripheral CD3(+), CD4(+), and CD8(+) T Cells and IgG and IgM antibodies in COVID-19 patients at different stages of infection. Microbiol. Spectr. 2022;10(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8865559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35196808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rydyznski Moderbacher C., Ramirez S.I., Dan J.M., Grifoni A., Hastie K.M., Weiskopf D., Belanger S., Abbott R.K., Kim C., Choi J., Kato Y., Crotty E.G., Kim C., Rawlings S.A., Mateus J., Tse L.P.V., Frazier A., Baric R., Peters B., Greenbaum J., Ollmann Saphire E., Smith D.M., Sette A., Crotty S. Antigen-specific adaptive immunity to SARS-CoV-2 in acute COVID-19 and associations with age and disease severity. Cell. 2020;183(4):996&#x2013;1012. e19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7494270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33010815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong F., Dai Y., Zheng T., Cheng L., Zhao D., Wang H., Liu M., Pei H., Jin T., Yu D., Zhou P. Peripheral CD4+ T cell subsets and antibody response in COVID-19 convalescent individuals the. J. Clin. Investig. 2020;130(12):6588&#x2013;6599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7685722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32841212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dan J.M., Mateus J., Kato Y., Hastie K.M., Yu E.D., Faliti C.E., Grifoni A., Ramirez S.I., Haupt S., Frazier A., Nakao C., Rayaprolu V., Rawlings S.A., Peters B., Krammer F., Simon V., Saphire E.O., Smith D.M., Weiskopf D., Sette A., Crotty S. Immunological memory to SARS-CoV-2 assessed for up to 8 months after infection. Science. 2021;371(6529)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7919858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33408181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multisystem involvement is common in post-COVID-19 syndrome. Nat. Med. 2022;28(6):1139&#x2013;1140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9125959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35606552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzik T.J., Mohiddin S.A., Dimarco A., Patel V., Savvatis K., Marelli-Berg F.M., Madhur M.S., Tomaszewski M., Maffia P., D'Acquisto F., Nicklin S.A., Marian A.J., Nosalski R., Murray E.C., Guzik B., Berry C., Touyz R.M., Kreutz R., Wang D.W., Bhella D., Sagliocco O., Crea F., Thomson E.C., McInnes I.B. COVID-19 and the cardiovascular system: implications for risk assessment diagnosis and treatment options. Cardiovasc. Res. 2020;116(10):1666&#x2013;1687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7197627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32352535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrow A.J., Sykes R., McIntosh A., Kamdar A., Bagot C., Bayes H.K., Blyth K.G., Briscoe M., Bulluck H., Carrick D., Church C., Corcoran D., Findlay I., Gibson V.B., Gillespie L., Grieve D., Hall Barrientos P., Ho A., Lang N.N., Lennie V., Lowe D.J., Macfarlane P.W., Mark P.B., Mayne K.J., McConnachie A., McGeoch R., McGinley C., McKee C., Nordin S., Payne A., Rankin A.J., Robertson K.E., Roditi G., Ryan N., Sattar N., Allwood-Spiers S., Stobo D., Touyz R.M., Veldtman G., Watkins S., Weeden S., Weir R.A., Welsh P., Wereski R., Basu N., Brown A., Butler E., Dobbin S.J.H., Dougherty A., Dymock L., Fallon K., Gilmour L., Hopkins T., Lees J.S., McInnes I.B., McLennan E., Savage F., Siebert S., Tynan N., Woodward R., Mangion K., Berry C. C.-. consortium a multisystem cardio-renal investigation of post-COVID-19 illness. Nat. Med. 2022;28(6):1303&#x2013;1313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9205780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35606551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B., Xie Y., Xu E., Al-Aly Z. Kidney outcomes in long COVID. J. Am. Soc. Nephrol. 2021;32(11):2851&#x2013;2862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8806085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34470828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caillet C., Stofberg M.L., Muleya V., Shonhai A., Zininga T. Host cell stress response as a predictor of COVID-19 infectivity and disease progression. Front. Mol. Biosci. 2022;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9411049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36032680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frisbee J.C., Brooks S.D., Stanley S.C., d'Audiffret A.C. An unpredictable chronic mild stress protocol for instigating depressive symptoms behavioral changes and negative health outcomes in rodents. J. Vis. Exp. 2015;106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4692768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26650668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai K.C., Huang Y.C., Liaw C.C., Tsai C.I., Chiou C.T., Lin C.J., Wei W.C., Lin S.J., Tseng Y.H., Yeh K.M., Lin Y.L., Jan J.T., Liang J.J., Liao C.C., Chiou W.F., Kuo Y.H., Lee S.M., Lee M.Y., Su Y.C. A traditional Chinese medicine formula NRICM101 to target COVID-19 through multiple pathways: a bedside-to-bench study. Biomed. Pharmacother. Biomedecine Pharmacother. 2021;133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7676327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33249281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y.-J. Lin, C.-Y. Chiang, M.A. Shibu, S.-H. Su, K.T.P. Dass, P.-Y. Lin, S.-Z. Lin, T.-J. Ho, W.-W. Kuo, C.-Y. Huang, Novel Herbal Formulation Jing Si Exhibits Multiple Functions to Inhibit Replication Activity and Subsides Viral Load of COVID-19 Variants, Research Square, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen X., Yin F. The mechanisms and clinical application of traditional Chinese medicine lianhua-qingwen capsule. Biomed. Pharmacother. 2021;142</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34385103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren W., Ma Y., Wang R., Liang P., Sun Q., Pu Q., Dong L., Mazhar M., Luo G., Yang S. Research advance on Qingfei Paidu decoction in prescription principle mechanism analysis and clinical application. Front. Pharmacol. 2021;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33584265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu P., Zhong L., Xiao J., Hu Y., Liu T., Ren Z., Wang Y., Zheng K. Ethanol extract from Artemisia argyi leaves inhibits HSV-1 infection by destroying the viral envelope. Virol. J. 2023;20(1):8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9841929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36647143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y., Zhang B., Wang N., Li M., Xi N. Investigation of major flavonoids from Artemisia argyi as a potential COVID-19 drug: molecular docking and DFT calculations. Crystals. 2022;12(7):990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon E.B., Yang H.J., Choi J.G., Li W. Protective effect of flavonoids from Ohwia caudata against influenza a virus infection. Molecules. 2020;25(19)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7583851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32987774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling L.J., Lu Y., Zhang Y.Y., Zhu H.Y., Tu P., Li H., Chen D.F. Flavonoids from Houttuynia cordata attenuate H1N1-induced acute lung injury in mice via inhibition of influenza virus and Toll-like receptor signalling. Phytomedicine Int. J. Phytother. Phytopharm. 2020;67</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31958713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Matos P.H., da Silva T.P., Mansano A.B., Gancedo N.C., Tonin F.S., Pelloso F.C., Petruco M.V., de Melo E.B., Fernandez-Llimos F., Sanches A.C.C., de Mello J.C.P., Chierrito D., de Medeiros Ara&#xfa;jo D.C. Bioactive compounds as potential angiotensin-converting enzyme II inhibitors against COVID-19: a scoping review. Inflamm. Res. Off. J. Eur. Histamine Res. Soc. 2022;71(12):1489&#x2013;1500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9616414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36307652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murck H. Symptomatic protective action of glycyrrhizin (Licorice) in COVID-19 infection? Front. Immunol. 2020;11:1239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32574273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahrosh H.S., Mustafa G. An in silico approach to target RNA-dependent RNA polymerase of COVID-19 with naturally occurring phytochemicals. Environ. Dev. Sustain. 2021;23(11):16674&#x2013;16687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8018901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33841038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahadur Gurung A., Ajmal Ali M., Lee J., Abul Farah M., Mashay Al-Anazi K., Al-Hemaid F. Identification of SARS-CoV-2 inhibitors from extracts of Houttuynia cordata Thunb. Saudi J. Biol. Sci. 2021;28(12):7517&#x2013;7527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8420092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34512097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrzanowski J., Chrzanowska A., Grabo&#x144; W. Glycyrrhizin: an old weapon against a novel coronavirus. Phytother. Res. PTR. 2021;35(2):629&#x2013;636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32902005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crance J.M., Biziagos E., Passagot J., van Cuyck-Gandr&#xe9; H., Deloince R. Inhibition of hepatitis a virus replication in vitro by antiviral compounds. J. Med. Virol. 1990;31(2):155&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2167349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crance J.M., L&#xe9;v&#xea;que F., Biziagos E., van Cuyck-Gandr&#xe9; H., Jouan A., Deloince R. Studies on mechanism of action of glycyrrhizin against hepatitis a virus replication in vitro. Antivir. Res. 1994;23(1):63&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8141593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Fan S., Mao Y., Ji Y., Jin L., Lu J., Chen X. Cardiovascular protective effect of polysaccharide from Ophiopogon japonicus in diabetic rats. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2016;82:505&#x2013;513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26434529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Chen Q., Ren R., Zhang Q., Yan G., Yin D., Zhang M., Yang Y. Platycodon grandiflorus polysaccharides deeply participate in the anti-chronic bronchitis effects of Platycodon grandiflorus decoction, a representative of "the lung and intestine are related". Front. Pharmacol. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9489837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36160385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M.S., Hur Y.G., Kim W.G., Park B.W., Ahn K.S., Kim J.J., Bae H. Inhibitory effect of Platycodon grandiflorum on T(H)1 and T(H)2 immune responses in a murine model of 2,4-dinitrofluorobenzene-induced atopic dermatitis-like skin lesions. Ann. Allergy Asthma Immunol. Off. Publ. Am. Coll. Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2011;106(1):54&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21195946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noh E.M., Kim J.M., Lee H.Y., Song H.K., Joung S.O., Yang H.J., Kim M.J., Kim K.S., Lee Y.R. Immuno-enhancement effects of Platycodon grandiflorum extracts in splenocytes and a cyclophosphamide-induced immunosuppressed rat model. BMC Complement Alter. Med. 2019;19(1):322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6868875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31752816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng J., He J., Ji B., Li Y., Zhang X. Antihyperglycemic effects of Platycodon grandiflorum (Jacq.) A. DC. extract on streptozotocin-induced diabetic mice. Plant Foods Hum. Nutr. 2007;62(1):7&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17226070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim T.Y., Jeon S., Jang Y., Gotina L., Won J., Ju Y.H., Kim S., Jang M.W., Won W., Park M.G., Pae A.N., Han S., Kim S., Lee C.J. Platycodin D a natural component of Platycodon grandiflorum prevents both lysosome- and TMPRSS2-driven SARS-CoV-2 infection by hindering membrane fusion. Exp. Mol. Med. 2021;53(5):956&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8143993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34035463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang W.F., Tsai H.P., Chang Y.H., Chang T.Y., Hsieh C.F., Lin C.Y., Lin G.H., Chen Y.L., Jheng J.R., Liu P.C., Yang C.M., Chin Y.F., Chen C.C., Kau J.H., Hung Y.J., Hsieh P.S., Horng J.T. Perilla (Perilla frutescens) leaf extract inhibits SARS-CoV-2 via direct virus inactivation. Biomed. J. 2021;44(3):293&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7840404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34119448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoudi S., Balmeh N., Mohammadi N., Sadeghian-Rizi T. The novel drug discovery to combat COVID-19 by repressingimportant virus proteins involved in pathogenesis using medicinal herbal compounds. Avicenna J.Med. Biotechnol. 2021;13(3):107&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8377408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34484639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Huang Q., Wang D.C., Ingbar D.H., Wang X. Acute lung injury in patients with COVID-19 infection. Clin. Transl. Med. 2020;10(1):20&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7240840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32508022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubenfeld G.D., Caldwell E., Peabody E., Weaver J., Martin D.P., Neff M., Stern E.J., Hudson L.D. Incidence and outcomes of acute lung injury the. New Engl. J. Med. 2005;353(16):1685&#x2013;1693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16236739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balnis J., Adam A.P., Chopra A., Chieng H.C., Drake L.A., Martino N., Bossardi Ramos R., Feustel P.J., Overmyer K.A., Shishkova E., Coon J.J., Singer H.A., Judson M.A., Jaitovich A. Unique inflammatory profile is associated with higher SARS-CoV-2 acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) mortality. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 2021;320(3):R250&#x2013;R257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7938634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33434104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coperchini F., Chiovato L., Rotondi M. Interleukin-6 CXCL10 and infiltrating macrophages in COVID-19-related cytokine storm: not one for all but all for one! Front. Immunol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8107352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33981314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coperchini F., Chiovato L., Ricci G., Croce L., Magri F., Rotondi M. The cytokine storm in COVID-19: further advances in our understanding the role of specific chemokines involved. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2021;58:82&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33573850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano T., Murakami M. COVID-19: a new virus but a familiar receptor and cytokine release syndrome. Immunity. 2020;52(5):731&#x2013;733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7175868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hariharan A., Hakeem A.R., Radhakrishnan S., Reddy M.S., Rela M. The role and therapeutic potential of NF-kappa-B pathway in severe COVID-19 patients. Inflammopharmacology. 2021;29(1):91&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7648206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33159646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado-Roche L., Mesta F. Oxidative stress as key player in severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV) infection. Arch. Med. Res. 2020;51(5):384&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7190501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32402576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin N.R., Park S.H., Ko J.W., Ryu H.W., Jeong S.H., Kim J.C., Shin D.H., Lee H.S., Shin I.S. Artemisia argyi attenuates airway inflammation in lipopolysaccharide induced acute lung injury model. Lab. Anim. Res. 2017;33(3):209&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5645598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29046695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Kuraishy H.M., Al-Gareeb A.I., Al-Hussaniy H.A., Al-Harcan N.A.H., Alexiou A., Batiha G.E. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) and Covid-19: a new frontiers for therapeutic modality. Int. Immunopharmacol. 2022;104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8733219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35032828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M., Tedesco Junior W.L.D., Lozovoy M.A.B., Mori M.T.E., Danelli T., Almeida E.R.D., Tejo A.M., Tano Z.N., Reiche E.M.V., Sim&#xe3;o A.N.C. In COVID-19, NLRP3 inflammasome genetic variants are associated with critical disease and these effects are partly mediated by the sickness symptom complex: a nomothetic network approach. Mol. Psychiatry. 2022;27(4):1945&#x2013;1955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8752583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35022530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Kuraishy H.M., Al-Gareeb A.I., Alkazmi L., Habotta O.A., Batiha G.E. High-mobility group box 1 (HMGB1) in COVID-19: extrapolation of dangerous liaisons. Inflammopharmacology. 2022;30(3):811&#x2013;820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9040700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35471628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potere N., Del Buono M.G., Caricchio R., Cremer P.C., Vecchi&#xe9; A., Porreca E., Dalla Gasperina D., Dentali F., Abbate A., Bonaventura A. Interleukin-1 and the NLRP3 inflammasome in COVID-19: pathogenetic and therapeutic implications. EBioMedicine. 2022;85</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9536001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36209522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J., Kremer S., Merdji H., Clere-Jehl R., Schenck M., Kummerlen C., Collange O., Boulay C., Fafi-Kremer S., Ohana M., Anheim M., Meziani F. Neurologic features in severe SARS-CoV-2 infection the. New Engl. J. Med. 2020;382(23):2268&#x2013;2270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7179967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32294339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandemirli S.G., Dogan L., Sarikaya Z.T., Kara S., Akinci C., Kaya D., Kaya Y., Yildirim D., Tuzuner F., Yildirim M.S., Ozluk E., Gucyetmez B., Karaarslan E., Koyluoglu I., Demirel Kaya H.S., Mammadov O., Kisa Ozdemir I., Afsar N., Citci Yalcinkaya B., Rasimoglu S., Guduk D.E., Kedir Jima A., Ilksoz A., Ersoz V., Yonca Eren M., Celtik N., Arslan S., Korkmazer B., Dincer S.S., Gulek E., Dikmen I., Yazici M., Unsal S., Ljama T., Demirel I., Ayyildiz A., Kesimci I., Bolsoy Deveci S., Tutuncu M., Kizilkilic O., Telci L., Zengin R., Dincer A., Akinci I.O., Kocer N. Brain MRI findings in patients in the intensive care unit with COVID-19 infection. Radiology. 2020;297(1):E232&#x2013;E235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7507997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32384020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokic D., Mikacic M., Kumric M., Ticinovic Kurir T., Rancic I., Martinovic D., Bukic J., Vrdoljak J., Lizatovic I.K., Stipic S.S., Supe Domic D., Bozic J. Association between brain injury markers and testosterone in critically-Ill COVID-19 male patients. Microorganisms. 2022;10(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9697553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36363686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buzhdygan T.P., DeOre B.J., Baldwin-Leclair A., Bullock T.A., McGary H.M., Khan J.A., Razmpour R., Hale J.F., Galie P.A., Potula R., Andrews A.M., Ramirez S.H. The SARS-CoV-2 spike protein alters barrier function in 2D static and 3D microfluidic in-vitro models of the human blood-brain barrier. Neurobiol. Dis. 2020;146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7547916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33053430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boldrini M., Canoll P.D., Klein R.S. How COVID-19 affects the brain. JAMA Psychiatry. 2021;78(6):682&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9894299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33769431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J., Radke J., Dittmayer C., Franz J., Thomas C., Mothes R., Laue M., Schneider J., Br&#xfc;nink S., Greuel S., Lehmann M., Hassan O., Aschman T., Schumann E., Chua R.L., Conrad C., Eils R., Stenzel W., Windgassen M., R&#xf6;&#xdf;ler L., Goebel H.H., Gelderblom H.R., Martin H., Nitsche A., Schulz-Schaeffer W.J., Hakroush S., Winkler M.S., Tampe B., Scheibe F., K&#xf6;rtv&#xe9;lyessy P., Reinhold D., Siegmund B., K&#xfc;hl A.A., Elezkurtaj S., Horst D., Oesterhelweg L., Tsokos M., Ingold-Heppner B., Stadelmann C., Drosten C., Corman V.M., Radbruch H., Heppner F.L. Olfactory transmucosal SARS-CoV-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with COVID-19. Nat. Neurosci. 2021;24(2):168&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo M.S., Malsy J., P&#xf6;ttgen J., Seddiq Zai S., Ufer F., Hadjilaou A., Schmiedel S., Addo M.M., Gerloff C., Heesen C., Schulze Zur Wiesch J., Friese M.A. Frequent neurocognitive deficits after recovery from mild COVID-19. Brain Commun. 2020;2(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33376990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>