<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37185117</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1943-3654</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Respiratory care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Respir Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Year in Review: Long COVID and Pulmonary Rehabilitation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>846</StartPage><EndPage>851</EndPage><MedlinePgn>846-851</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4187/respcare.10928</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>There have been an estimated 100 million people diagnosed with COVID-19 in the United States, with a majority of patients reporting persistent symptoms expressed as long COVID. The 2 most frequently reported long COVID symptoms are shortness of breath and fatigue. Exercise training during pulmonary rehabilitation (PR) is a successful strategy for improving the lives of people with persistent respiratory symptoms caused by a variety of lung diseases. This narrative review assessed the impact of exercise interventions on functional exercise capacity measures and related symptoms (dyspnea, fatigue) in people with long COVID over the last year. Articles were accessed through electronic databases including PubMed, Embase, CINAHL Plus with full text (EBSCO), and LitCovid. Findings for this Year in Review revealed that exercise interventions and PR show promise for improving functional exercise capacity, dyspnea, and fatigue in people with long COVID. This review supports the need for more rigorous scientific studies on the benefits of structured PR in people with long COVID who have respiratory-related symptoms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by Daedalus Enterprises.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burnett</LastName><ForeName>Dave M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Kansas Medical Center, Department of Respiratory Care and Diagnostic Sciences, Kansas City, Kansas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skinner</LastName><ForeName>Cheryl E</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Kansas Medical Center, Department of Respiratory Care and Diagnostic Sciences, Kansas City, Kansas. cskinner@kumc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Respir Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7510357</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0020-1324</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004417" MajorTopicYN="N">Dyspnea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ICU</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional capacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">literature review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory therapy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have disclosed no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37185117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10209004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4187/respcare.10928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">respcare.10928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bek LM, Berentschot JC, Heijenbrok-Kal MH, Huijts S, van Genderen ME, Vlake JH, et al. . Symptoms persisting after hospitalization for COVID-19: 12 months interim results of the CO-FLOW study. ERJ Open Res 2022;8(4):00355-2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9421428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36284829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE, Ba DM, Parsons N, Poudel GR, et al. . Short-term and long-term rates of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a systematic review. JAMA Netw Open 2021;4(10):e2128568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34643720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, Wang Q, Ren L, Wang Y, et al. . 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet 2021;398(10302):747-758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>See&#xdf;le J, Waterboer T, Hippchen T, Simon J, Kirchner M, Lim A, et al. . Persistent symptoms in adult patients 1 year after coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a prospective cohort study. Clin Infect Dis 2022;74(7):1191-1198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34223884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Husain M, Harrison PJ. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med 2021;18(9):e1003773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wynberg E, van Willigen HDG, Dijkstra M, Boyd A, Kootstra NA, van den Aardweg JG, et al. ; RECoVERED Study Group. Evolution of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) symptoms during the first 12 months after illness onset. Clin Infect Dis 2022;75(1):e482-e490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8522402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34473245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo X, Jian W, Su Z, Chen M, Peng H, Peng P, et al. . Abnormal pulmonary function in COVID-19 patients at time of hospital discharge. Eur Respir J 2020;55(6):2001217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32381497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaes AW, Goertz YMJ, Van Herck M, Machado FVC, Meys R, Delbressine JM, et al. . Recovery from COVID-19: a sprint or marathon? 6-month follow-up data from online long COVID-19 support group members. ERJ Open Res 2021;7(2):00141-2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8012818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34041295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bek LM, Berentschot JC, Hellemons ME, Huijts SM, Aerts J, van Bommel J, et al. ; CO-FLOW Collaboration Group. CO-FLOW: COVID-19 follow-up care paths and long-term outcomes within the Dutch health care system: study protocol of a multi-center prospective cohort study following patients 2 years after hospital discharge. BMC Health Serv Res 2021;21(1):847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8379596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34419032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polastri M, Nava S, Clini E, Vitacca M, Gosselink R. COVID-19 and pulmonary rehabilitation: preparing for phase three. Eur Respir J 2020;55(6):2001822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7401308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32586841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas P, Baldwin C, Bissett B, Boden I, Gosselink R, Granger CL, et al. . Physiotherapy management for COVID-19 in the acute hospital setting: clinical practice recommendations. J Physiother 2020;66(2):73-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7165238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32312646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M, Carone M, Clini EM, Paneroni M, Lazzeri M, Lanza A, et al. ; ITS - AIPO, the ARIR, and the SIP/IRS. Joint statement on the role of respiratory rehabilitation in the COVID-19 crisis: the Italian position paper. Respiration 2020;99(6):493-499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7316664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32428909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M, Lazzeri M, Guffanti E, Frigerio P, D&#x2019;Abrosca F, Gianola S, et al. . Italian suggestions for pulmonary rehabilitation in COVID-19 patients recovering from acute respiratory failure: results of a Delphi process. Monaldi Arch Chest Dis 2020;90(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32573175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy B, Casey D, Devane D, Murphy K, Murphy E, Lacasse Y. Pulmonary rehabilitation for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2015(2):CD003793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10008021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25705944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puhan MA, Gimeno-Santos E, Cates CJ, Troosters T. Pulmonary rehabilitation following exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2016;12:CD005305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6463852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27930803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindenauer PK, Stefan MS, Pekow PS, Mazor KM, Priya A, Spitzer KA, et al. . Association between initiation of pulmonary rehabilitation after hospitalization for COPD and 1-year survival among Medicare beneficiaries. JAMA 2020;323(18):1813-1823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7218499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32396181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ries AL, Bauldoff GS, Carlin BW, Casaburi R, Emery CF, Mahler DA, et al. . Pulmonary rehabilitation: joint ACCP/AACVPR evidence-based clinical practice guidelines. Chest 2007;131(5 Suppl):4S-42S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17494825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spruit MA, Holland AE, Singh SJ, Tonia T, Wilson KC, Troosters T. COVID-19: interim guidance on rehabilitation in the hospital and post-hospital phase from a European Respiratory Society and American Thoracic Society&#x2013;coordinated International Task Force. Eur Respir J 2020;56(6):2002197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32817258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capin JJ, Jolley SE, Morrow M, Connors M, Hare K, MaWhinney S, et al. . Safety, feasibility, and initial efficacy of an app-facilitated telerehabilitation (AFTER) program for COVID-19 survivors: a pilot randomized study. BMJ Open 2022;12(7):e061285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9329728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35882451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Xia W, Zhan C, Liu S, Yin Z, Wang J, et al. . A telerehabilitation program in post-discharge COVID-19 patients (TERECO): a randomized controlled trial. Thorax 2022;77(7):697-706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8318721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Valle MF, Valenzuela J, Marzuca-Nassr GN, Cabrera-Inostroza C, Del Sol M, Lizana PA, et al. . Eight weeks of supervised pulmonary rehabilitation are effective in improving resting heart rate and heart rate recovery in severe COVID-19 patient survivors of mechanical ventilation. Medicina (Kaunas) 2022;58(4):514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9028941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35454353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahham A, Holland AE. The need for expanding pulmonary rehabilitation services. Life (Basel) 2021;11(11):1236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8622005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34833112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desveaux L, Janaudis-Ferreira T, Goldstein R, Brooks D. An international comparison of pulmonary rehabilitation: a systematic review. COPD 2015;12(2):144-153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24984085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishi SP, Zhang W, Kuo YF, Sharma G. Pulmonary rehabilitation utilization in older adults with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, 2003 to 2012. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev 2016;36(5):375-382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5001907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27428819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moscovice IS, Casey MM, Wu Z. Disparities in geographic access to hospital outpatient pulmonary rehabilitation programs in the United States. Chest 2019;156(2):308-315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30978331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rochester CL, Vogiatzis I, Holland AE, Lareau SC, Marciniuk DD, Puhan MA, et al. ; ATS/ERS Task Force on Policy in Pulmonary Rehabilitation. An official American Thoracic Society/European Respiratory Society policy statement: enhancing implementation, use, and delivery of pulmonary rehabilitation. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2015;192(11):1373-1386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26623686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Zhang W, Yang Y, Zhang J, Li Y, Chen Y. Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: a randomized controlled study. Complement Ther Clin Pract 2020;39:101166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed I, Mustafaoglu R, Yeldan I, Yasaci Z, Erhan B. Effect of pulmonary rehabilitation approaches on dyspnea, exercise capacity, fatigue, lung functions, and quality of life in patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2022;103(10):2051-2062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9334878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35908659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Shi H, Liu X, Sun T, Wu J, Liu Z. Effect of pulmonary rehabilitation for patients with post-COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022;9:837420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8899076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35265644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fugazzaro S, Contri A, Esseroukh O, Kaleci S, Croci S, Massari M, et al. . Rehabilitation interventions for post-acute COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022;19(9.)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9104923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35564579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira A, Pinto A, Garcia B, Eid RAC, Mol CG, Nawa RK. Telerehabilitation improves physical function and reduces dyspnea in people with COVID-19 and post-COVID-19 conditions: a systematic review. J Physiother 2022;68(2):90-98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8994568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35414491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>