<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38729195</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1474-547X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>403</Volume><Issue>10440</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Lancet (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The long COVID evidence gap in England.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1981</StartPage><EndPage>1982</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1981-1982</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S0140-6736(24)00744-X</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0140-6736(24)00744-X</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Knuppel</LastName><ForeName>Anika</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Lancet Public Health, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boyd</LastName><ForeName>Andy</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Population Health Sciences, Bristol Medical School, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Macleod</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Population Health Sciences, Bristol Medical School, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK; NIHR Applied Research Collaboration (ARC) West, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaturvedi</LastName><ForeName>Nishi</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC Unit of Lifelong Health and Ageing at UCL, University College London, London W1E 7HB, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Williams</LastName><ForeName>Dylan M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC Unit of Lifelong Health and Ageing at UCL, University College London, London W1E 7HB, UK. Electronic address: dylan.williams@ucl.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016422">Letter</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985213R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0140-6736</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004739" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">England</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094505" MajorTopicYN="N">Evidence Gaps</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019317" MajorTopicYN="N">Evidence-Based Medicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>NC and AB were responsible for funding acquisition, data collection, and curation. DMW conceptualised the study. AK and DMW were responsible for data analysis and manuscript writing, and accessed and verified the underlying study data. All authors contributed to the study design and interpretation, and gave approval of the final manuscript. AK is a Senior Editor for The Lancet Public Health, she conducted this research when affiliated with MRC Unit of Lifelong Health and Ageing at UCL. NC has participated on a data safety monitoring board or advisory board for AstraZeneca. All other authors declare no competing interests. Data used in this research are made available via the UK LLC, and cannot be used or shared outside its Trusted Research Environment (TRE). Researchers can apply to use UK LLC's resource using the procedure outlined in the UK LLC Data Access and Acceptable Use Policy. The UK LLC uses a system of managed open access for researchers who demonstrate their project is intended to improve the public good. Code used to analyse longitudinal study data and linked EHRs within the UK LLC are available online at https://github.com/UKLLC/LLC_0006. This research was funded by the National Institute for Health and Care Research (NIHR; grants COV-LT-0009; MC_PC_20051). The funders of the study had a role in the data collection, resource development, and analytical time, and no role in the output of the research, study design, data analysis, data interpretation, or writing of the report. The UK LLC is an initiative of the UK Research &amp; Innovation-funded Longitudinal Health and Wellbeing National Core Study led by University College London (UCL) and University of Bristol (grant code: MC_PC_20059). JM is partly funded by the NIHR Applied Research Collaboration West. This work uses data accessed within UK LLC's TRE, hosted by the Secure eResearch Platform (SeRP UK). We thank the SeRP UK Team at Swansea University and NHS Digital Health and Care Wales for providing the TRE's infrastructure and support. This work uses data provided by participants of the contributing longitudinal population-based studies within the UK LLC TRE, which have been collected through their longitudinal study or as part of their care and support or interactions with UK Government services (study details are included in the appendix [pp 6&#x2013;11]). We thank the study participants and each contributing study team, including data managers, administrators, and those collecting data. We thank the NHS and particularly NHS Digital for their work in curating participants' health records and for making these available for public benefit research designed to improve health services. Finally, we acknowledge the wider input of researchers in the CONVALESCENCE Study Collaborative towards data collection and the development of infrastructure and code lists that underpinned this project.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38729195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(24)00744-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0140-6736(24)00744-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>