<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38058684</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2220-3206</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>International study of the Complex Stress Reaction Syndrome: Implications for transdiagnostic clinical practice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>803</StartPage><EndPage>815</EndPage><MedlinePgn>803-815</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5498/wjp.v13.i10.803</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The debate regarding diagnostic classification systems in psychiatry (categorial <i>vs</i> dimensional systems) has essential implications for the diagnosis, prevention and treatment of stress reactions. We previously found a unique pattern of stress reaction in a study executed during the coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic using large representative samples in two countries, and termed it the Complex Stress Reaction Syndrome (CSRS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate CSRS, Type A (psychiatric symptoms, spanning anxiety, depression, stress symptoms, and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD)), with or without long-coronavirus disease (COVID) residuals (CSRS, Type B, neuropsychiatric symptoms spanning cognitive deficits and fatigue, excluding systemic symptoms). Our two-tailed hypothesis was that CSRS is a condition related to an unrecognized type of stress reaction in daily life in the general population (Type A) or that it is related to the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection and its long-COVID residuals (Type B).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">977 individuals in four continents (North America, Europe, Australia and the Middle East) completed the online study questionnaire in six languages using the Qualtrics platform. The study was managed by six teams in six countries that promoted the study on social media. The questionnaire assessed anxiety, depression, stress symptoms and PTSD (CSRS, Type A), cognitive deficits and fatigue (CSRS, Type B). The data were analyzed using Proportion Analyses, Multivariate Analysis of Co-Variance (MANCOVA), linear regression analyses and validated clinical cutoff points.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The results of the Proportion Analyses showed that the prevalence of 4 symptoms spanning anxiety, depression, stress symptoms, and PTSD was significantly higher than the most prevalent combinations of fewer symptoms across 4 continents, age groups, and gender. This supports the transdiagnostic argument embedded in the CSRS (Type A). The same pattern of results was found in infected/recovered individuals. The prevalence of the 4 psychiatric symptoms combination was significantly greater than that of 5 and 6 symptoms, when adding cognitive deficits and fatigue, respectively. MANCOVA showed a significant three-way interaction (age &#xd7; gender &#xd7; continent). Further analyses showed that the sources of this three-way interaction were threefold relating to two sub-populations at-risk: (1) Individuals that self-identified as non-binary gender scored significantly higher on all 4 psychiatric symptoms of the CSRS, Type A at young age groups (&lt; 50 years old) in North America compared to (self-identified) women and men located in the 4 continents studied, and to other ages across the adult life span; and (2) This pattern of results (CSRS, Type A) was found also in women at young ages (&lt; 40 years old) in North America who scored higher compared to men and women in other continents and other ages. Linear regression analyses confirmed the MANCOVA results.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These results show a combined mental health risk factor related to stress reactivity, suggesting that the CSRS is sensitive to populations at risk and may be applied to future identification of other vulnerable sub-populations. It also supports the transdiagnostic approach for more accurate prevention and treatment. Time will tell if such transdiagnostic syndromes will be part of the discussions on the next revisions of the traditional classification systems or whether the crisis in psychiatry further evolves.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2023. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldstein Ferber</LastName><ForeName>Sari</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences, University of Delaware, Newark, DE 19716, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Bar Ilan University, Ramat Gan 5290002, Israel. sgf@udel.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weller</LastName><ForeName>Aron</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology and The Gonda Brain Research Center, Bar Ilan University, Ramat Gan 5290002, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayes</LastName><ForeName>Adele M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences, University of Delaware, Newark, DE 19716, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vannorsdall</LastName><ForeName>Tracy D</ForeName><Initials>TD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Department of Neurology, The Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD 21287, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ajlouni</LastName><ForeName>Yaroup</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jordan Health Aid-International, Amman 1234, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qudah</LastName><ForeName>Mo'nes</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jordan Health Aid-International, Amman 1234, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zalsman</LastName><ForeName>Gil</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geha Mental Health Center, Petah Tiqva, Israel and Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Ramat Aviv 6997801, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Molecular Imaging and Neuropathology, Department of Psychiatry, Columbia University, New York, NY 10032, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shoval</LastName><ForeName>Gal</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geha Mental Health Center, Petah Tiqva, Israel and Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Ramat Aviv 6997801, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ 08544, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jannini</LastName><ForeName>Tommaso Benedetto</ForeName><Initials>TB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Systems Medicine, Tor Vergata University of Rome, Rome 00133, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fiedler</LastName><ForeName>Racquel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology and The Gonda Brain Research Center, Bar Ilan University, Ramat Gan 5290002, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Lily X</ForeName><Initials>LX</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UNSW School of Psychology, UNSW Sydney, Sydney 2052, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shayani</LastName><ForeName>Danielle R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences, University of Delaware, Newark, DE 19716, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kachuki Dory</LastName><ForeName>Elin</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology and The Gonda Brain Research Center, Bar Ilan University, Ramat Gan 5290002, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stolowicz-Melman</LastName><ForeName>Dana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology and The Gonda Brain Research Center, Bar Ilan University, Ramat Gan 5290002, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Evans</LastName><ForeName>Connor</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, Pacific University, Forest Grove, OR 97116, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trow</LastName><ForeName>Megan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oregon Chapter of Fulbright Association, Oregon, OR 97045, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Lorenzo</LastName><ForeName>Giorgio</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Systems Medicine, Tor Vergata University of Rome, Rome 00179, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS, Fondazione Santa Lucia, Rome 00179, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rossi</LastName><ForeName>Rodolfo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Systems Medicine, Tor Vergata University of Rome, Rome 00133, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610480</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2220-3206</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Affective disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Complex Stress Reaction Syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Debate in psychiatry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress reactivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transdiagnostic</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38058684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10696285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5498/wjp.v13.i10.803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Di Nicola V, Stoyanov D. Psychiatry in crisis: At the crossroads of social sciences, the humanities, and neuroscience. Psychiatr Cri . 2021:1&#x2013;174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Nicola V, Stoyanov D. Psychiatric Nosology Revisited: At the Crossroads of Psychology and Medicine. Psychiatry Cri. 2021:31&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waszczuk MA, Jonas KG, Bornovalova M, Breen G, Bulik CM, Docherty AR, Eley TC, Hettema JM, Kotov R, Krueger RF, Lencz T, Li JJ, Vassos E, Waldman ID. Dimensional and transdiagnostic phenotypes in psychiatric genome-wide association studies. Mol Psychiatry. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10764644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37402851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solmi M, Soardo L, Kaur S, Azis M, Cabras A, Censori M, Fausti L, Besana F, Salazar de Pablo G, Fusar-Poli P. Meta-analytic prevalence of comorbid mental disorders in individuals at clinical high risk of psychosis: the case for transdiagnostic assessment. Mol Psychiatry. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10611568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37296309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JJ, Piras E, Tamburini S, Bu K, Wallach DS, Remsen B, Cantor A, Kong J, Goetz D, Hoffman KW, Bonner M, Joe P, Mueller BR, Robinson-Papp J, Lotan E, Gonen O, Malaspina D, Clemente JC. Gut and oral microbiome modulate molecular and clinical markers of schizophrenia-related symptoms: A transdiagnostic, multilevel pilot study. Psychiatry Res. 2023;326:115279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10595250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37331068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endrass T, Weiss F. Performance Monitoring: A Transdiagnostic Biomarker of Adaptive Behavior in Mental Disorders. Biol Psychiatry. 2023;93:962&#x2013;963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37197835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Griffiths K, Palmer EOC, Ker S, Liman C, Wee SN, Kollins SH, Patel R. Early trajectory of clinical global impression as a transdiagnostic predictor of psychiatric hospitalisation: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet Psychiatry. 2023;10:334&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36966787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotov R, Krueger RF, Watson D, Achenbach TM, Althoff RR, Bagby RM, Brown TA, Carpenter WT, Caspi A, Clark LA, Eaton NR, Forbes MK, Forbush KT, Goldberg D, Hasin D, Hyman SE, Ivanova MY, Lynam DR, Markon K, Miller JD, Moffitt TE, Morey LC, Mullins-Sweatt SN, Ormel J, Patrick CJ, Regier DA, Rescorla L, Ruggero CJ, Samuel DB, Sellbom M, Simms LJ, Skodol AE, Slade T, South SC, Tackett JL, Waldman ID, Waszczuk MA, Widiger TA, Wright AGC, Zimmerman M. The Hierarchical Taxonomy of Psychopathology (HiTOP): A dimensional alternative to traditional nosologies. J Abnorm Psychol. 2017;126:454&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28333488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey BJ, Craddock N, Cuthbert BN, Hyman SE, Lee FS, Ressler KJ. DSM-5 and RDoC: progress in psychiatry research? Nat Rev Neurosci. 2013;14:810&#x2013;814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4372467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24135697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reininghaus U, B&#xf6;hnke JR, Chavez-Baldini U, Gibbons R, Ivleva E, Clementz BA, Pearlson GD, Keshavan MS, Sweeney JA, Tamminga CA. Transdiagnostic dimensions of psychosis in the Bipolar-Schizophrenia Network on Intermediate Phenotypes (B-SNIP) World Psychiatry. 2019;18:67&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6313235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30600629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caraci F, Enna SJ, Zohar J, Racagni G, Zalsman G, van den Brink W, Kasper S, Koob GF, Pariante CM, Piazza PV, Yamada K, Spedding M, Drago F. A new nomenclature for classifying psychotropic drugs. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2017;83:1614&#x2013;1616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5510058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28401576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sambuco N, Bradley MM, Lang PJ. Hippocampal and amygdala volumes vary with transdiagnostic psychopathological dimensions of distress, anxious arousal, and trauma. Biol Psychol. 2023;177:108501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36646300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudmundsson OO, Walters GB, Ingason A, Johansson S, Zayats T, Athanasiu L, Sonderby IE, Gustafsson O, Nawaz MS, Jonsson GF, Jonsson L, Knappskog PM, Ingvarsdottir E, Davidsdottir K, Djurovic S, Knudsen GPS, Askeland RB, Haraldsdottir GS, Baldursson G, Magnusson P, Sigurdsson E, Gudbjartsson DF, Stefansson H, Andreassen OA, Haavik J, Reichborn-Kjennerud T, Stefansson K. Attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder shares copy number variant risk with schizophrenia and autism spectrum disorder. Transl Psychiatry. 2019;9:258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6797719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31624239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong Q, Scarpazza C, Dai J, He M, Xu X, Shi Y, Zhou B, Vieira S, McCrory E, Ai Y, Yang C, Zhang F, Lui S, Mechelli A. A transdiagnostic neuroanatomical signature of psychiatric illness. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2019;44:869&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6461829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30127342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkes L, Satterthwaite TD, Bassett DS. Towards precise resting-state fMRI biomarkers in psychiatry: synthesizing developments in transdiagnostic research, dimensional models of psychopathology, and normative neurodevelopment. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2020;65:120&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7770086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33242721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein Ferber S, Shoval G, Weller A, Zalsman G. Not one thing at a time: When concomitant multiple stressors produce a transdiagnostic clinical picture. World J Psychiatry. 2023;13:402&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10401502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37547732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darwin C. On the Origin of Species. New York: PF Collier &amp; Son, 2007: 1809-1822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus RS, Folkman S. Stress, Appraisal, and Coping. New York: Springer, 2009: 444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferber SG, Weller A, Maor R, Feldman Y, Harel-Fisch Y, Mikulincer M. Perceived social support in the social distancing era: the association between circles of potential support and COVID-19 reactive psychopathology. Anxiety Stress Coping. 2022;35:58&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34652983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasrallah HA. Re-inventing the DSM as a transdiagnostic model: Psychiatric disorders are extensively interconnected. Ann Clin Psychiatry. 2021;33:148&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34398730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellini G, Castellani W, Lelli L, Sauro CL, Dini C, Lazzeretti L, Bencini L, Mannucci E, Ricca V. Association between resting energy expenditure, psychopathology and HPA-axis in eating disorders. World J Clin Cases. 2014;2:257&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4097152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25032200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherry KE, De Vito AN, Calamia MR, Elliott EM, Yu S, Sampson L, Galea S, Mansoor M, McKneely KJ, Nguyen QP. Disaster stressors and psychological well-being in older adults after a flood. Psychol Aging. 2021;36:660&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33856820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corley SS, Ornstein KA, Rasul R, Lieberman-Cribbin W, Maisel H, Taioli E, Schwartz RM. Mental Health Effects of Hurricane Sandy on Older Adults. J Appl Gerontol. 2022;41:1131&#x2013;1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34752154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Florencio LL, Navarro-Pardo E, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Torres-Macho J, Pellicer-Valero OJ. Clustering analysis reveals different profiles associating long-term post-COVID symptoms, COVID-19 symptoms at hospital admission and previous medical co-morbidities in previously hospitalized COVID-19 survivors. Infection. 2023;51:61&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9028890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35451721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waddell SL, Jayaweera DT, Mirsaeidi M, Beier JC, Kumar N. Perspectives on the Health Effects of Hurricanes: A Review and Challenges. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33803162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein Ferber S, Shoval G, Rossi R, Trezza V, Di Lorenzo G, Zalsman G, Weller A, Mann JJ. Transdiagnostic considerations of mental health for the post-COVID era: Lessons from the first surge of the pandemic. World J Clin Cases. 2023;11:809&#x2013;820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9928692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36818632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong J, Lipsitz O, Nasri F, Lui LMW, Gill H, Phan L, Chen-Li D, Iacobucci M, Ho R, Majeed A, McIntyre RS. Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on mental health in the general population: A systematic review. J Affect Disord. 2020;277:55&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7413844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32799105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce M, Hope H, Ford T, Hatch S, Hotopf M, John A, Kontopantelis E, Webb R, Wessely S, McManus S, Abel KM. Mental health before and during the COVID-19 pandemic: a longitudinal probability sample survey of the UK population. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;7:883&#x2013;892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7373389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32707037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi R, Socci V, Pacitti F, Di Lorenzo G, Di Marco A, Siracusano A, Rossi A. Mental Health Outcomes Among Frontline and Second-Line Health Care Workers During the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Pandemic in Italy. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3:e2010185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7256664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32463467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization.  Mental health in emergencies 2022. [cited 31 July 2023]. Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/mental-health-in-emergencies .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein Ferber S, Shoval G, Zalsman G, Weller A. Does COVID-19 related symptomatology indicate a transdiagnostic neuropsychiatric disorder? - Multidisciplinary implications. World J Psychiatry. 2022;12:1004&#x2013;1015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9476837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36158308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JB, L&#xf6;we B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166:1092&#x2013;1097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16717171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Strine TW, Spitzer RL, Williams JB, Berry JT, Mokdad AH. The PHQ-8 as a measure of current depression in the general population. J Affect Disord. 2009;114:163&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18752852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Kamarck T, Mermelstein R. A global measure of perceived stress. J Health Soc Behav. 1983;24:385&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6668417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cloitre M, Hyland P, Prins A, Shevlin M. The international trauma questionnaire (ITQ) measures reliable and clinically significant treatment-related change in PTSD and complex PTSD. Eur J Psychotraumatol. 2021;12:1930961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34211640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strober LB, Binder A, Nikelshpur OM, Chiaravalloti N, DeLuca J. The Perceived Deficits Questionnaire: Perception, Deficit, or Distress? Int J MS Care. 2016;18:183&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4984790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27551243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linnhoff S, Haghikia A, Zaehle T. Cognitive fatigue-related sensory gating deficits in people with multiple sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis. 2023;176:105950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36493977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newcomb ME, Hill R, Buehler K, Ryan DT, Whitton SW, Mustanski B. High Burden of Mental Health Problems, Substance Use, Violence, and Related Psychosocial Factors in Transgender, Non-Binary, and Gender Diverse Youth and Young Adults. Arch Sex Behav. 2020;49:645&#x2013;659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7018588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31485801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuno E, Budge S. Non-binary/Genderqueer Identities: a Critical Review of the Literature. Curr Sex Health Rep. 2017;9:116&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Graaf NM, Huisman B, Cohen-Kettenis PT, Twist J, Hage K, Carmichael P, Kreukels BPC, Steensma TD. Psychological Functioning in Non-binary Identifying Adolescents and Adults. J Sex Marital Ther. 2021;47:773&#x2013;784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34344272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyne CA, Poquiz JL, Janssen A, Chen D. Evidence-Based Psychological Practice for Transgender and Non-Binary Youth: Defining the Need, Framework for Treatment Adaptation, and Future Directions. Evid Based Pract Child Adolesc Ment Health . 2020;5:340&#x2013;353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kung KTF. Autistic Traits, Gender Minority Stress, and Mental Health in Transgender and Non-Binary Adults. J Autism Dev Disord. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36652125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschfeld RM, Cross CK. Epidemiology of affective disorders. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 1982;39:35&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7055407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Graaf R, Bijl RV, Smit F, Vollebergh WA, Spijker J. Risk factors for 12-month comorbidity of mood, anxiety, and substance use disorders: findings from the Netherlands Mental Health Survey and Incidence Study. Am J Psychiatry. 2002;159:620&#x2013;629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11925301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi R, Socci V, Pacitti F, Mensi S, Di Marco A, Siracusano A, Di Lorenzo G. Mental Health Outcomes Among Healthcare Workers and the General Population During the COVID-19 in Italy. Front Psychol. 2020;11:608986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33363500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alibudbud R. Gender in mental health: Comparison of the rate and social factors of depression, anxiety, and stress among young adult Filipino heterosexual cisgender men and women and LGBT+ individuals. Int J Soc Psychiatry. 2023;69:430&#x2013;437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35734786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrara F, Zovi A, Masi M, Langella R, Trama U, Boccellino M, Vitiello A. Long COVID could become a widespread post-pandemic disease? A debate on the organs most affected. Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol. 2023;396:1583&#x2013;1589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9918819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36773054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley SE, Karlson EW, Levitan EB, Levy B, McComsey GA, McCorkell L, Nadkarni GN, Parthasarathy S, Singh U, Walker TA, Selvaggi CA, Shinnick DJ, Schulte CCM, Atchley-Challenner R, Alba GA, Alicic R, Altman N, Anglin K, Argueta U, Ashktorab H, Baslet G, Bassett IV, Bateman L, Bedi B, Bhattacharyya S, Bind MA, Blomkalns AL, Bonilla H, Bush PA, Castro M, Chan J, Charney AW, Chen P, Chibnik LB, Chu HY, Clifton RG, Costantine MM, Cribbs SK, Davila Nieves SI, Deeks SG, Duven A, Emery IF, Erdmann N, Erlandson KM, Ernst KC, Farah-Abraham R, Farner CE, Feuerriegel EM, Fleurimont J, Fonseca V, Franko N, Gainer V, Gander JC, Gardner EM, Geng LN, Gibson KS, Go M, Goldman JD, Grebe H, Greenway FL, Habli M, Hafner J, Han JE, Hanson KA, Heath J, Hernandez C, Hess R, Hodder SL, Hoffman MK, Hoover SE, Huang B, Hughes BL, Jagannathan P, John J, Jordan MR, Katz SD, Kaufman ES, Kelly JD, Kelly SW, Kemp MM, Kirwan JP, Klein JD, Knox KS, Krishnan JA, Kumar A, Laiyemo AO, Lambert AA, Lanca M, Lee-Iannotti JK, Logarbo BP, Longo MT, Luciano CA, Lutrick K, Maley JH, Marathe JG, Marconi V, Marshall GD, Martin CF, Matusov Y, Mehari A, Mendez-Figueroa H, Mermelstein R, Metz TD, Morse R, Mosier J, Mouchati C, Mullington J, Murphy SN, Neuman RB, Nikolich JZ, Ofotokun I, Ojemakinde E, Palatnik A, Palomares K, Parimon T, Parry S, Patterson JE, Patterson TF, Patzer RE, Peluso MJ, Pemu P, Pettker CM, Plunkett BA, Pogreba-Brown K, Poppas A, Quigley JG, Reddy U, Reece R, Reeder H, Reeves WB, Reiman EM, Rischard F, Rosand J, Rouse DJ, Ruff A, Saade G, Sandoval GJ, Schlater SM, Shepherd F, Sherif ZA, Simhan H, Singer NG, Skupski DW, Sowles A, Sparks JA, Sukhera FI, Taylor BS, Teunis L, Thomas RJ, Thorp JM, Thuluvath P, Ticotsky A, Tita AT, Tuttle KR, Urdaneta AE, Valdivieso D, VanWagoner TM, Vasey A, Verduzco-Gutierrez M, Wallace ZS, Ward HD, Warren DE, Weiner SJ, Welch S, Whiteheart SW, Wiley Z, Wisnivesky JP, Yee LM, Zisis S, Horwitz LI, Foulkes AS RECOVER Consortium. Development of a Definition of Postacute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection. JAMA. 2023;329:1934&#x2013;1946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10214179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vaus J, Hornsey MJ, Kuppens P, Bastian B. Exploring the East-West Divide in Prevalence of Affective Disorder: A Case for Cultural Differences in Coping With Negative Emotion. Pers Soc Psychol Rev. 2018;22:285&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29034806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gradus JL. Prevalence and prognosis of stress disorders: a review of the epidemiologic literature. Clin Epidemiol. 2017;9:251&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5422316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28496365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simkus J.  Convenience Sampling: Definition, Method and Examples. Psychology 2023. [cited 31 July 2023]. Available from: https://www.simplypsychology.org/convenience-sampling.html .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce M, McManus S, Jessop C, John A, Hotopf M, Ford T, Hatch S, Wessely S, Abel KM. Says who? The significance of sampling in mental health surveys during COVID-19. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;7:567&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7266586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32502467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan RM, Chambers DA, Glasgow RE. Big data and large sample size: a cautionary note on the potential for bias. Clin Transl Sci. 2014;7:342&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5439816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25043853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>