<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37400780</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6963</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC health services research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Health Serv Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Responsive and resilient healthcare? 'Moments of Resilience' in post-hospitalisation services for COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>720</StartPage><MedlinePgn>720</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">720</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12913-023-09645-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">COVID-19 caused disruption to healthcare services globally, resulting in high numbers of hospital admissions and with those discharged often requiring ongoing support. Within the UK, post-discharge services typically developed organically and were shaped over time by local need, funding, and government guidance. Drawing on the Moments of Resilience framework, we explore the development of follow-up services for hospitalised patients by considering the links between resilience at different system levels over time. This study contributes to the resilient healthcare literature by providing empirical evidence of how diverse stakeholders developed and adapted services for patients following hospitalisation with COVID-19 and how action taken at one system level influenced another.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Qualitative research comprising comparative case studies based on interviews. Across three purposively selected case studies (two in England, one in Wales) a total of 33 semi-structured interviews were conducted with clinical staff, managers and commissioners who had been involved in developing and/or implementing post-hospitalisation follow-up services. The interviews were audio-recorded and professionally transcribed. Analysis was conducted with the aid of NVivo 12.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Case studies demonstrated three distinct examples of how healthcare organisations developed and adapted their post-discharge care provision for patients, post-hospitalisation with COVID-19. Initially, the moral distress of witnessing the impact of COVID-19 on patients who were being discharged coupled with local demand gave clinical staff the impetus to take action. Clinical staff and managers worked closely to plan and deliver organisations' responses. Funding availability and other contextual factors influenced situated and immediate responses and structural adaptations to the post-hospitalisation services. As the pandemic evolved, NHS England and the Welsh government provided funding and guidance for systemic adaptations to post-COVID assessment clinics. Over time, adaptations made at the situated, structural, and systemic levels influenced the resilience and sustainability of services.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This paper addresses understudied, yet inherently important, aspects of resilience in healthcare by exploring when and where resilience occurs across the healthcare system and how action taken at one system level influenced another. Comparison across the case studies showed that organisations responded in similar and different ways and on varying timescales to a disruption and national level strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Overton</LastName><ForeName>Charlotte</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Population Health Sciences, University of Leicester, Leicester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Emerson</LastName><ForeName>Tristan</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Population Health Sciences, University of Leicester, Leicester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>A Evans</LastName><ForeName>Rachael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Leicester NIHR Biomedical Research Centre - Respiratory, University Hospitals of Leicester NHS Trust, Leicester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Sciences, University of Leicester, Leicester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Armstrong</LastName><ForeName>Natalie</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Population Health Sciences, University of Leicester, Leicester, UK. Natalie.Armstrong@le.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>PCR-03-C19</GrantID><Agency>National Institute for Health and Care Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Health Serv Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088677</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6963</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000359" MajorTopicYN="N">Aftercare</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010351" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Discharge</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003695" MajorTopicYN="N">Delivery of Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006268" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Facilities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthcare</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resilience framework</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37400780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10316547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-023-09645-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12913-023-09645-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Turenne CP, Gautier L, Degroote S, Guillard E, Chabrol F, Ridde V. Conceptual analysis of health systems resilience: a scoping review. Soc Sci Med. 2019;232:168&#x2013;80. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2019.04.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2019.04.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31100697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiig S, O&#x2019;Hara JK. Resilient and responsive healthcare services and systems: challenges and opportunities in a changing world. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021;21(1):1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1186/s12913-021-07087-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-021-07087-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8487709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34602063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macrae C, Wiig S. Resilience: From Practice to Theory and Back Again. Exploring resilience a scientific journey from practice to theory. Springer Open. 2019:121&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiig S, Fahlbruch B. Exploring Resilience&#x2013;An introduction. Exploring resilience: Springer, Cham; 2019. pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowling J, Jason K, Krinner LM, Vercruysse CM, Reichard G. Definition and operationalization of resilience in qualitative health literature: a scoping review. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2021:1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macrae C. Moments of resilience: time, space and the organisation of safety in complex sociotechnical systems. Exploring resilience: Springer, Cham; 2019. pp. 15&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paschoalotto MAC, Lazzari EA, Rocha R, Massuda A, Castro MC. Health systems resilience: is it time to revisit resilience after COVID-19? Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2023:115716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9851720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36702027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ewert B, Wallenburg I, Winblad U, Bal R. Any lessons to learn? Pathways and impasses towards health system resilience in post-pandemic times. Health Econ Policy Law. 2023;18(1):66&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1017/S1744133122000238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1744133122000238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36121039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilson L, Ellokor S, Lehmann U, Brady L. Organizational change and everyday health system resilience: lessons from Cape Town, South Africa. Soc Sci Med. 2020;266:113407. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7538378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33068870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchet K, Nam SL, Ramalingam B, Pozo-Martin F. Governance and capacity to manage resilience of health systems: towards a new conceptual framework. Int J health policy Manage. 2017;6(8):431. doi: 10.15171/ijhpm.2017.36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15171/ijhpm.2017.36</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5553211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28812842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson JE, Ross AJ, Macrae C, Wiig S. Defining adaptive capacity in healthcare: a new framework for researching resilient performance. Appl Ergon. 2020;87:103111. doi: 10.1016/j.apergo.2020.103111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apergo.2020.103111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32310111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GOV.UK. Coronavirus (COVID-19) in the UK 2022 [cited 2022 15/12/22]. Available from: https://coronavirus.data.gov.uk/details/healthcare.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsh Government. NHS beds, admissions and hospitalisations during the coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic 2022 [cited 2022 15/12/22]. Available from: https://www.gov.wales/nhs-beds-admissions-and-hospitalisations-during-coronavirus-covid-19-pandemic.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, Leavy OC, Richardson M, Elneima O, McCauley H, Shikotra A, et al. Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine; 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9034855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35472304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK: 1 December 2022 [cited 2022 15/12/22]. Available from: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/1december</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown DA, O&#x2019;Brien KK. Conceptualising long COVID as an episodic health condition. BMJ Global Health. 2021;6(9):e007004. doi: 10.1136/bmjgh-2021-007004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2021-007004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8460526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34551971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Thoracic Society. Guidance on Respiratory Follow Up of Patients with a Clinico-Radiological Diagnosis of COVID-19 Pneumonia 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID. 2020. Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England. Long COVID patients to get help at more than 60 clinics 2020 [cited 2022 15/12/22]. Available from: https://www.england.nhs.uk/2020/12/long-covid-patients-to-get-help-at-more-than-60-clinics/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England. The NHS plan for improving long COVID services. 2022. Available from: https://www.england.nhs.uk/publication/the-nhs-plan-for-improving-long-covid-services/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsh Government. All Wales Rehabilitation Framework: Principles to achieve a person-centred value-based approach 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsh Government. Adferiad (Recovery) long COVID programme. How we will work with NHS Wales to support people with Long COVID. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidhu MS, Ford GA, Fulop NJ, Roberts CM. Learning networks in the pandemic: mobilising evidence for improvement. BMJ. 2022;379:e070215. doi: 10.1136/bmj-2022-070215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2022-070215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36207025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xe9;cary S, Gaboury I, Poirier S, Garcia C, Simpson S, Bull M et al. Humility and acceptance: working within our limits with long covid and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2021;51(5): 97&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33930983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, McAuley H, Harrison EM, Shikotra A, Singapuri A, Sereno M, et al. Physical, cognitive, and mental health impacts of COVID-19 after hospitalisation (PHOSP-COVID): a UK multicentre, prospective cohort study. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine. 2021;9(11):1275&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00383-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00383-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34627560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin RK. Case Study Research: design and methods. Sage; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houchen-Wolloff L, Overton C, Ibbetson A, Walters A, et al. A typology of healthcare pathways for adults after hospitalisation for COVID-19 in the UK: towards understanding clinical and cost-effectiveness. ERJ Open Research. In press, available in Early View 10.1183/23120541.00565-2022 onstant comparison met</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schensul SL, Schensul JJ, LeCompte MD. Essential Ethnographic Methods: observations, interviews, and questionnaires. Rowman Altamira; 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dye JF, Schatz IM, Rosenberg BA, Coleman ST. Constant comparison method: a kaleidoscope of data. qualitative Rep. 2000;4(1/2):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qualitative Res Psychol. 2006;3(2):77&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1191/1478088706qp063oa.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juvet TM, Corbaz-Kurth S, Roos P, Benzakour L, Cereghetti S, Moullec G, et al. Adapting to the unexpected: problematic work situations and resilience strategies in healthcare institutions during the COVID-19 pandemic&#x2019;s first wave. Saf Sci. 2021;139:105277. doi: 10.1016/j.ssci.2021.105277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssci.2021.105277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8545718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34720426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleming P, Thomas S, Williams D, Kennedy J, Burke S. Implications for health system reform, workforce recovery and rebuilding in the context of the great recession and COVID-19: a case study of workforce trends in Ireland 2008&#x2013;2021. Hum Resour Health. 2022;20(1):1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1186/s12960-022-00747-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12960-022-00747-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9134726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35619111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiig S, Aase K, Billett S, Canfield C, R&#xf8;ise O, Nj&#xe5; O, et al. Defining the boundaries and operational concepts of resilience in the resilience in healthcare research program. BMC Health Serv Res. 2020;20(1):1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1186/s12913-020-05224-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-020-05224-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7168985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32306981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuijper S, Felder M, Bal R, Wallenburg I. Assembling care: how nurses organise care in uncharted territory and in times of pandemic. Sociol Health Illn. 2022;44(8):1305&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1111/1467-9566.13508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1467-9566.13508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35929533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyng HB, Macrae C, Guise V, Haraldseid-Driftland C, Fagerdal B, Schibevaag L, et al. Balancing adaptation and innovation for resilience in healthcare&#x2013;a metasynthesis of narratives. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021;21(1):1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1186/s12913-021-06592-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-021-06592-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8325788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34332581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ree E, Ellis LA, Wiig S. Managers&#x2019; role in supporting resilience in healthcare: a proposed model of how managers contribute to a healthcare system&#x2019;s overall resilience. Int J Health Gov. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barasa E, Mbau R, Gilson L. What is resilience and how can it be nurtured? A systematic review of empirical literature on organizational resilience. Int J health policy Manage. 2018;7(6):491. doi: 10.15171/ijhpm.2018.06.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15171/ijhpm.2018.06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6015506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29935126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bal R, de Graaff B, van de Bovenkamp H, Wallenburg I. Practicing Corona&#x2013;Towards a research agenda of health policies. Health Policy. 2020;124(7):671&#x2013;3. doi: 10.1016/j.healthpol.2020.05.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.healthpol.2020.05.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32425282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>