<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36415469</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>medRxiv : the preprint server for health sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>medRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Characterizing and Predicting Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS CoV-2 infection (PASC) in a Large Academic Medical Center in the US.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2022.10.21.22281356</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1101/2022.10.21.22281356</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A growing number of Coronavirus Disease-2019 (COVID-19) survivors are affected by Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS CoV-2 infection (PACS). Using electronic health records data, we aimed to characterize PASC-associated diagnoses and to develop risk prediction models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In our cohort of 63,675 COVID-19 positive patients, 1,724 (2.7 %) had a recorded PASC diagnosis. We used a case control study design and phenome-wide scans to characterize PASC-associated phenotypes of the pre-, acute-, and post-COVID-19 periods. We also integrated PASC-associated phenotypes into Phenotype Risk Scores (PheRSs) and evaluated their predictive performance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In the post-COVID-19 period, known PASC symptoms (e.g., shortness of breath, malaise/fatigue) and musculoskeletal, infectious, and digestive disorders were enriched among PASC cases. We found seven phenotypes in the pre-COVID-19 period (e.g., irritable bowel syndrome, concussion, nausea/vomiting) and 69 phenotypes in the acute-COVID-19 period (predominantly respiratory, circulatory, neurological) associated with PASC. The derived pre- and acute-COVID-19 PheRSs stratified risk well, e.g., the combined PheRSs identified a quarter of the COVID-19 positive cohort with an at least 2.9-fold increased risk for PASC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The uncovered PASC-associated diagnoses across categories highlighted a complex arrangement of presenting and likely predisposing features, some with a potential for risk stratification approaches.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fritsche</LastName><ForeName>Lars G</ForeName><Initials>LG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, University of Michigan School of Public Health, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Precision Health Data Science, University of Michigan School of Public Health, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Weijia</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, University of Michigan School of Public Health, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Precision Health Data Science, University of Michigan School of Public Health, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Admon</LastName><ForeName>Andrew J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, University of Michigan Medical School, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, University of Michigan School of Public Health, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VA Center for Clinical Management Research, LTC Charles S. Kettles VA Medical Center, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mukherjee</LastName><ForeName>Bhramar</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, University of Michigan School of Public Health, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Precision Health Data Science, University of Michigan School of Public Health, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, University of Michigan School of Public Health, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Michigan Institute for Data Science, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K08 HL155407</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P30 CA046592</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>medRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101767986</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateIn"><RefSource>J Clin Med. 2023 Feb 07;12(4):1328. doi: 10.3390/jcm12041328</RefSource><PMID Version="1">36835863</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus Disease-2019</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS CoV-2 infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electronic health records</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phenome-wide association study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phenotype risk score</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID conditions</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36415469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9681058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2022.10.21.22281356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2022.10.21.22281356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Corporation Microsoft. Bing COVID-19 Tracker. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594:259&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global Prevalence of Post COVID-19 Condition or Long COVID: A Meta-Analysis and Systematic Review. J Infect Dis. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Ayuzo Del Valle NC, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, et al. Long-COVID in children and adolescents: a systematic review and metaanalyses. Sci Rep. 2022;12:9950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9226045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35739136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Post-COVID Conditions: Information for Healthcare Providers. Avaliable: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-index.html.
https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-index.html2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Public Health Recommendations. Avaliable: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-public-health-recs.html.
https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-public-health-recs.html2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Long COVID or Post-COVID Conditions. Avaliable: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html.
https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-conditions.html2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM. Chronic COVID syndrome: Need for an appropriate medical terminology for long-COVID and COVID long-haulers. J Med Virol. 2021;93:2555&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33095459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath A. Long-Haul COVID. Neurology. 2020;95:559&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, Rivera SC, McMullan C, Chandan JS, et al. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med. 2021;114:428&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal M, Abo Omirah M, Hussein A, Saeed H. Assessment and characterisation of post-COVID-19 manifestations. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:e13746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chippa V, Aleem A, Anjum F. Post Acute Coronavirus (COVID-19) Syndrome. StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing Copyright &#xa9; 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.; 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher A, Balfanz P, Cornelissen C, M&#xfc;ller A, Bergs I, Marx N, et al. Follow up of patients with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): Pulmonary and extrapulmonary disease sequelae. Respiratory medicine. 2020;174:106197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33120193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanou MI, Palaiodimou L, Bakola E, Smyrnis N, Papadopoulou M, Paraskevas GP, et al. Neurological manifestations of long-COVID syndrome: a narrative review. Ther Adv Chronic Dis. 2022;13:20406223221076890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8859684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35198136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re&#x2019;em Y, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Sillett R, Zhu L, Mendel J, Camplisson I, Dercon Q, et al. Neurological and psychiatric risk trajectories after SARS-CoV-2 infection: an analysis of 2-year retrospective cohort studies including 1&#x2008;284&#x2008;437 patients. Lancet Psychiatry. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9385200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35987197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj L, Kannapadi NV, Briggs J, Seal SM, Battaglini D, Fanning J, et al. Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: A meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci. 2022;434:120162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8798975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Wang CY, Wang SI, Wei JC. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes in COVID-19 survivors among non-vaccinated population: A retrospective cohort study from the TriNetX US collaborative networks. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;53:101619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9366236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35971425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu E, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Long-term neurologic outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9671811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36138154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Bermingham C, Pouwels KB, Glickman M, Nafilyan V, Zaccardi F, et al. Trajectory of long covid symptoms after covid-19 vaccination: community based cohort study. Bmj. 2022;377:e069676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35584816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Bowe B, Xie Y. Long COVID after breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nature Medicine. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9307472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35614233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F, Tomasoni D, Falcinella C, Barbanotti D, Castoldi R, Mul&#xe8; G, et al. Female gender is associated with long COVID syndrome: a prospective cohort study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28:611.e9&#x2013;.e16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet. 2022;399:2263&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35717982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo SM, Liu TC, Motwani Y, Sim MS, Viswanathan N, Samras N, et al. Factors Associated with Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (PASC) After Diagnosis of Symptomatic COVID-19 in the Inpatient and Outpatient Setting in a Diverse Cohort. J Gen Intern Med. 2022;37:1988&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8989256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35391623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27:626&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia C, Zurbuchen Y, Taeschler P, Ballouz T, Menges D, Hasler S, et al. Immunoglobulin signature predicts risk of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Commun. 2022;13:446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8789854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35078982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaff ER, Girvin AT, Bennett TD, Bhatia A, Brooks IM, Deer RR, et al. Identifying who has long COVID in the USA: a machine learning approach using N3C data. Lancet Digit Health. 2022;4:e532&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9110014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35589549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, Ng RH, Wang K, Choi J, et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185:881&#x2013;95 e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvatore M, Beesley LJ, Fritsche LG, Hanauer D, Shi X, Mondul AM, et al. Phenotype risk scores (PheRS) for pancreatic cancer using time-stamped electronic health record data: Discovery and validation in two large biobanks. J Biomed Inform. 2021;113:103652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7855433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33279681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvatore M, Gu T, Mack JA, Prabhu Sankar S, Patil S, Valley TS, et al. A Phenome-Wide Association Study (PheWAS) of COVID-19 Outcomes by Race Using the Electronic Health Records Data in Michigan Medicine. J Clin Med. 2021;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8037108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33805886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estiri H, Strasser ZH, Brat GA, Semenov YR, Consortium for Characterization of C-bEHR, Patel CJ, et al. Evolving phenotypes of non-hospitalized patients that indicate long COVID. BMC Med. 2021;19:249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34565368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Center for Immunization and Respiratory Diseases (NCIRD); Division of Viral Diseases. Evaluating and Caring for Patients with Post-COVID Conditions: Interim Guidance. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke P, Melendez R. National Neighborhood Data Archive (NaNDA): Neighborhood Socioeconomic and Demographic Characteristics by Tract, United States, 2000&#x2013;2010. In: National Neighborhood Data Archive (NaNDA), editor. openICPSR-111107, nanda_ses2000&#x2013;2010_01P.* ed 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melendez R, Clarke P, Khan A, Gomez-Lopez I, Li M, Chenoweth M. National Neighborhood Data Archive (NaNDA): Socioeconomic Status and Demographic Characteristics of ZIP Code Tabulation Areas, United States, 2008&#x2013;2017. ICPSR - Interuniversity Consortium for Political and Social Research. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasparini A. comorbidity: An R package for computing comorbidity scores. Journal of Open Source Software. 2018;3:648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elixhauser A, Steiner C, Harris DR, Coffey RM. Comorbidity measures for use with administrative data. Med Care. 1998;36:8&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9431328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu P, Gifford A, Meng X, Li X, Campbell H, Varley T, et al. Mapping ICD-10 and ICD10-CM Codes to Phecodes: Workflow Development and Initial Evaluation. JMIR Med Inform. 2019;7:e14325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6911227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31553307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll RJ, Bastarache L, Denny JC. R PheWAS: data analysis and plotting tools for phenome-wide association studies in the R environment. Bioinformatics. 2014;30:2375&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4133579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24733291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho DE, Imai K, King G, Stuart EA. MatchIt: Nonparametric Preprocessing for Parametric Causal Inference. J Stat Softw. 2011;42:1&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman JH, Hastie T, Tibshirani R. Regularization Paths for Generalized Linear Models via Coordinate Descent. J Stat Softw. 2010;33:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2929880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20808728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoerl AE, Kennard RW. Ridge Regression: Biased Estimation for Nonorthogonal Problems. Technometrics. 1970;12:55&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangiafico S. rcompanion: Functions to Support Extension Education Program Evaluation. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Signorell A. {DescTools}: Tools for Descriptive Statistics. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-&#xc1;lvarez MX, I&#xe1;cio V. {ROCnReg}: An {R} Package for Receiver Operating Characteristic Curve Inference With and Without Covariates. The R Journal. 2021;13:525&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosmidis I. {brglm2}: Bias Reduction in Generalized Linear Models. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. Vienna, Austria: R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osmanov IM, Spiridonova E, Bobkova P, Gamirova A, Shikhaleva A, Andreeva M, et al. Risk factors for post-COVID-19 condition in previously hospitalised children using the ISARIC Global follow-up protocol: a prospective cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2022;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8576804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34210789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vodnar DC, Mitrea L, Teleky BE, Szabo K, Calinoiu LF, Nemes SA, et al. Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) Caused by (SARS-CoV-2) Infections: A Real Challenge for Human Gut Microbiota. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2020;10:575559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7756003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33363049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Hall S, Vitetta L. Altered gut microbial metabolites could mediate the effects of risk factors in Covid-19. Rev Med Virol. 2021;31:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7995004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34546607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Vitetta L. Gut-brain axis in the neurological comorbidity of COVID-19. Brain Commun. 2021;3:fcab118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8195160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34169281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apple AC, Oddi A, Peluso MJ, Asken BM, Henrich TJ, Kelly JD, et al. Risk factors and abnormal cerebrospinal fluid associate with cognitive symptoms after mild COVID-19. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2022;9:221&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8862406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35043593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings G, Monaghan A, Xue F, Mockler D, Romero-Ortu&#xf1;o R. A Systematic Review of Persistent Symptoms and Residual Abnormal Functioning following Acute COVID-19: Ongoing Symptomatic Phase vs. Post-COVID-19 Syndrome. J Clin Med. 2021;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8708187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34945213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang YR, Oh JY, Lee JH, Small PM, Chung KF, Song WJ. Long-COVID severe refractory cough: discussion of a case with 6-week longitudinal cough characterization. Asia Pac Allergy. 2022;12:e19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9066079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35571551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Pellicer-Valero OJ, Navarro-Pardo E, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, Florencio LL, Guijarro C, et al. Symptoms Experienced at the Acute Phase of SARS-CoV-2 Infection as Risk Factor of Long-term Post-COVID Symptoms: The LONG-COVID-EXP-CM Multicenter Study. International Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2022;116:241&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8743274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35017102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera Martimbianco AL, Pacheco RL, Bagattini &#xc2; M, Riera R. Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID-19: A systematic review. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75:e14357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8236920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33977626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen MS, Kristiansen MF, Hanusson KD, Danielsen ME, B &#xc1;S, Gaini S, et al. Long COVID in the Faroe Islands: A Longitudinal Study Among Nonhospitalized Patients. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e4058&#x2013;e63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7799340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33252665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares MN, Eggelbusch M, Naddaf E, Gerrits KHL, van der Schaaf M, van den Borst B, et al. Skeletal muscle alterations in patients with acute Covid-19 and post-acute sequelae of Covid-19. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022;13:11&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8818659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34997689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28:583&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35132265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thabane L, Mbuagbaw L, Zhang S, Samaan Z, Marcucci M, Ye C, et al. A tutorial on sensitivity analyses in clinical trials: the what, why, when and how. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2013;13:92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3720188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23855337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgonovo E, Plischke E. Sensitivity analysis: A review of recent advances. European Journal of Operational Research. 2016;248:869&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell ML, Catalfamo CJ, Farland LV, Ernst KC, Jacobs ET, Klimentidis YC, et al. Postacute sequelae of COVID-19 in a non-hospitalized cohort: Results from the Arizona CoVHORT. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0254347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8336814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34347785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson EJ, Williams DM, Walker AJ, Mitchell RE, Niedzwiedz CL, Yang TC, et al. Long COVID burden and risk factors in 10 UK longitudinal studies and electronic health records. Nat Commun. 2022;13:3528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9240035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35764621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitaker M, Elliott J, Chadeau-Hyam M, Riley S, Darzi A, Cooke G, et al. Persistent COVID-19 symptoms in a community study of 606,434 people in England. Nat Commun. 2022;13:1957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9005552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35413949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9034855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35472304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A&#x2019;Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. Bmj. 2020;370:m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brackel CLH, Lap CR, Buddingh EP, van Houten MA, van der Sande L, Langereis EJ, et al. Pediatric long-COVID: An overlooked phenomenon? Pediatr Pulmonol. 2021;56:2495&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34102037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkin A, Davison J, Tarrant R, Ross D, Halpin S, Simms A, et al. A Multidisciplinary NHS COVID-19 Service to Manage Post-COVID-19 Syndrome in the Community. J Prim Care Community Health. 2021;12:21501327211010994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8064663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33880955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Center for Health Statistics. Long COVID Household Pulse Survey. Avaliable: https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/covid19/pulse/long-covid.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Foer D, MacPhaul E, Lo YC, Bates DW, Zhou L. PASCLex: A comprehensive post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) symptom lexicon derived from electronic health record clinical notes. J Biomed Inform. 2022;125:103951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8590503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34785382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripepi G, Jager KJ, Dekker FW, Zoccali C. Selection Bias and Information Bias in Clinical Research. Nephron Clinical Practice. 2010;115:c94&#x2013;c9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20407272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Q, Liu J, Liu Q, Kang L, Liu R, Jing W, et al. Global Percentage of Asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 Infections Among the Tested Population and Individuals With Confirmed COVID-19 Diagnosis: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2137257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8672238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34905008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Guo Y, Mao R, Zhang J. Proportion of asymptomatic coronavirus disease 2019: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2021;93:820&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7404334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32691881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Burdens of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 by severity of acute infection, demographics and health status. Nat Commun. 2021;12:6571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8589966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34772922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gluckman TJ, Bhave NM, Allen LA, Chung EH, Spatz ES, Ammirati E, et al. 2022 ACC Expert Consensus Decision Pathway on Cardiovascular Sequelae of COVID-19 in Adults: Myocarditis and Other Myocardial Involvement, Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection, and Return to Play: A Report of the American College of Cardiology Solution Set Oversight Committee. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79:1717&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8926109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35307156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kell DB, Laubscher GJ, Pretorius E. A central role for amyloid fibrin microclots in long COVID/PASC: origins and therapeutic implications. Biochem J. 2022;479:537&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8883497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35195253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker AM, Brigham E, Connolly B, McPeake J, Agranovich AV, Kenes MT, et al. Addressing the post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a multidisciplinary model of care. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:1328&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8525917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34678213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Caring for People with Post-COVID Conditions. Avaliable: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/care-post-covid.html.
2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Thomas IJ, Munter SE, Deeks SG, Henrich TJ. Lack of Antinuclear Antibodies in Convalescent Coronavirus Disease 2019 Patients With Persistent Symptoms. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;74:2083&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9187313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34617982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE, Ba DM, Parsons N, Poudel GR, et al. Short-term and Long-term Rates of Postacute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection: A Systematic Review. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2128568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34643720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>