<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38415507</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>96</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The characteristics of BCR-CDR3 repertoire in COVID-19 patients and SARS-CoV-2 vaccinated volunteers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e29488</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e29488</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.29488</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The global COVID-19 pandemic has caused more than 1 billion infections, and numerous SARS-CoV-2 vaccines developed rapidly have been administered over 10 billion doses. The world is continuously concerned about the cytokine storms induced by the interaction between SARS-CoV-2 and host, long COVID, breakthrough infections postvaccination, and the impact of SARS-CoV-2 variants. BCR-CDR3 repertoire serves as a molecular target for monitoring the antiviral response "trace" of B cells, evaluating the effects, mechanisms, and memory abilities of individual responses to B cells, and has been successfully applied in analyzing the infection mechanisms, vaccine improvement, and neutralizing antibodies preparation of influenza virus, HIV, MERS, and Ebola virus. Based on research on BCR-CDR3 repertoire of COVID-19 patients and volunteers who received different SARS-CoV-2 vaccines in multiple laboratories worldwide, we focus on analyzing the characteristics and changes of BCR-CDR3 repertoire, such as diversity, clonality, V&amp;J genes usage and pairing, SHM, CSR, shared CDR3 clones, as well as the summary on BCR sequences targeting virus-specific epitopes in the preparation and application research of SARS-CoV-2 potential therapeutic monoclonal antibodies. This review provides comparative data and new research schemes for studying the possible mechanisms of differences in B cell response between SARS-CoV-2 infection or vaccination, and supplies a foundation for improving vaccines after SARS-CoV-2 mutations and potential antibody therapy for infected individuals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Jiaping</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, Center of Immunomolecular Engineering, Innovation &amp; Practice Base for Graduate Students Education, Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fushun People's Hospital, Zigong, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, Center of Immunomolecular Engineering, Innovation &amp; Practice Base for Graduate Students Education, Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yangyang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, Center of Immunomolecular Engineering, Innovation &amp; Practice Base for Graduate Students Education, Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Xinsheng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6960-4003</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, Center of Immunomolecular Engineering, Innovation &amp; Practice Base for Graduate Students Education, Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82160279</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>(2018) 5637</GrantID><Agency>Guizhou Provincial Hundred Level Talent Fund</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000086663">COVID-19 Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D057134">Antibodies, Neutralizing</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000914">Antibodies, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000711908">SARS-CoV-2 variants</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086663" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057134" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Neutralizing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000914" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Viral</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BCR-CDR3 repertoire</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2 vaccine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-throughput sequencing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">single-cell sequencing</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38415507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.29488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Gadanec LK, McSweeney KR, Qaradakhi T, Ali B, Zulli A, Apostolopoulos V. Can SARS-CoV-2 virus use multiple receptors to enter host cells? Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(3):992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan JFW, Kok KH, Zhu Z, et al. Genomic characterization of the 2019 novel human-pathogenic coronavirus isolated from a patient with atypical pneumonia after visiting Wuhan. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2020;9(1):221-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao W, Li T. COVID-19: towards understanding of pathogenesis. Cell Res. 2020;30(5):367-369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco-Melo D, Nilsson-Payant BE, Liu WC, et al. Imbalanced host response to SARS-CoV-2 drives development of COVID-19. Cell. 2020;181(5):1036-1045.e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee S. Toll-like receptor 4 in COVID-19: friend or foe? Future Virol. 2022;17(7):415-417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Mukherjee S. In silico studies on the comparative characterization of the interactions of SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein with ACE-2 receptor homologs and human TLRs. J Med Virol. 2020;92(10):2105-2113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Das NC, Patra R, Mukherjee S. In silico analyses on the comparative sensing of SARS-CoV-2 mRNA by the intracellular TLRs of humans. J Med Virol. 2021;93(4):2476-2486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patra R, Chandra Das N, Mukherjee S. Targeting human TLRs to combat COVID-19: A solution? J Med Virol. 2021;93(2):615-617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raoult D, Zumla A, Locatelli F, Ippolito G, Kroemer G. Coronavirus infections: epidemiological, clinical and immunological features and hypotheses. Cell Stress. 2020;4(4):66-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Yu T, Du R, et al. Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a retrospective cohort study. The Lancet. 2020;395(10229):1054-1062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan WJ, Zhong NS. Clinical characteristics of Covid-19 in China. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(19):1861-1862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Sen Gupta PS, Panda SK, Rana MK, Mukherjee S. Designing AbhiSCoVac-a single potential vaccine for all &#x2018;corona culprits': immunoinformatics and immune simulation approaches. J Mol Liq. 2022;351:118633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Guan WJ, Zhong NS. Strategies and advances in combating COVID-19 in China. Engineering. 2020;6(10):1076-1084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Wu D, Guo W, et al. Clinical and immunological features of severe and moderate coronavirus disease 2019. J Clin Invest. 2020;130(5):2620-2629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seydoux E, Homad LJ, MacCamy AJ, et al. Analysis of a SARS-CoV-2-infected individual reveals development of potent neutralizing antibodies with limited somatic mutation. Immunity. 2020;53(1):98-105.e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sosa-Hern&#xe1;ndez VA, Torres-Ru&#xed;z J, Cervantes-D&#xed;az R, et al. B cell subsets as severity-associated signatures in COVID-19 patients. Front Immunol. 2020;11:611004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen SCA, Yang F, Jackson KJL, et al. Human B cell clonal expansion and convergent antibody responses to SARS-CoV-2. Cell Host Microbe. 2020;28(4):516-525.e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boechat JL, Chora I, Morais A, Delgado L. The immune response to SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19 immunopathology-current perspectives. Pulmonology. 2021;27(5):423-437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnet SFM. The Clonal Selection Theory of Acquired Immunity. Vol 3. Vanderbilt University Press; 1959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy K, Weaver C. Janeway's Immunobiology. 9th ed. Garland Science/Taylor &amp; Francis Group, LLC; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wrammert J, Smith K, Miller J, et al. Rapid cloning of high-affinity human monoclonal antibodies against influenza virus. Nature. 2008;453(7195):667-671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheid JF, Mouquet H, Feldhahn N, et al. Broad diversity of neutralizing antibodies isolated from memory B cells in HIV-infected individuals. Nature. 2009;458(7238):636-640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Shi W, Chappell JD, et al. Importance of neutralizing monoclonal antibodies targeting multiple antigenic sites on the Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus spike glycoprotein to avoid neutralization escape. J Virol. 2018;92(10):e02002-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corti D, Misasi J, Mulangu S, et al. Protective monotherapy against lethal Ebola virus infection by a potently neutralizing antibody. Science. 2016;351(6279):1339-1342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tregoning JS, Flight KE, Higham SL, Wang Z, Pierce BF. Progress of the COVID-19 vaccine effort: viruses, vaccines and variants versus efficacy, effectiveness and escape. Nat Rev Immunol. 2021;21(10):626-636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Vaccines Tracker. 2023. https://covid19.trackvaccines.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gra&#xf1;a C, Ghosn L, Evrenoglou T, et al. Efficacy and safety of COVID-19 vaccines. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2022;12(12):015477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathieu E, Ritchie H, Rod&#xe9;s-Guirao L, et al. Coronavirus Pandemic (COVID-19). Our World in Data.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cromer D, Juno JA, Khoury D, et al. Prospects for durable immune control of SARS-CoV-2 and prevention of reinfection. Nat Rev Immunol. 2021;21(6):395-404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Y, Pi X, Bartels-Burgahn F, et al. Structural principles of B cell antigen receptor assembly. Nature. 2022;612(7938):156-161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu JL, Davis MM. Diversity in the CDR3 region of V(H) is sufficient for most antibody specificities. Immunity. 2000;13(1):37-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidman JG, Leder P. The arrangement and rearrangement of antibody genes. Nature. 1978;276(5690):790-795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauss G, Lieber MR. Mechanistic constraints on diversity in human V(D)J recombination. Mol Cell Biol. 1996;16(1):258-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krebs JE, Goldstein ES, Kilpatrick ST, et al. Lewin's GENES X. Jones &amp; Bartlett Publishers; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Li J, Shi B, Yao X. [T cell receptor (TCR) repertoire and common analytical tools for high-throughput sequencing]. Xi Bao Yu Fen Zi Mian Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2021;37(9):851-857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbiani DF, Gaebler C, Muecksch F, et al. Convergent antibody responses to SARS-CoV-2 in convalescent individuals. Nature. 2020;584(7821):437-442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y, Su B, Guo X, et al. Potent neutralizing antibodies against SARS-CoV-2 identified by high-throughput single-cell sequencing of convalescent patients' B cells. Cell. 2020;182(1):73-84.e16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin X, Zhou W, Luo M, et al. Global characterization of B cell receptor repertoire in COVID-19 patients by single-cell V(D)J sequencing. Brief Bioinform. 2021;22(6):bbab192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulthei&#xdf; C, Paschold L, Simnica D, et al. Next-generation sequencing of T and B cell receptor repertoires from COVID-19 patients showed signatures associated with severity of disease. Immunity. 2020;53(2):442-455.e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galson JD, Schaetzle S, Bashford-Rogers RJM, et al. Deep sequencing of B cell receptor repertoires from COVID-19 patients reveals strong convergent immune signatures. Front Immunol. 2020;11:605170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreer C, Zehner M, Weber T, et al. Longitudinal isolation of potent near-germline SARS-CoV-2-neutralizing antibodies from COVID-19 patients. Cell. 2020;182(6):1663-1673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotagiri P, Mescia F, Rae WM, et al. B cell receptor repertoire kinetics after SARS-CoV-2 infection and vaccination. Cell Rep. 2022;38(7):110393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Bai H, Gong T, et al. Novel skewed usage of B-cell receptors in COVID-19 patients with various clinical presentations. Immunol Lett. 2022;249:23-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Zhang J, Wang D, et al. Profiling of the immune repertoire in COVID-19 patients with mild, severe, convalescent, or retesting-positive status. J Autoimmun. 2021;118:102596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai H, Hu J, Huang L, et al. The relationship between convergent IGH signatures and severity of COVID-19 patients by next-generation sequencing of B-cell repertoire. Front Microbiol. 2022;12:833054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao H, Yu L, Yan F, et al. Landscape of B cell receptor repertoires in COVID-19 patients revealed through CDR3 sequencing of immunoglobulin heavy and light chains. Immunol Invest. 2022;51(7):1994-2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Yan Q, Luo K, et al. Analysis of B cell receptor repertoires reveals key signatures of the systemic B cell response after SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Virol. 2022;96(4):e0160021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Q, Wu S, Xiao C, et al. Integrated single-cell analysis revealed immune dynamics during Ad5-nCoV immunization. Cell Discov. 2021;7(1):64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Schmidt F, Weisblum Y, et al. mRNA vaccine-elicited antibodies to SARS-CoV-2 and circulating variants. Nature. 2021;592(7855):616-622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin K, Zhou Y, Ai J, et al. B cell receptor signatures associated with strong and poor SARS-CoV-2 vaccine responses. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2022;11(1):452-464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraley ER, Khanal S, Pierce SH, et al. Effects of prior infection with SARS-CoV-2 on B cell receptor repertoire response during vaccination. Vaccines. 2022;10(9):1477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowe JE. Influenza virus-specific human antibody repertoire studies. J Immunol. 2019;202(2):368-373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan Q, Xu J-H, Yu Y-Y, Lo KK E, El-Nezami H, Zeng Z. Human immune repertoire in hepatitis B virus infection. World J Gastroenterol. 2021;27(25):3790-3801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Setliff I, Shiakolas AR, Pilewski KA, et al. High-throughput mapping of B cell receptor sequences to antigen specificity. Cell. 2019;179(7):1636-1646.e15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sureshchandra S, Lewis SA, Doratt BM, Jankeel A, Coimbra Ibraim I, Messaoudi I. Single-cell profiling of T and B cell repertoires following SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccine. JCI Insight. 2021;6(24):e153201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He B, Liu S, Xu M, et al. Comparative global B cell receptor repertoire difference induced by SARS-CoV-2 infection or vaccination via single-cell V(D)J sequencing. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2022;11(1):2007-2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurlburt NK, Seydoux E, Wan Y-H, et al. Structural basis for potent neutralization of SARS-CoV-2 and role of antibody affinity maturation. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):5413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montague Z, Lv H, Otwinowski J, et al. Dynamics of B cell repertoires and emergence of cross-reactive responses in patients with different severities of COVID-19. Cell Rep. 2021;35(8):109173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi B, Ma L, He X, et al. Comparative analysis of human and mouse immunoglobulin variable heavy regions from IMGT/LIGM-DB with IMGT/HighV-QUEST. Theor Biol Med Modell. 2014;11:30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwer PJM, Caniels TG, van der Straten K, et al. Potent neutralizing antibodies from COVID-19 patients define multiple targets of vulnerability. Science. 2020;369(6504):643-650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Wang H, Ji Q, et al. Molecular deconvolution of the neutralizing antibodies induced by an inactivated SARS-CoV-2 virus vaccine. Protein Cell. 2021;12(10):818-823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong R, Luo L, Zhao Y, et al. Characterizing the cellular and molecular variabilities of peripheral immune cells in healthy recipients of BBIBP-CorV inactivated SARS-CoV-2 vaccine by single-cell RNA sequencing. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2023;12(1):e2187245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen W, Su W, Tang H, et al. Immune cell profiling of COVID-19 patients in the recovery stage by single-cell sequencing. Cell Discov. 2020;6:31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu X, Li S, Li P, et al. Longitudinal analysis of T and B cell receptor repertoire transcripts reveal dynamic immune response in COVID-19 patients. Front Immunol. 2020;11:582010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis CW, Jackson KJL, McElroy AK, et al. Longitudinal analysis of the human B cell response to ebola virus infection. Cell. 2019;177(6):1566-1582.e17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He B, Liu S, Wang Y, et al. Rapid isolation and immune profiling of SARS-CoV-2 specific memory B cell in convalescent COVID-19 patients via LIBRA-seq. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6(1):195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang H, Zhao Y, Li X, et al. Landscapes and dynamic diversifications of B-cell receptor repertoires in COVID-19 patients. Hum Immunol. 2022;83(2):119-129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collier DA, Ferreira IATM, Kotagiri P, et al Age-related immune response heterogeneity to SARS-CoV-2 vaccine BNT162b2. Nature. 2021;596(7872):417-422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullen G, Galson JD, Hall G, et al. Cross-reactive SARS-CoV-2 neutralizing antibodies from deep mining of early patient responses. Front Immunol. 2021;12:678570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Berg K, Vermeulen M, Glatt TN, et al. COVID-19: convalescent plasma as a potential therapy. S Afr Med J. 2020;110(7):562-563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao X. COVID-19: immunopathology and its implications for therapy. Nat Rev Immunol. 2020;20(5):269-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z, Chen C, Li W, et al. Potent neutralization of SARS-CoV-2 by human antibody heavy-chain variable domains isolated from a large library with a new stable scaffold. Mabs. 2020;12(1):1778435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Li C, Xia S, et al. Identification of human single-domain antibodies against SARS-CoV-2. Cell Host Microbe. 2020;27(6):891-898.e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan J, Xing S, Ding L, et al. Human-IgG-neutralizing monoclonal antibodies block the SARS-CoV-2 infection. Cell Rep. 2020;32(3):107918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Mattos Barbosa MG, Liu H, Huynh D, et al. IgV somatic mutation of human anti-SARS-CoV-2 monoclonal antibodies governs neutralization and breadth of reactivity. JCI Insight. 2021;6(9):e147386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers TF, Zhao F, Huang D, et al. Isolation of potent SARS-CoV-2 neutralizing antibodies and protection from disease in a small animal model. Science. 2020;369(6506):956-963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi R, Shan C, Duan X, et al. A human neutralizing antibody targets the receptor-binding site of SARS-CoV-2. Nature. 2020;584(7819):120-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Wang F, Shen C, et al. A noncompeting pair of human neutralizing antibodies block COVID-19 virus binding to its receptor ACE2. Science. 2020;368(6496):1274-1278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rappazzo CG, Tse LV, Kaku CI, et al. Broad and potent activity against SARS-like viruses by an engineered human monoclonal antibody. Science. 2021;371(6531):823-829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y, Zhang G, Yang Q, et al. Discovery and characterization of potent pan-variant SARS-CoV-2 neutralizing antibodies from individuals with Omicron breakthrough infection. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):3537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muecksch F, Wang Z, Cho A, et al. Increased memory B cell potency and breadth after a SARS-CoV-2 mRNA boost. Nature. 2022;607(7917):128-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreano E, Paciello I, Pierleoni G, et al. B cell analyses after SARS-CoV-2 mRNA third vaccination reveals a hybrid immunity like antibody response. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):53.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>