<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39392098</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0274</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of industrial medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Ind Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence of COVID-19 and Long COVID by industry and occupation: Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System 2022.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ajim.23665</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Workers in healthcare and other essential occupations had elevated risks for COVID-19 infection early in the pandemic. No survey of U.S. workers to date has comprehensively assessed the prevalence of both COVID-19 and Long COVID across industries and occupations (I&amp;O) at a detailed level.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System data for 2022 from 39 states, Guam, and the U.S. Virgin Islands were used to estimate prevalence of self-reported history of COVID-19 and Long COVID, as well as the prevalence of Long COVID among those reporting prior COVID-19, by broad and detailed I&amp;O. Adjusted prevalence ratios were used to compare outcome prevalence in each I&amp;O to prevalence among all other workers combined.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">By broad I&amp;O, workers in healthcare, protective services, and education had elevated prevalences of COVID-19. The prevalence of Long COVID was elevated in healthcare and protective service but not education workers. Detailed I&amp;O with significantly elevated prevalences of COVID-19 but not Long COVID included Dairy Product Manufacturing industry workers and subsets of mining workers. Both COVID-19 and Long COVID were elevated among bartenders/drinking places and personal care and appearance workers. The prevalence of Long COVID was elevated among farmworkers who reported having had COVID-19.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Industries and occupations with elevated levels of COVID-19 or Long COVID in this study may warrant increased measures to prevent transmission of airborne respiratory viruses. Accommodations are a key component for supporting workers in all workplaces. This new information about the distribution of Long COVID by I&amp;O suggests where employer understanding and implementation of tailored workplace supports and accommodations are most needed to support continued employment of affected workers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silver</LastName><ForeName>S R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7679-5028</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, Division of Field Studies and Engineering, Health Informatics Branch, Cincinnati, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0692-5103</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, Division of Field Studies and Engineering, Health Informatics Branch, Cincinnati, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ford</LastName><ForeName>N D</ForeName><Initials>ND</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6463-5094</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Coronaviruses and Other Respiratory Viruses Division, Epidemiology Branch, Atlanta, Georgia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>D</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8088-6427</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, Division of Field Studies and Engineering, Hazard Evaluations and Technical Assistance Branch, Cincinnati, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saydah</LastName><ForeName>S H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6350-5300</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Coronaviruses and Other Respiratory Viruses Division, Epidemiology Branch, Atlanta, Georgia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Ind Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8101110</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0271-3586</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID&#x2010;19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">employment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unemployment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wellbeing</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39392098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajim.23665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Goda GS, Jackson E, Nicholas LH, Stith SS. The impact of Covid&#x2010;19 on older workers' employment and social security spillovers. J Popul Econ. 2023;36(2):813&#x2010;846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groenewold MR, Burrer SL, Ahmed F, Uzicanin A, Free H, Luckhaupt SE. Increases in health&#x2010;related workplace absenteeism among workers in essential critical infrastructure occupations during the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic&#x2014;United States, March&#x2013;April 2020. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69(27):853&#x2010;858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallegos M, Morgan ML, Burgos&#x2010;Videla C, Caycho&#x2010;Rodr&#xed;guez T, Martino P, Cervigni M. The impact of long Covid on people's capacity to work. Ann Work Expo Health. 2023;67(7):801&#x2010;804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonner C, Ghouralal SL. Long COVID and chronic conditions in the US workforce: prevalence, productivity loss, and disability. J Occup Environ Med. 2024;66(3):e80&#x2010;e86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballouz T, Menges D, Anagnostopoulos A, et al. Recovery and symptom trajectories up to two years after SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection: population based, longitudinal cohort study. BMJ. 2023;381:e074425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green CE, Leeds JS, Leeds CM. Occupational effects in patients with post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome. Occup Med. 2024;74(1):86&#x2010;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlis RH, Trujillo KL, Safarpour A, et al. Association of post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 condition symptoms and employment status. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6(2):e2256152. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.56152</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemh&#xf6;fer C, Sturm C, Loudovici&#x2010;Krug D, et al. Quality of life and ability to work of patients with Post&#x2010;COVID syndrome in relation to the number of existing symptoms and the duration since infection up to 12 months: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. Qual Life Res. 2023;32(7):1991&#x2010;2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksieck P, Ballouz T, Haile SR, et al. Post COVID&#x2010;19 condition, work ability and occupational changes in a population&#x2010;based cohort. Lancet Reg Health&#x2014;Europe. 2023;31:100671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward JA, Parish K, DiLaura G, Dolovich S, Saloner B. COVID&#x2010;19 cases among employees of U.S. Federal and state prisons. Am J Prev Med. 2021;60(6):840&#x2010;844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walshe N, Fennelly M, Hellebust S, et al. Assessment of environmental and occupational risk factors for the mitigation and containment of a COVID&#x2010;19 outbreak in a meat processing plant. Front Public Health. 2021;9:769238. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2021.769238</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen LH, Drew DA, Graham MS, et al. Risk of COVID&#x2010;19 among front&#x2010;line health&#x2010;care workers and the general community: a prospective cohort study. Lancet Public Health. 2020;5(9):e475&#x2010;e483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaitens J, Condon M, Fernandes E, McDiarmid M. COVID&#x2010;19 and essential workers: a narrative review of health outcomes and moral injury. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(4):1446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avdiu B, Nayyar G. When face&#x2010;to&#x2010;face interactions become an occupational hazard: jobs in the time of COVID&#x2010;19. Econ Lett. 2020;197:109648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker M. Who cannot work from home? Characterizing occupations facing increased risk during the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic using 2018 BLS data. In medRxiv; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaffney A, Himmelstein DU, McCormick D, Woolhandler S. COVID&#x2010;19 risk by workers' occupation and industry in the United States, 2020&#x2012;2021. Am J Public Health. 2023;113(6):647&#x2010;656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groenewold MR, Billock R, Free H, et al. Excess risk of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection among in&#x2010;person nonhealthcare workers in six states, September 2020&#x2013;June 2021. Am J Ind Med. 2023;66(7):587&#x2010;600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bui DP, McCaffrey K, Friedrichs M, et al. Racial and ethnic disparities among COVID&#x2010;19 cases in workplace outbreaks by industry sector&#x2014;Utah, March 6&#x2013;June 5, 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69:1133&#x2010;1138. doi:10.15585/mmwr.mm6933e3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wuellner S. Washington COVID&#x2010;19 cases by industry. January 2020&#x2013;June 2020 Washington State Departmen of Labor and Industries; 2021. https://lni.wa.gov/safety-health/safety-research/files/2021/103_06_2021_COVID_Industry_Report.pdf. Accessed 08/20/2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pray IW, Grajewski B, Morris C, et al. Measuring work&#x2010;related risk of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID&#x2010;19): comparison of COVID&#x2010;19 incidence by occupation and industry&#x2014;Wisconsin, September 2020 to May 2021. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76(3):e163&#x2010;e171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver S, Boiano J, Li J. Patient care aides: differences in healthcare coverage, health&#x2010;related behaviors, and health outcomes in a low&#x2010;wage workforce by healthcare setting. Am J Ind Med. 2020;63(1):60&#x2010;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh AK, Venkatraman S, Soroka O, et al. Association between overcrowded households, multigenerational households, and COVID&#x2010;19: a cohort study. Public Health. 2021;198:273&#x2010;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parotto M, Gy&#xf6;ngy&#xf6;si M, Howe K, et al. Post&#x2010;acute sequelae of COVID&#x2010;19: understanding and addressing the burden of multisystem manifestations. Lancet Respir Med. 2023;11(8):739&#x2010;754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2010;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach K. New data shows long Covid is keeping as many as 4 million people out of work. Brookings; 08/24/2022 2022. https://www.brookings.edu/articles/new-data-shows-long-covid-is-keeping-as-many-as-4-million-people-out-of-work/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green CE, Leeds JS, Leeds CM. Occupational effects in patients with post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome. Occup Med. 2023;74(1):86&#x2010;92. doi:10.1093/occmed/kqad118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ham DI. Long&#x2010;haulers and labor market outcomes. Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon J, Milne R, Rayner C, et al. Impact of Long COVID on productivity and informal caregiving. Eur J Health Econ. 2024;25(7):1095&#x2010;1115. doi:10.1007/s10198&#x2010;023&#x2010;01653&#x2010;z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen K, Yarker J. &#x201c;It's a rollercoaster&#x201d;: the recovery and return to work experiences of workers with long COVID. Work Stress. 2024;38:1&#x2010;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunt J, Hemming S, Elander J, Baraniak A, Burton K, Ellington D. Experiences of workers with post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 symptoms can signpost suitable workplace accommodations. Int J Workplace Health Manag. 2022;15(3):359&#x2010;374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kromydas T, Demou E, Edge R, et al. Occupational differences in the prevalence and severity of long&#x2010;COVID: analysis of the Coronavirus (COVID&#x2010;19) Infection Survey. Occup Environ Med. 2023;80(10):545&#x2010;552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabnam S, Razieh C, Dambha&#x2010;Miller H, et al. Socioeconomic inequalities of Long COVID: a retrospective population&#x2010;based cohort study in the United Kingdom. J R Soc Med. 2023;116(8):263&#x2010;273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett ML, Grabowski DC. Nursing homes are ground zero for COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic. JAMA Health Forum. 2020;1(3):e200369&#x2010;e200369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams HR, Loomer L, Gandhi A, Grabowski DC. Characteristics of U.S. nursing homes with COVID&#x2010;19 cases. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2020;68(8):1653&#x2010;1656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razzaghi H, Srivastav A, de Perio MA, Laney AS, Black CL. Influenza and COVID&#x2010;19 vaccination coverage among health care personnel&#x2014;United States, 2021&#x2013;22. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71(42):1319&#x2010;1326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Al&#x2010;Aly Z. Acute and postacute sequelae associated with SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 reinfection. Nat Med. 2022;28(11):2398&#x2010;2405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver SR, Li J, Marsh SM, Carbone EG. Prepandemic mental health and well&#x2010;being: differences within the health care workforce and the need for targeted resources. J Occup Environ Med. 2022;64(12):1025&#x2010;1035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llach CD, Vieta E. Mind long COVID: psychiatric sequelae of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2021;49:119&#x2010;121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gimeno&#x2010;Miguel A, Bliek&#x2010;Bueno K, Poblador&#x2010;Plou B, et al. Chronic diseases associated with increased likelihood of hospitalization and mortality in 68,913 COVID&#x2010;19 confirmed cases in Spain: a population&#x2010;based cohort study. PLoS One. 2021;16(11):e0259822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arjun MC, Singh AK, Pal D, et al. Characteristics and predictors of Long COVID among diagnosed cases of COVID&#x2010;19. PLoS One. 2022;17(12):e0278825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altmann DM, Whettlock EM, Liu S, Arachchillage DJ, Boyton RJ. The immunology of long COVID. Nat Rev Immunol. 2023;23(10):618&#x2010;634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Sivan M, Perlowski A, Nikolich J&#x17d;. Long COVID: a clinical update. Lancet. 2024;404(10453):707&#x2010;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver SR, Li J, Boal WL, Shockey TL, Groenewold MR. Prevalence of underlying medical conditions among selected essential critical infrastructure workers&#x2014;behavioral risk factor surveillance system, 31 states, 2017&#x2013;2018. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69(36):1244&#x2010;1249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marjenberg Z, Leng S, Tascini C, et al. Risk of long COVID main symptoms after SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):15332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marra AR, Kobayashi T, Callado GY, et al. The effectiveness of COVID&#x2010;19 vaccine in the prevention of post&#x2010;COVID conditions: a systematic literature review and meta&#x2010;analysis of the latest research. Antimicrobial Steward Healthc Epidemiol. 2023;3(1):168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catal&#xe0; M, Mercad&#xe9;&#x2010;Besora N, Kolde R, et al. The effectiveness of COVID&#x2010;19 vaccines to prevent long COVID symptoms: staggered cohort study of data from the UK, Spain, and Estonia. Lancet Respir Med. 2024;12(3):225&#x2010;236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byambasuren O, Stehlik P, Clark J, Alcorn K, Glasziou P. Effect of covid&#x2010;19 vaccination on long covid: systematic review. BMJ Med. 2023;2(1):e000385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Z, Stallings&#x2010;Smith S, Patel S, Case S, Hong Y&#x2010;R. COVID&#x2010;19 booster vaccine uptake and reduced risks for long&#x2010;COVID: a cross&#x2010;sectional study of a U.S. adult population. Vaccine. 2024;42:3529&#x2010;3535.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClung N, Chamberland M, Kinlaw K, et al. The advisory committee on immunization practices' ethical principles for allocating initial supplies of COVID&#x2010;19 vaccine&#x2014;United states, 2020. Am J Transplant. 2021;21(1):420&#x2010;425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraser EM, Neuss MJ. Who calls the shots? A legal and historical perspective on vaccine mandates. Chest. 2022;162(3):659&#x2010;663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services. Biden&#x2010;Harris administration to expand vaccination requirements for health care settings. Press Releases; 2021. https://www.cms.gov/newsroom/press-releases/biden-harris-administration-expand-vaccination-requirements-health-care-settings. Accessed 04/10/2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorgensen TM, Stahr JF White House announces vaccination mandate or weekly testing for large employers, and vaccination mandate for federal employees and contractors. 2021; https://web.archive.org/web/20211110181326/https:/www.employmentlawlandscape.com/2021/09/white-house-announces-vaccination-mandate-or-weekly-testing-for-large-employers-and-vaccination-mandate-for-federal-employees-and-contractors/. Accessed 04/10/2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Education Week. Where teachers are required to get vaccinated against COVID&#x2010;19 (2021;Accessed 04/10/2024. https://www.edweek.org/policy-politics/where-teachers-are-required-to-get-vaccinated-against-covid-19/2021/08#:~:text=Nationally%2C%20by%20August%202021%2C%2087,vaccinations%20to%20individual%20school%20districts</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King WC, Rubinstein M, Reinhart A, Mejia R. COVID&#x2010;19 vaccine hesitancy January&#x2010;May 2021 among 18&#x2013;64 year old US adults by employment and occupation. Prev Med Rep. 2021;24:101569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneberger PK, Cox&#x2010;Ganser JM, Guthrie GM, Groth CP. Estimates of COVID&#x2010;19 vaccine uptake in major occupational groups and detailed occupational categories in the United States, April&#x2013;May 2021. Am J Ind Med. 2022;65(7):525&#x2010;536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smarsh B, Yankey D, Hung M&#x2010;C, et al. Disparities in COVID&#x2010;19 vaccine uptake, attitudes, and experiences between food system and non&#x2013;food system essential workers. J Agric Food Syst Community Dev. 2024;13(2):1&#x2010;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steege AL, Luckhaupt SE, Guerin RJ, et al. Characteristics associated with a previous COVID&#x2010;19 diagnosis, vaccine uptake, and intention to be vaccinated among essential workers in the US household pulse survey. Am J Public Health. 2022;112(11):1599&#x2010;1610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo D, Mei B, Wang P, et al. Prevalence and risk factors for persistent symptoms after COVID&#x2010;19: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2024;30(3):328&#x2010;335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latkin CA, Dayton L, Yi G, Colon B, Kong X. Mask usage, social distancing, racial, and gender correlates of COVID&#x2010;19 vaccine intentions among adults in the US. PLoS One. 2021;16(2):e0246970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen QC, Yardi I, Gutierrez FXM, Mane H, Yue X. Leveraging 13 million responses to the U.S. COVID&#x2010;19 Trends and Impact Survey to examine vaccine hesitancy, vaccination, and mask wearing, January 2021&#x2013;February 2022. BMC Public Health. 2022;22(1):1911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones JM, Manrique IM, Stone MS, et al. Estimates of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 seroprevalence and incidence of primary SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infections among blood donors, by COVID&#x2010;19 vaccination status&#x2014;United States, April 2021&#x2013;September 2022. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2023;72(22):601&#x2010;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi DS, McDonald E, Shah M, et al. Prevalence of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection among US blood donors by industry, May&#x2013;December 2021. Am J Ind Med. 2024;67(2):169&#x2010;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savych BLong COVID in the workers' compensation system in 2020 and 2021. Workers Compensation Research Institute. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billock RM, Steege AL, Mini&#xf1;o A. COVID&#x2010;19 mortality by usual occupation and Industry:46 states and New York City, United States, 2020. Natl Vital Stat Rep. 2022;71(6):1&#x2010;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampasian V, Elghazaly H, Chattopadhyay R, et al Risk factors associated with post&#x2212; COVID&#x2010;19 condition: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. JAMA Intern Med. 2023;183(6):566&#x2010;580. doi:10.1001/jamainternmed.2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford ND, Slaughter D, Edwards D, et al. Long COVID and significant activity limitation among adults, by age &#x2010; United States, June 1&#x2010;13, 2022, to June 7&#x2010;19, 2023. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2023;72(32):866&#x2010;870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boal WL, Li J, Silver SR. Health care access among essential critical infrastructure workers, 31 states, 2017&#x2013;2018. Public Health Rep. 2022;137(2):301&#x2010;309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Association of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation. Multidisciplinary Quality Improvement Initiative: Published Guidance https://www.aapmr.org/advocacy/current-priorities/long-covid-pasc/multidisciplinary-quality-improvement-initiative?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=AAPMR. Accessed 08/20/2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>