<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36156538</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-5923</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The American journal of case reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Case Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Alleviation of Post-COVID-19 Cognitive Deficits by Treatment with EGb 761&#xae;: A Case Series.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e937094</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e937094</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12659/AJCR.937094</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>BACKGROUND Cognitive symptoms persisting longer than 3 months after infection, such as memory loss, or difficulties concentrating, have been reported in up to one-third of patients after COVID-19. Evidence-based therapeutic interventions to treat post-COVID-19 symptoms (also called "Long-COVID symptoms") have not yet been established, and the treating physicians must rely on conjecture to help patients. Based on its mechanism of action and its efficacy in treating cognitive impairment, as well as its good tolerability, the Ginkgo biloba special extract EGb 761 has been suggested as a remedy to alleviate cognitive post-COVID-19 symptoms. In many studies, EGb 761 has been demonstrated to protect endothelial cells, to have potent anti-inflammatory effects, and to enhance neuroplasticity. CASE REPORT Here, we report for the first time the application of EGb 761 in the therapy of post-COVID-19-related cognitive deficits. Three women and 2 men, aged 26 to 59 years (average age 34.6 years), presented with concentration and attention deficits, cognitive deficiencies, and/or fatigue 9-35 weeks after infection. A daily dose of 2&#xd7;80 mg of EGb 761 did not cause any detectable adverse effects, and it substantially improved or completely restored cognitive deficits and, when initially present, also other symptoms, such as fatigue and hyposmia, within an observation period of up to 6 months. CONCLUSIONS Our observations support the hypothesis that EGb 761 might be a low-risk treatment option for post-COVID-19 patients with cognitive symptoms. Moreover, we derive recommendations for randomized controlled clinical trials to confirm efficacy in that indication.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zifko</LastName><ForeName>Udo A</ForeName><Initials>UA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Evangelical Hospital Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yacob</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Evangelical Hospital Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Braun</LastName><ForeName>Benedikt J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Evangelical Hospital Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dietz</LastName><ForeName>Gunnar P H</ForeName><Initials>GPH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Medicine G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Case Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101489566</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1941-5923</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000893">Anti-Inflammatory Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010936">Plant Extracts</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>19FUJ2C58T</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C063170">Ginkgo biloba extract</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000893" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Inflammatory Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042783" MajorTopicYN="N">Endothelial Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020441" MajorTopicYN="N">Ginkgo biloba</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010936" MajorTopicYN="N">Plant Extracts</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of interest:</b> Dr. Willmar Schwabe GmbH &amp; Co. KG, manufacturer of medicinal products containing the special extract from <i>Ginkgo biloba</i> leaves, EGb 761<sup>&#xae;</sup>. GPHD is employed by that company. Other authors do not have a conflict of interest. The company was in no way involved in the diagnostic or therapeutic decisions and data acquisition by the treating physicians</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36156538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9523733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/AJCR.937094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">937094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gallo Marin B, Aghagoli G, Lavine K, et al. Predictors of COVID-19 severity: A literature review. Rev Med Virol. 2021;31(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7855377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32845042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer L, Laksono BM, de Vrij FMS, Kushner SA, et al. The neuroinvasiveness, neurotropism, and neurovirulence of SARS-CoV-2. Trends Neurosci. 2022;45:358&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8890977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35279295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zifko U, Schmiedlechner T, Saelens J, et al. COVID-19: Involvement of the nervous system. Identifying neurological predictors defining the course of the disease. J Neurol Sci. 2021;425:117438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8028603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33857734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M. Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nat Immunol. 2022;23(2):194&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T, Hittle M, Goodman SN. Assessment of the frequency and variety of persistent symptoms among patients with COVID-19: A systematic review. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(5):e2111417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8155823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34037731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy ST, Garg T, Shah C, et al. Cerebrovascular disease in patients with COVID-19: A review of the literature and case series. Case Rep Neurol. 2020;12(2):199&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7325208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32647526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardu C, Gambardella J, Morelli MB, et al. Hypertension, thrombosis, kidney failure, and diabetes: Is COVID-19 an endothelial disease? A comprehensive evaluation of clinical and basic evidence. J Clin Med. 2020;9(5):1417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7290769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32403217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poyatos P, Luque N, Eizaguirre S, et al. Post-COVID-19 patients show an increased endothelial progenitor cell production. Transl Res. 2022;243:14&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8785258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35085821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haffke M, Freitag H, Rudolf G, et al. Endothelial dysfunction and altered endothelial biomarkers in patients with post-COVID-19 syndrome and chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) J Transl Med. 2022;20(1):138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35317812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J, Liu D, Feng L, et al. Protective Effect of Standardized Extract of Ginkgo biloba against Cisplatin-Induced Nephrotoxicity. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2013;2013:846126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3858901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24371467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Pei DS, Ji HX, Xing SH. Protective effect of a standardized Ginkgo extract (ginaton) on renal ischemia/reperfusion injury via suppressing the activation of JNK signal pathway. Phytomedicine. 2008;15(11):923&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18929474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naidu MU, Shifow AA, Kumar KV, Ratnakar KS. Ginkgo biloba extract ameliorates gentamicin-induced nephrotoxicity in rats. Phytomedicine. 2000;7(3):191&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11185729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;tt F, Aretz S, Auffahrt GU, Kopitz J. [Role of energy metabolism in retinal pigment epithelium] Ophthalmologe. 2013;110(4):346&#x2013;52. [in German]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23319062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behar-Cohen FF, Heydolph S, Faure V, et al. Peroxynitrite cytotoxicity on bovine retinal pigmented epithelial cells in culture. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 1996;226(3):842&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8831699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu KX, He W, Rinne T, et al. The effect of Ginkgo biloba extract (EGb 761&#xae;) pre-treatment on intestinal epithelial apoptosis induced by intestinal ischemia/reperfusion in rats: Role of ceramide. Am J Chin Med. 2007;35(5):805&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17963320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen JW, Chen YH, Lin FY, et al. Ginkgo biloba extract inhibits tumor necrosis factor-alpha-induced reactive oxygen species generation, transcription factor activation, and cell adhesion molecule expression in human aortic endothelial cells. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2003;23(9):1559&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12893683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu YZ, Li SQ, Zu XG, et al. Ginkgo biloba extract improves coronary artery circulation in patients with coronary artery disease: Contribution of plasma nitric oxide and endothelin-1. PhytotherRes. 2008;22(6):734&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18446847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CH, Mo JH, Shim SH, et al. Effect of Ginkgo biloba and dexamethasone in the treatment of 3-methylindole-induced anosmia mouse model. AmJRhinol. 2008;22(3):292&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18588762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansour SM, Bahgat AK, El-Khatib AS, Khayyal MT. Ginkgo biloba extract (EGb 761&#xae;) normalizes hypertension in 2K, 1C hypertensive rats: Role of antioxidant mechanisms, ACE inhibiting activity and improvement of endothelial dysfunction. Phytomedicine. 2011;18(8&#x2013;9):641&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21353510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang XH, Zhang M, Wu JX, et al. Gingko biloba extract EGb 761&#xae; alleviates heat-stress damage in chicken heart tissue by stimulating Hsp70 expression in vivo in vascular endothelial cells. Br Poult Sci. 2020;61(2):180&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31760785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao P, Yan H, Wang J. EGb 761&#xae; protects brain microvascular endothelial cells against oxygen-glucose deprivation-induced injury through lncRNA Rmst/miR-150 axis. Neurochem Res. 2020;45(10):2398&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32728986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu YL, Tsai WC, Wu CH, et al. Ginkgo biloba induces thrombomodulin expression and tissue-type plasminogen activator secretion via the activation of Kruppel-like factor 2 within endothelial cells. Am J Chin Med. 2020;48(2):357&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32108493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond BJ, Shiflett SC, Feiwel N, et al. Ginkgo biloba extract: mechanisms and clinical indications. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2000;81(5):668&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10807109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim MA, Ramadan HH, Mohammed RN. Evidence that Ginkgo biloba could use in the influenza and coronavirus COVID-19 infections. J Basic Clin Physiol Pharmacol. 2021;32(3):131&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33594843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tchantchou F, Lacor PN, Cao Z, et al. Stimulation of neurogenesis and synaptogenesis by bilobalide and quercetin via common final pathway in hippocampal neurons. J Alzheimers Dis. 2009;18(4):787&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19661619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tchantchou F, Xu Y, Wu Y, et al. EGb 761&#xae; enhances adult hippocampal neurogenesis and phosphorylation of CREB in transgenic mouse model of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Faseb J. 2007;21(10):2400&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17356006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fehske CJ, Leuner K, M&#xfc;ller WE. Ginkgo biloba extract (EGb 761&#xae;) influences monoaminergic neurotransmission via inhibition of NE uptake, but not MAO activity after chronic treatment. Pharmacol Res. 2009;60(1):68&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19427589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckert A, Keil U, Kressmann S, et al. Effects of EGb 761&#xae; Ginkgo biloba extract on mitochondrial function and oxidative stress. Pharmacopsychiatry. 2003;36(Suppl. 1):S15&#x2013;S23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13130384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellermann AJ, Kloft C. Is there a risk of bleeding associated with standardized Ginkgo biloba extract therapy? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Pharmacotherapy. 2011;31(5):490&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21923430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Leber A, Jawad MY, et al. Registered clinical trials investigating treatment of long COVID: A scoping review and recommendations for research. Infect Dis (Lond) 2022;54(7):467&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8935463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35282780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;ndiger Arbeitskreis der Kompetenz- und Behandlungszentren f&#xfc;r Krankheiten durch hochpathogene Erreger am Robert Koch-Institut  Hinweise zu Erkennung Diagnostik und Therapie von Patienten mit COVID-19.  ( https://edoc.rki.de/bitstream/handle/176904/6511/STAKOB-Therapie_2020-03-13-14h_Hyperlinks-14Maerz13h.pdf?sequence=1). 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine ZS, Phillips NA, Bedirian V, et al. The Montreal Cognitive Assessment, MoCA: A brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2005;53(4):695&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guy W. CGI Clinical Global Impressions. In: Guy W, editor. ECDEU assessment manual for psychopharmacology. Rockville, Md: U.S. Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare; 1976. pp. 217&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F, et al. SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature. 2022;604(7907):697&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9046077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo BS, Lee HJ, Mo JH, et al. Treatment of postviral olfactory loss with glucocorticoids, Ginkgo biloba, and mometasone nasal spray. Arch OtolaryngolHead Neck Surg. 2009;135(10):1000&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19841338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo YC, Yao LY, Wei YX. [Clinical treatment effect of glucocorticoids and extract of Ginkgo biloba on post-viral olfactory dysfunction.] Lin Chung Er Bi Yan Hou Tou Jing Wai Ke Za Zhi. 2017;31(20):1585&#x2013;88. [in Chinese]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29797955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattes RD, Pawlik MK. Effects of Ginkgo biloba on alertness and chemosensory function in healthy adults. Hum Psychopharmacol. 2004;19(2):81&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14994317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Droy-Lefaix MT. Effect of the antioxidant action of Ginkgo biloba extract (EGb 761&#xae;) on aging and oxidative stress. Age (Omaha) 1997;20(3):141&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3455891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23604306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee GS, Cho JH, Park CS, et al. The effect of Ginkgo biloba on the expression of intermediate-early antigen (c-fos) in the experimentally induced anosmic mouse. Auris Nasus Larynx. 2009;36(3):287&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19010624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Didier A, Jourdan F. The Ginkgo biloba extract modulates the balance between proliferation and differentiation in the olfactory epithelium of adult mice following bulbectomy. Cell Mol Biol (Noisy-le-grand) 2002;48(6):717&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12396084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier S, Schlaefke S. Efficacy and tolerability of Ginkgo biloba extract EGb 761&#xa9; in dementia: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized placebo-controlled trials. Clinical Interventions in Aging. 2014;9:2065&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4259871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25506211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrucci R, Dini M, Rosci C, et al. One-year cognitive follow-up of COVID-19 hospitalized patients. Eur J Neurol. 2022;29(7):2006&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9111730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35285122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>