<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36802108</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2702</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long-term health consequences of COVID-19 in survivors hospitalised at a tertiary care hospital and their correlation with acute COVID-19 severity and associated risk factors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>115</StartPage><EndPage>125</EndPage><MedlinePgn>115-125</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocn.16652</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine post-COVID syndromes in the Indian population, correlating a wide spectrum of post-COVID manifestations with acute disease severity and associated risk factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Post-COVID Syndrome (PCS) is defined as signs and symptoms that develop during or after acute COVID-19 infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN OF STUDY" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a prospective observational cohort with repetitive measurements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study followed RT-PCR confirmed COVID-19-positive survivors discharged from HAHC Hospital, New Delhi, for a period of 12&#x2009;weeks. The patients were interviewed over the phone at 4&#x2009;weeks and 12&#x2009;weeks from the onset of symptoms for evaluation of clinical symptoms and health-related quality of life parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 200 patients completed the study. At the baseline, 50% of the patients were categorised as severe based on their acute infection assessment. At 12&#x2009;weeks after symptom onset, fatigue (23.5%), hair loss (12.5%) and dyspnea (9%) were the main persistent symptoms. The incidence of hair loss (12.5%), memory loss (4.5%) and brain fog (5%) were found to be increased as compared to the acute infection period. Severity of the acute COVID infection behaved as an independent predictor for the development of PCS, with high odds of experiencing persistent cough (OR&#xa0;=&#xa0;13.1), memory loss (OR&#xa0;=&#xa0;5.2) and fatigue (OR&#xa0;=&#xa0;3.3). Further, 30% of subjects in the severe group experienced statistically significant fatigue at 12&#x2009;weeks (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">From the results of our study, it can be concluded that there is a huge disease burden of post-COVID Syndrome (PCS). The PCS comprised multisystem symptoms ranging from serious complaints of dyspnea, memory loss and brain fog to non-serious complaints of fatigue and hair loss. Severity of the acute COVID infection behaved as an independent predictor for the development of PCS. Our findings strongly recommend vaccination against COVID-19, for protection from disease severity as well as prevention of PCS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RELEVANCE TO CLINICAL PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The findings of our study support the multidisciplinary approach required for the management of PCS with a team comprising of physicians, nurses, physiotherapists and psychiatrists working in close coordination for the rehabilitation of these patients. As nurses are considered the most trusted professionals in the community and the class of health workers associated with rehabilitation, focus should be given to educating them on PCS, which would prove to be an important strategy for efficient monitoring and long-term management of COVID-19 survivors.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jain</LastName><ForeName>Vineet</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Hamdard Institute of Medical Sciences and Research and associated HAHC Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nabi</LastName><ForeName>Nusrat</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Hamdard Institute of Medical Sciences and Research and associated HAHC Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aggarwal</LastName><ForeName>Sanjana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Hamdard Institute of Medical Sciences and Research and associated HAHC Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alam</LastName><ForeName>Zaara</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Hamdard Institute of Medical Sciences and Research and associated HAHC Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chandra</LastName><ForeName>Kailash</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4938-9622</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Hamdard Institute of Medical Sciences and Research and associated HAHC Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Dharmander</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Hamdard Institute of Medical Sciences and Research and associated HAHC Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kashyap</LastName><ForeName>Varun</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Medicine, Hamdard Institute of Medical Sciences and Research and associated HAHC Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Islam</LastName><ForeName>Farzana</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Medicine, Hamdard Institute of Medical Sciences and Research and associated HAHC Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kohli</LastName><ForeName>Sunil</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Hamdard Institute of Medical Sciences and Research and associated HAHC Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9207302</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0962-1067</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062606" MajorTopicYN="N">Tertiary Care Centers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000505" MajorTopicYN="N">Alopecia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004417" MajorTopicYN="N">Dyspnea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005222" MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008569" MajorTopicYN="N">Memory Disorders</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 disease severity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 sequelae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 survivors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ongoing COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">persistent COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36802108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.16652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>AIIMS/ ICMR-COVID-19 National Task Force/ Joint Monitoring Group. (2021, January 14). Clinical guidelines for management of adult COVID-19 patients. https://www.icmr.gov.in/pdf/covid/techdoc/COVID_Clinical_Management_14012022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan, N. A. (2020). Track COVID-19 sickness, not just positive tests and deaths. Nature, 584(7820), 170. https://doi.org/10.1038/D41586-020-02335-Z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold, D. T., Hamilton, F. W., Milne, A., Morley, A. J., Viner, J., Attwood, M., Noel, A., Gunning, S., Hatrick, J., Hamilton, S., Elvers, K. T., Hyams, C., Bibby, A., Moran, E., Adamali, H. I., Dodd, J. W., Maskell, N. A., &amp; Barratt, S. L. (2021). Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up: Results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax, 76(4), 399-401. https://doi.org/10.1136/THORAXJNL-2020-216086</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani, D., Bermingham, C., Pouwels, K. B., Glickman, M., Nafilyan, V., Zaccardi, F., Khunti, K., Alwan, N. A., &amp; Walker, A. S. (2022). Trajectory of long covid symptoms after covid-19 vaccination: Community based cohort study. BMJ (Clinical Research ed.), 377, e069676. https://doi.org/10.1136/BMJ-2021-069676</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani, D., Khunti, K., Nafilyan, V., Maddox, T., Humberstone, B., Diamond, I., &amp; Banerjee, A. (2021). Post-covid syndrome in individuals admitted to hospital with covid-19: Retrospective cohort study. BMJ, 372, n693. https://doi.org/10.1136/BMJ.N693</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bektas, A., Schurman, S. H., Franceschi, C., &amp; Ferrucci, L. (2020). A public health perspective of aging: Do hyper-inflammatory syndromes such as COVID-19, SARS, ARDS, cytokine storm syndrome, and post-ICU syndrome accelerate short- and long-term inflammaging? Immunity &amp; Ageing: I &amp; A, 17(1), 1-27. https://doi.org/10.1186/S12979-020-00196-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortolato, B., Carvalho, A. F., Soczynska, J. K., Perini, G. I., &amp; McIntyre, R. S. (2015). The involvement of TNF-&#x3b1; in cognitive dysfunction associated with major depressive disorder: An opportunity for domain specific treatments. Current Neuropharmacology, 13(5), 558-576. https://doi.org/10.2174/1570159X13666150630171433</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caraballo, C., Desai, N. R., Mulder, H., Alhanti, B., Wilson, F. P., Fiuzat, M., Felker, G. M., Pi&#xf1;a, I. L., O'Connor, C. M., Lindenfeld, J., Januzzi, J. L., Cohen, L. S., &amp; Ahmad, T. (2019). Clinical implications of the New York heart association classification. Journal of the American Heart Association, 8(23), e014240. https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.119.014240</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Schneider, C., Laurent, E., Lemaignen, A., Beaufils, E., Bourbao-Tournois, C., Laribi, S., Flament, T., Ferreira-Maldent, N., Bruy&#xe8;re, F., Stefic, K., Gaudy-Graffin, C., Grammatico-Guillon, L., &amp; Bernard, L. (2021). Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Clinical Microbiology and Infection: The Official Publication of the European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, 27(2), 258-263. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.CMI.2020.09.052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charan, J., &amp; Biswas, T. (2013). How to calculate sample size for different study designs in medical research? Indian Journal of Psychological Medicine, 35(2), 121-126. https://doi.org/10.4103/0253-7176.116232</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couzin-Frankel, J. (2020). The mystery of the pandemic's &#x2018;happy hypoxia. Science, 368(6490), 455-456. https://doi.org/10.1126/SCIENCE.368.6490.455/ASSET/5945F01B-ED4A-4C04-B765-197DDC9DAA8B/ASSETS/GRAPHIC/368_455_F1.JPEG</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Cruz, R. F., Waller, M. D., Perrin, F., Periselneris, J., Norton, S., Smith, L.-J., Patrick, T., Walder, D., Heitmann, A., Lee, K., Madula, R., McNulty, W., Macedo, P., Lyall, R., Warwick, G., Galloway, J. B., Birring, S. S., Patel, A., Patel, I., &amp; Jolley, C. J. (2020). Chest radiography is a poor predictor of respiratory symptoms and functional impairment in survivors of severe COVID-19 pneumonia. ERJ Open Research, 7(1), 655-2020. https://doi.org/10.1183/23120541.00655-2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Graaf, M. A., Antoni, M. L., ter Kuile, M. M., Arbous, M. S., Duinisveld, A. J. F., Feltkamp, M. C. W., Groeneveld, G. H., Hinnen, S. C. H., Janssen, V. R., Lijfering, W. M., Omara, S., Postmus, P. E., Ramai, S. R. S., Rius-Ottenheim, N., Schalij, M. J., Schiemanck, S. K., Smid, L., St&#xf6;ger, J. L., Visser, L. G., &#x2026; Roukens, A. H. E. (2021). Short-term outpatient follow-up of COVID-19 patients: A multidisciplinary approach. EClinicalMedicine, 32, 100731. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.ECLINM.2021.100731</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delorme, C., Paccoud, O., Kas, A., Hesters, A., Bombois, S., Shambrook, P., Boullet, A., Doukhi, D., Le Guennec, L., Godefroy, N., Maatoug, R., Fossati, P., Millet, B., Navarro, V., Bruneteau, G., Demeret, S., &amp; Pourcher, V. (2020). COVID-19-related encephalopathy: A case series with brain FDG-positron-emission tomography/computed tomography findings. European Journal of Neurology, 27(12), 2651-2657. https://doi.org/10.1111/ENE.14478</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhawan, R. T., Gopalan, D., Howard, L., Vicente, A., Park, M., Manalan, K., Wallner, I., Marsden, P., Dave, S., Branley, H., Russell, G., Dharmarajah, N., &amp; Kon, O. M. (2021). Beyond the clot: Perfusion imaging of the pulmonary vasculature after COVID-19. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine, 9(1), 107-116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhont, S., Derom, E., Van Braeckel, E., Depuydt, P., &amp; Lambrecht, B. N. (2020). The pathophysiology of &#x201c;happy&#x201d; hypoxemia in COVID-19. Respiratory Research, 21(1), 1-9. https://doi.org/10.1186/S12931-020-01462-5/FIGURES/2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg, P., Arora, U., Kumar, A., &amp; Wig, N. (2021). The &#x201c;post-COVID&#x201d; syndrome: How deep is the damage? Journal of Medical Virology, 93(2), 673-674. https://doi.org/10.1002/JMV.26465</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grover, S., Sahoo, S., Mishra, E., Gill, K. S., Mehra, A., Nehra, R., Suman, A., Bhalla, A., &amp; Puri, G. D. (2021). Fatigue, perceived stigma, self-reported cognitive deficits and psychological morbidity in patients recovered from COVID-19 infection. Asian Journal of Psychiatry, 64, 1-8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajp.2021.102815</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin, S. J., McIvor, C., Whyatt, G., Adams, A., Harvey, O., McLean, L., Walshaw, C., Kemp, S., Corrado, J., Singh, R., Collins, T., O'Connor, R. J., &amp; Sivan, M. (2021). Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. Journal of Medical Virology, 93(2), 1013-1022. https://doi.org/10.1002/JMV.26368</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herdman, M., Gudex, C., Lloyd, A., Janssen, M., Kind, P., Parkin, D., Bonsel, G., &amp; Badia, X. (2011). Development and preliminary testing of the new five-level version of EQ-5D (EQ-5D-5L). Quality of Life Research: An International Journal of Quality of Life Aspects of Treatment, Care and Rehabilitation, 20(10), 1727-1736. https://doi.org/10.1007/S11136-011-9903-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C., Huang, L., Wang, Y., Li, X., Ren, L., Gu, X., Kang, L., Guo, L., Liu, M., Zhou, X., Luo, J., Huang, Z., Tu, S., Zhao, Y., Chen, L., Xu, D., Li, Y., Li, C., Peng, L., &#x2026; Cao, B. (2021). 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: A cohort study. The Lancet, 397(10270), 220-232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C., Wang, Y., Li, X., Ren, L., Zhao, J., Hu, Y., Zhang, L., Fan, G., Xu, J., Gu, X., Cheng, Z., Yu, T., Xia, J., Wei, Y., Wu, W., Xie, X., Yin, W., Li, H., Liu, M., &#x2026; Cao, B. (2020). Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. The Lancet, 395(10223), 497-506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal, F. M., Lam, K., Sounderajah, V., Clarke, J. M., Ashrafian, H., &amp; Darzi, A. (2021). Characteristics and predictors of acute and chronic post-COVID syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine, 36, 100899. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.ECLINM.2021.100899</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahler, D. A., &amp; Wells, C. K. (1988). Evaluation of clinical methods for rating dyspnea. Chest, 93(3), 580-586. https://doi.org/10.1378/CHEST.93.3.580</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matza, L. S., Morlock, R., Sexton, C., Malley, K., &amp; Feltner, D. (2010). Identifying HAM-A cutoffs for mild, moderate, and severe generalized anxiety disorder. International Journal of Methods in Psychiatric Research, 19(4), 223-232. https://doi.org/10.1002/MPR.323</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miglis, M. G., Goodman, B. P., Ch&#xe9;mali, K. R., &amp; Stiles, L. (2021). Re: &#x2018;Post-COVID-19 chronic symptoms&#x2019; by Davido et al. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 27(3), 494. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.CMI.2020.08.028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez, O., Merino, E., Leon-Ramirez, J. M., Andres, M., Ramos, J. M., Arenas-Jim&#xe9;nez, J., Asensio, S., Sanchez, R., Ruiz-Torregrosa, P., Galan, I., Scholz, A., Amo, A., Gonz&#xe1;lez-delaAleja, P., Boix, V., &amp; Gil, J. (2021). Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: A Mediterranean cohort study. The Journal of Infection, 82(3), 378-383. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.JINF.2021.01.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) guidelines. (2020). COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19 | Guidance | NICE. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office of National Statistics. (2021). Updated estimates of the prevalence of long COVID symptoms - Office for National Statistics. https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/healthandlifeexpectancies/adhocs/12788updatedestimatesoftheprevalenceoflongcovidsymptoms</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabin, R., &amp; De Charro, F. (2001). EQ-5D: A measure of health status from the EuroQol group. Annals of Medicine, 33(5), 337-343. https://doi.org/10.3109/07853890109002087</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rees, E. M., Nightingale, E. S., Jafari, Y., Waterlow, N. R., Clifford, S., Carl, C. A., Group, C. W, Jombart, T., Procter, S. R., &amp; Knight, G. M. (2020). COVID-19 length of hospital stay: A systematic review and data synthesis. BMC Medicine, 18(1), 1-22. https://doi.org/10.1186/S12916-020-01726-3/FIGURES/4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers, J. P., Chesney, E., Oliver, D., Pollak, T. A., McGuire, P., Fusar-Poli, P., Zandi, M. S., Lewis, G., &amp; David, A. S. (2020). Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: A systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. The Lancet Psychiatry, 7(7), 611-627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudroff, T., Kamholz, J., Fietsam, A. C., Deters, J. R., &amp; Bryant, A. D. (2020). Post-COVID-19 fatigue: Potential contributing factors. Brain Sciences, 10(12), 1-7. https://doi.org/10.3390/BRAINSCI10121012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serafini, G., Parmigiani, B., Amerio, A., Aguglia, A., Sher, L., &amp; Amore, M. (2020). The psychological impact of COVID-19 on the mental health in the general population. QJM: Monthly Journal of the Association of Physicians, 113(8), 229-235. https://doi.org/10.1093/QJMED/HCAA201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw, B., Daskareh, M., &amp; Gholamrezanezhad, A. (2021). The lingering manifestations of COVID-19 during and after convalescence: Update on long-term pulmonary consequences of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). La Radiologia Medica, 126(1), 40-46. https://doi.org/10.1007/S11547-020-01295-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem, K., Ghanima, W., Olsen, M. K., Gilboe, H. M., &amp; Einvik, G. (2021). Prevalence and determinants of fatigue after COVID-19 in non-hospitalized subjects: A population-based study. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 18(4), 1-11. https://doi.org/10.3390/IJERPH18042030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde, M. W., Kim, S. S., Lindsell, C. J., Billig Rose, E., Shapiro, N. I., Files, D. C., Gibbs, K. W., Erickson, H. L., Steingrub, J. S., Smithline, H. A., Gong, M. N., Aboodi, M. S., Exline, M. C., Henning, D. J., Wilson, J. G., Khan, A., Qadir, N., Brown, S. M., Peltan, I. D., &#x2026; Wu, M. J. (2022). Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network - United States, march-June 2020. MMWR. Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report, 69(30), 993-998. https://doi.org/10.15585/MMWR.MM6930E1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udwadia, Z., Koul, P., &amp; Richeldi, L. (2021). Post-COVID lung fibrosis: The tsunami that will follow the earthquake. Lung India: Official Organ of Indian Chest Society, 38(Supplement), 41-S47. https://doi.org/10.4103/LUNGINDIA.LUNGINDIA_818_20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2022). WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard | WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard with vaccination data. https://covid19.who.int/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, W., Wu, Y., Wang, W., Zhao, D., Liang, L., Wang, M., Yang, Y., Sun, J., Shi, P., &amp; Huo, Y. (2011). A longitudinal study of carotid plaque and risk of ischemic cardiovascular disease in the Chinese population. Journal of the American Society of Echocardiography: Official Publication of the American Society of Echocardiography, 24(7), 729-737. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.ECHO.2011.02.011</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>