<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36990762</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1843</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Respirology (Carlton, Vic.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Respirology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Contemporary Concise Review 2022: Sleep.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>518</StartPage><EndPage>524</EndPage><MedlinePgn>518-524</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/resp.14500</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>COVID-19 AND SLEEP: The COVID-19 pandemic is associated with an increase in insomnia and impaired sleep quality Health care workers are particularly susceptible and improved with cognitive behavioural therapy for insomnia (CBT-I) Long COVID has significant effects on sleep OSA impacts on the severity of acute COVID-19 illness OBSTRUCTIVE SLEEP APNOEA: Large trials of clinically representative patients confirm the cardiovascular benefits of CPAP treatment in OSA CPAP may improve long-term cognitive outcomes in OSA, but further research is needed Racial disparities in OSA prevalence and mortality risk are becoming evident Periodic evaluation of OSA risk in pregnancy is important as timing may be key for intervention to prevent or treat cardiovascular risk factors INSOMNIA: Comorbid insomnia and obstructive sleep apnoea (COMISA) can frequently co-exist and the combined negative effects of both may be deleterious, particularly to cardiovascular health There is evidence for effectiveness with novel orexin receptor antagonists.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Respirology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd on behalf of Asian Pacific Society of Respirology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Driscoll</LastName><ForeName>Denise M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Sleep Medicine, Eastern Health, Box Hill, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eastern Health Clinical School, Monash University, Box Hill, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Young</LastName><ForeName>Alan C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0718-1564</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Sleep Medicine, Eastern Health, Box Hill, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eastern Health Clinical School, Monash University, Box Hill, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Respirology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9616368</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1323-7799</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007319" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020181" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insomnia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">narcolepsy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obstructive sleep apnoea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">restless legs syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36990762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.14500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli S, Zagaria A, Ratti PL, Albano A, Fazio V, Musetti A, et al. Subjective sleep alterations in healthy subjects worldwide during COVID-19 pandemic: a systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression. Sleep Med. 2022;100:89-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlRasheed MM, Fekih-Romdhane F, Jahrami H, Pires GN, Saif Z, Alenezi AF, et al. The prevalence and severity of insomnia symptoms during COVID-19: a global systematic review and individual participant data meta-analysis. Sleep Med. 2022;100:7-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin CM, Vezina-Im LA, Ivers H, Micoulaud-Franchi JA, Philip P, Lamy M, et al. Prevalent, incident, and persistent insomnia in a population-based cohort tested before (2018) and during the first-wave of COVID-19 pandemic (2020). Sleep. 2022;45(1):zsab258. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsab258</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salfi F, Amicucci G, Corigliano D, Viselli L, D'Atri A, Tempesta D, et al. Two years after lockdown: longitudinal trajectories of sleep disturbances and mental health over the COVID-19 pandemic, and the effects of age, gender and chronotype. J Sleep Res. 2022;e13767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drager LF, Pachito DV, Moreno CRC, Tavares AR, Conway SG, Assis M, et al. Insomnia episodes, new-onset pharmacological treatments, and other sleep disturbances during the COVID-19 pandemic: a nationwide cross-sectional study in Brazilian health care professionals. J Clin Sleep Med. 2022;18(2):373-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy E, DeViva JC, Na PJ, Pietrzak RH. New-onset and exacerbated insomnia symptoms during the COVID-19 pandemic in US military veterans: a nationally representative, prospective cohort study. J Sleep Res. 2022;31(1):e13450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou K, Kong J, Wan Y, Zhang X, Liu X, Qu B, et al. Positive impacts of e-aid cognitive behavioural therapy on the sleep quality and mood of nurses on site during the COVID-19 pandemic. Sleep Breath. 2022;26(4):1947-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amra B, Ghadiry F, Vaezi A, Nematollahy A, Radfar N, Haghjoo S, et al. Effect of one-shot cognitive behavioral therapy on insomnia and heart rate variability of health care workers at the time of COVID-19 pandemic: a randomized controlled trial. Sleep Breath. 2022;100:S116. doi:10.1016/j.sleep.2022.05.321</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merikanto I, Dauvilliers Y, Chung F, Wing YK, De Gennaro L, Holzinger B, et al. Sleep symptoms are essential features of long-COVID-comparing healthy controls with COVID-19 cases of different severity in the international COVID sleep study (ICOSS-II). J Sleep Res. 2023;32(1):e13754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rognvaldsson KG, Eythornorsson ES, Emilsson OI, Eysteinsdottir B, Palsson R, Gottfreethsson M, et al. Obstructive sleep apnea is an independent risk factor for severe COVID-19: a population-based study. Sleep. 2022;45(3):zsab272. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsab272</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voncken SFJ, Feron TMH, Laven S, Karaca U, Beerhorst K, Klarenbeek P, et al. Impact of obstructive sleep apnea on clinical outcomes in patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Sleep Breath. 2022;26(3):1399-407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerves-Pinquie C, Bailly S, Goupil F, Pigeanne T, Launois S, Leclair-Visonneau L, et al. Positive airway pressure adherence, mortality, and cardiovascular events in patients with sleep apnea. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2022;206(11):1393-404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trzepizur W, Blanchard M, Ganem T, Balusson F, Feuilloy M, Girault JM, et al. Sleep apnea-specific hypoxic burden, symptom subtypes, and risk of cardiovascular events and all-cause mortality. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2022;205(1):108-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CH, Timofeeva M, O'Brien T, Lyons OD. Obstructive sleep apnea and nocturnal attacks of paroxysmal atrial fibrillation. J Clin Sleep Med. 2022;18(5):1279-86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchner S, Wester M, Hobelsberger S, Fisser C, Debl K, Hetzenecker A, et al. Obstructive sleep apnoea is associated with the development of diastolic dysfunction after myocardial infarction with preserved ejection fraction. Sleep Med. 2022;94:63-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey MD, Wickwire EM, Somers VK, Albrecht JS. Adherence to continuous positive airway pressure reduces the risk of 30-day hospital readmission among older adults with comorbid obstructive sleep apnea and cardiovascular disease. J Clin Sleep Med. 2022;18(12):2739-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Wang X, Fan J, Guo R, Hao W, Gong W, et al. Effect of obstructive sleep apnoea on coronary collateral vessel development in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction. Respirology. 2022;27(8):653-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azarbarzin A, Zinchuk A, Wellman A, Labarca G, Vena D, Gell L, et al. Cardiovascular benefit of continuous positive airway pressure in adults with coronary artery disease and obstructive sleep apnea without excessive sleepiness. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2022;206(6):767-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messineo L, Taranto-Montemurro L, Calianese N, Gell LK, Azarbarzin A, Labarca G, et al. Atomoxetine and fesoterodine combination improves obstructive sleep apnoea severity in patients with milder upper airway collapsibility. Respirology. 2022;27(11):975-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong AM, Landry SA, Joosten SA, Thomson LDJ, Turton A, Stonehouse J, et al. Examining the impact of multilevel upper airway surgery on the obstructive sleep apnoea endotypes and their utility in predicting surgical outcomes. Respirology. 2022;27(10):890-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panza GS, Puri S, Lin HS, Badr MS, Mateika JH. Daily exposure to mild intermittent hypoxia reduces blood pressure in male patients with obstructive sleep apnea and hypertension. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2022;205(8):949-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward SA, Storey E, Gasevic D, Naughton MT, Hamilton GS, Trevaks RE, et al. Sleep-disordered breathing was associated with lower health-related quality of life and cognitive function in a cross-sectional study of older adults. Respirology. 2022;27(9):767-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Rozario AL, Hoyos CM, Wong KKH, Unger G, Kim JW, Vakulin A, et al. Improvements in cognitive function and quantitative sleep electroencephalogram in obstructive sleep apnea after six months of continuous positive airway pressure treatment. Sleep. 2022;45(6):zsac013. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsac013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shieu MM, Zaheed A, Shannon C, Chervin RD, Conceicao A, Paulson HL, et al. Positive airway pressure and cognitive disorders in adults with obstructive sleep apnea: a systematic review of the literature. Neurology. 2022;99(4):e334-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franks KH, Rowsthorn E, Nicolazzo J, Boland A, Lavale A, Baker J, et al. The treatment of sleep dysfunction to improve cognitive function: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sleep Med. 2023;101:118-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YC, Chang KY, Mador MJ. Racial disparity in sleep apnea-related mortality in the United States. Sleep Med. 2022;90:204-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah MI, Tamanna S. Racial disparity in cardiovascular morbidity and mortality associated with obstructive sleep apnea: the sleep heart health study. Sleep Med. 2023;101:528-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M, Stone A, Soose RJ, Cohen SM, Howard J, Capasso R, et al. Does race-ethnicity affect upper airway stimulation adherence and treatment outcome of obstructive sleep apnea? J Clin Sleep Med. 2022;18(9):2167-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Votteler S, Knaack L, Janicki J, Fink GR, Burghaus L. Sex differences in polysomnographic findings in patients with obstructive sleep apnea. Sleep Med. 2023;101:429-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalleinen N, Saaresranta T, Polo O, Raitakari OT, Riskumaki M, Vahlberg T, et al. Early signs of sleep-disordered breathing in healthy women predict carotid intima-media thickening after 10&#x2009;years. Sleep Med. 2022;96:8-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunietz GL, Hao W, Shedden K, Holzman C, Chervin RD, Lisabeth LD, et al. Maternal habitual snoring and blood pressure trajectories in pregnancy. J Clin Sleep Med. 2022;18(1):31-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanapo L, Bublitz MH, Bai A, Mehta N, Messerlian GM, Catalano P, et al. Association between sleep disordered breathing in early pregnancy and glucose metabolism. Sleep. 2022;45(4):zsab281. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsab281</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facco FL, Redline S, Hunter SM, Zee PC, Grobman WA, Silver RM, et al. Sleep-disordered breathing in pregnancy and after delivery: associations with cardiometabolic health. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2022;205(10):1202-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson DL, Fung AM, Pell G, Skrzypek H, Barnes M, Bourjeily G, et al. Polysomnographic analysis of maternal sleep position and its relationship to pregnancy complications and sleep-disordered breathing. Sleep. 2022;45(4):zsac032. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsac032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quin N, Lee JJ, Pinnington DM, Newman L, Manber R, Bei B. Differentiating perinatal insomnia disorder and sleep disruption: a longitudinal study from pregnancy to 2&#x2009;years postpartum. Sleep. 2022;45(2):zsab293. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsab293</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendle AM, Salemi JL, Jackson CL, Buysse DJ, Louis JM. Insomnia during pregnancy and severe maternal morbidity in the United States: nationally representative data from 2006 to 2017. Sleep. 2022;45(10):zsac175. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsac175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felder JN, Epel ES, Neuhaus J, Krystal AD, Prather AA. Randomized controlled trial of digital cognitive behavior therapy for prenatal insomnia symptoms: effects on postpartum insomnia and mental health. Sleep. 2022;45(2):zsab280. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsab280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mysliwiec V, Brock MS, Pruiksma KE, Straud CL, Taylor DJ, Hansen S, et al. A comprehensive evaluation of insomnia, obstructive sleep apnea and comorbid insomnia and obstructive sleep apnea in US military personnel. Sleep. 2022;45(12):zsac203. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsac203</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon B, Luyster FS, Sereika SM, DiNardo MM, Callan JA, Chasens ER. Comorbid obstructive sleep apnea and insomnia and its associations with mood and diabetes-related distress in type 2 diabetes mellitus. J Clin Sleep Med. 2022;18(4):1103-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagg SA, Ilieva E, Ljunggren M, Franklin KA, Middelveld R, Lundback B, et al. The negative health effects of having a combination of snoring and insomnia. J Clin Sleep Med. 2022;18(4):973-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechat B, Appleton S, Melaku YA, Hansen K, McEvoy RD, Adams R, et al. The association of co-morbid insomnia and sleep apnea with prevalent cardiovascular disease and incident cardiovascular events. J Sleep Res. 2022;31(5):e13563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechat B, Appleton S, Melaku YA, Hansen K, McEvoy RD, Adams R, et al. Comorbid insomnia and sleep apnoea is associated with all-cause mortality. Eur Respir J. 2022;60(1):2101958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechat B, Loffler KA, Wallace DM, Reynolds A, Appleton SL, Scott H, et al. All-cause mortality in people with co-occurring insomnia symptoms and sleep apnea: analysis of the Wisconsin sleep cohort. Nat Sci Sleep. 2022;14:1817-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu AY, Crawford MR, Dawson SC, Fogg LF, Turner AD, Wyatt JK, et al. A randomized controlled trial of cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia and PAP for obstructive sleep apnea and comorbid insomnia: effects on nocturnal sleep and daytime performance. J Clin Sleep Med. 2022;18(3):789-800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mignot E, Mayleben D, Fietze I, Leger D, Zammit G, Bassetti CLA, et al. Safety and efficacy of daridorexant in patients with insomnia disorder: results from two multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trials. Lancet Neurol. 2022;21(2):125-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Crescenzo F, D'Alo GL, Ostinelli EG, Ciabattini M, Di Franco V, Watanabe N, et al. Comparative effects of pharmacological interventions for the acute and long-term management of insomnia disorder in adults: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Lancet. 2022;400(10347):170-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brostrom A, Alimoradi Z, Lind J, Ulander M, Lundin F, Pakpour A. Worldwide estimation of restless legs syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of prevalence in the general adult population. J Sleep Res. 2023;e13783. doi:10.1111/jsr.13783</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Hoeven AE, Fronczek R, Schinkelshoek MS, Roelandse FWC, Bakker JA, Overeem S, et al. Intermediate hypocretin-1 cerebrospinal fluid levels and typical cataplexy: their significance in the diagnosis of narcolepsy type 1. Sleep. 2022;45(5):zsac052. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsac052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postiglione E, Barateau L, Pizza F, Lopez R, Antelmi E, Rassu AL, et al. Narcolepsy with intermediate cerebrospinal level of hypocretin-1. Sleep. 2022;45(2):zsab285. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsab285</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>