<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37018063</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1864-0648</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of biophotonics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Biophotonics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Use of either transcranial or whole-body photobiomodulation treatments improves COVID-19 brain fog.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e202200391</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e202200391</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jbio.202200391</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>There is increasing recognition of post-COVID-19 sequelae involving chronic fatigue and brain fog, for which photobiomodulation (PBM) therapy has been utilized. This open-label, pilot, human clinical study examined the efficacy of two PBM devices, for example, a helmet (1070&#x2009;nm) for transcranial (tPBM) and a light bed (660 and 850&#x2009;nm) for whole body (wbPBM), over a 4-week period, with 12 treatments for two separate groups (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;7 per group). Subjects were evaluated with a neuropsychological test battery, including the Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA), the digit symbol substitution test (DSST), the trail-making tests A and B, the physical reaction time (PRT), and a quantitative electroencephalography system (WAVi), both pre- and post- the treatment series. Each device for PBM delivery was associated with significant improvements in cognitive tests (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 and beyond). Changes in WAVi supported the findings. This study outlines the benefits of utilizing PBM therapy (transcranial or whole-body) to help treat long-COVID brain fog.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Journal of Biophotonics published by Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bowen</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shepherd University, Shepherdstown, West Virginia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>West Virginia University, Martinsburg, West Virginia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arany</LastName><ForeName>Praveen R</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6116-2340</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shepherd University, Shepherdstown, West Virginia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University at Buffalo, Buffalo, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Biophotonics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101318567</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1864-063X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004569" MajorTopicYN="N">Electroencephalography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D028022" MajorTopicYN="Y">Low-Level Light Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LLLT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Photobiomodulation therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain fog</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37018063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jbio.202200391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Coronaviridae Study Group of the International Committee on Taxonomy of V, Nat. Microbiol. 2020, 5, 536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. J. Guan, Z. Y. Ni, Y. Hu, W. H. Liang, C. Q. Ou, J. X. He, L. Liu, H. Shan, C. L. Lei, D. S. C. Hui, B. Du, L. J. Li, G. Zeng, K. Y. Yuen, R. C. Chen, C. L. Tang, T. Wang, P. Y. Chen, J. Xiang, S. Y. Li, J. L. Wang, Z. J. Liang, Y. X. Peng, L. Wei, Y. Liu, Y. H. Hu, P. Peng, J. M. Wang, J. Y. Liu, Z. Chen, G. Li, Z. J. Zheng, S. Q. Qiu, J. Luo, C. J. Ye, S. Y. Zhu, N. S. Zhong, N. Engl. J. Med. 2020, 382, 1708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Al-Aly, Y. Xie, B. Bowe, Nature 2021, 594, 259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Nalbandian, K. Sehgal, A. Gupta, M. V. Madhavan, C. McGroder, J. S. Stevens, J. R. Cook, A. S. Nordvig, D. Shalev, T. S. Sehrawat, N. Ahluwalia, B. Bikdeli, D. Dietz, C. Der-Nigoghossian, N. Liyanage-Don, G. F. Rosner, E. J. Bernstein, S. Mohan, A. A. Beckley, D. S. Seres, T. K. Choueiri, N. Uriel, J. C. Ausiello, D. Accili, D. E. Freedberg, M. Baldwin, A. Schwartz, D. Brodie, C. K. Garcia, M. S. V. Elkind, J. M. Connors, J. P. Bilezikian, D. W. Landry, E. Y. Wan, Nat. Med. 2021, 27, 601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. B. Soriano, S. Murthy, J. C. Marshall, P. Relan, J. V. Diaz, Condition WHOCCDWGoP-C, Lancet Infect. Dis. 2022, 22, e102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. L. Graham, J. R. Clark, Z. S. Orban, P. H. Lim, A. L. Szymanski, C. Taylor, R. M. DiBiase, D. T. Jia, R. Balabanov, S. U. Ho, A. Batra, E. M. Liotta, I. J. Koralnik, Ann. Clin. Transl. Neurol. 2021, 8, 1073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Taquet, R. Sillett, L. Zhu, J. Mendel, I. Camplisson, Q. Dercon, P. J. Harrison, Lancet Psychiatry 2022, 9, 815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Venkataramani, F. Winkler, N. Engl. J. Med. 2022, 387, 1813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. J. Boegel, M. Gabriel, M. Sasges, B. Petri, M. R. D'Agostino, A. Zhang, J. C. Ang, M. S. Miller, S. M. Meunier, M. G. Aucoin, Microbiol. Spectr. 2021, 9, e0053721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Chiappa, B. Frascella, G. P. Vigezzi, M. Moro, L. Diamanti, L. Gentile, P. Lago, N. Clementi, C. Signorelli, N. Mancini, A. Odone, J. Hosp. Infect. 2021, 114, 63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. S. Enwemeka, V. V. Bumah, J. L. Mokili, J. Photochem. Photobiol. B 2021, 222, 112282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. A. Sigman, S. Mokmeli, M. Monici, M. A. Vetrici, Am. J. Case Rep. 2020, 21, e926779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. A. Sigman, S. Mokmeli, M. A. Vetrici, Can. J. Respir. Ther. 2020, 56, 52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Vetrici, S. Mokmeli, A. R. Bohm, M. Monici, S. A. Sigman, J. Inflamm. Res. 2021, 14, 965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. R. Arany, Photobiomodul. Photomed. Laser Surg. 2020, 38, 524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Cassano, M. A. Caldieraro, R. Norton, D. Mischoulon, N. H. Trinh, M. Nyer, C. Dording, M. R. Hamblin, B. Campbell, D. V. Iosifescu, Photobiomodul. Photomed. Laser Surg. 2019, 37, 651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Nejatifard, S. Asefi, R. Jamali, M. R. Hamblin, R. Fekrazad, Cytokine+ 2021, 137, 155312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. K. Williams, J. Raimondo, D. Cahn, A. Williams, D. Schell, J. Biophotonics. 2022, 15, e202100194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. C. Kitchen, M. Berman, J. Halper, P. Chazot, Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2022, 23, 5221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. R. Arany, J. Dent. Res. 2016, 95, 977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Moskvin, E. Askhadulin, A. Kochetkov, Rehabil. Res. Pract. 2021, 2021, 6626932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Surazakov, A. Klassen, O. Gizinger, J. Photochem. Photobiol. B 2020, 213, 112083.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Soheilifar, H. Fathi, N. Naghdi, Lasers Med. Sci. 2021, 36, 935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Pooam, B. Aguida, S. Drahy, N. Jourdan, M. Ahmad, Commun. Integr. Biol. 2021, 14, 66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. B. Macedo, C. R. Tim, H. W. Kido, J. B. Macedo, C. C. S. Martignago, A. C. M. Renno, G. B. Macedo, L. Assis, Lasers Med. Sci. 2022, 37, 1921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Jahani Sherafat, S. Mokmeli, M. Rostami-Nejad, Z. Razaghi, M. Rezaei Tavirani, M. Razzaghi, J. Lasers Med. Sci. 2020, 11, S23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. B. Fernandes, C. J. de Lima, A. Villaverde, P. C. Pereira, H. C. Carvalho, R. A. Zangaro, Photobiomodul. Photomed. Laser Surg. 2020, 38, 395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Fekrazad, S. Asefi, M. Pourhajibagher, F. Vahdatinia, S. Fekrazad, A. Bahador, H. Abrahamse, M. R. Hamblin, Adv. Exp. Med. Biol. 2021, 1318, 517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. S. Enwemeka, V. V. Bumah, D. S. Masson-Meyers, J. Photochem. Photobiol. B 2020, 207, 111891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Dominguez, S. A. Velasquez, M. A. David, Photobiomodul. Photomed. Laser Surg. 2020, 38, 258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. T. L. de Matos, D. V. Buchaim, K. T. Pomini, S. M. Barbalho, E. L. Guiguer, C. H. B. Reis, C. R. S. Bueno, M. R. D. Cunha, E. Pereira, R. L. Buchaim, Life (Basel) 2021, 11, 580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. M. de Lima, F. Aimbire, H. Miranda, R. P. Vieira, A. P. de Oliveira, R. Albertini, J. Lasers Med. Sci. 2014, 5, 63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. M. de Lima, L. M. Moreira, A. B. Villaverde, R. Albertini, H. C. Castro-Faria-Neto, F. Aimbire, Lasers Med. Sci. 2011, 26, 389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. M. de Lima, L. Vitoretti, F. Coelho, R. Albertini, A. C. Breithaupt-Faloppa, W. T. de Lima, F. Aimbire, Lasers Med. Sci. 2013, 28, 551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Mafra de Lima, M. S. Costa, R. Albertini, J. A. Silva Jr., F. Aimbire, Lasers Surg. Med. 2009, 41, 68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. C. Oliveira Jr., F. R. Greiffo, N. C. Rigonato-Oliveira, R. W. Custodio, V. R. Silva, N. R. Damaceno-Rodrigues, F. M. Almeida, R. Albertini, R. A. Lopes-Martins, L. V. de Oliveira, P. T. de Carvalho, A. P. Ligeiro de Oliveira, E. C. Leal Jr., R. P. Vieira, J. Photochem. Photobiol. B 2014, 134, 57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. R. Pigatto, I. S. Coelho, R. S. Aquino, L. F. Bauermann, A. R. S. Santos, Mol. Neurobiol. 2017, 54, 3205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. R. Pigatto, C. S. Silva, N. A. Parizotto, J. Photochem. Photobiol. B 2019, 196, 111513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Sandor, Z. Helyes, K. Elekes, J. Szolcsanyi, Neurosci. Lett. 2009, 451, 204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Chiappelli, Bioinformation 2020, 16, 288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. D. Pyne, A. M. Brickman, Neurodegener Dis. 2021, 21, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Imai, K. Kuba, S. Rao, Y. Huan, F. Guo, B. Guan, P. Yang, R. Sarao, T. Wada, H. Leong-Poi, M. A. Crackower, A. Fukamizu, C. C. Hui, L. Hein, S. Uhlig, A. S. Slutsky, C. Jiang, J. M. Penninger, Nature 2005, 436, 112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. C. Fajgenbaum, C. H. June, N. Engl. J. Med. 2020, 383, 2255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Wicik, C. Eyileten, D. Jakubik, S. N. Simoes, D. C. Martins Jr., R. Pavao, J. M. Siller-Matula, M. Postula, J. Clin. Med. 2020, 9, 3743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Ollivier, A. Bertrand, F. Clarencon, S. Gerber, S. Deltour, F. Domont, S. Trunet, D. Dormont, D. Leclercq, J. Neurol. Sci. 2017, 373, 188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Carfi, R. Bernabei, F. Landi, C.-P.-A. C. S. G. Gemelli Against, JAMA 2020, 324, 603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. A. Muili, S. Gopalakrishnan, S. L. Meyer, J. T. Eells, J. A. Lyons, PLoS One 2012, 7, e30655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Purushothuman, D. M. Johnstone, C. Nandasena, J. van Eersel, L. M. Ittner, J. Mitrofanis, J. Stone, Neurosci. Lett. 2015, 591, 155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. M. Johnstone, C. Hamilton, L. C. Gordon, C. Moro, N. Torres, F. Nicklason, J. Stone, A. L. Benabid, J. Mitrofanis, J. Alzheimers Dis. 2021, 83, 1399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Enengl, M. R. Hamblin, P. Dungel, J. Alzheimers Dis. 2020, 75, 1073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. R. Hamblin, J. Neurosci. Res. 2018, 96, 731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Hennessy, M. R. Hamblin, J. Opt. 2017, 19, 013003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Miranda-Silva, W. Gomes-Silva, Y. Zadik, N. Yarom, A. R. Al-Azri, C. H. L. Hong, A. Ariyawardana, D. P. Saunders, M. E. Correa, P. R. Arany, J. Bowen, K. K. F. Cheng, W. J. E. Tissing, P. Bossi, S. Elad, Support Care Cancer 2021, 29, 3539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Robijns, R. G. Nair, J. Lodewijckx, P. Arany, A. Barasch, J. M. Bjordal, P. Bossi, A. Chilles, P. M. Corby, J. B. Epstein, S. Elad, R. Fekrazad, E. R. Fregnani, M. T. Genot, A. M. C. Ibarra, M. R. Hamblin, V. Heiskanen, K. Hu, J. Klastersky, R. Lalla, S. Latifian, A. Maiya, J. Mebis, C. A. Migliorati, D. M. J. Milstein, B. Murphy, J. E. Raber-Durlacher, H. J. Roseboom, S. Sonis, N. Treister, Y. Zadik, R. J. Bensadoun, Front. Oncol. 2022, 12, 927685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zadik, P. R. Arany, E. R. Fregnani, P. Bossi, H. S. Antunes, R. J. Bensadoun, L. A. Gueiros, A. Majorana, R. G. Nair, V. Ranna, W. J. E. Tissing, A. Vaddi, R. Lubart, C. A. Migliorati, R. V. Lalla, K. K. F. Cheng, S. Elad, Support Care Cancer 2019, 27, 3969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. S. Nasreddine, N. A. Phillips, V. Bedirian, S. Charbonneau, V. Whitehead, I. Collin, J. L. Cummings, H. Chertkow, J. Am. Geriatr. Soc. 2005, 53, 695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Jaeger, J. Clin. Psychopharmacol. 2018, 38, 513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Ashendorf, A. L. Jefferson, M. K. O'Connor, C. Chaisson, R. C. Green, R. A. Stern, Arch. Clin. Neuropsychol. 2008, 23, 129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. C. Young, V. Maximiano, P. R. Arany, J. Biophotonics 2022, 15, e202100398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Y. Lee, J. W. Choi, H. Kim, Geophys. Res. Lett. 2008, 27, 71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Saint-Leger, J. L. Leveque, Br. J. Dermatol. 1982, 106, 669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wan, J. He, L. Chen, L. Qiu, F. Wang, X. L. Chen, Med. Sci. Monit. 2022, 28, e937697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Lopez-Leon, T. Wegman-Ostrosky, C. Perelman, R. Sepulveda, P. A. Rebolledo, A. Cuapio, S. Villapol, Sci. Rep. 2021, 11, 16144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Kaczynski, E. Mylonakis, Ann. Intern. Med. 2022, 175, JC10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. L. Levine, JAMA 2022, 328, 823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. E. Tedford, S. DeLapp, S. Jacques, J. Anders, Lasers Surg. Med. 2015, 47, 312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Yue, M. S. Humayun, J. Biomed. Opt. 2015, 20, 88001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Salehpour, P. Cassano, N. Rouhi, M. R. Hamblin, L. De Taboada, F. Farajdokht, J. Mahmoudi, Photobiomodul. Photomed. Laser Surg. 2019, 37, 581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. D. Morries, P. Cassano, T. A. Henderson, Neuropsychiatr. Dis. Treat. 2015, 11, 2159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. H. Berman, J. P. Halper, T. W. Nichols, H. Jarrett, A. Lundy, J. H. Huang, J. Neurol. Neurosci. 2017, 8, 176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. E. Saltmarche, M. A. Naeser, K. F. Ho, M. R. Hamblin, L. Lim, Photomed. Laser Surg. 2017, 35, 432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. I. Martin, L. Chao, M. H. Krengel, M. D. Ho, M. Yee, R. Lew, J. Knight, M. R. Hamblin, M. A. Naeser, Front. Neurol. 2020, 11, 574386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Naeser, M. D. Ho, P. I. Martin, M. R. Hamblin, B. B. Koo, Photobiomodul. Photomed. Laser Surg. 2020, 38, 115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Liebert, B. Bicknell, E. L. Laakso, G. Heller, P. Jalilitabaei, S. Tilley, J. Mitrofanis, H. Kiat, BMC Neurol. 2021, 21, 256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Qi, D. Nizamutdinov, M. H. Berman, G. Dougal, P. L. Chazot, E. Wu, A. B. Stevens, S. S. Yi, J. H. Huang, Cureus 2021, 13, e16188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. V. Iosifescu, R. J. Norton, U. Tural, D. Mischoulon, K. Collins, E. McDonald, L. De Taboada, S. Foster, C. Cusin, A. Yeung, A. Clain, D. Schoenfeld, M. R. Hamblin, P. Cassano, J. Clin. Psychiatry 2022, 83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. P. Sommer, J. Bieschke, R. P. Friedrich, D. Zhu, E. E. Wanker, H. J. Fecht, D. Mereles, W. Hunstein, Photomed. Laser Surg. 2012, 30, 54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Farfara, H. Tuby, D. Trudler, E. Doron-Mandel, L. Maltz, R. J. Vassar, D. Frenkel, U. Oron, J. Mol. Neurosci. 2015, 55, 430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Blivet, J. Meunier, F. J. Roman, J. Touchon, Alzheimers Dement. (N Y) 2018, 4, 54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. M. Cho, S. Y. Lee, J. H. Park, M. J. Kim, K. J. Park, B. T. Choi, Y. I. Shin, N. G. Kim, H. K. Shin, J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med Sci. 2020, 75, 631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. S. Chan, T. L. Lee, M. R. Hamblin, M. C. Cheung, J. Alzheimers Dis. 2021, 83, 1471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Naeser, P. I. Martin, M. D. Ho, M. H. Krengel, Y. Bogdanova, J. A. Knight, M. K. Yee, R. Zafonte, J. Frazier, M. R. Hamblin, B. B. Koo, Photomed. Laser Surg. 2016, 34, 610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Naeser, R. Zafonte, M. H. Krengel, P. I. Martin, J. Frazier, M. R. Hamblin, J. A. Knight, W. P. Meehan 3rd., E. H. Baker, J. Neurotrauma. 2014, 31, 1008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Gonzalez-Lima, B. R. Barksdale, J. C. Rojas, Biochem. Pharmacol. 2014, 88, 584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Vargas, D. W. Barrett, C. L. Saucedo, L. D. Huang, J. A. Abraham, H. Tanaka, A. P. Haley, F. Gonzalez-Lima, Lasers Med. Sci. 2017, 32, 1153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wang, J. P. Dmochowski, L. Zeng, E. Kallioniemi, M. Husain, F. Gonzalez-Lima, H. Liu, Neurophotonics 2019, 6, 025013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wang, H. Wanniarachchi, A. Wu, F. Gonzalez-Lima, H. Liu, Sci. Rep. 2021, 11, 18917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. J. Blanco, W. T. Maddox, F. Gonzalez-Lima, J. Neuropsychol. 2017, 11, 14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Rojas, A. K. Bruchey, F. Gonzalez-Lima, J. Alzheimers Dis. 2012, 32, 741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wang, F. Tian, D. D. Reddy, S. S. Nalawade, D. W. Barrett, F. Gonzalez-Lima, H. Liu, J. Cereb. Blood Flow Metab 2017, 37, 3789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. D. S. Cardoso, D. W. Barrett, Z. Wade, S. Gomes da Silva, F. Gonzalez-Lima, Front. Neurosci. 2022, 16, 818005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. T. Wong-Riley, H. L. Liang, J. T. Eells, B. Chance, M. M. Henry, E. Buchmann, M. Kane, H. T. Whelan, J. Biol. Chem. 2005, 280, 4761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. I. Karu, S. F. Kolyakov, Photomed. Laser Surg. 2005, 23, 355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, Y. Y. Huang, Y. Wang, P. Lyu, M. R. Hamblin, Biochim. Biophys. Acta. Gen. Subj. 2017, 1861, 441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. D. Yim, G. Gallos, J. F. Perez-Zoghbi, Y. Zhang, D. Xu, A. Wu, D. E. Berkowitz, C. W. Emala, Am. J. Physiol. Lung Cell Mol. Physiol. 2019, 316, L82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Sikka, G. P. Hussmann, D. Pandey, S. Cao, D. Hori, J. T. Park, J. Steppan, J. H. Kim, V. Barodka, A. C. Myers, L. Santhanam, D. Nyhan, M. K. Halushka, R. C. Koehler, S. H. Snyder, L. A. Shimoda, D. E. Berkowitz, Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 2014, 111, 17977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Buscone, A. N. Mardaryev, B. Raafs, J. W. Bikker, C. Sticht, N. Gretz, N. Farjo, N. E. Uzunbajakava, N. V. Botchkareva, Lasers Surg. Med. 2017, 49, 705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Barreto Ortiz, D. Hori, Y. Nomura, X. Yun, H. Jiang, H. Yong, J. Chen, S. Paek, D. Pandey, G. Sikka, A. Bhatta, A. Gillard, J. Steppan, J. H. Kim, H. Adachi, V. M. Barodka, L. Romer, S. S. An, L. A. Shimoda, L. Santhanam, D. E. Berkowitz, Am. J. Physiol. Lung. Cell Mol. Physiol. 2018, 314, L93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. R. Arany, A. Cho, T. D. Hunt, G. Sidhu, K. Shin, E. Hahm, G. X. Huang, J. Weaver, A. C. Chen, B. L. Padwa, M. R. Hamblin, M. H. Barcellos-Hoff, A. B. D. J. M. Kulkarni, Sci. Transl. Med. 2014, 6, 238ra269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. T. Hashmi, Y. Y. Huang, B. Z. Osmani, S. K. Sharma, M. A. Naeser, M. R. Hamblin, PMR 2010, 2, S292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Rojas, F. Gonzalez-Lima, Eye. Brain 2011, 3, 49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Saieva, G. Taglialatela, Sci. Rep. 2022, 12, 10848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Basso, W. A. Suzuki, Brain Plast. 2017, 2, 127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Herold, A. Torpel, L. Schega, N. G. Muller, Eur. Rev. Aging Phys. Act. 2019, 16, 10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Hotting, B. Roder, Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev. 2013, 37, 2243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Azcue, J. C. Gomez-Esteban, M. Acera, B. Tijero, T. Fernandez, N. Ayo-Mentxakatorre, T. Perez-Concha, A. Murueta-Goyena, J. V. Lafuente, A. Prada, A. Lopez de Munain, G. Ruiz-Irastorza, L. Ribacoba, I. Gabilondo, R. Del Pino, J. Transl. Med. 2022, 20, 569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. A. Matias-Guiu, V. Pytel, J. Matias-Guiu, J. Alzheimers Dis. 2020, 78, 537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. N. Aiello, E. Fiabane, M. R. Manera, A. Radici, F. Grossi, M. Ottonello, D. Pain, C. Pistarini, Neurol. Sci. 2022, 43, 81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Lynch, S. J. Ferrando, R. Dornbush, S. Shahar, A. Smiley, L. Klepacz, Gen. Hosp. Psychiatry. 2022, 78, 80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Vrankic, S. Vlahinic, Z. Sverko, I. Markovinovic, Sensors (Basel) 2022, 22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. McGee, A. Liebert, G. Herkes, B. Bicknell, V. Pang, C. S. McLachlan, H. Kiat, Front. Neurosci. 2022, 16, 945796.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>