<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35586759</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2434-9194</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Global health &amp; medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Glob Health Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID: current status in Japan and knowledge about its molecular background.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>83</StartPage><EndPage>93</EndPage><MedlinePgn>83-93</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.35772/ghm.2022.01013</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Even after recovering from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), patients can experience prolonged complaints, referred to as "long COVID". Similar to reports in Caucasians, a follow-up study in Japan revealed that fatigue, dyspnea, cough, anosmia/dysgeusia, and dyssomnia are common symptoms. Although the precise mode of long COVID remains elusive, multiple etiologies such as direct organ damage by infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2), autoimmunity, prolonged inflammatory reactions, and psychiatric impairment seem to be involved. Notably, SARS-CoV-2 is neurotropic, and viral RNA and proteins are continuously detectable in multiple organs, including the brain. Viral proteins exert a number of different toxic effects on cells, suggesting that persistent infection is a key element for understanding long COVID. Here, we first reviewed the current status of long COVID in Japan, and then summarized literature that help us understand the molecular background of the symptoms. Finally, we discuss the feasibility of vaccination as a treatment for patients with long COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>2022, National Center for Global Health and Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsunaga</LastName><ForeName>Akihiro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Intractable Diseases, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsuzuki</LastName><ForeName>Shinya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AMR Clinical Reference Center, National Center for Global Health and Medicine Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morioka</LastName><ForeName>Shinichiro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Disease Control and Prevention Center, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohmagari</LastName><ForeName>Norio</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Disease Control and Prevention Center, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishizaka</LastName><ForeName>Yukihito</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Intractable Diseases, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Glob Health Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101771579</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2434-9186</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoantibody</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">persistency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccination</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viral proteins</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35586759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9066464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35772/ghm.2022.01013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. . Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021; 27:601-615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M. Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nat Immunol. 2022; 23:194-202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Wo r ld Heal th Organ izat i o n. A c l i n ical cas e definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021. 
https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/345824 (accessed March 9, 2022). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, Villapol S. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021; 11:16144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazato Y, Morioka S, Tsuzuki S, Akashi M, Osanai Y, Tanaka K, Terada M, Suzuki M, Kutsuna S, Saito S, Hayakawa K, Ohmagari N. Prolonged and late-onset symptoms of coronavirus disease 2019. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2020; 7:ofaa507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33230486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Pellicer- Valero &#xd3;J, Navarro-Pardo E, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Arias-Naval&#xf3;n JA, Cigar&#xe1;n-M&#xe9;ndez M, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Barrera V, Arendt-Nielsen L. Female sex is a risk factor associated with long-term post-COVID related-symptoms but not with COVID-19 symptoms: The LONG-COVID-EXP-CM multicenter study. J Clin Med. 2022; 11:413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8778106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35054108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KG, Brokstad KA, et al. . Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med. 2021; 27:1607-1613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin D, Margalit I, Nehme M, et al. . Patterns of long COVID symptoms: A multi-center cross sectional study. J Clin Med. 2022; 11:898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8875229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35207171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishikura H, Maruyama J, Hoshino K, Matsuoka Y, Yano M, Arimura T, Katano H, Kato S, Kitamura T, Nakamura Y. Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) associated delayed-onset fulminant myocarditis in patient with a history of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection. J Infect Chemother. 2021; 27:1760-1764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8358135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34446351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Falahi Z, Al-Harthi S, Farhan H, Al Busaidi I, Al Alawi AM. Late-onset COVID-19-related multi-system inflammatory syndrome in a middle-aged man. Cureus. 2021; 13:e15855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8301271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34327082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q, Zheng B, Daines L, Sheikh A. Long-term sequelae of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis of one-year follow-up studies on post-COVID symptoms. Pathogens. 2022; 11:269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8875269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35215212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed H, Patel K, Greenwood DC, Halpin S, Lewthwaite P, Salawu A, Eyre L, Breen A, O'Connor R, Jones A, Sivan M. Long-term clinical outcomes in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus outbreaks after hospitalisation or ICU admission: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Rehabil Med. 2020; 52:jrm00063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32449782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aucott JN, Rebman AW. Long-haul COVID: heed the lessons from other infection-triggered illnesses. Lancet. 2021; 397:967-968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7952095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33684352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez- Mayordomo V, et al. . Fatigue and dyspnoea as main persistent post-COVID-19 symptoms in previously hospitalized patients: Related functional limitations and disability. Respiration. 2022; 101:132-141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8678253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34569550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortini A, Rosso A, Cecchini P, Torrigiani A, Lo Forte A, Carrai P, Alessi C, Fabbrizzi F, Lovicu E, Sbaragli S, Faraone A. One-year evolution of DLCO changes and respiratory symptoms in patients with post COVID-19 respiratory syndrome. Infection. 2022; 50:513-517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8777423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35061232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnweber T, Sahanic S, Pizzini A, et al. . Cardiopulmonary recovery after COVID-19: an observational prospective multicentre trial. Eur Respir J. 2021; 57:2003481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam GY, Befus AD, Damant RW, Ferrara G, Fuhr DP, Stickland MK, Varughese RA, Wong EY, Smith MP. Exertional intolerance and dyspnea with preserved lung function: an emerging long COVID phenotype? Respir Res. 2021; 22:222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8343348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34362372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melms JC, Biermann J, Huang H, et al. . A molecular single-cell lung atlas of lethal COVID-19. Nature. 2021; 595:114-119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8814825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33915568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazen H. Postinfluenzal alopecia. JAMA. 1919; 72:1452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starace M, Iorizzo M, Sechi A, et al. . Trichodynia and telogen effluvium in COVID-19 patients: Results of an international expert opinion survey on diagnosis and management. JAAD Int. 2021; 5:11-18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8328568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34368790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagan N, Meah N, York K, Bokhari L, Fletcher G, Chen G, Tobin DJ, Messenger A, Irvine AD, Sinclair R, Wall D. Shedding light on therapeutics in alopecia and their relevance to COVID-19. Clin Dermatol. 2021; 39:76-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7738938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33972056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, et al. . Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022; 185:881-895.e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilinska K, Jakubowska P, Von Bartheld CS, Butowt R. Expression of the SARS-CoV-2 entry proteins, ACE2 and TMPRSS2, in cells of the olfactory epithelium: Identification of cell types and trends with age. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2020; 11:1555-1562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7241737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brann DH, Tsukahara T, Weinreb C, et al. . Non-neuronal expression of SARS-CoV-2 entry genes in the olfactory system suggests mechanisms underlying COVID-19- associated anosmia. Sci Adv. 2020; 6:eabc5801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10715684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32937591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantuti-Castelvetri L, Ojha R, Pedro LD, et al. . Neuropilin-1 facilitates SARS-CoV-2 cell entry and infectivity. Science. 2020; 370:856-860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33082293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirschenbaum D, Imbach LL, Ulrich S, Rushing EJ, Keller E, Reimann RR, Frauenknecht KBM, Lichtblau M, Witt M, Hummel T, Steiger P, Aguzzi A, Frontzek K. Inflammatory olfactory neuropathy in two patients with COVID-19. Lancet. 2020; 396:166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7351381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32659210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler ES, Bailey AL, Kafai NM, et al. . SARS-CoV-2 infection of human ACE2-transgenic mice causes severe lung inflammation and impaired function. Nat Immunol. 2020; 21:1327-1335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7578095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32839612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng J, Wong LR, Li K, Verma AK, Ortiz ME, Wohlford-Lenane C, Leidinger MR, Knudson CM, Meyerholz DK, McCray PB Jr, Perlman S. COVID-19 treatments and pathogenesis including anosmia in K18- hACE2 mice. Nature. 2021; 589:603-607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7855185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale-Cross L, Szalayova I, Scoggins A, Palkovits M, Mezey E. SARS-CoV-2 entry sites are present in all structural elements of the human glossopharyngeal and vagal nerves: clinical implications. bioRxiv. 2022; 2021.12.30.474580</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8978584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35390636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
UpToDate. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). 
https://www.uptodate.com/landing/covid19?source=promobox (accessed March 9, 2022). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization. Support for rehabilitation: self-management after COVID-19-related illuness. 
2020. 
https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/344472/WHO-EURO-2021-855-40590-59892-eng.pdf?sequence=1&amp;isAllowed=y (accessed March 9, 2022). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. COVID-19. 
https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/your-health/quarantine-isolation.html (accessed March 9, 2022). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera JE, Niehaus WN, Whiteson J, Azola A, Baratta JM, Fleming TK, Kim SY, Naqvi H, Sampsel S, Silver JK, Gutierrez MV, Maley J, Herman E, Abramoff B. Multidisciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of fatigue in postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) patients. PM R. 2021; 13:1027-1043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8441628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34346558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Homerton University Hospital. Post COVID-19 patients infromation pack. Helping you to recover and manage your symptoms following COVID-19. 
https://gp-website-cdn-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/downloads/1589364822-a2ac4f0d54141da323f4087888276478.pdf (accessed March 9, 2022). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kattar N, Do TM, Unis GD, Migneron MR, Thomas AJ, McCoul ED. Olfactory training for postviral olfactory dysfunction: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2021; 164:244-254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32660334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carod-Artal FJ. Neurological complications of coronavirus and COVID-19. Rev Neurol. 2020; 70:311-322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32329044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbour N, Day R, Newcombe J, Talbot PJ. Neuroinvasion by human respiratory coronaviruses. J Virol. 2000; 74:8913-8921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC102086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10982334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau KK, Yu WC, Chu CM, Lau ST, Sheng B, Yuen KY. Possible central nervous system infection by SARS coronavirus. Emerg Infect Dis. 2004; 10:342-344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3322928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15030709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Zhong S, Liu J, Li L, Li Y, Wu X, Li Z, Deng P, Zhang J, Zhong N, Ding Y, Jiang Y. Detection of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus in the brain: potential role of the chemokine mig in pathogenesis. Clin Infect Dis. 2005; 41:1089-1096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7107994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16163626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J, Radke J, Dittmayer C, et al. . Olfactory transmucosal SARS-CoV-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with COVID-19. Nat Neurosci. 2021; 24:168-175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke J, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Hagel C, et al. . Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol. 2020; 19:919-929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7535629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng CT, Huang C, Newman P, Wang N, Narayanan K, Watts DM, Makino S, Packard MM, Zaki SR, Chan TS, Peters CJ. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus infection of mice transgenic for the human Angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 virus receptor. J Virol. 2007; 81:1162-1173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1797529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17108019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Netland J, Meyerholz DK, Moore S, Cassell M, Perlman S. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus infection causes neuronal death in the absence of encephalitis in mice transgenic for human ACE2. J Virol. 2008; 82:7264-7275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2493326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18495771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeOre BJ, Tran KA, Andrews AM, Ramirez SH, Galie PA. SARS-CoV-2 spike protein disrupts blood-brain barrier integrity via RhoA activation. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2021; 16:722-728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8536479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34687399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): An overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front Microbiol. 2021; 12:698169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV, Misra A. Post COVID-19 syndrome ("Long COVID") and diabetes: Challenges in diagnosis and management. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021; 15:102235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8317446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34384972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James JA, Kaufman KM, Farris AD, Taylor-Albert E, Lehman TJ, Harley JB. An increased prevalence of Epstein-Barr virus infection in young patients suggests a possible etiology for systemic lupus erythematosus. J Clin Invest. 1997; 100:3019-3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC508514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9399948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Sui L, Wu P, Wang W, Wang Z, Yu Y, Hou Z, Tan G, Liu Q, Wang G. A dual-role of SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein in regulating innate immune response. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021; 6:331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34471099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leisman DE, Ronner L, Pinotti R, Taylor MD, Sinha P, Calfee CS, Hirayama AV, Mastroiani F, Turtle CJ, Harhay MO, Legrand M, Deutschman CS. Cytokine elevation in severe and critical COVID-19: a rapid systematic review, meta-analysis, and comparison with other inflammatory syndromes. Lancet Respir Med. 2020; 8:1233-1244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7567529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33075298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Ong CM, Yun C, Mo W, Whitman JD, Lynch KL, Wu AHB. Diagnostic value of nucleocapsid protein in blood for SARS-CoV-2 infection. Clin Chem. 2021; 68:240-248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8436384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34358289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barhoumi T, Alghanem B, Shaibah H, Mansour FA, Alamri HS, Akiel MA, Alroqi F, Boudjelal M. SARS-CoV-2 coronavirus spike protein-induced apoptosis, inflammatory, and oxidative stress responses in THP-1- like-macrophages: Potential role of angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitor (Perindopril). Front Immunol. 2021; 12:728896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8488399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34616396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirato K, Kizaki T. SARS-CoV-2 spike protein S1 subunit induces pro-inflammatory responses via toll-like receptor 4 signaling in murine and human macrophages. Heliyon. 2021; 7:e06187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7887388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33644468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki YJ, Nikolaienko SI, Dibrova VA, Dibrova YV, Vasylyk VM, Novikov MY, Shults NV, Gychka SG. SARS-CoV-2 spike protein-mediated cell signaling in lung vascular cells. Vascul Pharmacol. 2021; 137:106823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7680014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33232769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank MG, Nguyen KH, Ball JB, Hopkins S, Kelley T, Baratta MV, Fleshner M, Maier SF. SARS-CoV-2 spike S1 subunit induces neuroinflammatory, microglial and behavioral sickness responses: Evidence of PAMP-like properties. Brain Behav Immun. 2022; 100:267-277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8667429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34915155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi Y, Lafferty JA, Clements JR, Todd JK, Gelfand EW, Kappler J, Marrack P, Kotzin BL. Selective expansion of T cells expressing V beta 2 in toxic shock syndrome. J Exp Med. 1990; 172:981-984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2188536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2117641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deacy AM, Gan SK, Derrick JP. Superantigen recognition and interactions: Functions, mechanisms and applications. Front Immunol. 2021; 12:731845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8488440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34616400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng MH, Porritt RA, Rivas MN, Krieger JM, Ozdemir AB, Garcia G Jr, Arumugaswami V, Fries BC, Arditi M, Bahar I. A monoclonal antibody against staphylococcal enterotoxin B superantigen inhibits SARS-CoV-2 entry in vitro. Structure. 2021; 29:951-962 e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8082696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33930306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto K. Possible mechanisms of autoantibody production and the connection of viral infections in human autoimmune diseases. Tohoku J Exp Med. 1994; 173:75-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7528946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas M, Restrepo-Jim&#xe9;nez P, Monsalve DM, Pacheco Y, Acosta-Ampudia Y, Ram&#xed;rez-Santana C, Leung PSC, Ansari AA, Gershwin ME, Anaya JM. Molecular mimicry and autoimmunity. J Autoimmun. 2018; 95:100-123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30509385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacheco Y, Acosta-Ampudia Y, Monsalve DM, Chang C, Gershwin ME, Anaya JM. Bystander activation and autoimmunity. J Autoimmun. 2019; 103:102301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31326230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotz PH. Autoantibodies are anti-idiotype antibodies to antiviral antibodies. Lancet. 1983; 2:824-826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6137652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canas CA. The triggering of post-COVID-19 autoimmunity phenomena could be associated with both transient immunosuppression and an inappropriate form of immune reconstitution in susceptible individuals. Med Hypotheses. 2020; 145:110345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7556280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33080459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodruff MC, Ramonell RP, Saini AS, et al. . Relaxed peripheral tolerance drives broad de novo autoreactivity in severe COVID-19. medRxiv. 2021; 2020.10.21.20216192</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acay A, Demir K, Asik G, Tunay H, Acarturk G. Assessment of the frequency of autoantibodies in chronic viral hepatitis. Pak J Med Sci. 2015; 31:150-154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4386176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25878633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutton RN, Emond RT, Thomas DB, Doniach D. The occurrence of autoantibodies in infectious mononucleosis. Clin Exp Immunol. 1974; 17:427-436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1554074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4619789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen P, Andersen HK. Smooth-muscle antibodies and other tissue antibodies in cytomegalovirus infection. Clin Exp Immunol. 1975; 22:22-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1538345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">174854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vo HTM, Duong V, Ly S, Li QZ, Dussart P, Cantaert T. Autoantibody profiling in plasma of dengue virus-infected individuals. Pathogens. 2020; 9:1060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7766539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33352902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucchese G, Floel A. Molecular mimicry between SARS-CoV-2 and respiratory pacemaker neurons. Autoimmun Rev. 2020; 19:102556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7252083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32361194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanduc D, Shoenfeld Y. On the molecular determinants of the SARS-CoV-2 attack. Clin Immunol. 2020; 215:108426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7165084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32311462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vojdani A, Kharrazian D. Potential antigenic cross-reactivity between SARS-CoV-2 and human tissue with a possible link to an increase in autoimmune diseases. Clin Immunol. 2020; 217:108480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7246018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32461193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Tan W, Chen H, Zhu Y, Wan L, Jiang K, Guo Y, Tang K, Xie C, Yi H, Kuang Y, Luo Y. Dynamic changes in lymphocyte subsets and parallel cytokine levels in patients with severe and critical COVID-19. BMC Infect Dis. 2021; 21:79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7812569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sosa-Hern&#xe1;ndez VA, Torres-Ru&#xed;z J, Cervantes-D&#xed;az R, Romero-Ram&#xed;rez S, P&#xe1;ez-Franco JC, Meza-S&#xe1;nchez DE, Ju&#xe1;rez-Vega G, P&#xe9;rez-Fragoso A, Ortiz-Navarrete V, Ponce-de-Le&#xf3;n A, Llorente L, Berr&#xf3;n-Ruiz L, Mej&#xed;a- Dom&#xed;nguez NR, G&#xf3;mez-Mart&#xed;n D, Maravillas-Montero JL. B cell subsets as severity-associated signatures in COVID-19 patients. Front Immunol. 2020; 11:611004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7744304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33343585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Cerrillo I, Landete P, Aldave B, et al. . Differential redistribution of activated monocyte and dendritic cell subsets to the lung associates with severity of COVID-19. medRxiv. 2020; 2020.05.13.20100925</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favaloro EJ, Henry BM, Lippi G. COVID-19 and antiphospholipid antibodies: Time for a reality check? Semin Thromb Hemost. 2022; 48:72-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34130340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang EY, Mao T, Klein J, et al. . Diverse functional autoantibodies in patients with COVID-19. Nature. 2021; 595:283-288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34010947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi Y, Haga S, Ishizaka Y, Mimori A. Autoantibodies to angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 in patients with connective tissue diseases. Arthritis Res Ther. 2010; 12:R85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2911869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20470389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia H. Pulmonary angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) and inflammatory lung disease. Shock. 2016; 46:239-248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27082314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gue YX, Gorog DA. Reduction in ACE2 may mediate the prothrombotic phenotype in COVID-19. Eur Heart J. 2020; 41:3198-3199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32691041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupi L, Adamo M, Inciardi RM, Metra M. ACE2 down-regulation may contribute to the increased thrombotic risk in COVID-19. Eur Heart J. 2020; 41:3200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32691039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight JS, Caricchio R, Casanova JL, et al. . The intersection of COVID-19 and autoimmunity. J Clin Invest. 2021; 131:e154886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34710063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary MC, Crain CR, Qiu X, Hanage W, Li JZ. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) sequence characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) persistence and reinfection. Clin Infect Dis. 2022; 74:237-245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8135388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33906227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gousseff M, Penot P, Gallay L, et al. . Clinical recurrences of COVID-19 symptoms after recovery: Viral relapse, reinfection or inflammatory rebound? J Infect. 2020; 81:816-846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7326402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32619697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Kim SY, Kim TS, et al. . Evidence of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 reinfection after recovery from mild coronavirus disease 2019. Clin Infect Dis. 2021; 73:e3002-e3008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7890673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33219681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chertow D, Stein S, Ramelli S, Grazioli A, Chung J-Y, Singh M, Yinda CK, Winkler C, Dickey J, Yiaya K. SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence throughout the human body and brain. Research Square. 2021. DOI: 1021203/rs3rs-1139035/v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumata R, Ito J, Takahashi K, Suzuki T, Sato K. A tissue level atlas of the healthy human virome. BMC Biol. 2020; 18:55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7269688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32493363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy MK, Morrison TE. Persistent RNA virus infections: do PAMPS drive chronic disease? Curr Opin Virol. 2017; 23:8-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5474173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28214732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidhu MS, Crowley J, Lowenthal A, Karcher D, Menonna J, Cook S, Udem S, Dowling P. Defective measles virus in human subacute sclerosing panencephalitis brain. Virology. 1994; 202:631-641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8030228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia J, Chia A, Voel ler M, Lee T, Chang R. Acute enterovirus infection followed by myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) and viral persistence. J Clin Pathol. 2010; 63:165-168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19828908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishikawa H, Barber GN. STING is an endoplasmic reticulum adaptor that facilitates innate immune signalling. Nature. 2008; 455:674-678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2804933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18724357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vabret N, Britton GJ, Gruber C, et al. . Immunology of COVID-19: Current state of the science. Immunity. 2020; 52:910-941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7200337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32505227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webb LG, Fernandez-Sesma A. RNA viruses and the cGAS-STING pathway: reframing our understanding of innate immune sensing. Curr Opin Virol. 2022; 53:101206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35180533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rui Y, Su J, Shen S, et al. . Unique and complementary suppression of cGAS-STING and RNA sensing- triggered innate immune responses by SARS-CoV-2 proteins. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021; 6:123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7958565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33723219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Richards A, Barrasa MI, Hughes SH, Young RA, Jaenisch R. Reverse-transcribed SARS-CoV-2 RNA can integrate into the genome of cultured human cells and can be expressed in patient-derived tissues. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2021; 118:e2105968118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8166107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33958444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodier JL, Kazazian HH, Jr. Retrotransposons revisited: the restraint and rehabilitation of parasites. Cell. 2008; 135:23-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18854152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smits N, Rasmussen J, Bodea GO, Amarilla AA, Gerdes P, Sanchez-Luque FJ, Ajjikuttira P, Modhiran N, Liang B, Faivre J, Deveson IW, Khromykh AA, Watterson D, Ewing AD, Faulkner GJ. No evidence of human genome integration of SARS-CoV-2 found by long-read DNA sequencing. Cell Rep. 2021; 36:109530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8316065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34380018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel N, Goyal N, Nagaraja R, Kumar R. Systemic corticosteroids for management of 'long-COVID': an evaluation after 3 months of treatment. Monaldi Arch Chest Dis. 2021. doi:104081/monaldi20211981</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34730322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehme M, Braillard O, Salamun J, Jacquerioz F, Courvoisier DS, Spechbach H, Guessous I. Symptoms after COVID-19 vaccination in patients with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2. J Gen Intern Med. 2022; doi: 10.1007/s11606-022-07443-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8863092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35194744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT, Milne A, Samms E, Stadon L, Maskell NA, Hamilton FW. Symptoms after COVID-19 vaccination in patients with persistent symptoms after acute infection: A case series. Ann Intern Med. 2021; 174:1334-1336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8252827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34029484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherlinger M, Pijnenburg L, Chatelus E, Arnaud L, Gottenberg JE, Sibilia J, Felten R. Effect of SARS-CoV-2 vaccination on symptoms from post-acute sequelae of COVID-19: Results from the nationwide VAXILONG study. Vaccines (Basel). 2021; 10:46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8781023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35062706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta S, Chandra A, Ray BK, Pandit A. Treatment related fluctuation and response to intravenous immunoglobulin therapy in post COVID-19 Guillain-Barre syndrome. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021; 15:102246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8361026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34416468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>