<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37801299</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4644</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>124</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cellular biochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cell Biochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intrinsic factors behind long-COVID: II. SARS-CoV-2, extracellular vesicles, and neurological disorders.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1466</StartPage><EndPage>1485</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1466-1485</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcb.30486</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>With the decline in the number of new Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infections, the World Health Organization announced the end of the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. However, the repercussions of this viral pandemic may remain with us for a longer period of time, as it has remodeled the lives of humankind in many ways, including social and economic. Of course, its most important repercussions remain on the human health level. Long-coronavirus disease (COVID) or post-COVID is a state for which we do not have a concrete definition, a specific international classification of diseases Code, clear diagnostic tools, or well-known effective cures as of yet. In this second article from the Intrinsic Factors behind long-COVID Series, we try to link long-COVID symptoms with their causes, starting from the nervous system. Extracellular vesicles (ECVs) play very complex and ramified roles in the bodies of both healthy and not-healthy individuals. ECVs may facilitate the entry of many bioactive molecules and pathogens into the tissues and cells of the nervous system across the blood-brain barrier. Based on the size, quantity, and quality of their cargo, ECVs are directly proportional to the pathological condition and its severity through intertwined mechanisms that evoke inflammatory immune responses typically accompanied by pathological symptoms over variable time periods according to the type of these symptoms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Maradny</LastName><ForeName>Yousra A</ForeName><Initials>YA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Protein Research Department, Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology Research Institute, City of Scientific Research and Technological Applications (SRTA-City), New Borg EL-Arab, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Microbiology and Immunology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Arab Academy for Science, Technology and Maritime Transport (AASTMT), El-Alamein, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rubio-Casillas</LastName><ForeName>Alberto</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biology Laboratory, Autl&#xe1;n Regional Preparatory School, University of Guadalajara, Autl&#xe1;n, Jalisco, Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohamed</LastName><ForeName>Kareem I</ForeName><Initials>KI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Microbiology and Immunology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Arab Academy for Science, Technology and Maritime Transport (AASTMT), El-Alamein, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uversky</LastName><ForeName>Vladimir N</ForeName><Initials>VN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4037-5857</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine and USF Health Byrd Alzheimer's Research Institute, Morsani College of Medicine, University of South Florida, Tampa, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Redwan</LastName><ForeName>Elrashdy M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biological Science Department, Faculty of Science, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cell Biochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8205768</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0730-2312</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009422" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nervous System Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000067128" MajorTopicYN="Y">Extracellular Vesicles</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">central nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">extracellular vesicles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peripheral nervous system</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37801299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcb.30486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, et al. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020;395(10223):497-506. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed Y, El-Maradny YA, Saleh AK, Nayl AA, El-Gendi H, El-Fakharany EM. A comprehensive insight into current control of COVID-19: immunogenicity, vaccination, and treatment. Biomed Pharmacother. 2022;153:113499. doi:10.1016/j.biopha.2022.113499</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy D, Ghosh R, Dubey S, Dubey MJ, Benito-Le&#xf3;n J, Kanti Ray B. Neurological and neuropsychiatric impacts of COVID-19 pandemic. Can J Neurol Sci. 2021;48(1):9-24. doi:10.1017/cjn.2020.173</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsh EB, Kornberg M, Kessler K, et al. Quality Committee of the American Academy of, N COVID-19 and vaccination in the setting of neurologic disease: an emerging issue in neurology. Neurology. 2021;97(15):720-728. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000012578</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenting A, Gruters A, van Os Y, et al. COVID-19 neurological manifestations and underlying mechanisms: a scoping review. Front Psychiatry. 2020;11:860. doi:10.3389/fpsyt.2020.00860</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltezou HC, Pavli A, Tsakris A. Post-COVID syndrome: an insight on its pathogenesis. Vaccines. 2021;9(5):497. doi:10.3390/vaccines9050497</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Burden of Disease Long Covid Collaborators, Wulf Hanson S, Abbafati C, Aerts JG, et al. Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA. 2022;328(16):1604-1615. doi:10.1001/jama.2022.18931</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morello R, Mariani F, Mastrantoni L, et al. Risk factors for post-COVID-19 condition (Long Covid) in children: a prospective cohort study. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;59:101961. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2023.101961</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampasian V, Elghazaly H, Chattopadhyay R, et al. Risk factors associated with post-COVID-19 condition: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Intern Med. 2023;183:566. doi:10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.0750</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pezzini A, Padovani A. Lifting the mask on neurological manifestations of COVID-19. Nat Rev Neurol. 2020;16(11):636-644. doi:10.1038/s41582-020-0398-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu JM, Tan BH, Wu S, Gui Y, Suo JL, Li YC. Evidence of central nervous system infection and neuroinvasive routes, as well as neurological involvement, in the lethality of SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Med Virol. 2021;93(3):1304-1313. doi:10.1002/jmv.26570</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann B, Schmidbauer ML, Dimitriadis K, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid findings in COVID-19 patients with neurological symptoms. J Neurol Sci. 2020;418:117090. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2020.117090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantuti-Castelvetri L, Ojha R, Pedro LD, et al. Neuropilin-1 facilitates SARS-CoV-2 cell entry and infectivity. Science. 2020;370(6518):856-860. doi:10.1126/science.abd2985</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo D, Vasto S, Scalisi L, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 neurological syndrome: a new medical challenge. J Clin Med. 2021;10(9):1947. doi:10.3390/jcm10091947</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Yang Y, Liang X, et al. COVID-19 associated ischemic stroke and hemorrhagic stroke: incidence, potential pathological mechanism, and management. Front Neurol. 2020;11:571996. doi:10.3389/fneur.2020.571996</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassanpour M, Rezaie J, Nouri M, Panahi Y. The role of extracellular vesicles in COVID-19 virus infection. Infect Genet Evol. 2020;85:104422. doi:10.1016/j.meegid.2020.104422</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elrashdy F, Aljaddawi AA, Redwan EM, Uversky VN. On the potential role of exosomes in the COVID-19 reinfection/reactivation opportunity. J Biomol Struct Dyn. 2021;39(15):5831-5842. doi:10.1080/07391102.2020.1790426</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Maradny YA, Rubio-Casillas A, Uversky VN, Redwan EM. Intrinsic factors behind long-COVID: I. prevalence of the extracellular vesicles. JCB. 2023;124(5):656-673. doi:10.1002/jcb.30415</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raposo G, Stoorvogel W. Extracellular vesicles: exosomes, microvesicles, and friends. J Cell Biol. 2013;200(4):373-383. doi:10.1083/jcb.201211138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z&#xf6;ller M. Tetraspanins: push and pull in suppressing and promoting metastasis. Nat Rev Cancer. 2009;9(1):40-55. doi:10.1038/nrc2543</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long X, Yao X, Jiang Q, et al. Astrocyte-derived exosomes enriched with miR-873a-5p inhibit neuroinflammation via microglia phenotype modulation after traumatic brain injury. J Neuroinflammation. 2020;17(1):89. doi:10.1186/s12974-020-01761-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verkhratsky A, Ho MS, Zorec R, Parpura V. The concept of neuroglia. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2019;1175:1-13. doi:10.1007/978-981-13-9913-8_1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong GU, Lyu J, Kim KD, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection of microglia elicits proinflammatory activation and apoptotic cell death. Microbiol Spectr. 2022;10(3):e0109122. doi:10.1128/spectrum.01091-22</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, He W, Zhang J. A richer and more diverse future for microglia phenotypes. Heliyon. 2023;9(4):e14713. doi:10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e14713</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo D, Picone P, Caruana L, et al. Inflammatory mediators as biomarkers in brain disorders. Inflammation. 2014;37(3):639-648. doi:10.1007/s10753-013-9780-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho BP, Song DY, Sugama S, et al. Pathological dynamics of activated microglia following medial forebrain bundle transection. GLIA. 2006;53(1):92-102. doi:10.1002/glia.20265</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block ML, Zecca L, Hong JS. Microglia-mediated neurotoxicity: uncovering the molecular mechanisms. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2007;8(1):57-69. doi:10.1038/nrn2038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Town T, Jeng D, Alexopoulou L, Tan J, Flavell RA. Microglia recognize double-stranded RNA via TLR3. J Immunol. 2006;176(6):3804-3812. doi:10.4049/jimmunol.176.6.3804</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verkhratsky A, Parpura V, Vardjan N, Zorec R. Physiology of astroglia. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2019;1175:45-91. doi:10.1007/978-981-13-9913-8_3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beard E, Lengacher S, Dias S, Magistretti PJ, Finsterwald C. Astrocytes as key regulators of brain energy metabolism: new therapeutic perspectives. Front Physiol. 2022;12:825816. doi:10.3389/fphys.2021.825816</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Yuan Z, Yang S, et al. Brain energy metabolism: astrocytes in neurodegenerative diseases. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2023;29(1):24-36. doi:10.1111/cns.13982</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paniz-Mondolfi A, Bryce C, Grimes Z, et al. Central nervous system involvement by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2). J Med Virol. 2020;92(7):699-702. doi:10.1002/jmv.25915</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatnagar J, Gary J, Reagan-Steiner S, et al. Evidence of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 replication and tropism in the lungs, airways, and vascular endothelium of patients with fatal coronavirus disease 2019: an autopsy case series. J Infect Dis. 2021;223(5):752-764. doi:10.1093/infdis/jiab039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang F, Wang DY. COVID-19 anosmia: high prevalence, plural neuropathogenic mechanisms, and scarce neurotropism of SARS-CoV-2? Viruses. 2021;13(11):2225. doi:10.3390/v13112225</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez VS, Zetter MA, Guerra EC, et al. ACE2 expression in rat brain: implications for COVID-19 associated neurological manifestations. Exp Neurol. 2021;345:113837. doi:10.1016/j.expneurol.2021.113837</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindskog C, M&#xe9;ar L, Virhammar J, et al. Protein expression profile of ACE2 in the normal and COVID-19-affected human brain. J Proteome Res. 2022;21(9):2137-2145. doi:10.1021/acs.jproteome.2c00184</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao J, Li W, Bao J, et al. The expression of SARS-CoV-2 receptor ACE2 and CD147, and protease TMPRSS2 in human and mouse brain cells and mouse brain tissues. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2020;533(4):867-871. doi:10.1016/j.bbrc.2020.09.042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Liu T, Yang N, et al. Neurological manifestations of patients with COVID-19: potential routes of SARS-CoV-2 neuroinvasion from the periphery to the brain. Front Med. 2020;14(5):533-541. doi:10.1007/s11684-020-0786-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uversky VN, Elrashdy F, Aljadawi A, Ali SM, Khan RH, Redwan EM. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection reaches the human nervous system: how? J Neurosci Res. 2021;99(3):750-777. doi:10.1002/jnr.24752</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito G, Pesce M, Seguella L, Sanseverino W, Lu J, Sarnelli G. Can the enteric nervous system be an alternative entrance door in SARS-CoV2 neuroinvasion? Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:93-94. doi:10.1016/j.bbi.2020.04.060</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doty RL, Petersen I, Mensah N, Christensen K. Genetic and environmental influences on odor identification ability in the very old. Psychol Aging. 2011;26(4):864-871. doi:10.1037/a0023263</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari V, Koganti R, Russell G, Sharma A, Shukla D. Role of tunneling nanotubes in viral infection, neurodegenerative disease, and cancer. Front Immunol. 2021;12:680891. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.680891</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubio-Casillas A, Redwan EM, Uversky VN. SARS-CoV-2: a master of immune evasion. Biomedicines. 2022;10(6):1339. doi:10.3390/biomedicines10061339</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pepe A, Pietropaoli S, Vos M, Barba-Spaeth G, Zurzolo C. Tunneling nanotubes provide a route for SARS-CoV-2 spreading. Sci Adv. 2022;8(29):eabo0171. doi:10.1126/sciadv.abo0171</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lochhead JJ, Kellohen KL, Ronaldson PT, Davis TP. Distribution of insulin in trigeminal nerve and brain after intranasal administration. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):2621. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-39191-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M, Clijsters M, Choi S, et al. Anatomical barriers against SARS-CoV-2 neuroinvasion at vulnerable interfaces visualized in deceased COVID-19 patients. Neuron. 2022;110(23):3919-3935.e6. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2022.11.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Zhou L, Bao L, et al. SARS-CoV-2 crosses the blood-brain barrier accompanied with basement membrane disruption without tight junctions alteration. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6(1):337. doi:10.1038/s41392-021-00719-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Stadio A, Brenner MJ, De Luca P, et al. Olfactory dysfunction, headache, and mental clouding in adults with long-COVID-19: what is the link between cognition and olfaction? a cross-sectional study. Brain Sci. 2022;12(2):154. doi:10.3390/brainsci12020154</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samanta S, Rajasingh S, Drosos N, Zhou Z, Dawn B, Rajasingh J. Exosomes: new molecular targets of diseases. Acta Pharmacol Sin. 2018;39(4):501-513. doi:10.1038/aps.2017.162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borges FT, Reis LA, Schor N. Extracellular vesicles: structure, function, and potential clinical uses in renal diseases. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2013;46(10):824-830. doi:10.1590/1414-431X20132964</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf6;ssing C, Ryan KM. 50 years on and still very much alive: apoptosis: a basic biological phenomenon with wide-ranging implications in tissue kinetics. Br J Cancer. 2023;128(3):426-431. doi:10.1038/s41416-022-02020-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revenfeld ALS, Baek R, Nielsen MH, Stensballe A, Varming K, J&#xf8;rgensen M. Diagnostic and prognostic potential of extracellular vesicles in peripheral blood. Clin Ther. 2014;36(6):830-846. doi:10.1016/j.clinthera.2014.05.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowal J, Arras G, Colombo M, et al. Proteomic comparison defines novel markers to characterize heterogeneous populations of extracellular vesicle subtypes. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2016;113(8):E968-E977. doi:10.1073/pnas.1521230113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Y, El Andaloussi S, Wood MJA. Exosomes and microvesicles: extracellular vesicles for genetic information transfer and gene therapy. Hum Mol Gen. 2012;21(R1):R125-R134. doi:10.1093/hmg/dds317</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo A, Tandon M, Alevizos I, Illei GG. The majority of microRNAs detectable in serum and saliva is concentrated in exosomes. PLoS One. 2012;7(3):e30679. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0030679</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banigan MG, Kao PF, Kozubek JA, et al. Differential expression of exosomal microRNAs in prefrontal cortices of schizophrenia and bipolar disorder patients. PLoS One. 2013;8(1):e48814. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0048814</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xfc;hbeis C, Fr&#xf6;hlich D, Kuo WP, Kr&#xe4;mer-Albers EM. Extracellular vesicles as mediators of neuron-glia communication. Front Cell Neurosci. 2013;7:182. doi:10.3389/fncel.2013.00182</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocucci E, Meldolesi J. Ectosomes and exosomes: shedding the confusion between extracellular vesicles. Trends Cell Biol. 2015;25(6):364-372. doi:10.1016/j.tcb.2015.01.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vardjan N, Parpura V, Verkhratsky A, Zorec R. Gliocrine system: astroglia as secretory cells of the CNS. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2019;1175:93-115. doi:10.1007/978-981-13-9913-8_4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kr&#xe4;mer-Albers EM, Bretz N, Tenzer S, et al. Oligodendrocytes secrete exosomes containing major myelin and stress-protective proteins: trophic support for axons? Proteomics Clin Appl. 2007;1(11):1446-1461. doi:10.1002/prca.200700522</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobrie A, Colombo M, Raposo G, Th&#xe9;ry C. Exosome secretion: molecular mechanisms and roles in immune responses. Traffic. 2011;12(12):1659-1668. doi:10.1111/j.1600-0854.2011.01225.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolesnikova L, Bergh&#xf6;fer B, Bamberg S, Becker S. Multivesicular bodies as a platform for formation of the Marburg virus envelope. J Virol. 2004;78(22):12277-12287. doi:10.1128/JVI.78.22.12277-12287.2004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buschow SI, Nolte-'t Hoen ENM, van Niel G, Pols MS, et al. MHC II in dendritic cells is targeted to lysosomes or T cell-induced exosomes via distinct multivesicular body pathways. Traffic. 2009;10(10):1528-1542. doi:10.1111/j.1600-0854.2009.00963.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo M, Moita C, van Niel G, et al. Analysis of ESCRT functions in exosome biogenesis, composition and secretion highlights the heterogeneity of extracellular vesicles. J Cell Sci. 2013;126(Pt 24):5553-5565. doi:10.1242/jcs.128868</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baietti MF, Zhang Z, Mortier E, et al. Syndecan-syntenin-ALIX regulates the biogenesis of exosomes. Nat Cell Biol. 2012;14(7):677-685. doi:10.1038/ncb2502</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrowski M, Carmo NB, Krumeich S, et al. Rab27a and Rab27b control different steps of the exosome secretion pathway. Nat Cell Biol. 2010;12(1):19-30. doi:10.1038/ncb2000</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faur&#xe9; J, Lachenal G, Court M, et al. Exosomes are released by cultured cortical neurones. Mol Cell Neurosci. 2006;31(4):642-648. doi:10.1016/j.mcn.2005.12.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshansky V, Futai M. The V-type H+-ATPase in vesicular trafficking: targeting, regulation and function. Curr Opin Cell Biol. 2008;20(4):415-426. doi:10.1016/j.ceb.2008.03.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu Y, Dubyak GR. P2X7 receptors regulate multiple types of membrane trafficking responses and non-classical secretion pathways. Purinergic Signal. 2009;5(2):163-173. doi:10.1007/s11302-009-9132-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lespagnol A, Duflaut D, Beekman C, et al. Exosome secretion, including the DNA damage-induced p53-dependent secretory pathway, is severely compromised in TSAP6/Steap3-null mice. Cell Death Differ. 2008;15(11):1723-1733. doi:10.1038/cdd.2008.104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider A, Simons M. Exosomes: vesicular carriers for intercellular communication in neurodegenerative disorders. Cell Tissue Res. 2013;352(1):33-47. doi:10.1007/s00441-012-1428-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basso M, Pozzi S, Tortarolo M, et al. Mutant copper-zinc superoxide dismutase (SOD1) induces protein secretion pathway alterations and exosome release in astrocytes. J Biol Chem. 2013;288(22):15699-15711. doi:10.1074/jbc.M112.425066</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu G, Yao H, Chaudhuri AD, et al. Exosome-mediated shuttling of microRNA-29 regulates HIV Tat and morphine-mediated neuronal dysfunction. Cell Death Dis. 2012;3(8):e381. doi:10.1038/cddis.2012.114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron GS. Conversion of raft associated prion protein to the protease-resistant state requires insertion of PrP-res (PrP(Sc)) into contiguous membranes. EMBO J. 2002;21(5):1031-1040. doi:10.1093/emboj/21.5.1031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verderio C, Muzio L, Turola E, et al. Myeloid microvesicles are a marker and therapeutic target for neuroinflammation. Ann Neurol. 2012;72(4):610-624. doi:10.1002/ana.23627</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potolicchio I, Carven GJ, Xu X, et al. Proteomic analysis of microglia-derived exosomes: metabolic role of the aminopeptidase CD13 in neuropeptide catabolism. J Immunol. 2005;175(4):2237-2243. doi:10.4049/jimmunol.175.4.2237</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esser MT, Graham DR, Coren LV, et al. Differential incorporation of CD45, CD80 (B7-1), CD86 (B7-2), and major histocompatibility complex class I and II molecules into human immunodeficiency virus type 1 virions and microvesicles: implications for viral pathogenesis and immune regulation. J Virol. 2001;75(13):6173-6182. doi:10.1128/JVI.75.13.6173-6182.2001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellingham SA, Coleman BM, Hill AF. Small RNA deep sequencing reveals a distinct miRNA signature released in exosomes from prion-infected neuronal cells. Nucleic Acids Res. 2012;40(21):10937-10949. doi:10.1093/nar/gks832</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkle M, El-Daly SM, Fabbri M, Calin GA. Noncoding RNA therapeutics-challenges and potential solutions. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2021;20(8):629-651. doi:10.1038/s41573-021-00219-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolte-'t hoen ENM, Buermans HPJ, Waasdorp M, Stoorvogel W, Wauben MHM, t Hoen PAC. Deep sequencing of RNA from immune cell-derived vesicles uncovers the selective incorporation of small non-coding RNA biotypes with potential regulatory functions. Nucleic Acids Res. 2012;40(18):9272-9285. doi:10.1093/nar/gks658</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valadi H, Ekstr&#xf6;m K, Bossios A, Sj&#xf6;strand M, Lee JJ, L&#xf6;tvall JO. Exosome-mediated transfer of mRNAs and microRNAs is a novel mechanism of genetic exchange between cells. Nat Cell Biol. 2007;9(6):654-659. doi:10.1038/ncb1596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2022. Long COVID or post-COVID conditions. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html#:~:text=People%20with%20Post%2DCOVID%20Conditions%20(or%20Long%20COVID)%20may,away%20or%20come%20back%20again</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 2022. Post COVID-19 condition (Long COVID). https://www.who.int/europe/news-room/fact-sheets/item/post-covid-19-condition#:~:text=It%20is%20defined%20as%20the,months%20with%20no%20other%20explanation</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad SJ, Feigen CM, Vazquez JP, Kobets AJ, Altschul DJ. Neurological sequelae of COVID-19. J Integr Neurosci. 2022;21(3):77. doi:10.31083/j.jin2103077</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fotuhi M, Mian A, Meysami S, Raji CA. Neurobiology of COVID-19. J Alzheimer's Dis. 2020;76(1):3-19. doi:10.3233/JAD-200581</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M, et al. Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 in wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(6):683-690. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.1127</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deeks SG, Mustapic M, et al. SARS-CoV-2 and mitochondrial proteins in neural-derived exosomes of COVID-19. Ann Neurol. 2022;91(6):772-781. doi:10.1002/ana.26350</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Casta&#xf1;eda A, Lu P, Geraghty AC, et al. Mild respiratory COVID can cause multi-lineage neural cell and myelin dysregulation. Cell. 2022;185(14-2452-2468.e2416. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2022.06.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akuthota P, Carmo LAS, Bonjour K, et al. Extracellular microvesicle production by human eosinophils activated by &#x201c;inflammatory&#x201d; stimuli. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2016;4:117. doi:10.3389/fcell.2016.00117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song WJ, Hui CKM, Hull JH, et al. Confronting COVID-19-associated cough and the post-COVID syndrome: role of viral neurotropism, neuroinflammation, and neuroimmune responses. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9(5):533-544. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00125-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kai H, Kai M. Interactions of coronaviruses with ACE2, angiotensin II, and RAS inhibitors-lessons from available evidence and insights into COVID-19. Hypertension Res. 2020;43(7):648-654. doi:10.1038/s41440-020-0455-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuzawa Y, Kimura K, Ogawa H, Tamura K. Impact of renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system inhibitors on COVID-19. Hypertension Res. 2022;45(7):1147-1153. doi:10.1038/s41440-022-00922-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Q, Shults NV, Gychka SG, Harris BT, Suzuki YJ. Protein expression of angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) is upregulated in brains with Alzheimer's disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(4):1687. doi:10.3390/ijms22041687</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLegge MH, Smoke A. Neurodegeneration and inflammation. Nutr Clin Pract. 2008;23(1):35-41. doi:10.1177/011542650802300135</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow EJ, Schwartz NG, Tobolowsky FA, et al. Symptom screening at illness onset of health care personnel with SARS-CoV-2 infection in King County, Washington. JAMA. 2020;323(20):2087-2089. doi:10.1001/jama.2020.6637</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giacomelli A, Pezzati L, Conti F, et al. Self-reported olfactory and taste disorders in patients with severe acute respiratory coronavirus 2 infection: a cross-sectional study. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71(15):889-890. doi:10.1093/cid/ciaa330</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM, Khaleeq A, Ali U, Syeda H. Evidence of the COVID-19 virus targeting the CNS: tissue distribution, host-virus interaction, and proposed neurotropic mechanisms. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2020;11(7):995-998. doi:10.1021/acschemneuro.0c00122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galougahi MK, Ghorbani J, Bakhshayeshkaram M, Naeini AS, Haseli S. Olfactory bulb magnetic resonance imaging in SARS-CoV-2-induced anosmia: the first report. Academic Radiol. 2020;27(6):892-893. doi:10.1016/j.acra.2020.04.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA, Akbari A, Emami A, et al. Long COVID syndrome-associated brain fog. J Med Virol. 2022;94(3):979-984. doi:10.1002/jmv.27404</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings G, Monaghan A, Xue F, Duggan E, Romero-Ortu&#xf1;o R. Comprehensive clinical characterisation of brain fog in adults reporting long COVID symptoms. J Clin Med. 2022;11(12):3440. doi:10.3390/jcm11123440</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monje M, Iwasaki A. The neurobiology of long COVID. Neuron. 2022;110(21):3484-3496. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2022.10.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatliff J, Campanella M. TSPO is a REDOX regulator of cell mitophagy. Biochem Soc Trans. 2015;43(4):543-552. doi:10.1042/BST20150037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magr&#xec; A, Lipari CLR, Risiglione P, et al. ERK1/2-dependent TSPO overactivation associates with the loss of mitophagy and mitochondrial respiration in ALS. Cell Death Dis. 2023;14(2):122. doi:10.1038/s41419-023-05643-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung G, Lin YC, Papadopoulos V. Translocator protein in the rise and fall of central nervous system neurons. Front Cell Neurosci. 2023;17:1210205. doi:10.3389/fncel.2023.1210205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picciolini S, Mangolini V, Rod&#xe0; F, et al. Multiplexing biosensor for the detection of extracellular vesicles as biomarkers of tissue damage and recovery after ischemic stroke. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(9):7937. doi:10.3390/ijms24097937</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard C, Liu S, Adams D, et al. Axonal regeneration and neuroinflammation: roles for the translocator protein 18 kDa. J Neuroendocrinol. 2012;24(1):71-81. doi:10.1111/j.1365-2826.2011.02215.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Campion JY, Dudouet P, et al. 18F-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in patients with long COVID. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48(9):2823-2833. doi:10.1007/s00259-021-05215-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Lazarini F, Morbelli S, et al. Long COVID and the brain network of Proust's madeleine: targeting the olfactory pathway. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27(9):1196-1198. doi:10.1016/j.cmi.2021.05.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwland JM, Nutma E, Philippens IHCHM, et al. Longitudinal positron emission tomography and postmortem analysis reveals widespread neuroinflammation in SARS-CoV-2 infected rhesus macaques. J Neuroinflammation. 2023;20(1):179. doi:10.1186/s12974-023-02857-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braga J, Lepra M, Kish SJ, et al. Neuroinflammation after COVID-19 with persistent depressive and cognitive symptoms. JAMA Psychiatry. 2023;80(8):787-795. doi:10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2023.1321</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ketchesin KD, Zong W, Hildebrand MA, et al. Diurnal rhythms across the human dorsal and ventral striatum. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2021;118(2):e2016150118. doi:10.1073/pnas.2016150118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liljeholm M, O'Doherty JP. Contributions of the striatum to learning, motivation, and performance: an associative account. Trends Cogn Sci. 2012;16(9):467-475. doi:10.1016/j.tics.2012.07.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Q, Ba X, Wang Q, Cheng J, Nan J, He T. Functional differentiation of the dorsal striatum: a coordinate-based neuroimaging meta-analysis. Quant Imaging Med Surg. 2023;13(1):471-488. doi:10.21037/qims-22-133</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrepf A. When even the ground was burning: neuroinflammation in the wake of COVID-19. Brain Behav Immun. 2022;105:27-28. doi:10.1016/j.bbi.2022.06.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Mu S, Tian Y, et al. Porcine hemagglutinating encephalomyelitis virus Co-Opts multivesicular-derived exosomes for transmission. mBio. 2023;14(1):e0305422. doi:10.1128/mbio.03054-22</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra R, Banerjea AC. SARS-CoV-2 spike targets USP33-IRF9 axis via exosomal miR-148a to activate human microglia. Front Immunol. 2021;12:656700. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.656700</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro FL, Geddes VEV, Monteiro FLL, et al. MicroRNAs 145 and 148a are upregulated during congenital zika virus infection. ASN Neuro. 2019;11:175909141985098. doi:10.1177/1759091419850983</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amerik AY, Hochstrasser M. Mechanism and function of deubiquitinating enzymes. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2004;1695(1-3):189-207. doi:10.1016/j.bbamcr.2004.10.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofer MJ, Li W, Lim SL, Campbell IL. The type I interferon-&#x3b1; mediates a more severe neurological disease in the absence of the canonical signaling molecule interferon regulatory factor 9. J Neurosci. 2010;30(3):1149-1157. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3711-09.2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagheri-Hosseinabadi Z, Ostad Ebrahimi H, Bahrehmand F, Taghipour G, Abbasifard M. The relationship between serum levels of interleukin-2 and IL-8 with circulating microRNA-10b in patients with COVID-19. Iran J Immunol. 2021;18(1):65-73. doi:10.22034/iji.2021.88780.1904</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang P, Zhao Y, Li J, et al. Downregulated miR-451a as a feature of the plasma cfRNA landscape reveals regulatory networks of IL-6/IL-6R-associated cytokine storms in COVID-19 patients. Cell Mol Immunol. 2021;18(4):1064-1066. doi:10.1038/s41423-021-00652-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y, Fang D, Gao X, et al. Circulating microRNAs as emerging regulators of COVID-19. Theranostics. 2023;13(1):125-147. doi:10.7150/thno.78164</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Choi Y, Lim CW, et al. Potential therapeutic effect of micrornas in extracellular vesicles from mesenchymal stem cells against SARS-CoV-2. Cells. 2021;10(9):2393. doi:10.3390/cells10092393</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrenfeld M, Tincani A, Andreoli L, et al. Covid-19 and autoimmunity. Autoimmun Rev. 2020;19(8):102597. doi:10.1016/j.autrev.2020.102597</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aharon A, Dangot A, Kinaani F, et al. Extracellular vesicles of COVID-19 patients reflect inflammation, thrombogenicity, and disease severity. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(6):5918. doi:10.3390/ijms24065918</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Abramo A, Vita S, Maffongelli G, et al. Prolonged and severe SARS-CoV-2 infection in patients under B-cell-depleting drug successfully treated: a tailored approach. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;107:247-250. doi:10.1016/j.ijid.2021.04.068</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messner CB, Demichev V, Wendisch D, et al. Ultra-high-throughput clinical proteomics reveals classifiers of COVID-19 infection. Cell Systems. 2020;11(1):11-24.e4. doi:10.1016/j.cels.2020.05.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesce E, Manfrini N, Cordiglieri C, et al. Exosomes recovered from the plasma of COVID-19 patients expose SARS-CoV-2 spike-derived fragments and contribute to the adaptive immune response. Front Immunol. 2022;12:785941. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.785941</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun B, Tang N, Peluso MJ, et al. Characterization and biomarker analyses of post-COVID-19 complications and neurological manifestations. Cells. 2021;10(2):386. doi:10.3390/cells10020386</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz IC, Bertoni APS, Wink MR. MSC-Exosomes carrying miRNA - could they enhance tocilizumab activity in neuropathology of COVID-19? Stem Cell Rev Rep. 2023;19(1):279-283. doi:10.1007/s12015-022-10409-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deitchman AN, Torres L, et al. Long-term SARS-CoV-2-specific immune and inflammatory responses in individuals recovering from COVID-19 with and without post-acute symptoms. Cell Rep. 2021;36(6):109518. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2021.109518</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim ST, Janaway B, Costello H, Trip A, Price G. Persistent psychotic symptoms following COVID-19 infection. BJPsych Open. 2020;6(5):e105. doi:10.1192/bjo.2020.76</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark IA. Chronic cerebral aspects of long COVID, post-stroke syndromes and similar states share their pathogenesis and perispinal etanercept treatment logic. Pharmacol Res Perspect. 2022;10(2):e00926. doi:10.1002/prp2.926</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalcante-Silva LHA, Carvalho DCM, Lima &#xc9;A, et al. Neutrophils and COVID-19: the road so far. Int Immunopharmacol. 2021;90:107233. doi:10.1016/j.intimp.2020.107233</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veleri S. Neurotropism of SARS-CoV-2 and neurological diseases of the central nervous system in COVID-19 patients. Exp Brain Res. 2022;240(1):9-25. doi:10.1007/s00221-021-06244-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi A, Domingues R, Setz C, Outeiro TF, Krisko A. SARS-CoV-2: at the crossroad between aging and neurodegeneration. Mov Disorders. 2020;35(5):716-720. doi:10.1002/mds.28084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J, Kremer S, Merdji H, et al. Neurologic features in severe SARS-CoV-2 infection. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(23):2268-2270. doi:10.1056/NEJMc2008597</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves VS, Santos SACS, Leite-Aguiar R, et al. SARS-CoV-2 spike protein alters microglial purinergic signaling. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1158460. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2023.1158460</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savio LEB, Leite-Aguiar R, Alves VS, Coutinho-Silva R, Wyse ATS. Purinergic signaling in the modulation of redox biology. Redox Biol. 2021;47:102137. doi:10.1016/j.redox.2021.102137</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clough E, Inigo J, Chandra D, et al. Mitochondrial dynamics in SARS-COV2 spike protein treated human microglia: implications for Neuro-COVID. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2021;16(4):770-784. doi:10.1007/s11481-021-10015-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues TS, de S&#xe1; KSG, Ishimoto AY, et al. Inflammasomes are activated in response to SARS-CoV-2 infection and are associated with COVID-19 severity in patients. J Exp Med. 2021;218(3):e20201707. doi:10.1084/jem.20201707</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, He L, Zhang Q, et al. Organ distribution of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) associated coronavirus (SARS-CoV) in SARS patients: implications for pathogenesis and virus transmission pathways. J Pathol. 2004;203(2):622-630. doi:10.1002/path.1560</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stamatovic SM, Shakui P, Keep RF, et al. Monocyte chemoattractant protein-1 regulation of blood-brain barrier permeability. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2005;25(5):593-606. doi:10.1038/sj.jcbfm.9600055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winston CN, Romero HK, Ellisman M, et al. Assessing neuronal and astrocyte derived exosomes from individuals with mild traumatic brain injury for markers of neurodegeneration and cytotoxic activity. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:1005. doi:10.3389/fnins.2019.01005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YS, Lee WJ, Wang SJ, Fuh JL. Levels of plasma neurofilament light chain and cognitive function in patients with Alzheimer or Parkinson disease. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):17368. doi:10.1038/s41598-018-35766-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang AP, Liu J, Tao W, Li H. The diagnostic and predictive role of NLR, d-NLR and PLR in COVID-19 patients. Int Immunopharmacol. 2020;84:106504. doi:10.1016/j.intimp.2020.106504</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usul E, &#x15e;an I, Bekg&#xf6;z B, &#x15e;ahin A. Role of hematological parameters in COVID-19 patients in the emergency room. Biomark Med. 2020;14(13):1207-1215. doi:10.2217/bmm-2020-0317</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas A, Roux-Dalvai F, Droit A, Lavoie JP. Neutrophil-derived exosomes: a new mechanism contributing to airway smooth muscle remodeling. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol. 2016;55(3):450-461. doi:10.1165/rcmb.2016-0033OC</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambardella J, Coppola A, Izzo R, Fiorentino G, Trimarco B, Santulli G. Role of endothelial miR-24 in COVID-19 cerebrovascular events. Crit Care. 2021;25(1):306. doi:10.1186/s13054-021-03731-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willison HJ, Jacobs BC, van Doorn PA. Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome. Lancet. 2016;388(10045):717-727. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(16)00339-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padroni M, Mastrangelo V, Asioli GM, et al. Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome following COVID-19: new infection, old complication? J Neurol. 2020;267(7):1877-1879. doi:10.1007/s00415-020-09849-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savelieff MG, Feldman EL, Stino AM. Neurological sequela and disruption of neuron-glia homeostasis in SARS-CoV-2 infection. Neurobiol Dis. 2022;168:105715. doi:10.1016/j.nbd.2022.105715</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Restrepo-Vera JL, Llaurad&#xf3; A, Palas&#xed; A, et al. Immunological, clinical, and epidemiological features of Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Acta Neurol Scand. 2023;2023:1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapogiannis D, Mustapic M, Shardell MD, et al. Association of extracellular vesicle biomarkers with alzheimer disease in the Baltimore longitudinal study of aging. JAMA Neurol. 2019;76(11):1340-1351. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2019.2462</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winston CN, Goetzl EJ, Akers JC, et al. Prediction of conversion from mild cognitive impairment to dementia with neuronally derived blood exosome protein profile. Alzheimers Dement (Amst). 2016;3:63-72. doi:10.1016/j.dadm.2016.04.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi M, Kovac A, Korff A, et al. CNS tau efflux via exosomes is likely increased in Parkinson's disease but not in Alzheimer's disease. Alzheimer's Dement. 2016;12(11):1125-1131. doi:10.1016/j.jalz.2016.04.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen RX, Shen H, Huang SX, et al. P2Y6 receptor inhibition aggravates ischemic brain injury by reducing microglial phagocytosis. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2020;26(4):416-429. doi:10.1111/cns.13296</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lankford KL, Arroyo EJ, Nazimek K, Bryniarski K, Askenase PW, Kocsis JD. Intravenously delivered mesenchymal stem cell-derived exosomes target M2-type macrophages in the injured spinal cord. PLoS One. 2018;13(1):e0190358. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0190358</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao M, Jin M, Xu S, et al. Exosomes from long noncoding RNA-Gm37494-ADSCs repair spinal cord injury via shifting microglial M1/M2 polarization. Inflammation. 2020;43(4):1536-1547. doi:10.1007/s10753-020-01230-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granholm AC. Long-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 in the brain: clinical consequences and molecular mechanisms. J Clin Med. 2023;12(9):3190. doi:10.3390/jcm12093190</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derkow K, R&#xf6;ssling R, Schipke C, et al. Distinct expression of the neurotoxic microRNA family let-7 in the cerebrospinal fluid of patients with Alzheimer's disease. PLoS One. 2018;13(7):e0200602. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0200602</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasca S, Jurj A, Petrushev B, Tomuleasa C, Matei D. MicroRNA-155 implication in M1 polarization and the impact in inflammatory diseases. Front Immunol. 2020;11:625. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2020.00625</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeKosky ST, Kochanek PM, Valadka AB, et al. Blood biomarkers for detection of brain injury in COVID-19 patients. J Neurotrauma. 2021;38(1):1-43. doi:10.1089/neu.2020.7332</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera JA, Boutajangout A, Masurkar AV, et al. Comparison of serum neurodegenerative biomarkers among hospitalized COVID-19 patients versus non-COVID subjects with normal cognition, mild cognitive impairment, or Alzheimer's dementia. Alzheimer's Dement. 2022;18(5):899-910. doi:10.1002/alz.12556</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Sans HM, Forman CA, et al. Plasma markers of neurologic injury and inflammation in people with self-reported neurologic postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2022;9(5):e200003. doi:10.1212/NXI.0000000000200003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai YJ, Liu SH, Manachevakul S, Lee TA, Kuo CT, Bello D. Biomarkers in long COVID-19: a systematic review. Front Med. 2023;10:1085988. doi:10.3389/fmed.2023.1085988</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antar AAR, Yu T, Demko ZO, et al. Long COVID brain fog and muscle pain are associated with longer time to clearance of SARS-CoV-2 RNA from the upper respiratory tract during acute infection. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1147549. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2023.1147549</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hakeim HK, Al-Rubaye HT, Almulla AF, Al-Hadrawi DS, Maes M. Chronic fatigue, depression and anxiety symptoms in long COVID are strongly predicted by neuroimmune and neuro-oxidative pathways which are caused by the inflammation during acute infection. J Clin Med. 2023;12(2):511. doi:10.3390/jcm12020511</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costela-Ruiz VJ, Illescas-Montes R, Puerta-Puerta JM, Ruiz C, Melguizo-Rodr&#xed;guez L. SARS-CoV-2 infection: the role of cytokines in COVID-19 disease. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2020;54:62-75. doi:10.1016/j.cytogfr.2020.06.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrara F, Zovi A, Masi M, et al. Long COVID could become a widespread post-pandemic disease? A debate on the organs most affected. Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol. 2023;396(7):1583-1589. doi:10.1007/s00210-023-02417-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MAAK, Sany MRU, Islam MS, Islam ABMMK. Epigenetic regulator miRNA pattern differences among SARS-CoV, SARS-CoV-2, and SARS-CoV-2 world-wide isolates delineated the mystery behind the epic pathogenicity and distinct clinical characteristics of pandemic COVID-19. Front Genet. 2020;11:765. doi:10.3389/fgene.2020.00765</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Q, Wang Q, Zhao B, et al. Identification of a SARS-CoV-2 virus-encoded small non-coding RNA in association with the neurological disorders in COVID-19 patients. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2022;7(1):107. doi:10.1038/s41392-022-00969-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butowt R, von Bartheld CS. Anosmia in COVID-19: underlying mechanisms and assessment of an olfactory route to brain infection. Neuroscientist. 2021;27(6):582-603. doi:10.1177/1073858420956905</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghipour S, Mathias RA. Herpesviruses hijack host exosomes for viral pathogenesis. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2017;67:91-100. doi:10.1016/j.semcdb.2017.03.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J, Radke J, Dittmayer C, et al. Olfactory transmucosal SARS-CoV-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with COVID-19. Nat Neurosci. 2021;24(2):168-175. doi:10.1038/s41593-020-00758-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askari H, Rabiei F, Lohrasbi F, Ghadir S, Ghasemi-Kasman M. The latest cellular and molecular mechanisms of COVID-19 on non-lung organs. Brain Sci. 2023;13(3):415. doi:10.3390/brainsci13030415</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finsterer J, Stollberger C. Causes of hypogeusia/hyposmia in SARS-CoV2 infected patients. J Med Virol. 2020;92(10):1793-1794. doi:10.1002/jmv.25903</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Li M, Wang M, et al. Acute cerebrovascular disease following COVID-19: a single center, retrospective, observational study. Stroke Vasc Neurol. 2020;5(3):279-284. doi:10.1136/svn-2020-000431</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>