<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37163427</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2152-5250</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Aging and disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Aging Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Complications of COVID-19 on the Central Nervous System: Mechanisms and Potential Treatment for Easing Long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1492</StartPage><EndPage>1510</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1492-1510</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14336/AD.2023.0312</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) invades human cells by binding to the angiotensin-converting-enzyme-2 (ACE-2) using a spike protein and leads to Coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19). COVID-19 primarily causes a respiratory infection that can lead to severe systemic inflammation. It is also common for some patients to develop significant neurological and psychiatric symptoms. The spread of SARS-CoV-2 to the CNS likely occurs through several pathways. Once spread in the CNS, many acute symptoms emerge, and such infections could also transpire into severe neurological complications, including encephalitis or ischemic stroke. After recovery from the acute infection, a significant percentage of patients develop "long COVID," a condition in which several symptoms of COVID-19 persist for prolonged periods. This review aims to discuss acute and chronic neurological problems after SARS-CoV-2 infection. The potential mechanisms by which SARS-CoV-2 enters the CNS and causes neuroinflammation, neuropathological changes observed in post-mortem brains of COVID-19 patients, and cognitive and mood problems in COVID-19 survivors are discussed in the initial part. The later part of the review deliberates the causes of long COVID, approaches for noninvasive tracking of neuroinflammation in long COVID patients, and the potential therapeutic strategies that could ease enduring CNS symptoms observed in long COVID.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Zhuang-Yao D</ForeName><Initials>ZD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Regenerative Medicine, Department of Cell Biology and Genetics, Texas A&amp;M University Health Science Center School of Medicine, College Station, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Ketty</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sam Houston State University College of Osteopathic Medicine, Conroe, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shetty</LastName><ForeName>Ashok K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Regenerative Medicine, Department of Cell Biology and Genetics, Texas A&amp;M University Health Science Center School of Medicine, College Station, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS106907</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Aging Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101540533</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2152-5250</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>
<b>Competing Interests</b>
. The authors declare that there are no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37163427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10529748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14336/AD.2023.0312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">AD.2023.0312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhu N, Zhang D, Wang W, Li X, Yang B, Song J, et al.. (2020). A Novel Coronavirus from Patients with Pneumonia in China, 2019. N Engl J Med, 382:727-733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31978945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holshue ML, DeBolt C, Lindquist S, Lofy KH, Wiesman J, Bruce H, et al.. (2020). First Case of 2019 Novel Coronavirus in the United States. N Engl J Med, 382:929-936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32004427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y, Yang H, Ji W, Wu W, Chen S, Zhang W, et al.. (2020). Virology, Epidemiology, Pathogenesis, and Control of COVID-19. Viruses, 12:372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7232198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32230900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doremalen Nv, Bushmaker T, Morris DH, Holbrook MG, Gamble A, Williamson BN, et al.. (2020). Aerosol and Surface Stability of SARS-CoV-2 as Compared with SARS-CoV-1. N Engl J Med, 382:1564-1567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7121658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32182409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, Wang H, Shen H, Li Z, Geng J, Han H, et al.. (2003). The clinical pathology of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS): a report from China. J Pathol, 200:282-289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7168017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12845623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajlan AM, Ahyad RA, Jamjoom LG, Alharthy A, Madani TA (2014). Middle East Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus (MERS-CoV) Infection: Chest CT Findings. AJR Am J Roentgenol, 203:782-787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24918624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Li M, Wang M, Zhou Y, Chang J, Xian Y, et al.. (2020). Acute cerebrovascular disease following COVID-19: a single center, retrospective, observational study. Stroke Vasc Neurol, 5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7371480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32616524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothan HA, Byrareddy SN (2020). The epidemiology and pathogenesis of coronavirus disease (COVID-19) outbreak. J Autoimmun, 109:102433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7127067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32113704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Yu Y, Xu J, Shu H, Xia Ja, Liu H, et al.. (2020). Clinical course and outcomes of critically ill patients with SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a single-centered, retrospective, observational study. Lancet Respir Med, 8:475-481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32105632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H-Y, Li X-L, Yan Z-R, Sun X-P, Han J, Zhang B-W (2020). Potential neurological symptoms of COVID-19. Ther Adv Neurol Disord, 13:1756286420917830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7119227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32284735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Moore MJ, Vasilieva N, Sui J, Wong SK, Berne MA, et al.. (2003). Angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 is a functional receptor for the SARS coronavirus. Nature, 426:450-454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14647384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuki K, Fujiogi M, Koutsogiannaki S (2020). COVID-19 pathophysiology: A review. Clin Immunol, 215:108427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7169933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Fu B, Zheng X, Wang D, Zhao C, Qi Y, et al.. (2020). Pathogenic T-cells and inflammatory monocytes incite inflammatory storms in severe COVID-19 patients. Natl Sci Rev, 7:998-1002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7108005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34676125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Wang Z, Cao W, Wu Q, Yuan Y, Zhang X (2021). Regulatory T cells in COVID-19. Aging Dis, 12:1545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8460308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34631206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Hu B, Hu C, Zhu F, Liu X, Zhang J, et al.. (2020). Clinical Characteristics of 138 Hospitalized Patients With 2019 Novel Coronavirus-Infected Pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA, 323:1061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen A-t, Wang C-y, Zhu W-l, Chen W (2022). Coagulation Disorders and Thrombosis in COVID-19 Patients and a Possible Mechanism Involving Endothelial Cells: A Review. Aging Dis, 13:144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8782553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35111367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Xiong W, Liu D, Liu J, Yang D, Li N, et al.. (2020). New onset acute symptomatic seizure and risk factors in coronavirus disease 2019: A retrospective multicenter study. Epilepsia, 61:e49-e53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32304092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA, Simani L, Shahisavandi M, Barzegar Z (2021). COVID-19, de novo seizures, and epilepsy: a systematic review. Neurol Sci, 42:415-431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7686454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33237493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings MJ, Baldwin MR, Abrams D, Jacobson SD, Meyer BJ, Balough EM, et al.. (2020). Epidemiology, clinical course, and outcomes of critically ill adults with COVID-19 in New York City: a prospective cohort study. Lancet, 395:1763-1770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7237188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scullen T, Keen J, Mathkour M, Dumont AS, Kahn L (2020). Coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19)-Associated Encephalopathies and Cerebrovascular Disease: The New Orleans Experience. World Neurosurg, 141:e437-e446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32474092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danzi GB, Loffi M, Galeazzi G, Gherbesi E (2020). Acute pulmonary embolism and COVID-19 pneumonia: a random association? Eur Heart J, 41:1858-1858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32227120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F, ftGAC-P-ACS Group (2020). Persistent Symptoms in Patients After Acute COVID-19. JAMA, 324:603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro E, Priori A, Beghi E, Helbok R, Campiglio L, Bassetti CL, et al.. (2020). The international European Academy of Neurology survey on neurological symptoms in patients with COVID-19 infection. Eur J Neurol, 27:1727-1737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32558002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao F, Han Z, Wang R, Luo Y (2021). Neurological Manifestations of COVID-19: Causality or Coincidence? Aging Dis, 12:27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7801278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33532124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filatov A, Sharma P, Hindi F, Espinosa PS Neurological Complications of Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19): Encephalopathy. Cureus, 12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7170017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32328364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desforges M, Le Coupanec A, Stodola JK, Meessen-Pinard M, Talbot PJ (2014). Human coronaviruses: Viral and cellular factors involved in neuroinvasiveness and neuropathogenesis. Virus Res, 194:145-158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7114389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25281913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durrant DM, Ghosh S, Klein RS (2016). The Olfactory Bulb: An Immunosensory Effector Organ during Neurotropic Viral Infections. ACS Chem Neurosci, 7:464-469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5775964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27058872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xydakis MS, Albers MW, Holbrook EH, Lyon DM, Shih RY, Frasnelli JA, et al.. (2021). Post-viral effects of COVID-19 in the olfactory system and their implications. Lancet Neurol, 20:753-761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8324113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckman D, Bonillas A, Diniz GB, Ott S, Roh JW, Elizaldi SR, et al.. (2022). SARS-CoV-2 infects neurons and induces neuroinflammation in a non-human primate model of COVID-19. Cell Rep, 41:111573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9554328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36288725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seehusen F, Clark JJ, Sharma P, Bentley EG, Kirby A, Subramaniam K, et al.. (2022). Neuroinvasion and neurotropism by SARS-CoV-2 variants in the K18-hACE2 mouse. Viruses, 14:1020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9146514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35632761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butowt R, Meunier N, Bryche B, von Bartheld CS (2021). The olfactory nerve is not a likely route to brain infection in COVID-19: a critical review of data from humans and animal models. Acta Neuropathol, 141:809-822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8075028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33903954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston M, Zakharov A, Papaiconomou C, Salmasi G, Armstrong D (2004). Evidence of connections between cerebrospinal fluid and nasal lymphatic vessels in humans, non-human primates and other mammalian species. Cerebrospinal Fluid Res, 1:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC546409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15679948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zakharov A, Papaiconomou C, Koh L, Djenic J, Bozanovic-Sosic R, Johnston M (2004). Integrating the roles of extracranial lymphatics and intracranial veins in cerebrospinal fluid absorption in sheep. Microvasc Res, 67:96-104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14709407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty AK, Zanirati G (2020). The Interstitial System of the Brain in Health and Disease. Aging Dis, 11:200-211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6961771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32010493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achar A, Ghosh C (2020). COVID-19-Associated Neurological Disorders: The Potential Route of CNS Invasion and Blood-Brain Barrier Relevance. Cells, 9:2360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7692725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33120941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng M (2022). ACE2 and COVID-19 Susceptibility and Severity. Aging Dis, 13:360-372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8947832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35371596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Melo IS, Sabino-Silva R, Cunha TM, Goulart LR, Reis WL, Jardim ACG, et al.. (2021). Hydroelectrolytic Disorder in COVID-19 patients: Evidence Supporting the Involvement of Subfornical Organ and Paraventricular Nucleus of the Hypothalamus. Neurosci Biobehav Rev, 124:216-223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7872848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong WE (2015). Chapter 14 - Hypothalamic Supraoptic and Paraventricular Nuclei. In: The Rat Nervous System (Fourth Edition). Paxinos G, editor. San Diego: Academic Press. 295-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragab D, Salah Eldin H, Taeimah M, Khattab R, Salem R (2020). The COVID-19 Cytokine Storm; What We Know So Far. Front Immunol, 11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7308649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32612617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y, et al.. (2020). Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet, 395:497-506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avula A, Nalleballe K, Narula N, Sapozhnikov S, Dandu V, Toom S, et al.. (2020). COVID-19 presenting as stroke. Brain Behav Immun, 87:115-119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32360439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao W, Zhang C, Wang H, Wu Q, Yuan Y, Chen J, et al.. (2021). Ischemic Stroke: An Underestimated Complication of COVID-19. Aging Dis, 12:691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8139195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34094634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E, Bartley CM, Chow RD, Ngo TT, Jiang R, Zamecnik CR, et al.. (2021). Divergent and self-reactive immune responses in the CNS of COVID-19 patients with neurological symptoms. Cell Rep Med, 2:100288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8091032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33969321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank MG, Nguyen KH, Ball JB, Hopkins S, Kelley T, Baratta MV, et al.. (2022). SARS-CoV-2 spike S1 subunit induces neuroinflammatory, microglial and behavioral sickness responses: Evidence of PAMP-like properties. Brain Behav Immun, 100:267-277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8667429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34915155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanley B, Naresh KN, Roufosse C, Nicholson AG, Weir J, Cooke GS, et al.. (2020). Histopathological findings and viral tropism in UK patients with severe fatal COVID-19: a post-mortem study. Lancet Microbe, 1:e245-e253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7440861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32844161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabbri VP, Foschini MP, Lazzarotto T, Gabrielli L, Cenacchi G, Gallo C, et al.. (2021). Brain ischemic injury in COVID-19-infected patients: a series of 10 post-mortem cases. Brain Pathol, 31:205-210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33002281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichard RR, Kashani KB, Boire NA, Constantopoulos E, Guo Y, Lucchinetti CF (2020). Neuropathology of COVID-19: a spectrum of vascular and acute disseminated encephalomyelitis (ADEM)-like pathology. Acta Neuropathol, 140:1-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32449057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rentero D, Juanes A, Losada CP, &#xc1;lvarez S, Parra A, Santana V, et al.. (2020). New-onset psychosis in COVID-19 pandemic: a case series in Madrid. Psychiatry Res, 290:113097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7217785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32480119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer M, Coogan AN, Faltraco F, Thome J (2020). COVID-19 paranoia in a patient suffering from schizophrenic psychosis - a case report. Psychiatry Res, 288:113001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7162758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32315884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcloughlin BC, Miles A, Webb TE, Knopp P, Eyres C, Fabbri A, et al.. (2020). Functional and cognitive outcomes after COVID-19 delirium. Eur Geriatr Med, 11:857-862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7358317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32666303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemanno F, Houdayer E, Parma A, Spina A, Forno AD, Scatolini A, et al.. (2021). COVID-19 cognitive deficits after respiratory assistance in the subacute phase: A COVID-rehabilitation unit experience. PLoS One, 16:e0246590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7870071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33556127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H, Lu S, Chen J, Wei N, Wang D, Lyu H, et al.. (2020). The landscape of cognitive function in recovered COVID-19 patients. J Psychiatr Res, 129:98-102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7324344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32912598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahase E (2020). Covid-19: What do we know about &#x201c;long covid&#x201d;? Br Med J, 370:m2815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32665317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naeije R, Caravita S (2021). Phenotyping long COVID. Eur Respir J, 58:2101763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8287735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34244323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P, Torocastro M, Panagopoulos D, Sutton R, et al.. (2021). Autonomic dysfunction in &#x2018;long COVID&#x2019;: rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin Med, 21:e63-e67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Q, Xu M, Li J, Liu Y, Zhang J, Xu Y, et al.. (2021). Clinical sequelae of COVID-19 survivors in Wuhan, China: a single-centre longitudinal study. Clin Microbiol Infect, 27:89-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7510771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32979574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo P, Benito Ballesteros A, Yeung SP, Liu R, Saha A, Curtis L, et al.. (2022). COVCOG 1: Factors Predicting Physical, Neurological and Cognitive Symptoms in Long COVID in a Community Sample. A First Publication From the COVID and Cognition Study. Front Aging Neurosci, 14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8968323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35370617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ, Liu S (2022). Proposed subtypes of post-COVID-19 syndrome (or long-COVID) and their respective potential therapies. Rev Med Virol, 32:e2315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34888989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Pittet LF, Curtis N (2022). The Challenge of Studying Long COVID: An Updated Review. Pediatr Infect Dis J, 41:424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8997013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35213866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan P (2021). NICE guideline on long COVID. Lancet Respir Med, 9:129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Schneider C, Laurent E, Lemaignen A, Beaufils E, Bourbao-Tournois C, Laribi S, et al.. (2021). Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Clin Microbiol Infect, 27:258-263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH, Crooks MG (2021). Post-COVID-19 Symptom Burden: What is Long-COVID and How Should We Manage It? Lung, 199:113-119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, Myles P, Williams T, Gokhale KM, et al.. (2022). Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat Med, 28:1706-1714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Munblit D, Rose CD, Sinatti D, Ricchiuto A, Carfi A, et al.. (2021). Preliminary Evidence on Long COVID in children. Acta Paediatr, 110:2208-2211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33835507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consiglio CR, Cotugno N, Sardh F, Pou C, Amodio D, Rodriguez L, et al.. (2020). The Immunology of Multisystem Inflammatory Syndrome in Children with COVID-19. Cell, 183:968-981.e967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7474869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32966765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertting O (2021). More research is needed on the long-term effects of COVID-19 on children and adolescents. Acta Paediatr, 110:744-745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7986825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33395729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Kapur S, Alberts J, Badley AD, Decker GA, et al.. (2020). Multi-organ impairment in low-risk individuals with long COVID. medRxiv.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doykov I, H&#xe4;llqvist J, Gilmour KC, Grandjean L, Mills K, Heywood WE (2021). &#x2018;The long tail of Covid-19&#x2019; - The detection of a prolonged inflammatory response after a SARS-CoV-2 infection in asymptomatic and mildly affected patients. F1000Research, 9:1349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7745182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33391730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toscano G, Palmerini F, Ravaglia S, Ruiz L, Invernizzi P, Cuzzoni MG, et al.. (2020). Guillain-Barr&#xe9; Syndrome Associated with SARS-CoV-2. N Engl J Med, 382:2574-2576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7182017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32302082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Restivo DA, Centonze D, Alesina A, Marchese-Ragona R (2020). Myasthenia Gravis Associated With SARS-CoV-2 Infection. Ann Intern Med, 173:1027-1028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32776781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miglis MG, Prieto T, Shaik R, Muppidi S, Sinn D-I, Jaradeh S (2020). A case report of postural tachycardia syndrome after COVID-19. Clin Auton Res, 30:449-451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7471493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32880754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukandala G, Tynan R, Lanigan S, O&#x2019;Connor JJ (2016). The Effects of Hypoxia and Inflammation on Synaptic Signaling in the CNS. Brain Sci, 6:6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4810176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26901230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spalletta G, Boss&#xf9; P, Ciaramella A, Bria P, Caltagirone C, Robinson RG (2006). The etiology of poststroke depression: a review of the literature and a new hypothesis involving inflammatory cytokines. Mol Psychiatry, 11:984-991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16894392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bluth&#xe9; RM, Pawlowski M, Suarez S, Parnet P, Pittman Q, Kelley KW, et al.. (1994). Synergy between tumor necrosis factor &#x3b1; and interleukin-1 in the induction of sickness behavior in mice. Psychoneuroendocrinology, 19:197-207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8190839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spudich S, Nath A (2022). Nervous system consequences of COVID-19. Science, 375:267-269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35050660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ (2021). Persistent Brainstem Dysfunction in Long-COVID: A Hypothesis. ACS Chem Neurosci, 12:573-580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Morbelli S, Kaphan E, Campion J-Y, Dudouet P, Ceccaldi M, et al.. (2021). From early limbic inflammation to long COVID sequelae. Brain, 144:e65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34142116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochachka PW, Clark CM, Brown WD, Stanley C, Stone CK, Nickles RJ, et al.. (1994). The Brain at High Altitude: Hypometabolism as a Defense against Chronic Hypoxia? J Cereb Blood Flow Metab, 14:671-679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8014215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hugon J, Msika E-F, Queneau M, Farid K, Paquet C (2022). Long COVID: cognitive complaints (brain fog) and dysfunction of the cingulate cortex. J Neurol, 269:44-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8211714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34143277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman R, Abuzinadah AR, Gibbons C, Jones P, Miglis MG, Sinn DI (2018). Orthostatic Hypotension. J Am Coll Cardiol, 72:1294-1309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30190008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein DS (2020). The extended autonomic system, dyshomeostasis, and COVID-19. Clin Auton Res, 30:299-315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7374073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32700055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu LD, Duricka DL (2022). Stellate ganglion block reduces symptoms of Long COVID: A case series. J Neuroimmunol, 362:577784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8653406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34922127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessen NA, Munk ASF, Lundgaard I, Nedergaard M (2015). The Glymphatic System: A Beginner&#x2019;s Guide. Neurochem Res, 40:2583-2599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4636982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25947369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iliff JJ, Wang M, Liao Y, Plogg BA, Peng W, Gundersen GA, et al.. (2012). A Paravascular Pathway Facilitates CSF Flow Through the Brain Parenchyma and the Clearance of Interstitial Solutes, Including Amyloid &#x3b2;. Sci Transl Med, 4:147ra111-147ra111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3551275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22896675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wostyn P (2021). COVID-19 and chronic fatigue syndrome: Is the worst yet to come? Med Hypotheses, 146:110469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33401106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norwood JN, Zhang Q, Card D, Craine A, Ryan TM, Drew PJ (2019). Anatomical basis and physiological role of cerebrospinal fluid transport through the murine cribriform plate. eLife, 8:e44278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6524970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31063132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afari N, Buchwald D (2003). Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: A Review. Am J Psychiatry, 160:221-236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12562565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins N, Pickard J, Lever A (2013). Lumbar puncture, chronic fatigue syndrome and idiopathic intracranial hypertension: a cross-sectional study. JRSM Short Rep, 4:2042533313507920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3899735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24475346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson P, Kedra A, Shotar E, Bonnin S, Boch A-L, Shor N, et al.. (2021). Idiopathic Intracranial Hypertension: Glymphedema of the Brain. J Neuroophthalmol, 41:93-97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33034442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyajima N, Ito M, Rokugawa T, Iimori H, Momosaki S, Omachi S, et al.. (2018). Detection of neuroinflammation before selective neuronal loss appearance after mild focal ischemia using [18F]DPA-714 imaging. EJNMMI Res, 8:43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5993708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29884977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshelh Z, Albrecht DS, Bergan C, Akeju O, Clauw DJ, Conboy L, et al.. (2020). In-vivo imaging of neuroinflammation in veterans with Gulf War illness. Brain Behav Immun, 87:498-507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7864588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32027960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm MM, Kaiser J, Schwab ME (2018). Extracellular Vesicles: Multimodal Envoys in Neural Maintenance and Repair. Trends Neurosci, 41:360-372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29605090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulliam L, Gupta A (2015). Modulation of Cellular Function Through Immune-Activated Exosomes. DNA Cell Biol, 34:459-463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4504252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25945690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanninen KM, Bister N, Koistinaho J, Malm T (2016). Exosomes as new diagnostic tools in CNS diseases. Biochim Biophys Acta - Mol Basis Dis, 1862:403-410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26432482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malloci M, Perdomo L, Veerasamy M, Andriantsitohaina R, Simard G, Mart&#xed;nez MC (2019). Extracellular Vesicles: Mechanisms in Human Health and Disease. Antioxid Redox Signal, 30:813-856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29634347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty AK, Upadhya R (2021). Extracellular Vesicles in Health and Disease. Aging Dis, 12:1358-1362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8407881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34527414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saman S, Kim W, Raya M, Visnick Y, Miro S, Saman S, et al.. (2012). Exosome-associated Tau Is Secreted in Tauopathy Models and Is Selectively Phosphorylated in Cerebrospinal Fluid in Early Alzheimer Disease *. J Biol Chem, 287:3842-3849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3281682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22057275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan Z, Pathak D, Venkatesan Kalavai S, Yoshii-Kitahara A, Muraoka S, Bhatt N, et al.. (2021). Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease brain-derived extracellular vesicles spread tau pathology in interneurons. Brain, 144:288-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7880668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33246331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez M, Avila J, Hern&#xe1;ndez F (2019). Propagation of Tau via Extracellular Vesicles. Front Neurosci, 13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6614378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31312118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetzl EJ, Boxer A, Schwartz JB, Abner EL, Petersen RC, Miller BL, et al.. (2015). Altered lysosomal proteins in neural-derived plasma exosomes in preclinical Alzheimer disease. Neurology, 85:40-47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4501943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26062630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustapic M, Eitan E, Werner JK, Berkowitz ST, Lazaropoulos MP, Tran J, et al.. (2017). Plasma Extracellular Vesicles Enriched for Neuronal Origin: A Potential Window into Brain Pathologic Processes. Front Neurosci, 11:278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5439289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28588440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi M, Liu C, Cook TJ, Bullock KM, Zhao Y, Ginghina C, et al.. (2014). Plasma exosomal &#x3b1;-synuclein is likely CNS-derived and increased in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Acta Neuropathol, 128:639-650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4201967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24997849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan L, Chung C-C, Hsieh Y-C, Wu R-M, Hong C-T (2023). Plasma extracellular vesicle tau, &#x3b2;-amyloid, and &#x3b1;-synuclein and the progression of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a follow-up study. Ther Adv Neurol Disord, 16:17562864221150329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9896092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36741351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung C-C, Chan L, Chen J-H, Bamodu OA, Hong C-T (2020). Neurofilament light chain level in plasma extracellular vesicles and Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Ther Adv Neurol Disord, 13:1756286420975917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7724268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33335563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winston CN, Goetzl EJ, Akers JC, Carter BS, Rockenstein EM, Galasko D, et al.. (2016). Prediction of conversion from mild cognitive impairment to dementia with neuronally derived blood exosome protein profile. Alzheimer's &amp; Dementia: Diagnosis, Assessment &amp; Disease Monitoring, 3:63-72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4925777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27408937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madhu LN, Attaluri S, Kodali M, Shuai B, Upadhya R, Gitai D, et al.. (2019). Neuroinflammation in Gulf War Illness is linked with HMGB1 and complement activation, which can be discerned from brain-derived extracellular vesicles in the blood. Brain Behav Immun, 81:430-443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31255677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plassmeyer M, Alpan O, Corley MJ, Premeaux TA, Lillard K, Coatney P, et al.. (2022). Caspases and therapeutic potential of caspase inhibitors in moderate-severe SARS-CoV-2 infection and long COVID. Allergy, 77:118-129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8222863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33993490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker J, Stanifer ML, Leist SR, Stolp B, Maiakovska O, West A, et al.. (2022). Ex vivo and in vivo suppression of SARS-CoV-2 with combinatorial AAV/RNAi expression vectors. Mol Ther, 30:2005-2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8758558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35038579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui L, Fang Z, De Souza CM, Lerbs T, Guan Y, Li I, et al.. (2023). Innate immune cell activation causes lung fibrosis in a humanized model of long COVID. Proc Natl Acad Sci, 120:e2217199120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10013740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36848564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodali M, Parihar VK, Hattiangady B, Mishra V, Shuai B, Shetty AK (2015). Resveratrol Prevents Age-Related Memory and Mood Dysfunction with Increased Hippocampal Neurogenesis and Microvasculature and Reduced Glial Activation. Sci Rep, 5:8075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4894403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25627672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal D, Welsch MA, Keller JN, Francis J (2011). Chronic exercise modulates RAS components and improves balance between pro- and anti-inflammatory cytokines in the brain of SHR. Basic Res Cardiol, 106:1069-1085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3261080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22124756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otsuka S, Setoyama K, Takada S, Nakanishi K, Terashi T, Norimatsu K, et al.. (2021). Preconditioning Exercise in Rats Attenuates Early Brain Injury Resulting from Subarachnoid Hemorrhage by Reducing Oxidative Stress, Inflammation, and Neuronal Apoptosis. Mol Neurobiol.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34368932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song S-H, Jee Y-S, Ko I-G, Lee S-W, Sim Y-J, Kim D-Y, et al.. (2018). Treadmill exercise and wheel exercise improve motor function by suppressing apoptotic neuronal cell death in brain inflammation rats. J Exerc Rehabil, 14:911-919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6323344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30656148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodali M, Hattiangady B, Shetty GA, Bates A, Shuai B, Shetty AK (2018). Curcumin treatment leads to better cognitive and mood function in a model of Gulf War Illness with enhanced neurogenesis, and alleviation of inflammation and mitochondrial dysfunction in the hippocampus. Brain Behav Immun, 69:499-514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7023905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29454881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra V, Shuai B, Kodali M, Shetty GA, Hattiangady B, Rao X, et al.. (2015). Resveratrol Treatment after Status Epilepticus Restrains Neurodegeneration and Abnormal Neurogenesis with Suppression of Oxidative Stress and Inflammation. Sci Rep, 5:17807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4671086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26639668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickey B, Madhu LN, Shetty AK (2021). Gulf War Illness: Mechanisms Underlying Brain Dysfunction and Promising Therapeutic Strategies. Pharmacol Ther, 220:107716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8011829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33164782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attaluri S, Arora M, Madhu LN, Kodali M, Shuai B, Melissari L, et al.. (2022). Oral Nano-Curcumin in a Model of Chronic Gulf War Illness Alleviates Brain Dysfunction with Modulation of Oxidative Stress, Mitochondrial Function, Neuroinflammation, Neurogenesis, and Gene Expression. Aging Dis, 13:583-613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8947830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35371600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty AK (2011). Promise of resveratrol for easing status epilepticus and epilepsy. Pharmacol Ther, 131:269-286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3133838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21554899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Liu J, Shi J-S (2010). Anti-inflammatory activities of resveratrol in the brain: Role of resveratrol in microglial activation. Eur J Pharmacol, 636:1-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20361959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S-W, Jin Y, Shin J-H, Kim I-D, Lee H-K, Park S, et al.. (2012). Glycyrrhizic acid affords robust neuroprotection in the postischemic brain via anti-inflammatory effect by inhibiting HMGB1 phosphorylation and secretion. Neurobiol Dis, 46:147-156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22266336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lay&#xe9; S, Nadjar A, Joffre C, Bazinet RP (2018). Anti-Inflammatory Effects of Omega-3 Fatty Acids in the Brain: Physiological Mechanisms and Relevance to Pharmacology. Pharmacol Rev, 70:12-38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29217656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Chen F, Zhou B (2018). Antioxidative, anti-inflammatory and anti-apoptotic effects of ellagic acid in liver and brain of rats treated by D-galactose. Sci Rep, 8:1465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5780521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29362375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodali M, Castro OW, Kim D-K, Thomas A, Shuai B, Attaluri S, et al.. (2020). Intranasally Administered Human MSC-Derived Extracellular Vesicles Pervasively Incorporate into Neurons and Microglia in both Intact and Status Epilepticus Injured Forebrain. Int J Mol Sci, 21:181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6981466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31888012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long Q, Upadhya D, Hattiangady B, Kim D-K, An SY, Shuai B, et al.. (2017). Intranasal MSC-derived A1-exosomes ease inflammation, and prevent abnormal neurogenesis and memory dysfunction after status epilepticus. Proc Natl Acad Sci, 114:E3536-E3545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5410779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28396435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhya R, Zingg W, Shetty S, Shetty AK (2020). Astrocyte-derived extracellular vesicles: Neuroreparative properties and role in the pathogenesis of neurodegenerative disorders. J Control Release, 323:225-239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7299747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32289328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D-k, Nishida H, An SY, Shetty AK, Bartosh TJ, Prockop DJ (2016). Chromatographically isolated CD63+CD81+ extracellular vesicles from mesenchymal stromal cells rescue cognitive impairments after TBI. Proc Natl Acad Sci, 113:170-175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4711859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26699510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanzoni G, Linetsky E, Correa D, Messinger Cayetano S, Alvarez RA, Kouroupis D, et al.. (2021). Umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells for COVID-19 acute respiratory distress syndrome: A double-blind, phase 1/2a, randomized controlled trial. STEM CELLS Transl Med, 10:660-673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8046040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33400390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leng Z, Zhu R, Hou W, Feng Y, Yang Y, Han Q, et al.. (2020). Transplantation of ACE2- Mesenchymal Stem Cells Improves the Outcome of Patients with COVID-19 Pneumonia. Aging Dis, 11:216-228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7069465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32257537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengupta V, Sengupta S, Lazo A, Hicok KC, Moseley T (2020). Response to Lim et al. re: &#x201c;Exosomes Derived from Bone Marrow Mesenchymal Stem Cells as Treatment for Severe COVID-19&#x201d;. Stem Cells Dev, 29:879-881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7374618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32520639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty AK (2020). Mesenchymal Stem Cell Infusion Shows Promise for Combating Coronavirus (COVID-19)- Induced Pneumonia. Aging Dis, 11:462-464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7069463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32257554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias M, Butr&#xf3;n P, Torre-Villalvazo I, Torre-Anaya EA, Sierra-Madero J, Rodriguez-Andoney JJ, et al.. (2021). Mesenchymal Stem Cells for the Compassionate Treatment of Severe Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome Due to COVID 19. Aging Dis, 12:360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7990366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33815870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentile P (2021). SARS-CoV-2: the &#x201c;Uncensored&#x201d; Truth about Its Origin and Adipose-Derived Mesenchymal Stem Cells as New Potential Immune-Modulatory Weapon. Aging Dis, 12:330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7990360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33815867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty AK, Shetty PA, Zanirati G, Jin K (2021). Further validation of the efficacy of mesenchymal stem cell infusions for reducing mortality in COVID-19 patients with ARDS. NPJ Regen Med, 6:1-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8429629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34504110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalaj K, Figueira RL, Antounians L, Lauriti G, Zani A (2020). Systematic review of extracellular vesicle-based treatments for lung injury: are EVs a potential therapy for COVID-19? J Extracell Vesicles, 9:1795365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7481829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32944185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheraton M, Deo N, Kashyap R, Surani S A Review of Neurological Complications of COVID-19. Cureus, 12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32455089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magusali N, Graham AC, Piers TM, Panichnantakul P, Yaman U, Shoai M, et al.. (2021). A genetic link between risk for Alzheimer's disease and severe COVID-19 outcomes via the OAS1 gene. Brain, 144:3727-3741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34619763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantonen J, Mahzabin S, M&#xe4;yr&#xe4;np&#xe4;&#xe4; MI, Tynninen O, Paetau A, Andersson N, et al.. (2020). Neuropathologic features of four autopsied COVID-19 patients. Brain Pathol, 30:1012-1016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7436498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32762083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen MP, Quesne JL, Officer-Jones L, Teod&#xf2;sio A, Thaventhiran J, Ficken C, et al.. (2021). Neuropathological findings in two patients with fatal COVID-19. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol, 47:17-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32895961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulfamante G, Bocci T, Falleni M, Campiglio L, Coppola S, Tosi D, et al.. (2021). Brainstem neuropathology in two cases of COVID-19: SARS-CoV-2 trafficking between brain and lung. [J] Neurol.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8129960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34003372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhodes RH, Love GL, Lameira FDS, Sadough MS, Fox SE, Heide RSV (2021). Acute Endotheliitis (Type 3 Hypersensitivity Vasculitis) in Ten COVID-19 Autopsy Brains. medRxiv:2021.2001.2016.21249632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirschenbaum D, Imbach LL, Rushing EJ, Frauenknecht KBM, Gascho D, Ineichen BV, et al.. (2021). Intracerebral endotheliitis and microbleeds are neuropathological features of COVID-19. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol, 47:454-459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33249605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remmelink M, De Mendon&#xe7;a R, D&#x2019;Haene N, De Clercq S, Verocq C, Lebrun L, et al.. (2020). Unspecific post-mortem findings despite multiorgan viral spread in COVID-19 patients. Crit Care, 24:495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7422463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32787909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo D, Falasca L, Marchioni L, Tammaro A, Adebanjo GAR, Ippolito G, et al.. (2021). Neuropathology and Inflammatory Cell Characterization in 10 Autoptic COVID-19 Brains. Cells, 10:2262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8469459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34571912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younger DS (2020). Postmortem neuropathology in COVID-19. Brain Pathol, 31:385-386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7645938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33098141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Normandin E, Bhattacharyya S, Mukerji S, Keller K, Ali A, Adams G, et al.. (2021). Neuropathological Features of COVID-19 (4641). Neurology, 96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7304421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho C-Y, Salimian M, Hegert J, O&#x2019;Brien J, Choi SG, Ames H, et al.. (2022). Postmortem Assessment of Olfactory Tissue Degeneration and Microvasculopathy in Patients With COVID-19. JAMA Neurol, 79:544-553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9002725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35404378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin MdGM, Paes VR, Cardoso EF, Neto CEBP, Kanamura CT, Leite CdC, et al.. (2022). Postmortem brain 7T MRI with minimally invasive pathological correlation in deceased COVID-19 subjects. Insights into Imaging, 13:7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8760871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35032223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stram MN, Seifert AC, Cortes E, Akyatan A, Woodoff-Leith E, Borukhov V, et al.. (2022). Neuropathology of Pediatric SARS-CoV-2 Infection in the Forensic Setting: Novel Application of Ex Vivo Imaging in Analysis of Brain Microvasculature. Front Neurol, 13:894565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9170881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35685741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruz-Caracuel I, Pian-Arias H, Corral &#xcd;, Carretero-Barrio I, Bueno-Sacrist&#xe1;n D, P&#xe9;rez-Mies B, et al.. (2022). Neuropathological findings in fatal COVID-19 and their associated neurological clinical manifestations. Pathology, S003130252200160X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9182090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35691726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>