<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38450272</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2807-2618</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Narra J</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Narra J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Correlation between high sensitivity C reactive protein (Hs-CRP) and neutrophil-to- lymphocyte ratio (NLR) with functional capacity in post COVID-19 syndrome patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e183</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e183</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e183</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.52225/narra.v3i2.183</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Post coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) syndrome is one of the causes of reduced functional capacity and work productivity, in particular for healthcare workers. The pathophysiology of the post COVID-19 syndrome is related to complex and multisystem inflammatory mechanisms, and cardiopulmonary exercise rehabilitation program is one of the efforts to improve the recovery process for patients with post COVID-19 syndrome. The aim of this study was to determine the correlation between the level of high sensitivity C-reactive protein (Hs-CRP) and neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio (NLR) with functional capacity (VO<sub>2max</sub>) in individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome who received moderate- and high-intensity supervised cardiopulmonary exercise. A prospective cohort study was conducted at the Integrated Cardiac Rehabilitation Center of Dr. Zainoel Abidin Hospital, Banda Aceh, Indonesia. The supervised cardiopulmonary exercise was conducted for six weeks according to the participant's baseline VO<sub>2max</sub>. Spearman's and Pearson's correlation tests were used to assess the correlations. A total of 30 individuals (19 and 11 had moderate and high intensity exercise, respectively) were involved in this study. At moderate intensity exercise, the average Hs-CRP and NLR were 3.3 mg/L and 1.99, respectively; while at high intensity, the values were 3.8 mg/L and 1.79, respectively. No significant correlation between Hs-CRP level and functional capacity in both moderate-intensity and high intensity groups. In contrast, NLR was negatively correlated with functional capacity (<i>r</i>=-0.545, <i>p</i>=0.016) in moderate intensity exercise group. In conclusion, NLR value was negatively correlated with functional capacity in individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome after receiving moderate intensity supervised cardiopulmonary exercise program. Therefore, moderate intensity of cardiopulmonary exercise maybe be used as a program to accelerate the recovery for those with post COVID-19 syndrome.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Widasari</LastName><ForeName>Nina</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Vascular Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Syiah Kuala, Banda Aceh, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Vascular Medicine, Dr. Zainoel Abidin Hospital, Banda Aceh, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heriansyah</LastName><ForeName>Teuku</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Vascular Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Syiah Kuala, Banda Aceh, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Vascular Medicine, Dr. Zainoel Abidin Hospital, Banda Aceh, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ridwan</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Vascular Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Syiah Kuala, Banda Aceh, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Vascular Medicine, Dr. Zainoel Abidin Hospital, Banda Aceh, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Munirwan</LastName><ForeName>Haris</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Vascular Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Syiah Kuala, Banda Aceh, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Vascular Medicine, Dr. Zainoel Abidin Hospital, Banda Aceh, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurniawan</LastName><ForeName>Ferry D</ForeName><Initials>FD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonology, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Syiah Kuala, Banda Aceh, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonology, Dr. Zainoel Abidin Hospital, Banda Aceh, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Indonesia</Country><MedlineTA>Narra J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918625888906676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2807-2618</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hs-CRP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NLR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiopulmonary exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional capacity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38450272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10916408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52225/narra.v3i2.183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">NarraJ-3-e183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Larsen NW, Stiles LE, Miglis MG. Preparing for the long-haul: Autonomic complications of COVID-19. Auton Neurosci 2021;235:102841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8254396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford E.D, et al. . Managing the long term effects of covid-19: Summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ 2021;372:136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long QX, Tang XJ, Shi QL, et al. . Clinical and immunological assessment of asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infections. Nat Med 2020;26:1200&#x2013;1204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32555424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xf3;rdova-mart&#xed;nez A, P&#xe9;rez-valdecantos D, Caballero-garc&#xed;a A, et al. . Effect of exercise in the recovery process after the inflammation process caused by coronavirus. J Hum Sport Exerc 2021;18:1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maamar M, Artime A, Pariente E, et al. . Post-COVID-19 syndrome, low-grade inflammation and inflammatory markers: a cross-sectional study. Curr Med Res Opin 2022;38:901&#x2013;909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8935459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35166141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang I, Pranata R, Lim MA, et al. . C-reactive protein, procalcitonin, D-dimer, and ferritin in severe coronavirus disease-2019: a meta-analysis. Ther Adv Respir Dis 2020;14:1753466620937175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7336828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32615866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, et al. . Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS ONE 2020;15:e0240784&#x2013;e0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arena R, Myers J, Williams MA, et al. . Assessment of functional capacity in clinical and research settings. Circulation 2007;116:329&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17576872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed I. COVID-19 - does exercise prescription and maximal oxygen uptake (VO2max) have a role in risk-stratifying patients? Clin Med 2020;20:282&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7354019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32327405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acar RD, Sariba&#x15f; E, G&#xfc;ney PA, et al. . COVID-19: The new cause of dyspnoea as a result of reduced lung and peripheral muscle performance. J Breath Research 2021;15:47103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34469877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerqueira &#xc9;, Marinho DA, Neiva HP, et al. . Inflammatory effects of high and moderate intensity exercise&#x2014;a systematic review. Front Physiol 2020;10: 1550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6962351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31992987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng G, Qiu P, Xia R, et al. . Effect of aerobic exercise on inflammatory markers in healthy middle-aged and older adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Aging Neurosci 2019;11:98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6497785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31080412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balducci S, Zanuso S, Nicolucci A, et al. . Anti-inflammatory effect of exercise training in subjects with type 2 diabetes and the metabolic syndrome is dependent on exercise modalities and independent of weight loss. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis 2010;20:608&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19695853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michigan A, Johnson T V., Master VA. Review of the relationship between C-reactive protein and exercise. Mol Diagn Ther 2011;15:265&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22047154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Effects of aerobic exercise on C-reactive protein, body composition, and maximum oxygen consumption in adults: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Metabolism 2006;55:1500&#x2013;1507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17046553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, S&#xe1;nchez-L&#xf3;pez M, Escalante Y, et al. . Exercise-based interventions and C-reactive protein in overweight and obese youths: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Pediatric Research 2016;79:522&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26690715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildiz A, Yuksel M, Oylumlu M, et al. . The association between the neutrophil/lymphocyte ratio and functional capacity in patients with idiopathic dilated cardiomyopathy. Anadolu Kardiyol Derg 2015;15:13&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5336890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25179880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drugescu A, Roca M, Zota IM, et al. . Value of the neutrophil to lymphocyte ratio and platelet to lymphocyte ratio in predicting CPET Performance in patients with stable CAD and recent elective PCI. Medicina 2022;58:814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9229341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35744077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Chen Y, Tang X.. Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in China. Glob Health Med 2020;2:66&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7731342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33330780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. Guideline for exercise testing. 2006;:21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Gaughan C.. Technical article: Updated estimates of the prevalence of post-acute symptoms among people with coronavirus (COVID-19) in the UK.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher GF, Balady GJ, Amsterdam EA, et al. . Exercise standards for testing and training: a statement for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2001;104:1694&#x2013;1740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lear SA, Brozic A, Myers JN, et al. . Exercise Stress Testing. Sports Med 1999;27:285&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10368877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santisteban KJ, Lovering AT, Halliwill JR, et al. . Sex differences in VO2max and the impact on endurance-exercise performance. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022;19:4946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9105160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35564339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gameil MA, Marzouk RE, Elsebaie AH, et al. . Long-term clinical and biochemical residue after COVID-19 recovery. Egypt Liver J 2021;11:74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8435147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34777873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehring SM, Goyal A, Patel BC. C Reactive protein. In: StatPearls. Treasure Island: (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28722873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose GL, Skinner TL, Mielke GI, et al. . The effect of exercise intensity on chronic inflammation: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sport is J Sci Med Sport 2021;24:345&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33153926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forget P, Khalifa C, Defour J-P, et al. . What is the normal value of the neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio? BMC Res Notes. 2017;10:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5217256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28057051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaniganti US, DrC Karigar, Chatterjee P.. NLR: An incipient marker to monitor inflammation, overtraining, and recovery in athletes. Int J Phys Educ Sports Health 2022;9:138&#x2013;141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villelabeitia Jaureguizar K, Vicente-Campos D, Ruiz Bautista L, et al. . Effect of high-intensity interval versus continuous exercise training on functional capacity and quality of life in patients with coronary artery disease: A randomized clinical trial. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev 2016;36:96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26872000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed AA, Alawna M.. The effect of aerobic exercise on immune biomarkers and symptoms severity and progression in patients with COVID-19: A randomized control trial. J Bodyw Mov Ther 2021;28:425&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8339452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34776174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natale VM, Brenner IK, Moldoveanu AI, et al. . Effects of three different types of exercise on blood leukocyte count during and following exercise. Sao Paulo Med J 2003;121:09&#x2013;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11108609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12751337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes JH, Mendes RR, Franca CS, et al. . Acute leucocyte, muscle damage, and stress marker responses to high-intensity functional training. PLoS ONE 2020;15:e0243276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7714345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33270727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>