<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37233729</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2050-084X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>eLife</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Elife</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Immune mechanisms underlying COVID-19 pathology and post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC).</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e86014</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7554/eLife.86014</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>With a global tally of more than 500 million cases of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infections to date, there are growing concerns about the post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC), also known as long COVID. Recent studies suggest that exaggerated immune responses are key determinants of the severity and outcomes of the initial SARS-CoV-2 infection as well as subsequent PASC. The complexity of the innate and adaptive immune responses in the acute and post-acute period requires in-depth mechanistic analyses to identify specific molecular signals as well as specific immune cell populations which promote PASC pathogenesis. In this review, we examine the current literature on mechanisms of immune dysregulation in severe COVID-19 and the limited emerging data on the immunopathology of PASC. While the acute and post-acute phases may share some parallel mechanisms of immunopathology, it is likely that PASC immunopathology is quite distinct and heterogeneous, thus requiring large-scale longitudinal analyses in patients with and without PASC after an acute SARS-CoV-2 infection. By outlining the knowledge gaps in the immunopathology of PASC, we hope to provide avenues for novel research directions that will ultimately lead to precision therapies which restore healthy immune function in PASC patients.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohandas</LastName><ForeName>Sindhu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8397-6249</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Children's Hospital Los Angeles, Keck School of Medicine, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jagannathan</LastName><ForeName>Prasanna</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6305-758X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases and Geographic Medicine, Department of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henrich</LastName><ForeName>Timothy J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Experimental Medicine, University of California, San Francisco, San Francisco, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sherif</LastName><ForeName>Zaki A</ForeName><Initials>ZA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1772-7041</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry &amp; Molecular Biology, Howard University College of Medicine, Washington, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bime</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary, Allergy, Critical Care &amp; Sleep Medicine, Department of Medicine, University of Arizona College of Medicine, Tucson, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quinlan</LastName><ForeName>Erin</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Portman</LastName><ForeName>Michael A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Seattle Children's Hospital, Division of Pediatric Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, University of Washington, Seattle, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gennaro</LastName><ForeName>Marila</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health Research Institute and Department of Medicine, Rutgers New Jersey Medical School, Newark, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rehman</LastName><ForeName>Jalees</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2787-9292</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Illinois, College of Medicine, Chicago, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>RECOVER Mechanistic Pathways Task Force</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K08 HL141623</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>OT2 HL161847</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01 AI150741</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Elife</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101579614</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-084X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adaptive immunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunopathology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">innate immunity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>SM, PJ, TH, ZS, CB, MP, MG, JR No competing interests declared, EQ is employed by the NIH which funded the RECOVER trial</CoiStatement><InvestigatorList><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bradfute</LastName><ForeName>Steven B</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Global Health, Department of Internal Medicine, University of New Mexico Health Sciences Center, Albuquerque, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin K</ForeName><Initials>BK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Medicine, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Connors</LastName><ForeName>Thomas J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Division of Critical Care, Columbia University Vagelos College of Physicians and Surgeons and New York - Presbyterian Morgan Stanley Children's Hospital, New York, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coombs</LastName><ForeName>K</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIH RECOVER Research Initiative: Patient representative, Bethesda, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gomez</LastName><ForeName>Christian R</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Lung Diseases, National Institutes of Health, National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute, Bethesda, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Julg</LastName><ForeName>Boris D</ForeName><Initials>BD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Disease Division, Massachusetts General Hospital, Ragon Institute of MGH, MIT and Harvard, Cambridge, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>C</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIH RECOVER Research Initiative: Patient representative, Bethesda, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brian Reeves</LastName><ForeName>W</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Joe R. and Teresa Lozano Long School of Medicine, University of Texas San Antonio, San Antonio, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator></InvestigatorList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37233729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10219649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.86014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">86014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Afrin LB, Weinstock LB, Molderings GJ. Covid-19 Hyperinflammation and post-COVID-19 illness may be rooted in mast cell activation syndrome. International Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2020;100:327&#x2013;332. doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2020.09.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2020.09.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7529115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32920235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliyu M, Zohora FT, Anka AU, Ali K, Maleknia S, Saffarioun M, Azizi G. Interleukin-6 cytokine: an overview of the immune regulation, immune dysregulation, and therapeutic approach. International Immunopharmacology. 2022;111:109130. doi: 10.1016/j.intimp.2022.109130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.intimp.2022.109130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35969896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aschenbrenner AC, Mouktaroudi M, Kr&#xe4;mer B, Oestreich M, Antonakos N, Nuesch-Germano M, Gkizeli K, Bonaguro L, Reusch N, Ba&#xdf;ler K, Saridaki M, Knoll R, Pecht T, Kapellos TS, Doulou S, Kr&#xf6;ger C, Herbert M, Holsten L, Horne A, Gem&#xfc;nd ID, Rovina N, Agrawal S, Dahm K, van Uelft M, Drews A, Lenkeit L, Bruse N, Gerretsen J, Gierlich J, Becker M, H&#xe4;ndler K, Kraut M, Theis H, Mengiste S, De Domenico E, Schulte-Schrepping J, Seep L, Raabe J, Hoffmeister C, ToVinh M, Keitel V, Rieke G, Talevi V, Skowasch D, Aziz NA, Pickkers P, van de Veerdonk FL, Netea MG, Schultze JL, Kox M, Breteler MMB, Nattermann J, Koutsoukou A, Giamarellos-Bourboulis EJ, Ulas T, German COVID-19 Omics Initiative DeCOI Disease severity-specific neutrophil signatures in blood Transcriptomes stratify COVID-19 patients. Genome Medicine. 2021;13:7. doi: 10.1186/s13073-020-00823-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13073-020-00823-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7805430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33441124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassler K, Schulte-Schrepping J, Warnat-Herresthal S, Aschenbrenner AC, Schultze JL. The myeloid cell compartment-cell by cell. Annual Review of Immunology. 2019;37:269&#x2013;293. doi: 10.1146/annurev-immunol-042718-041728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-immunol-042718-041728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30649988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastard P, Rosen LB, Zhang Q, Michailidis E, Hoffmann HH, Zhang Y, Dorgham K, Philippot Q, Rosain J, B&#xe9;ziat V, Manry J, Shaw E, Haljasm&#xe4;gi L, Peterson P, Lorenzo L, Bizien L, Trouillet-Assant S, Dobbs K, de Jesus AA, Belot A, Kallaste A, Catherinot E, Tandjaoui-Lambiotte Y, Le Pen J, Kerner G, Bigio B, Seeleuthner Y, Yang R, Bolze A, Spaan AN, Delmonte OM, Abers MS, Aiuti A, Casari G, Lampasona V, Piemonti L, Ciceri F, Bilguvar K, Lifton RP, Vasse M, Smadja DM, Migaud M, Hadjadj J, Terrier B, Duffy D, Quintana-Murci L, van de Beek D, Roussel L, Vinh DC, Tangye SG, Haerynck F, Dalmau D, Martinez-Picado J, Brodin P, Nussenzweig MC, Boisson-Dupuis S, Rodr&#xed;guez-Gallego C, Vogt G, Mogensen TH, Oler AJ, Gu J, Burbelo PD, Cohen JI, Biondi A, Bettini LR, D&#x2019;Angio M, Bonfanti P, Rossignol P, Mayaux J, Rieux-Laucat F, Husebye ES, Fusco F, Ursini MV, Imberti L, Sottini A, Paghera S, Quiros-Roldan E, Rossi C, Castagnoli R, Montagna D, Licari A, Marseglia GL, Duval X, Ghosn J, HGID Lab. NIAID-USUHS Immune Response to COVID Group. COVID Clinicians. COVID-STORM Clinicians. Imagine COVID Group. French COVID Cohort Study Group. Milieu Int&#xe9;rieur Consortium. CoV-Contact Cohort. Amsterdam UMC Covid-19 Biobank. COVID Human Genetic Effort. Tsang JS, Goldbach-Mansky R, Kisand K, Lionakis MS, Puel A, Zhang SY, Holland SM, Gorochov G, Jouanguy E, Rice CM, Cobat A, Notarangelo LD, Abel L, Su HC, Casanova JL. Autoantibodies against type I Ifns in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science. 2020;370:eabd4585. doi: 10.1126/science.abd4585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abd4585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer DK, Forero A. Mechanisms of antiviral immune evasion of SARS-Cov-2. Journal of Molecular Biology. 2022;434:167265. doi: 10.1016/j.jmb.2021.167265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmb.2021.167265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8457632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34562466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornevik K, Cortese M, Healy BC, Kuhle J, Mina MJ, Leng Y, Elledge SJ, Niebuhr DW, Scher AI, Munger KL, Ascherio A. Longitudinal analysis reveals high prevalence of Epstein-Barr virus associated with multiple sclerosis. Science. 2022;375:296&#x2013;301. doi: 10.1126/science.abj8222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abj8222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35025605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco-Melo D, Nilsson-Payant BE, Liu W-C, Uhl S, Hoagland D, M&#xf8;ller R, Jordan TX, Oishi K, Panis M, Sachs D, Wang TT, Schwartz RE, Lim JK, Albrecht RA, tenOever BR. Imbalanced host response to SARS-Cov-2 drives development of COVID-19. Cell. 2020;181:1036&#x2013;1045. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2020.04.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.04.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7227586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32416070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohnacker S, Hartung F, Henkel F, Quaranta A, Kolmert J, Priller A, Ud-Dean M, Giglberger J, Kugler LM, Pechtold L, Yazici S, Lechner A, Erber J, Protzer U, Lingor P, Knolle P, Chaker AM, Schmidt-Weber CB, Wheelock CE, Esser-von Bieren J. Mild COVID-19 imprints a long-term inflammatory Eicosanoid- and Chemokine memory in monocyte-derived Macrophages. Mucosal Immunology. 2022;15:515&#x2013;524. doi: 10.1038/s41385-022-00526-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41385-022-00526-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9038526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35288643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budnevsky AV, Avdeev SN, Kosanovic D, Shishkina VV, Filin AA, Esaulenko DI, Ovsyannikov ES, Samoylenko TV, Redkin AN, Suvorova OA, Perveeva IM. Role of mast cells in the pathogenesis of severe lung damage in COVID-19 patients. Respiratory Research. 2022;23:371. doi: 10.1186/s12931-022-02284-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-022-02284-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9769495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36544127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmona-Rivera C, Zhang Y, Dobbs K, Markowitz TE, Dalgard CL, Oler AJ, Claybaugh DR, Draper D, Truong M, Delmonte OM, Licciardi F, Ramenghi U, Crescenzio N, Imberti L, Sottini A, Quaresima V, Fiorini C, Discepolo V, Lo Vecchio A, Guarino A, Pierri L, Catzola A, Biondi A, Bonfanti P, Poli Harlowe MC, Espinosa Y, Astudillo C, Rey-Jurado E, Vial C, de la Cruz J, Gonzalez R, Pinera C, Mays JW, Ng A, Platt A, Drolet B, Moon J, Cowen EW, Kenney H, Weber SE, Castagnoli R, Magliocco M, Stack MA, Montealegre G, Barron K, Fink DL, Kuhns DB, Hewitt SM, Arkin LM, Chertow DS, Su HC, Notarangelo LD, Kaplan MJ, NIH COVID Autopsy Consortium. COVID STORM Clinicians Multicenter analysis of neutrophil extracellular trap dysregulation in adult and pediatric COVID-19. JCI Insight. 2022;7:e160332. doi: 10.1172/jci.insight.160332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci.insight.160332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9534551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35852866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter MJ, Fish M, Jennings A, Doores KJ, Wellman P, Seow J, Acors S, Graham C, Timms E, Kenny J, Neil S, Malim MH, Tibby SM, Shankar-Hari M. Peripheral Immunophenotypes in children with Multisystem inflammatory syndrome associated with SARS-Cov-2 infection. Nature Medicine. 2020;26:1701&#x2013;1707. doi: 10.1038/s41591-020-1054-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-020-1054-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32812012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang SE, Feng A, Meng W, Apostolidis SA, Mack E, Artandi M, Barman L, Bennett K, Chakraborty S, Chang I, Cheung P, Chinthrajah S, Dhingra S, Do E, Finck A, Gaano A, Ge&#xdf;ner R, Giannini HM, Gonzalez J, Greib S, G&#xfc;ndisch M, Hsu AR, Kuo A, Manohar M, Mao R, Neeli I, Neubauer A, Oniyide O, Powell AE, Puri R, Renz H, Schapiro J, Weidenbacher PA, Wittman R, Ahuja N, Chung HR, Jagannathan P, James JA, Kim PS, Meyer NJ, Nadeau KC, Radic M, Robinson WH, Singh U, Wang TT, Wherry EJ, Skevaki C, Luning Prak ET, Utz PJ. New-onset IgG Autoantibodies in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Nature Communications. 2021;12:5417. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-25509-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-25509-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34521836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B, Julg B, Mohandas S, Bradfute SB, RECOVER Mechanistic Pathways Task Force Viral persistence, reactivation, and mechanisms of long COVID. eLife. 2023;12:e86015. doi: 10.7554/eLife.86015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.86015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10159620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37140960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng MH, Zhang S, Porritt RA, Noval Rivas M, Paschold L, Willscher E, Binder M, Arditi M, Bahar I. Superantigenic character of an insert unique to SARS-Cov-2 spike supported by skewed TCR repertoire in patients with Hyperinflammation. PNAS. 2020;117:25254&#x2013;25262. doi: 10.1073/pnas.2010722117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2010722117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7568239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32989130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou J, Thomas PG, Randolph AG. Immunology of SARS-Cov-2 infection in children. Nature Immunology. 2022;23:177&#x2013;185. doi: 10.1038/s41590-021-01123-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-021-01123-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8981222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen KW, Linderman SL, Moodie Z, Czartoski J, Lai L, Mantus G, Norwood C, Nyhoff LE, Edara VV, Floyd K, De Rosa SC, Ahmed H, Whaley R, Patel SN, Prigmore B, Lemos MP, Davis CW, Furth S, O&#x2019;Keefe JB, Gharpure MP, Gunisetty S, Stephens K, Antia R, Zarnitsyna VI, Stephens DS, Edupuganti S, Rouphael N, Anderson EJ, Mehta AK, Wrammert J, Suthar MS, Ahmed R, McElrath MJ. Longitudinal analysis shows durable and broad immune memory after SARS-Cov-2 infection with persisting antibody responses and memory B and T cells. Cell Reports. Medicine. 2021;2:100354. doi: 10.1016/j.xcrm.2021.100354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xcrm.2021.100354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8253687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34250512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combes AJ, Courau T, Kuhn NF, Hu KH, Ray A, Chen WS, Chew NW, Cleary SJ, Kushnoor D, Reeder GC, Shen A, Tsui J, Hiam-Galvez KJ, Mu&#xf1;oz-Sandoval P, Zhu WS, Lee DS, Sun Y, You R, Magnen M, Rodriguez L, Im KW, Serwas NK, Leligdowicz A, Zamecnik CR, Loudermilk RP, Wilson MR, Ye CJ, Fragiadakis GK, Looney MR, Chan V, Ward A, Carrillo S, UCSF COMET Consortium. Matthay M, Erle DJ, Woodruff PG, Langelier C, Kangelaris K, Hendrickson CM, Calfee C, Rao AA, Krummel MF. Global absence and targeting of protective immune States in severe COVID-19. Nature. 2021;596:124&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1038/s41586-021-03718-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-021-03718-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8567458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33494096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dan JM, Mateus J, Kato Y, Hastie KM, Yu ED, Faliti CE, Grifoni A, Ramirez SI, Haupt S, Frazier A, Nakao C, Rayaprolu V, Rawlings SA, Peters B, Krammer F, Simon V, Saphire EO, Smith DM, Weiskopf D, Sette A, Crotty S. Immunological memory to SARS-Cov-2 assessed for up to 8 months after infection. Science. 2021;371:6529. doi: 10.1126/science.abf4063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abf4063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7919858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33408181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nature Reviews Microbiology. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146. doi: 10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond MS, Kanneganti TD. Innate immunity: the first line of defense against SARS-Cov-2. Nature Immunology. 2022;23:165&#x2013;176. doi: 10.1038/s41590-021-01091-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-021-01091-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8935980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrenfeld M, Tincani A, Andreoli L, Cattalini M, Greenbaum A, Kanduc D, Alijotas-Reig J, Zinserling V, Semenova N, Amital H, Shoenfeld Y. Covid-19 and Autoimmunity. Autoimmunity Reviews. 2020;19:102597. doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2020.102597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2020.102597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7289100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32535093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favalli EG, Ingegnoli F, De Lucia O, Cincinelli G, Cimaz R, Caporali R. COVID-19 infection and rheumatoid arthritis: Faraway, so close. Autoimmunity Reviews. 2020;19:102523. doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2020.102523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2020.102523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32205186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frieri M. Mast cell activation syndrome. Clinical Reviews in Allergy &amp; Immunology. 2018;54:353&#x2013;365. doi: 10.1007/s12016-015-8487-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12016-015-8487-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25944644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frishberg A, Kooistra E, Nuesch-Germano M, Pecht T, Milman N, Reusch N, Warnat-Herresthal S, Bruse N, H&#xe4;ndler K, Theis H, Kraut M, van Rijssen E, van Cranenbroek B, Koenen HJ, Heesakkers H, van den Boogaard M, Zegers M, Pickkers P, Becker M, Aschenbrenner AC, Ulas T, Theis FJ, Shen-Orr SS, Schultze JL, Kox M. Mature neutrophils and a NF-kappaB-to-IFN transition determine the unifying disease recovery Dynamics in COVID-19. Cell Reports. Medicine. 2022;3:100652. doi: 10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9110324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35675822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaebler C, Wang Z, Lorenzi JCC, Muecksch F, Finkin S, Tokuyama M, Cho A, Jankovic M, Schaefer-Babajew D, Oliveira TY, Cipolla M, Viant C, Barnes CO, Bram Y, Breton G, H&#xe4;ggl&#xf6;f T, Mendoza P, Hurley A, Turroja M, Gordon K, Millard KG, Ramos V, Schmidt F, Weisblum Y, Jha D, Tankelevich M, Martinez-Delgado G, Yee J, Patel R, Dizon J, Unson-O&#x2019;Brien C, Shimeliovich I, Robbiani DF, Zhao Z, Gazumyan A, Schwartz RE, Hatziioannou T, Bjorkman PJ, Mehandru S, Bieniasz PD, Caskey M, Nussenzweig MC. Evolution of antibody immunity to SARS-Cov-2. Nature. 2021;591:639&#x2013;644. doi: 10.1038/s41586-021-03207-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-021-03207-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galani IE, Rovina N, Lampropoulou V, Triantafyllia V, Manioudaki M, Pavlos E, Koukaki E, Fragkou PC, Panou V, Rapti V, Koltsida O, Mentis A, Koulouris N, Tsiodras S, Koutsoukou A, Andreakos E. Untuned antiviral immunity in COVID-19 revealed by temporal type I/III interferon patterns and flu comparison. Nature Immunology. 2021;22:32&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1038/s41590-020-00840-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-020-00840-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33277638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P, Tahmasebi N, Gant V, Gupta R. Long COVID following mild SARS-Cov-2 infection: characteristic T cell alterations and response to Antihistamines. Journal of Investigative Medicine. 2022;70:61&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1136/jim-2021-002051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jim-2021-002051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8494538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold JE, Okyay RA, Licht WE, Hurley DJ. Investigation of long COVID prevalence and its relationship to Epstein-Barr virus reactivation. Pathogens. 2021;10:763. doi: 10.3390/pathogens10060763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pathogens10060763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8233978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34204243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gracia-Ramos AE, Martin-Nares E, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Molina G. New onset of autoimmune diseases following COVID-19 diagnosis. Cells. 2021;10:12. doi: 10.3390/cells10123592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells10123592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8700122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34944099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruber CN, Patel RS, Trachtman R, Lepow L, Amanat F, Krammer F, Wilson KM, Onel K, Geanon D, Tuballes K, Patel M, Mouskas K, O&#x2019;Donnell T, Merritt E, Simons NW, Barcessat V, Del Valle DM, Udondem S, Kang G, Gangadharan S, Ofori-Amanfo G, Laserson U, Rahman A, Kim-Schulze S, Charney AW, Gnjatic S, Gelb BD, Merad M, Bogunovic D. Mapping systemic inflammation and antibody responses in Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) Cell. 2020;183:982&#x2013;995. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2020.09.034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.09.034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7489877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadjadj J, Yatim N, Barnabei L, Corneau A, Boussier J, Smith N, P&#xe9;r&#xe9; H, Charbit B, Bondet V, Chenevier-Gobeaux C, Breillat P, Carlier N, Gauzit R, Morbieu C, P&#xe8;ne F, Marin N, Roche N, Szwebel T-A, Merkling SH, Treluyer J-M, Veyer D, Mouthon L, Blanc C, Tharaux P-L, Rozenberg F, Fischer A, Duffy D, Rieux-Laucat F, Kern&#xe9;is S, Terrier B. Impaired type I interferon activity and inflammatory responses in severe COVID-19 patients. Science. 2020;369:718&#x2013;724. doi: 10.1126/science.abc6027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abc6027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7402632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriksson L, Kelter U. Ultrasonography and scintigraphy of the liver in focal and diffuse disease. Acta Radiologica. 1987;28:165&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2953370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoang TN, Pino M, Boddapati AK, Viox EG, Starke CE, Upadhyay AA, Gumber S, Nekorchuk M, Busman-Sahay K, Strongin Z, Harper JL, Tharp GK, Pellegrini KL, Kirejczyk S, Zandi K, Tao S, Horton TR, Beagle EN, Mahar EA, Lee MYH, Cohen J, Jean SM, Wood JS, Connor-Stroud F, Stammen RL, Delmas OM, Wang S, Cooney KA, Sayegh MN, Wang L, Filev PD, Weiskopf D, Silvestri G, Waggoner J, Piantadosi A, Kasturi SP, Al-Shakhshir H, Ribeiro SP, Sekaly RP, Levit RD, Estes JD, Vanderford TH, Schinazi RF, Bosinger SE, Paiardini M. Baricitinib treatment resolves lower-airway macrophage inflammation and neutrophil recruitment in SARS-Cov-2-infected Rhesus macaques. Cell. 2021;184:460&#x2013;475. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2020.11.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.11.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7654323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33278358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hohberger B, Harrer T, Mardin C, Kruse F, Hoffmanns J, Rogge L, Heltmann F, Moritz M, Szewczykowski C, Schottenhamml J, Kr&#xe4;ter M, Bergua A, Zenkel M, Gie&#xdf;l A, Schl&#xf6;tzer-Schrehardt U, L&#xe4;mmer R, Herrmann M, Haberland A, G&#xf6;ttel P, M&#xfc;ller J, Wallukat G. Case report: neutralization of Autoantibodies targeting G-protein-coupled receptors improves capillary impairment and fatigue symptoms after COVID-19 infection. Frontiers in Medicine. 2021;8:754667. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2021.754667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.754667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8637609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34869451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Q, Wu X, Zheng X, Luo S, Xu S, Weng J. Targeting inflammation and cytokine storm in COVID-19. Pharmacological Research. 2020;159:105051. doi: 10.1016/j.phrs.2020.105051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2020.105051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7320704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32603772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huckriede J, Anderberg SB, Morales A, de Vries F, Hultstr&#xf6;m M, Bergqvist A, Ortiz-P&#xe9;rez JT, Sels JW, Wichapong K, Lipcsey M, van de Poll M, Larsson A, Luther T, Reutelingsperger C, de Frutos PG, Frithiof R, Nicolaes GAF. Evolution of Netosis markers and Damps have Prognostic value in critically ill COVID-19 patients. Scientific Reports. 2021;11:15701. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-95209-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-95209-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8333321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34344929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenks SA, Cashman KS, Zumaquero E, Marigorta UM, Patel AV, Wang X, Tomar D, Woodruff MC, Simon Z, Bugrovsky R, Blalock EL, Scharer CD, Tipton CM, Wei C, Lim SS, Petri M, Niewold TB, Anolik JH, Gibson G, Lee FE-H, Boss JM, Lund FE, Sanz I. Distinct Effector B cells induced by unregulated toll-like receptor 7 contribute to pathogenic responses in systemic lupus erythematosus. Immunity. 2018;49:725&#x2013;739. doi: 10.1016/j.immuni.2018.08.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2018.08.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6217820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30314758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorch SK, Kubes P. An emerging role for neutrophil extracellular traps in Noninfectious disease. Nature Medicine. 2017;23:279&#x2013;287. doi: 10.1038/nm.4294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.4294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28267716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukema BN, Smit K, Hopman MTE, Bongers CCWG, Pelgrim TC, Rijk MH, Platteel TN, Venekamp RP, Zwart DLM, Rutten FH, Koenderman L. Neutrophil and eosinophil responses remain abnormal for several months in primary care patients with COVID-19 disease. Frontiers in Allergy. 2022;3:942699. doi: 10.3389/falgy.2022.942699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/falgy.2022.942699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9365032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35966226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Junqueira C, Crespo &#xc2;, Ranjbar S, de Lacerda LB, Lewandrowski M, Ingber J, Parry B, Ravid S, Clark S, Schrimpf MR, Ho F, Beakes C, Margolin J, Russell N, Kays K, Boucau J, Das Adhikari U, Vora SM, Leger V, Gehrke L, Henderson LA, Janssen E, Kwon D, Sander C, Abraham J, Goldberg MB, Wu H, Mehta G, Bell S, Goldfeld AE, Filbin MR, Lieberman J. Fcgammar-mediated SARS-Cov-2 infection of monocytes activates inflammation. Nature. 2022;606:576&#x2013;584. doi: 10.1038/s41586-022-04702-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-022-04702-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10071495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35385861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser R, Leunig A, Pekayvaz K, Popp O, Joppich M, Polewka V, Escaig R, Anjum A, Hoffknecht ML, Gold C, Brambs S, Engel A, Stockhausen S, Knottenberg V, Titova A, Haji M, Scherer C, Muenchhoff M, Hellmuth JC, Saar K, Schubert B, Hilgendorff A, Schulz C, K&#xe4;&#xe4;b S, Zimmer R, H&#xfc;bner N, Massberg S, Mertins P, Nicolai L, Stark K. Self-sustaining IL-8 loops drive a Prothrombotic neutrophil phenotype in severe COVID-19. JCI Insight. 2021;6:e150862. doi: 10.1172/jci.insight.150862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci.insight.150862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8492337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34403366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneko N, Kuo H-H, Boucau J, Farmer JR, Allard-Chamard H, Mahajan VS, Piechocka-Trocha A, Lefteri K, Osborn M, Bals J, Bartsch YC, Bonheur N, Caradonna TM, Chevalier J, Chowdhury F, Diefenbach TJ, Einkauf K, Fallon J, Feldman J, Finn KK, Garcia-Broncano P, Hartana CA, Hauser BM, Jiang C, Kaplonek P, Karpell M, Koscher EC, Lian X, Liu H, Liu J, Ly NL, Michell AR, Rassadkina Y, Seiger K, Sessa L, Shin S, Singh N, Sun W, Sun X, Ticheli HJ, Waring MT, Zhu AL, Alter G, Li JZ, Lingwood D, Schmidt AG, Lichterfeld M, Walker BD, Yu XG, Padera RF, Pillai S, Massachusetts Consortium on Pathogen Readiness Specimen Working Group Loss of Bcl-6-expressing T follicular helper cells and germinal centers in COVID-19. Cell. 2020;183:143&#x2013;157. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2020.08.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.08.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7437499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32877699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karki R, Sharma BR, Tuladhar S, Williams EP, Zalduondo L, Samir P, Zheng M, Sundaram B, Banoth B, Malireddi RKS, Schreiner P, Neale G, Vogel P, Webby R, Jonsson CB, Kanneganti TD. Synergism of TNF-alpha and IFN-gamma triggers inflammatory cell death, tissue damage, and mortality in SARS-Cov-2 infection and cytokine shock syndromes. Cell. 2021;184:149&#x2013;168. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2020.11.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.11.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7674074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33278357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasuga Y, Zhu B, Jang KJ, Yoo JS. Innate immune sensing of Coronavirus and viral evasion strategies. Experimental &amp; Molecular Medicine. 2021;53:723&#x2013;736. doi: 10.1038/s12276-021-00602-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s12276-021-00602-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8099713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33953325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J, Wood J, Jaycox J, Lu P, Dhodapkar RM, Gehlhausen JR, Tabachnikova A, Tabacof L, Malik AA, Kamath K, Greene K, Monteiro VS, Pe&#xf1;a-Hernandez M, Mao T, Bhattacharjee B, Takahashi T, Lucas C, Silva J, Mccarthy D, Breyman E, Tosto-Mancuso J, Dai Y, Perotti E, Akduman K, Tzeng TJ, Xu L, Yildirim I, Krumholz HM, Shon J, Medzhitov R, Omer SB, van Dijk D, Ring AM, Putrino D, Iwasaki A. Distinguishing Features of Long COVID Identified through Immune Profiling. medRxiv. 2022 doi: 10.1101/2022.08.09.22278592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2022.08.09.22278592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10620090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37748514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight JS, Caricchio R, Casanova JL, Combes AJ, Diamond B, Fox SE, Hanauer DA, James JA, Kanthi Y, Ladd V, Mehta P, Ring AM, Sanz I, Selmi C, Tracy RP, Utz PJ, Wagner CA, Wang JY, McCune WJ. The intersection of COVID-19 and Autoimmunity. Journal of Clinical Investigation. 2021;131:24. doi: 10.1172/JCI154886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI154886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34710063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knoll R, Schultze JL, Schulte-Schrepping J. Monocytes and Macrophages in COVID-19. Frontiers in Immunology. 2021;12:720109. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2021.720109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.720109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8335157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34367190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang FM, Lee KM-C, Teijaro JR, Becher B, Hamilton JA. GM-CSF-based treatments in COVID-19: reconciling opposing therapeutic approaches. Nature Reviews. Immunology. 2020;20:507&#x2013;514. doi: 10.1038/s41577-020-0357-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-020-0357-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7309428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32576980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanz TV, Brewer RC, Ho PP, Moon JS, Jude KM, Fernandez D, Fernandes RA, Gomez AM, Nadj GS, Bartley CM, Schubert RD, Hawes IA, Vazquez SE, Iyer M, Zuchero JB, Teegen B, Dunn JE, Lock CB, Kipp LB, Cotham VC, Ueberheide BM, Aftab BT, Anderson MS, DeRisi JL, Wilson MR, Bashford-Rogers RJM, Platten M, Garcia KC, Steinman L, Robinson WH. Clonally expanded B cells in multiple sclerosis bind EBV Ebna1 and Glialcam. Nature. 2022;603:321&#x2013;327. doi: 10.1038/s41586-022-04432-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-022-04432-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9382663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35073561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao M, Liu Y, Yuan J, Wen Y, Xu G, Zhao J, Cheng L, Li J, Wang X, Wang F, Liu L, Amit I, Zhang S, Zhang Z. Single-cell landscape of Bronchoalveolar immune cells in patients with COVID-19. Nature Medicine. 2020;26:842&#x2013;844. doi: 10.1038/s41591-020-0901-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-020-0901-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Littlefield KM, Watson RO, Schneider JM, Neff CP, Yamada E, Zhang M, Campbell TB, Falta MT, Jolley SE, Fontenot AP, Palmer BE. SARS-Cov-2-specific T cells associate with inflammation and reduced lung function in pulmonary post-acute Sequalae of SARS-Cov-2. PLOS Pathogens. 2022;18:e1010359. doi: 10.1371/journal.ppat.1010359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1010359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9176759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35617421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowery SA, Sariol A, Perlman S. Innate immune and inflammatory responses to SARS-Cov-2: implications for COVID-19. Cell Host &amp; Microbe. 2021;29:1052&#x2013;1062. doi: 10.1016/j.chom.2021.05.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chom.2021.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8126603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34022154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall M. The four most urgent questions about long COVID. Nature. 2021;594:168&#x2013;170. doi: 10.1038/d41586-021-01511-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/d41586-021-01511-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34108700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Col&#xf3;n GJ, Ratnasiri K, Chen H, Jiang S, Zanley E, Rustagi A, Verma R, Chen H, Andrews JR, Mertz KD, Tzankov A, Azagury D, Boyd J, Nolan GP, Sch&#xfc;rch CM, Matter MS, Blish CA, McLaughlin TL. SARS-Cov-2 infection drives an inflammatory response in human Adipose tissue through infection of Adipocytes and Macrophages. Science Translational Medicine. 2022;14:eabm9151. doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.abm9151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.abm9151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9529056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36137009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, McAuley DF, Brown M, Sanchez E, Tattersall RS, Manson JJ, HLH Across Speciality Collaboration, UK COVID-19: consider cytokine storm syndromes and immunosuppression. Lancet. 2020;395:1033&#x2013;1034. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30628-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30628-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meizlish ML, Pine AB, Bishai JD, Goshua G, Nadelmann ER, Simonov M, Chang C-H, Zhang H, Shallow M, Bahel P, Owusu K, Yamamoto Y, Arora T, Atri DS, Patel A, Gbyli R, Kwan J, Won CH, Dela Cruz C, Price C, Koff J, King BA, Rinder HM, Wilson FP, Hwa J, Halene S, Damsky W, van Dijk D, Lee AI, Chun HJ. A neutrophil activation signature predicts critical illness and mortality in COVID-19. Blood Advances. 2021;5:1164&#x2013;1177. doi: 10.1182/bloodadvances.2020003568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2020003568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7908851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33635335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merad M, Martin JC. Pathological inflammation in patients with COVID-19: a key role for monocytes and Macrophages. Nature Reviews Immunology. 2020;20:355&#x2013;362. doi: 10.1038/s41577-020-0331-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-020-0331-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7201395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32376901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merad M, Subramanian A, Wang TT. An aberrant inflammatory response in severe COVID-19. Cell Host &amp; Microbe. 2021;29:1043&#x2013;1047. doi: 10.1016/j.chom.2021.06.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chom.2021.06.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8279571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merad M, Blish CA, Sallusto F, Iwasaki A. The Immunology and Immunopathology of COVID-19. Science. 2022;375:1122&#x2013;1127. doi: 10.1126/science.abm8108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abm8108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35271343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middleton EA, He XY, Denorme F, Campbell RA, Ng D, Salvatore SP, Mostyka M, Baxter-Stoltzfus A, Borczuk AC, Loda M, Cody MJ, Manne BK, Portier I, Harris ES, Petrey AC, Beswick EJ, Caulin AF, Iovino A, Abegglen LM, Weyrich AS, Rondina MT, Egeblad M, Schiffman JD, Yost CC. Neutrophil extracellular traps contribute to Immunothrombosis in COVID-19 acute respiratory distress syndrome. Blood. 2020;136:1169&#x2013;1179. doi: 10.1182/blood.2020007008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.2020007008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7472714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32597954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra PK, Bruiners N, Ukey R, Datta P, Onyuka A, Handler D, Hussain S, Honnen W, Singh S, Guerrini V, Yin Y, Dewald H, Choudhary A, Horton DB, Barrett ES, Roy J, Weiss SH, Fitzgerald-Bocarsly P, Blaser MJ, Carson JL, Panettieri RA, Lardizabal A, Chang TLY, Pinter A, Gennaro ML. Vaccination BOOSTS Protective Responses and Counters SARS-Cov-2-Induced Pathogenic Memory B Cells. medRxiv. 2021 doi: 10.1101/2021.04.11.21255153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.04.11.21255153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moody R, Sonda S, Johnston FH, Smith KJ, Stephens N, McPherson M, Flanagan KL, Plebanski M. Antibodies against spike protein correlate with broad Autoantigen recognition 8 months post SARS-Cov-2 exposure, and anti-Calprotectin Autoantibodies associated with better clinical outcomes. Frontiers in Immunology. 2022;13:945021. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2022.945021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.945021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9403331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36032086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreews M, Gouge KL, Khaldi-Plassart S, Pescarmona R, Mathieu AL, Malcus C, Djebali S, Bellomo A, Dauwalder O, Perret M, Villard M, Chopin E, Rouvet I, Vandenesh F, Dupieux C, Pouyau R, Teyssedre S, Guerder M, Louazon T, Moulin-Zinsch A, Duperril M, Patural H, Giovannini-Chami L, Portefaix A, Kassai B, Venet F, Monneret G, Lombard C, Flodrops H, Guillebon JMD, Bajolle F, Launay V, Bastard P, Zhang SY, Dubois V, Thaunat O, Richard JC, Mezidi M, Allatif O, Saker K, Dreux M, Abel L, Casanova JL, Marvel J, Trouillet-Assant S, Klatzmann D, Walzer T, Mariotti-Ferrandiz E, Javouhey E, Belot A. Polyclonal expansion of TCR Vbeta 21.3(+) Cd4(+) and Cd8(+) T cells is a hallmark of Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children. Science Immunology. 2021;6:59</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8815705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34035116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss P. The T cell immune response against SARS-Cov-2. Nature Immunology. 2022;23:186&#x2013;193. doi: 10.1038/s41590-021-01122-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-021-01122-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng H, Havervall S, Rosell A, Aguilera K, Parv K, von Meijenfeldt FA, Lisman T, Mackman N, Th&#xe5;lin C, Phillipson M. Circulating markers of neutrophil extracellular traps are of Prognostic value in patients with COVID-19. Arteriosclerosis, Thrombosis, and Vascular Biology. 2021;41:988&#x2013;994. doi: 10.1161/ATVBAHA.120.315267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/ATVBAHA.120.315267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33267662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen SCA, Yang F, Jackson KJL, Hoh RA, R&#xf6;ltgen K, Jean GH, Stevens BA, Lee J-Y, Rustagi A, Rogers AJ, Powell AE, Hunter M, Najeeb J, Otrelo-Cardoso AR, Yost KE, Daniel B, Nadeau KC, Chang HY, Satpathy AT, Jardetzky TS, Kim PS, Wang TT, Pinsky BA, Blish CA, Boyd SD. Human B cell Clonal expansion and Convergent antibody responses to SARS-Cov-2. Cell Host &amp; Microbe. 2020;28:516&#x2013;525. doi: 10.1016/j.chom.2020.09.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chom.2020.09.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7470783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32941787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noval Rivas M, Porritt RA, Cheng MH, Bahar I, Arditi M. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children and long COVID: the SARS-Cov-2 viral Superantigen hypothesis. Frontiers in Immunology. 2022;13:941009. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2022.941009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.941009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9300823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35874696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BK, Francisco EB, Yogendra R, Long E, Pise A, Rodrigues H, Hall E, Herrera M, Parikh P, Guevara-Coto J, Triche TJ, Scott P, Hekmati S, Maglinte D, Chang X, Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez RA, Mora J. Persistence of SARS Cov-2 S1 protein in Cd16+ monocytes in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) up to 15 months post-infection. Frontiers in Immunology. 2021;12:746021. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2021.746021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.746021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8784688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deitchman AN, Torres L, Iyer NS, Munter SE, Nixon CC, Donatelli J, Thanh C, Takahashi S, Hakim J, Turcios K, Janson O, Hoh R, Tai V, Hernandez Y, Fehrman EA, Spinelli MA, Gandhi M, Trinh L, Wrin T, Petropoulos CJ, Aweeka FT, Rodriguez-Barraquer I, Kelly JD, Martin JN, Deeks SG, Greenhouse B, Rutishauser RL, Henrich TJ. Long-term SARS-Cov-2-specific immune and inflammatory responses in individuals recovering from COVID-19 with and without post-acute symptoms. Cell Reports. 2021a;36:109518. doi: 10.1016/j.celrep.2021.109518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.celrep.2021.109518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8342976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34358460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Lu S, Tang AF, Durstenfeld MS, Ho H-E, Goldberg SA, Forman CA, Munter SE, Hoh R, Tai V, Chenna A, Yee BC, Winslow JW, Petropoulos CJ, Greenhouse B, Hunt PW, Hsue PY, Martin JN, Daniel Kelly J, Glidden DV, Deeks SG, Henrich TJ. Markers of immune activation and inflammation in individuals with Postacute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome Coronavirus 2 infection. The Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2021b;224:1839&#x2013;1848. doi: 10.1093/infdis/jiab490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiab490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8643408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34677601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deveau TM, Munter SE, Ryder D, Buck A, Beck-Engeser G, Chan F, Lu S, Goldberg SA, Hoh R, Tai V, Torres L, Iyer NS, Deswal M, Ngo LH, Buitrago M, Rodriguez A, Chen JY, Yee BC, Chenna A, Winslow JW, Petropoulos CJ, Deitchman AN, Hellmuth J, Spinelli MA, Durstenfeld MS, Hsue PY, Kelly JD, Martin JN, Deeks SG, Hunt PW, Henrich TJ. Impact of pre-existing chronic viral infection and reactivation on the development of long COVID. medRxiv. 2022a doi: 10.1101/2022.06.21.22276660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2022.06.21.22276660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Thomas IJ, Munter SE, Deeks SG, Henrich TJ. Lack of Antinuclear antibodies in Convalescent Coronavirus disease 2019 patients with persistent symptoms. Clinical Infectious Diseases. 2022b;74:2083&#x2013;2084. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciab890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9187313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34617982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Mitchell A, Wang CY, Takahashi S, Hoh R, Tai V, Durstenfeld MS, Hsue PY, Kelly JD, Martin JN, Wilson MR, Greenhouse B, Deeks SG, DeRisi JL, Henrich TJ. Low prevalence of interferon &#x391; Autoantibodies in people experiencing symptoms of post-Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) conditions, or long COVID. The Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2023;227:246&#x2013;250. doi: 10.1093/infdis/jiac372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiac372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9494362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36089700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perico L, Benigni A, Casiraghi F, Ng LFP, Renia L, Remuzzi G. Immunity, endothelial injury and complement-induced Coagulopathy in COVID-19. Nature Reviews. Nephrology. 2021;17:46&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1038/s41581-020-00357-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41581-020-00357-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7570423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33077917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB, Howe A, Munier CML, Patel SK, Juno JA, Burrell LM, Kent SJ, Dore GJ, Kelleher AD, Matthews GV. Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-Cov-2 infection. Nature Immunology. 2022;23:210&#x2013;216. doi: 10.1038/s41590-021-01113-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-021-01113-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popescu I, Snyder ME, Iasella CJ, Hannan SJ, Koshy R, Burke R, Das A, Brown MJ, Lyons EJ, Lieber SC, Chen X, Sembrat JC, Bhatt P, Deng E, An X, Linstrum K, Kitsios G, Konstantinidis I, Saul M, Kass DJ, Alder JK, Chen BB, Lendermon EA, Kilaru S, Johnson B, Pilewski JM, Kiss JE, Wells AH, Morris A, McVerry BJ, McMahon DK, Triulzi DJ, Chen K, Sanchez PG, McDyer JF. Cd4(+) T-cell dysfunction in severe COVID-19 disease is tumor necrosis factor-&#x391;/tumor necrosis factor receptor 1-dependent. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine. 2022;205:1403&#x2013;1418. doi: 10.1164/rccm.202111-2493OC.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202111-2493OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9875894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35348444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porritt RA, Binek A, Paschold L, Rivas MN, McArdle A, Yonker LM, Alter G, Chandnani HK, Lopez M, Fasano A, Van Eyk JE, Binder M, Arditi M. The autoimmune signature of Hyperinflammatory Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children. Journal of Clinical Investigation. 2021;131:20. doi: 10.1172/JCI151520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI151520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8516454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34437303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radermecker C, Detrembleur N, Guiot J, Cavalier E, Henket M, d&#x2019;Emal C, Vanwinge C, Cataldo D, Oury C, Delvenne P, Marichal T. Neutrophil extracellular traps infiltrate the lung airway, interstitial, and vascular compartments in severe COVID-19. The Journal of Experimental Medicine. 2020;217:12. doi: 10.1084/jem.20201012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1084/jem.20201012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7488867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32926097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reese JT, Blau H, Casiraghi E, Bergquist T, Loomba JJ, Callahan TJ, Laraway B, Antonescu C, Coleman B, Gargano M, Wilkins KJ, Cappelletti L, Fontana T, Ammar N, Antony B, Murali TM, Caufield JH, Karlebach G, McMurry JA, Williams A, Moffitt R, Banerjee J, Solomonides AE, Davis H, Kostka K, Valentini G, Sahner D, Chute CG, Madlock-Brown C, Haendel MA, Robinson PN, Consortium NC, Consortium R. Generalisable long COVID subtypes: findings from the NIH N3C and RECOVER programmes. EBioMedicine. 2023;87:104413. doi: 10.1016/j.ebiom.2022.104413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2022.104413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9769411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36563487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson WH, Steinman L. Epstein-Barr virus and multiple sclerosis. Science. 2022;375:264&#x2013;265. doi: 10.1126/science.abm7930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abm7930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35025606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;ltgen K, Nielsen SCA, Silva O, Younes SF, Zaslavsky M, Costales C, Yang F, Wirz OF, Solis D, Hoh RA, Wang A, Arunachalam PS, Colburg D, Zhao S, Haraguchi E, Lee AS, Shah MM, Manohar M, Chang I, Gao F, Mallajosyula V, Li C, Liu J, Shoura MJ, Sindher SB, Parsons E, Dashdorj NJ, Dashdorj ND, Monroe R, Serrano GE, Beach TG, Chinthrajah RS, Charville GW, Wilbur JL, Wohlstadter JN, Davis MM, Pulendran B, Troxell ML, Sigal GB, Natkunam Y, Pinsky BA, Nadeau KC, Boyd SD. Immune Imprinting, breadth of variant recognition, and germinal center response in human SARS-Cov-2 infection and vaccination. Cell. 2022;185:1025&#x2013;1040. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2022.01.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2022.01.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35148837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rydyznski Moderbacher C, Ramirez SI, Dan JM, Grifoni A, Hastie KM, Weiskopf D, Belanger S, Abbott RK, Kim C, Choi J, Kato Y, Crotty EG, Kim C, Rawlings SA, Mateus J, Tse LPV, Frazier A, Baric R, Peters B, Greenbaum J, Ollmann Saphire E, Smith DM, Sette A, Crotty S. Antigen-specific adaptive immunity to SARS-Cov-2 in acute COVID-19 and associations with age and disease severity. Cell. 2020;183:996&#x2013;1012. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2020.09.038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.09.038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7494270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33010815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacco K, Castagnoli R, Vakkilainen S, Liu C, Delmonte OM, Oguz C, Kaplan IM, Alehashemi S, Burbelo PD, Bhuyan F, de Jesus AA, Dobbs K, Rosen LB, Cheng A, Shaw E, Vakkilainen MS, Pala F, Lack J, Zhang Y, Fink DL, Oikonomou V, Snow AL, Dalgard CL, Chen J, Sellers BA, Montealegre Sanchez GA, Barron K, Rey-Jurado E, Vial C, Poli MC, Licari A, Montagna D, Marseglia GL, Licciardi F, Ramenghi U, Discepolo V, Lo Vecchio A, Guarino A, Eisenstein EM, Imberti L, Sottini A, Biondi A, Mat&#xf3; S, Gerstbacher D, Truong M, Stack MA, Magliocco M, Bosticardo M, Kawai T, Danielson JJ, Hulett T, Askenazi M, Hu S, NIAID Immune Response to COVID Group. Barnett J, Cheng X, Kaladi K, Kuram V, Mackey J, Bansal NM, Martins AJ, Palterer B, Matthews H, Mudunuri U, Nambiar M, Oler AJ, Rastegar A, Samuel S, Shyu C, Waingankar V, Weber S, Xirasagar S, Chile MIS-C Group. Espinosa Y, Astudillo C, Pi&#xf1;era C, Gonz&#xe1;lez R, Pavia Pediatric COVID-19 Group. De Filippo M, Votto M, Montagna L, Cohen JI, Su HC, Kuhns DB, Lionakis MS, Snyder TM, Holland SM, Goldbach-Mansky R, Tsang JS, Notarangelo LD. Immunopathological signatures in Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children and pediatric COVID-19. Nature Medicine. 2022;28:1050&#x2013;1062. doi: 10.1038/s41591-022-01724-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01724-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9119950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35177862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulert GS, Grom AA. Pathogenesis of macrophage activation syndrome and potential for Cytokine- directed therapies. Annual Review of Medicine. 2015;66:145&#x2013;159. doi: 10.1146/annurev-med-061813-012806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-med-061813-012806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5846123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25386930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultze JL, Aschenbrenner AC. COVID-19 and the human innate immune system. Cell. 2021;184:1671&#x2013;1692. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2021.02.029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2021.02.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7885626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33743212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>See&#xdf;le J, Waterboer T, Hippchen T, Simon J, Kirchner M, Lim A, M&#xfc;ller B, Merle U. Persistent symptoms in adult patients 1 year after Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): A prospective cohort study. Clinical Infectious Diseases. 2022;74:1191&#x2013;1198. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciab611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34223884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sefik E, Qu R, Junqueira C, Kaffe E, Mirza H, Zhao J, Brewer JR, Han A, Steach HR, Israelow B, Blackburn HN, Velazquez SE, Chen YG, Halene S, Iwasaki A, Meffre E, Nussenzweig M, Lieberman J, Wilen CB, Kluger Y, Flavell RA. Inflammasome activation in infected Macrophages drives COVID-19 pathology. Nature. 2022;606:585&#x2013;593. doi: 10.1038/s41586-022-04802-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-022-04802-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9288243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35483404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekine T, Perez-Potti A, Rivera-Ballesteros O, Str&#xe5;lin K, Gorin J-B, Olsson A, Llewellyn-Lacey S, Kamal H, Bogdanovic G, Muschiol S, Wullimann DJ, Kammann T, Emg&#xe5;rd J, Parrot T, Folkesson E, Rooyackers O, Eriksson LI, Henter J-I, S&#xf6;nnerborg A, Allander T, Albert J, Nielsen M, Klingstr&#xf6;m J, Gredmark-Russ S, Bj&#xf6;rkstr&#xf6;m NK, Sandberg JK, Price DA, Ljunggren H-G, Aleman S, Buggert M, Akber M, Berglin L, Bergsten H, Brighenti S, Brownlie D, Butrym M, Chambers B, Chen P, Jeannin MC, Grip J, Gomez AC, Dillner L, Lozano ID, Dzidic M, Tullberg MF, F&#xe4;rnert A, Glans H, Haroun-Izquierdo A, Henriksson E, Hertwig L, Kalsum S, Kokkinou E, Kvedaraite E, Loreti M, Lourda M, Maleki K, Malmberg K-J, Marquardt N, Maucourant C, Michaelsson J, Mj&#xf6;sberg J, Moll K, Muva J, M&#xe5;rtensson J, Naucl&#xe9;r P, Norrby-Teglund A, Medina LP, Persson B, Radler L, Ringqvist E, Sandberg JT, Sohlberg E, Soini T, Svensson M, Tynell J, Varnaite R, Kries AV, Unge C. Robust T cell immunity in Convalescent individuals with asymptomatic or mild COVID-19. Cell. 2020;183:158&#x2013;168. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2020.08.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.08.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32979941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sette A, Crotty S. Adaptive immunity to SARS-Cov-2 and COVID-19. Cell. 2021;184:861&#x2013;880. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2021.01.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2021.01.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7803150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah S, Danda D, Kavadichanda C, Das S, Adarsh MB, Negi VS. Autoimmune and rheumatic musculoskeletal diseases as a consequence of SARS-Cov-2 infection and its treatment. Rheumatology International. 2020;40:1539&#x2013;1554. doi: 10.1007/s00296-020-04639-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00296-020-04639-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7360125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32666137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherif ZA, Gomez CR, Connors TJ, Henrich TJ, Reeves WB, Force RMPT. Pathogenic mechanisms of post-acute sequelae of SARS-Cov-2 infection (PASC. eLife. 2023;12:e86002. doi: 10.7554/eLife.86002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.86002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10032659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36947108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqi HK, Mehra MR. COVID-19 illness in native and immunosuppressed States: A clinical-therapeutic staging proposal. The Journal of Heart and Lung Transplantation. 2020;39:405&#x2013;407. doi: 10.1016/j.healun.2020.03.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.healun.2020.03.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32362390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvin A, Chapuis N, Dunsmore G, Goubet A-G, Dubuisson A, Derosa L, Almire C, H&#xe9;non C, Kosmider O, Droin N, Rameau P, Catelain C, Alfaro A, Dussiau C, Friedrich C, Sourdeau E, Marin N, Szwebel T-A, Cantin D, Mouthon L, Borderie D, Deloger M, Bredel D, Mouraud S, Drubay D, Andrieu M, Lhonneur A-S, Saada V, Stoclin A, Willekens C, Pommeret F, Griscelli F, Ng LG, Zhang Z, Bost P, Amit I, Barlesi F, Marabelle A, P&#xe8;ne F, Gachot B, Andr&#xe9; F, Zitvogel L, Ginhoux F, Fontenay M, Solary E. Elevated Calprotectin and abnormal myeloid cell Subsets discriminate severe from mild COVID-19. Cell. 2020;182:1401&#x2013;1418. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2020.08.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.08.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7405878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32810439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha S, Rosin NL, Arora R, Labit E, Jaffer A, Cao L, Farias R, Nguyen AP, de Almeida LGN, Dufour A, Bromley A, McDonald B, Gillrie MR, Fritzler MJ, Yipp BG, Biernaskie J. Dexamethasone modulates immature neutrophils and interferon programming in severe COVID-19. Nature Medicine. 2022;28:201&#x2013;211. doi: 10.1038/s41591-021-01576-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01576-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8799469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34782790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skendros P, Mitsios A, Chrysanthopoulou A, Mastellos DC, Metallidis S, Rafailidis P, Ntinopoulou M, Sertaridou E, Tsironidou V, Tsigalou C, Tektonidou M, Konstantinidis T, Papagoras C, Mitroulis I, Germanidis G, Lambris JD, Ritis K. Complement and tissue factor-enriched neutrophil extracellular traps are key drivers in COVID-19 Immunothrombosis. The Journal of Clinical Investigation. 2020;130:6151&#x2013;6157. doi: 10.1172/JCI141374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI141374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7598040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song JW, Zhang C, Fan X, Meng FP, Xu Z, Xia P, Cao WJ, Yang T, Dai XP, Wang SY, Xu RN, Jiang TJ, Li WG, Zhang DW, Zhao P, Shi M, Agrati C, Ippolito G, Maeurer M, Zumla A, Wang FS, Zhang JY. Immunological and inflammatory profiles in mild and severe cases of COVID-19. Nature Communications. 2020;11:3410. doi: 10.1038/s41467-020-17240-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-17240-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7343781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32641700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, Ng RH, Wang K, Choi J, Li S, Hong S, Zhang R, Xie J, Kornilov SA, Scherler K, Pavlovitch-Bedzyk AJ, Dong S, Lausted C, Lee I, Fallen S, Dai CL, Baloni P, Smith B, Duvvuri VR, Anderson KG, Li J, Yang F, Duncombe CJ, McCulloch DJ, Rostomily C, Troisch P, Zhou J, Mackay S, DeGottardi Q, May DH, Taniguchi R, Gittelman RM, Klinger M, Snyder TM, Roper R, Wojciechowska G, Murray K, Edmark R, Evans S, Jones L, Zhou Y, Rowen L, Liu R, Chour W, Algren HA, Berrington WR, Wallick JA, Cochran RA, Micikas ME, Wrin T, Petropoulos CJ, Cole HR, Fischer TD, Wei W, Hoon DSB, Price ND, Subramanian N, Hill JA, Hadlock J, Magis AT, Ribas A, Lanier LL, Boyd SD, Bluestone JA, Chu H, Hood L, Gottardo R, Greenberg PD, Davis MM, Goldman JD, Heath JR. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185:881&#x2013;895. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2022.01.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2022.01.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanson KV, Deng M, Ting JP-Y. The Nlrp3 Inflammasome: molecular activation and regulation to Therapeutics. Nature Reviews. Immunology. 2019;19:477&#x2013;489. doi: 10.1038/s41577-019-0165-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-019-0165-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7807242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31036962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szewczykowski C, Mardin C, Lucio M, Wallukat G, Hoffmanns J, Schr&#xf6;der T, Raith F, Rogge L, Heltmann F, Moritz M, Beitlich L, Schottenhamml J, Herrmann M, Harrer T, Ganslmayer M, Kruse FE, Kr&#xe4;ter M, Guck J, L&#xe4;mmer R, Zenkel M, Gie&#xdf;l A, Hohberger B. Long COVID: Association of functional Autoantibodies against G-protein-coupled receptors with an impaired retinal Microcirculation. International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 2022;23:7209. doi: 10.3390/ijms23137209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23137209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9266742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35806214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan AT, Linster M, Tan CW, Le Bert N, Chia WN, Kunasegaran K, Zhuang Y, Tham CYL, Chia A, Smith GJD, Young B, Kalimuddin S, Low JGH, Lye D, Wang L-F, Bertoletti A. Early induction of functional SARS-Cov-2-specific T cells Associates with rapid viral clearance and mild disease in COVID-19 patients. Cell Reports. 2021;34:108728. doi: 10.1016/j.celrep.2021.108728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.celrep.2021.108728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7826084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33516277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton CM, Fucile CF, Darce J, Chida A, Ichikawa T, Gregoretti I, Schieferl S, Hom J, Jenks S, Feldman RJ, Mehr R, Wei C, Lee FE-H, Cheung WC, Rosenberg AF, Sanz I. Diversity, cellular origin and Autoreactivity of antibody-Secreting cell population expansions in acute systemic lupus erythematosus. Nature Immunology. 2015;16:755&#x2013;765. doi: 10.1038/ni.3175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ni.3175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4512288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26006014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twaddell SH, Baines KJ, Grainge C, Gibson PG. The emerging role of neutrophil extracellular traps in respiratory disease. Chest. 2019;156:774&#x2013;782. doi: 10.1016/j.chest.2019.06.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2019.06.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31265835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valent P, Akin C, Arock M, Brockow K, Butterfield JH, Carter MC, Castells M, Escribano L, Hartmann K, Lieberman P, Nedoszytko B, Orfao A, Schwartz LB, Sotlar K, Sperr WR, Triggiani M, Valenta R, Horny HP, Metcalfe DD. Definitions, criteria and global classification of mast cell disorders with special reference to mast cell activation syndromes: a consensus proposal. International Archives of Allergy and Immunology. 2012;157:215&#x2013;225. doi: 10.1159/000328760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000328760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3224511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22041891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderbeke L, Van Mol P, Van Herck Y, De Smet F, Humblet-Baron S, Martinod K, Antoranz A, Arijs I, Boeckx B, Bosisio FM, Casaer M, Dauwe D, De Wever W, Dooms C, Dreesen E, Emmaneel A, Filtjens J, Gouwy M, Gunst J, Hermans G, Jansen S, Lagrou K, Liston A, Lorent N, Meersseman P, Mercier T, Neyts J, Odent J, Panovska D, Penttila PA, Pollet E, Proost P, Qian J, Quintelier K, Raes J, Rex S, Saeys Y, Sprooten J, Tejpar S, Testelmans D, Thevissen K, Van Buyten T, Vandenhaute J, Van Gassen S, Vel&#xe1;squez Pereira LC, Vos R, Weynand B, Wilmer A, Yserbyt J, Garg AD, Matthys P, Wouters C, Lambrechts D, Wauters E, Wauters J. Monocyte-driven atypical cytokine storm and aberrant neutrophil activation as key mediators of COVID-19 disease severity. Nature Communications. 2021;12:4117. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-24360-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-24360-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8257697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34226537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Ploeg K, Kirosingh AS, Mori DAM, Chakraborty S, Hu Z, Sievers BL, Jacobson KB, Bonilla H, Parsonnet J, Andrews JR, Press KD, Ty MC, Ruiz-Betancourt DR, de la Parte L, Tan GS, Blish CA, Takahashi S, Rodriguez-Barraquer I, Greenhouse B, Singh U, Wang TT, Jagannathan P. TNF-&#x391;(+) Cd4(+) T cells dominate the SARS-Cov-2 specific T cell response in COVID-19 outpatients and are associated with durable antibodies. Cell Reports Medicine. 2022;3:100640. doi: 10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9061140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35588734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vannella KM, Oguz C, Stein SR, Pittaluga S, Dikoglu E, Kanwal A, Ramelli SC, Briese T, Su L, Wu X, Ramos-Benitez MJ, Perez-Valencia LJ, Babyak A, Cha NR, Chung JY, Ylaya K, Madathil RJ, Saharia KK, Scalea TM, Tran QK, Herr DL, Kleiner DE, Hewitt SM, Notarangelo LD, Grazioli A, Chertow DS. Evidence of SARS-Cov-2-specific T-cell-mediated myocarditis in a MIS-A case. Frontiers in Immunology. 2021;12:779026. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2021.779026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.779026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8695925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34956207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veras FP, Pontelli MC, Silva CM, Toller-Kawahisa JE, de Lima M, Nascimento DC, Schneider AH, Caetit&#xe9; D, Tavares LA, Paiva IM, Rosales R, Col&#xf3;n D, Martins R, Castro IA, Almeida GM, Lopes MIF, Benatti MN, Bonjorno LP, Giannini MC, Luppino-Assad R, Almeida SL, Vilar F, Santana R, Bollela VR, Auxiliadora-Martins M, Borges M, Miranda CH, Pazin-Filho A, da Silva LLP, Cunha LD, Zamboni DS, Dal-Pizzol F, Leiria LO, Siyuan L, Batah S, Fabro A, Mauad T, Dolhnikoff M, Duarte-Neto A, Saldiva P, Cunha TM, Alves-Filho JC, Arruda E, Louzada-Junior P, Oliveira RD, Cunha FQ. SARS-Cov-2-triggered neutrophil extracellular traps mediate COVID-19 pathology. Journal of Experimental Medicine. 2020;217:12. doi: 10.1084/jem.20201129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1084/jem.20201129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7488868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32926098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayakumar B, Boustani K, Ogger PP, Papadaki A, Tonkin J, Orton CM, Ghai P, Suveizdyte K, Hewitt RJ, Desai SR, Devaraj A, Snelgrove RJ, Molyneaux PL, Garner JL, Peters JE, Shah PL, Lloyd CM, Harker JA. Immuno-Proteomic profiling reveals aberrant immune cell regulation in the Airways of individuals with ongoing post-COVID-19 respiratory disease. Immunity. 2022;55:542&#x2013;556. doi: 10.1016/j.immuni.2022.01.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2022.01.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8789571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35151371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vora SM, Lieberman J, Wu H. Inflammasome activation at the crux of severe COVID-19. Nature Reviews. Immunology. 2021;21:694&#x2013;703. doi: 10.1038/s41577-021-00588-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-021-00588-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8351223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallukat G, Hohberger B, Wenzel K, F&#xfc;rst J, Schulze-Rothe S, Wallukat A, H&#xf6;nicke A-S, M&#xfc;ller J. Functional Autoantibodies against G-protein coupled receptors in patients with persistent long-COVID-19 symptoms. Journal of Translational Autoimmunity. 2021;4:100100. doi: 10.1016/j.jtauto.2021.100100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtauto.2021.100100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8049853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33880442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang EY, Mao T, Klein J, Dai Y, Huck JD, Jaycox JR, Liu F, Zhou T, Israelow B, Wong P, Coppi A, Lucas C, Silva J, Oh JE, Song E, Perotti ES, Zheng NS, Fischer S, Campbell M, Fournier JB, Wyllie AL, Vogels CBF, Ott IM, Kalinich CC, Petrone ME, Watkins AE, Yale IMPACT Team. Obaid A, Moore AJ, Casanovas-Massana A, Lu-Culligan A, Nelson A, Nunez A, Martin A, Geng B, Odio CD, Harden CA, Todeasa C, Jensen C, Kim D, McDonald D, Shepard D, Courchaine E, White EB, Silva E, Kudo E, DeIuliis G, Rahming H, Park H-J, Matos I, Nouws J, Valdez J, Lim J, Rose K-A, Anastasio K, Brower K, Glick L, Sharma L, Sewanan L, Knaggs L, Minasyan M, Batsu M, Kuang M, Nakahata M, Linehan M, Askenase MH, Simonov M, Smolgovsky M, Sonnert N, Naushad N, Vijayakumar P, Martinello R, Datta R, Handoko R, Bermejo S, Prophet S, Bickerton S, Velazquez S, Rice T, Khoury-Hanold W, Peng X, Yang Y, Cao Y, Strong Y, Dela Cruz C, Farhadian SF, Schulz WL, Ma S, Grubaugh ND, Ko AI, Iwasaki A, Ring AM. Diverse functional Autoantibodies in patients with COVID-19. Nature. 2021;595:283&#x2013;288. doi: 10.1038/s41586-021-03631-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-021-03631-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34010947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Sanborn MA, Dai Y, Rehman J. Temporal Transcriptomic analysis using Trendcatcher identifies early and persistent neutrophil activation in severe COVID-19. JCI Insight. 2022;7:e157255. doi: 10.1172/jci.insight.157255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci.insight.157255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9057597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35175937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wechsler JB, Butuci M, Wong A, Kamboj AP, Youngblood BA. Mast cell activation is associated with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Allergy. 2022;77:1288&#x2013;1291. doi: 10.1111/all.15188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/all.15188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9299596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34820848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstock LB, Brook JB, Walters AS, Goris A, Afrin LB, Molderings GJ. Mast cell activation symptoms are prevalent in long-COVID. International Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2021;112:217&#x2013;226. doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2021.09.043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2021.09.043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34563706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiech M, Chroscicki P, Swatler J, Stepnik D, De Biasi S, Hampel M, Brewinska-Olchowik M, Maliszewska A, Sklinda K, Durlik M, Wierzba W, Cossarizza A, Piwocka K. Remodeling of T cell Dynamics during long COVID is dependent on severity of SARS-Cov-2 infection. Frontiers in Immunology. 2022;13:886431. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2022.886431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.886431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9226563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35757700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winchester N, Calabrese C, Calabrese LH. The intersection of COVID-19 and Autoimmunity: what is our current understanding. Pathogens &amp; Immunity. 2021;6:31&#x2013;54. doi: 10.20411/pai.v6i1.417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20411/pai.v6i1.417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8097827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33969248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodruff MC, Ramonell RP, Nguyen DC, Cashman KS, Saini AS, Haddad NS, Ley AM, Kyu S, Howell JC, Ozturk T, Lee S, Suryadevara N, Case JB, Bugrovsky R, Chen W, Estrada J, Morrison-Porter A, Derrico A, Anam FA, Sharma M, Wu HM, Le SN, Jenks SA, Tipton CM, Staitieh B, Daiss JL, Ghosn E, Diamond MS, Carnahan RH, Crowe JE, Hu WT, Lee FE-H, Sanz I. Extrafollicular B cell responses correlate with neutralizing antibodies and morbidity in COVID-19. Nature Immunology. 2020;21:1506&#x2013;1516. doi: 10.1038/s41590-020-00814-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-020-00814-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33028979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodruff MC, Nguyen DC, Faliti CE, Saini AS, Lee FE-H, Sanz I. Response under pressure: deploying emerging technologies to understand B-cell-mediated immunity in COVID-19. Nature Methods. 2022;19:387&#x2013;391. doi: 10.1038/s41592-022-01450-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41592-022-01450-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9703369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35396475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia H, Shi PY. Antagonism of type I interferon by severe acute respiratory syndrome Coronavirus 2. Journal of Interferon &amp; Cytokine Research. 2020;40:543&#x2013;548. doi: 10.1089/jir.2020.0214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jir.2020.0214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7757701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33337934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacharias H, Dubey S, Koduri G, D&#x2019;Cruz D. Rheumatological complications of Covid 19. Autoimmunity Reviews. 2021;20:102883. doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2021.102883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2021.102883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8256657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34237419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Bastard P, Cobat A, Casanova J-L, COVID Human Genetic Effort Human genetic and immunological determinants of critical COVID-19 pneumonia. Nature. 2022;603:587&#x2013;598. doi: 10.1038/s41586-022-04447-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-022-04447-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8957595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35090163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Fu B, Zheng X, Wang D, Zhao C, Qi Y, Sun R, Tian Z, Xu X, Wei H. Pathogenic T-cells and inflammatory monocytes incite inflammatory storms in severe COVID-19 patients. National Science Review. 2020a;7:998&#x2013;1002. doi: 10.1093/nsr/nwaa041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nsr/nwaa041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7108005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34676125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Han T, Chen J, Hou C, Hua L, He S, Guo Y, Zhang S, Wang Y, Yuan J, Zhao C, Zhang J, Jia Q, Zuo X, Li J, Wang L, Cao Q, Jia E. Clinical and autoimmune characteristics of severe and critical cases of COVID-19. Clinical and Translational Science. 2020b;13:1077&#x2013;1086. doi: 10.1111/cts.12805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cts.12805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32315487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Y, Yalavarthi S, Shi H, Gockman K, Zuo M, Madison JA, Blair CN, Weber A, Barnes BJ, Egeblad M, Woods RJ, Kanthi Y, Knight JS. Neutrophil extracellular traps in COVID-19. JCI Insight. 2020;5:e138999. doi: 10.1172/jci.insight.138999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci.insight.138999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7308057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32329756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo J, Dowell AC, Pearce H, Verma K, Long HM, Begum J, Aiano F, Amin-Chowdhury Z, Hoschler K, Brooks T, Taylor S, Hewson J, Hallis B, Stapley L, Borrow R, Linley E, Ahmad S, Parker B, Horsley A, Amirthalingam G, Brown K, Ramsay ME, Ladhani S, Moss P. Robust SARS-Cov-2-specific T cell immunity is maintained at 6 months following primary infection. Nature Immunology. 2021a;22:620&#x2013;626. doi: 10.1038/s41590-021-00902-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-021-00902-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7610739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33674800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Y, Yalavarthi S, Navaz SA, Hoy CK, Harbaugh A, Gockman K, Zuo M, Madison JA, Shi H, Kanthi Y, Knight JS. Autoantibodies stabilize neutrophil extracellular traps in COVID-19. JCI Insight. 2021b;6:15. doi: 10.1172/jci.insight.150111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci.insight.150111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8410057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34166229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Y, Zuo M, Yalavarthi S, Gockman K, Madison JA, Shi H, Woodard W, Lezak SP, Lugogo NL, Knight JS, Kanthi Y. Neutrophil extracellular traps and thrombosis in COVID-19. Journal of Thrombosis and Thrombolysis. 2021c;51:446&#x2013;453. doi: 10.1007/s11239-020-02324-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11239-020-02324-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7642240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33151461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>