<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38659602</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2220-3206</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Psychiatric outcomes in outpatients affected by long COVID: A link between mental health and persistence of olfactory complaint.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>507</StartPage><EndPage>512</EndPage><MedlinePgn>507-512</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5498/wjp.v14.i4.507</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Anosmia was one of the main symptoms of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). A psychiatric history (<i>i.e.,</i> depression) may be an independent contributor to the risk of COVID-19 diagnosis, and COVID-19 survivors appear to have an increased risk of neuropsychiatric sequelae (bidirectional association).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To compare the rate of psychiatric disorder among post-COVID patients without anosmia <i>vs</i> patients with persistent olfactory complaints.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a prospective case control study from March 2020 to May 2021. Patients recruited at the ENT department of Nice University Hospital had a subjective olfactory complaint (visual analogue scale) for over 6 wk and a molecular or CT-proven severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 diagnosis confirmed by serology. Post-COVID patients without persistent olfactory disorders were recruited at the university hospital infectiology department. Psychiatric medical histories were collected by a psychiatrist during the assessments.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Thirty-four patients with post-COVID-19 olfactory complaints were included in the first group of the study. Fifty percent of the patients were female (<i>n</i> = 17). The group's mean age was 40.5 &#xb1; 12.9 years. The control group included 32 participants, of which 34.4% were female (<i>n</i> = 11), and had a mean age of 61.2 &#xb1; 12.2 years. The rate of psychiatric disorder among post-COVID patients with olfactory complaints was significatively higher (41.7%) than among patients without (18.8%) (<i>&#x3c7;</i><sup>2</sup> = 5.9, <i>P</i> = 0.015).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The presence of a psychiatric history may constitute a potential risk factor for the development of long COVID due to persistent anosmia. It therefore seems important to establish reinforced health monitoring after a COVID 19 infection in at-risk patients. Further prospective, translational, and collaborative studies are needed to extrapolate these results to the general population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2024. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Metelkina-Fernandez</LastName><ForeName>Victoria</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Nice University Hospital, Nice 06000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dumas</LastName><ForeName>Louise-Emilie</ForeName><Initials>LE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Universit&#xe9; C&#xf4;te d'Azur, Nice 06200, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vandersteen</LastName><ForeName>Clair</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ENT, Head and Neck Institute, Nice 06100, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chirio</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectiology, Nice University Hospital, Nice 06200, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gros</LastName><ForeName>Auriane</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthophony, Universit&#xe9; C&#xf4;te d'Azur, Nice 06100, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fernandez</LastName><ForeName>Arnaud</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Universit&#xe9; C&#xf4;te d'Azur, Nice 06200, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cobtek, Universit&#xe9; C&#xf4;te d'Azur, Nice 06100, France. arnaud.fernandez@hpu.lenval.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Askenazy</LastName><ForeName>Florence</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Universit&#xe9; C&#xf4;te d'Azur, Nice 06200, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manera</LastName><ForeName>Valeria</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cobtek, Universit&#xe9; C&#xf4;te d'Azur, Nice 06100, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610480</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2220-3206</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anosmia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroplasticity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychiatric history</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychiatry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: Authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38659602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11036454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5498/wjp.v14.i4.507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhu N, Zhang D, Wang W, Li X, Yang B, Song J, Zhao X, Huang B, Shi W, Lu R, Niu P, Zhan F, Ma X, Wang D, Xu W, Wu G, Gao GF, Tan W China Novel Coronavirus Investigating and Research Team. A Novel Coronavirus from Patients with Pneumonia in China, 2019. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:727&#x2013;733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31978945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechien JR, Chiesa-Estomba CM, Place S, Van Laethem Y, Cabaraux P, Mat Q, Huet K, Plzak J, Horoi M, Hans S, Rosaria Barillari M, Cammaroto G, Fakhry N, Martiny D, Ayad T, Jouffe L, Hopkins C, Saussez S COVID-19 Task Force of YO-IFOS. Clinical and epidemiological characteristics of 1420 European patients with mild-to-moderate coronavirus disease 2019. J Intern Med. 2020;288:335&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32352202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichert JL, Sch&#xf6;pf V. Olfactory Loss and Regain: Lessons for Neuroplasticity. Neuroscientist. 2018;24:22&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28459173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEwen BS. Physiology and neurobiology of stress and adaptation: central role of the brain. Physiol Rev. 2007;87:873&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17615391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Harrison PJ. Bidirectional associations between COVID-19 and psychiatric disorder: retrospective cohort studies of 62&#x2008;354 COVID-19 cases in the USA. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:130&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>6 Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236&#x2009;379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, Myles P, Williams T, Gokhale KM, Taverner T, Chandan JS, Brown K, Simms-Williams N, Shah AD, Singh M, Kidy F, Okoth K, Hotham R, Bashir N, Cockburn N, Lee SI, Turner GM, Gkoutos GV, Aiyegbusi OL, McMullan C, Denniston AK, Sapey E, Lord JM, Wraith DC, Leggett E, Iles C, Marshall T, Price MJ, Marwaha S, Davies EH, Jackson LJ, Matthews KL, Camaradou J, Calvert M, Haroon S. Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat Med. 2022;28:1706&#x2013;1714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEwen BS. Allostasis and the Epigenetics of Brain and Body Health Over the Life Course: The Brain on Stress. JAMA Psychiatry. 2017;74:551&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28445556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J, Radke J, Dittmayer C, Franz J, Thomas C, Mothes R, Laue M, Schneider J, Br&#xfc;nink S, Greuel S, Lehmann M, Hassan O, Aschman T, Schumann E, Chua RL, Conrad C, Eils R, Stenzel W, Windgassen M, R&#xf6;&#xdf;ler L, Goebel HH, Gelderblom HR, Martin H, Nitsche A, Schulz-Schaeffer WJ, Hakroush S, Winkler MS, Tampe B, Scheibe F, K&#xf6;rtv&#xe9;lyessy P, Reinhold D, Siegmund B, K&#xfc;hl AA, Elezkurtaj S, Horst D, Oesterhelweg L, Tsokos M, Ingold-Heppner B, Stadelmann C, Drosten C, Corman VM, Radbruch H, Heppner FL. Olfactory transmucosal SARS-CoV-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with COVID-19. Nat Neurosci. 2021;24:168&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers JP, Chesney E, Oliver D, Pollak TA, McGuire P, Fusar-Poli P, Zandi MS, Lewis G, David AS. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: a systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;7:611&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7234781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molero P, Reina G, Blom JD, Mart&#xed;nez-Gonz&#xe1;lez M&#xc1;, Reinken A, de Kloet ER, Molendijk ML. COVID-19 risk, course and outcome in people with mental disorders: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Epidemiol Psychiatr Sci. 2023;32:e61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10594644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37859501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>