<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39280382</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Autonomic Imbalance and Elevated Inflammatory Cytokines in Long COVID: A Cross-Sectional Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e66971</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e66971</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e66971</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.66971</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Following an infection with SARS-CoV-2, the virus that causes coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), many individuals fully recover. On the other hand, a few have symptoms that last for weeks, months, or even years after their initial diagnosis. Symptoms of COVID-19 persisting for four weeks and more are termed long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess the long-term cardiovascular morbidity by battery of cardiac autonomic function tests as well as the persistence of inflammation in COVID-recovered patients three months after initial infection.&#xa0; Methodology: 150 patients were selected who had recovered from COVID-19 at least three months prior to the study. After obtaining informed written consent, a throat swab was tested for COVID-19, and those with negative reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) results were subjected to autonomic function testing. Serum interleukin-6 and C-reactive protein levels were determined by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Out of 150 subjects 36 were found to have autonomic dysfunction graded according to Ewing's criteria. Individuals with autonomic dysfunction also had significantly increased inflammatory biomarker levels. There was also significant correlation between inflammatory markers and autonomic function test and heart rate variability parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Even years after the COVID-19 pandemic was declared, new symptom patterns and syndromes such as 'long COVID' are appearing.&#xa0;A better understanding of the pathophysiological mechanisms of post-COVID manifestations that affect the autonomic nervous system, as well as customized therapeutic care, should help reduce COVID-19 sequelae, particularly if we act early in the disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Jatiya et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jatiya</LastName><ForeName>Lakshmi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Aarupadai Veedu Medical College and Hospital, Vinayaka Mission's Research Foundation (VMRF), Puducherry, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marie Feula</LastName><ForeName>Jothi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, All India Institute of Medical Sciences Madurai, Madurai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>R</LastName><ForeName>Latha</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Aarupadai Veedu Medical College and Hospital, Vinayaka Mission's Research Foundation (VMRF), Puducherry, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>R</LastName><ForeName>Vidhyalakshmi</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Chettinad Medical College and Hospital, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajesh</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Forensic Medicine and Toxicology, Velammal Medical College Hospital and Research Institute, Madurai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autonomic imbalance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interleukin &#x2013; 6</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long haul covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post covid syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Consent was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Aarupadai Veedu Medical College (AVMC) Institutional Ethics Committee issued approval AV/IEC/2021/016. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39280382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11401969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.66971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dysautonomia in COVID-19 patients: a narrative review on clinical course, diagnostic and therapeutic strategies. Carmona-Torre F, M&#xed;nguez-Olaondo A, L&#xf3;pez-Bravo A, et al. Front Neurol. 2022;13:886609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9198643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35720084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autonomic balance determines the severity of COVID-19 courses. Leitzke M, Stefanovic D, Meyer JJ, Schimpf S, Sch&#xf6;nknecht P. Bioelectron Med. 2020;6:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7683278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33292846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chippa V, Aleem A, Anjum F. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island: StatPearls Publishing; 2024. Postacute coronavirus (COVID-19) syndrome.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The neurological manifestations of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Moghimi N, Di Napoli M, Biller J, et al. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2021;21:44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8237541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34181102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medium-term impact of COVID-19 on pulmonary function, functional capacity and quality of life. Anastasio F, Barbuto S, Scarnecchia E, et al.  https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33574080/ Eur Respir J. 2021;58</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7877327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33574080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of cardiovascular autonomic nervous functions in diabetics: study in a rural teaching hospital. Pathak A, Gupta S, Kumar S, Agrawal S. J Pract Cardiovasc Sci. 2017;3:150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of the degree of agreement of four methods for diagnosing diabetic autonomic neuropathy. Peng Y, Liu YS, Wu MY, et al.  https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fneur.2021.637099. Front Neurol. 2021;12:637099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8185195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34113304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology and clinical characteristics of COVID-19. Huang X, Wei F, Hu L, Wen L, Chen K. Arch Iran Med. 2020;23:268&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32271601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potential role of autonomic dysfunction in COVID-19 morbidity and mortality. Del Rio R, Marcus NJ, Inestrosa NC. Front Physiol. 2020;11:561749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7597395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33178034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 and cardiovascular autonomic dysfunction: what do we know? Bisaccia G, Ricci F, Recce V, et al. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis. 2021;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8621226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34821709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autonomic dysfunction in COVID-19 patients receiving mechanical ventilation: a cross-sectional study. Silva RB, Neves VR, Barros MC, Gambassi BB, Schwingel PA, Sobral Filho DC. Sao Paulo Med J. 2023;141:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10109544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37075456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The interplay between autonomic nervous system and inflammation across systemic autoimmune diseases. Bellocchi C, Carandina A, Montinaro B, et al. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8910153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35269591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>'The long tail of Covid-19' - the detection of a prolonged inflammatory response after a SARS-CoV-2 infection in asymptomatic and mildly affected patients. Doykov I, H&#xe4;llqvist J, Gilmour KC, Grandjean L, Mills K, Heywood WE. F1000Res. 2020;9:1349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7745182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33391730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: mechanisms, risk factors and recovery. Astin R, Banerjee A, Baker MR, et al. Exp Physiol. 2023;108:12&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10103775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36412084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association of elevated inflammatory markers and severe COVID-19: a meta-analysis. Ji P, Zhu J, Zhong Z, Li H, Pang J, Li B, Zhang J. Medicine (Baltimore) 2020;99:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7676531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33217868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>