<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38948732</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2692-8205</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>bioRxiv : the preprint server for biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>bioRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sex differences and immune correlates of Long COVID development, persistence, and resolution.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2024.06.18.599612</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1101/2024.06.18.599612</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sex differences have been observed in acute COVID-19 and Long COVID (LC) outcomes, with greater disease severity and mortality during acute infection in males and a greater proportion of females developing LC. We hypothesized that sex-specific immune dysregulation contributes to the pathogenesis of LC. To investigate the immunologic underpinnings of LC development and persistence, we used single-cell transcriptomics, single-cell proteomics, and plasma proteomics on blood samples obtained during acute SARS-CoV-2 infection and at 3 and 12 months post-infection in a cohort of 45 patients who either developed LC or recovered. Several sex-specific immune pathways were associated with LC. Specifically, males who would develop LC at 3 months had widespread increases in <i>TGF-&#x3b2;</i> signaling during acute infection in proliferating NK cells. Females who would develop LC demonstrated increased expression of <i>XIST</i>, an RNA gene implicated in autoimmunity, and increased <i>IL1</i> signaling in monocytes at 12 months post infection. Several immune features of LC were also conserved across sexes. Both males and females with LC had reduced co-stimulatory signaling from monocytes and broad upregulation of <i>NF-&#x3ba;B</i> transcription factors. In both sexes, those with persistent LC demonstrated increased LAG3, a marker of T cell exhaustion, reduced <i>ETS1</i> transcription factor expression across lymphocyte subsets, and elevated intracellular IL-4 levels in T cell subsets, suggesting that ETS1 alterations may drive an aberrantly elevated Th2-like response in LC. Altogether, this study describes multiple innate and adaptive immune correlates of LC, some of which differ by sex, and offers insights toward the pursuit of tailored therapeutics.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamlin</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7336-6028</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pienkos</LastName><ForeName>Shaun M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Leslie</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stanford Immunology Program, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stabile</LastName><ForeName>Mikayla A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinedo</LastName><ForeName>Kassandra</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rao</LastName><ForeName>Mallika</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stanford Center for Clinical Research, Stanford University; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grant</LastName><ForeName>Philip</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bonilla</LastName><ForeName>Hector</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holubar</LastName><ForeName>Marisa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Upinder</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacobson</LastName><ForeName>Karen B</ForeName><Initials>KB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jagannathan</LastName><ForeName>Prasanna</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6305-758X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maldonado</LastName><ForeName>Yvonne</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holmes</LastName><ForeName>Susan P</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, Stanford University; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Subramanian</LastName><ForeName>Aruna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blish</LastName><ForeName>Catherine A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stanford Medical Scientist Training Program, Stanford University School of Medicine; Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chan Zuckerberg Biohub; San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>OT2 HL161847</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR001085</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01 AI150741</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>T32 AI007502</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>T32 AI007290</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>bioRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101680187</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2692-8205</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Competing interests: Upinder Singh reports research support from National Institutes of Health, Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, and Pfizer, Inc.; she is an advisor to Regeneron and Gilead. Catherine Blish is an advisor to Immunebridge and DeepCell on topics unrelated to this research. All other authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38948732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11212991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2024.06.18.599612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2024.06.18.599612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard (available at https://covid19.who.int).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronavirus disease (COVID-19): Post COVID-19 condition (available at https://www.who.int/news-room/questions-and-answers/item/coronavirus-disease-(covid-19)-post-covid-19-condition).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. S. for P. Affairs (ASPA), About Long COVID (2023) (available at https://www.covid.gov/be-informed/longcovid/about).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC, Healthcare WorkersCent. Dis. Control Prev. (2020) (available at https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-conditions.html).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H. E., McCorkell L., Vogel J. M., Topol E. J., Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 21, 133&#x2013;146 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merad M., Blish C. A., Sallusto F., Iwasaki A., The immunology and immunopathology of COVID-19. Science 375, 1122&#x2013;1127 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35271343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reese J. T., Blau H., Casiraghi E., Bergquist T., Loomba J. J., Callahan T. J., Laraway B., Antonescu C., Coleman B., Gargano M., Wilkins K. J., Cappelletti L., Fontana T., Ammar N., Antony B., Murali T. M., Caufield J. H., Karlebach G., McMurry J. A., Williams A., Moffitt R., Banerjee J., Solomonides A. E., Davis H., Kostka K., Valentini G., Sahner D., Chute C. G., Madlock-Brown C., Haendel M. A., Robinson P. N., N3C Consortium, RECOVER Consortium, Generalisable long COVID subtypes: findings from the NIH N3C and RECOVER programmes. EBioMedicine 87, 104413 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9769411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36563487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T., Jolley S. E., Karlson E. W., Levitan E. B., Levy B., McComsey G. A., McCorkell L., Nadkarni G. N., Parthasarathy S., Singh U., Walker T. A., Selvaggi C. A., Shinnick D. J., Schulte C. C. M., Atchley-Challenner R., Alba G. A., Alicic R., Altman N., Anglin K., Argueta U., Ashktorab H., Baslet G., Bassett I. V., Bateman L., Bedi B., Bhattacharyya S., Bind M.-A., Blomkalns A. L., Bonilla H., Bush P. A., Castro M., Chan J., Charney A. W., Chen P., Chibnik L. B., Chu H. Y., Clifton R. G., Costantine M. M., Cribbs S. K., Davila Nieves S. I., Deeks S. G., Duven A., Emery I. F., Erdmann N., Erlandson K. M., Ernst K. C., Farah-Abraham R., Farner C. E., Feuerriegel E. M., Fleurimont J., Fonseca V., Franko N., Gainer V., Gander J. C., Gardner E. M., Geng L. N., Gibson K. S., Go M., Goldman J. D., Grebe H., Greenway F. L., Habli M., Hafner J., Han J. E., Hanson K. A., Heath J., Hernandez C., Hess R., Hodder S. L., Hoffman M. K., Hoover S. E., Huang B., Hughes B. L., Jagannathan P., John J., Jordan M. R., Katz S. D., Kaufman E. S., Kelly J. D., Kelly S. W., Kemp M. M., Kirwan J. P., Klein J. D., Knox K. S., Krishnan J. A., Kumar A., Laiyemo A. O., Lambert A. A., Lanca M., Lee-Iannotti J. K., Logarbo B. P., Longo M. T., Luciano C. A., Lutrick K., Maley J. H., Marathe J. G., Marconi V., Marshall G. D., Martin C. F., Matusov Y., Mehari A., Mendez-Figueroa H., Mermelstein R., Metz T. D., Morse R., Mosier J., Mouchati C., Mullington J., Murphy S. N., Neuman R. B., Nikolich J. Z., Ofotokun I., Ojemakinde E., Palatnik A., Palomares K., Parimon T., Parry S., Patterson J. E., Patterson T. F., Patzer R. E., Peluso M. J., Pemu P., Pettker C. M., Plunkett B. A., Pogreba-Brown K., Poppas A., Quigley J. G., Reddy U., Reece R., Reeder H., Reeves W. B., Reiman E. M., Rischard F., Rosand J., Rouse D. J., Ruff A., Saade G., Sandoval G. J., Schlater S. M., Shepherd F., Sherif Z. A., Simhan H., Singer N. G., Skupski D. W., Sowles A., Sparks J. A., Sukhera F. I., Taylor B. S., Teunis L., Thomas R. J., Thorp J. M., Thuluvath P., Ticotsky A., Tita A. T., Tuttle K. R., Urdaneta A. E., Valdivieso D., VanWagoner T. M., Vasey A., Verduzco-Gutierrez M., Wallace Z. S., Ward H. D., Warren D. E., Weiner S. J., Welch S., Whiteheart S. W., Wiley Z., Wisnivesky J. P., Yee L. M., Zisis S., Horwitz L. I., Foulkes A. S., RECOVER Consortium, Development of a Definition of Postacute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection. JAMA 329, 1934&#x2013;1946 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10214179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozonoff A., Jayavelu N. D., Liu S., Melamed E., Milliren C. E., Qi J., Geng L. N., McComsey G. A., Cairns C. B., Baden L. R., Schaenman J., Shaw A. C., Samaha H., Seyfert-Margolis V., Krammer F., Rosen L. B., Steen H., Syphurs C., Dandekar R., Shannon C. P., Sekaly R. P., Ehrlich L. I. R., Corry D. B., Kheradmand F., Atkinson M. A., Brakenridge S. C., Higuita N. I. A., Metcalf J. P., Hough C. L., Messer W. B., Pulendran B., Nadeau K. C., Davis M. M., Sesma A. F., Simon V., van Bakel H., Kim-Schulze S., Hafler D. A., Levy O., Kraft M., Bime C., Haddad E. K., Calfee C. S., Erle D. J., Langelier C. R., Eckalbar W., Bosinger S. E., Peters B., Kleinstein S. H., Reed E. F., Augustine A. D., Diray-Arce J., Maecker H. T., Altman M. C., Montgomery R. R., Becker P. M., Rouphael N., Features of acute COVID-19 associated with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 phenotypes: results from the IMPACC study. Nat. Commun. 15, 216 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10764789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38172101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny G., McCann K., O&#x2019;Brien C., Savinelli S., Tinago W., Yousif O., Lambert J. S., O&#x2019;Broin C., Feeney E. R., De Barra E., Doran P., Mallon P. W. G., All-Ireland Infectious Diseases (AIID) Cohort Study Group, Identification of Distinct Long COVID Clinical Phenotypes Through Cluster Analysis of Self-Reported Symptoms. Open Forum Infect. Dis. 9, ofac060 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8900926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35265728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y., Yuan D., Chen D. G., Ng R. H., Wang K., Choi J., Li S., Hong S., Zhang R., Xie J., Kornilov S. A., Scherler K., Pavlovitch-Bedzyk A. J., Dong S., Lausted C., Lee I., Fallen S., Dai C. L., Baloni P., Smith B., Duvvuri V. R., Anderson K. G., Li J., Yang F., Duncombe C. J., McCulloch D. J., Rostomily C., Troisch P., Zhou J., Mackay S., DeGottardi Q., May D. H., Taniguchi R., Gittelman R. M., Klinger M., Snyder T. M., Roper R., Wojciechowska G., Murray K., Edmark R., Evans S., Jones L., Zhou Y., Rowen L., Liu R., Chour W., Algren H. A., Berrington W. R., Wallick J. A., Cochran R. A., Micikas M. E., ISB-Swedish COVID-19 Biobanking Unit, Wrin T., Petropoulos C. J., Cole H. R., Fischer T. D., Wei W., Hoon D. S. B., Price N. D., Subramanian N., Hill J. A., Hadlock J., Magis A. T., Ribas A., Lanier L. L., Boyd S. D., Bluestone J. A., Chu H., Hood L., Gottardo R., Greenberg P. D., Davis M. M., Goldman J. D., J. R. Heath, Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell 185, 881&#x2013;895.e20 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J., Wood J., Jaycox J., Dhodapkar R. M., Lu P., Gehlhausen J. R., Tabachnikova A., Greene K., Tabacof L., Malik A. A., Silva Monteiro V., Silva J., Kamath K., Zhang M., Dhal A., Ott I. M., Valle G., Pe&#xf1;a-Hernandez M., Mao T., Bhattacharjee B., Takahashi T., Lucas C., Song E., Mccarthy D., Breyman E., Tosto-Mancuso J., Dai Y., Perotti E., Akduman K., Tzeng T. J., Xu L., Geraghty A. C., Monje M., Yildirim I., Shon J., Medzhitov R., Lutchmansingh D., Possick J. D., Kaminski N., Omer S. B., Krumholz H. M., Guan L., Dela Cruz C. S., van Dijk D., Ring A. M., Putrino D., Iwasaki A., Distinguishing features of Long COVID identified through immune profiling. Nature (2023), doi:10.1038/s41586-023-06651-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-023-06651-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10620090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37748514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin K., Peluso M. J., Thomas R., Shin M.-G., Neidleman J., Luo X., Hoh R., Anglin K., Huang B., Argueta U., Lopez M., Valdivieso D., Asare K., Ibrahim R., St&#xe4;ndker L., Lu S., Goldberg S. A., Lee S. A., Lynch K. L., Kelly J. D., Martin J. N., M&#xfc;nch J., Deeks S. G., Henrich T. J., Roan N. R., Long COVID manifests with T cell dysregulation, inflammation, and an uncoordinated adaptive immune response to SARS-CoV-2. BioRxiv Prepr. Serv. Biol., 2023.02.09.527892 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10834368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38212464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C., Darley D. R., Wilson D. B., Howe A., Munier C. M. L., Patel S. K., Juno J. A., Burrell L. M., Kent S. J., Dore G. J., Kelleher A. D., Matthews G. V., Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat. Immunol. 23, 210&#x2013;216 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso M. J., Deitchman A. N., Torres L., Iyer N. S., Munter S. E., Nixon C. C., Donatelli J., Thanh C., Takahashi S., Hakim J., Turcios K., Janson O., Hoh R., Tai V., Hernandez Y., Fehrman E. A., Spinelli M. A., Gandhi M., Trinh L., Wrin T., Petropoulos C. J., Aweeka F. T., Rodriguez-Barraquer I., Kelly J. D., Martin J. N., Deeks S. G., Greenhouse B., Rutishauser R. L., Henrich T. J., Long-term SARS-CoV-2-specific immune and inflammatory responses in individuals recovering from COVID-19 with and without post-acute symptoms. Cell Rep. 36, 109518 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8342976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34358460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso M. J., Lu S., Tang A. F., Durstenfeld M. S., Ho H.-E., Goldberg S. A., Forman C. A., Munter S. E., Hoh R., Tai V., Chenna A., Yee B. C., Winslow J. W., Petropoulos C. J., Greenhouse B., Hunt P. W., Hsue P. Y., Martin J. N., Daniel Kelly J., Glidden D. V., Deeks S. G., Henrich T. J., Markers of Immune Activation and Inflammation in Individuals With Postacute Sequelae of Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 Infection. J. Infect. Dis. 224, 1839&#x2013;1848 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8643408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34677601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PHOSP-COVID Collaborative Group, Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet Respir. Med. 10, 761&#x2013;775 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9034855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35472304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Littlefield K. M., Watson R. O., Schneider J. M., Neff C. P., Yamada E., Zhang M., Campbell T. B., Falta M. T., Jolley S. E., Fontenot A. P., Palmer B. E., SARS-CoV-2-specific T cells associate with inflammation and reduced lung function in pulmonary post-acute sequalae of SARS-CoV-2. PLOS Pathog. 18, e1010359 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9176759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35617421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulthei&#xdf; C., Willscher E., Paschold L., Gottschick C., Klee B., Henkes S.-S., Bosurgi L., Dutzmann J., Sedding D., Frese T., Girndt M., H&#xf6;ll J. I., Gekle M., Mikolajczyk R., Binder M., The IL-1&#x3b2;, IL-6, and TNF cytokine triad is associated with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Cell Rep. Med. 3, 100663 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35732153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson R. C., Simons N. W., Wilkins L., Cheng E., Del Valle D. M., Hoffman G. E., Cervia C., Fennessy B., Mouskas K., Francoeur N. J., Johnson J. S., Lepow L., Le Berichel J., Chang C., Beckmann A. G., Wang Y.-C., Nie K., Zaki N., Tuballes K., Barcessat V., Cedillo M. A., Yuan D., Huckins L., Roussos P., Marron T. U., Mount Sinai COVID-19 Biobank Team, Glicksberg B. S., Nadkarni G., Heath J. R., Gonzalez-Kozlova E., Boyman O, Kim-Schulze S., Sebra R., Merad M., Gnjatic S., Schadt E. E., Charney A. W., Beckmann N. D., Molecular states during acute COVID-19 reveal distinct etiologies of long-term sequelae. Nat. Med. 29, 236&#x2013;246 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9873574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36482101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Casta&#xf1;eda A., Lu P., Geraghty A. C., Song E., Lee M.-H., Wood J., O&#x2019;Dea M. R., Dutton S., Shamardani K., Nwangwu K., Mancusi R., Yal&#xe7;in B., Taylor K. R., Acosta-Alvarez L., Malacon K., Keough M. B., Ni L., Woo P. J., Contreras-Esquivel D., Toland A. M. S., Gehlhausen J. R., Klein J., Takahashi T., Silva J., Israelow B., Lucas C., Mao T., Pe&#xf1;a-Hern&#xe1;ndez M. A., Tabachnikova A., Homer R. J., Tabacof L., Tosto-Mancuso J., Breyman E., Kontorovich A., McCarthy D., Quezado M., Vogel H., Hefti M. M., Perl D. P., Liddelow S., Folkerth R., Putrino D., Nath A., Iwasaki A., Monje M., Mild respiratory COVID can cause multi-lineage neural cell and myelin dysregulation. Cell 185, 2452&#x2013;2468.e16 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9189143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35768006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott N. A., Pearmain L., Knight S. B., Brand O., Morgan D. J., Jagger C., Harbach S., Khan S., Shuwa H. A., Franklin M., K&#xe4;stele V., Williams T., Prise I., McClure F. A., Hackney P., Smith L., Menon M., Konkel J. E., Lawless C., Wilson J., Mathioudakis A. G., Stanel S. C., Ustianowski A., Lindergard G., Brij S., Diar Bakerly N., Dark P., Brightling C., Rivera-Ortega P., Lord G. M., Horsley A., CIRCO K., Piper Hanley, Felton T., Simpson A., Grainger J. R., Hussell T., Mann E. R., Monocyte migration profiles define disease severity in acute COVID-19 and unique features of long COVID. Eur. Respir. J. 61, 2202226 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10040898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36922030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayakumar B., Boustani K., Ogger P. P., Papadaki A., Tonkin J., Orton C. M., Ghai P., Suveizdyte K., Hewitt R. J., Desai S. R., Devaraj A., Snelgrove R. J., Molyneaux P. L., Garner J. L., Peters J. E., Shah P. L., Lloyd C. M., Harker J. A., Immuno-proteomic profiling reveals aberrant immune cell regulation in the airways of individuals with ongoing post-COVID-19 respiratory disease. Immunity 55, 542&#x2013;556.e5 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8789571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35151371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visvabharathy L., Hanson B. A., Orban Z. S., Lim P. H., Palacio N. M., Jimenez M., Clark J. R., Graham E. L., Liotta E. M., Tachas G., Penaloza-MacMaster P., Koralnik I. J., Neuro-PASC is characterized by enhanced CD4+ and diminished CD8+ T cell responses to SARS-CoV-2 Nucleocapsid protein. Front. Immunol. 14, 1155770 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10258318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37313412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuwa H. A., Shaw T. N., Knight S. B., Wemyss K., McClure F. A., Pearmain L., Prise I., Jagger C., Morgan D. J., Khan S., Brand O., Mann E. R., Ustianowski A., Bakerly N. D., Dark P., Brightling C. E., Brij S., CIRCO T., Felton A. Simpson J. R. Grainger T. Hussell J. E. Konkel M. Menon, Alterations in T and B cell function persist in convalescent COVID-19 patients. Med N. Y. N 2, 720&#x2013;735.e4 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8011689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33821250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruffieux H., Hanson A. L., Lodge S., Lawler N. G., Whiley L., Gray N., Nolan T. H., Bergamaschi L., Mescia F., Turner L., de Sa A., Pelly V. S., Cambridge Institute of Therapeutic Immunology and Infectious Disease-National Institute of Health Research (CITIID-NIHR) BioResource COVID-19 Collaboration, Kotagiri P., Kingston N., Bradley J. R., Holmes E., Wist J., Nicholson J. K., Lyons P. A., Smith K. G. C., Richardson S., Bantug G. R., Hess C., A patient-centric modeling framework captures recovery from SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat. Immunol. 24, 349&#x2013;358 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9892000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36717723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talla A., Vasaikar S. V., Szeto G. L., Lemos M. P., Czartoski J. L., MacMillan H., Moodie Z., Cohen K. W., Fleming L. B., Thomson Z., Okada L., Becker L. A., Coffey E. M., De Rosa S. C., Newell E. W., Skene P. J., Li X., Bumol T. F., Juliana McElrath M., Torgerson T. R., Persistent serum protein signatures define an inflammatory subcategory of long COVID. Nat. Commun. 14, 3417 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10252177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37296110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins F. R., Govender M., Svanberg C., Nordgren J., Waller H., Nilsdotter-Augustinsson &#xc5;., Henningsson A. J., Hagbom M., Sj&#xf6;wall J., Nystr&#xf6;m S., Larsson M., Major alterations to monocyte and dendritic cell subsets lasting more than 6 months after hospitalization for COVID-19. Front. Immunol. 13, 1082912 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9846644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36685582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Captur G., Moon J. C., Topriceanu C.-C., Joy G., Swadling L., Hallqvist J., Doykov I., Patel N., Spiewak J., Baldwin T., Hamblin M., Menacho K., Fontana M., Treibel T. A., Manisty C., O&#x2019;Brien B., Gibbons J. M., Pade C., Brooks T., Altmann D. M., Boyton R. J., McKnight &#xc1;., Maini M. K., Noursadeghi M., Mills K., Heywood W. E., UK COVIDsortium Investigators, Plasma proteomic signature predicts who will get persistent symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection. EBioMedicine 85, 104293 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9515404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36182629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamlin R. E., Blish C. A., Challenges and opportunities in long COVID research. Immunity 57, 1195&#x2013;1214 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11210969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38865966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaebler C., Wang Z., Lorenzi J. C. C., Muecksch F., Finkin S., Tokuyama M., Cho A., Jankovic M., Schaefer-Babajew D., Oliveira T. Y., Cipolla M., Viant C., Barnes C. O., Bram Y., Breton G., H&#xe4;ggl&#xf6;f T., Mendoza P., Hurley A., Turroja M., Gordon K., Millard K. G., Ramos V., Schmidt F., Weisblum Y., Jha D., Tankelevich M., Martinez-Delgado G., Yee J., Patel R., Dizon J., Unson-O&#x2019;Brien C., Shimeliovich I., Robbiani D. F., Zhao Z., Gazumyan A., Schwartz R. E., Hatziioannou T., Bjorkman P. J., Mehandru S., Bieniasz P. D., Caskey M., Nussenzweig M. C., Evolution of antibody immunity to SARS-CoV-2. Nature 591, 639&#x2013;644 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein S. R., Ramelli S. C., Grazioli A., Chung J.-Y., Singh M., Yinda C. K., Winkler C. W., Sun J., Dickey J. M., Ylaya K., Ko S. H., Platt A. P., Burbelo P. D., Quezado M., Pittaluga S., Purcell M., Munster V. J., Belinky F., Ramos-Benitez M. J., Boritz E. A., Lach I. A., Herr D. L., Rabin J., Saharia K. K., Madathil R. J., Tabatabai A., Soherwardi S., McCurdy M. T., NIH COVID-19 Autopsy Consortium, Peterson K. E., Cohen J. I., de Wit E., Vannella K. M., Hewitt S. M., Kleiner D. E., Chertow D. S., SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence in the human body and brain at autopsy. Nature 612, 758&#x2013;763 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9749650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36517603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swank Z., Senussi Y., Manickas-Hill Z., Yu X. G., Li J. Z., Alter G., Walt D. R., Persistent Circulating Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 Spike Is Associated With Post-acute Coronavirus Disease 2019 Sequelae. Clin. Infect. Dis. 76, e487&#x2013;e490 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10169416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36052466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craddock V., Mahajan A., Spikes L., Krishnamachary B., Ram A. K., Kumar A., Chen L., Chalise P., Dhillon N. K., Persistent circulation of soluble and extracellular vesicle-linked Spike protein in individuals with postacute sequelae of COVID-19. J. Med. Virol. 95, e28568 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10048846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36756925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulthei&#xdf; C., Willscher E., Paschold L., Gottschick C., Klee B., Bosurgi L., Dutzmann J., Sedding D., Frese T., Girndt M., H&#xf6;ll J. I., Gekle M., Mikolajczyk R., Binder M., Liquid biomarkers of macrophage dysregulation and circulating spike protein illustrate the biological heterogeneity in patients with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. J. Med. Virol. 95, e28364 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9878213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36458566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso M. J., Deeks S. G., Mustapic M., Kapogiannis D., Henrich T. J., Lu S., Goldberg S. A., Hoh R., Chen J. Y., Martinez E. O., Kelly J. D., Martin J. N., Goetzl E. J., SARS-CoV-2 and Mitochondrial Proteins in Neural-Derived Exosomes of COVID-19. Ann. Neurol. 91, 772&#x2013;781 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9082480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35285072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hany M., Zidan A., Gaballa M., Ibrahim M., Agayby A. S. S., Abouelnasr A. A., Sheta E., Torensma B., Lingering SARS-CoV-2 in Gastric and Gallbladder Tissues of Patients with Previous COVID-19 Infection Undergoing Bariatric Surgery. Obes. Surg. 33, 139&#x2013;148 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9628579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36316598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung C. C. L., Goh D., Lim X., Tien T. Z., Lim J. C. T., Lee J. N., Tan B., Tay Z. E. A., Wan W. Y., Chen E. X., Nerurkar S. N., Loong S., Cheow P. C., Chan C. Y., Koh Y. X., Tan T. T., Kalimuddin S., Tai W. M. D., Ng J. L., Low J. G.-H., Yeong J., Lim K. H., Residual SARS-CoV-2 viral antigens detected in GI and hepatic tissues from five recovered patients with COVID-19. Gut 71, 226&#x2013;229 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34083386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Q., Milanez-Almeida P., Martins A. J., Radtke A. J., Hoehn K. B., Oguz C., Chen J., Liu C., Tang J., Grubbs G., Stein S., Ramelli S., Kabat J., Behzadpour H., Karkanitsa M., Spathies J., Kalish H., Kardava L., Kirby M., Cheung F., Preite S., Duncker P. C., Kitakule M. M., Romero N., Preciado D., Gitman L., Koroleva G., Smith G., Shaffer A., McBain I. T., McGuire P. J., Pittaluga S., Germain R. N., Apps R., Schwartz D. M., Sadtler K., Moir S., Chertow D. S., Kleinstein S. H., Khurana S., Tsang J. S., Mudd P., Schwartzberg P. L., Manthiram K., Adaptive immune responses to SARS-CoV-2 persist in the pharyngeal lymphoid tissue of children. Nat. Immunol. 24, 186&#x2013;199 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10777159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36536106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tejerina F., Catalan P., Rodriguez-Grande C., Adan J., Rodriguez-Gonzalez C., Mu&#xf1;oz P., Aldamiz T., Diez C., Perez L., Fanciulli C., Garcia de Viedma D., Gregorio Mara&#xf1;on Microbiology ID COVID 19 Study Group, Post-COVID-19 syndrome. SARS-CoV-2 RNA detection in plasma, stool, and urine in patients with persistent symptoms after COVID-19. BMC Infect. Dis. 22, 211 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8892394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35240997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh D., Lim J. C. T., Ferna&#xed;ndez S. B., Joseph C. R., Edwards S. G., Neo Z. W., Lee J. N., Caballero S. G., Lau M. C., Yeong J. P. S., Case report: Persistence of residual antigen and RNA of the SARS-CoV-2 virus in tissues of two patients with long COVID. Front. Immunol. 13, 939989 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9483160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36131932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zollner A., Koch R., Jukic A., Pfister A., Meyer M., R&#xf6;ssler A., Kimpel J., Adolph T. E., Tilg H., Postacute COVID-19 is Characterized by Gut Viral Antigen Persistence in Inflammatory Bowel Diseases. Gastroenterology 163, 495&#x2013;506.e8 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9057012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35508284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Melo G. D., Lazarini F., Levallois S., Hautefort C., Michel V., Larrous F., Verillaud B., Aparicio C., Wagner S., Gheusi G., Kergoat L., Kornobis E., Donati F., Cokelaer T., Hervochon R., Madec Y., Roze E., Salmon D., Bourhy H., Lecuit M., Lledo P.-M., COVID-19-related anosmia is associated with viral persistence and inflammation in human olfactory epithelium and brain infection in hamsters. Sci. Transl. Med. 13, eabf8396 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8158965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33941622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao Q., Doyle M. E., Liu Q.-R., Appleton A., O&#x2019;Connell J. F., Weng N., Egan J. M., Long-Term Dysfunction of Taste Papillae in SARS-CoV-2. NEJM Evid. 2, EVIDoa2300046 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10745124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38145006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lima T. M., Martins R. B., Miura C. S., Souza M. V. O., Cassiano M. H. A., Rodrigues T. S., Veras F. P., de F. Sousa J., Gomes R., de Almeida G. M., Melo S. R., da Silva G. C., Dias M., Capato C. F., Silva M. L., Luiz V. E. D. de B., Carenzi L. R., Zamboni D. S., Jorge D. M. de M., Cunha F. de Q., Tamashiro E., Anselmo-Lima W. T., Valera F. C. P., Arruda E., Tonsils are major sites of persistence of SARS-CoV-2 in children. Microbiol. Spectr. 11, e0134723 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10581087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37737615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan A., Zlitni S., Brooks E. F., Vance S. E., Dahlen A., Hedlin H., Park R. M., Han A., Schmidtke D. T., Verma R., Jacobson K. B., Parsonnet J., Bonilla H. F., Singh U., Pinsky B. A., Andrews J. R., Jagannathan P., Bhatt A. S., Gastrointestinal symptoms and fecal shedding of SARS-CoV-2 RNA suggest prolonged gastrointestinal infection. Med N. Y. N 3, 371&#x2013;387.e9 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9005383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35434682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso M. J., Swank Z. N., Goldberg S. A., Lu S., Dalhuisen T., Borberg E., Senussi Y., Luna M. A., Chang Song C., Clark A., Zamora A., Lew M., Viswanathan B., Huang B., Anglin K., Hoh R., Hsue P. Y., Durstenfeld M. S., Spinelli M. A., Glidden D. V., Henrich T. J., Kelly J. D., Deeks S. G., Walt D. R., Martin J. N., Plasma-based antigen persistence in the post-acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection. MedRxiv Prepr. Serv. Health Sci., 2023.10.24.23297114 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38604216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peghin M., Palese A., Venturini M., De Martino M., Gerussi V., Graziano E., Bontempo G., Marrella F., Tommasini A., Fabris M., Curcio F., Isola M., Tascini C., Post-COVID-19 symptoms 6 months after acute infection among hospitalized and non-hospitalized patients. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. Off. Publ. Eur. Soc. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. Dis. 27, 1507&#x2013;1513 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8180450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34111579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Abell&#xe1;n J., Padilla S., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Gonz&#xe1;lez M., Garc&#xed;a J. A., Agull&#xf3; V., Andreo M., Ruiz S., Galiana A., Guti&#xe9;rrez F., Masi&#xe1; M., Antibody Response to SARS-CoV-2 is Associated with Long-term Clinical Outcome in Patients with COVID-19: a Longitudinal Study. J. Clin. Immunol. 41, 1490&#x2013;1501 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8285689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Abell&#xe1;n J., Fern&#xe1;ndez M., Padilla S., Garc&#xed;a J. A., Agull&#xf3; V., Lozano V., Ena N., Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;nchez L., Guti&#xe9;rrez F., Masi&#xe1; M., Immunologic phenotype of patients with long-COVID syndrome of 1-year duration. Front. Immunol. 13, 920627 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9451924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36090973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin K., Peluso M. J., Luo X., Thomas R., Shin M.-G., Neidleman J., Andrew A., Young K. C., Ma T., Hoh R., Anglin K., Huang B., Argueta U., Lopez M., Valdivieso D., Asare K., Deveau T.-M., Munter S. E., Ibrahim R., St&#xe4;ndker L., Lu S., Goldberg S. A., Lee S. A., Lynch K. L., Kelly J. D., Martin J. N., M&#xfc;nch J., Deeks S. G., Henrich T. J., Roan N. R., Long COVID manifests with T cell dysregulation, inflammation and an uncoordinated adaptive immune response to SARS-CoV-2. Nat. Immunol., 1&#x2013;8 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10834368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38212464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang E. Y., Mao T., Klein J., Dai Y., Huck J. D., Jaycox J. R., Liu F., Zhou T., Israelow B., Wong P., Coppi A., Lucas C., Silva J., Oh J. E., Song E., Perotti E. S., Zheng N. S., Fischer S., Campbell M., Fournier J. B., Wyllie A. L., Vogels C. B. F., Ott I. M., Kalinich C. C., Petrone M. E., Watkins A. E., Yale IMPACT Team, Dela Cruz C., Farhadian S. F., Schulz W. L., Ma S., Grubaugh N. D., Ko A. I., Iwasaki A., Ring A. M., Diverse functional autoantibodies in patients with COVID-19. Nature 595, 283&#x2013;288 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34010947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia C., Zurbuchen Y., Taeschler P., Ballouz T., Menges D., Hasler S., Adamo S., Raeber M. E., B&#xe4;chli E., Rudiger A., St&#xfc;ssi-Helbling M., Huber L. C., Nilsson J., Held U., Puhan M. A., Boyman O., Immunoglobulin signature predicts risk of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat. Commun. 13, 446 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8789854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35078982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter A. G., Shields A. M., Karim A., Birch D., Faustini S. E., Steadman L., Ward K., Plant T., Reynolds G., Veenith T., Cunningham A. F., Drayson M. T., Wraith D. C., Establishing the prevalence of common tissue-specific autoantibodies following severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection. Clin. Exp. Immunol. 205, 99&#x2013;105 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34082475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son K., Jamil R., Chowdhury A., Mukherjee M., Venegas C., Miyasaki K., Zhang K., Patel Z., Salter B., Yuen A. C. Y., Lau K. S.-K., Cowbrough B., Radford K., Huang C., Kjarsgaard M., Dvorkin-Gheva A., Smith J., Li Q.-Z., Waserman S., Ryerson C. J., Nair P., Ho T., Balakrishnan N., Nazy I., Bowdish D. M. E., Svenningsen S., Carlsten C., Mukherjee M., Circulating anti-nuclear autoantibodies in COVID-19 survivors predict long COVID symptoms. Eur. Respir. J. 61, 2200970 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9515477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36137590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallukat G., Hohberger B., Wenzel K., F&#xfc;rst J., Schulze-Rothe S., Wallukat A., H&#xf6;nicke A.-S., M&#xfc;ller J., Functional autoantibodies against G-protein coupled receptors in patients with persistent Long-COVID-19 symptoms. J. Transl. Autoimmun. 4, 100100 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8049853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33880442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch F., Ehm F., Vivirito A., Wende D., Batram M., Loser F., Menzer S., Jacob J., Roessler M., Seifert M., Kind B., K&#xf6;nig C., Schulte C., Buschmann T., Hertle D., Ballesteros P., Ba&#xdf;ler S., Bertele B., Bitterer T., Riederer C., Sobik F., Reitzle L., Scheidt-Nave C., Schmitt J., Incident autoimmune diseases in association with SARS-CoV-2 infection: a matched cohort study. Clin. Rheumatol. 42, 2905&#x2013;2914 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10497688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37335408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szewczykowski C., Mardin C., Lucio M., Wallukat G., Hoffmanns J., Schr&#xf6;der T., Raith F., Rogge L., Heltmann F., Moritz M., Beitlich L., Schottenhamml J., Herrmann M., Harrer T., Ganslmayer M., Kruse F. E., Kr&#xe4;ter M., Guck J., L&#xe4;mmer R., Zenkel M., Gie&#xdf;l A., Hohberger B., Long COVID: Association of Functional Autoantibodies against G-Protein-Coupled Receptors with an Impaired Retinal Microcirculation. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 23, 7209 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9266742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35806214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso M. J., Deveau T.-M., Munter S. E., Ryder D., Buck A., Beck-Engeser G., Chan F., Lu S., Goldberg S. A., Hoh R., Tai V., Torres L., Iyer N. S., Deswal M., Ngo L. H., Buitrago M., Rodriguez A., Chen J. Y., Yee B. C., Chenna A., Winslow J. W., Petropoulos C. J., Deitchman A. N., Hellmuth J., Spinelli M. A., Durstenfeld M. S., Hsue P. Y., Kelly J. D., Martin J. N., Deeks S. G., Hunt P. W., Henrich T. J., Chronic viral coinfections differentially affect the likelihood of developing long COVID. J. Clin. Invest. 133, e163669 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9888380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36454631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold J. E., Okyay R. A., Licht W. E., Hurley D. J., Investigation of Long COVID Prevalence and Its Relationship to Epstein-Barr Virus Reactivation. Pathog. Basel Switz. 10, 763 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8233978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34204243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubchenko S., Kril I., Nadizhko O., Matsyura O., Chopyak V., Herpesvirus infections and post-COVID-19 manifestations: a pilot observational study. Rheumatol. Int. 42, 1523&#x2013;1530 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9159383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35650445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia-Hasler C., Br&#xfc;ningk S. C., Hoch T., Fan B., Muzio G., Thompson R. C., Ceglarek L., Meledin R., Westermann P., Emmenegger M., Taeschler P., Zurbuchen Y., Pons M., Menges D., Ballouz T., Cervia-Hasler S., Adamo S., Merad M., Charney A. W., Puhan M., Brodin P., Nilsson J., Aguzzi A., Raeber M. E., Messner C. B., Beckmann N. D., Borgwardt K., Boyman O., Persistent complement dysregulation with signs of thromboinflammation in active Long Covid. Science 383, eadg7942 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38236961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E., Vlok M., Venter C., Bezuidenhout J. A., Laubscher G. J., Steenkamp J., Kell D. B., Persistent clotting protein pathology in Long COVID/Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) is accompanied by increased levels of antiplasmin. Cardiovasc. Diabetol. 20, 172 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8381139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34425843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D., Di Giuda D., Sigfrid L., Pizzuto D. A., Di Sante G., De Rose C., Lazzareschi I., Sali M., Baldi F., Chieffo D. P. R., Munblit D., Valentini P., Evidence of lung perfusion defects and ongoing inflammation in an adolescent with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Lancet Child Adolesc. Health 5, 677&#x2013;680 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8324416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasini E., Corsetti G., Romano C., Scarabelli T. M., Chen-Scarabelli C., Saravolatz L., Dioguardi F. S., Serum Metabolic Profile in Patients With Long-Covid (PASC) Syndrome: Clinical Implications. Front. Med. 8 (2021) (available at 10.3389/fmed.2021.714426).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.714426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8339407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34368201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty H., Townsend L., Morrin H., Ahmad A., Comerford C., Karampini E., Englert H., Byrne M., Bergin C., O&#x2019;Sullivan J. M., Martin-Loeches I., Nadarajan P., Bannan C., Mallon P. W., Curley G. F., Preston R. J. S., Rehill A. M., McGonagle D., Ni Cheallaigh C., Baker R. I., Renn&#xe9; T., Ward S. E., O&#x2019;Donnell J. S., Irish COVID-19 Vasculopathy Study (iCVS) investigators, Persistent endotheliopathy in the pathogenesis of long COVID syndrome. J. Thromb. Haemost. JTH 19, 2546&#x2013;2553 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8420256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34375505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasannan N., Heightman M., Hillman T., Wall E., Bell R., Kessler A., Neave L., Doyle A., Devaraj A., Singh D., Dehbi H.-M., Scully M., Impaired exercise capacity in post-COVID-19 syndrome: the role of VWF-ADAMTS13 axis. Blood Adv. 6, 4041&#x2013;4048 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9098525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35543533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appelman B., Charlton B. T., Goulding R. P., Kerkhoff T. J., Breedveld E. A., Noort W., Offringa C., Bloemers F. W., van Weeghel M., Schomakers B. V., Coelho P., Posthuma J. J., Aronica E., Joost Wiersinga W., van Vugt M., W&#xfc;st R. C. I., Muscle abnormalities worsen after post-exertional malaise in long COVID. Nat. Commun. 15, 17 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10766651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38177128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kell D. B., Laubscher G. J., Pretorius E., A central role for amyloid fibrin microclots in long COVID/PASC: origins and therapeutic implications. Biochem. J. 479, 537&#x2013;559 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8883497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35195253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charnley M., Islam S., Bindra G. K., Engwirda J., Ratcliffe J., Zhou J., Mezzenga R., Hulett M. D., Han K., Berryman J. T., Reynolds N. P., Neurotoxic amyloidogenic peptides in the proteome of SARS-COV2: potential implications for neurological symptoms in COVID-19. Nat. Commun. 13, 3387 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9189797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35697699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo L., Appelman B., Mooij-Kalverda K., Houtkooper R. H., van Weeghel M., Vaz F. M., Dijkhuis A., Dekker T., Smids B. S., Duitman J. W., Bugiani M., Brinkman P., Sikkens J. J., Lavell H. A. A., W&#xfc;st R. C. I., van Vugt M., Lutter R., van Agtmael M. A., Algera A. G., Appelman B., van Baarle F. E. H. P., Beudel M., Bogaard H. J., Bomers M., Bonta P. I., Bos L. D. J., Botta M., de Brabander J., de Bree G. J., de Bruin S., Bugiani M., Bulle E. B., Chouchane O., Cloherty A. P. M., Buis D., de Rotte M. C. F. J., Dijkstra M., Dongelmans D. A., Dujardin R. W. G., Elbers P. E., Fleuren L. M., Geerlings S. E., Geijtenbeek T. B. H., Girbes A. R. J., Goorhuis A., Grobusch M. P., Hagens L. A., Hamann J., Harris V. C., Hemke R., Hermans S. M., Heunks L. M. A., Hollmann M. W., Horn J., Hovius J. W., de Jong M. D., Koing R., Lim E. H. T., van Mourik N., Nellen J. F., Nossent E. J., Paulus F., Peters E., Pi&#xf1;a-Fuentes D., van der Poll T., Preckel B., Prins J. M., Raasveld S. J., Reijnders T. D. Y., Schinkel M., Schrauwen F. a. P., Schultz M. J., Schuurman A. R., Schuurmans J., Sigaloff K., Slim M. A., Smeele P., Smit M. R., Stijnis C., Stilma W., Teunissen C. E., Thoral P., Tsonas A. M., Tuinman P. R., van der Valk M., Veelo D. P., Volleman C., de Vries H., van Vught L. A., van Vugt M., Wouters D., Zwinderman A. H., Brouwer M. C., Wiersinga W. J., Vlaar A. P. J., van de Beek D., Prolonged indoleamine 2,3-dioxygenase-2 activity and associated cellular stress in post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. eBioMedicine 94 (2023), doi:10.1016/j.ebiom.2023.104729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2023.104729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10406961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37506544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunn A. V. W., Guy G. W., Brysch W., Bell J. D., Understanding Long COVID; Mitochondrial Health and Adaptation&#x2014;Old Pathways, New Problems. Biomedicines 10, 3113 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9775339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36551869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q., Su Q., Zhang F., Tun H. M., Mak J. W. Y., Lui G. C.-Y., Ng S. S. S., Ching J. Y. L., Li A., Lu W., Liu C., Cheung C. P., Hui D. S. C., Chan P. K. S., Chan F. K. L., Ng S. C., Multi-kingdom gut microbiota analyses define COVID-19 severity and post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat. Commun. 13, 6806 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9648868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36357381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q., Mak J. W. Y., Su Q., Yeoh Y. K., Lui G. C.-Y., Ng S. S. S., Zhang F., Li A. Y. L., Lu W., Hui D. S.-C., Chan P. K., Chan F. K. L., Ng S. C., Gut microbiota dynamics in a prospective cohort of patients with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Gut 71, 544&#x2013;552 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carneiro V. L., Littlefield K. M., Watson R., Palmer B. E., Lozupone C., Inflammation-associated gut microbiome in postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 points towards new therapeutic targets. Gut 73, 376&#x2013;378 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10850647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36717218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vestad B., Ueland T., Lerum T. V., Dahl T. B., Holm K., Barratt-Due A., K&#xe5;sine T., Dyrhol-Riise A. M., Stiksrud B., Tonby K., Hoel H., Olsen I. C., Henriksen K. N., Tveita A., Manotheepan R., Haugli M., Eiken R., Berg &#xc5;., Halvorsen B., Lekva T., Ranheim T., Michelsen A. E., Kildal A. B., Johannessen A., Thoresen L., Skudal H., Kittang B. R., Olsen R. B., Ystr&#xf8;m C. M., Skei N. V., Hannula R., Aballi S., Kv&#xe5;le R., Skj&#xf8;nsberg O. H., Aukrust P., Hov J. R., Tr&#xf8;seid M., NOR-Solidarity study group, Respiratory dysfunction three months after severe COVID-19 is associated with gut microbiota alterations. J. Intern. Med. 291, 801&#x2013;812 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35212063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong A. C., Devason A. S., Umana I. C., Cox T. O., Dohnalov&#xe1; L., Litichevskiy L., Perla J., Lundgren P., Etwebi Z., Izzo L. T., Kim J., Tetlak M., Descamps H. C., Park S. L., Wisser S., McKnight A. D., Pardy R. D., Kim J., Blank N., Patel S., Thum K., Mason S., Beltra J.-C., Michieletto M. F., Ngiow S. F., Miller B. M., Liou M. J., Madhu B., Dmitrieva-Posocco O., Huber A. S., Hewins P., Petucci C., Chu C. P., Baraniecki-Zwil G., Giron L. B., Baxter A. E., Greenplate A. R., Kearns C., Montone K., Litzky L. A., Feldman M., Henao-Mejia J., Striepen B., Ramage H., Jurado K. A., Wellen K. E., O&#x2019;Doherty U., Abdel-Mohsen M., Landay A. L., Keshavarzian A., Henrich T. J., Deeks S. G., Peluso M. J., Meyer N. J., Wherry E. J., Abramoff B. A., Cherry S., Thaiss C. A., Levy M., Serotonin reduction in post-acute sequelae of viral infection. Cell 0 (2023), doi:10.1016/j.cell.2023.09.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2023.09.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11227373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37848036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira C., Harris B. H. L., Di Giovannantonio M., Rosadas C., Short C.-E., Quinlan R., Sureda-Vives M., Fernandez N., Day-Weber I., Khan M., Marchesin F., Katsanovskaja K., Parker E., Taylor G. P., Tedder R. S., McClure M. O., Dani M., Fertleman M., The Association Between Antibody Response to Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 Infection and Post-COVID-19 Syndrome in Healthcare Workers. J. Infect. Dis. 223, 1671&#x2013;1676 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7989400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33675366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong S. W. X., Fong S.-W., Young B. E., Chan Y.-H., Lee B., Amrun S. N., Chee R. S.-L., Yeo N. K.-W., Tambyah P., Pada S., Tan S. Y., Ding Y., Renia L., Leo Y.-S., Ng L. F. P., Lye D. C., Persistent Symptoms and Association With Inflammatory Cytokine Signatures in Recovered Coronavirus Disease 2019 Patients. Open Forum Infect. Dis. 8, ofab156 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8083585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34095336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkhouli M., Nanjundappa A., Annie F., Bates M. C., Bhatt D. L., Sex Differences in Case Fatality Rate of COVID-19: Insights From a Multinational Registry. Mayo Clin. Proc. 95, 1613&#x2013;1620 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7256502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Y., Wu P., Lu W., Liu K., Ma K., Huang L., Cai J., Zhang H., Qin Y., Sun H., Ding W., Gui L., Wu P., Sex-specific clinical characteristics and prognosis of coronavirus disease-19 infection in Wuhan, China: A retrospective study of 168 severe patients. PLoS Pathog. 16, e1008520 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7209966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32343745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson S., Hirsch J. S., Narasimhan M., Crawford J. M., McGinn T., Davidson K. W., the Northwell COVID-19 Research Consortium, Barnaby D. P., Becker L. B., Chelico J. D., Cohen S. L., Cookingham J., Coppa K., Diefenbach M. A., Dominello A. J., Duer-Hefele J., Falzon L., Gitlin J., Hajizadeh N., Harvin T. G., Hirschwerk D. A., Kim E. J., Kozel Z. M., Marrast L. M., Mogavero J. N., Osorio G. A., Qiu M., Zanos T. P., Presenting Characteristics, Comorbidities, and Outcomes Among 5700 Patients Hospitalized With COVID-19 in the New York City Area. JAMA 323, 2052&#x2013;2059 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7177629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32320003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi G., Mattiuzzi C., Sanchis-Gomar F., Henry B. M., Clinical and demographic characteristics of patients dying from COVID-19 in Italy vs China. J. Med. Virol. 92, 1759&#x2013;1760 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T., Wu D., Chen H., Yan W., Yang D., Chen G., Ma K., Xu D., Yu H., Wang H., Wang T., Guo W., Chen J., Ding C., Zhang X., Huang J., Han M., Li S., Luo X., Zhao J., Ning Q., Clinical characteristics of 113 deceased patients with coronavirus disease 2019: retrospective study. BMJ 368, m1091 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7190011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabi&#xe3;o J., Sassi B., Pedrollo E. F., Gerchman F., Kramer C. K., Leit&#xe3;o C. B., Pinto L. C., Why do men have worse COVID-19-related outcomes? A systematic review and meta-analysis with sex adjusted for age. Braz. J. Med. Biol. Res. 55, e11711 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8856598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35195196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doerre A., Doblhammer G., The influence of gender on COVID-19 infections and mortality in Germany: Insights from age- and gender-specific modeling of contact rates, infections, and deaths in the early phase of the pandemic. PloS One 17, e0268119 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9075634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35522614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre C. H., Murray B., Varsavsky T., Graham M. S., Penfold R. S., Bowyer R. C., Pujol J. C., Klaser K., Antonelli M., Canas L. S., Molteni E., Modat M., Jorge Cardoso M., May A., Ganesh S., Davies R., Nguyen L. H., Drew D. A., Astley C. M., Joshi A. D., Merino J., Tsereteli N., Fall T., Gomez M. F., Duncan E. L., Menni C., Williams F. M. K., Franks P. W., Chan A. T., Wolf J., Ourselin S., Spector T., Steves C. J., Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat. Med. 27, 626&#x2013;631 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C., Haupert S. R., Zimmermann L., Shi X., Fritsche L. G., Mukherjee B., Global Prevalence of Post-Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Condition or Long COVID: A Meta-Analysis and Systematic Review. J. Infect. Dis. 226, 1593&#x2013;1607 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Gennaro F., Belati A., Tulone O., Diella L., Fiore Bavaro D., Bonica R., Genna V., Smith L., Trott M., Bruyere O., Mirarchi L., Cusumano C., Dominguez L. J., Saracino A., Veronese N., Barbagallo M., Incidence of long COVID-19 in people with previous SARS-Cov2 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis of 120,970 patients. Intern. Emerg. Med. 18, 1573&#x2013;1581 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9709360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36449260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wulf Hanson S., Abbafati C., Aerts J. G., Al-Aly Z., Ashbaugh C., Ballouz T., Blyuss O., Bobkova P., Bonsel G., Borzakova S., Buonsenso D., Butnaru D., Carter A., Chu H., De Rose C., Diab M. M., Ekbom E., El Tantawi M., Fomin V., Frithiof R., Gamirova A., Glybochko P. V., Haagsma J. A., Haghjooy Javanmard S., Hamilton E. B., Harris G., Heijenbrok-Kal M. H., Helbok R., Hellemons M. E., Hillus D., Huijts S. M., Hultstr&#xf6;m M., Jassat W., Kurth F., Larsson I.-M., Lipcsey M., Liu C., Loflin C. D., Malinovschi A., Mao W., Mazankova L., McCulloch D., Menges D., Mohammadifard N., Munblit D., Nekliudov N. A., Ogbuoji O., Osmanov I. M., Pe&#xf1;alvo J. L., Petersen M. S., Puhan M. A., Rahman M., Rass V., Reinig N., Ribbers G. M., Ricchiuto A., Rubertsson S., Samitova E., Sarrafzadegan N., Shikhaleva A., Simpson K. E., Sinatti D., Soriano J. B., Spiridonova E., Steinbeis F., Svistunov A. A., Valentini P., van de Water B. J., van den Berg-Emons R., Wallin E., Witzenrath M., Wu Y., Xu H., Zoller T., Adolph C., Albright J., Amlag J. O., Aravkin A. Y., Bang-Jensen B. L., Bisignano C., Castellano R., Castro E., Chakrabarti S., Collins J. K., Dai X., Daoud F., Dapper C., Deen A., Duncan B. B., Erickson M., Ewald S. B., Ferrari A. J., Flaxman A. D., Fullman N., Gamkrelidze A., Giles J. R., Guo G., Hay S. I., He J., Helak M., Hulland E. N., Kereselidze M., Krohn K. J., Lazzar-Atwood A., Lindstrom A., Lozano R., Malta D. C., M&#xe5;nsson J., Mantilla Herrera A. M., Mokdad A. H., Monasta L., Nomura S., Pasovic M., Pigott D. M., Reiner R. C., Reinke G., Ribeiro A. L. P., Santomauro D. F., Sholokhov A., Spurlock E. E., Walcott R., Walker A., Wiysonge C. S., Zheng P., Bettger J. P., Murray C. J. L., Vos T., Estimated Global Proportions of Individuals With Persistent Fatigue, Cognitive, and Respiratory Symptom Clusters Following Symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA 328, 1604&#x2013;1615 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A., Nirantharakumar K., Hughes S., Myles P., Williams T., Gokhale K. M., Taverner T., Chandan J. S., Brown K., Simms-Williams N., Shah A. D., Singh M., Kidy F., Okoth K., Hotham R., Bashir N., Cockburn N., Lee S. I., Turner G. M., Gkoutos G. V., Aiyegbusi O. L., McMullan C., Denniston A. K., Sapey E., Lord J. M., Wraith D. C., Leggett E., Iles C., Marshall T., Price M. J., Marwaha S., Davies E. H., Jackson L. J., Matthews K. L., Camaradou J., Calvert M., Haroon S., Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat. Med. 28, 1706&#x2013;1714 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson E. J., Williams D. M., Walker A. J., Mitchell R. E., Niedzwiedz C. L., Yang T. C., Huggins C. F., Kwong A. S. F., Silverwood R. J., Di Gessa G., Bowyer R. C. E., Northstone K., Hou B., Green M. J., Dodgeon B., Doores K. J., Duncan E. L., Williams F. M. K., OpenSAFELY Collaborative, Steptoe A., Porteous D. J., McEachan R. R. C., Tomlinson L., Goldacre B., Patalay P., Ploubidis G. B., Katikireddi S. V., Tilling K., Rentsch C. T., Timpson N. J., Chaturvedi N., Steves C. J., Long COVID burden and risk factors in 10 UK longitudinal studies and electronic health records. Nat. Commun. 13, 3528 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9240035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35764621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sylvester S. V., Rusu R., Chan B., Bellows M., O&#x2019;Keefe C., Nicholson S., Sex differences in sequelae from COVID-19 infection and in long COVID syndrome: a review. Curr. Med. Res. Opin. 38, 1391&#x2013;1399 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35726132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F., Tomasoni D., Falcinella C., Barbanotti D., Castoldi R., Mul&#xe8; G., Augello M., Mondatore D., Allegrini M., Cona A., Tesoro D., Tagliaferri G., Vigan&#xf2; O., Suardi E., Tincati C., Beringheli T., Varisco B., Battistini C. L., Piscopo K., Vegni E., Tavelli A., Terzoni S., Marchetti G., d&#x2019;Arminio Monforte A., Female gender is associated with long COVID syndrome: a prospective cohort study. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. Off. Publ. Eur. Soc. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. Dis. 28, 611.e9&#x2013;611.e16 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsyth K. S., Jiwrajka N., Lovell C. D., Toothacre N. E., Anguera M. C., The conneXion between sex and immune responses. Nat. Rev. Immunol., 1&#x2013;16 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11216897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38383754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein S. L., Flanagan K. L., Sex differences in immune responses. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 16, 626&#x2013;638 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27546235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang B., Cai Y., Li N., Li K., Wang Z., Li L., Wu L., Zhu M., Li J., Wang Z., Wu M., Li W., Wu W., Zhang L., Xia X., Wang S., Chen H., Wang Q., Sex-based clinical and immunological differences in COVID-19. BMC Infect. Dis. 21, 647 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8256650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34225644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser C., Li J. Z., Eron J. J., Aga E., Daar E. S., Wohl D. A., Coombs R. W., Javan A. C., Bender Ignacio R. A., Jagannathan P., Ritz J., Sieg S. F., Parikh U. M., Hughes M. D., Currier J. S., Smith D. M., Chew K. W., ACTIV-2/A5401 Study Team, Predictors of SARS-CoV-2 RNA From Nasopharyngeal Swabs and Concordance With Other Compartments in Nonhospitalized Adults With Mild to Moderate COVID-19. Open Forum Infect. Dis. 9, ofac618 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9709705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36467293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho J. Q., Sepand M. R., Bigdelou B., Shekarian T., Esfandyarpour R., Chauhan P., Serpooshan V., Beura L. K., Hutter G., Zanganeh S., The immune response to COVID-19: Does sex matter? Immunology 166, 429&#x2013;443 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9111683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35470422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao Y., Hao S., Andersen-Nissen E., Mauck W. M., Zheng S., Butler A., Lee M. J., Wilk A. J., Darby C., Zager M., Hoffman P., Stoeckius M., Papalexi E., Mimitou E. P., Jain J., Srivastava A., Stuart T., Fleming L. M., Yeung B., Rogers A. J., McElrath J. M., Blish C. A., Gottardo R., Smibert P., Satija R., Integrated analysis of multimodal single-cell data. Cell 184, 3573&#x2013;3587.e29 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8238499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34062119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Rouphael N., Duraisingham S., Romero-Steiner S., Presnell S., Davis C., Schmidt D. S., Johnson S. E., Milton A., Rajam G., Kasturi S., Carlone G. M., Quinn C., Chaussabel D., Palucka A. K., Mulligan M. J., Ahmed R., Stephens D. S., Nakaya H. I., Pulendran B., Molecular signatures of antibody responses derived from a systems biology study of five human vaccines. Nat. Immunol. 15, 195&#x2013;204 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3946932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24336226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Padilla C. M. L., Niewold T. B., The Type I Interferons: Basic Concepts and Clinical Relevance in Immune-mediated Inflammatory Diseases. Gene 576, 14&#x2013;21 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26410416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dou D. R., Zhao Y., Belk J. A., Zhao Y., Casey K. M., Chen D. C., Li R., Yu B., Srinivasan S., Abe B. T., Kraft K., Hellstr&#xf6;m C., Sj&#xf6;berg R., Chang S., Feng A., Goldman D. W., Shah A. A., Petri M., Chung L. S., Fiorentino D. F., Lundberg E. K., Wutz A., Utz P. J., Chang H. Y., Xist ribonucleoproteins promote female sex-biased autoimmunity. Cell 187, 733&#x2013;749.e16 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10949934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38306984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szappanos D., Tschismarov R., Perlot T., Westermayer S., Fischer K., Platanitis E., Kallinger F., Novatchkova M., Lassnig C., M&#xfc;ller M., Sexl V., Bennett K. L., Foong-Sobis M., Penninger J. M., Decker T., The RNA helicase DDX3X is an essential mediator of innate antimicrobial immunity. PLoS Pathog. 14, e1007397 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6283616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30475900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt M. H., Goulmy E., Kloosterboer F. M., Blokland E., de Paus R. A., Willemze R., Falkenburg J. H., UTY gene codes for an HLA-B60-restricted human male-specific minor histocompatibility antigen involved in stem cell graft rejection: characterization of the critical polymorphic amino acid residues for T-cell recognition. Blood 96, 3126&#x2013;3132 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11049993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren E. H., Gavin M. A., Simpson E., Chandler P., Page D. C., Disteche C., Stankey K. A., Greenberg P. D., Riddell S. R., The human UTY gene encodes a novel HLA-B8-restricted H-Y antigen. J. Immunol. Baltim. Md 1950 164, 2807&#x2013;2814 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10679124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L., Cao J., Cai W. L., Lang S. M., Horton J. R., Jansen D. J., Liu Z. Z., Chen J. F., Zhang M., Mott B. T., Pohida K., Rai G., Kales S. C., Henderson M. J., Hu X., Jadhav A., Maloney D. J., Simeonov A., Zhu S., Iwasaki A., Hall M. D., Cheng X., Shadel G. S., Yan Q., KDM5 histone demethylases repress immune response via suppression of STING. PLoS Biol. 16, e2006134 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6095604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30080846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiu L., Ma B., Ding L., Antioncogenic roles of USP9Y and DDX3Y in lung cancer: USP9Y stabilizes DDX3Y by preventing its degradation through deubiquitination. Acta Histochem. 126, 152132 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38217953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browaeys R., Gilis J., Sang-Aram C., Bleser P. D., Hoste L., Tavernier S., Lambrechts D., Seurinck R., Saeys Y., MultiNicheNet: a flexible framework for differential cell-cell communication analysis from multi-sample multi-condition single-cell transcriptomics data, 2023.06.13.544751 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson M. J., Role of chemokines in the biology of natural killer cells. J. Leukoc. Biol. 71, 173&#x2013;183 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11818437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Z., Zhou C., Zhou L., Wang Z., Zhu X., Mu X., Overexpression of DAPK1-mediated inhibition of IKK&#x3b2;/CSN5/PD-L1 axis enhances natural killer cell killing ability and inhibits tumor immune evasion in gastric cancer. Cell. Immunol. 372, 104469 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35114597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma&#x15b;likowski B. M., Wang L., Wu Y., Fielding B., B&#xe9;dard P.-A., JunD/AP-1 Antagonizes the Induction of DAPK1 To Promote the Survival of v-Src-Transformed Cells. J. Virol. 91, 10.1128/jvi.01925-16 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jvi.01925-16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5165225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27795443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reich N. C., A Death-Promoting Role for ISG54/IFIT2. J. Interferon Cytokine Res. 33, 199&#x2013;205 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3624773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23570386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder L., Herwartz C., Jordanovski D., Steger G., ZNF395 Is an Activator of a Subset of IFN-Stimulated Genes. Mediators Inflamm. 2017, 1248201 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5339479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28316371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubois C. M., Blanchette F., Laprise M. H., Leduc R., Grondin F., Seidah N. G., Evidence that furin is an authentic transforming growth factor-beta1-converting enzyme. Am. J. Pathol. 158, 305&#x2013;316 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1850265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11141505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X.-Q., Zhang Q.-Q., Zhang H.-Y., Guo X.-H., Fan H.-Q., Liu L.-X., Interaction between insulin-like growth factor binding protein-related protein 1 and transforming growth factor beta 1 in primary hepatic stellate cells. Hepatobiliary Pancreat. Dis. Int. HBPD INT 16, 395&#x2013;404 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28823370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang G., Lu J., Yang M., Wang Y., Liu H., Xu C., Elevated GALNT10 expression identifies immunosuppressive microenvironment and dismal prognosis of patients with high grade serous ovarian cancer. Cancer Immunol. Immunother. CII 69, 175&#x2013;187 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11027854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31853576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cain S. A., Woods S., Singh M., Kimber S. J., Baldock C., ADAMTS6 cleaves the large latent TGF&#x3b2; complex and increases the mechanotension of cells to activate TGF&#x3b2;. Matrix Biol. 114, 18&#x2013;34 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36368447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanagisawa K., Osada H., Masuda A., Kondo M., Saito T., Yatabe Y., Takagi K., Takahashi T., Takahashi T., Induction of apoptosis by Smad3 and down-regulation of Smad3 expression in response to TGF-&#x3b2; in human normal lung epithelial cells. Oncogene 17, 1743&#x2013;1747 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9796704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matassa D. S., Amoroso M. R., Maddalena F., Landriscina M., Esposito F., New insights into TRAP1 pathway. Am. J. Cancer Res. 2, 235&#x2013;248 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3304566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22432061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua G., Zhang Q., Fan Z., Heat shock protein 75 (TRAP1) antagonizes reactive oxygen species generation and protects cells from granzyme M-mediated apoptosis. J. Biol. Chem. 282, 20553&#x2013;20560 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17513296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taveirne S., Wahlen S., Van Loocke W., Kiekens L., Persyn E., Van Ammel E., De Mulder K., Roels J., Tilleman L., Aumercier M., Matthys P., Van Nieuwerburgh F., Kerre T. C. C., Taghon T., Van Vlierberghe P., Vandekerckhove B., Leclercq G., The transcription factor ETS1 is an important regulator of human NK cell development and terminal differentiation. Blood 136, 288&#x2013;298 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32350509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen D., Tang T.-X., Deng H., Yang X.-P., Tang Z.-H., Interleukin-7 Biology and Its Effects on Immune Cells: Mediator of Generation, Differentiation, Survival, and Homeostasis. Front. Immunol. 12 (2021) (available at 10.3389/fimmu.2021.747324).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.747324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8674869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34925323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J.-H., Yu Q., Erman B., Appelbaum J. S., Montoya-Durango D., Grimes H. L., Singer A., Suppression of IL7R&#x3b1; Transcription by IL-7 and Other Prosurvival Cytokines: A Novel Mechanism for Maximizing IL-7-Dependent T Cell Survival. Immunity 21, 289&#x2013;302 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15308108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takada Y. K., Yu J., Shimoda M., Takada Y., Integrin Binding to the Trimeric Interface of CD40L Plays a Critical Role in CD40/CD40L Signaling. J. Immunol. Baltim. Md 1950 203, 1383&#x2013;1391 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31331973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takada Y. K., Shimoda M., Maverakis E., Felding B. H., Cheng R. H., Takada Y., Soluble CD40L activates soluble and cell-surface integrin &#x3b1;v&#x3b2;3, &#x3b1;5&#x3b2;1, and &#x3b1;4&#x3b2;1 by binding to the allosteric ligand-binding site (site 2). J. Biol. Chem. 296, 100399 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7960543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33571526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Gao D., Lunsford K. E., Frankel W. L., Bumgardner G. L., Targeting LFA-1 synergizes with CD40/CD40L blockade for suppression of both CD4-dependent and CD8-dependent rejection. Am. J. Transplant. Off. J. Am. Soc. Transplant. Am. Soc. Transpl. Surg. 3, 1251&#x2013;1258 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14510698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinistro A., Almerighi C., Ciaprini C., Natoli S., Sussarello E., Di Fino S., Cal&#xf2;-Carducci F., Rocchi G., Bergamini A., Downregulation of CD40 ligand response in monocytes from sepsis patients. Clin. Vaccine Immunol. CVI 15, 1851&#x2013;1858 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2593171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18945879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elgueta R., Benson M. J., de Vries V. C., Wasiuk A., Guo Y., Noelle R. J., Molecular mechanism and function of CD40/CD40L engagement in the immune system. Immunol. Rev. 229, 10.1111/j.1600-065X.2009.00782.x (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-065X.2009.00782.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3826168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19426221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perera P.-Y., Lichy J. H., Waldmann T. A., Perera L. P., The role of Interleukin-15 in inflammation and immune responses to infection: implications for its therapeutic use. Microbes Infect. Inst. Pasteur 14, 247&#x2013;261 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3270128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22064066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tau G., Rothman P., Biologic functions of the IFN-&#x3b3; receptors. Allergy 54, 1233&#x2013;1251 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4154595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10688427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pimentel J. M., Zhou J.-Y., Wu G. S., The Role of TRAIL in Apoptosis and Immunosurveillance in Cancer. Cancers 15, 2752 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10216286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37345089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao T. V., Hu Z., Ohtsuki S., Jin K., Wu B., Berry G. J., Frye R. L., Goronzy J. J., Weyand C. M., Hyperactivity of the CD155 immune checkpoint suppresses anti-viral immunity in patients with coronary artery disease. Nat. Cardiovasc. Res. 1, 634&#x2013;648 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9974158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36860353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reymond N., Imbert A.-M., Devilard E., Fabre S., Chabannon C., Xerri L., Farnarier C., Cantoni C., Bottino C., Moretta A., Dubreuil P., Lopez M., DNAM-1 and PVR regulate monocyte migration through endothelial junctions. J. Exp. Med. 199, 1331&#x2013;1341 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2211807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15136589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobosh B., Zandi K., Giraldo D. M., Goh S. L., Musall K., Aldeco M., LeCher J., Giacalone V. D., Yang J., Eddins D. J., Bhasin M., Ghosn E., Sukhatme V., Schinazi R. F., Tirouvanziam R., Baricitinib attenuates the proinflammatory phase of COVID-19 driven by lung-infiltrating monocytes. Cell Rep. 39, 110945 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9130711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35688145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stikker B. S., Stik G., van Ouwerkerk A. F., Trap L., Spicuglia S., Hendriks R. W., Stadhouders R., Severe COVID-19-associated variants linked to chemokine receptor gene control in monocytes and macrophages. Genome Biol. 23, 96 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9009160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35421995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoggins J. W., Rice C. M., Interferon-stimulated genes and their antiviral effector functions. Curr. Opin. Virol. 1, 519&#x2013;525 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3274382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22328912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xfc;nvogel O., Esser-Nobis K., Reustle A., Schult P., M&#xfc;ller B., Metz P., Trippler M., Windisch M. P., Frese M., Binder M., Fackler O., Bartenschlager R., Ruggieri A., Lohmann V., DDX60L Is an Interferon-Stimulated Gene Product Restricting Hepatitis C Virus Replication in Cell Culture. J. Virol. 89, 10548&#x2013;10568 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4580188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26269178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng X., Yang D., Yu R., Zhu H., EPSTI1 Is Involved in IL-28A-Mediated Inhibition of HCV Infection. Mediators Inflamm. 2015, 716315 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4469844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26146465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parthasarathy S., Fehr A. R., PARP14: A key ADP-ribosylating protein in host-virus interactions? PLoS Pathog. 18, e1010535 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9182250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35679255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubel P., Urban C., Bergant V., Schneider W. M., Knauer B., Stukalov A., Scaturro P., Mann A., Brunotte L., Hoffmann H. H., Schoggins J. W., Schwemmle M., Mann M., Rice C. M., Pichlmair A., A protein-interaction network of interferon-stimulated genes extends the innate immune system landscape. Nat. Immunol. 20, 493&#x2013;502 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30833792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verhelst J., Parthoens E., Schepens B., Fiers W., Saelens X., Interferon-inducible protein Mx1 inhibits influenza virus by interfering with functional viral ribonucleoprotein complex assembly. J. Virol. 86, 13445&#x2013;13455 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3503048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23015724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Pietro A., Kajaste-Rudnitski A., Oteiza A., Nicora L., Towers G. J., Mechti N., Vicenzi E., TRIM22 inhibits influenza A virus infection by targeting the viral nucleoprotein for degradation. J. Virol. 87, 4523&#x2013;4533 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3624352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23408607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Z., Yan Q., Cao W., Liu Z., Wang X., Identification of key molecules in COVID-19 patients significantly correlated with clinical outcomes by analyzing transcriptomic data. Front. Immunol. 13, 930866 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9441550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36072597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei C., Meng F., Wang X., Yan S., Zheng Q., Zhang X., Fu W., Xue J., Wang S., He Y., Sun X., Jiang X., Wang Y., CD30L is involved in the regulation of the inflammatory response through inducing homing and differentiation of monocytes via CCL2/CCR2 axis and NF-&#x3ba;B pathway in mice with colitis. Int. Immunopharmacol. 110, 108934 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35834956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baillie K., Davies H. E., Keat S. B. K., Ladell K., Miners K. L., Jones S. A., Mellou E., Toonen E. J. M., Price D. A., Morgan B. P., Zelek W. M., Complement dysregulation is a prevalent and therapeutically amenable feature of long COVID. Med N. Y. N 5, 239&#x2013;253.e5 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38359836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyashita M., Oshiumi H., Matsumoto M., Seya T., DDX60, a DEXD/H box helicase, is a novel antiviral factor promoting RIG-I-like receptor-mediated signaling. Mol. Cell. Biol. 31, 3802&#x2013;3819 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3165724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21791617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeDiego M. L., Martinez-Sobrido L., Topham D. J., Novel Functions of IFI44L as a Feedback Regulator of Host Antiviral Responses. J. Virol. 93, e01159&#x2013;19 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6803278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31434731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Q., Wang D., Lin R., Lv Q., Wang W., IFI44 is an immune evasion biomarker for SARS-CoV-2 and Staphylococcus aureus infection in patients with RA. Front. Immunol. 13, 1013322 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9520788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36189314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aksentijevich I., Masters S. L., Ferguson P. J., Dancey P., Frenkel J., van Royen-Kerkhoff A., Laxer R., Tedg&#xe5;rd U., Cowen E. W., Pham T.-H., Booty M., Estes J. D., Sandler N. G., Plass N., Stone D. L., Turner M. L., Hill S., Butman J. A., Schneider R., Babyn P., El-Shanti H. I., Pope E., Barron K., Bing X., Laurence A., Lee C.-C. R., Chapelle D., Clarke G. I., Ohson K., Nicholson M., Gadina M., Yang B., Korman B. D., Gregersen P. K., van Hagen P. M., Hak A. E., Huizing M., Rahman P., Douek D. C., Remmers E. F., Kastner D. L., Goldbach-Mansky R., An autoinflammatory disease with deficiency of the interleukin-1-receptor antagonist. N. Engl. J. Med. 360, 2426&#x2013;2437 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2876877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19494218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Q., Jin Y., Chen X., Ye X., Shen X., Lin M., Zeng C., Zhou T., Zhang J., NF-&#x3ba;B in biology and targeted therapy: new insights and translational implications. Signal Transduct. Target. Ther. 9, 53 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10910037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38433280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oeckinghaus A., Ghosh S., The NF-&#x3ba;B Family of Transcription Factors and Its Regulation. Cold Spring Harb. Perspect. Biol. 1, a000034 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2773619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20066092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilmore T. D., Gerondakis S., The c-Rel Transcription Factor in Development and Disease. Genes Cancer 2, 695&#x2013;711 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3218406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22207895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atsaves V., Leventaki V., Rassidakis G. Z., Claret F. X., AP-1 Transcription Factors as Regulators of Immune Responses in Cancer. Cancers 11, 1037 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6678392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31340499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassuk A. G., Leiden J. M., A direct physical association between ETS and AP-1 transcription factors in normal human T cells. Immunity 3, 223&#x2013;237 (1995).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7648395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrett-Sinha L. A., Review of Ets1 structure, function, and roles in immunity. Cell. Mol. Life Sci. CMLS 70, 3375&#x2013;3390 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3636162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23288305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim C. J., Lee C.-G., Jung J.-Y., Ghosh A., Hasan S. N., Hwang S.-M., Kang H., Lee C., Kim G.-C., Rudra D., Suh C.-H., Im S.-H., The Transcription Factor Ets1 Suppresses T Follicular Helper Type 2 Cell Differentiation to Halt the Onset of Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Immunity 49, 1034&#x2013;1048.e8 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30566881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller A. M., Role of IL-33 in inflammation and disease. J. Inflamm. Lond. Engl. 8, 22 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3175149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21871091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saikruang W., Ang Yan Ping L., Abe H., Kasumba D. M., Kato H., Fujita T., The RNA helicase DDX3 promotes IFNB transcription via enhancing IRF-3/p300 holocomplex binding to the IFNB promoter. Sci. Rep. 12, 3967 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8913847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35273248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodansky A., Wang C.-Y., Saxena A., Mitchell A., Kung A. F., Takahashi S., Anglin K., Huang B., Hoh R., Lu S., Goldberg S. A., Romero J., Tran B., Kirtikar R., Grebe H., So M., Greenhouse B., Durstenfeld M. S., Hsue P. Y., Hellmuth J., Kelly J. D., Martin J. N., Anderson M. S., Deeks S. G., Henrich T. J., DeRisi J. L., Peluso M. J., Autoantigen profiling reveals a shared post-COVID signature in fully recovered and long COVID patients. JCI Insight 8, e169515 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10393220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37288661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witkowski M., Tizian C., Ferreira-Gomes M., Niemeyer D., Jones T. C., Heinrich F., Frischbutter S., Angermair S., Hohnstein T., Mattiola I., Nawrath P., McEwen S., Zocche S., Viviano E., Heinz G. A., Maurer M., K&#xf6;lsch U., Chua R. L., Aschman T., Meisel C., Radke J., Sawitzki B., Roehmel J., Allers K., Moos V., Schneider T., Hanitsch L., Mall M. A., Conrad C., Radbruch H., Duerr C. U., Trapani J. A., Marcenaro E., Kallinich T., Corman V. M., Kurth F., Sander L. E., Drosten C., Treskatsch S., Durek P., Kruglov A., Radbruch A., Mashreghi M.-F., Diefenbach A., Untimely TGF&#x3b2; responses in COVID-19 limit antiviral functions of NK cells. Nature 600, 295&#x2013;301 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34695836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorelik L., Constant S., Flavell R. A., Mechanism of transforming growth factor beta-induced inhibition of T helper type 1 differentiation. J. Exp. Med. 195, 1499&#x2013;1505 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2193549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12045248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorelik L., Flavell R. A., Transforming growth factor-beta in T-cell biology. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2, 46&#x2013;53 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11905837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blundell S., Ray K. K., Buckland M., White P. D., Chronic fatigue syndrome and circulating cytokines: A systematic review. Brain. Behav. Immun. 50, 186&#x2013;195 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26148446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva Julio, Takahashi Takehiro, Wood Jamie, Lu Peiwen, Tabachnikova Alexandra, Gehlhausen Jeff R., Greene Kerrie, Bhattacharjee Bornali, Valter Silva Monteiro Carolina Lucas, Dhodapkar Rahul M., Tabacof Laura, Mario Pe&#xf1;a-Hernandez Kathy Kamath, Mao Tianyang, Mccarthy Dayna, Medzhitov Ruslan, David van Dijk Harlan M. Krumholz, Guan Leying, Putrino David, Iwasaki Akiko, Sex differences in symptomatology and immune profiles of Long COVID. medRxiv, 2024.02.29.24303568 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riou C., Dumont A. R., Yassine-Diab B., Haddad E. K., Sekaly R.-P., IL-4 influences the differentiation and the susceptibility to activation-induced cell death of human naive CD8+ T cells. Int. Immunol. 18, 827&#x2013;835 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16611649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesundara D. K., Tscharke D. C., Jackson R. J., Ranasinghe C., Reduced interleukin-4 receptor &#x3b1; expression on CD8+ T cells correlates with higher quality anti-viral immunity. PloS One 8, e55788 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3561338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23383283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro M., Corren J., Pavord I. D., Maspero J., Wenzel S., Rabe K. F., Busse W. W., Ford L., Sher L., FitzGerald J. M., Katelaris C., Tohda Y., Zhang B., Staudinger H., Pirozzi G., Amin N., Ruddy M., Akinlade B., Khan A., Chao J., Martincova R., Graham N. M. H., Hamilton J. D., Swanson B. N., Stahl N., Yancopoulos G. D., Teper A., Dupilumab Efficacy and Safety in Moderate-to-Severe Uncontrolled Asthma. N. Engl. J. Med. 378, 2486&#x2013;2496 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29782217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID - Household Pulse Survey - COVID-19 (2024) (available at https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/covid19/pulse/long-covid.htm).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson K. B., Rao M., Bonilla H., Subramanian A., Hack I., Madrigal M., Singh U., Jagannathan P., Grant P., Patients With Uncomplicated Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Have Long-Term Persistent Symptoms and Functional Impairment Similar to Patients with Severe COVID-19: A Cautionary Tale During a Global Pandemic. Clin. Infect. Dis. Off. Publ. Infect. Dis. Soc. Am. 73, e826&#x2013;e829 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33624010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris P. A., Taylor R., Thielke R., Payne J., Gonzalez N., Conde J. G., Research electronic data capture (REDCap)--a metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J. Biomed. Inform. 42, 377&#x2013;381 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2700030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18929686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris P. A., Taylor R., Minor B. L., Elliott V., Fernandez M., O&#x2019;Neal L., McLeod L., Delacqua G., Delacqua F., Kirby J., Duda S. N., REDCap Consortium, The REDCap consortium: Building an international community of software platform partners. J. Biomed. Inform. 95, 103208 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7254481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31078660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagannathan P., Andrews J. R., Bonilla H., Hedlin H., Jacobson K. B., Balasubramanian V., Purington N., Kamble S., de Vries C. R., Quintero O., Feng K., Ley C., Winslow D., Newberry J., Edwards K., Hislop C., Choong I., Maldonado Y., Glenn J., Bhatt A., Blish C., Wang T., Khosla C., Pinsky B. A., Desai M., Parsonnet J., Singh U., Peginterferon Lambda-1a for treatment of outpatients with uncomplicated COVID-19: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Nat. Commun. 12, 1967 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8009873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holubar M., Subramanian A., Purington N., Hedlin H., Bunning B., Walter K. S., Bonilla H., Boumis A., Chen M., Clinton K., Dewhurst L., Epstein C., Jagannathan P., Kaszynski R. H., Panu L., Parsonnet J., Ponder E. L., Quintero O., Sefton E., Singh U., Soberanis L., Truong H., Andrews J. R., Desai M., Khosla C., Maldonado Y., Favipiravir for Treatment of Outpatients With Asymptomatic or Uncomplicated Coronavirus Disease 2019: A Double-Blind, Randomized, Placebo-Controlled, Phase 2 Trial. Clin. Infect. Dis. Off. Publ. Infect. Dis. Soc. Am. 75, 1883&#x2013;1892 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35446944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zunder E. R., Finck R., Behbehani G. K., Amir E. D., Krishnaswamy S., Gonzalez V. D., Lorang C. G., Bjornson Z., Spitzer M. H., Bodenmiller B., Fantl W. J., Pe&#x2019;er D., Nolan G. P., Palladium-based mass tag cell barcoding with a doublet-filtering scheme and single-cell deconvolution algorithm. Nat. Protoc. 10, 316&#x2013;333 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4347881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25612231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finck R., Simonds E. F., Jager A., Krishnaswamy S., Sachs K., Fantl W., Pe&#x2019;er D., Nolan G. P., Bendall S. C., Normalization of mass cytometry data with bead standards. Cytometry A 83A, 483&#x2013;494 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3688049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23512433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowell H., Zanotelli V., Chevrier S., Robinson M., CATALYST: Cytometry dATa anALYSis Tools Bioconductor (available at http://bioconductor.org/packages/CATALYST/).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liaw A., Wiener M., Classification and regression by randomForest. R News 2, 18&#x2013;22 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevola (kathy-nevola) K., Sandin (marisand) M., Guess (jrguess) J., Forsberg (simfor) S., Cambronero (Orbmac) C., Pucholt (AskPascal) P., Zhang (boxizhang) B., Sheikhi (MasoumehSheikhi) M., Diamanti (klevdiamanti) K., Kar (amrita-kar) A., Conze (leiliuC) L., Hod&#xe9;n (kristianHoden) K., Eriksson (b_watcher) P., Moloney N., L&#xf6;tstedt B., Sprecher E., Barbagallo (jbarbagallo) J., Mansson (olofmansson) O., Caster (OlaCaster) O., Olink, OlinkAnalyze: Facilitate Analysis of Proteomic Data from Olink (2024) (available at https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/OlinkAnalyze/index.html).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azimuth (available at https://azimuth.hubmapconsortium.org/references/human_pbmc/).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy D. J., Campbell K. R., Lun A. T. L., Wills Q. F., Scater: pre-processing, quality control, normalization and visualization of single-cell RNA-seq data in R. Bioinformatics 33, 1179&#x2013;1186 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5408845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28088763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lun A. T. L., McCarthy D. J., Marioni J. C., A step-by-step workflow for low-level analysis of single-cell RNA-seq data with Bioconductor. F1000Research 5, 2122 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5112579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27909575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Love M. I., Huber W., Anders S., Moderated estimation of fold change and dispersion for RNA-seq data with DESeq2. Genome Biol. 15, 550 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4302049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25516281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowell H. L., Germain P., Soneson C., Sonrel A., Robinson M. D., muscat: Multi-sample multi-group scRNA-seq data analysis tools. (available at https://github.com/HelenaLC/muscat).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beisser D., Klau G. W., Dandekar T., M&#xfc;ller T., Dittrich M. T., BioNet: an R-Package for the functional analysis of biological networks. Bioinforma. Oxf. Engl. 26, 1129&#x2013;1130 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20189939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szklarczyk D., Kirsch R., Koutrouli M., Nastou K., Mehryary F., Hachilif R., Gable A. L., Fang T., Doncheva N. T., Pyysalo S., Bork P., Jensen L. J., von Mering C., The STRING database in 2023: protein-protein association networks and functional enrichment analyses for any sequenced genome of interest. Nucleic Acids Res. 51, D638&#x2013;D646 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9825434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36370105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briatte F., Bojanowski M., Canouil M., Charlop-Powers Z., Fisher J. C., Johnson K., Rinker T., ggnetwork: Geometries to Plot Networks with &#x201c;ggplot2&#x201d; (2024) (available at https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ggnetwork/index.html).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann F. J., Simonds E. F., Bendall S. C., A Universal Live Cell Barcoding-Platform for Multiplexed Human Single Cell Analysis. Sci. Rep. 8, 10770 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6050312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30018331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>