<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37665495</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1534-6293</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current neurology and neuroscience reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Headache in COVID-19 and Long COVID: to Know Facts for Clinical Practice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>551</StartPage><EndPage>560</EndPage><MedlinePgn>551-560</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11910-023-01296-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Headache is one of the most frequent symptoms of the acute and post-acute phase of COVID-19. Specific epidemiology, clinical features, risk factors, pathophysiology, and treatment have been reported in these two scenarios. With this narrative review of the literature, we aim to provide updated knowledge on headache in the COVID-19 setting and give clinicians a practical approach on this topic to guide them in their clinical practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Headache mechanisms in COVID-19 are still poorly understood. Strong evidence is also lacking on how to best treat and manage these patients, especially those with persistent and disabling headache after COVID-19. Data are also scarce on the characteristics of headache in COVID-19 caused by the new SARS-CoV-2 (Omicron) variants and how these may influence the acute and persistent symptoms of COVID-19. Patients with pre-existing primary headache disorders remain a particularly concerning population due to their biological predisposition in suffering from headaches and the potential risk of worsening in the setting of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Although there is an exponential growth of scientific evidence, studies are often controversial and focused on the first wave of the pandemic, making COVID-19 headache still a challenging matter for clinicians. New research is therefore needed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>G&#xf3;mez-Dab&#xf3;</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Department, Hospital Universitari Vall d'Hebron, Department of Medicine, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Melgarejo-Mart&#xed;nez</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Department, Hospital Universitari Vall d'Hebron, Department of Medicine, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caronna</LastName><ForeName>Edoardo</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5525-0267</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Headache Unit, Neurology Department, Hospital Universitari Vall d'Hebron, Department of Medicine, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain. edoardo.caronna@vhir.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Headache and Neurological Pain Research Group, Vall d'Hebron Research Institute, Department of Medicine, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Ps. Vall d'Hebron 119-129, 08035, Barcelona, Spain. edoardo.caronna@vhir.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pozo-Rosich</LastName><ForeName>Patricia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Headache Unit, Neurology Department, Hospital Universitari Vall d'Hebron, Department of Medicine, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Headache and Neurological Pain Research Group, Vall d'Hebron Research Institute, Department of Medicine, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Ps. Vall d'Hebron 119-129, 08035, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100931790</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1528-4042</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Headache</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-COVID syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37665495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11910-023-01296-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11910-023-01296-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Papers of particular interest, published recently, have been highlighted as: &#x2022; Of importance &#x2022;&#x2022;&#xa0;Of&#xa0;major&#xa0;importance</Title><Reference><Citation>&#x2022;&#x2022; Caronna E, Ballv&#xe9; A, Llaurad&#xf3; A, Gallardo VJ, Mar&#xed;a Ariton D, Lallana S, et al. Headache: a striking prodromal and persistent symptom, predictive of COVID-19 clinical evolution. Cephalalgia. 2020;40(13):1410&#x2013;21. First prospective study describing COVID-19 headache (incidence, characteristics, related inflammatory responses etc), observing that presence of headache in the acute phase of COVID-19 is predictive of a shorter disease duration.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caronna E, Alpuente A, Torres-Ferrus M, Pozo-Rosich P. Toward a better understanding of persistent headache after mild COVID-19: three migraine-like yet distinct scenarios. Headache. 2021;61(8):1277&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34363619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8444902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.14197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampaio Rocha-Filho PA. Headache associated with COVID-19: epidemiology, characteristics, pathophysiology, and management. Headache. 2022;62(6):650&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35545780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9348060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.14319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tana C, Bentivegna E, Cho SJ, Harriott AM, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Labastida-Ramirez A, et al. Long COVID headache. J Headache Pain. 2022;23:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s10194-022-01450-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronavirus Search Trends-Google Trends. https://trends.google.com/trends/story/GB_cu_JSW_pHABAADqAM_en . Accessed 8 April 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olesen J. Headache Classification Committee of the International Headache Society (IHS) The International Classification of Headache Disorders, 3rd edition. Cephalalgia. 2018;38(1):1&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-2982.2008.01709.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan SM, Farland LV, Catalfamo CJ, Austhof E, Bell ML, Chen Z, et al. Elucidating symptoms of COVID-19 illness in the Arizona CoVHORT: a longitudinal cohort study. BMJ Open. 2022;12(1):e053403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant MC, Geoghegan L, Arbyn M, Mohammed Z, McGuinness L, Clarke EL, et al. The prevalence of symptoms in 24,410 adults infected by the novel coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2; COVID-19): a systematic review and meta-analysis of 148 studies from 9 countries. PloS One. 2020;15(6):e0234765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N, Zhou M, Dong X, Qu J, Gong F, Han Y, et al. Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of 99 cases of 2019 novel coronavirus pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a descriptive study. Lancet. 2020;395(10223):507&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32007143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7135076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30211-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro E, Priori A, Beghi E, Helbok R, Campiglio L, Bassetti CL, et al. The international European Academy of Neurology survey on neurological symptoms in patients with COVID-19 infection. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27(9):1727&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32558002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7323212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misra S, Kolappa K, Prasad M, Radhakrishnan D, Thakur KT, Solomon T, et al. Frequency of neurologic manifestations in COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurology. 2021;97(23):E2269&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34635561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8665434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000012930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Arendt-Nielsen L, et al. Headache as an acute and post-COVID-19 symptom in COVID-19 survivors: a meta-analysis of the current literature. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28(11):3820&#x2013;5. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34327787/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34327787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8444899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uygun &#xd6;, Erta&#x15f; M, Ekizo&#x11f;lu E, Bolay H, &#xd6;zge A, Kocasoy Orhan E, et al. Headache characteristics in COVID-19 pandemic-a survey study. J Headache Pain. 2020;21(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Trigo J, Talavera B, Mart&#xed;nez-P&#xed;as E, Sierra &#xc1;, Porta-Etessam J, et al. Frequency and type of red flags in patients with Covid-19 and headache: a series of 104 hospitalized patients. Headache. 2020;60(8):1664&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7436570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.13927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha-Filho PAS, Magalh&#xe3;es JE. Headache associated with COVID-19: frequency, characteristics and association with anosmia and ageusia. Cephalalgia. 2020;40(13):1443&#x2013;51. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33146035/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33146035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7645592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0333102420966770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vihta KD, Pouwels KB, Peto TEA, Pritchard E, Eyre DW, House T, et al. Symptoms and severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) positivity in the general population in the United Kingdom. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;75(1):E329&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34748629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Cuadrado ML, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Torres-Macho J, Pellicer-Valero OJ, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, et al. Headache as a COVID-19 onset symptom and post-COVID-19 symptom in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors infected with the Wuhan, Alpha, or Delta SARS-CoV-2 variants. Headache. 2022;62(9):1148&#x2013;52. The authors conducted a comparison of acute and post-acute COVID-19 symptoms, such as headache, among individuals who were not vaccinated during three different waves of the pandemic, providing data on three different SARS-CoV-2 variants (Wuhan, Alpha or Delta).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham MS, Sudre CH, May A, Antonelli M, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Changes in symptomatology, reinfection, and transmissibility associated with the SARS-CoV-2 variant B.1.1.7: an ecological study. Lancet. Public Health. 2021;6(5):e335&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33857453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JJ, Choe YJ, Jeong H, Kim M, Kim S, Yoo H, et al. Importation and transmission of SARS-CoV-2 B.1.1.529 (Omicron) variant of concern in Korea. J Korean Med Sci. 2021;36(50):e346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacobucci G. Covid-19: GPs urge government to clear up confusion over symptoms. BMJ. 2021;373:n1654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meo SA, Meo AS, Al-Jassir FF, Klonoff DC. Omicron SARS-CoV-2 new variant: global prevalence and biological and clinical characteristics. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2021;25(24):8012&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34982465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandal LT, MacDonald E, Veneti L, Ravlo T, Lange H, Naseer U, et al. Outbreak caused by the SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variant in Norway, November to December 2021. Eurosurveillance. 2021;26(50):2101147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34915975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8728491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2021.26.50.2101147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vihta KD, Pouwels KB, Peto TE, Pritchard E, House T, Studley R, et al. Omicron-associated changes in SARS-CoV-2 symptoms in the United Kingdom. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;2:133&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirca F, Aydo&#x1e7;an S, G&#xf6;zalan A, Kayipmaz AE, &#xd6;zdemir FAE, Tek&#xe7;e YT, et al. Comparison of clinical characteristics of wild-type SARS-CoV-2 and Omicron. Rev Assoc Med Bras. 2022;68(10):1476&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36417656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9683927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1806-9282.20220880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang N, Wang C, Huang J, Dong J, Ye J, Fu Y, et al. Clinical and pulmonary CT characteristics of patients infected with the SARS-CoV-2 omicron variant compared with those of patients infected with the alpha viral strain. Front Public Health. 2022;10:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8(5):416&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00084-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(4):e102&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022;&#x2022; Garcia-Azorin D, Layos-Romero A, Porta-Etessam J, Membrilla JA, Caronna E, Gonzalez-Martinez A, et al. Post-COVID-19 persistent headache: a multicentric 9-months follow-up study of 905 patients. Cephalalgia. 2022;42(8):804&#x2013;9. Prospective study, investigating headache in the post-acute phase (until 9 months since infection). They demonstrated that headache intensity during the acute phase, but not previous migraine history, is associated with more prolonged duration of headache.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morioka S, Tsuzuki S, Suzuki M, Terada M, Akashi M, Osanai Y, et al. Post COVID-19 condition of the Omicron variant of SARS-CoV-2. J Infect Chemother. 2022;28(11):1546&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35963600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9365517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiac.2022.08.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARSCoV-2. Lancet. 2022;399(10343):2263-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(22)00941-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du M, Ma Y, Deng J, Liu M, Liu J. Comparison of long COVID-19 caused by different SARS-CoV-2 strains: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(23):16010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caronna E, Pozo-Rosich P. Headache as a symptom of COVID-19: narrative review of 1-year research. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 1916;1:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toptan T, Aktan &#xc7;, Ba&#x15f;ar&#x131; A, Bolay H. Case series of headache characteristics in COVID-19: headache can be an isolated symptom. Headache. 2020;60(8):1788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7436308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.13940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Planchuelo-G&#xf3;mez &#xc1;, Trigo J, de Luis-Garc&#xed;a R, Guerrero &#xc1;L, Porta-Etessam J, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D. Deep phenotyping of headache in hospitalized COVID-19 patients via principal component analysis. Front Neurol. 2020;11:583870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez JT, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Planchuelo-G&#xf3;mez &#xc1;, Garc&#xed;a-Iglesias C, Due&#xf1;as-Guti&#xe9;rrez C, Guerrero &#xc1;L. Phenotypic characterization of acute headache attributed to SARS-CoV-2: An ICHD-3 validation study on 106 hospitalized patients. Cephalalgia. 2020;40(13):1432&#x2013;42. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33146037/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33146037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7645601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0333102420965146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Martinez A, Fanjul V, Ramos C, Serrano Ballesteros J, Bustamante M, Villa Mart&#xed; A, et al. Headache during SARS-CoV-2 infection as an early symptom associated with a more benign course of disease: a case-control study. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28(10):3426&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33417287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampaio Rocha-Filho PA, Albuquerque PM, Carvalho LCLS, Dandara Pereira Gama M, Magalh&#xe3;es JE. Headache, anosmia, ageusia and other neurological symptoms in COVID-19: a cross-sectional study. J Headache Pain. 2022;23(1):2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Membrilla JA, de Lorenzo &#xcd;, Sastre M, D&#xed;az de Ter&#xe1;n J. Headache as a cardinal symptom of coronavirus disease 2019: a cross-sectional study. Headache. 2020;60(10):2176&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32989732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7646273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.13967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Sierra &#xc1;, Trigo J, Alberdi A, Blanco M, Calcerrada I, et al. Frequency and phenotype of headache in covid-19: a study of 2194 patients. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):14674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karada&#x15f; &#xd6;, &#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk B, Sonkaya AR, Ta&#x15f;delen B, &#xd6;zge A, Bolay H. Latent class cluster analysis identified hidden headache phenotypes in COVID-19: impact of pulmonary infiltration and IL-6. Neurol Sci. 2021;42(5):1665&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33559789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7870778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-020-04978-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heneka MT, Golenbock D, Latz E, Morgan D, Brown R. Immediate and long-term consequences of COVID-19 infections for the development of neurological disease. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2020;12(1):69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie K, Chan D, Watermeyer T. The cognitive consequences of the COVID-19 epidemic: collateral damage? Brain Commun. 2020;2(2):fcaa069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Cancela-Cilleruelo I, Guerrero-Peral A, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, et al. Post-COVID-19 symptoms 2 years after SARS-CoV-2 infection among hospitalized vs nonhospitalized patients. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(11):e2242106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36378309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9667330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.42106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):16144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Moskatel LS, Smirnoff L. Protracted headache after COVID-19: a case series of 31 patients from a tertiary headache center. Headache. 2022;62(7):903&#x2013;7. Case series describing individuals who converted from episodic to chronic migraine following COVID-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torrente A, Alonge P, Di Stefano V, Baschi R, Ornello R, Correnti E, et al. New-onset headache following COVID-19: an Italian multicentre case series. J Neurol Sci. 2023;446:120591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Do TP, Remmers A, Schytz HW, Schankin C, Nelson SE, Obermann M, et al. Red and orange flags for secondary headaches in clinical practice: SNNOOP10 list. Neurology. 2019;92(3):134&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30587518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6340385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000006697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellul MA, Benjamin L, Singh B, Lant S, Michael BD, Easton A, et al. Neurological associations of COVID-19. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19(9):767&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32622375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7332267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30221-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukushima EFA, Nasser A, Bhargava A, Moudgil S. Post-infectious focal encephalitis due to COVID-19. Germs. 2021;11(1):111&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33898348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8057841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18683/germs.2021.1247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Kruip MJHA, van der Meer NJM, Arbous MS, Gommers DAMPJ, Kant KM, et al. Incidence of thrombotic complications in critically ill ICU patients with COVID-19. Thromb Res. 2020;191:145&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32291094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7146714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.thromres.2020.04.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J, Tacquard C, Severac F, Leonard-Lorant I, Ohana M, Delabranche X, et al. High risk of thrombosis in patients with severe SARS-CoV-2 infection: a multicenter prospective cohort study. Intensive Care Med. 2020;46(6):1089&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32367170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7197634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-020-06062-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva MTT, Lima MA, Torezani G, Soares CN, Dantas C, Brand&#xe3;o CO, et al. Isolated intracranial hypertension associated with COVID-19. Cephalalgia. 2020;40(13):1452&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33146040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7645603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0333102420965963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodigiani C, Iapichino G, Carenzo L, Cecconi M, Ferrazzi P, Sebastian T, et al. Venous and arterial thromboembolic complications in COVID-19 patients admitted to an academic hospital in Milan, Italy. Thromb Res. 2020;191:9&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32353746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7177070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.thromres.2020.04.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel JR, Amick BC, Vyas KS, Bircan E, Boothe D, Nembhard WN. Racial disparities in symptomatology and outcomes of COVID-19 among adults of Arkansas. Prev Med Rep. 2022;28:101840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trigo J, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Planchuelo-G&#xf3;mez &#xc1;, Mart&#xed;nez-P&#xed;as E, Talavera B, Hern&#xe1;ndez-P&#xe9;rez I, et al. Factors associated with the presence of headache in hospitalized COVID-19 patients and impact on prognosis: a retrospective cohort study. J Headache Pain. 2020;21(1):94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Gallardo VJ, Shapiro RE, Caronna E, Pozo-Rosich P. The relationship of headache as a symptom to COVID-19 survival: a systematic review and meta-analysis of survival of 43,169 inpatients with COVID-19. Headache. 2022;62(8):1019&#x2013;1028.&#xa0;Meta-analysis observing a significantly higher survival rate among inpatients with COVID-19 headache compared to those without headache.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maglietta G, Diodati F, Puntoni M, Lazzarelli S, Marcomini B, Patrizi L, et al. Prognostic factors for post-COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Med. 2022;11(6):1541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go&#xeb;rtz YMJ, Van Herck M, Delbressine JM, Vaes AW, Meys R, Machado FVC, et al. Persistent symptoms 3 months after a SARS-CoV-2 infection: the post-COVID-19 syndrome? ERJ Open Res. 2020;6(4):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00542-2020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):626&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Schneider C, Laurent E, Lemaignen A, Beaufils E, Bourbao-Tournois C, Laribi S, et al. Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27(2):258&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmi.2020.09.052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahidy FS, Pan AP, Ahnstedt H, Munshi Y, Choi HA, Tiruneh Y, et al. Sex differences in susceptibility, severity, and outcomes of coronavirus disease 2019: cross-sectional analysis from a diverse US metropolitan area. PloS One. 2021;16(1):e0245556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pivonello R, Auriemma RS, Pivonello C, Isidori AM, Corona G, Colao A, et al. Sex disparities in COVID-19 severity and outcome: are men weaker or women stronger? Neuroendocrinology. 2021;111(11):1066&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33242856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000513346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilotto A, Cristillo V, Cotti Piccinelli S, Zoppi N, Bonzi G, Sattin D, et al. Long-term neurological manifestations of COVID-19: prevalence and predictive factors. Neurol Sci. 2021;42(12):4903&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34523082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8439956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-021-05586-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):601&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, Florencio LL, Guerrero AL, et al. Previous history of migraine is associated with fatigue, but not headache, as long-term post-COVID symptom after severe acute respiratory SARS-CoV-2 infection: a case-control study. Front Hum Neurosci. 2021;15:678472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caronna E, Jos&#xe9; Gallardo V, Alpuente A, Torres-Ferrus M, S&#xe1;nchez-Mateo NM, Viguera-Romero J, et al. Safety of anti-CGRP monoclonal antibodies in patients with migraine during the COVID-19 pandemic: present and future implications. Neurologia. 2021;36(8):611&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34654536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7973059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nrl.2021.03.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magdy R, Elmazny A, Soliman SH, Elsebaie EH, Ali SH, Abdel Fattah AM, et al. Post-COVID-19 neuropsychiatric manifestations among COVID-19 survivors suffering from migraine: a case-control study. J Headache Pain. 2022;23(1):101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigal ME, Serrano D, Buse D, Scher A, Stewart WF, Lipton RB. Acute migraine medications and evolution from episodic to chronic migraine: a longitudinal population-based study. Headache. 2008;48(8):1157&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18808500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1526-4610.2008.01217.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abboud H, Abboud FZ, Kharbouch H, Arkha Y, El Abbadi N, El Ouahabi A. COVID-19 and SARS-Cov-2 infection: pathophysiology and clinical effects on the nervous system. World Neurosurg. 2020;140:49&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32474093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7255736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wneu.2020.05.193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM, Khaleeq A, Ali U, Syeda H. Evidence of the COVID-19 virus targeting the CNS: tissue distribution, host-virus interaction, and proposed neurotropic mechanisms. ACS Chem Nerosci. 2020;11(7):995&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acschemneuro.0c00122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolay H, Karadas &#xd6;, Ozt&#xfc;rk B, Sonkaya R, Tasdelen B, Bulut TDS, et al. HMGB1, NLRP3, IL-6 and ACE2 levels are elevated in COVID-19 with headache: a window to the infection-related headache mechanism. J Headache Pain. 2021;22(1):94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34384355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8358545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s10194-021-01306-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xe1;rate G, Toriello M, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Quintanilla V, P&#xe9;rez-Pereda S, Madera J, Pascual M, et al. Serum alpha-CGRP levels are increased in COVID-19 patients with headache indicating an activation of the trigeminal system. BMC Neurol. 2023;23(1):109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Ani F, Chehade S, Lazo-Langner A. Thrombosis risk associated with COVID-19 infection. A scoping review. Thromb Res. 2020;192:152&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32485418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7255332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.thromres.2020.05.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu TM, Seet CYH, Koh JS, Tham CH, Chiew HJ, De Leon JA, et al. Acute ischemic stroke during the convalescent phase of asymptomatic COVID-2019 infection in men. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(4):e217498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga Z, Flammer AJ, Steiger P, Haberecker M, Andermatt R, Zinkernagel AS, et al. Endothelial cell infection and endotheliitis in COVID-19. Lancet. 2020;395(10234):1417&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7172722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30937-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner R, Myers RR. Endoneurial injection of TNF-alpha produces neuropathic pain behaviors. Neuroreport. 1996;7(18):2897&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9116205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00001756-199611250-00018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragab D, Salah Eldin H, Taeimah M, Khattab R, Salem R. The COVID-19 cytokine storm; what we know so far. Front Immunol. 2020;11:1446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, McAuley DF, Brown M, Sanchez E, Tattersall RS, Manson JJ. COVID-19: consider cytokine storm syndromes and immunosuppression. Lancet. 2020;395(10229):1033&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7270045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30628-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perini F, D&#x2019;Andrea G, Galloni E, Pignatelli F, Billo G, Alba S, et al. Plasma cytokine levels in migraineurs and controls. Headache. 2005;45(7):926&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15985111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1526-4610.2005.05135.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrmann F, Schulz G, Lindemann A, Meyenburg W, Oster W, Krumwieh D, et al. Hematopoietic responses in patients with advanced malignancy treated with recombinant human granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor. J Clin Oncol. 1989;7(2):159&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2644395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.1989.7.2.159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolay H, G&#xfc;l A, Baykan B. COVID-19 is a real headache! Headache. 2020;60(7):1415&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32412101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7272895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.13856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trigo J, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Sierra-Menc&#xed;a &#xc1;, Tamayo-Velasco &#xc1;, Mart&#xed;nez-Paz P, Tamayo E, et al. Cytokine and interleukin profile in patients with headache and COVID-19: a pilot, CASE-control, study on 104 patients. J Headache Pain. 2021;22(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis A, Frontera J, Placantonakis DG, Lighter J, Galetta S, Balcer L, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid in COVID-19: a systematic review of the literature. J Neurol Sci. 2021;421:117316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke J, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Hagel C, Sperhake JP, Schr&#xf6;der AS, Edler C, et al. Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19(11):919&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7535629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30308-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon IH, Normandin E, Bhattacharyya S, Mukerji SS, Keller K, Ali AS, et al. Neuropathological features of Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(10):989&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMc2019373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosentino G, Todisco M, Hota N, Della Porta G, Morbini P, Tassorelli C, et al. Neuropathological findings from COVID-19 patients with neurological symptoms argue against a direct brain invasion of SARS-CoV-2: a critical systematic review. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28(11):3856&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8444743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J, Radke J, Dittmayer C, Franz J, Thomas C, Mothes R, et al. Olfactory transmucosal SARS-CoV-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with COVID-19. Nat Neurosci. 2021;24(2):168&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41593-020-00758-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imboden H, Patil J, Nussberger J, Nicoud F, Hess B, Ahmed N, et al. Endogenous angiotensinergic system in neurons of rat and human trigeminal ganglia. Regul Pept. 2009;154(1&#x2013;3):23&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19323983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2727722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.regpep.2009.02.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang AC, Kern F, Losada PM, Agam MR, Maat CA, Schmartz GP, et al. Dysregulation of brain and choroid plexus cell types in severe COVID-19. Nature. 2021;595(7868):565&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34153974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8400927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-021-03710-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Campion JY, Dudouet P, Kaphan E, Bregeon F, Tissot-Dupont H, et al. 18F-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in patients with long COVID. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48(9):2823&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33501506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7837643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-021-05215-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R, Wang K, Yu J, Howard D, French L, Chen Z, Wen C, Xu Z. The Spatial and Cell-Type Distribution of SARS-CoV-2 Receptor ACE2 in the Human and Mouse Brains. Front Neurol. 2021;11:573095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F, Arthofer C, Wang C, McCarthy P, et al. SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature. 2022;604(7907):697&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9046077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-022-04569-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubair AS, McAlpine LS, Gardin T, Farhadian S, Kuruvilla DE, Spudich S. Neuropathogenesis and neurologic manifestations of the coronaviruses in the age of coronavirus disease 2019: a review. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(8):1018&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7484225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.2065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukiw WJ, Pogue A, Hill JM. SARS-CoV-2 infectivity and neurological targets in the brain. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2022;42(1):217&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32840758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10571-020-00947-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazhenets G, Schroeter N, Bormann T, Thurow J, Wagner D, Frings L, et al. Slow but evident recovery from neocortical dysfunction and cognitive impairment in a series of chronic COVID-19 patients. J Nucl Med. 2021;62(7):910&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8882885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2967/jnumed.121.262128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak GA, Singh K, Miller-Fleming TW, Wendt FR, Ehsan N, Hou K, et al. Integrative genomic analyses identify susceptibility genes underlying COVID-19 hospitalization. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):4569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng W, Adams MJ, Hebert HL, Deary IJ, McIntosh AM, Smith BH. A genome-wide association study finds genetic associations with broadly-defined headache in UK Biobank (N=223,773). EBioMedicine. 2018;28:180&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29397368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5898025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2018.01.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acz&#xe9;l T, Kecsk&#xe9;s A, Kun J, Szenthe K, B&#xe1;n&#xe1;ti F, Szathmary S, et al. Hemokinin-1 gene expression is upregulated in trigeminal ganglia in an inflammatory orofacial pain model: potential role in peripheral sensitization. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(8)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martelletti P, Stirparo G, Morrone S, Rinaldi C, Giacovazzo M. Inhibition of intercellular adhesion molecule-1 (ICAM-1), soluble ICAM-1 and interleukin-4 by nitric oxide expression in migraine patients. J Mol Med. 1997;75(6):448&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9231885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s001090050130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krymchantowski AV, Silva-N&#xe9;to RP, Jevoux C, Krymchantowski AG. Indomethacin for refractory COVID or post-COVID headache: a retrospective study. Acta Neurol Belg. 2022;122(2):465&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34546559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13760-021-01790-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catal&#xe1;n IP, Mart&#xed; CR, Sota DP de la, &#xc1;lvarez AC, Gimeno MJE, Juana SF, et al. Corticosteroids for COVID-19 symptoms and quality of life at 1 year from admission. J Med Virol 2022;94(1):205&#x2013;210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dono F, Consoli S, Evangelista G, D&#x2019;Apolito M, Russo M, Carrarini C, et al. New daily persistent headache after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a report of two cases. Neurol Sci. 2021;42(10):3965&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34264414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8280630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-021-05444-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash S, Shah ND. Post-infectious new daily persistent headache may respond to intravenous methylprednisolone. J Headache Pain. 2010;11(1):59&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19936615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10194-009-0171-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Martinez A, Guerrero-Peral &#xc1;L, Arias-Rivas S, Silva L, Sierra &#xc1;, Gago-Veiga AB, et al. Amitriptyline for post-COVID headache: effectiveness, tolerability, and response predictors. J Neurol. 2022;269(11):5702&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35829760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9553757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-022-11225-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendtsen L, Evers S, Linde M, Mitsikostas DD, Sandrini G, Schoenen J. EFNS guideline on the treatment of tension-type headache - report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17(11):1318&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20482606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-1331.2010.03070.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham EL, Koralnik IJ, Liotta EM. Therapeutic approaches to the neurologic manifestations of COVID-19. Neurotherapeutics. 2022;19(5):1435&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35861926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9302225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-022-01267-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grassini A, Marcinn&#xf2; A, Roveta F, Gallo E, Cermelli A, Boschi S, et al. Impact of COVID-19 on chronic migraine treated with erenumab: a case report. Neurol Sci. 2021;42(8):3079&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34021438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8139216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-021-05329-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93(2):1013&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poyraz B&#xc7;, Poyraz CA, Olgun Y, G&#xfc;rel &#xd6;, Alkan S, &#xd6;zdemir YE, et al. Psychiatric morbidity and protracted symptoms after COVID-19. Psychiatry Res. 2021 Jan;1:295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forchette L, Sebastian W, Liu T. A comprehensive review of COVID-19 virology, vaccines, variants, and therapeutics. Curr Med Sci. 2021;41(6):1037&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34241776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8267225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11596-021-2395-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng OT, Marimuthu K, Lim N, Lim ZQ, Thevasagayam NM, Koh V, et al. Analysis of COVID-19 incidence and severity among adults vaccinated with 2-dose mRNA COVID-19 or inactivated SARS-CoV-2 vaccines with and without boosters in Singapore. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(8):e2228900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36018588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9419014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.28900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchan SA, Chung H, Brown KA, Austin PC, Fell DB, Gubbay JB, et al. Estimated effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccines against omicron or delta symptomatic infection and severe outcomes. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(9):e2232760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36136332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9500552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.32760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strain WD, Sherwood O, Banerjee A, Van der Togt V, Hishmeh L, Rossman J. The impact of COVID vaccination on symptoms of long COVID: an international survey of people with lived experience of long COVID. Vaccines. 2022;10(5):652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35632408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9146071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vaccines10050652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall V, Foulkes S, Insalata F, Kirwan P, Saei A, Atti A, et al. Protection against SARS-CoV-2 after Covid-19 vaccination and previous infection. N Engl J Med. 2022;386(13):1207&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35172051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2118691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe A, Iwagami M, Yasuhara J, Takagi H, Kuno T. Protective effect of COVID-19 vaccination against long COVID syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Vaccine. 2023;41(11):1783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36774332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9905096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2023.02.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>