<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37363406</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1003-5257</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of acupuncture-moxibustion</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Acupunct Moxibustion</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research progress on central mechanism of acupuncture treatment for chronic fatigue syndrome.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.wjam.2023.03.002</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chronic fatigue syndrome is a neurological disorder characterized by extreme fatigue that lasts for a long time and doesn't alleviate with rest. The number of the cases has been increasing during the era of COVID-19 pandemic. Acupuncture may have some effect on chronic fatigue syndrome, but its mechanism remains unclear. This article was to summarize the specific manifestations of abnormal central mechanism in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome through laboratory tests and neuroimaging. It was found from the laboratory evaluation that there were changes in the structure of the frontal cortex, thalamus and other brain tissues; factors, including IFN-&#x3b1; and IL-10 in cerebrospinal fluid were found abnormal; results of oxidative and nitrosative stress and changes in neurobiochemical substances, e.g. hypothalamus hormone levels and neurotransmitter concentrations, were observed. With magnetic resonance imaging and positron emission tomography, it was shown that the partial brain of persons with chronic fatigue syndrome had morphological changes with diminished grey matter and white; changes in cerebral blood flow velocity caused by decreased perfusion and functional activity with abnormal connectivity in brain were detected. In addition, there was significant decrease in glucose metabolism accompanied with neuroinflammatory response; metabolic disorders of serotonergic, cholinergic, glutamatergic and &#x3b3;-aminobutyric acid energy neurotransmitters were also discovered. The regulatory effect of acupuncture on the above central neurological abnormalities in chronic fatigue syndrome model animals was elaborated, and the direction for further research was analyzed in order to provide ideas for further research on the central mechanism of acupuncture treatment for chronic fatigue syndrome.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 World Journal of Acupuncture Moxibustion House. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Bin-Bin</ForeName><Initials>BB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Heilongjiang University of Chinese Medicine, Harbin 150040, China (, 150040, ).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Chu-Wen</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Heilongjiang University of Chinese Medicine, Harbin 150040, China (, 150040, ).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture-Moxibustion, First Affiliated Hospital, Heilongjiang University of Chinese Medicine, Harbin 150040, China (, 150040, ).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qu</LastName><ForeName>Yuan-Yuan</ForeName><Initials>YY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Heilongjiang University of Chinese Medicine, Harbin 150040, China (, 150040, ).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Zhong-Ren</ForeName><Initials>ZR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heilongjiang Key Laboratory of Clinical (Encephalopathy) Neurobiology of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Harbin 150040, China ((), 150040, ).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Heilongjiang University of Chinese Medicine, Harbin 150040, China (, 150040, ).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Lin</ForeName><Initials>YL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture-Moxibustion, Second Affiliated Hospital, Heilongjiang University of Chinese Medicine, Harbin 150001, China (, 150001, ).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Qing-Yong</ForeName><Initials>QY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Heilongjiang University of Chinese Medicine, Harbin 150040, China (, 150040, ).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Heilongjiang University of Chinese Medicine, Harbin 150040, China (, 150040, ).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shao</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Ying</ForeName><Initials>YY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Heilongjiang University of Chinese Medicine, Harbin 150040, China (, 150040, ).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Tian-Song</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture-Moxibustion, First Affiliated Hospital, Heilongjiang University of Chinese Medicine, Harbin 150040, China (, 150040, ).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heilongjiang Key Laboratory of Clinical (Encephalopathy) Neurobiology of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Harbin 150040, China ((), 150040, ).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China</Country><MedlineTA>World J Acupunct Moxibustion</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9303005</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1003-5257</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acupuncture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Central mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic fatigue syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroimaging technology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sequelae of COVID-19</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there is no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37363406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10061266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wjam.2023.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1003-5257(23)00022-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K., Straus S.E., Hickie I., Sharpe M.C., Dobbins J.G., Komaroff A. The chronic fatigue syndrome: a comprehensive approach to its definition and study. International chronic fatigue syndrome study group. Ann Intern Med. 1994;121(12):953&#x2013;959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7978722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chronic C., Syndrome F., Populations B., Medicine I.O. National Academies Press; Washington: 2015. Beyond myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: redefining an illness.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25695122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Clinical Excellence (NICE). Myalgic encephalomyelitis (or encephalopathy)/chronic fatigue syndrome: diagnosis and management. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng206.2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirin A.A., Dimmock M.E., Jason L.A. Updated ME/CFS prevalence estimates reflecting post-COVID increases and associated economic costs and funding implications. Fatigue Biomed Health Behav. 2022;10(02):83&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim E.J., Ahn Y.C., Jang E.S., Lee S.W., Lee S.H., Son C.G. Systematic review and meta-analysis of the prevalence of chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME) J Transl Med. 2020;18(01):100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7038594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32093722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unger E.R., Lin J.S., Tian H., Natelson B.H., Lange G., Vu D., et al. Multi-site clinical assessment of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (MCAM): design and implementation of a prospective/retrospective rolling cohort study. Am J Epidemiol. 2017;185(08):617&#x2013;626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5565838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28338983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pendergrast T., Brown A., Sunnquist M., Jantke R., Newton J.L., Strand E.B., et al. Housebound versus nonhousebound patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis and chronic fatigue syndrome. Chronic Illn. 2016;12(04):292&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5464362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27127189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toogood P.L., Clauw D.J., Phadke S., Hoffman D. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS): Where will the drugs come from? Pharmacol Res. 2021;165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33529750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman L., Bested A.C., Bonilla H.F., Chheda B.V., Chu L., Curtin J.M., et al. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: essentials of diagnosis and management. Mayo Clin Proc. 2021;96(11):2861&#x2013;2878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geraghty K., Hann M., Kurtev S. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients' reports of symptom changes following cognitive behavioural therapy, graded exercise therapy and pacing treatments: analysis of a primary survey compared with secondary surveys. J Health Psychol. 2019;24(10):1318&#x2013;1333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28847166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan S.Y., Xiong Z.Y., Liu X.Y., Liu C.Z., Liu B.Y. MReview of clinical research in acupuncture and moxibustion from 2010 to 2020 and future prospects. Chin Acupunct Moxibustion. 2022;42(01):116&#x2013;118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35025168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du X.T., Tian W.P., Liu B., Li L.N. Prevention and treatment of. acupuncture for cancer-related fatigue caused by chemotherapy of intestinal cancer: a randomized controlled trial. World J Acupunct Moxibustion. 2021;31(02):83&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y.S., Li Y.M., Jing X.H., Wang Y.Q., Han S.P., Pan W.X., et al. The significance of "A neuroanatomical basis for electroacupuncture to drive the vagal-adrenal axis" published in Nature for acupuncture research. Acupunct Res. 2022;47(01):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35128863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheikh F.E.B., HJ M.A.O., Zhao L., Shen X.Y. Meridian system and mechanism of acupuncture action: a scientific evaluation. World J Acupunct Moxibustion. 2020;30(02):130&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnie X.J., Louis L.J., Guan-Yuan J. The anti-inflammatory effect of acupuncture and its significance in analgesia. World J Acupunct Moxibustion. 2019;29(01):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin Z.H., Wang L.J., Cheng Y., Chen J., Hong X.J., Zhao L., et al. Acupuncture for chronic fatigue syndrome: an overview of systematic reviews. Chin J Integr Med. 2021;27(12):940&#x2013;946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32279152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng C.W., Qu Y.Y., Sun Z.R., Yang Y., Wang Y.L., Li C.R., et al. Experimental research progres of acupuncture and moxibustion in preventing and treat chronic fatigue syndrome. Neural Injury Funct Reconstr. 2021;16(12):730&#x2013;735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng C.W., Qu Y.Y., Fan Z.L., Sun Z.R., Yang Y., Li C.R., et al. Exploration on acupoint selection rule of acupuncture in treatment of chronic fatigue syndrome based on collection visualization analysis system. Liaoning J Tradit Chin Med. 2021;48(03):162&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall R., Paul L., Wood L. The search for pain relief in people with chronic fatigue syndrome: a descriptive study. Physiother Theory Pract. 2011;27(05):373&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21039301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holgate S.T., Komaroff A.L., Mangan D., Wessely S. Chronic fatigue syndrome: understanding a complex illness. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2011;12(09):539&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21792218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan W.X. Neurobiological mechanisms of acupuncture. China J Tradit Chin Med. 2018;33(10):4281&#x2013;4297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan M.Z., Li J., Rong B., Jia J., Li H.N. Effect of abdominal manipulation on remodeling of hippocampal neurons in chronic stress-induced chronic fatigue syndrome and its mechanism of negative feedback regulation of hippocampus-HPA axis. J Jilin Univ (Med Ed) 2021;47(04):842&#x2013;848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrero K., Silver M., Cocchetto A., Masliah E., Langford D. CNS findings in chronic fatigue syndrome and a neuropathological case report. J Investig Med. 2017;65(06):974&#x2013;983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28386034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C.Z., Lei B., Zhang P. Effects of acupuncture on cognitive function and hippocampal neurons in rats with chronic fatigue syndrome. Chin J Rehabil Med. 2021;36(08):1009&#x2013;1011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng C.W., Qu Y.Y., Sun Z.R., Wang Y.L., Zhang F., Wang Q.Y., et al. Electroacupuncture improves cognitive function by inhibiting NF-&#x3ba;B activity in rats with chronic fatigue syndrome. Acupunct Res. 2021;46(09):775&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34558244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Wang D.L., Guo J., Shi T.Y., Qu Y.Y., Wang Y., et al. Effect of electroacupuncture on behavior and pathomorphology of brain tissue in rats with chronic fatigue syndrome. China Med Herald. 2018;15(26):9&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X.Y. Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine; 2018. Study on influence of acupuncture for CFS model Rats&#x2019; mi RNA-184 expression in hippocampal and its regulating mechanism on 5-HT/Gnai/PLC/Casp-3 pathway.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd A., Hickie I., Brockman A., Dwyer J., Wakefield D. Cytokine levels in serum and cerebrospinal fluid in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome and control subjects. J Infect Dis. 1991;164(05):1023&#x2013;1024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1940455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natelson B.H., Weaver S.A., Tseng C.L., Ottenweller J.E. Spinal fluid abnormalities in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. Clin Diagn Lab Immunol. 2005;12(01):52&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC540195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15642984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson D., Brenu E.W., Gottschalk G., Ramos S., Nguyen T., Staines D., et al. Cytokines in the cerebrospinal fluids of patients with chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis. Mediators Inflamm. 2015;2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4365360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25834308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornig M., Gottschalk G., Peterson D.L., Knox K.K., Schultz A.F., Eddy M.L., et al. Cytokine network analysis of cerebrospinal fluid in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Mol Psychiatry. 2016;21(02):261&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25824300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T.S., Yang Y., Wang D.L., Wang Y.L., Guo J., Shi T.Y., et al. Effects of scalp electroacupuncture on expression of p65 and COX-2 protein in hippocampus and hypothalamus of rats with chronic fatigue syndrome. Neural Inj Funct Reconstr. 2018;13(07):325&#x2013;327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shui L., Wu Y., Lu J., GL A., Si Q., Ga L.T., et al. Effect of warm acupuncture of mongolian on iNOS signaling pathway of chronic fatigue rats and its influence on cytokines expression in hippocampus and hypothalamus. Liaoning J Tradit Chin Med. 2021;48(09):196&#x2013;198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shui L., Wu Y., Lu J., Wu Q.Z., Chen Y.S., Sa R.T.Y., et al. Effect of mongolian warm acupuncture on expression of caspase&#xa0;&#x2212;&#xa0;3 and serum death receptor DR and Fas in chroinic fatigue syndrome model rats. Liaoning J Tradit Chin Med. 2021;48(05):192&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si Q., Shui L., Chen Y.S. Effect of mongolian medicine warming acupuncture on cytokine content in hippocampus and hypothalamus of fatigue model rats. Chin J Ethnomed Ethnopharmacy. 2020;29(02):11&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T.S., Xu J., Yu G.Q., Wang Y., Wei Q.S., You Z., et al. Effect of electroacupuncture on Smad4 protein expression in hippocampus and hypothalamus of CFS model rats. Acta Chin Med Pharmacol. 2016;44(02):49&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D.L., Yang Y., Jiang F., Guo J., Shi T.Y., Qu Y.Y., et al. Effects of electric acupuncture on the transforming growth factor-&#x3b2;1 protein and gene expression in rats with chronic fatigue syndrome. Neural Inj Funct Reconstr. 2018;13(04):169&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deumer U.S., Varesi A., Floris V., Savioli G., Mantovani E., Lopez-Carrasco P., et al. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS): an overview. J Clin Med. 2021;10(20):4786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8538807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34682909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris G., Anderson G., Maes M. Hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal hypofunction in myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME)/chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS) as a consequence of activated immune-inflammatory and oxidative and nitrosative pathways. Mol Neurobiol. 2017;54(09):6806&#x2013;6819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27766535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C.Z., Lei B. Effects of acupuncture intervention on learning-memory ability and cerebral superoxide dismutase activity and malonaldehyde concentration in chronic fatigue syndrome rats. Acupunct Res. 2013;38(06):478&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24588031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si Q. Inner Mongolia medical university; 2019. Effect of mongolian medicine warm needling therapy on hypothalamic free radicals in chronic fatigue rats.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P., Yin J.P., Jin X.Q., Chen S.Y., Li J.J., Huang L.S., et al. Effect of "Beishu Points" electroacupuncture stimulation on CRHmRNA, ACTH and CORT in rats with chronic fatigue sydome. Guiding J Tradit Chin Med. 2018;24(12):32&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin X.Q. Traditional Chinese Medicine University Of Guangzhou; 2017. Effect of electroacupuncture at different frequencies back-shu points on HPA axis and immune system in chronic fatigue rats and clinical research.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X.J. CRH in Hypothalamus by EA. Traditional Chinese Medicine University Of Guangzhou; 2013. The research of regulating CFS Rats&#x2019; 5-HT1aR in hippocampus.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu C.J., Xie K., Qu J., Liu B.L. Experimental research of effects of acupuncture on the HPA axis of chronic fatigue rats induced by multiple stress factors. Liaoning Journal of Traditional Chinese Medicine. 2010;37(10):2055&#x2013;2057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng H. Beijing University of Chinese Medicine; 2003. Research on the regulation mechanism of neural immune network in rats with chronic electrical stress fatigue syndrome model.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y.S., Zhu Y.H., Peng X.H., Zhong Z.D., Yuan Q., Pei Y., et al. Central mechanism of electroacupuncture adjustment effect on hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis function in chronic fatigue rats. Chin Acupunct Moxibustion. 2013;33(01):53&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S.W. Liaoning University Of Traditional Chinese Medicine; 2011. Effect of acupuncture on hypothalamic-pituitary-testicular axis in chronic fatigue rats induced by multiple stresses.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S. Liaoning University Of Traditional Chinese Medicine; 2010. Effect of acupuncture on HPT axis in chronic fatigue rats induced by multiple stresses.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei Y. Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine; 2012. Mechanism of hypothalamic CRH regulated by electroacupuncture in chronic fatigue rats.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B.L. Liaoning University Of Traditional Chinese Medicine; 2009. Experimental research of acupuncture intervention on hippocampal 5-HT and 5-HT1A receptor mRNA expression in multifactor chronic fatigue rats.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y.H., Tang C.Z., Yang J.J., Xian Z.H., Lin J.Q., Li H.Y. Effect of acupuncture on monoamine neurotransmitters in hypothalamus and pituitary in chronic fatigue rats. J Basic Chin Med. 2008;14(09):713&#x2013;714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S.J. Beijing University of Chinese Medicine; 2006. Experimental study on effect of electroacupuncture on the change of neural function of the kidney deficiency rat model under the chronic multipie stress.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J.J. Beijing University of Chinese Medicine; 2004. Effect of electroacupuncture on neuro-immune function in the liver-stagnation syndrome rat model induced by complex stresses.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin H.J. Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine; 2018. Study on the regulating mechanism of acupuncture for sleep disorders in patients with CFS based on adenosine and it's receptors in the basal forebrain.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong X.J. Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine; 2011. Research on the effect and mechanism of acupuncture on characteristic of locomotor activity circadian rhythm in Syrian hamster model of chronic fatigue syndrome.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Chen J.F., Cao M.N., Shi B., Zhang G.X., Zhang S. Research on digital image processing and MATLAB teaching of medical imaging technology specialty. Basic Med Educ. 2018;20(04):324&#x2013;326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng C.W., Qu Y.Y., Sun Z.R., Li C.R., Sun W.B., Wang Q.Y., et al. Research progresses of MRI on brain structures and functions of chronic fatigue syndrome. Chin J Med Imaging Technol. 2022;38(05):775&#x2013;778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanElzakker M.B., Brumfield S.A., Lara M.P. Neuroinflammation and cytokines in Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS): a critical review of research methods. Front Neurol. 2018;9:1033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6335565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30687207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan Z.Y., Barnden L.R., Kwiatek R.A., Bhuta S., Hermens D.F., Lagopoulos J. Neuroimaging characteristics of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS): a systematic review. J Transl Med. 2020;18(01):335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7466519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32873297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almutairi B., Langley C., Crawley E., Thai N.J. Using structural and functional MRI as a neuroimaging technique to investigate chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalopathy: a systematic review. BMJ Open. 2020;10(08):e31672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7462162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32868345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maksoud R., du Preez S., Eaton-Fitch N., Thapaliya K., Barnden L., Cabanas H., et al. A systematic review of neurological impairments in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome using neuroimaging techniques. PLoS One. 2020;15(04)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7192498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32353033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mairal E., Barberon B., Laine N., Coulange M., Guedj E. Reversible widespread brain 18F-FDG PET hypometabolism in chronic fatigue syndrome treated by hyperbaric oxygen therapy. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48(5):1680&#x2013;1681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33420913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahbai S., Kauv P., Abrivard M., Blanc-Durand P., Aoun-Sebati M., Emsen B., et al. Severe posterior hypometabolism but normal perfusion in a patient with chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis revealed by PET/MRI. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2019;46(2):531&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30552447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakatomi Y., Mizuno K., Ishii A., Wada Y., Tanaka M., Tazawa S., et al. Neuroinflammation in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis: an (1)(1)C-(R)-PK11195 PET study. J Nucl Med. 2014;55(06):945&#x2013;950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24665088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto S., Ouchi Y., Onoe H., Yoshikawa E., Tsukada H., Takahashi H., et al. Reduction of serotonin transporters of patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. Neuroreport. 2004;15(17):2571&#x2013;2574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15570154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleare A.J., Messa C., Rabiner E.A., Grasby P.M. Brain 5-HT1A receptor binding in chronic fatigue syndrome measured using positron emission tomography and [11C]WAY-100635. Biol Psychiatry. 2005;57(03):239&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15691524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto S., Ouchi Y., Nakatsuka D., Tahara T., Mizuno K., Tajima S., et al. Reduction of [11C](+)3-MPB binding in brain of chronic fatigue syndrome with serum autoantibody against muscarinic cholinergic receptor. PLoS One. 2012;7(12):e51515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3519853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23240035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuratsune H., Yamaguti K., Lindh G., Evengard B., Hagberg G., Matsumura K., et al. Brain regions involved in fatigue sensation: reduced acetylcarnitine uptake into the brain. Neuroimage. 2002;17(03):1256&#x2013;1265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12414265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang L.W. Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine; 2015. A multimodal MRI study of central mechanism in acupuncture for cognitive function of CFS.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z.M. Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine; 2019. Neurobiochemical mechanism of acupuncture for chronic fatigue syndrome based on magnetic resonance spectroscopy.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>