<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38816141</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2352-3018</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The lancet. HIV</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet HIV</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dynamics of virological and immunological markers of HIV persistence after allogeneic haematopoietic stem-cell transplantation in the IciStem cohort: a prospective observational cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e389</StartPage><EndPage>e405</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e389-e405</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S2352-3018(24)00090-0</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2352-3018(24)00090-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Allogeneic haematopoietic stem-cell transplantation (allo-HSCT) markedly reduces HIV reservoirs, but the mechanisms by which this occurs are only partly understood. In this study, we aimed to describe the dynamics of virological and immunological markers of HIV persistence after allo-HSCT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this prospective observational cohort study, we analysed the viral reservoir and serological dynamics in IciStem cohort participants with HIV who had undergone allo-HSCT and were receiving antiretroviral therapy, ten of whom had received cells from donors with the CCR5&#x394;32 mutation. Participants from Belgium, Canada, Germany, Italy, the Netherlands, Spain, Switzerland, and the UK were included in the cohort both prospectively and retrospectively between June 1, 2014 and April 30, 2019. In the first 6 months after allo-HSCT, participants had monthly assessments, with annual assessments thereafter, with the protocol tailored to accommodate for the individual health status of each participant. HIV reservoirs were measured in blood and tissues and HIV-specific antibodies were measured in plasma. We used the Wilcoxon signed-rank test to compare data collected before and after allo-HSCT in participants for whom longitudinal data were available. When the paired test was not possible, we used the Mann-Whitney U test. We developed a mathematical model to study the factors influencing HIV reservoir reduction in people with HIV after allo-HSCT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We included 30 people with HIV with haematological malignancies who received a transplant between Sept 1, 2009 and April 30, 2019 and were enrolled within the IciStem cohort and included in this analysis. HIV reservoirs in peripheral blood were reduced immediately after full donor chimerism was achieved, generally accompanied by undetectable HIV-DNA in bone marrow, ileum, lymph nodes, and cerebrospinal fluid, regardless of donor CCR5 genotype. HIV-specific antibody levels and functionality values declined more slowly than direct HIV reservoir values, decaying significantly only months after full donor chimerism. Mathematical modelling suggests that allogeneic immunity mediated by donor cells is the main viral reservoir depletion mechanism after massive reservoir reduction during conditioning chemotherapy before allo-HSCT (half-life of latently infected replication-competent cells decreased from 44 months to 1&#xb7;5 months).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our work provides, for the first time, data on the effects of allo-HSCT in the context of HIV infection. Additionally, we raise the question of which marker can serve as the last reporter of the residual viraemia, postulating that the absence of T-cell immune responses might be a more reliable marker than antibody decline after allo-HSCT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">amfAR (American Foundation for AIDS Research; ARCHE Program), National Institutes of Health, National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, and Dutch Aidsfonds.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved, including those for text and data mining, AI training, and similar technologies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salgado</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IrsiCaixa, Badalona, Spain; Germans Trias i Pujol Research Institute, Badalona, Spain; Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n Biom&#xe9;dica en Red en Enfermedades Infecciosas, Instituto de Salud Carlos III, Madrid, Spain. Electronic address: msalgado@irsicaixa.es.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xe1;lvez</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IrsiCaixa, Badalona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nijhuis</LastName><ForeName>Monique</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Virology, Department of Medical Microbiology, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, Netherlands; HIV Pathogenesis Research Unit, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwon</LastName><ForeName>Mi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Hospital Universitario Gregorio Mara&#xf1;&#xf3;n, Institute of Health Research Gregorio Mara&#xf1;&#xf3;n, Madrid, Spain; Instituto de Investigaci&#xf3;n Sanitaria Gregorio Mara&#xf1;&#xf3;n, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cardozo-Ojeda</LastName><ForeName>E Fabian</ForeName><Initials>EF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine and Infectious Diseases Division, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, WA, USA; Xencor, Pasadena, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Badiola</LastName><ForeName>Jon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Hospital Virgen de las Nieves, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gorman</LastName><ForeName>Matthew J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ragon Institute of Mass General, MIT, and Harvard, Cambridge, MA, USA; Moderna Therapeutics, Cambridge, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huyveneers</LastName><ForeName>Laura E P</ForeName><Initials>LEP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Virology, Department of Medical Microbiology, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Urrea</LastName><ForeName>Victor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IrsiCaixa, Badalona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bandera</LastName><ForeName>Alessandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Unit, Foundation IRCCS Ca' Granda Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico, Milan, Italy; Department of Pathophysiology and Transplantation, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jensen</LastName><ForeName>Bj&#xf6;rn-Erik Ole</ForeName><Initials>BO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Hepatology, and Infectious Diseases, Medical Faculty and University Hospital D&#xfc;sseldorf, Heinrich Heine University, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vandekerckhove</LastName><ForeName>Linos</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HIV Cure Research Center, Department of Internal Medicine and Pediatrics, Ghent University Hospital, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jurado</LastName><ForeName>Manuel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Hospital Virgen de las Nieves, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raj</LastName><ForeName>Kavita</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kings College Hospital, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schulze Zur Wiesch</LastName><ForeName>Julian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Unit, Department of Medicine, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany; German Center for Infection Research, Partner Site Hamburg-L&#xfc;beck-Borstel-Riems, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bail&#xe9;n</LastName><ForeName>Rebeca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Hospital Universitario Gregorio Mara&#xf1;&#xf3;n, Institute of Health Research Gregorio Mara&#xf1;&#xf3;n, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eberhard</LastName><ForeName>Johanna M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Unit, Department of Medicine, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany; German Center for Infection Research, Partner Site Hamburg-L&#xfc;beck-Borstel-Riems, Hamburg, Germany; Helmholtz Institute for One Health, Greifswald, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nabergoj</LastName><ForeName>Mitja</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Hematology, H&#xf4;pitaux Universitaires de Gen&#xe8;ve, Geneva, Switzerland; Hematology Service, Institut Central des H&#xf4;pitaux, Sion, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>H&#xfc;tter</LastName><ForeName>Gero</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>DKMS Collection Center, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salda&#xf1;a-Moreno</LastName><ForeName>Raquel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital General de Jerez de la Frontera, C&#xe1;diz, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oldford</LastName><ForeName>Sharon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nova Scotia Health, Dalhousie University, Halifax, NS, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barrett</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nova Scotia Health, Dalhousie University, Halifax, NS, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramirez</LastName><ForeName>Maria Luisa Montes</ForeName><Initials>MLM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n Biom&#xe9;dica en Red en Enfermedades Infecciosas, Instituto de Salud Carlos III, Madrid, Spain; University Hospital La Paz, IdiPAZ, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garba</LastName><ForeName>Salisu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine and Infectious Diseases Division, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, WA, USA; Merck, Rahway, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Ravi Kumar</ForeName><Initials>RK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Revollo</LastName><ForeName>Boris</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, University Hospital Germans Trias i Pujol, Institut Catal&#xe0; d'Oncologia, Badalona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferra-Coll</LastName><ForeName>Christelle</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, University Hospital Germans Trias i Pujol, Institut Catal&#xe0; d'Oncologia, Badalona, Spain; University of Vic-Central University of Catalonia, Vic, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuball</LastName><ForeName>Jurgen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology and Center for Translational Immunology, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alter</LastName><ForeName>Galit</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ragon Institute of Mass General, MIT, and Harvard, Cambridge, MA, USA; Moderna Therapeutics, Cambridge, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xe1;ez-Ciri&#xf3;n</LastName><ForeName>Asier</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Viral Reservoirs and Immune Control Unit, Institut Pasteur, Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diez-Martin</LastName><ForeName>Jose Luis</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Hospital Universitario Gregorio Mara&#xf1;&#xf3;n, Institute of Health Research Gregorio Mara&#xf1;&#xf3;n, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duke</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine and Infectious Diseases Division, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, WA, USA; Department of Medicine, Allergy and Infectious Diseases Division, University of Washington, WA, Seattle, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schiffer</LastName><ForeName>Joshua T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine and Infectious Diseases Division, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, WA, USA; Clinical Research Division, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, WA, USA; Department of Medicine, Allergy and Infectious Diseases Division, University of Washington, WA, Seattle, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wensing</LastName><ForeName>Annemarie</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Virology, Department of Medical Microbiology, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, Netherlands; Ezintsha, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martinez-Picado</LastName><ForeName>Javier</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IrsiCaixa, Badalona, Spain; Germans Trias i Pujol Research Institute, Badalona, Spain; Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n Biom&#xe9;dica en Red en Enfermedades Infecciosas, Instituto de Salud Carlos III, Madrid, Spain; University of Vic-Central University of Catalonia, Vic, Spain; Catalan Institution for Research and Advanced Studies, Barcelona, Spain. Electronic address: jmpicado@irsicaixa.es.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>IciStem Consortium</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P01 AI178376</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UM1 AI164561</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet HIV</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101645355</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2352-3018</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015483">HIV Antibodies</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018380" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015658" MajorTopicYN="Y">HIV Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015497" MajorTopicYN="N">HIV-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014184" MajorTopicYN="N">Transplantation, Homologous</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019562" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Load</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015483" MajorTopicYN="N">HIV Antibodies</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests AB reports grants from Gilead Sciences and participating on the advisory board of ViiV Healthcare. AW reports funding for this manuscript from the American Foundation for AIDS Research (amfAR) and Aidsfunds; grants from Gilead and NOW; consulting fees from ViiV Healthcare/GSK, MSD, and Gilead Sciences; participating on the board of the Dutch Federation of Medical Microbiology, the board of the European Society for Translational Antiviral Research, chair on the IAS-USA mutations work group, the Committee of ZonMW (Dutch research organization) Research, and the Committee of the Dutch Federation for Long Covid; and received funding from Ark. AS-C reports funding for this manuscript from amfAR; grants from ANRS, the National Institutes of Health (NIH), Institute Pasteur, and MSDAVENIR; honoraria from MSD, ViiV Healthcare, and Gilead Sciences; and is chair of the Scientific and Medical Committee of Sidaction. B-EOJ reports consulting fees from Gilead Sciences, ViiV Healthcare, and Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme; honoraria from Gilead Sciences and ViiV Healthcare; travel expenses for attending meetings from Gilead; and is scientific secretary for the German AIDS Society. BR reports honoraria from Gilead Sciences, Janssen, and ViiV Healthcare; payment for advice from ViiV Healthcare; and travel expenses for attending meetings and travel from ViiV Healthcare and Gilead Sciences. GH reports travel expenses for attending the meeting and travel for the HIV Persistence Workshop 2022. JB reports receiving honoraria from AbbVie, Pfizer, and Gilead Sciences; and travel expenses for attending meetings from AbbVie, Pfizer, and Gilead Sciences. JK reports grants from Novartis and Miltenyi Biotech; royalties from GADETA and Miltenyi Biotech; a patent with GADETA; and holds stock interest in GADETA. JM-P reports funding for this manuscript from amfAR. JSZW reports funding for this manuscript from The German Center for Infection Research, EU H2020 Research and Innovation Programme, HW &amp; J Hector Foundation, the German Research Foundation, The Hamburg Investment and Development Bank, and amfAR; and honoraria from Nobite, GSK, and Gilead Sciences. JTS reports funding for this manuscript from the NIH and National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases. LB report grants from Abbvie and Gilead Sciences; consulting fees from Abbvie and Gilead Sciences; and honoraria from AbbVie and Gilead Sciences. LV reports receiving grants from ViiV Healthcare and Gilead Sciences; and consulting fees from ViiV Healthcare and Gilead Sciences. MJG and GA declare being an employee of Ragon Institute of Mass General, MIT, and Harvard during the study; and an employee of Moderna afterwards. MNi reports receiving consulting fees from Gilead Sciences; and honoraria for lectures from ViiV Healthcare. All other authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement><InvestigatorList><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muscatello</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calmy</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chapel</LastName><ForeName>Anais</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mamez</LastName><ForeName>Anne-Claire</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Passaes</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brisseau</LastName><ForeName>Clarissa</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olivarria</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Knops</LastName><ForeName>Elena</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heger</LastName><ForeName>Eva</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bikhezar</LastName><ForeName>Fatima</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perdomo-Celis</LastName><ForeName>Federico</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kobbe</LastName><ForeName>Guido</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gabriel</LastName><ForeName>Ian H</ForeName><Initials>IH</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lunzen</LastName><ForeName>Jan V</ForeName><Initials>JV</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dalmau</LastName><ForeName>Judith</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;n-Carbonero</LastName><ForeName>Luz</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Puertas</LastName><ForeName>Mari Carmen</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garcia-Guerrero</LastName><ForeName>Mari Carmen</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Scheerder</LastName><ForeName>Marie-Ang&#xe9;lique</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Angin</LastName><ForeName>Mathieu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xfc;bke</LastName><ForeName>Nadine</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balsalobre</LastName><ForeName>Pascual</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Paz</LastName><ForeName>Raquel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaiser</LastName><ForeName>Rolf</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerre</LastName><ForeName>Tessa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harrer</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luedde</LastName><ForeName>Tom</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rocha</LastName><ForeName>Vanderson</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Investigator></InvestigatorList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38816141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2001014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11417461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-3018(24)00090-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2352-3018(24)00090-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Finzi D, Blankson J, Siliciano JD, et al. Latent infection of CD4+ T cells provides a mechanism for lifelong persistence of HIV-1, even in patients on effective combination therapy. Nat Med 1999; 5: 512&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10229227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xfc;tter G, Nowak D, Mossner M, et al. Long-Term Control of HIV by CCR5 Delta32/Delta32 Stem-Cell Transplantation. New England Journal of Medicine 2009; 360: 692&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19213682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta RK, Abdul-Jawad S, McCoy LE, et al. HIV-1 remission following CCR5&#x394;32/&#x394;32 haematopoietic stem-cell transplantation. Nature 2019; 568: 244&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7275870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30836379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen BEO, Knops E, Cords L, et al. In-depth virological and immunological characterization of HIV-1 cure after CCR5&#x394;32/&#x394;32 allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Nat Med 2023; 29: 583&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10033413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36807684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu J, Besien K Van, Glesby MJ, et al. HIV-1 remission and possible cure in a woman after haplo-cord blood transplant. Cell 2023; : 1115&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10616809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36931242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickter JK, Aribi A, Cardoso AA, et al. HIV-1 Remission after Allogeneic Hematopoietic-Cell Transplantation. New England Journal of Medicine 2024; 390: 669&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10906479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38354149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;ez-Ciri&#xf3;n A, Mamez A, Avettand-Fenoel V, et al. Absence of viral rebound for 18 months without antiretrovirals after allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation with wild-type CCR5 donor cells to treat a biphenotypic sarcoma. IAS 2023, 23&#x2013;26 July, Brisbane, Australia 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allers K, H&#xfc;tter G, Hofmann J, et al. Evidence for the cure of HIV infection by CCR5&#x394;32/&#x394;32 stem cell transplantation. Blood 2011; 117: 2791&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21148083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henrich TJ, Hu Z, Li JZ, et al. Long-term reduction in peripheral blood HIV type 1 reservoirs following reduced-intensity conditioning allogeneic stem cell transplantation. J Infect Dis 2013; 207: 1694&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3636784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23460751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salgado M, Kwon M, G&#xe1;lvez C, et al. Mechanisms That Contribute to a Profound Reduction of the HIV-1 Reservoir After Allogeneic Stem Cell Transplant. Ann Intern Med 2018; published online Oct 16. DOI:10.7326/M18-0759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M18-0759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30326031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xfc;tter G, Thiel E. Allogeneic transplantation of CCR5-deficient progenitor cells in a patient with HIV infection: an update after 3 years and the search for patient no. 2. AIDS 2011; 25: 273&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21173593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huyveneers LEP, Bruns A, Stam A, et al. Autopsy Study Defines Composition and Dynamics of the HIV-1 Reservoir after Allogeneic Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation with CCR5&#x394;32/&#x394;32 Donor Cells. Viruses 2022; 14: 1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9503691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36146874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberhard JM, Angin M, Passaes C, et al. Vulnerability to reservoir reseeding due to high immune activation after allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation in individuals with HIV-1. Sci Transl Med 2020; 12. DOI:10.1126/SCITRANSLMED.AAY9355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/SCITRANSLMED.AAY9355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32376772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta RK, Peppa D, Hill AL, et al. Evidence for HIV-1 cure after CCR5&#x394;32/&#x394;32 allogeneic haemopoietic stem-cell transplantation 30 months post analytical treatment interruption: a case report. Lancet HIV 2020; 7: e340&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7606918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32169158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon M, Bail&#xe9;n R, Balsalobre P, et al. Allogeneic stem-cell transplantation in HIV-1-infected patients with high-risk hematological disorders. AIDS 2019; 33: 1441&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30932952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte RF, Salgado M, S&#xe1;nchez-Ortega I, et al. CCR5 &#x394;32 homozygous cord blood allogeneic transplantation in a patient with HIV: a case report. Lancet HIV 2015; 2: e236&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26423196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keating SM, Hanson D, Lebedeva M, et al. Lower-sensitivity and avidity modifications of the vitros anti-HIV 1+2 assay for detection of recent HIV infections and incidence estimation. J Clin Microbiol 2012; 50: 3968&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3503010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23035182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardozo-Ojeda EF, Duke ER, Peterson CW, et al. Thresholds for post-rebound SHIV control after CCR5 gene-edited autologous hematopoietic cell transplantation. Elife 2021; 10: 1&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7803377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33432929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves DB, Duke ER, Hughes SM, Prlic M, Hladik F, Schiffer JT. Anti-proliferative therapy for HIV cure: a compound interest approach. Sci Rep 2017; 7. DOI:10.1038/S41598-017-04160-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/S41598-017-04160-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5479830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28638104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besson GJ, Lalama CM, Bosch RJ, et al. HIV-1 DNA decay dynamics in blood during more than a decade of suppressive antiretroviral therapy. Clin Infect Dis 2014; 59: 1312&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4200019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25073894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siliciano JD, Kajdas J, Finzi D, et al. Long-term follow-up studies confirm the stability of the latent reservoir for HIV-1 in resting CD4+ T cells. Nat Med 2003; 9: 727&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12754504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durand CM, Capoferri AA, Redd AD, et al. Allogeneic Bone Marrow Transplant for HIV Patients with Hematologic Malignancies with Post-transplant Cyclophosphamide: a Feasibility Study Summary HHS Public Access. DOI:10.1016/S2352-3018(20)30073-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-3018(20)30073-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummins NW, Rizza S, Litzow MR, et al. Extensive virologic and immunologic characterization in an HIV-infected individual following allogeneic stem cell transplant and analytic cessation of antiretroviral therapy: A case study. PLoS Med 2017; 14: 1&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5705162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29182633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koelsch K, Rasmussen T, Hey-Nguyen W, et al. Impact of allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation on the HIV reservoir and immune response in three HIV infected individuals. JAIDS Journal of Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndromes 2017; : 1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6097982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28350553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu HL, Busman-Sahay K, Weber WC, et al. Allogeneic immunity clears latent virus following allogeneic stem cell transplantation in SIV-infected ART-suppressed macaques. Immunity 2023; : 1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10524637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37236188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xfc;tter G, Verheyen J, Esser S, H&#xfc;tter G. More on shift of HIV tropism in stem-cell transplantation with CCR5 delta32/delta32 mutation. N Engl J Med 2014; 371: 2437&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25162903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verheyen J, Thielen A, L&#xfc;bke N, et al. Rapid rebound of a preexisting CXCR4-tropic human immunodeficiency virus variant after allogeneic transplantation with CCR5 &#x394;32 homozygous stem cells. Clinical Infectious Diseases 2019; 68: 684&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30020413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henrich TJ, Hanhauser E, Marty FM, et al. Antiretroviral-Free HIV-1 Remission and Viral Rebound After Allogeneic Stem Cell Transplantation: Report of 2 Cases. Ann Intern Med 2014; : 1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4236912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25047577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal S, Mehta J. Reimmunization after blood or marrow stem cell transplantation. Bone Marrow Transplant 1999; 23: 637&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10218839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canou&#xef; E, L&#xe9;curoux C, Avettand-Feno&#xeb;l V, et al. A Subset of Extreme Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) Controllers Is Characterized by a Small HIV Blood Reservoir and a Weak T-Cell Activation Level. Open Forum Infect Dis 2017; 4. DOI:10.1093/OFID/OFX064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/OFID/OFX064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5450900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28584850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendoza D, Johnson S a SA, Peterson B a BA, et al. Comprehensive analysis of unique cases with extraordinary control over HIV replication. Blood 2012; 119: 4645&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3367872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22490332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besson GJ, Lalama CM, Bosch RJ, et al. HIV-1 DNA decay dynamics in blood during more than a decade of suppressive antiretroviral therapy. Clin Infect Dis 2014; 59: 1312&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4200019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25073894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siliciano JD, Kajdas J, Finzi D, et al. Long-term follow-up studies confirm the stability of the latent reservoir for HIV-1 in resting CD4+ T cells. Nat Med 2003; 9: 727&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12754504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>