<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38663423</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1474-4457</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Lancet. Infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The persistence of SARS-CoV-2 in tissues and its association with long COVID symptoms: a cross-sectional cohort study in China.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>845</StartPage><EndPage>855</EndPage><MedlinePgn>845-855</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S1473-3099(24)00171-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1473-3099(24)00171-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Growing evidence suggests that symptoms associated with post-COVID-19 condition (also known as long COVID) can affect multiple organs and systems in the human body, but their association with viral persistence is not clear. The aim of this study was to investigate the persistence of SARS-CoV-2 in diverse tissues at three timepoints following recovery from mild COVID-19, as well as its association with long COVID symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This single-centre, cross-sectional cohort study was done at China-Japan Friendship Hospital in Beijing, China, following the omicron wave of COVID-19 in December, 2022. Individuals with mild COVID-19 confirmed by PCR or a lateral flow test scheduled to undergo gastroscopy, surgery, or chemotherapy, or scheduled for treatment in hospital for other reasons, at 1 month, 2 months, or 4 months after infection were enrolled in this study. Residual surgical samples, gastroscopy samples, and blood samples were collected approximately 1 month (18-33 days), 2 months (55-84 days), or 4 months (115-134 days) after infection. SARS-CoV-2 was detected by digital droplet PCR and further confirmed through RNA in-situ hybridisation, immunofluorescence, and immunohistochemistry. Telephone follow-up was done at 4 months post-infection to assess the association between the persistence of SARS-CoV-2 RNA and long COVID symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Between Jan 3 and April 28, 2023, 317 tissue samples were collected from 225 patients, including 201 residual surgical specimens, 59 gastroscopy samples, and 57 blood component samples. Viral RNA was detected in 16 (30%) of 53 solid tissue samples collected at 1 month, 38 (27%) of 141 collected at 2 months, and seven (11%) of 66 collected at 4 months. Viral RNA was distributed across ten different types of solid tissues, including liver, kidney, stomach, intestine, brain, blood vessel, lung, breast, skin, and thyroid. Additionally, subgenomic RNA was detected in 26 (43%) of 61 solid tissue samples tested for subgenomic RNA that also tested positive for viral RNA. At 2 months after infection, viral RNA was detected in the plasma of three (33%), granulocytes of one (11%), and peripheral blood mononuclear cells of two (22%) of nine patients who were immunocompromised, but in none of these blood compartments in ten patients who were immunocompetent. Among 213 patients who completed the telephone questionnaire, 72 (34%) reported at least one long COVID symptom, with fatigue (21%, 44 of 213) being the most frequent symptom. Detection of viral RNA in recovered patients was significantly associated with the development of long COVID symptoms (odds ratio 5&#xb7;17, 95% CI 2&#xb7;64-10&#xb7;13, p&lt;0&#xb7;0001). Patients with higher virus copy numbers had a higher likelihood of developing long COVID symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings suggest that residual SARS-CoV-2 can persist in patients who have recovered from mild COVID-19 and that there is a significant association between viral persistence and long COVID symptoms. Further research is needed to verify a mechanistic link and identify potential targets to improve long COVID symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">National Natural Science Foundation of China, National Key R&amp;D Program of China, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences Innovation Fund for Medical Sciences, and New Cornerstone Science Foundation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRANSLATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">For the Chinese translation of the abstract see Supplementary Materials section.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved, including those for text and data mining, AI training, and similar technologies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Wenting</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China; Peking Union Medical College, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Di</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China; Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Chaoyang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China; Department of General Thoracic Surgery, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Du</LastName><ForeName>Shiyu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hua</LastName><ForeName>Zhan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastrointestinal Surgery, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nie</LastName><ForeName>Qiangqiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Xiaofeng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Meng</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Breast and Thyroid Surgery, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Haidong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Second Division of Hepatopancreatobiliary Surgery, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jiuyang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Yanbing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhan</LastName><ForeName>Yuliang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Operating Theatre, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoying</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China; Department of Clinical Research and Data Management, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Weijie</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China; Department of General Thoracic Surgery, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China; Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hongyan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Medical Sciences, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Weiliang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Medical Sciences, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Mingzhi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China; Changping Laboratory, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaolei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Second Division of Hepatopancreatobiliary Surgery, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Liguo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Second Division of Hepatopancreatobiliary Surgery, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Chuanzhen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Medical Sciences, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Medical Sciences, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yuting</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Medical Sciences, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Medical Sciences, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Ling</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Chuan-Peng</ForeName><Initials>CP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China; Department of Neurosurgery, Peking University China-Japan Friendship School of Clinical Medicine, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Hongyu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China; Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shiyao</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Fei</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Thoracic Surgery, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yeming</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China. Electronic address: wzai_163pass@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zai</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Medical Sciences, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Haibo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China; Changping Laboratory, Beijing, China. Electronic address: shrineswe@vip.qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Respiratory Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Health and Multimorbidity, National Clinical Research Center for Respiratory Diseases, Institute of Respiratory Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Center of Respiratory Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China; New Cornerstone Science Laboratory, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China; Peking Union Medical College, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing, China; Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China; Changping Laboratory, Beijing, China; Tsinghua University-Peking University Joint Center for Life Sciences, Beijing, China. Electronic address: caobin_ben@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101130150</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1473-3099</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests We declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38663423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(24)00171-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1473-3099(24)00171-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>