<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36166652</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1929-0748</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR research protocols</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Res Protoc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Understanding Racial Disparities in COVID-19-Related Complications: Protocol for a Mixed Methods Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e38914</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e38914</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e38914</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/38914</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In the United States, the COVID-19 pandemic has magnified the disproportionate and long-standing health disparities experienced by Black communities. Although it is acknowledged that social determinants of health (SDOH) rather than biological factors likely contribute to this disparity, few studies using rigorous analytic approaches in large, information-rich community-based data sets are dedicated to understanding the underlying drivers of these racial disparities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The overall aim of our study is to elucidate the mechanisms by which racial disparities in severe COVID-19 outcomes arise, using both quantitative and qualitative methods.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this protocol, we outline a convergent parallel mixed methods approach to identifying, quantifying, and contextualizing factors that contribute to the dramatic disparity in COVID-19 severity (ie, hospitalization, mortality) in Black versus white COVID-19 patients within the integrated health care system of Kaiser Permanente Georgia (KPGA). Toward this end, we will generate two quantitative cohorts of KPGA members with a confirmed COVID-19 diagnosis between January 1, 2020, and September 30, 2021: (1) an electronic medical record (EMR) cohort including routinely captured data on diagnoses, medications, and laboratory values, and a subset of patients hospitalized at Emory Healthcare to capture additional in-hospital data; and (2) a survey cohort, where participants will answer a range of questions related to demographics (eg, race, education), usual health behaviors (eg, physical activity, smoking), impact of COVID-19 (eg, job loss, caregiving responsibilities), and medical mistrust. Key outcomes of interest for these two cohorts include hospitalization, mortality, intensive care unit admission, hospital readmission, and long COVID-19. Finally, we will conduct qualitative semistructured interviews to capture perceptions of and experiences of being hospitalized with COVID-19 as well as related interactions with KPGA health care providers. We will analyze and interpret the quantitative and qualitative data separately, and then integrate the qualitative and quantitative findings using a triangulation design approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This study has been funded by a Woodruff Health Sciences grant from December 2020 to December 2022. As of August 31, 2022, 31,500 KPGA members diagnosed with COVID-19 have been included in the EMR cohort, including 3028 who were hospitalized at Emory Healthcare, and 482 KPGA members completed the survey. In addition, 20 KPGA members (10 Black and 10 white) have been interviewed about their experiences navigating care with COVID-19. Quantitative and qualitative data cleaning and coding have been completed. Data analysis is underway with results anticipated to be published in December 2022.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Results from this mixed methods pilot study in a diverse integrated care setting in the southeastern United States will provide insights into the mechanisms underpinning racial disparities in COVID-19 complications. The quantitative and qualitative data will provide important context to generate hypotheses around the mechanisms for racial disparities in COVID-19, and may help to inform the development of multilevel strategies to reduce the burden of racial disparities in COVID-19 and its ongoing sequelae. Incorporating contextual information, elucidated from qualitative interviews, will increase the efficacy, adoption, and sustainability of such strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERNATIONAL REGISTERED REPORT IDENTIFIER (IRRID)" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">RR1-10.2196/38914.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Jessica L Harding, Shivani A Patel, Teaniese Davis, Rachel E Patzer, Bennett McDonald, Doraina Walker-Williams, Ram Jagannathan, Larissa Teunis, Jennifer Gander. Originally published in JMIR Research Protocols (https://www.researchprotocols.org), 06.10.2022.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harding</LastName><ForeName>Jessica L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6664-8630</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, Rollins School of Public Health, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Shivani A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0082-5857</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubert Department of Global Health, Rollins School of Public Health, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davis</LastName><ForeName>Teaniese</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7408-0291</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research and Evaluation, Kaiser Permanente, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patzer</LastName><ForeName>Rachel E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2573-9963</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, Rollins School of Public Health, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDonald</LastName><ForeName>Bennett</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5202-5056</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research and Evaluation, Kaiser Permanente, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walker-Williams</LastName><ForeName>Doraina</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2933-0965</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research and Evaluation, Kaiser Permanente, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jagannathan</LastName><ForeName>Ram</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4267-5033</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Hospital Medicine, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teunis</LastName><ForeName>Larissa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7144-9073</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gander</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4798-0750</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research and Evaluation, Kaiser Permanente, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Res Protoc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101599504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1929-0748</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disease severity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disparity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">equity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ethnicity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mixed methods</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pandemic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">race</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">racial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social determinants of health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36166652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9555818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/38914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v11i10e38914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Azar KMJ, Shen Z, Romanelli RJ, Lockhart SH, Smits K, Robinson S, Brown S, Pressman AR. Disparities in outcomes among COVID-19 patients in a large health care system In California. Health Aff. 2020 Jul 01;39(7):1253&#x2013;1262. doi: 10.1377/hlthaff.2020.00598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1377/hlthaff.2020.00598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold JAW, Wong KK, Szablewski CM, Patel PR, Rossow J, da Silva J, Natarajan P, Morris SB, Fanfair RN, Rogers-Brown J, Bruce BB, Browning SD, Hernandez-Romieu AC, Furukawa NW, Kang M, Evans ME, Oosmanally N, Tobin-D'Angelo M, Drenzek C, Murphy DJ, Hollberg J, Blum JM, Jansen R, Wright DW, Sewell WM, Owens JD, Lefkove B, Brown FW, Burton DC, Uyeki TM, Bialek SR, Jackson BR. Characteristics and clinical outcomes of adult patients hospitalized with COVID-19 - Georgia, March 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020 May 08;69(18):545&#x2013;550. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm6918e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm6918e1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7737948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killerby ME, Link-Gelles R, Haight SC, Schrodt CA, England L, Gomes DJ, Shamout M, Pettrone K, O'Laughlin K, Kimball A, Blau EF, Burnett E, Ladva CN, Szablewski CM, Tobin-D'Angelo M, Oosmanally N, Drenzek C, Murphy DJ, Blum JM, Hollberg J, Lefkove B, Brown FW, Shimabukuro T, Midgley CM, Tate JE, CDC COVID-19 Response Clinical Team Characteristics associated with hospitalization among patients with COVID-19 - Metropolitan Atlanta, Georgia, March-April 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020 Jun 26;69(25):790&#x2013;794. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm6925e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm6925e1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7316317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32584797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahajan U, Larkins-Pettigrew M. Racial demographics and COVID-19 confirmed cases and deaths: a correlational analysis of 2886 US counties. J Public Health. 2020 Aug 18;42(3):445&#x2013;447. doi: 10.1093/pubmed/fdaa070. 
 
5841318</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/pubmed/fdaa070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7313814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32435809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price-Haywood EG, Burton J, Fort D, Seoane L. Hospitalization and mortality among Black patients and white patients with Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020 Jun 25;382(26):2534&#x2013;2543. doi: 10.1056/NEJMsa2011686. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMsa2011686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7269015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32459916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 United States cases by county. Johns Hopkins University and Medicine Coronavirus Research Center.  [2020-04-17].  
 https://coronavirus.jhu.edu/us-map
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webb Hooper M, N&#xe1;poles AM, P&#xe9;rez-Stable EJ. COVID-19 and racial/ethnic disparities. JAMA. 2020 Jun 23;323(24):2466&#x2013;2467. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.8598. 
 
2766098</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.8598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9310097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32391864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NIMHD Minority Health and Health Disparities Research Framework. National Institutes of Health National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities.  [2021-03-15].  
 https://www.nimhd.nih.gov/about/overview/research-framework.html
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minkler M, Wallerstein N. Community-based participatory research: from process to outcomes. San Francisco, CA: Jossey-Bass; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly-Pumarol IJ, Henderson PQ, Rushing JT, Andrews JE, Kost RG, Wagenknecht LE. Delivery of the research participant perception survey through the patient portal. J Clin Transl Sci. 2018 Jun 21;2(3):163&#x2013;168. doi: 10.1017/cts.2018.32. 
 
00032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/cts.2018.32</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6199552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30370068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennink M, Hutter I, Bailey A. Qualitative research methods. New York, NY: SAGE Publications Limited; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger N. Discrimination and health inequities. Int J Health Serv. 2014;44(4):643&#x2013;710. doi: 10.2190/HS.44.4.b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2190/HS.44.4.b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25626224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger N, Waterman PD, Kosheleva A, Chen JT, Carney DR, Smith KW, Bennett GG, Williams DR, Freeman E, Russell B, Thornhill G, Mikolowsky K, Rifkin R, Samuel L. PLoS One. 2011 Nov 18;6(11):e27636. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0027636. 
 
PONE-D-11-17049</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0027636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0027636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3220691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22125618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannidis JPA, Powe NR, Yancy C. Recalibrating the use of race in medical research. JAMA. 2021 Feb 16;325(7):623&#x2013;624. doi: 10.1001/jama.2021.0003.2775794</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.0003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33492329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin SS, Kelsey JL. Use of race and ethnicity in epidemiologic research: concepts, methodological issues, and suggestions for research. Epidemiol Rev. 2000 Jan 01;22(2):187&#x2013;202. doi: 10.1093/oxfordjournals.epirev.a018032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oxfordjournals.epirev.a018032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11218371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott M, Fremont A, Morrison P, Pantoja P, Lurie N. A new method for estimating race/ethnicity and associated disparities where administrative records lack self-reported race/ethnicity. Health Serv Res. 2008 Oct;43(5 Pt 1):1722&#x2013;1736. doi: 10.1111/j.1475-6773.2008.00854.x. 
 
HESR854</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1475-6773.2008.00854.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2653886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18479410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bursac Z, Gauss CH, Williams DK, Hosmer DW. Purposeful selection of variables in logistic regression. Source Code Biol Med. 2008 Dec 16;3(1):17. doi: 10.1186/1751-0473-3-17. 
 
1751-0473-3-17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1751-0473-3-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1751-0473-3-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2633005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19087314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg S, Kim L, Whitaker M, O'Halloran A, Cummings C, Holstein R, Prill M, Chai SJ, Kirley PD, Alden NB, Kawasaki B, Yousey-Hindes K, Niccolai L, Anderson EJ, Openo KP, Weigel A, Monroe ML, Ryan P, Henderson J, Kim S, Como-Sabetti K, Lynfield R, Sosin D, Torres S, Muse A, Bennett NM, Billing L, Sutton M, West N, Schaffner W, Talbot HK, Aquino C, George A, Budd A, Brammer L, Langley G, Hall AJ, Fry A. Hospitalization rates and characteristics of patients hospitalized with laboratory-confirmed coronavirus disease 2019 - COVID-NET, 14 States, March 1-30, 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020 Apr 17;69(15):458&#x2013;464. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm6915e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm6915e3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andridge RR, Little RJ. The use of sample weights in hot deck imputation. J Off Stat. 2009;25(1):21&#x2013;36. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3117228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21691591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isong I, Rao S, Bind M, Avenda&#xf1;o M, Kawachi I, Richmond T. Racial and ethnic disparities in early childhood obesity. Pediatrics. 2018 Jan;141(1):e20170865. doi: 10.1542/peds.2017-0865. 
 
peds.2017-0865</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2017-0865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5744272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29269386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson J, VanderWeele T. Decomposition analysis to identify intervention targets for reducing disparities. Epidemiology. 2018 Nov;29(6):825&#x2013;835. doi: 10.1097/EDE.0000000000000901. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/EDE.0000000000000901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6218173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30063540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racial Data Dashboard. The COVID Tracking Project at The Atlantic. 2021.  [2021-03-10].  
 https://covidtracking.com/race/dashboard
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Wang L. Sample size planning for detecting mediation effects: a power analysis procedure considering uncertainty in effect size estimates. Multivariate Behav Res. 2019 Apr 15;54(6):822&#x2013;839. doi: 10.1080/00273171.2019.1593814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00273171.2019.1593814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30983425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 OBSSR Research Tools. National Institute of Health Office of Behavioral and Social Science Research. 2020.  [2021-08-11].  
 https://obssr.od.nih.gov/research-resources
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders EB, Stappers PJ. Co-creation and the new landscapes of design. CoDesign. 2008 Mar;4(1):5&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1080/15710880701875068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15710880701875068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis S. Qualitative inquiry and research design: choosing among five approaches. Health Promotion Practice. 2015 Apr 02;16(4):473&#x2013;475. doi: 10.1177/1524839915580941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1524839915580941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis JJ, Johnston M, Robertson C, Glidewell L, Entwistle V, Eccles MP, Grimshaw JM. What is an adequate sample size? Operationalising data saturation for theory-based interview studies. Psychol Health. 2010 Dec;25(10):1229&#x2013;1245. doi: 10.1080/08870440903194015.916180756</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08870440903194015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20204937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetters MD, Molina-Azorin JF. A checklist of mixed methods elements in a submission for advancing the methodology of mixed methods research. J Mixed Method Res. 2019 Oct 10;13(4):414&#x2013;423. doi: 10.1177/1558689819875832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1558689819875832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su D, Alshehri K, Ern J, Chen B, Chen L, Chen Z, Han X, King KM, Li H, Li J, Li Y, Michaud T, Shi L, Ramos AK, Wen M, Zhang D. Racism experience among American adults during COVID-19: a mixed-methods study. Health Equity. 2022 Aug 01;6(1):554&#x2013;563. doi: 10.1089/heq.2022.0070. 
 
10.1089/heq.2022.0070</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/heq.2022.0070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9448514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36081888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding J, Andes L, Rolka D, Imperatore G, Gregg EW, Li Y, Albright A. National and state-level trends in nontraumatic lower-extremity amputation among U.S. medicare beneficiaries with diabetes, 2000-2017. Diabetes Care. 2020 Oct;43(10):2453&#x2013;2459. doi: 10.2337/dc20-0586.dc20-0586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc20-0586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10982954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32723844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding J, Benoit S, Gregg E, Pavkov M, Perreault L. Trends in rates of infections requiring hospitalization among adults with versus without diabetes in the U.S., 2000-2015. Diabetes Care. 2020 Jan;43(1):106&#x2013;116. doi: 10.2337/dc19-0653.dc19-0653</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc19-0653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31615853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding J, Shaw J, Peeters A, Cartensen B, Magliano D. Cancer risk among people with type 1 and type 2 diabetes: disentangling true associations, detection bias, and reverse causation. Diabetes Care. 2015 Feb;38(2):264&#x2013;270. doi: 10.2337/dc14-1996.dc14-1996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc14-1996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25488912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding J, Shaw J, Peeters A, Guiver T, Davidson S, Magliano D. Mortality trends among people with type 1 and type 2 diabetes in Australia: 1997-2010. Diabetes Care. 2014 Sep;37(9):2579&#x2013;2586. doi: 10.2337/dc14-0096.dc14-0096</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc14-0096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24947787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrager JD, Patzer RE, Kim JJ, Pitts SR, Chokshi FH, Phillips JS, Zhang X. Racial and ethnic differences in diagnostic imaging utilization during adult emergency department visits in the United States, 2005 to 2014. J Am Coll Radiol. 2019 Aug;16(8):1036&#x2013;1045. doi: 10.1016/j.jacr.2019.03.002.S1546-1440(19)30305-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacr.2019.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31092354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiley Z, Ross-Driscoll K, Wang Z, Smothers L, Mehta A, Patzer R. Racial and ethnic differences and clinical outcomes of patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) presenting to the emergency department. Clin Infect Dis. 2022 Feb 11;74(3):387&#x2013;394. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciab290. 
 
6209403</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8083480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33822023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loh V, Harding J, Koshkina V, Barr E, Shaw J, Magliano D. The validity of self-reported cancer in an Australian population study. Aust N Z J Public Health. 2014 Feb 04;38(1):35&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1111/1753-6405.12164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1753-6405.12164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24494943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>QuickFacts Georgia. U.S. Census Bureau.  [2021-03-14].  
 https://www.census.gov/quickfacts/GA
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiefel MC, Gordon NP, Wilson-Anumudu FJ, Arsen EL. Sociodemographic determinants of health and well-being among adults residing in the Combined Kaiser Permanente Regions. Perm J. 2019;23:18-091. doi: 10.7812/TPP/18-091. 
 
18-091</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7812/TPP/18-091?url_ver=Z39.88-2003&amp;rfr_id=ori:rid:crossref.org&amp;rfr_dat=cr_pub%3dpubmed</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7812/TPP/18-091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6499116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31050642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bautista MC, Jiang S, Armstrong MA, Kakar S, Postlethwaite D, Li D. Significant racial disparities exist in noncardia gastric cancer outcomes among Kaiser Permanente's patient population. Dig Dis Sci. 2015 Apr 30;60(4):984&#x2013;995. doi: 10.1007/s10620-014-3409-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10620-014-3409-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25354832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young-Wolff KC, Adams SR, Tan AS, Adams AS, Klebaner D, Campbell CI, Satre DD, Salloum RG, Carter-Harris L, Prochaska JJ. Disparities in knowledge and use of tobacco treatment among smokers in California following healthcare reform. Prev Med Rep. 2019 Jun;14:100847. doi: 10.1016/j.pmedr.2019.100847. 
 
S2211-3355(19)30032-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmedr.2019.100847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6476812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31024786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall CJ, Rodriguez HP, Dyer W, Schmittdiel JA. Racial and ethnic disparities in diabetes care quality among women of reproductive age in an integrated delivery system. Womens Health Issues. 2020 May;30(3):191&#x2013;199. doi: 10.1016/j.whi.2020.03.003.S1049-3867(20)30020-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.whi.2020.03.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32340896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>