<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34339806</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1090-2139</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>97</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Brain, behavior, and immunity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Brain Behav Immun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19 - A systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>328</StartPage><EndPage>348</EndPage><MedlinePgn>328-348</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bbi.2021.07.018</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0889-1591(21)00281-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>It has become evident that coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) has a multi-organ pathology that includes the brain and nervous system. Several studies have also reported acute psychiatric symptoms in COVID-19 patients. An increasing number of studies are suggesting that psychiatric deficits may persist after recovery from the primary infection. In the current systematic review, we provide an overview of the available evidence and supply information on potential risk factors and underlying biological mechanisms behind such psychiatric sequelae. We performed a systematic search for psychiatric sequelae in COVID-19 patients using the databases PubMed and Embase. Included primary studies all contained information on the follow-up period and provided quantitative measures of mental health. The search was performed on June 4th 2021. 1725 unique studies were identified. Of these, 66 met the inclusion criteria and were included. Time to follow-up ranged from immediately after hospital discharge up to 7&#xa0;months after discharge, and the number of participants spanned 3 to 266,586 participants. Forty studies reported anxiety and/or depression, 20 studies reported symptoms- or diagnoses of post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), 27 studies reported cognitive deficits, 32 articles found fatigue at follow-up, and sleep disturbances were found in 23 studies. Highlighted risk factors were disease severity, duration of symptoms, and female sex. One study showed brain abnormalities correlating with cognitive deficits, and several studies reported inflammatory markers to correlate with symptoms. Overall, the results from this review suggest that survivors of COVID-19 are at risk of psychiatric sequelae but that symptoms generally improve over time.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schou</LastName><ForeName>Thor Mertz</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Neuropsychiatry Unit, Department of Clinical Medicine, Aarhus University, 8000 Aarhus C, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joca</LastName><ForeName>Samia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine, Aarhus University, 8000 Aarhus C, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wegener</LastName><ForeName>Gregers</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Neuropsychiatry Unit, Department of Clinical Medicine, Aarhus University, 8000 Aarhus C, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bay-Richter</LastName><ForeName>Cecilie</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Neuropsychiatry Unit, Department of Clinical Medicine, Aarhus University, 8000 Aarhus C, Denmark. Electronic address: cbr@clin.au.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Brain Behav Immun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8800478</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0889-1591</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Infect. 2022 Jun;84(6):834-872. doi: 10.1016/j.jinf.2022.03.008</RefSource><PMID Version="1">35283185</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001008" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety Disorders</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013313" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PTSD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychiatric sequelae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8363196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2021.07.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0889-1591(21)00281-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: let patients help define long-lasting COVID symptoms. Nature 586, 170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33029005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achtyes E., Keaton S.A., Smart LeAnn, Burmeister A.R., Heilman P.L., Krzyzanowski S., Nagalla M., Guillemin G.J., Escobar Galvis M.L., Lim C.K., Muzik M., Postolache T.T., Leach R., Brundin L. Inflammation and kynurenine pathway dysregulation in post-partum women with severe and suicidal depression. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;83:239&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6906225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31698012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z., Xie Y., Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594(7862):259&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albu S., Zozaya N.R., Murillo N., Garc&#xed;a-Molina A., Chac&#xf3;n C.A.F., Kumru H. What's going on following acute covid-19? Clinical characteristics of patients in an out-patient rehabilitation program. NeuroRehabilitation. 2021;48(4):469&#x2013;480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33998551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemanno F., Houdayer E., Parma A., Spina A., Del Forno A., Scatolini A., Angelone S., Brugliera L., Tettamanti A., Beretta L., Iannaccone S., Di Gennaro F. COVID-19 cognitive deficits after respiratory assistance in the subacute phase: a COVID-rehabilitation unit experience. PLoS One. 2021;16(2):e0246590. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0246590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0246590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7870071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33556127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin, M., Schommers, P., Stecher, M., Dewald, F., Gieselmann, L., Gruell, H., Horn, C., Vanshylla, K., Cristanziano, V.D., Osebold, L., Roventa, M., Riaz, T., Tschernoster, N., Altmueller, J., Rose, L., Salomon, S., Priesner, V., Luers, J.C., Albus, C., Rosenkranz, S., Gathof, B., F&#xe4;tkenheuer, G., Hallek, M., Klein, F., Su&#xe1;rez, I., Lehmann, C., 2021. Post-COVID syndrome in non-hospitalised patients with COVID-19: a longitudinal prospective cohort study. Lancet Reg. Health Eur. 6, 100122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8129613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34027514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellan, M., Soddu, D., Balbo, P.E., Baricich, A., Zeppegno, P., Avanzi, G.C., Baldon, G., Bartolomei, G., Battaglia, M., Battistini, S., Binda, V., Borg, M., Cantaluppi, V., Castello, L.M., Clivati, E., Cisari, C., Costanzo, M., Croce, A., Cuneo, D., De Benedittis, C., De Vecchi, S., Feggi, A., Gai, M., Gambaro, E., Gattoni, E., Gramaglia, C., Grisafi, L., Guerriero, C., Hayden, E., Jona, A., Invernizzi, M., Lorenzini, L., Loreti, L., Martelli, M., Marzullo, P., Matino, E., Panero, A., Parachini, E., Patrucco, F., Patti, G., Pirovano, A., Prosperini, P., Quaglino, R., Rigamonti, C., Sainaghi, P.P., Vecchi, C., Zecca, E., Pirisi, M., 2021. Respiratory and psychophysical sequelae among patients with COVID-19 four months after hospital discharge. JAMA Netw. Open 4, e2036142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7841464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33502487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boari G.E.M., Bonetti S., Braglia-Orlandini F., Chiarini G., Faustini C., Bianco G., Santagiuliana M., Guarinoni V., Saottini M., Viola S., Ferrari-Toninelli G., Pasini G., Bonzi B., Desenzani P., Tusi C., Malerba P., Zanotti E., Turini D., Rizzoni D. Short-term consequences of SARS-CoV-2-related pneumonia: a follow up study. High Blood Press Cardiovasc. Prev. 2021;28(4):373&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8080190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33909284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady K.T., Killeen T.K., Brewerton T., Lucerini S. Comorbidity of psychiatric disorders and posttraumatic stress disorder. J. Clin. Psychiatry. 2000;61(Suppl 7):22&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10795606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen K.Y., Li T., Gong F.H., Zhang J.S., Li X.K. Predictors of Health-Related Quality of Life and Influencing Factors for COVID-19 Patients, a Follow-Up at One Month. Front Psychiatry. 2020;11:668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7360857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32733299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chevinsky J.R., Tao G., Lavery A.M., Kukielka E.A., Click E.S., Malec D., Kompaniyets L., Bruce B.B., Yusuf H., Goodman A.B., Dixon M.G., Nakao J.H., Datta S.D., Mac Kenzie W.R., Kadri S., Saydah S., Giovanni J.E., Gundlapalli A.V. Late conditions diagnosed 1&#x2013;4 months following an initial COVID-19 encounter: a matched cohort study using inpatient and outpatient administrative data - United States, March 1-June 30, 2020. Clin. Infect Dis. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8135331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33909072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia J.K.S., Chia A.Y. Chronic fatigue syndrome is associated with chronic enterovirus infection of the stomach. J. Clin. Pathol. 2008;61(1):43&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Cruz, R.F., Waller, M.D., Perrin, F., Periselneris, J., Norton, S., Smith, L.J., Patrick, T., Walder, D., Heitmann, A., Lee, K., Madula, R., McNulty, W., Macedo, P., Lyall, R., Warwick, G., Galloway, J.B., Birring, S.S., Patel, A., Patel, I., Jolley, C.J., 2021. Chest radiography is a poor predictor of respiratory symptoms and functional impairment in survivors of severe COVID-19 pneumonia. ERJ Open Res. 7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7585700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33575312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher A., Balfanz P., Cornelissen C., M&#xfc;ller A., Bergs I., Marx N., M&#xfc;ller-Wieland D., Hartmann B., Dreher M., M&#xfc;ller T. Follow up of patients with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): Pulmonary and extrapulmonary disease sequelae. Respir. Med. 2020;174:106197. doi: 10.1016/j.rmed.2020.106197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2020.106197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33120193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahl J., Ormstad H., Aass H.C.D., Malt U.F., Bendz L.T., Sandvik L., Brundin L., Andreassen O.A. The plasma levels of various cytokines are increased during ongoing depression and are reduced to normal levels after recovery. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2014;45:77&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24845179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantzer R., O'Connor J.C., Freund G.G., Johnson R.W., Kelley K.W. From inflammation to sickness and depression: when the immune system subjugates the brain. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 2008;9(1):46&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2919277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18073775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darley D.R., Dore G.J., Cysique L., Wilhelm K.A., Andresen D., Tonga K., Stone E., Byrne A., Plit M., Masters J., Tang H., Brew B., Cunningham P., Kelleher A., Matthews G. Persistent symptoms up to four months after community and hospital-managed SARS-CoV-2 infection. Med. J. Aust. 2021;214(6):279&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty S.E., Guo Y., Heath K., Dasmari&#xf1;as M.C., Jubilo K.G., Samranvedhya J., Lipsitch M., Cohen K. Risk of clinical sequelae after the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8132065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Graaf, M.A., Antoni, M.L., Ter Kuile, M.M., Arbous, M.S., Duinisveld, A.J.F., Feltkamp, M.C.W., Groeneveld, G.H., Hinnen, S.C.H., Janssen, V.R., Lijfering, W.M., Omara, S., Postmus, P.E., Ramai, S.R.S., Rius-Ottenheim, N., Schalij, M.J., Schiemanck, S.K., Smid, L., St&#xf6;ger, J.L., Visser, L.G., de Vries, J.J.C., Wijngaarden, M.A., Geelhoed, J.J.M., Roukens, A.H.E., 2021. Short-term outpatient follow-up of COVID-19 patients: a multidisciplinary approach. EClinicalMedicine, 100731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7843037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33532720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lorenzo R., Conte C., Lanzani C., Benedetti F., Roveri L., Mazza M.G., Brioni E., Giacalone G., Canti V., Sofia V., D&#x2019;Amico M., Di Napoli D., Ambrosio A., Scarpellini P., Castagna A., Landoni G., Zangrillo A., Bosi E., Tresoldi M., Ciceri F., Rovere-Querini P., Adrish M. Residual clinical damage after COVID-19: a retrospective and prospective observational cohort study. PLoS One. 2020;15(10):e0239570. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0239570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0239570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7556454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33052920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Divani A.A., Andalib S., Di Napoli M., Lattanzi S., Hussain M.S., Biller J., McCullough L.D., Azarpazhooh M.R., Seletska A., Mayer S.A., Torbey M. Coronavirus disease 2019 and stroke: clinical manifestations and pathophysiological insights. J. Stroke Cerebrovasc. Dis. 2020;29(8):104941. doi: 10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2020.104941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2020.104941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7214348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32689643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drzyzga &#x141;., Obuchowicz E., Marcinowska A., Herman Z.S. Cytokines in schizophrenia and the effects of antipsychotic drugs. Brain Behav. Immun. 2006;20(6):532&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16580814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egbert, A.R., Cankurtaran, S., Karpiak, S., 2020. Brain abnormalities in COVID-19 acute/subacute phase: a rapid systematic review. Brain Behav Immun.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7366124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32682993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera J.A., Yang D., Lewis A., Patel P., Medicherla C., Arena V., Fang T., Andino A., Snyder T., Madhavan M., Gratch D., Fuchs B., Dessy A., Canizares M., Jauregui R., Thomas B., Bauman K., Olivera A., Bhagat D., Sonson M., Park G., Stainman R., Sunwoo B., Talmasov D., Tamimi M., Zhu Y., Rosenthal J., Dygert L., Ristic M., Ishii H., Valdes E., Omari M., Gurin L., Huang J., Czeisler B.M., Kahn D.E., Zhou T., Lin J., Lord A.S., Melmed K., Meropol S., Troxel A.B., Petkova E., Wisniewski T., Balcer L., Morrison C., Yaghi S., Galetta S. A prospective study of long-term outcomes among hospitalized COVID-19 patients with and without neurological complications. J. Neurol. Sci. 2021;426:117486. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2021.117486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2021.117486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8113108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34000678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam N., Madathil S., Tahani N., Bolton S., Parekh D., Stockley J., Goyal S., Qureshi H., Yasmin S., Cooper B.G., Short J., Geberhiwot T. Medium-term outcome of severe to critically ill patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Clin. Infect Dis. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8135551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33893486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavriatopoulou M., Korompoki E., Fotiou D., Ntanasis-Stathopoulos I., Psaltopoulou T., Kastritis E., Terpos E., Dimopoulos M.A. Organ-specific manifestations of COVID-19 infection. Clin. Exp. Med. 2020;20(4):493&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32720223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gennaro M.M., Mariagrazia P., De Lorenzo R., Cristiano M., Sara P., Roberto F., Fabio C., Patrizia R.Q., Francesco B. Persistent psychopathology and neurocognitive impairment in COVID-19 survivors: effect of inflammatory biomarkers at three-month follow-up. Brain Behav. Immun. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33639239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez J., Ben&#xed;tez I.D., Carmona P., Santisteve S., Monge A., Moncus&#xed;-Moix A., Gort-Paniello C., Pinilla L., Carratal&#xe1; A., Zuil M., Ferrer R., Ceccato A., Fern&#xe1;ndez L., Motos A., Riera J., Men&#xe9;ndez R., Garcia-Gasulla D., Pe&#xf1;uelas O., Bermejo-Martin J.F., Labarca G., Caballero J., Torres G., de Gonzalo-Calvo D., Torres A., Barb&#xe9; F. PULMONARY FUNCTION AND RADIOLOGICAL FEATURES IN SURVIVORS OF CRITICAL COVID-19: A 3-MONTH PROSPECTIVE COHORT. Chest. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7930807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33676998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowrisankar Y.V., Clark M.A. Angiotensin II regulation of angiotensin-converting enzymes in spontaneously hypertensive rat primary astrocyte cultures. J. Neurochem. 2016;138(1):74&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27085714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham E.L., Clark J.R., Orban Z.S., Lim P.H., Szymanski A.L., Taylor C., DiBiase R.M., Jia D.T., Balabanov R., Ho S.U., Batra A., Liotta E.M., Koralnik I.J. Persistent neurologic symptoms and cognitive dysfunction in non-hospitalized Covid-19 &#x201c;long haulers&#x201d;. Ann. Clin. Transl. Neurol. 2021;8(5):1073&#x2013;1085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33755344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin S.J., McIvor C., Whyatt G., Adams A., Harvey O., McLean L., Walshaw C., Kemp S., Corrado J., Singh R., Collins T., O'Connor R.J., Sivan M. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J. Med. Virol. 2021;93(2):1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J., Kremer S., Merdji H., Clere-Jehl R., Schenck M., Kummerlen C., Collange O., Boulay C., Fafi-Kremer S., Ohana M., Anheim M., Meziani F. Neurologic features in severe SARS-CoV-2 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020;382(23):2268&#x2013;2270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7179967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32294339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J., Kremer S., Merdji H., Schenck M., Severac F., Clere-Jehl R., Studer A., Radosavljevic M., Kummerlen C., Monnier A., Boulay C., Fafi-Kremer S., Castelain V., Ohana M., Anheim M., Schneider F., Meziani F. Delirium and encephalopathy in severe COVID-19: a cohort analysis of ICU patients. Crit. Care. 2020;24:491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7414289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32771053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry B.M., Aggarwal G., Wong J., Benoit S., Vikse J., Plebani M., Lippi G. Lactate dehydrogenase levels predict coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) severity and mortality: A pooled analysis. Am. J. Emer. Med. 2020;38(9):1722&#x2013;1726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7251362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn M., Wathelet M., Fovet T., Amad A., Vuotto F., Faure K., Astier T., No&#xeb;l H., Henry M., Duhem S., Vaiva G., D&#x2019;Hondt F. Is COVID-19 associated with posttraumatic stress disorder? J. Clin. Psychiatry. 2020;82(1) doi: 10.4088/JCP.20m13641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.20m13641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33296149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Y., Chen, Y., Zheng, Y., You, C., Tan, J., Hu, L., Zhang, Z., Ding, L., 2020. Factors related to mental health of inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China. Brain Behav Immun.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7362867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32681866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C., Huang L., Wang Y., Li X., Ren L., Gu X., Kang L., Guo L.i., Liu M., Zhou X., Luo J., Huang Z., Tu S., Zhao Y., Chen L.i., Xu D., Li Y., Li C., Peng L.u., Li Y., Xie W., Cui D., Shang L., Fan G., Xu J., Wang G., Wang Y., Zhong J., Wang C., Wang J., Zhang D., Cao B. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S., Zhuang W., Wang D., Zha L., Xu X., Li X., Shi Q., Wang X.S., Qiao G. Persistent somatic symptom burden and sleep disturbance in patients with COVID-19 during hospitalization and after discharge: a prospective cohort study. Med. Sci. Monit. 2021;27</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8057653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33854028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulme K., Hudson J.L., Rojczyk P., Little P., Moss-Morris R. Biopsychosocial risk factors of persistent fatigue after acute infection: a systematic review to inform interventions. J. Psychosom. Res. 2017;99:120&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28712416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal A., Iqbal K., Arshad Ali S., Azim D., Farid E., Baig M.D., Bin Arif T., Raza M. The COVID-19 sequelae: a cross-sectional evaluation of post-recovery symptoms and the need for rehabilitation of COVID-19 survivors. Cureus. 2021;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7932827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33680620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kempuraj, D., Selvakumar, G.P., Ahmed, M.E., Raikwar, S.P., Thangavel, R., Khan, A., Zaheer, S.A., Iyer, S.S., Burton, C., James, D., Zaheer, A., 2020. COVID-19, mast cells, cytokine storm, psychological stress, and neuroinflammation. Neuroscientist, 1073858420941476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32684080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr J.R. Epstein-barr virus induced gene-2 upregulation identifies a particular subtype of chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis. Front. Pediatr. 2019;7:59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6424879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30918887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong, X., Zheng, K., Tang, M., Kong, F., Zhou, J., Diao, L., Wu, S., Jiao, P., Su, T., Dong, Y., 2020. Prevalence and factors associated with depression and anxiety of hospitalized patients with COVID-19. medRxiv, 2020.2003.2024.20043075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang L., Yang B., Jiang N., Fu W., He X., Zhou Y., Ma W.L., Wang X. Three-month follow-up study of survivors of coronavirus disease 2019 after discharge. J. Korean Med. Sci. 2020;35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7721559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33289374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L.-y., Wang J., Ou-yang X.-Y., Miao Q., Chen R., Liang F.-X., Zhang Y.-p., Tang Q., Wang T. The immediate impact of the 2019 novel coronavirus (COVID-19) outbreak on subjective sleep status. Sleep Med. 2021;77:348&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7831667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32593614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindqvist D., Janelidze S., Hagell P., Erhardt S., Samuelsson M., Minthon L., Hansson O., Bj&#xf6;rkqvist M., Tr&#xe4;skman-Bendz L., Brundin L. Interleukin-6 is elevated in the cerebrospinal fluid of suicide attempters and related to symptom severity. Biol. Psychiatry. 2009;66(3):287&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19268915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindqvist D., Wolkowitz O.M., Mellon S., Yehuda R., Flory J.D., Henn-Haase C., Bierer L.M., Abu-Amara D., Coy M., Neylan T.C., Makotkine I., Reus V.I., Yan X., Taylor N.M., Marmar C.R., Dhabhar F.S. Proinflammatory milieu in combat-related PTSD is independent of depression and early life stress. Brain Behav. Immun. 2014;42:81&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24929195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu N., Zhang F., Wei C., Jia Y., Shang Z., Sun L., Wu L., Sun Z., Zhou Y., Wang Y., Liu W. Prevalence and predictors of PTSS during COVID-19 outbreak in China hardest-hit areas: gender differences matter. Psychiatry Res. 2020;287:112921. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2020.112921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2020.112921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32240896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenzo R., Cinel E., Cilla M., Compagnone N., Ferrante M., Falbo E., Patrizi A., Castellani J., Magnaghi C., Calvisi S.L., Arcidiacono T., Lanzani C.L., Canti V., Mazza M.G., Martinenghi S., Vitali G., Benedetti F., Ciceri F., Conte C., Rovere Querini P. Physical and psychological sequelae at three months after acute illness in COVID-19 survivors. Panminerva Med. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34060280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y., Li X., Geng D., Mei N., Wu P.-Y., Huang C.-C., Jia T., Zhao Y., Wang D., Xiao A., Yin B. Cerebral micro-structural changes in COVID-19 patients - An MRI-based 3-month follow-up study. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100484. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mak I.W.C., Chu C.M., Pan P.C., Yiu M.G.C., Chan V.L. Long-term psychiatric morbidities among SARS survivors. Gen. Hosp. Psychiatry. 2009;31(4):318&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7112501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19555791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mak I.W.C., Chu C.M., Pan P.C., Yiu M.G.C., Ho S.C., Chan V.L. Risk factors for chronic post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) in SARS survivors. Gen. Hosp. Psychiatry. 2010;32(6):590&#x2013;598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7132390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21112450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matalon N., Dorman-Ilan S., Hasson-Ohayon I., Hertz-Palmor N., Shani S., Basel D., Gross R., Chen W., Abramovich A., Afek A., Ziv A., Kreiss Y., Pessach I.M., Gothelf D. Trajectories of post-traumatic stress symptoms, anxiety, and depression in hospitalized COVID-19 patients: a one-month follow-up. J. Psychosom. Res. 2021;143:110399. doi: 10.1016/j.jpsychores.2021.110399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2021.110399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7885629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33618149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke J., L&#xfc;tgehetmann M., Hagel C., Sperhake J.P., Schr&#xf6;der A.S., Edler C., Mushumba H., Fitzek A., Allweiss L., Dandri M., Dottermusch M., Heinemann A., Pfefferle S., Schwabenland M., Sumner Magruder D., Bonn S., Prinz M., Gerloff C., P&#xfc;schel K., Krasemann S., Aepfelbacher M., Glatzel M. Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19(11):919&#x2013;929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7535629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattioli F., Stampatori C., Righetti F., Sala E., Tomasi C., De Palma G. Neurological and cognitive sequelae of Covid-19: a four month follow-up. J. Neurol. 2021:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8088203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33932157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza M.G., De Lorenzo R., Conte C., Poletti S., Vai B., Bollettini I., Melloni E.M.T., Furlan R., Ciceri F., Rovere-Querini P., group C.-B.O.C.S., Benedetti F. Anxiety and depression in COVID-19 survivors: Role of inflammatory and clinical predictors. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;89:594&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7390748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza M.G., Palladini M., De Lorenzo R., Magnaghi C., Poletti S., Furlan R., Ciceri F., Rovere-Querini P., Benedetti F. Persistent psychopathology and neurocognitive impairment in COVID-19 survivors: Effect of inflammatory biomarkers at three-month follow-up. Brain Behav. Immun. 2021;94:138&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33639239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcloughlin B.C., Miles A., Webb T.E., Knopp P., Eyres C., Fabbri A., Humphries F., Davis D. Functional and cognitive outcomes after COVID-19 delirium. Eur. Geriatr. Med. 2020;11(5):857&#x2013;862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7358317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32666303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P., McAuley D.F., Brown M., Sanchez E., Tattersall R.S., Manson J.J., Hlh Across Speciality Collaboration U.K. COVID-19: consider cytokine storm syndromes and immunosuppression. Lancet. 2020;395:1033&#x2013;1034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez R., Balanz&#xe1;-Mart&#xed;nez V., Luperdi S.C., Estrada I., Latorre A., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Jim&#xe9;nez P., Feced L., Bouzas L., Y&#xe9;pez K., Ferrando A., Herv&#xe1;s D., Zald&#xed;var E., Reyes S., Berk M., Men&#xe9;ndez R. Short-term neuropsychiatric outcomes and quality of life in COVID-19 survivors. J. Intern. Med. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33533521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miskowiak K.W., Johnsen S., Sattler S.M., Nielsen S., Kunalan K., Rungby J., Lapperre T., Porsberg C.M. Cognitive impairments four months after COVID-19 hospital discharge: pattern, severity and association with illness variables. Eur. Neuropsychopharmacol. 2021;46:39&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33823427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monti G., Leggieri C., Fominskiy E., Scandroglio A.M., Colombo S., Tozzi M., Moizo E., Mucci M., Crivellari M., Pieri M., Guzzo F., Piemontese S., De Lorenzo R., Da Prat V., Fedrizzi M., Faustini C., Di Piazza M., Conte F., Lembo R., Esposito A., Dagna L., Landoni G., Zangrillo A. Two months quality of life of COVID-19 invasively ventilated survivors; an Italian single-center study. Acta Anaesthesiol. Scand. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33655487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin L., Savale L., Pham T., Colle R., Figueiredo S., Harrois A., Gasnier M., Lecoq A.L., Meyrignac O., Noel N., Baudry E., Bellin M.F., Beurnier A., Choucha W., Corruble E., Dortet L., Hardy-Leger I., Radiguer F., Sportouch S., Verny C., Wyplosz B., Zaidan M., Becquemont L., Montani D., Monnet X. Four-month clinical status of a cohort of patients after hospitalization for COVID-19. JAMA. 2021;325(15):1525. doi: 10.1001/jama.2021.3331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.3331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7970386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33729425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muccioli L., Pensato U., Cani I., Guarino M., Cortelli P., Bisulli F. Covid-19-associated encephalopathy and cytokine-mediated neuroinflammation. Ann. Neurol. 2020;88(4):860&#x2013;861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negrini F., Ferrario I., Mazziotti D., Berchicci M., Bonazzi M., de Sire A., Negrini S., Zapparoli L. Neuropsychological features of severe hospitalized coronavirus disease 2019 patients at clinical stability and clues for postacute rehabilitation. Arch. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 2021;102(1):155&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7521874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nemoto W., Yamagata R., Nakagawasai O., Nakagawa K., Hung W.Y., Fujita M., Tadano T., Tan-No K. Effect of spinal angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 activation on the formalin-induced nociceptive response in mice. Eur. J. Pharmacol. 2020;872:172950. doi: 10.1016/j.ejphar.2020.172950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejphar.2020.172950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31987711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noviello D., Costantino A., Muscatello A., Bandera A., Consonni D., Vecchi M., Basilisco G. Functional gastrointestinal and somatoform symptoms five months after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a controlled cohort study. Neurogastroenterol. Motil. 2021:e14187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8209890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34060710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortelli P., Ferrazzoli D., Sebastianelli L., Engl M., Romanello R., Nardone R., Bonini I., Koch G., Saltuari L., Quartarone A., Oliviero A., Kofler M., Versace V. Neuropsychological and neurophysiological correlates of fatigue in post-acute patients with neurological manifestations of COVID-19: insights into a challenging symptom. J. Neurol. Sci. 2021;420:117271. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2020.117271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2020.117271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passos I.C., Vasconcelos-Moreno M.P., Costa L.G., Kunz M., Brietzke E., Quevedo J., Salum G., Magalh&#xe3;es P.V, Kapczinski F., Kauer-Sant'Anna M. Inflammatory markers in post-traumatic stress disorder: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression. Lancet Psychiatry. 2015;2(11):1002&#x2013;1012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26544749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen, M.S., Kristiansen, M.F., Hanusson, K.D., Danielsen, M.E., B, &#xc1;.S., Gaini, S., Str&#xf8;m, M., Weihe, P., 2020. Long COVID in the Faroe Islands - a longitudinal study among non-hospitalized patients. Clin Infect Dis.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7799340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33252665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilotto A., Odolini S., Masciocchi S., Comelli A., Volonghi I., Gazzina S., Nocivelli S., Pezzini A., Foca E., Caruso A., Leonardi M., Pasolini M.P., Gasparotti R., Castelli F., Ashton N.J., Blennow K., Zetterberg H., Padovani A. Steroid-responsive encephalitis in coronavirus disease 2019. Ann. Neurol. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7276848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32418288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poyraz B., Poyraz C.A., Olgun Y., G&#xfc;rel &#xd6;., Alkan S., &#xd6;zdemir Y.E., Balkan &#x130;., Karaali R. Psychiatric morbidity and protracted symptoms after COVID-19. Psychiatry Res. 2021;295:113604. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7695976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33296818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu G., Zhen Q., Wang W., Fan S., Wu Q., Zhang C., Li B., Liu G., Yu Y., Li Y., Yong L., Lu B., Ding Z., Ge H., Mao Y., Chen W., Xu Q., Zhang R., Cao L., Chen S., Li H., Zhang H., Hu X., Zhang Jing, Wang Y., Zhang H., Liang C., Sun L., Sun Y. Health related quality of life of COVID-19 patients after discharge: a multicenter follow up study. J Clin Nurs. 2021;30(11-12):1742&#x2013;1750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33656210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raison C.L., Capuron L., Miller A.H. Cytokines sing the blues: inflammation and the pathogenesis of depression. Trends Immunol. 2006;27(1):24&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3392963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16316783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers J.P., Chesney E., Oliver D., Pollak T.A., McGuire P., Fusar-Poli P., Zandi M.S., Lewis G., David A.S. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: a systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;7(7):611&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7234781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Duarte &#xc1;., Rivera-Izquierdo M., Guerrero-Fern&#xe1;ndez de Alba I., P&#xe9;rez-Contreras M., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Mart&#xed;nez N.F., Ruiz-Montero R., Serrano-Ortiz &#xc1;., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Serna R.O., Salcedo-Leal I., Jim&#xe9;nez-Mej&#xed;as E., C&#xe1;rdenas-Cruz A. Sequelae, persistent symptomatology and outcomes after COVID-19 hospitalization: the ANCOHVID multicentre 6-month follow-up study. BMC Med. 2021;19:129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8134820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudroff T., Fietsam A.C., Deters J.R., Bryant A.D., Kamholz J. Post-COVID-19 fatigue: potential contributing factors. Brain Sci. 2020;10(12):1012. doi: 10.3390/brainsci10121012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci10121012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7766297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33352638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salari N., Hosseinian-Far A., Jalali R., Vaisi-Raygani A., Rasoulpoor S., Mohammadi M., Rasoulpoor S., Khaledi-Paveh B. Prevalence of stress, anxiety, depression among the general population during the COVID-19 pandemic: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Global Health. 2020;16:57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7338126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32631403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sami R., Soltaninejad F., Amra B., Naderi Z., Haghjooy Javanmard S., Iraj B., Haji Ahmadi S., Shayganfar A., Dehghan M., Khademi N., Sadat Hosseini N., Mortazavi M., Mansourian M., Ma&#xf1;anas M.A., Marateb H.R., Adibi P., Di Gennaro F. A one-year hospital-based prospective COVID-19 open-cohort in the Eastern Mediterranean region: the Khorshid COVID Cohort (KCC) study. PLoS One. 2020;15(11):e0241537. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0241537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0241537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7644058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33151983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Y.F., Liu T., Yu J.N., Xu X.R., Zahid K.R., Wei Y.C., Wang X.H., Zhou F.L. Half-year follow-up of patients recovering from severe COVID-19: analysis of symptoms and their risk factors. J. Intern. Med. 2021;290(2):444&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33904618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soltani P., Patini Romeo. Retracted COVID-19 articles: a side-effect of the hot race to publication. Scientometrics. 2020;125(1):819&#x2013;822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7405382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32836531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparks S.W. Posttraumatic stress syndrome: what is it? J. Trauma Nurs. 2018;25:60&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29319653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre C.H., Murray B., Varsavsky T., Graham M.S., Penfold R.S., Bowyer R.C., Pujol J.C., Klaser K., Antonelli M., Canas L.S., Molteni E., Modat M., Jorge Cardoso M., May A., Ganesh S., Davies R., Nguyen L.H., Drew D.A., Astley C.M., Joshi A.D., Merino J., Tsereteli N., Fall T., Gomez M.F., Duncan E.L., Menni C., Williams F.M.K., Franks P.W., Chan A.T., Wolf J., Ourselin S., Spector T., Steves C.J. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat. Med. 2021;27(4):626&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L.L., Wang J., Wang Y.S., Hu P.F., Zhao Z.Q., Chen W., Ning B.F., Yin C., Hao Y.S., Wang Q., Wang C., Liu Y.L., Chen C., Yin J.Z., Huang H., Xie W.F. Symptomatic features and prognosis of 932 hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan. J. Dig. Dis. 2021;22:271&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33742780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes D.L., Holdsworth L., Jawad N., Gunasekera P., Morice A.H., Crooks M.G. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;199(2):113&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan W., Hao F., McIntyre R.S., Jiang L., Jiang X., Zhang L., Zhao X., Zou Y., Hu Y., Luo X., Zhang Z., Lai A., Ho R., Tran B., Ho C., Tam W. Is returning to work during the COVID-19 pandemic stressful? A study on immediate mental health status and psychoneuroimmunity prevention measures of Chinese workforce. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;87:84&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7179503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32335200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang S.W., Helmeste D., Leonard B. Inflammatory neuropsychiatric disorders and COVID-19 neuroinflammation. Acta Neuropsychiatr. 2021;33(4):165&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33926589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanriverdi A., Savci S., Kahraman B.O., Ozpelit E. Extrapulmonary features of post-COVID-19 patients: muscle function, physical activity, mood, and sleep quality. Ir. J. Med. Sci. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8172250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34080125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M., Geddes J.R., Husain M., Luciano S., Harrison P.J. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8(5):416&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M., Luciano S., Geddes J.R., Harrison P.J. Bidirectional associations between COVID-19 and psychiatric disorder: retrospective cohort studies of 62 354 COVID-19 cases in the USA. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8(2):130&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde M.W., Kim S.S., Lindsell C.J., Billig Rose E., Shapiro N.I., Files D.C., Gibbs K.W., Erickson H.L., Steingrub J.S., Smithline H.A., Gong M.N., Aboodi M.S., Exline M.C., Henning D.J., Wilson J.G., Khan A., Qadir N., Brown S.M., Peltan I.D., Rice T.W., Hager D.N., Ginde A.A., Stubblefield W.B., Patel M.M., Self W.H., Feldstein L.R., Hart K.W., McClellan R., Dorough L., Dzuris N., Griggs E.P., Kassem A.M., Marcet P.L., Ogokeh C.E., Sciarratta C.N., Siddula A., Smith E.R., Wu M.J. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a Multistate Health Care Systems Network - United States, March-June 2020. MMWR Morb. Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69(30):993&#x2013;998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasoni D., Bai F., Castoldi R., Barbanotti D., Falcinella C., Mul&#xe8; G., Mondatore D., Tavelli A., Vegni E., Marchetti G., d'Arminio Monforte A. Anxiety and depression symptoms after virological clearance of COVID-19: a cross-sectional study in Milan, Italy. J. Med. Virol. 2021;93(2):1175&#x2013;1179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32841387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L., Dyer A.H., Jones K., Dunne J., Mooney A., Gaffney F., O'Connor L., Leavy D., O'Brien K., Dowds J., Sugrue J.A., Hopkins D., Martin-Loeches I., Ni Cheallaigh C., Nadarajan P., McLaughlin A.M., Bourke N.M., Bergin C., O'Farrelly C., Bannan C., Conlon N., Madeddu G. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One. 2020;15(11):e0240784. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0240784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L., Moloney D., Finucane C., McCarthy K., Bergin C., Bannan C., Kenny R.A. Fatigue following COVID-19 infection is not associated with autonomic dysfunction. PLoS One. 2021;16(2):e0247280. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0247280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0247280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7906457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33630906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B., Peters J.B., Brink M., Schoon Y., Bleeker-Rovers C.P., Schers H., van Hees H.W.H., van Helvoort H., van den Boogaard M., van der Hoeven H., Reijers M.H., Prokop M., Vercoulen J., van den Heuvel M. Comprehensive health assessment three months after recovery from acute COVID-19. Clin. Infect. Dis. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venturelli S., Benatti S.V., Casati M., Binda F., Zuglian G., Imeri G., Conti C., Biffi A.M., Spada M.S., Bondi E., Camera G., Severgnini R., Giammarresi A., Marinaro C., Rossini A., Bonaffini P.A., Guerra G., Bellasi A., Cesa S., Rizzi M. Surviving COVID-19 in Bergamo province: a post-acute outpatient re-evaluation. Epidemiol. Infect. 2021;149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vindegaard N., Benros M.E. COVID-19 pandemic and mental health consequences: systematic review of the current evidence. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;89:531&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7260522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32485289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C., Pan R., Wan X., Tan Y., Xu L., McIntyre R.S., Choo F.N., Tran B., Ho R., Sharma V.K., Ho C. A longitudinal study on the mental health of general population during the COVID-19 epidemic in China. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;87:40&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7153528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P.R., Oyem P.C., Viguera A.C. Prevalence of psychiatric morbidity following discharge after COVID-19 hospitalization. Gen. Hosp. Psychiatry. 2020;69:131&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33494979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Chen L., Wu T., Shi H., Li Q., Jiang H., Zheng D., Wang X., Wei Y., Zhao Y., Qiao J. Impact of Covid-19 in pregnancy on mother's psychological status and infant's neurobehavioral development: a longitudinal cohort study in China. BMC Med. 2020;18:347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7609382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33143711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waters D.L., Vlietstra L., Qualls C., Morley J.E., Vellas B. Sex-specific muscle and metabolic biomarkers associated with gait speed and cognitive transitions in older adults: a 9-year follow-up. Geroscience. 2020;42(2):585&#x2013;593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7205909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32002783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weerahandi H., Hochman K., Simon E., Blaum C., Chodoch J., Duan E., Garry K., Kahan T., Karmen-Tuohy S., Karpel H., et al. Post-Discharge Health Status and Symptoms in Patients with Severe COVID-19. J. Gen. Internal Med. 2021;36:738&#x2013;745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33443703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteside D.M., Oleynick V., Holker E., Waldron E.J., Porter J., Kasprzak M. Neurocognitive deficits in severe COVID-19 infection: case series and proposed model. Clin. Neuropsychol. 2021;35(4):799&#x2013;818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33487098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong A.W., Shah A.S., Johnston J.C., Carlsten C., Ryerson C.J. Patient-reported outcome measures after COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Eur. Respir. J. 2020;56(5):2003276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7530908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33008936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, T.L., Weitzer, D.J., 2021. Long COVID and Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS)-A Systemic Review and Comparison of Clinical Presentation and Symptomatology. Medicina (Kaunas) 57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8145228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33925784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu D., Yang X.O. TH17 responses in cytokine storm of COVID-19: an emerging target of JAK2 inhibitor Fedratinib. J. Microbiol. Immunol. Infect. 2020;53(3):368&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32205092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J., Chen X., Yao S., Liu R. Anxiety persists after recovery from acquired COVID-19 in anaesthesiologists. J. Clin. Anesth. 2020;67:109984. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinane.2020.109984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinane.2020.109984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7340014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32659378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Q., Xu M., Li J., Liu Y., Zhang J., Xu Y., Dong W. Clinical sequelae of COVID-19 survivors in Wuhan, China: a single-centre longitudinal study. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. 2021;27(1):89&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7510771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32979574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin D., Margalit I., Yahav D., Runold M., Bruchfeld J. Long COVID-19-it's not over until? Clin. Microbiol. Infect. 2020;27(4):506&#x2013;508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33316400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young J.J., Bruno D., Pomara N. A review of the relationship between proinflammatory cytokines and major depressive disorder. J. Affect Disord. 2014;169:15&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25128861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan B., Li W., Liu H., Cai X., Song S., Zhao J., Hu X., Li Z., Chen Y., Zhang K., Liu Z., Peng J., Wang C., Wang J., An Y. Correlation between immune response and self-reported depression during convalescence from COVID-19. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;88:39&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7247486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32464158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H., Lu S., Chen J., Wei N., Wang D., Lyu H., Shi C., Hu S. The landscape of cognitive function in recovered COVID-19 patients. J. Psychiatr. Res. 2020;129:98&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7324344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32912598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>