<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35465246</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-3546</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Brain, behavior, &amp; immunity - health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Brain Behav Immun Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Circadian rhythm disruption in Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: Implications for the post-acute sequelae of COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100412</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100412</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100412</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bbih.2022.100412</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS) is a common and disabling disorder primarily characterized by persistent fatigue and exercise intolerance, with associated sleep disturbances, autonomic dysfunction, and cognitive problems. The causes of ME/CFS are not well understood but may coincide with immune and inflammatory responses following viral infections. During the current SARS-CoV2 coronavirus pandemic, ME/CFS has been increasingly reported to overlap with persistent "long COVID" symptoms, also called the post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC). Given the prominence of activity and sleep problems in ME/CFS, circadian rhythm disruption has been examined as a contributing factor in ME/CFS. While these studies of circadian rhythms have been pursued for decades, evidence linking circadian rhythms to ME/CFS remains inconclusive. A major limitation of older chronobiology studies of ME/CFS was the unavailability of modern molecular methods to study circadian rhythms and incomplete understanding of circadian rhythms outside the brain in peripheral organ systems. Major methodological and conceptual advancements in chronobiology have since been made. Over the same time, biomarker research in ME/CFS has progressed. Together, these new developments may justify renewed interest in circadian rhythm research in ME/CFS. Presently, we review ME/CFS from the perspective of circadian rhythms, covering both older and newer studies that make use of modern molecular methods. We focus on transforming growth factor beta (TGFB), a cytokine that has been previously associated with ME/CFS and has an important role in circadian rhythms, especially in peripheral cells. We propose that disrupted TGFB signaling in ME/CFS may play a role in disrupting physiological rhythms in sleep, activity, and cognition, leading to the insomnia, energy disturbances, cognition problems, depression, and autonomic dysfunction associated with ME/CFS. Since SARS-like coronavirus infections cause persistent changes in TGFB and previous coronavirus outbreaks have caused ME/CFS-like syndromes, chronobiological considerations may have immediate implications for understanding ME/CFS in the context of the COVID-19 pandemic and possibly suggest new avenues for therapeutic interventions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCarthy</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UC San Diego Department of Psychiatry and Center for Circadian Biology, 9500 Gilman Dr, La Jolla CA 92093, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VA San Diego Medical Center, San Diego CA, 3350 La Jolla Village Dr MC 116A, San Diego CA, 92161, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Brain Behav Immun Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101759062</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-3546</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic fatigue syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Circadian rhythm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myalgic encephalomyelitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Temperature</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transforming growth factor beta</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author has no conflicts of interest to report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35465246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9019698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbih.2022.100412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-3546(22)00002-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adamovich Y., Ladeuix B., Sobel J., Manella G., Neufeld-Cohen A., Assadi M.H., Golik M., Kuperman Y., Tarasiuk A., Koeners M.P., et al. Oxygen and carbon dioxide rhythms are circadian clock controlled and differentially directed by behavioral signals. Cell Metabol. 2019;29(5):1092&#x2013;1103 e1093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30773466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afari N., Buchwald D. Chronic fatigue syndrome: a review. Am. J. Psychiatr. 2003;160(2):221&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12562565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agorastos A., Hauger R.L., Barkauskas D.A., Moeller-Bertram T., Clopton P.L., Haji U., Lohr J.B., Geracioti T.D., Jr., Patel P.M., Chrousos G.P., et al. Circadian rhythmicity, variability and correlation of interleukin-6 levels in plasma and cerebrospinal fluid of healthy men. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2014;44:71&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24767621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akashi M., Soma H., Yamamoto T., Tsugitomi A., Yamashita S., Nishida E., Yasuda A., Liao J.K., Node K. Noninvasive method for assessing the human circadian clock using hair follicle cells. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2010;107(35):15643&#x2013;15648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2932591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20798039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan N.A. The road to addressing Long Covid. Science. 2021;373(6554):491&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34326224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antle M.C., Silver R. Circadian insights into motivated behavior. Curr. Top. Behav. Neurosci. 2016;27:137&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26419240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assaf G., Davis H., McCorkell L., Wei H., O'Neil B., Akrami A., Low R., Mercier J., Adetutu A. 2020. An analysis of the prolonged COVID-19 symptoms survey by patient-led research team; pp. 1&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D., Khunti K., Nafilyan V., Maddox T., Humberstone B., Diamond I., Banerjee A. Post-covid syndrome in individuals admitted to hospital with covid-19: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;372:n693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8010267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakaloudi D.R., Chourdakis M. A&#xa0;critical update on the role of mild and serious vitamin D deficiency prevalence and the COVID-19 epidemic in Europe. Nutrition. 2022;93:111441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8321689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34492624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedict C., Dimitrov S., Marshall L., Born J. Sleep enhances serum interleukin-7 concentrations in humans. Brain Behav. Immun. 2007;21(8):1058&#x2013;1062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17524612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beynon A.L., Thome J., Coogan A.N. Age and time of day influences on the expression of transforming growth factor-beta and phosphorylated SMAD3 in the mouse suprachiasmatic and paraventricular nuclei. Neuroimmunomodulation. 2009;16(6):392&#x2013;399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19609088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyond myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: redefining an illness. Mil. Med. 2015;180(7):721&#x2013;723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26126237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blundell S., Ray K.K., Buckland M., White P.D. Chronic fatigue syndrome and circulating cytokines: a systematic review. Brain Behav. Immun. 2015;50:186&#x2013;195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26148446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonsall D.R., Harrington M.E. Circadian rhythm disruption in chronic fatigue syndrome. Adv. Neuroimmune Biol. 2013;4(4):265&#x2013;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bou-Holaigah I., Rowe P.C., Kan J., Calkins H. The relationship between neurally mediated hypotension and the chronic fatigue syndrome. JAMA. 1995;274(12):961&#x2013;967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7674527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwer-Brolsma E.M., Vaes A.M.M., van der Zwaluw N.L., van Wijngaarden J.P., Swart K.M.A., Ham A.C., van Dijk S.C., Enneman A.W., Sohl E., van Schoor N.M., et al. Relative importance of summer sun exposure, vitamin D intake, and genes to vitamin D status in Dutch older adults: the B-PROOF study. J.&#xa0;Steroid Biochem. Mol. Biol. 2016;164:168&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26275945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchwald D., Herrell R., Ashton S., Belcourt M., Schmaling K., Sullivan P., Neale M., Goldberg J. A&#xa0;twin study of chronic fatigue. Psychosom. Med. 2001;63(6):936&#x2013;943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11719632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgueno A., Gemma C., Gianotti T.F., Sookoian S., Pirola C.J. Increased levels of resistin in rotating shift workers: a potential mediator of cardiovascular risk associated with circadian misalignment. Atherosclerosis. 2010;210(2):625&#x2013;629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20106477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T.M., Scheer F., Ronda J.M., Czeisler C.A., Wright K.P., Jr. Sleep inertia, sleep homeostatic and circadian influences on higher-order cognitive functions. J.&#xa0;Sleep Res. 2015;24(4):364&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5124508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25773686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cambras T., Castro-Marrero J., Zaragoza M.C., Diez-Noguera A., Alegre J. Circadian rhythm abnormalities and autonomic dysfunction in patients with Chronic Fatigue Syndrome/Myalgic Encephalomyelitis. PLoS One. 2018;13(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5991397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29874259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi J.H., Lee B., Lee J.Y., Kim C.H., Park B., Kim D.Y., Kim H.J., Park D.Y. Relationship between sleep duration, sun exposure, and serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D status: a cross-sectional study. Sci. Rep. 2020;10(1):4168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7060268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32144371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark L.V., Buckland M., Murphy G., Taylor N., Vleck V., Mein C., Wozniak E., Smuk M., White P.D. Cytokine responses to exercise and activity in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome: case-control study. Clin. Exp. Immunol. 2017;190(3):360&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5680051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28779554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clayton E.W. Beyond myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: an IOM report on redefining an illness. JAMA. 2015;313(11):1101&#x2013;1102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25668027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cockshell S.J., Mathias J.L. Cognitive functioning in chronic fatigue syndrome: a meta-analysis. Psychol. Med. 2010;40(8):1253&#x2013;1267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20047703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danielson S.J., Rappaport C.A., Loher M.K., Gehlbach B.K. Looking for light in the din: an examination of the circadian-disrupting properties of a medical intensive care unit. Intensive Crit. Care Nurs. 2018;46:57&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6004325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29605239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson S., Villarroel M., Harford M., Finnegan E., Jorge J., Young D., Watkinson P., Tarassenko L. Day-to-day progression of vital-sign circadian rhythms in the intensive care unit. Crit. Care. 2021;25(1):156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8063456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33888129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demitrack M.A., Dale J.K., Straus S.E., Laue L., Listwak S.J., Kruesi M.J., Chrousos G.P., Gold P.W. Evidence for impaired activation of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. J.&#xa0;Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 1991;73(6):1224&#x2013;1234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1659582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira-Gomes M., Kruglov A., Durek P., Heinrich F., Tizian C., Heinz G.A., Pascual-Reguant A., Du W., Mothes R., Fan C., et al. SARS-CoV-2 in severe COVID-19 induces a TGF-beta-dominated chronic immune response that does not target itself. Nat. Commun. 2021;12(1):1961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8010106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finger A.M., Jaschke S., Del Olmo M., Hurwitz R., Granada A.E., Herzel H., Kramer A. Intercellular coupling between peripheral circadian oscillators by TGF-beta signaling. Sci. Adv. 2021;7(30)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8302137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34301601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gast H., Gordic S., Petrzilka S., Lopez M., Muller A., Gietl A., Hock C., Birchler T., Fontana A. Transforming growth factor-beta inhibits the expression of clock genes. Ann. N. Y. Acad. Sci. 2012;1261:79&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22823397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Giorgio A., Hudson M., Jerjes W., Cleare A.J. 24-hour pituitary and adrenal hormone profiles in chronic fatigue syndrome. Psychosom. Med. 2005;67(3):433&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15911907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamidi S.H., Kadamboor Veethil S. Role of pirfenidone in TGF-beta pathways and other inflammatory pathways in acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-Cov-2) infection: a theoretical perspective. Pharmacol. Rep. 2021;73:712&#x2013;727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8057922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33880743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilos D.L., Nutter D., Gershtenson J., Ikle D., Hamilos S.S., Redmond D.P., Di Clementi J.D., Schmaling K.B., Jones J.F. Circadian rhythm of core body temperature in subjects with chronic fatigue syndrome. Clin. Physiol. 2001;21(2):184&#x2013;195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11318826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han A.J., Alexander L.C., Jr., Huebner J.L., Reed A.B., Kraus V.B. Increase in free and total plasma TGF-beta1 following physical activity. Cartilage. 2020 1947603520916523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8808803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32340467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Heukelom R.O., Prins J.B., Smits M.G., Bleijenberg G. Influence of melatonin on fatigue severity in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome and late melatonin secretion. Eur. J. Neurol. 2006;13(1):55&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16420393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickie I., Davenport T., Wakefield D., Vollmer-Conna U., Cameron B., Vernon S.D., Reeves W.C., Lloyd A. Post-infective and chronic fatigue syndromes precipitated by viral and non-viral pathogens: prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2006;333(7568):575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1569956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16950834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornig M., Montoya J.G., Klimas N.G., Levine S., Felsenstein D., Bateman L., Peterson D.L., Gottschalk C.G., Schultz A.F., Che X., et al. Distinct plasma immune signatures in ME/CFS are present early in the course of illness. Sci. Adv. 2015;1(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26079000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang T., Schor S.L., Hinck A.P. Biological activity differences between TGF-beta1 and TGF-beta3 correlate with differences in the rigidity and arrangement of their component monomers. Biochemistry. 2014;53(36):5737&#x2013;5749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4165442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25153513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamaluddin M.S., Weakley S.M., Yao Q., Chen C. Resistin: functional roles and therapeutic considerations for cardiovascular disease. Br. J. Pharmacol. 2012;165(3):622&#x2013;632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3315035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21545576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason L.A., Cotler J., Islam M.F., Sunnquist M., Katz B.Z. Risks for developing myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome in college students following infectious mononucleosis: a prospective cohort study. Clin. Infect. Dis. 2021;73(11):e3740&#x2013;e3746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8664491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33367564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsjo M.A., Olsson G.L., Wicksell R.K., Alving K., Holmstrom L., Andreasson A. The role of low-grade inflammation in ME/CFS (Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome) - associations with symptoms. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2020;113:104578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31901625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz B.Z., Shiraishi Y., Mears C.J., Binns H.J., Taylor R. Chronic fatigue syndrome after infectious mononucleosis in adolescents. Pediatrics. 2009;124(1):189&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2756827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19564299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff A.L., Bateman L. Will COVID-19 lead to myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome? Front. Med. 2020;7:606824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7848220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33537329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon N., Hirota T., Kawamoto T., Kato Y., Tsubota T., Fukada Y. Activation of TGF-beta/activin signalling resets the circadian clock through rapid induction of Dec1 transcripts. Nat. Cell Biol. 2008;10(12):1463&#x2013;1469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19029909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong S.Y., Stabler T.V., Criscione L.G., Elliott A.L., Jordan J.M., Kraus V.B. Diurnal variation of serum and urine biomarkers in patients with radiographic knee osteoarthritis. Arthritis Rheum. 2006;54(8):2496&#x2013;2504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16868970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam M.H., Wing Y.K., Yu M.W., Leung C.M., Ma R.C., Kong A.P., So W.Y., Fong S.Y., Lam S.P. Mental morbidities and chronic fatigue in severe acute respiratory syndrome survivors: long-term follow-up. Arch. Intern. Med. 2009;169(22):2142&#x2013;2147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20008700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landgraf D., Long J.E., Proulx C.D., Barandas R., Malinow R., Welsh D.K. Genetic disruption of circadian rhythms in the suprachiasmatic nucleus causes helplessness, behavioral despair, and anxiety-like behavior in mice. Biol. Psychiatr. 2016;80(11):827&#x2013;835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5102810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27113500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larun L., Brurberg K.G., Odgaard-Jensen J., Price J.R. Exercise therapy for chronic fatigue syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2016;2:CD003200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26852189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larun L., Brurberg K.G., Odgaard-Jensen J., Price J.R. Exercise therapy for chronic fatigue syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2019;10:CD003200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6953363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31577366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrie S.M., MacHale S.M., Cavanagh J.T., O'Carroll R.E., Goodwin G.M. The difference in patterns of motor and cognitive function in chronic fatigue syndrome and severe depressive illness. Psychol. Med. 2000;30(2):433&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10824663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee W.K., Kim Y., Jang H., Sim J.H., Choi H.J., Shin Y., Choi J.J. Exogenous transforming growth factor-beta in brain-induced symptoms of central fatigue and suppressed dopamine production in mice. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2021;22(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7961432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33806649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Sankrithi N., Davis F.C. Transforming growth factor-alpha is expressed in astrocytes of the suprachiasmatic nucleus in hamster: role of glial cells in circadian clocks. Neuroreport. 2002;13(16):2143&#x2013;2147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12438943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J.Z., Bunney B.G., Meng F., Hagenauer M.H., Walsh D.M., Vawter M.P., Evans S.J., Choudary P.V., Cartagena P., Barchas J.D., et al. Circadian patterns of gene expression in the human brain and disruption in major depressive disorder. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2013;110(24):9950&#x2013;9955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3683716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23671070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindley J., Deurveilher S., Rusak B., Semba K. Transforming growth factor-alpha and glial fibrillary acidic protein in the hamster circadian system: daily profile and cellular localization. Brain Res. 2008;1197:94&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18242590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo V.D., Panda S. Fasting, circadian rhythms, and time-restricted feeding in healthy lifespan. Cell Metabol. 2016;23(6):1048&#x2013;1059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5388543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27304506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Luit L., van der Meulen J., Cleophas T.J., Zwinderman A.H. Amplified amplitudes of circadian rhythms and nighttime hypotension in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome: improvement by inopamil but not by melatonin. Angiology. 1998;49(11):903&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9822046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacHale S.M., Cavanagh J.T., Bennie J., Carroll S., Goodwin G.M., Lawrie S.M. Diurnal variation of adrenocortical activity in chronic fatigue syndrome. Neuropsychobiology. 1998;38(4):213&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9813459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maidstone R., Anderson S.G., Ray D.W., Rutter M.K., Durrington H.J., Blaikley J.F. Shift work is associated with positive COVID-19 status in hospitalised patients. Thorax. 2021;76(6):601&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8098298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33903187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manella G., Aviram R., Bolshette N., Muvkadi S., Golik M., Smith D.F., Asher G. Hypoxia induces a time- and tissue-specific response that elicits intertissue circadian clock misalignment. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2020;117(1):779&#x2013;786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6955294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31848250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy M.J., Welsh D.K. Cellular circadian clocks in mood disorders. J.&#xa0;Biol. Rhythm. 2012;27(5):339&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23010657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milrad S.F., Hall D.L., Jutagir D.R., Lattie E.G., Ironson G.H., Wohlgemuth W., Nunez M.V., Garcia L., Czaja S.J., Perdomo D.M., et al. Poor sleep quality is associated with greater circulating pro-inflammatory cytokines and severity and frequency of chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME) symptoms in women. J.&#xa0;Neuroimmunol. 2017;303:43&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5258835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28038892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzaei H., Faghihloo E. Viruses as key modulators of the TGF-beta pathway; a double-edged sword involved in cancer. Rev. Med. Virol. 2018;28(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7169117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29345394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohawk J.A., Green C.B., Takahashi J.S. Central and peripheral circadian clocks in mammals. Annu. Rev. Neurosci. 2012;35:445&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3710582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22483041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moldofsky H., Patcai J. Chronic widespread musculoskeletal pain, fatigue, depression and disordered sleep in chronic post-SARS syndrome; a case-controlled study. BMC Neurol. 2011;11:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3071317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21435231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montoya J.G., Holmes T.H., Anderson J.N., Maecker H.T., Rosenberg-Hasson Y., Valencia I.J., Chu L., Younger J.W., Tato C.M., Davis M.M. Cytokine signature associated with disease severity in chronic fatigue syndrome patients. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2017;114(34):E7150&#x2013;E7158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5576836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28760971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon J.H., Cho C.H., Son G.H., Geum D., Chung S., Kim H., Kang S.G., Park Y.M., Yoon H.K., Kim L., et al. Advanced circadian phase in mania and delayed circadian phase in mixed mania and depression returned to normal after treatment of bipolar disorder. EBioMedicine. 2016;11:285&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5049992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27543154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris C.J., Purvis T.E., Hu K., Scheer F.A. Circadian misalignment increases cardiovascular disease risk factors in humans. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2016;113(10):E1402&#x2013;E1411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4790999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26858430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray G., Nicholas C.L., Kleiman J., Dwyer R., Carrington M.J., Allen N.B., Trinder J. Nature's clocks and human mood: the circadian system modulates reward motivation. Emotion. 2009;9(5):705&#x2013;716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19803592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A., Sehgal K., Gupta A., Madhavan M.V., McGroder C., Stevens J.S., Cook J.R., Nordvig A.S., Shalev D., Sehrawat T.S., et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat. Med. 2021;27(4):601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narasimamurthy R., Hatori M., Nayak S.K., Liu F., Panda S., Verma I.M. Circadian clock protein cryptochrome regulates the expression of proinflammatory cytokines. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2012;109(31):12662&#x2013;12667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3411996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22778400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oronsky B., Larson C., Hammond T.C., Oronsky A., Kesari S., Lybeck M., Reid T.R. A&#xa0;review of persistent post-COVID syndrome (PPCS) Clin. Rev. Allergy Immunol. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33609255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oscanoa T.J., Amado J., Vidal X., Laird E., Ghashut R.A., Romero-Ortuno R. The relationship between the severity and mortality of SARS-CoV-2 infection and 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration - a metaanalysis. Adv. Respir. Med. 2021;89(2):145&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33966262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyama Y., Iwasaka H., Koga H., Shingu C., Matsumoto S., Noguchi T. Uncoupling of peripheral and master clock gene rhythms by reversed feeding leads to an exacerbated inflammatory response after polymicrobial sepsis in mice. Shock. 2014;41(3):214&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24300828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Partch C.L., Green C.B., Takahashi J.S. Molecular architecture of the mammalian circadian clock. Trends Cell Biol. 2014;24(2):90&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3946763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23916625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pendergast J.S., Yamazaki S. The mysterious food-entrainable oscillator: insights from mutant and engineered mouse models. J.&#xa0;Biol. Rhythm. 2018;33(5):458&#x2013;474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6693510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30033846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman K., Burton A., Galbraith S., Lloyd A., Vollmer-Conna U. Sleep-wake behavior in chronic fatigue syndrome. Sleep. 2011;34(5):671&#x2013;678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3079947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21532961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasa S., Nora-Krukle Z., Henning N., Eliassen E., Shikova E., Harrer T., Scheibenbogen C., Murovska M., Prusty B.K. Chronic viral infections in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) J.&#xa0;Transl. Med. 2018;16(1):268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6167797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30285773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheer F.A., Hilton M.F., Mantzoros C.S., Shea S.A. Adverse metabolic and cardiovascular consequences of circadian misalignment. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2009;106(11):4453&#x2013;4458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2657421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19255424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheiermann C., Gibbs J., Ince L., Loudon A. Clocking in to immunity. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2018;18(7):423&#x2013;437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29662121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A.K., Fang H., Whistler T., Unger E.R., Rajeevan M.S. Convergent genomic studies identify association of GRIK2 and NPAS2 with chronic fatigue syndrome. Neuropsychobiology. 2011;64(4):183&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3701888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21912186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L., Dyer A.H., McCluskey P., O'Brien K., Dowds J., Laird E., Bannan C., Bourke N.M., Ni Cheallaigh C., Byrne D.G., et al. Investigating the relationship between vitamin D and persistent symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nutrients. 2021;13(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8308626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34371940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tryon W.W., Jason L., Frankenberry E., Torres-Harding S. Chronic fatigue syndrome impairs circadian rhythm of activity level. Physiol. Behav. 2004;82(5):849&#x2013;853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15451649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdez P. Circadian rhythms in attention. Yale J. Biol. Med. 2019;92(1):81&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6430172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30923475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsh D.K., Takahashi J.S., Kay S.A. Suprachiasmatic nucleus: cell autonomy and network properties. Annu. Rev. Physiol. 2010;72:551&#x2013;577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3758475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20148688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White P.D., Goldsmith K.A., Johnson A.L., Potts L., Walwyn R., DeCesare J.C., Baber H.L., Burgess M., Clark L.V., Cox D.L., et al. Comparison of adaptive pacing therapy, cognitive behaviour therapy, graded exercise therapy, and specialist medical care for chronic fatigue syndrome (PACE): a randomised trial. Lancet. 2011;377(9768):823&#x2013;836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3065633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21334061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams G., Pirmohamed J., Minors D., Waterhouse J., Buchan I., Arendt J., Edwards R.H. Dissociation of body-temperature and melatonin secretion circadian rhythms in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. Clin. Physiol. 1996;16(4):327&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8842569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams G., Waterhouse J., Mugarza J., Minors D., Hayden K. Therapy of circadian rhythm disorders in chronic fatigue syndrome: no symptomatic improvement with melatonin or phototherapy. Eur. J. Clin. Invest. 2002;32(11):831&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12423324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilshire C.E., Kindlon T., Courtney R., Matthees A., Tuller D., Geraghty K., Levin B. Rethinking the treatment of chronic fatigue syndrome-a reanalysis and evaluation of findings from a recent major trial of graded exercise and CBT. BMC Psychol. 2018;6(1):6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5863477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29562932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood C., Magnello M.E., Sharpe M.C. Fluctuations in perceived energy and mood among patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. J.&#xa0;R. Soc. Med. 1992;85(4):195&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1294721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1290537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyller V.B., Godang K., Morkrid L., Saul J.P., Thaulow E., Walloe L. Abnormal thermoregulatory responses in adolescents with chronic fatigue syndrome: relation to clinical symptoms. Pediatrics. 2007;120(1):e129&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17606539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyller V.B., Nguyen C.B., Ludviksen J.A., Mollnes T.E. Transforming growth factor beta (TGF-beta) in adolescent chronic fatigue syndrome. J.&#xa0;Transl. Med. 2017;15(1):245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5716371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29202780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wynn T.A. Cellular and molecular mechanisms of fibrosis. J.&#xa0;Pathol. 2008;214(2):199&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2693329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18161745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y., Liu Y., Cao L., Wang D., Guo M., Jiang A., Guo D., Hu W., Yang J., Tang Z., et al. Transcriptomic characteristics of bronchoalveolar lavage fluid and peripheral blood mononuclear cells in COVID-19 patients. Emerg. Microb. Infect. 2020;9(1):761&#x2013;770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7170362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32228226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Xu X., Jiang L., Dua K., Hansbro P.M., Liu G. SARS-CoV-2 induces transcriptional signatures in human lung epithelial cells that promote lung fibrosis. Respir. Res. 2020;21(1):182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7359430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32664949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youngstedt S.D., Elliott J.A., Kripke D.F. Human circadian phase-response curves for exercise. J.&#xa0;Physiol. 2019;597(8):2253&#x2013;2268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6462487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30784068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X., Nicholls J.M., Chen Y.G. Severe acute respiratory syndrome-associated coronavirus nucleocapsid protein interacts with Smad3 and modulates transforming growth factor-beta signaling. J.&#xa0;Biol. Chem. 2008;283(6):3272&#x2013;3280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8740907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18055455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>