<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36398720</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2869</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of sleep research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sleep Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The role of sleep and dreams in long-COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e13789</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e13789</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jsr.13789</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recent investigations show that many people affected by SARS-CoV2 (COVID-19) report persistent symptoms 2-3&#xa0;months from the onset of the infection. Here, we report the Italian findings from the second International COVID-19 Sleep Study survey, aiming to investigate sleep and dream alterations in participants with post-acute symptoms, and identify the best determinants of these alterations among patients with long-COVID. Data from 383 participants who have had COVID-19 were collected through a web-survey (May-November 2021). Descriptive analyses were performed to outline the sociodemographic characteristics of long-COVID (N&#xa0;=&#xa0;270, with at least two long-lasting symptoms) and short-COVID (N&#xa0;=&#xa0;113, with none or one long-lasting symptom) participants. They were then compared concerning sleep and dream measures. We performed multiple linear regressions considering as dependent variables sleep and dream parameters discriminating the long-COVID group. Age, gender, work status, financial burden, COVID-19 severity and the level of care were significantly different between long-COVID and short-COVID subjects. The long-COVID group showed greater sleep alterations (sleep quality, daytime sleepiness, sleep inertia, naps, insomnia, sleep apnea, nightmares) compared with the short-COVID group. We also found that the number of long-COVID symptoms, psychological factors and age were the best explanatory variables of sleep and oneiric alterations. Our findings highlight that sleep alterations are part of the clinical presentation of the long-COVID syndrome. Moreover, psychological status and the number of post-acute symptoms should be considered as state-like variables modulating the sleep problems in long-COVID individuals. Finally, according to previous investigations, oneiric alterations are confirmed as a reliable mental health index.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 European Sleep Research Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scarpelli</LastName><ForeName>Serena</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9260-7111</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Santis</LastName><ForeName>Alessandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alfonsi</LastName><ForeName>Valentina</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9929-0399</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gorgoni</LastName><ForeName>Maurizio</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5544-5483</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS Fondazione Santa Lucia, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morin</LastName><ForeName>Charles M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre d'&#xe9;tude des troubles du sommeil, &#xc9;cole de psychologie, Institut universitaire en sant&#xe9; mentale, Centre de recherche CERVO, Universit&#xe9; Laval, Quebec, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Espie</LastName><ForeName>Colin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1294-8734</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sleep and Circadian Neuroscience Institute, Nuffield Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merikanto</LastName><ForeName>Ilona</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1222-6678</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SleepWell Research Program, Faculty of Medicine, University of Helsinki, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health Solutions, Finnish Institute for Health and Welfare, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chung</LastName><ForeName>Frances</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Pain Medicine, University Health Network, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Penzel</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4304-0112</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Sleep Medicine Center, Charit&#xe9;-Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bjorvatn</LastName><ForeName>Bj&#xf8;rn</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7051-745X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Global Public Health and Primary Care, University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Norwegian Competence Center for Sleep Disorders, Haukeland University Hospital, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dauvilliers</LastName><ForeName>Yves</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sleep-Wake Disorders Unit, Department of Neurology, Gui-de-Chauliac Hospital, CHU Montpellier, INM, Univ Montpellier, INSERM, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holzinger</LastName><ForeName>Brigitte</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Consciousness and Dream Research, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical University Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wing</LastName><ForeName>Yun K</ForeName><Initials>YK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5745-5474</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Li Chiu Kong Family Sleep Assessment Unit, Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Partinen</LastName><ForeName>Markku</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8182-9368</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Helsinki Sleep Clinic, Terveystalo Healthcare, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Clinicum, University of Helsinki, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plazzi</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1051-0472</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Neuromotor Sciences (DIBINEM), University of Bologna, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS, Istituto delle Scienze Neurologiche, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Gennaro</LastName><ForeName>Luigi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3613-6631</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS Fondazione Santa Lucia, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Sleep Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9214441</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0962-1105</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nightmares</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oneiric activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep concerns</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36398720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jsr.13789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, H., Patel, K., Greenwood, D. C., Halpin, S., Lewthwaite, P., Salawu, A., &#x2026; Sivan, M. (2020). Long-term clinical outcomes in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS) outbreaks after hospitalisation or ICU admission: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Rehabilitation Medicine, 52(5), 1-11. https://doi.org/10.2340/16501977-2694</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly, Z., Xie, Y., &amp; Bowe, B. (2021). High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature, 594(7862), 259-264. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-021-03553-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfonsi, V., Gorgoni, M., Scarpelli, S., Zivi, P., Sdoia, S., Mari, E., &#x2026; De Gennaro, L. (2021). COVID-19 lockdown and poor sleep quality: Not the whole story. Journal of Sleep Research, 30(5), e13368. https://doi.org/10.1111/jsr.13368</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkodaymi, M. S., Omrani, O. A., Fawzy, N. A., Abou Shaar, B., Almamlouk, R., Riaz, M., &#x2026; Tleyjeh, I. M. (2022). Prevalence of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome symptoms at different follow-up periods: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 28(5), 657-656. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2022.01.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzueta, E., Perrin, P. B., Yuksel, D., Ramos-Usuga, D., Kiss, O., Iacovides, S., &#x2026; Baker, F. C. (2022). An international study of post-COVID sleep health. Sleep Health, S2352-7218(22), 00112-7. https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/3qdah</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold, D. T., Hamilton, F. W., Milne, A., Morley, A. J., Viner, J., Attwood, M., &#x2026; Barratt, S. L. (2021). Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up: Results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax, 76(4), 399-401. https://doi.org/10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216086</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolacci, C., Scarpelli, S., D'Atri, A., Gorgoni, M., Annarumma, L., Cloos, C., &#x2026; De Gennaro, L. (2020). The influence of sleep quality, vigilance, and sleepiness on driving-related cognitive abilities: A comparison between young and older adults. Brain Sciences, 10(6), 327. https://doi.org/10.3390/brainsci10060327</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastien, C. H., Valli&#xe8;res, A., &amp; Morin, C. M. (2001). Validation of the insomnia severity index as an outcome measure for insomnia research. Sleep Medicine, 2(4), 297-307. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1389-9457(00)00065-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boscolo-Rizzo, P., Guida, F., Polesel, J., Marcuzzo, A. V., Capriotti, V., D'Alessandro, A., &#x2026; Tirelli, G. (2021). Long COVID In adults at 12 months after mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. MedRxiv. https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.04.12.21255343</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cellini, N., Canale, N., Mioni, G., &amp; Costa, S. (2020). Changes in sleep pattern, sense of time and digital media use during COVID-19 lockdown in Italy. Journal of Sleep Research, 29(4), e13074. https://doi.org/10.1111/jsr.13074</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung, F., Yegneswaran, B., Liao, P., Chung, S. A., Vairavanathan, S., Islam, S., &#x2026; Shapiro, C. M. (2008). STOP questionnaire: A tool to screen patients for obstructive sleep apnea. The Journal of the American Society of Anesthesiologists, 108(5), 812-821. https://doi.org/10.1097/ALN.0b013e31816d83e4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conley, S., Knies, A., Batten, J., Ash, G., Miner, B., Hwang, Y., &#x2026; Redeker, N. S. (2019). Agreement between actigraphic and polysomnographic measures of sleep in adults with and without chronic conditions: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Medicine Reviews, 46, 151-160. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.smrv.2019.05.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty, S. E., Guo, Y., Heath, K., Dasmari&#xf1;as, M. C., Jubilo, K. G., Samranvedhya, J., &#x2026; Cohen, K. (2021). Risk of clinical sequelae after the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection: Retrospective cohort study. BMJ, 373, n1098. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n1098</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, H. E., Assaf, G. S., McCorkell, L., Wei, H., Low, R. J., Re'em, Y., &#x2026; Akrami, A. (2021). Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine, 38, 101019. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elo, A. L., Lepp&#xe4;nen, A., &amp; Jahkola, A. (2003). Validity of a single-item measure of stress symptoms. Scandinavian Journal of Work, Environment &amp; Health, 29, 444-451. http://www.jstor.org/stable/40967322</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher, K. A., Olson, S. M., Tenforde, M. W., Self, W. H., Wu, M., Lindsell, C. J., &#x2026; Marcet, P. L. (2021). Symptoms and recovery among adult outpatients with and without COVID-19 at 11 healthcare facilities-July 2020, United States. Influenza and Other Respiratory Viruses, 15(3), 345-351. https://doi.org/10.1111/irv.12832</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franceschini, C., Musetti, A., Zenesini, C., Palagini, L., Scarpelli, S., Quattropani, M. C., &#x2026; Castelnuovo, G. (2020). Poor sleep quality and its consequences on mental health during the COVID-19 lockdown in Italy. Frontiers in Psychology, Poor sleep quality and its consequences on mental health during the COVID-19 lockdown in Italy, 11, 574475.https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2020.574475</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xe4;nkl, E., Scarpelli, S., Neudorf, M. R., Bjorvatn, B., Bolstad, C. J., Chan, N. Y., &#x2026; Holzinger, B. (2021). How our dreams changed during the COVID-19 pandemic: Effects and correlates of dream recall frequency-a multinational study on 19,355 adults. Nature and Science of Sleep, 13, 1573-1591. https://doi.org/10.2147/NSS.S324142</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamaldo, C. E., Shaikh, A. K., &amp; McArthur, J. C. (2012). The sleep-immunity relationship. Neurologic Clinics, 30(4), 1313-1343. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ncl.2012.08.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorgoni, M., Scarpelli, S., Mangiaruga, A., Alfonsi, V., Bonsignore, M. R., Fanfulla, F., &#x2026; Vicini, C. (2021). Pre-sleep arousal and sleep quality during the COVID-19 lockdown in Italy. Sleep Medicine, 88, 46-57. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sleep.2021.10.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C., Huang, L., Wang, Y., Li, X., Ren, L., Gu, X., &#x2026; Cao, B. (2021). 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: A cohort study. The Lancet, 397(10270), 220-232. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahrami, H., BaHammam, A. S., Bragazzi, N. L., Saif, Z., Faris, M., &amp; Vitiello, M. V. (2021). Sleep problems during the COVID-19 pandemic by population: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Clinical Sleep Medicine, 17(2), 299-313. https://doi.org/10.5664/jcsm.8930</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janiri, D., Kotzalidis, G. D., &amp; Sani, G. (2021). Improving the assessment of COVID-19-associated posttraumatic stress disorder-Reply. JAMA Psychiatry, 78(7), 795-796. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2021.1126</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalmbach, D. A., Anderson, J. R., &amp; Drake, C. L. (2018). The impact of stress on sleep: Pathogenic sleep reactivity as a vulnerability to insomnia and circadian disorders. Journal of Sleep Research, 27(6), e12710. https://doi.org/10.1111/jsr.12710</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy, K. E., Bastien, C. H., Ruby, P. M., Killgore, W. D., Wills, C. C., &amp; Grandner, M. A. (2022). Nightmare content during the COVID-19 pandemic: Influence of COVID-related stress and sleep disruption in the United States. Journal of Sleep Research, 31(1), e13439. https://doi.org/10.1111/jsr.13439</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan, K., Miller, A. K., Reiter, K., &amp; Bonner-Jackson, A. (2022). Neurocognitive profiles in patients with persisting cognitive symptoms associated with COVID-19. Archives of Clinical Neuropsychology, 37(4), 729-737. https://doi.org/10.1093/arclin/acac004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke, K., Spitzer, R. L., Williams, J. B., &amp; L&#xf6;we, B. (2009). An ultra-brief screening scale for anxiety and depression: The PHQ-4. Psychosomatics, 50(6), 613-621. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0033-3182(09)70864-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam, M. H. B., Wing, Y. K., Yu, M. W. M., Leung, C. M., Ma, R. C., Kong, A. P., &#x2026; Lam, S. P. (2009). Mental morbidities and chronic fatigue in severe acute respiratory syndrome survivors: Long-term follow-up. Archives of Internal Medicine, 169(22), 2142-2147. https://doi.org/10.1001/archinternmed.2009.384</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon, S., Wegman-Ostrosky, T., Perelman, C., Sepulveda, R., Rebolledo, P. A., Cuapio, A., &amp; Villapol, S. (2021). More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Scientific Reports, 11(1), 1-12. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memtsoudis, S. G., Ivascu, N. S., Pryor, K. O., &amp; Goldstein, P. A. (2020). Obesity as a risk factor for poor outcome in COVID-19-induced lung injury: The potential role of undiagnosed obstructive sleep apnoea. British Journal of Anaesthesia, 125(2), e262-e263. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2020.04.078</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merikanto, I., Dauvilliers, Y., Chung, F., Holzinger, B., De Gennaro, L., Wing, Y. K., &#x2026; Lyamova, V. K. (2021). Disturbances in sleep, circadian rhythms and daytime functioning in relation to coronavirus infection and long-COVID-A multinational ICOSS study. Journal of Sleep Research, 31(4), e13542. https://doi.org/10.1111/jsr.13542</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merikanto, I., Dauvilliers, Y., Chung, F., Wing, Y. K., De Gennaro, L., Holzinger, B., &#x2026; Partinen, M. (2022). Sleep symptoms are essential features of long-COVID-comparing healthy controls with COVID-19 cases of different severity in the international COVID sleep study (ICOSS-II). Journal of Sleep Research, e13754. https://doi.org/10.1111/jsr.13754</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merikanto, I., Kortesoja, L., Benedict, C., Chung, F., Cedernaes, J., Espie, C. A., &#x2026; Bjorvatn, B. (2022). Evening-types show highest increase of sleep and mental health problems during the COVID-19 pandemic-Multinational study on 19 267 adults. Sleep, 45(2), zsab216. https://doi.org/10.1093/sleep/zsab216</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen, M., Manoharan, L., Elkheir, N., Cheng, V., Dagens, A., Hastie, C., &#x2026; Stavropoulou, C. (2021). Characterising long COVID: A living systematic review. BMJ Global Health, 6(9), e005427. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgh-2021-005427</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montaruli, A., Castelli, L., Mul&#xe8;, A., Scurati, R., Esposito, F., Galasso, L., &amp; Roveda, E. (2021). Biological rhythm and chronotype: New perspectives in health. Biomolecules, 11(4), 487. https://doi.org/10.3390/biom11040487</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin, C. M., Bjorvatn, B., Chung, F., Holzinger, B., Partinen, M., Penzel, T., &#x2026; Espie, C. A. (2021). Insomnia, anxiety, and depression during the COVID-19 pandemic: An international collaborative study. Sleep Medicine, 87, 38-45. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sleep.2021.07.035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr&#xf9;, G., Bertelloni, D., Diolaiuti, F., Mucci, F., Di Giuseppe, M., Biella, M., &#x2026; Conversano, C. (2021). Long-COVID syndrome? A study on the persistence of neurological, psychological and physiological symptoms. Healthcare, 9(5), 575. https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare9050575</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Partinen, M., &amp; Gislason, T. (1995). Basic Nordic sleep questionnaire (BNSQ): A quantitated measure of subjective sleep complaints. Journal of Sleep Research, 4, 150-155. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2869.1995.tb00205.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen, M. S., Kristiansen, M. F., Hanusson, K. D., Danielsen, M. E., &#xe1; Steig, B., Gaini, S., &#x2026; Weihe, P. (2021). Long COVID in The Faroe Islands: A longitudinal study among nonhospitalized patients. Clinical Infectious Diseases, 73(11), e4058-e4063. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciaa1792</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salfi, F., Lauriola, M., D'Atri, A., Amicucci, G., Viselli, L., Tempesta, D., &amp; Ferrara, M. (2021). Demographic, psychological, chronobiological, and work-related predictors of sleep disturbances during the COVID-19 lockdown in Italy. Scientific Reports, 11(1), 1-12. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-90993-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli, S., Alfonsi, V., Gorgoni, M., &amp; De Gennaro, L. (2022). What about dreams? State of the art and open questions. Journal of Sleep Research, 31, e13609. https://doi.org/10.1111/jsr.13609</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli, S., Alfonsi, V., Mangiaruga, A., Musetti, A., Quattropani, M. C., Lenzo, V., &#x2026; Franceschini, C. (2021). Pandemic nightmares: Effects on dream activity of the COVID-19 lockdown in Italy. Journal of Sleep Research, 30(5), e13300. https://doi.org/10.1111/jsr.13300</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli, S., Bartolacci, C., D'Atri, A., Gorgoni, M., &amp; De Gennaro, L. (2019). Mental sleep activity and disturbing dreams in the lifespan. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 16(19), 3658. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph16193658</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli, S., Nadorff, M. R., Bjorvatn, B., Chung, F., Dauvilliers, Y., Espie, C. A., &#x2026; De Gennaro, L. (2022). Nightmares in people with COVID-19: Did coronavirus infect our dreams? Nature and Science of Sleep, 14, 93-108. https://doi.org/10.2147/NSS.S344299</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli, S., Zagaria, A., Ratti, P. L., Albano, A., Fazio, V., Musetti, A., &#x2026; Franceschini, C. (2022). Subjective sleep alterations in healthy subjects worldwide during COVID-19 pandemic: A systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression. Sleep Medicine, 100, 89-102. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sleep.2022.07.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senaratna, C. V., Perret, J. L., Lodge, C. J., Lowe, A. J., Campbell, B. E., Matheson, M. C., &#x2026; Dharmage, S. C. (2017). Prevalence of obstructive sleep apnea in the general population: A systematic review. Sleep Medicine Reviews, 34, 70-81. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.smrv.2016.07.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spielman, A. J., Caruso, L. S., &amp; Glovinsky, P. B. (1987). A behavioral perspective on insomnia treatment. Psychiatric Clinics of North America, 10(4), 541-553. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0193-953X(18)30532-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulrich-Lai, Y. M., &amp; Herman, J. P. (2009). Neural regulation of endocrine and autonomic stress responses. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 10(6), 397-409. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn2647</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vgontzas, A. N., &amp; Chrousos, G. P. (2002). Sleep, the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis, and cytokines: Multiple interactions and disturbances in sleep disorders. Endocrinology and Metabolism Clinics, 31(1), 15-36. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0889-8529(01)00005-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh, K. A., Spillane, S., Comber, L., Cardwell, K., Harrington, P., Connell, J., &#x2026; O'Neill, M. (2020). The duration of infectiousness of individuals infected with SARS-CoV-2. Journal of Infection, 81(6), 847-856. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2020.10.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, WHO. (2021). A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Retrieved from WHO/2019-nCoV/Post_COVID19_condition/Clinical_case_definition/2021.1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, H., Zhang, Y., Kong, D., Li, S., &amp; Yang, N. (2020). Social capital and sleep quality in individuals who self-isolated for 14&#x2009;days during the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) outbreak in January 2020 in China. Medical Science Monitor: International Medical Journal of Experimental and Clinical Research, 26, e923921. https://doi.org/10.12659/MSM.923921</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong, Q., Xu, M., Li, J., Liu, Y., Zhang, J., Xu, Y., &amp; Dong, W. (2021). Clinical sequelae of COVID-19 survivors in Wuhan, China: A single-Centre longitudinal study. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 27(1), 89-95. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2020.09.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J., Zheng, Y., Gou, X., Pu, K., Chen, Z., Guo, Q., &#x2026; Zhou, Y. (2020). Prevalence of comorbidities in the novel Wuhan coronavirus (COVID-19) infection: A systematic review and meta-analysis. International Journal of Infectious Diseases, 94(1), 91-95. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2020.03.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaim, S., Chong, J. H., Sankaranarayanan, V., &amp; Harky, A. (2020). COVID-19 and multiorgan response. Current Problems in Cardiology, 45(8), 100618. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpcardiol.2020.100618</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, B., &amp; Wing, Y. K. (2006). Sex differences in insomnia: A meta-analysis. Sleep, 29(1), 85-93. https://doi.org/10.1093/sleep/29.1.85</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>