<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36588333</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1875-5739</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current neurovascular research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Neurovasc Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Apolipoprotein-&#x3b5;4 allele (APOE-&#x3b5;4) as a Mediator of Cognitive Loss and Dementia in Long COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>435</StartPage><EndPage>439</EndPage><MedlinePgn>435-439</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2174/156720261905221227114624</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maiese</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cellular and Molecular Signaling, New York, NY USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United Arab Emirates</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Neurovasc Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101208439</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1567-2026</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36588333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/156720261905221227114624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">CNR-EPUB-128470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amanollahi M.; Jameie M.; Heidari A.; Rezaei N.; The Dialogue Between Neuroinflammation and Adult Neurogenesis: Mechanisms Involved and Alterations in Neurological Diseases. Mol Neurobiol 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding M.R.; Qu Y.J.; Hu B.; An H.M.; Signal pathways in the treatment of Alzheimer's disease with traditional Chinese medicine. Biomed Pharmacother 2022,152,113208</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayaraman A.; Reynolds R.; Diverse pathways to neuronal necroptosis in Alzheimer's disease. Eur J Neurosci 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavroidi B.; Kaminari A.; Matiadis D.; The prophylactic and multimodal activity of two isatin thiosemicarbazones against Alzheimer's disease in vitro. Brain Sci 2022,12(6)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapaka D.; Bitra V.R.; Challa S.R.; Adiukwu P.C.; mTOR signaling as a molecular target for the alleviation of Alzheimer's disease pathogenesis. Neurochem Int 2022,155,105311</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Cognitive impairment with diabetes mellitus and metabolic disease: Innovative insights with the mechanistic target of rapamycin and circadian clock gene pathways. Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol 2020,13(1),23-34</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Dysregulation of metabolic flexibility: The impact of mTOR on autophagy in neurodegenerative disease. Int Rev Neurobiol 2020,155,1-35</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Addressing Alzheimer's Disease and cognitive loss through autophagy. Curr Neurovasc Res 2020,17(4),339-341</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caberlotto L.; Nguyen T.P.; Lauria M.; Cross-disease analysis of Alzheimer's disease and type-2 Diabetes highlights the role of autophagy in the pathophysiology of two highly comorbid diseases. Scientif Reports 2019,9(1),3965</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cacabelos R.; Carril J.C.; Cacabelos N.; Sirtuins in Alzheimer's Disease: SIRT2-Related GenoPhenotypes and Implications for PharmacoEpiGenetics. Int J Mol Sci 2019,20(5),1249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee G.; Pollard H.B.; Arispe N.; Annexin 5 and apolipoprotein E2 protect against Alzheimer's amyloid-beta-peptide cytotoxicity by competitive inhibition at a common phosphatidylserine interaction site. Peptides 2002,23(7),1249-1263</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margrett J.A.; Schofield T.; Martin P.; Novel Functional, Health, and Genetic determinants of cognitive terminal decline: Kuakini Honolulu heart program/Honolulu-Asia aging study. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris G.; Berk M.; Maes M.; Puri B.K.; Could Alzheimer's disease originate in the periphery and if so how so? Mol Neurobiol 2019,56(1),406-434</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng H.; Jia L.; Liu C.C.; TREM2 promotes microglial survival by activating Wnt/beta-catenin pathway. J Neurosci 2017,37(7),1771-1784</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong Z.Z.; Shang Y.C.; Hou J.; Maiese K.; Wnt1 neuroprotection translates into improved neurological function during oxidant stress and cerebral ischemia through AKT1 and mitochondrial apoptotic pathways. Oxid Med Cell Longev 2010,3(2),153-165</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Chong Z.Z.; Nicotinamide: Necessary nutrient emerges as a novel cytoprotectant for the brain. Trends Pharmacol Sci 2003,24(5),228-232</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Chong Z.Z.; Hou J.; Shang Y.C.; The vitamin nicotinamide: Translating nutrition into clinical care. Molecules 2009,14(9),3446-3485</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Vincent A.M.; Membrane asymmetry and DNA degradation: functionally distinct determinants of neuronal programmed cell death. J Neurosci Res 2000,59(4),568-580</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurki S.N.; Kantonen J.; Kaivola K.; APOE &#x3b5;4 associates with increased risk of severe COVID-19, cerebral microhaemorrhages and post-COVID mental fatigue: A Finnish biobank, autopsy and clinical study. Acta Neuropathol Communicat 2021,9(1),199</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Kuraishy H.M.; Al-Buhadily A.K.; Al-Gareeb A.I.; Citicoline and COVID-19: vis-&#xe0;-vis conjectured. Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol 2022,1-13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Kuraishy H.M.; Al-Gareeb A.I.; Al-Maiahy T.J.; Alexiou A.; Mukerjee N.; Batiha G.E.; Prostaglandins and non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs in Covid-19. Biotechnol Genet Eng Rev 2022,1-21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves H.R.; Lomba G.S.B.; Gon&#xe7;alves-de-Albuquerque C.F.; Burth P.; Irisin, Exercise, and COVID-19. Front Endocrinol 2022,13,879066</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He W.; Gao Y.; Zhou J.; Shi Y.; Xia D.; Shen H.M.; Friend or Foe? Implication of the autophagy-lysosome pathway in SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19. Int J Biol Sci 2022,18(12),4690-4703</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmud N.; Anik M.I.; Hossain M.K.; Advances in nanomaterial-based platforms to combat COVID-19: Diagnostics, Preventions, Therapeutics, and Vaccine developments. ACS Appl Bio Mater 2022,5(6),2431-2460</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinchera B.; Scotto R.; Buonomo A.R.; Diabetes and COVID-19: The potential role of mTOR. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2022,186,109813</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirzad M.; Nourigorji M.; Sajedi A.; Targeted therapy in Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): Implication from cell and gene therapy to immunotherapy and vaccine. Int Immunopharmacol 2022,111,109161</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoharides T.C.; Could SARS-CoV-2 Spike protein be responsible for Long-COVID syndrome? Mol Neurobiol 2022,59(3),1850-1861</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You H.; Zhao Q.; Dong M.; The key genes underlying pathophysiology correlation between the acute myocardial infarction and COVID-19. Int J Gen Med 2022,15,2479-2490</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; The Mechanistic Target of Rapamycin (mTOR): Novel considerations as an antiviral treatment. Curr Neurovasc Res 2020,17(3),332-337</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Nicotinamide: Oversight of Metabolic Dysfunction through SIRT1, mTOR, and Clock Genes. Curr Neurovasc Res 2020,17(5)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Circadian clock genes: Targeting innate immunity for antiviral strategies against COVID-19. Curr Neurovasc Res 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; The oversight of circadian clock genes for the Detection, Prevention, and Treatment of COVID-19 Infection. Curr Neurovasc Res 2021,18(5),471-473</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lally M.A.; Tsoukas P.; Halladay C.W.; O&#x2019;Neill E.; Gravenstein S.; Rudolph J.L.; Metformin is associated with decreased 30-day mortality among nursing home residents infected with SARS-CoV2. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2021,22(1),193-198</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benotmane I.; Perrin P.; Vargas G.G.; Biomarkers of cytokine release syndrome predict disease severity and mortality from COVID-19 in kidney transplant recipients. Transplantation 2021,105(1),158-169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheema P.S.; Nandi D.; Nag A.; Exploring the therapeutic potential of forkhead box O for outfoxing COVID-19. Open Biol 2021,11(6),210069</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farahani M.; Niknam Z.; Mohammadi Amirabad L.; Molecular pathways involved in COVID-19 and potential pathway-based therapeutic targets. Biomed Pharmacother 2021,145,112420</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Ruiz R.; Paredes J.L.; Niewold T.B.; COVID-19 in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: Lessons learned from the inflammatory disease. Transl Res 2021,232,13-36</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maity S.; Saha A.; Therapeutic potential of exploiting autophagy cascade against coronavirus infection. Front Microbiol 2021,12,675419</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen van Vuren E.; Steyn S.F.; Brink C.B.; M&#xf6;ller M.; Viljoen F.P.; Harvey B.H.; The neuropsychiatric manifestations of COVID-19: Interactions with psychiatric illness and pharmacological treatment. Biomed Pharmacother 2021,135,111200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungnak W; Huang N; Becavin C; SARS-CoV-2 entry factors are highly expressed in nasal epithelial cells together with innate immune genes. Nat Med 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swain O.; Romano S.K.; Miryala R.; Tsai J.; Parikh V.; Umanah G.K.E.; SARS-CoV-2 neuronal invasion and complications: Potential mechanisms and therapeutic approaches. J Neurosci 2021,41(25),5338-5349</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Eid R.; Ward F.J.; Targeting the PI3K/Akt/mTOR pathway: A therapeutic strategy in COVID-19 patients. Immunol Lett 2021,240,1-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diallo A.B.; Gay L.; Coiffard B.; Leone M.; Mezouar S.; Mege J.L.; Daytime variation in SARS-CoV-2 infection and cytokine production. Microb Pathog 2021,158,105067</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furtado G.E.; Letieri R.V.; Caldo-Silva A.; Sustaining efficient immune functions with regular physical exercise in the COVID-19 era and beyond. Eur J Clin Invest 2021,51(5),e13485</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasemnejad-Berenji M.; mTOR inhibition: A double-edged sword in patients with COVID-19? Hum Cell 2021,34(2),698-699</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi G.; Chiramel A.I.; Majdoul S.; Rapalogs downmodulate intrinsic immunity and promote cell entry of SARS-CoV-2. Biorxiv 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blagosklonny M.V.; From causes of aging to death from COVID-19. Aging (Albany NY) 2020,12(11),10004-10021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borges do Nascimento I.J.; Cacic N.; Abdulazeem H.M.; Novel Coronavirus Infection (COVID-19) in humans: A scoping review and Meta-analysis. J Clin Med 2020,9(4)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gusev E.; Sarapultsev A.; Hu D.; Chereshnev V.; Problems of pathogenesis and pathogenetic therapy of COVID-19 from the perspective of the general theory of pathological systems (General Pathological Processes). Intl J Mol Sci 2021,22(14)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Impacting dementia and cognitive loss with innovative strategies: Mechanistic target of rapamycin, clock genes, circular non-coding ribonucleic acids, and Rho/Rock. Neural Regenerat Res 2019,14(5),773-774</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; New Insights for nicotinamide: Metabolic disease, autophagy, and mTOR. Front Biosci(Landmark edition) 2020,25,1925-1973</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Targeting the core of neurodegeneration: FoxO, mTOR, and SIRT1. Neural Regenerat Res 2021,16(3),448-455</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Cognitive impairment and dementia: Gaining insight through circadian clock gene pathways. Biomolecules 2021,11(7),1-18</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Neurodegeneration, memory loss, and dementia: the impact of biological clocks and circadian rhythm. Front Biosci(Landmark edition) 2021,26(9),614-627</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; A common link in neurovascular regenerative pathways: Protein Kinase B (Akt). Curr Neurovasc Res 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Biomarkers for Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease and neurodegenerative disorders: A role for non-coding RNAs. Curr Neurovasc Res 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Pyroptosis, Apoptosis, and Autophagy: Critical players of inflammation and cell demise in the nervous system. Curr Neurovasc Res 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casciano F.; Zauli E.; Rimondi E.; Mura M.; The role of the mTOR pathway in diabetic retinopathy. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022,9,973856</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J.; Xu H.; Rong Z.; Chen L.; Wnt family member 1 (Wnt1) overexpression-induced M2 polarization of microglia alleviates inflammation-sensitized neonatal brain injuries. Bioengineered 2022,13(5),12409-12420</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardeland R.; Redox biology of Melatonin: Discriminating between circadian and non-circadian functions. Antioxid Redox Signal 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra P.; Davies D.A.; Albensi B.C.; The interaction between NF-&#x3ba;B and estrogen in Alzheimer's disease. Mol Neurobiol 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouresmaeil V.; Al Abudi A.H.; Mahimid A.H.; Sarafraz Yazdi M.; Es-Haghi A.; Evaluation of serum selenium and copper levels with inflammatory cytokines and indices of oxidative stress in Type 2 diabetes. Biol Trace Element Res 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sergio C.M.; Rolando C.A.; Erythropoietin regulates signaling pathways associated with neuroprotective events. Exp Brain Res 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He C.; Xu Y.; Sun J.; Li L.; Zhang J.H.; Wang Y.; Autophagy and apoptosis in acute CNS injuries: From mechanism to treatment. Antioxid Redox Signal 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirchenwitz M.; Stahnke S.; Grunau K.; The autophagy inducer SMER28 attenuates microtubule dynamics mediating neuroprotection. Scientific Reports 2022,12(1),17805</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puri D.; Kelkar A.; Gaurishankar B.; Subramanyam D.; Balance between autophagy and cell death is maintained by Polycomb-mediated regulation during stem cell differentiation. FEBS J 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senousy M.A.; Hanafy M.E.; Shehata N.; Rizk S.M.; Erythropoietin and bacillus calmette-gu&#xe9;rin vaccination mitigate 3-Nitropropionic Acid-Induced Huntington-like disease in rats by modulating the PI3K/Akt/mTOR/P70S6K pathway and enhancing the autophagy. ACS Chem Neurosci 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu G.; Wang T.; Ma C.; EPO activates PI3K-IKK&#x3b1;-CDK1 signaling pathway to promote the proliferation of Glial Cells under hypoxia environment. Genet Mol Biol 2022,45(1),e20210249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalgaonkar M.P.; Parmar U.M.; Kulkarni Y.A.; Oza M.J.; SIRT1-FOXOs activity regulates diabetic complications. Pharmacol Res 2022,175,106014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temiz-Resitoglu M.; Guden D.S.; Senol S.P.; Pharmacological inhibition of mammalian target of rapamycin attenuates deoxycorticosterone acetate Salt-Induced hypertension and related pathophysiology: Regulation of oxidative stress, inflammation, and cardiovascular hypertrophy in male rats. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol 2022,79(3),355-367</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong J.; Bonney S.; Gon&#xe7;alves R.V.; Esposito D.; Brassinosteroids control the inflammation, oxidative stress and cell migration through the control of mitochondrial function on skin regeneration. Life Sci 2022,307,120887</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang X.; Ma J.; Xu G.; Sun Z.; SHP-1 knockdown suppresses mitochondrial biogenesis and aggravates mitochondria-dependent apoptosis induced by all trans retinal through the STING/AMPK pathways. Mol Med 2022,28(1),125</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo J; Zhang Z; Luo M; Redox signaling at the crossroads of human health and disease. MedComm (2020) 2022,3(2),e127</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klionsky D.J.; Abdel-Aziz A.K.; Abdelfatah S.; Guidelines for the use and interpretation of assays for monitoring autophagy 2021,1-382</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Chong Z.Z.; Shang Y.C.; Wang S.; Targeting disease through novel pathways of apoptosis and autophagy. Expert opinion on therapeutic targets 2012,16(12),1203-1214</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y.; Xu J.; Hou Y.; Network medicine links SARS-CoV-2/COVID-19 infection to brain microvascular injury and neuroinflammation in dementia-like cognitive impairment. Alzheimers Res Ther 2021,13(1),110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safdari Lord J.; Soltani Rezaiezadeh J.; Yekaninejad M.S.; Izadi P.; The association of APOE genotype with COVID-19 disease severity. Scientif Reports 2022,12(1),13483</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Picking a bone with WISP1 (CCN4): New strategies against degenerative joint disease. J Transl Sci 2016,1(3),83-85</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Moving to the Rhythm with Clock (Circadian) Genes, Autophagy, mTOR, and SIRT1 in Degenerative Disease and Cancer. Curr Neurovasc Res 2017,14(3),299-304</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; The mechanistic target of rapamycin (mTOR) and the silent mating-type information regulation 2 homolog 1 (SIRT1): Oversight for neurodegenerative disorders. Biochem Soc Trans 2018,46(2),351-360</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Prospects and perspectives for WISP1 (CCN4) in Diabetes Mellitus. Curr Neurovasc Res 2020,17(3),327-331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Wnt Signaling and WISP1 (CCN4): Critical components in neurovascular disease, blood brain barrier regulation, and cerebral hemorrhage. Curr Neurovasc Res 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Li F.; Chong Z.Z.; Shang Y.C.; The Wnt signaling pathway: Aging gracefully as a protectionist? Pharmacol Ther 2008,118(1),58-81</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Fern&#xe1;ndez C.; Gonz&#xe1;lez P.; Gonz&#xe1;lez-P&#xe9;rez F.; Rodr&#xed;guez F.; Characterization of ex vivo and in vitro Wnt transcriptome induced by spinal cord injury in rat microglial cells. Brain sciences 2022,12(708)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D.; Zhang M.; Tian J.; WNT1-inducible signalling pathway protein 1 stabilizes atherosclerotic plaques in apolipoprotein-E-deficient mice via the focal adhesion kinase/mitogen-activated extracellular signal-regulated kinase/extracellular signal-regulated kinase pathway. J Hypertens 2022,40(9),1666-1681</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L.; Xu S.; Li P.; Li L.; A novel adipokine WISP1 attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced cell injury in 3T3-L1 adipocytes by regulating the PI3K/Akt pathway. Obes Res Clin Pract 2022,16(2),122-129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren L.L.; Zhou J.Y.; Liang S.J.; Wang X.Q.; Impaired intestinal stem cell activity in ETEC infection: Enterotoxins, cyclic nucleotides, and Wnt signaling. Arch Toxicol 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y.; Chen Y.; Liu R.; Li W.; Hua B.; Bao Y.; Wnt signaling pathways: A role in pain processing 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F.; Chong Z.Z.; Maiese K.; Winding through the WNT pathway during cellular development and demise. Histol Histopathol 2006,21(1),103-124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Novel nervous and multi-system regenerative therapeutic strategies for diabetes mellitus with mTOR. Neural Regenerat Res 2016,11(3),372-385</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma N.X.; Puls B.; Chen G.; Transcriptomic analyses of NeuroD1-mediated astrocyte-to-neuron conversion. Dev Neurobiol 2022,82(5),375-391</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X.R.; Wen X.; Wang Y.J.; MicroRNA-140-5p elevates cerebral protection of dexmedetomidine against hypoxic-ischaemic brain damage via the Wnt/beta-catenin signalling pathway. J Cell Mol Med 2018,22(6),3167-3182</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Forkhead transcription factors: New considerations for Alzheimer's disease and dementia. J Transl Sci 2016,2(4),241-247</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Sirtuins: Developing innovative treatments for aged-related memory loss and Alzheimer's Disease. Curr Neurovasc Res 2018,15(4)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanioka M.; Park W.K.; Shim I.; Neuroprotection from excitotoxic injury by local administration of lipid emulsion into the brain of rats. Int J Mol Sci 2020,21(8)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedighi M.; Baluchnejadmojarad T.; Afshin-Majd S.; Amiri M.; Aminzade M.; Roghani M.; Anti-aging Klotho protects SH-SY5Y cells against amyloid &#x3b2;1-42 neurotoxicity: Involvement of Wnt1/pCREB/Nrf2/HO-1 signaling. J Mol Neurosci 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engin A.B.; Engin A.; Alzheimer's disease and protein kinases. Adv Exp Med Biol 2021,1275,285-321</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarero-Basulto J.; Rivera-Cervantes M.; Gasca-Mart&#xed;nez D.; Garc&#xed;a-Sierra F.; Gasca-Mart&#xed;nez Y.; Beas-Z&#xe1;rate C.; Current evidence on the protective effects of recombinant human erythropoietin and its molecular variants against pathological hallmarks of Alzheimer's Disease. Pharmaceuticals (Basel, Switzerland) 2020,13(424),1-22</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Regeneration in the nervous system with erythropoietin. Front Biosci (Landmark edition) 2016,21,561-596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen J.J.; Pohl S.O.; Deshmukh A.; The role of Wnt signalling in angiogenesis. Clin Biochem Rev 2017,38(3),131-142</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai H.C.; Tzeng H.E.; Huang C.Y.; WISP-1 positively regulates angiogenesis by controlling VEGF-A expression in human osteosarcoma. Cell Death Disease 2017,8(4),e2750</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright L.H.; Herr D.J.; Brown S.S.; Kasiganesan H.; Menick D.R.; Angiokine Wisp-1 is increased in myocardial infarction and regulates cardiac endothelial signaling. JCI Insight 2018,3(4)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y.; Huang C.; Zhu S.Y.; Zou H.C.; Xu C.Y.; Chen Y.X.; Overexpression of HOTAIR attenuates Pi-induced vascular calcification by inhibiting Wnt/&#x3b2;-catenin through regulating miR-126/Klotho/SIRT1 axis. Mol Cell Biochem 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klimontov V.V.; Bulumbaeva D.M.; Fazullina O.N.; Circulating Wnt1-inducible signaling pathway protein-1 (WISP-1/CCN4) is a novel biomarker of adiposity in subjects with type 2 diabetes. J Cell Commun Signal 2020,14(1),101-109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J.J.; Shentu L.M.; Ma N.; Inhibition of NF-kappaB and Wnt/beta-catenin/GSK3beta signaling pathways ameliorates cardiomyocyte hypertrophy and fibrosis in Streptozotocin (STZ)-induced Type 1 diabetic rats. Curr Med Sci 2020,40(1),35-47</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L.; Hu J.; Yang L.; Association of WISP1/CCN4 with risk of overweight and gestational diabetes mellitus in chinese pregnant women. Dis Markers 2020,2020,4934206</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; New insights for oxidative stress and diabetes mellitus. Oxid Med Cell Longev 2015,2015,875961</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Heightened attention for Wnt signaling in diabetes mellitus. Curr Neurovasc Res 2020,17(3),215-217</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie X.; Wei X.; Ma H.; Fan L.; Chen W.D.; The complex role of Wnt ligands in type 2 diabetes mellitus and related complications. J Cell Mol Med 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J.X.; Fang K.; Gao X.R.; Liu S.; Ge J.F.; Resveratrol protects SH-SY5Y cells against oleic acid-induced glucolipid metabolic dysfunction and cell injuries via the Wnt/&#x3b2;-Catenin signalling pathway. Neurochem Res 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Y.C.; Chong Z.Z.; Hou J.; Maiese K.; Wnt1, FoxO3a, and NF-kappaB oversee microglial integrity and activation during oxidant stress. Cell Signal 2010,22(9),1317-1329</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Y.C.; Chong Z.Z.; Wang S.; Maiese K.; Erythropoietin and Wnt1 Govern pathways of mTOR, Apaf-1, and XIAP in inflammatory microglia. Curr Neurovasc Res 2011,8(4),270-285</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Y.C.; Chong Z.Z.; Wang S.; Maiese K.; WNT1 inducible signaling pathway protein 1 (WISP1) Targets PRAS40 to Govern beta-Amyloid apoptotic injury of microglia. Curr Neurovasc Res 2012,9(4),239-249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Y.C.; Chong Z.Z.; Wang S.; Maiese K.; Prevention of beta-amyloid degeneration of microglia by erythropoietin depends on Wnt1, the PI 3-K/mTOR pathway, Bad, and Bcl-xL. Aging (Albany NY) 2012,4(3),187-201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Y.C.; Chong Z.Z.; Wang S.; Maiese K.; Tuberous sclerosis protein 2 (TSC2) modulates CCN4 cytoprotection during apoptotic amyloid toxicity in microglia. Curr Neurovasc Res 2013,10(1),29-38</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Ruiz R.; Garc&#xed;a-Alam&#xe1;n A.; Esteban Y.; Wisp1 is a circulating factor that stimulates proliferation of adult mouse and human beta cells. Nat Communicat 2020,11(1),5982</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiese K.; Novel applications of trophic factors, Wnt and WISP for neuronal repair and regeneration in metabolic disease. Neural Regenerat Res 2015,10(4),518-528</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahin Ersoy G.; Altun Ensari T.; Subas S.; Giray B.; Simsek E.E.; Cevik O.; WISP1 is a novel adipokine linked to metabolic parameters in gestational diabetes mellitus. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med 2016,1-5</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>