<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36855220</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2702</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>21-22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Living with pulmonary sequelae of COVID-19 and the implications for clinical nursing practice: A qualitative systematised review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7650</StartPage><EndPage>7660</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7650-7660</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocn.16664</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To synthesise qualitative research on pulmonary sequelae of COVID-19 and identify patient needs and experiences to develop nursing care strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Qualitative research on long COVID by subtype has not yet occurred. As pulmonary sequelae constitute a serious long COVID subtype, exploring patient experience and needs can generate knowledge to guide nursing practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Systematised review methodology utilised on a purposive sample of published articles and reported using the PRISMA guidelines and checklists. Searched MEDLINE, Cumulative Index to Nursing and Allied Health, and Google Scholar, for English or French articles published from February 2020 to June 2022; qualitative research with adults recovering from COVID-19 with evidence of pulmonary sequelae.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Established principles for data extraction followed related to data reduction, data presentation, data comparison, and conclusion formulation and verification. Analysis was informed by Thorne's Interpretive Description and extended with Meleis' transitions theory, Mishel's uncertainty in illness theory and Moore et al.'s holistic theory of unpleasant symptoms. The quality of included studies was assessed Joanna Briggs Institute critical appraisal tool for qualitative research.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Four articles with six pooled participants provided data to yield three main themes: (1) a novel health-illness transition, (2) lung injury and pulmonary fibrosis as antecedent to illness uncertainty, (3) and pulmonary symptoms that are compounded by fatigue and weakness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Pulmonary sequelae of COVID-19 confers a unique health-illness transition, uncertainties and symptoms that can be addressed by theory informed nursing practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RELEVANCE TO CLINICAL PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Advocacy, optimising the nurse-patient relationship, offering up-to-date information and addressing uncertainty may help patients cope with pulmonary sequelae, a complex subtype of long COVID with important considerations for clinical nursing care. Despite a lack of evidence-informed clinical pathways, nurses can support patients to understand novel treatments, support discharge planning and acknowledge the synergistic nature of pulmonary symptoms and fatigue to support health-illness transitions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="NO PATIENT OR PUBLIC CONTRIBUTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This article involved analysis of previously published works.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Journal of Clinical Nursing published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Albright</LastName><ForeName>Cameron</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Disciplines, Athabasca University, Athabasca, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Limoges</LastName><ForeName>Jacqueline</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Disciplines, Athabasca University, Athabasca, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rempel</LastName><ForeName>Gwen R</ForeName><Initials>GR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0416-5967</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Disciplines, Athabasca University, Athabasca, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9207302</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0962-1067</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009732" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nursing Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002983" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Competence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nursing care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pandemic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary sequelae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transitions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">uncertainty</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36855220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.16664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ali, R. M. M., &amp; Ghonimy, M. B. I. (2021). Post-COVID-19 pneumonia lung fibrosis: A worrisome sequelae in surviving patients. Egyptian Journal of Radiology and Nuclear Medicine, 52(101), 1-8. https://doi.org/10.1186/s43055-021-00484-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin, B. J. H., Kakamad, F. H., Ahmed, G. S., Ahmed, S. F., Abdulla, B. A., Mikael, T. M., Salih, R. Q., Salh, A. M., &amp; Hussein, D. A. (2022). Post COVID-19 pulmonary fibrosis; A meta-analysis study. Annals of Medicine and Surgery, 77, 103590. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amsu.2022.103590</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker, K. M., DeSanto-Madeya, S., &amp; Banzett, R. B. (2017). Routine dyspnea assessment and documentation: Nurses' experience yields wide acceptance. BMC Nursing, 16(1), 1-11. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12912-016-0196-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazdyrev, E., Rusina, P., Panova, M., Novikov, F., Grishagin, I., &amp; Nebolsin, V. (2021). Lung fibrosis after COVID-19: Treatment prospects. Pharmaceuticals, 14(8), 807. https://doi.org/10.3390/ph14080807</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beauchamp, M. K., Janaudis-Ferreira, T., Wald, J., Aceron, R., Bhutani, M., Bourbeau, J., Brooks, D., Dechman, G., Goldstein, R., Goodridge, D., Hernandez, P., Marciniuk, D., Penz, E., Ryerson, C. J., Saey, D., Stickland, M. K., &amp; Weatherald, J. (2022). Canadian thoracic society position statement on rehabilitation for COVID-19 and implications for pulmonary rehabilitation. Canadian Journal of Respiratory, Critical Care, and Sleep Medicine, 6(1), 9-13. https://doi.org/10.1080/24745332.2021.1992939</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bek, L. M., Berentschot, J. C., Hellemons, M. E., Huijts, S. M., Aerts, J., van Bommel, J., van Genderen, M. E., Gommers, D., Ribbers, G. M., Heijenbrok-Kal, M. H., van den Berg-Emons, R., &amp; CO-FLOW Collaboration Group. (2021). CO-FLOW: COvid-19 follow-up care paths and long-term outcomes within the Dutch health care system: Study protocol of a multicenter prospective cohort study following patients 2&#x2009;years after hospital discharge. BMC Health Services Research, 21(847), 1-10. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913-021-06813-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellier-Teichmann, T., Roulet-Schwab, D., Antonini, M., Brandalesi, V., O'Reilly, L., Cara, C., Brousseau, S., &amp; Delmas, P. (2022). Transformation of clinical nursing practice following a caring-based educational intervention: A qualitative perspective. SAGE Open Nursing, 8, 23779608221078100. https://doi.org/10.1177/23779608221078100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharat, A., Querrey, M., Markov, N. S., Kim, S., Kurihara, C., Garza-Castillon, R., Manerikar, A., Shilatifard, A., Tomic, R., &amp; Politanska, Y. (2020). Lung transplantation for patients with severe COVID-19. Science Translational Medicine, 12(574), eabe4282. https://doi.org/10.1126/scitranslmed.abe4282</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boykin, A., Schoenhofer, S. O., Hilton, N., Scott, A. J., &amp; Smith, L. A. (2021). &#x201c;They have our backs&#x201d;: Nurse leaders and caring-based nursing theory in the time of COVID-19. Nurse Leader, 19(2), 179-183. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mnl.2020.08.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callard, F., &amp; Perego, E. (2021). How and why patients made long Covid. Social Science and Medicine, 268, 113426. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113426</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson, G. (2021). Research priorities for long Covid: Refined through an international multi-stakeholder forum. BMC Medicine, 19(1), 1-4. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12916-021-01947-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha, C., &amp; Baek, G. (2021). Symptoms and management of long COVID: A scoping review. Journal of Clinical Nursing, 1-18. https://doi.org/10.1111/jocn.16150</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook, H., Raza, S., Nowell, J., Young, M., &amp; Edison, P. (2021). Long covid-Mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ, 374, n1648. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n1648</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deer, R. R., Rock, M. A., Vasilevsky, N., Carmody, L., Rando, H., Anzalone, A. J., Basson, M. D., Bennett, T. D., Bergquist, T., Boudreau, E. A., Bramante, C. T., Byrd, J. B., Callahan, T. J., Chan, L. E., Chu, H., Chute, C. G., Coleman, B. D., Davis, H. E., Gagnier, J., &#x2026; Robinson, P. N. (2021). Characterizing long COVID: Deep phenotype of a complex condition. eBioMedicine, 74, 103722. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ebiom.2021.103722</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d'Ettorre, G., Gentilini Cacciola, E., Santinelli, L., De Girolamo, G., Spagnolello, O., Russo, A., Tarsitani, L., Ciccozzi, M., Mastroianni, C. M., d'Ettorre, G., &amp; Ceccarelli, G. (2022). Covid-19 sequelae in working age patients: A systematic review. Journal of Medical Virology, 94(3), 858-868. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.27399</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant, M. J., &amp; Booth, A. (2009). A typology of reviews: An analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies. Health Information and Libraries Journal, 26(2), 91-108. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groza, T., K&#xf6;hler, S., Moldenhauer, D., Vasilevsky, N., Baynam, G., Zemojtel, T., Schriml, L. M., Kibbe, W. A., Schofield, P. N., Beck, T., Vasant, D., Brookes, A. J., Zankl, A., Washington, N. L., Mungall, C. J., Lewis, S. E., Haendel, M. A., Parkinson, H., &amp; Robinson, P. N. (2015). The human phenotype ontology: Semantic unification of common and rare disease. The American Journal of Human Genetics, 97(1), 111-124. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajhg.2015.05.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, M., Kong, M., Shi, W., Wang, M., &amp; Yang, H. (2022). Listening to COVID-19 survivors: What they need after early discharge from hospital-a qualitative study. International Journal of Qualitative Studies on Health and Well-Being, 17(1), 2030001. https://doi.org/10.1080/17482631.2022.2030001 *</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen, B. S., R&#xf8;rtveit, K., Leiknes, I., Morken, I., Testad, I., Joa, I., &amp; Severinsson, E. (2012). Patient experiences of uncertainty-a synthesis to guide nursing practice and research. Journal of Nursing Management, 20(2), 266-277. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2834.2011.01369.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, L. M., Zautra, A. J., &amp; Davis, M. C. (2006). The role of illness uncertainty on coping with fibromyalgia symptoms. Health Psychology, 25(6), 696-703. https://doi.org/10.1037/0278-6133.25.6.696</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoshnood, Z., Mehdipour-Rabori, R., Nazari Robati, F., Helal Birjandi, M., &amp; Bagherian, S. (2021). Patients' experiences of living with coronavirus disease 2019: A qualitative study. Evidence Based Care, 11(1), 44-50 *</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingstone, T., Taylor, A. K., O'Donnell, C. A., Atherton, H., Blane, D. N., &amp; Chew-Graham, C. A. (2020). Finding the 'right' GP: A qualitative study of the experiences of people with long-COVID. BJGP Open, 4(5), 1-12. https://doi.org/10.3399/bjgpopen20X101143</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;hler, S., Vasilevsky, N. A., Engelstad, M., Foster, E., McMurry, J., Aym&#xe9;, S., Baynam, G., Bello, S. M., Boerkoel, C. F., Boycott, K. M., Brudno, M., Buske, O. J., Chinnery, P. F., Cipriani, V., Connell, L. E., Dawkins, H. J., DeMare, L., Devereau, A. D., de Vries, B. B., &#x2026; Robinson, P. N. (2017). The human phenotype ontology in 2017. Nucleic Acids Research, 45(1), D865-D876. https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkw1039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;rt&#xfc;nc&#xfc;, M., Kurt, A., &amp; Arslan, N. (2021). The experiences of COVID-19 patients in intensive care units: A qualitative study. OMEGA-Journal of Death and Dying. https://doi.org/10.1177/00302228211024120 *</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockshin, M. D., Crow, M. K., &amp; Barbhaiya, M. (2022). When a diagnosis has no name: Uncertainty and opportunity. Open Rheumatology, 4(3), 197-201. https://doi.org/10.1002/acr2.11368</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magdy, D. M., Metwally, A., Tawab, D. A., Hassan, S. A., Makboul, M., &amp; Farghaly, S. (2022). Long-term COVID-19 effects on pulmonary function, exercise capacity, and health status. Annals of Thoracic Medicine, 17(1), 28-36. https://doi.org/10.4103/atm.atm_82_21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Baz, I., Trobajo-Sanmart&#xed;n, C., Miqueleiz, A., Guevara, M., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Huerta, M., Burgui, C., Casado, I., Portillo, M. E., Navascu&#xe9;s, A., &amp; Ezpeleta, C. (2021). Product-specific COVID-19 vaccine effectiveness against secondary infection in close contacts, Navarre, Spain, April to August 2021. Eurosurveillance, 26(39), 2100894. https://doi.org/10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2021.26.39.2100894</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maxwell, E., &amp; Radford, M. (2021). Long Covid and the ghost of nursing theory. Journal of Research in Nursing, 26(5), 362-366. https://doi.org/10.1177/17449871211037473</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClymont, G. (2021). The role of patients and patient activism in the development of long COVID policy. Cambridge Journal of Science and Policy, 2(1), 1-12. https://doi.org/10.17863/CAM.75505</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meleis, A. I. (2015). Transitions theory. Nursing Theories and Nursing Practice, 4, 361-380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen, M., Manoharan, L., Elkheir, N., Cheng, V., Dagens, A., Hastie, C., O'Hara, M., Suett, J., Dahmash, D., Bugaeva, P., Rigby, I., Munblit, D., Harriss, E., Burls, A., Foote, C., Scott, J., Carson, G., Olliaro, P., Sigfrid, L., &amp; Stavropoulou, C. (2021). Characterising long COVID: A living systematic review. BMJ Global Health, 6(9), e005427. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgh-2021-005427</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishel, M. H. (1984). Perceived uncertainty and stress in illness. Research in Nursing and Health, 7(3), 163-171. https://doi.org/10.1002/nur.4770070304</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishel, M. H. (1988). Uncertainty in illness. Image: The Journal of Nursing Scholarship, 20(4), 225-232. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1547-5069.1988.tb00082.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore, A. K. (2022). The holistic theory of unpleasant symptoms. Journal of Holistic Nursing, 40(2), 193-202. https://doi.org/10.1177/08980101211031706</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myroniuk, T. W., Teti, M., &amp; Schatz, E. (2021). Without qualitative health data, precision health will be imprecise. International Journal of Qualitative Methods, 20, 1-4. https://doi.org/10.1177/16094069211045476</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page, M. J., McKenzie, J. E., Bossuyt, P. M., Boutron, I., Hoffmann, T. C., Mulrow, C. D., Shamseer, L., Tetzlaff, J. M., Akl, E. A., Brennan, S. E., Chou, R., Glanville, J., Grimshaw, J. M., Hr&#xf3;bjartsson, A., Lalu, M. M., Li, T., Loder, E. W., Mayo-Wilson, E., McDonald, S., &#x2026; Moher, D. (2021). The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Systematic Reviews, 10(1), 89. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13643-021-01626-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker, P. A., Davis, J. W., Latini, D. M., Baum, G., Wang, X., Ward, J. F., Kuban, D., Frank, S. J., Lee, A. K., &amp; Logothetis, C. J. (2016). Relationship between illness uncertainty, anxiety, fear of progression and quality of life in men with favourable-risk prostate cancer undergoing active surveillance. BJU International, 117(3), 469-477. https://doi.org/10.1111/bju.13099</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polit, D. F., &amp; Beck, C. T. (2008). Nursing research: Generating and assessing evidence for nursing practice. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai, D. K., Sharma, P., &amp; Kumar, R. (2021). Post covid 19 pulmonary fibrosis. Is it real threat? The Indian Journal of Tuberculosis, 68(3), 330-333. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijtb.2020.11.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reese, J. T., Blau, H., Casiraghi, E., Bergquist, T., Loomba, J. J., Callahan, T. J., Laraway, B., Antonescu, C., Coleman, B., Gargano, M., Wilkins, K. J., Cappelletti, L., Fontana, T., Ammar, N., Antony, B., Murali, T. M., Caufield, J. H., Karlebach, G., McMurry, J., &#x2026; RECOVER Consortium. (2023). Generalisable long COVID subtypes: Findings from the NIH N3C and RECOVER programmes. eBioMedicine, 87, 104413. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ebiom.2022.104413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santiago-Rodriguez, E. I., Maiorana, A., Peluso, M. J., Hoh, R., Tai, V., Fehrman, E. A., Hernandez, Y., Torres, L., Spinelli, M. A., &amp; Gandhi, M. (2021). Characterizing the COVID-19 illness experience to inform the study of post-acute sequelae and recovery. International Journal of Behavioral Medicine, 29, 610-623. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12529-021-10045-7 *</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanson, K. M. (1993). Nursing as informed caring for the well-being of others. IMAGE: Journal of Nursing Scholarship, 25(4), 352-357. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1547-5069.1993.tb00271.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szulczewski, L., Mullins, L. L., Bidwell, S. L., Eddington, A. R., &amp; Pai, A. L. H. (2017). Meta-analysis: Caregiver and youth uncertainty in pediatric chronic illness. Journal of Pediatric Psychology, 42(4), 395-421. https://doi.org/10.1093/jpepsy/jsw097</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanni, S. E., Fabro, A. T., de Albuquerque, A., Ferreira, E., Verrastro, C., Sawamura, M., Ribeiro, S. M., &amp; Baldi, B. G. (2021). Pulmonary fibrosis secondary to COVID-19: A narrative review. Expert Review of Respiratory Medicine, 15(6), 791-803. https://doi.org/10.1080/17476348.2021.1916472</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet, M., Dercon, Q., Luciano, S., Geddes, J. R., Husain, M., &amp; Harrison, P. J. (2021). Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: A 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Medicine, 18(9), e1003773. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1003773</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorne, S. (2016). Interpretive description: Qualitative research for applied practice. Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touman, A., Kahyat, M., Bulkhi, A., Khairo, M., Alyamani, W., Aldobyany, A. M., Ghaleb, N., Ashi, H., Alsobaie, M., &amp; Alqurashi, E. (2022). Post COVID-19 chronic parenchymal lung changes. Cureus, 14(5), e25197. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.25197</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vianello, A., Guarnieri, G., Braccioni, F., Lococo, S., Molena, B., Cecchetto, A., Giraudo, C., De Marchi, L. B., Caminati, M., &amp; Senna, G. (2022). The pathogenesis, epidemiology and biomarkers of susceptibility of pulmonary fibrosis in COVID-19 survivors. Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine (CCLM), 60(3), 307-316. https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2021-1021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallin, E., Hultstr&#xf6;m, M., Lipcsey, M., Frithiof, R., Rubertsson, S., &amp; Larsson, I. M. (2022). Intensive care-treated COVID-19 patients' perception of their illness and remaining symptoms. Acta Anaesthesiologica Scandinavica, 66(2), 240-247. https://doi.org/10.1111/aas.13992</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson, J. (2007). Watson's theory of human caring and subjective living experiences: Carative factors/caritas processes as a disciplinary guide to the professional nursing practice. Texto and Contexto-Enfermagem, 16, 129-135. https://doi.org/10.1590/S0104-07072007000100016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittemore, R., &amp; Knafl, K. (2005). The integrative review: Updated methodology. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 52(5), 546-553. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2648.2005.03621.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2021). Post COVID-19 condition (long COVID). https://www.who.int/srilanka/news/detail/16-10-2021-post-covid-19-condition</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2022). International classification of diseases 11th revision. https://www.who.int/standards/classifications/classification-of-diseases</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright, L. J., Afari, N., &amp; Zautra, A. (2009). The illness uncertainty concept: A review. Current Pain and Headache Reports, 13(2), 133-138. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11916-009-0023-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong, S. J., &amp; Liu, S. (2021). Proposed subtypes of post-COVID-19 syndrome (or long-COVID) and their respective potential therapies. Reviews in Medical Virology, 32, e2315. https://doi.org/10.1002/rmv.2315</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>