<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39361124</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-2649</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Quality of life research : an international journal of quality of life aspects of treatment, care and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Qual Life Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A pilot cross-sectional investigation of symptom clusters and associations with patient-reported outcomes in Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome and Post COVID-19 Condition.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11136-024-03794-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS) is associated with long-term disability and poor quality of life (QoL). Cardinal ME/CFS symptoms (including post-exertional malaise, cognitive dysfunction and sleep disturbances) have been observed in Post COVID-19 Condition (PCC). To gain further insight into the potential role of ME/CFS as a post-COVID-19 sequela, this study investigates associations between symptoms and patient-reported outcomes, as well as symptom clusters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Participants included Australian residents aged between 18 and 65 years formally diagnosed with ME/CFS fulfilling the Canadian or International Consensus Criteria or PCC meeting the World Health Organization case definition. Validated, self-administered questionnaires collected participants' sociodemographic and illness characteristics, symptoms, QoL and functional capacity. Associations between symptoms and patient-reported outcomes were investigated with multivariate linear regression models. Hierarchical cluster analysis was performed to identify symptom clusters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Most people with ME/CFS (pwME/CFS) and people with PCC (pwPCC) were female (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;48/60, 80.0% and n&#x2009;=&#x2009;19/30, 63.3%, respectively; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.12). PwME/CFS were significantly younger (x&#x304;=41.75, s&#x2009;=&#x2009;12.91 years) than pwPCC (x&#x304;=48.13, s&#x2009;=10.05 years; p&#x2009;=0.017). Autonomic symptoms (notably dyspnoea) were associated with poorer scores in most patient-reported outcome domains for both cohorts. None of the four symptom clusters identified were unique to ME/CFS or PCC. Clusters were largely delineated by the presence of gastrointestinal and neurosensory symptoms, illness duration, ME/CFS criteria met and total symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Illness duration may explain differences in symptom burden between pwME/CFS and pwPCC. PCC diagnostic criteria must be refined to distinguish pwPCC at risk of long-term ME/CFS-like illness and subsequently deliver necessary care and support.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weigel</LastName><ForeName>Breanna</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8452-6656</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Neuroimmunology and Emerging Diseases, Griffith University, 1 Parklands Drive, Southport Gold Coast, Brisbane, QLD, 4222, Australia. ncned@griffith.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Consortium Health International for Myalgic Encephalomyelitis, Griffith University, Gold Coast, Brisbane, QLD, 4222, Australia. ncned@griffith.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Pharmacy and Medical Sciences, Griffith University, Gold Coast, Brisbane, QLD, 4222, Australia. ncned@griffith.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eaton-Fitch</LastName><ForeName>Natalie</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0815-3162</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Neuroimmunology and Emerging Diseases, Griffith University, 1 Parklands Drive, Southport Gold Coast, Brisbane, QLD, 4222, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Consortium Health International for Myalgic Encephalomyelitis, Griffith University, Gold Coast, Brisbane, QLD, 4222, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thapaliya</LastName><ForeName>Kiran</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7667-770X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Neuroimmunology and Emerging Diseases, Griffith University, 1 Parklands Drive, Southport Gold Coast, Brisbane, QLD, 4222, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Consortium Health International for Myalgic Encephalomyelitis, Griffith University, Gold Coast, Brisbane, QLD, 4222, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marshall-Gradisnik</LastName><ForeName>Sonya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9270-2437</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Neuroimmunology and Emerging Diseases, Griffith University, 1 Parklands Drive, Southport Gold Coast, Brisbane, QLD, 4222, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Consortium Health International for Myalgic Encephalomyelitis, Griffith University, Gold Coast, Brisbane, QLD, 4222, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Qual Life Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9210257</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0962-9343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Post COVID-19 Condition (PCC), or Long COVID, refers to the ongoing symptoms experienced after acute COVID-19 illness. The symptoms reported by people with PCC (pwPCC) resemble Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS). However, existing diagnostic criteria for PCC are broad and cannot discern PCC subtypes (such as pwPCC experiencing ME/CFS-like illness), which may require different approaches to care. This study contributes to improving PCC case criteria and approaches to care for both ME/CFS and PCC by investigating the relationships between symptoms and patient-reported outcomes among pwPCC and people with ME/CFS (pwME/CFS).For both cohorts, symptoms had a negative relationship with all aspects of health. Autonomic symptoms, notably breathing issues, returned the most negative associations. Pain, flu-like symptoms and lack of temperature control appeared more burdensome among pwPCC. These symptoms may signify the early stages of ME/CFS. Symptom clusters were also identified for the first time among a combined cohort of pwME/CFS and pwPCC in this study. Importantly, none of the symptom clusters were specific to ME/CFS or PCC. Instead, symptom clusters were defined by the prevalence of gastrointestinal and neurosensory symptoms, illness duration, ME/CFS criteria met and the total number of symptoms.This study suggests that the few differences between ME/CFS and PCC may be explained by illness duration. These findings further implicate ME/CFS as a potential post-COVID-19 outcome. As ME/CFS is associated with profound reductions in quality of life and functioning, identifying pwPCC experiencing ME/CFS-like illness through refined diagnostic criteria must be prioritised to ensure the delivery of necessary care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post COVID-19 Condition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39361124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-024-03794-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11136-024-03794-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Eaton-Fitch, N., Johnston, S. C., Zalewski, P., Staines, D. R., &amp; Marshall-Gradisnik, S. M. (2020). Health-related quality of life in patients with Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: An Australian cross-sectional study. Quality of Life Research, 29(6), 1521&#x2013;1531. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11136-019-02411-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cambras, T., Castro-Marrero, J., Zaragoza, M. C., D&#xed;ez-Noguera, A., &amp; Alegre, J. (2018). Circadian rhythm abnormalities and autonomic dysfunction in patients with Chronic Fatigue Syndrome/Myalgic Encephalomyelitis. PLoS One, 13(6), e0198106. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0198106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strand, E. B., Mengshoel, M., Sandvik, A., Helland, L., Abraham, I. B. S., &amp; Solberg Nes, L. (2019). Pain is associated with reduced quality of life and functional status in patients with Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Scandinavian Journal of Pain, 19(1), 61&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1515/sjpain-2018-0095</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baraniuk, J. (2022). Myalgic Encephalomyelitis (Chronic Fatigue Syndrome). BMJ Best Practice. Retrieved October 23, 2023, from https://bestpractice.bmj.com/topics/en-gb/277</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carruthers, B. M., Van de Sande, M. I., De Meirleir, K. L., Klimas, N. G., Broderick, G., Mitchell, T., Staines, D. R., Powles, A. C. P., Speight, N., Vallings, R., Bateman, L., Baumgarten-Austrheim, B., Bell, D. S., Carlo-Stella, N., Chia, J., Darragh, A., Jo, D., Lewis, D., Light, A. R., &#x2026; Stevens, S. (2011). Myalgic Encephalomyelitis: International consensus criteria. Journal of Internal Medicine, 270(4), 327&#x2013;338. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2796.2011.02428.x .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carruthers, B. M., Jain, A. K., De Meirleir, K. L., Peterson, D. L., Klimas, N. G., Lerner, A. M., Bested, A. C., Flor-Henry, P., Joshi, P., Powles, A. C. P., Sherkey, J. A., &amp; Van de Sande, M. I. (2003). Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Journal Of Chronic Fatigue Syndrome, 11(1), 7&#x2013;115. https://doi.org/10.1300/J092v11n01_02</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, C. J., Hung, L. Y., Kogelnik, A. M., Kaufman, D., Aiyar, R. S., Chu, A. M., Wilhelmy, J., Li, P., Tannenbaum, L., Xiao, W., &amp; Davis, R. W. (2021). A comprehensive examination of severely ill ME/CFS patients. Healthcare, 9(10). https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare9101290</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston, S. C., Brenu, E. W., Hardcastle, S. L., Huth, T. K., Staines, D. R., &amp; Marshall-Gradisnik, S. M. (2014). A comparison of health status in patients meeting alternative definitions for Chronic Fatigue Syndrome/Myalgic Encephalomyelitis. Health and Quality of Life Outcomes, 12(1), 64. https://doi.org/10.1186/1477-7525-12-64</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bested, A. C., &amp; Marshall, L. M. (2015). Review of Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: An evidence-based approach to diagnosis and management by clinicians. Reviews on Environmental Health, 30(4), 223&#x2013;249. https://doi.org/10.1515/reveh-2015-0026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim, E. J., Ahn, Y. C., Jang, E. S., Lee, S. W., Lee, S. H., &amp; Son, C. G. (2020). Systematic review and meta-analysis of the prevalence of Chronic Fatigue Syndrome/Myalgic Encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME). Journal of Translational Medicine, 18(1), 100. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967-020-02269-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu, L., Valencia, I. J., Garvert, D. W., &amp; Montoya, J. G. (2019). Onset patterns and course of Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Frontiers in Pediatrics, 7, 12. https://doi.org/10.3389/fped.2019.00012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nacul, L., O&#x2019;Boyle, S., Palla, L., Nacul, F. E., Mudie, K., Kingdon, C. C., Cliff, J. M., Clark, T. G., Dockrell, H. M., &amp; Lacerda, E. M. (2020). How Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS) progresses: The natural history of ME/CFS. Frontiers in Neurology, 11. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2020.00826</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston, S. C., Staines, D. R., &amp; Marshall-Gradisnik, S. M. (2016). Epidemiological characteristics of Chronic Fatigue Syndrome/Myalgic Encephalomyelitis in Australian patients. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology,&#xa0;8, 97&#x2013;107. https://doi.org/10.2147/CLEP.S96797</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason, L. A., Yoo, S., &amp; Bhatia, S. (2021). Patient perceptions of infectious illnesses preceding Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Chronic Illness, 18(4), 901&#x2013;910. https://doi.org/10.1177/17423953211043106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choutka, J., Jansari, V., Hornig, M., &amp; Iwasaki, A. (2022). Unexplained post-acute infection syndromes. Nature Medicine, 28, 911&#x2013;923. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-01810-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, H. E., McCorkell, L., Vogel, M., J., &amp; Topol, E. J. (2023). Long COVID: Major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nature Reviews Microbiology, 21(3), 133&#x2013;146. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukocheva, O. A., Maksoud, R., Beeraka, N. M., Madhunapantula, S. V., Sinelnikov, M., Nikolenko, V. N., Neganova, M. E., Klochkov, S. G., Kamal, A., Staines, M., D. R., &amp; Marshall-Gradisnik, S. M. (2022). Analysis of Post COVID-19 Condition and its overlap with Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Journal of Advanced Research, 40, 179&#x2013;196. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jare.2021.11.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, T. L., &amp; Weitzer, D. J. (2021). Long COVID and Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS) - a systematic review and comparison of clinical presentation and symptomatology. Medicina (Kaunas, Lithuania), 57(5), 418. https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina57050418</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano, J. B., Allan, M., Alsokhn, C., Alwan, N. A., Askie, L., Davis, H. E., Diaz, J. V., Dua, T., De Groote, W., Jakob, R., Lado, M., Marshall, J., Murthy, S., Preller, J., Relan, P., Schiess, N., &amp; Seahwag (2023). A. A clinical case definition of Post COVID-19 Condition by a Delphi consensus. World Health Organization: Geneva, Switzerland. Retrieved September 5, from https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonilla, H., Quach, T. C., Tiwari, A., Bonilla, A. E., Miglis, M., Yang, P. C., Eggert, L. E., Sharifi, H., Horomanski, A., Subramanian, A., Smirnoff, L., Simpson, N., Halawi, H., Sum-Ping, O., Kalinowski, A., Patel, Z. M., Shafer, R. W., &amp; Geng, L. N. (2023). Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome is common in post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC): Results from a post-COVID-19 multidisciplinary clinic. Frontiers in Neurology, 14. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2023.1090747</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedor, C., Freitag, H., Meyer-Arndt, L., Wittke, K., Hanitsch, L. G., Zoller, T., Steinbeis, F., Haffke, M., Rudolf, G., Heidecker, B., Bobbert, T., Spranger, J., Volk, H. D., Skurk, C., Konietschke, F., Paul, F., Behrends, U., Bellmann-Strobl, J., &amp; Scheibenbogen, C. (2022). A prospective observational study of post-COVID-19 Chronic Fatigue Syndrome following the first pandemic wave in Germany and biomarkers associated with symptom severity. Nature Communications, 13(1), 5104. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-022-32507-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weigel, B., Eaton-Fitch, N., Thapaliya, K., &amp; Marshall-Gradisnik, S. M. (2024). Illness presentation and quality of life in Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome and Post COVID-19 Condition: A pilot Australian cross-sectional study. Quality of Life Research. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11136-024-03710-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retornaz, F., Rebaudet, S., Stavris, C., &amp; Jammes, Y. (2022). Long-term neuromuscular consequences of SARS-CoV-2 and their similarities with Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: Results of the retrospective CoLGEM study. Journal of Translational Medicine, 20(1), 429. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967-022-03638-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vernon, S. D., Hartle, M., Sullivan, K., Bell, J., Abbaszadeh, S., Unutmaz, D., &amp; Bateman, L. (2023). Post-exertional malaise among people with Long COVID compared to Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS). WORK: A Journal of Prevention, Assessment &amp; Rehabilitation, 74(4), 1179&#x2013;1186. https://doi.org/10.3233/WOR-220581</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey, R., DeMars, J., Franklin, K., Culos-Reed, S. N., Weatherald, J., &amp; Wrightson, J. G. (2022). Chronic fatigue and postexertional malaise in people living with long COVID: An observational study. Physical Therapy &amp; Rehabilitation Journal, 102(4), pzac005. https://doi.org/10.1093/ptj/pzac005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, H. E., Assaf, G. S., McCorkell, L., Wei, H., Low, R. J., Re&#x2019;em, Y., Redfield, S., Austin, J. P., &amp; Akrami, A. (2021). Characterising Long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. The Lancet Discovery Science, 38(August 2021), 101019. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves de Sousa, K. C., Gardel, D. G., &amp; Lopes, A. J. (2022). Postural balance and its association with functionality and quality of life in non-hospitalized patients with Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome. Physiotherapy Research International: The Journal for Researchers and Clinicians in Physical Therapy, 27(4), e1967. https://doi.org/10.1002/pri.1967</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pri.1967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, J., Lin, K., Zhang, H., Xue, Q., Zhu, K., Yuan, G., Sun, Y., Zhu, F., Ai, J., Wang, S., &amp; Zhang, W. (2023). A one-year follow-up study of systematic impact of long COVID symptoms among patients post SARS-CoV-2 omicron variants infection in Shanghai, China. Emerging Microbes &amp; Infections, 12(2), 2220578. https://doi.org/10.1080/22221751.2023.2220578</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martini Sasso, E., Muraki, K., Eaton-Fitch, N., Smith, P., Lesslar, O. L., Deed, G., &amp; Marshall-Gradisnik, S. M. (2022). Transient receptor potential melastatin 3 dysfunction in Post COVID-19 Condition and Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome patients. Molecular Medicine, 28(1), 98. https://doi.org/10.1186/s10020-022-00528-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff, A. L., &amp; Lipkin, W. I. (2021). Insights from Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome may help unravel the pathogenesis of Postacute COVID-19 Syndrome. Trends in Molecular Medicine, 27(9), 895&#x2013;906. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molmed.2021.06.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai, T., Jolley, S. E., Karlson, E. W., Levitan, E. B., Levy, B., McComsey, G. A., McCorkell, L., Nadkarni, G. N., Parthasarathy, S., Singh, U., Walker, T. A., Selvaggi, C. A., Shinnick, D. J., Schulte, C. C. M., Atchley-Challenner, R., Horwitz, L. I., Foulkes, A. S., &amp; RECOVER Consortium Authors. (2023). Development of a definition of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA, 329(22), 1934&#x2013;1946. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2023.8823</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basharat, S., Chao, Y. S., &amp; McGill, S. C. (2024). Subtypes of Post-COVID-19 Condition: A review of the emerging evidence. Canadian Agency for Drugs and Technologies in Health: Ottawa, Canada. Retrieved April 23, from https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK601826/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as, C., Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero, J. D., Florencio, L. L., Navarro-Pardo, E., Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez, J., Torres-Macho, J., &amp; Pellicer-Valero, O. J. (2022). Clustering analysis reveals different profiles associating long-term post-COVID symptoms, COVID-19 symptoms at hospital admission and previous medical co-morbidities in previously hospitalized COVID-19 survivors. Infection, 51(1), 61&#x2013;69. https://doi.org/10.1007/s15010-022-01822-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s15010-022-01822-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35451721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9028890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman, L., Bested, A. C., Bonilla, H. F., Chheda, B. V., Chu, L., Curtin, J. M., Dempsey, T. T., Dimmock, M. E., Dowell, T. G., Felsenstein, D., Kaufman, D. L., Klimas, N. G., Komaroff, A. L., Lapp, C. W., Levine, S. M., Montoya, J. G., Natelson, B. H., Peterson, D. L., Podell, R. N., &#x2026; Yellman, B. P. (2021). Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: Essentials of diagnosis and management. Mayo Clinic Proceedings, 96(11):2861&#x2013;78. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mayocp.2021.07.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maixner, W., Fillingim, R. B., Williams, D. A., Smith, S. B., &amp; Slade, G. D. (2016). Overlapping chronic pain conditions: Implications for diagnosis and classification. The Journal of Pain, 17(9 Suppl), T93&#x2013;107. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpain.2016.06.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran, A. V., Jayadevan, R., &amp; Sashidharan, S. (2021). Long COVID: An overview. Diabetes &amp; Metabolic Syndrome: Clinical Research &amp; Reviews, 15(3), 869&#x2013;875. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dsx.2021.04.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsx.2021.04.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Health and Medical Research Council, Australian Research Council, &amp; Universities Australia. National Statement on Ethical Conduct in Human Research. National Health and Medical Research Council: Canberra, Australia. Retrieved June 19 (2024). from https://www.nhmrc.gov.au/about-us/publications/national-statement-ethical-conduct-human-research-2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association. (2013). World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: Ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA, 310(20), 2191&#x2013;2194. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2013.281053</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Elm, E., Altman, D. G., Egger, M., Pocock, S. J., G&#xf8;tzsche, P. C., &amp; Vandenbroucke, J. P. (2008). The strengthening the reporting of Observational studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) statement: Guidelines for reporting observational studies. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology, 61(4), 344&#x2013;349. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.11.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.11.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization Constitution of the World Health Organization. World Health Organization: Geneva, Switzerland. Retrieved September 1, 2024, from https://www.who.int/about/governance/constitution</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware, J. E. Jr (2000). SF-36 Health Survey Update. Spine, 25(24), 3130&#x2013;3139. https://doi.org/10.1097/00007632-200012150-00008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00007632-200012150-00008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11124729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xdc;st&#xfc;n, T. B., Kostanjsek, N., Chatterji, S., Rehm, J., &amp; World Health Organization. &amp;. Measuring health and disability: Manual for WHO Disability Assessment Schedule (WHODAS 2.0). World Health Organization: Geneva, Switzerland. Retrieved September 20, 2023, from https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/measuring-health-and-disability-manual-for-who-disability-assessment-schedule-(-whodas-2.0 ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nittas, V., Gao, M., West, E. A., Ballouz, T., Menges, D., Hanson, W., S., &amp; Puhan, M. A. (2022). Long COVID through a public health lens: An umbrella review. Public Health Reviews, 43, 1604501. https://doi.org/10.3389/phrs.2022.1604501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/phrs.2022.1604501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35359614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8963488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corp, I. B. M. (Released 2022). IBM Statistical Package for the Social Sciences (SPSS) statistics for Windows, Version 29.0. Armonk, New York: IBM Corp.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang, T. A., &amp; Altman, D. G. (2023). Basic statistical recording for articles published in biomedical journals: The Statistical Analyses and Methods in the Published Literature or The SAMPL Guidelines. In: Smart P, Maisonneuve H, Polderman A (Eds.). Science Editor&#x2019;s Handbook, 2nd Ed. European Association of Science Editors: Cornwall, United Kingdom. Retrieved November 20, from https://www.equator-network.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/SAMPL-Guidelines-6-27-13.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamini, Y., &amp; Hochberg, Y. (1995). Controlling the false discovery rate: A practical and powerful approach to multiple testing. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society, Series B (Methodology), 57(1), 289&#x2013;300. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.2517-6161.1995.tb02031.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.2517-6161.1995.tb02031.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stensen, K., &amp; Lydersen, S. (2022). Internal consistency: From alpha to omega. Tidsskr Nor Laegeforen, 142(12). https://doi.org/10.4045/tidsskr.22.0112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weigel, B., Eaton-Fitch, N., Passmore, R., Cabanas, H., Staines, D., &amp; Marshall-Gradisnik, S. (2020). Gastrointestinal symptoms, dietary habits, and the effect on health-related quality of life among Australian Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome patients: A cross-sectional study. Annals of Epidemiology and Public Health, 3(1), 1045. https://meddocsonline.org/annals-of-epidemiology-and-public-health/gastrointestinal-symptoms-dietary-habits-and-the-effect-on-health-related-quality-of-life-among-australian-myalgic-encephalomyelitis-chronic-fatigue-syndrome-patients-a-cross-sectional-study.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro-Marrero, J., Faro, M., Aliste, L., S&#xe1;ez-Franc&#xe0;s, N., Calvo, N., Mart&#xed;nez-Mart&#xed;nez, A., de Fern&#xe1;ndez, T., &amp; Alegre, J. (2017). Comorbidity in Chronic Fatigue Syndrome/Myalgic encephalomyelitis: A nationwide population-based cohort study. Psychosomatics, 58(5), 533&#x2013;543. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psym.2017.04.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psym.2017.04.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28596045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marasco, G., Maida, M., Cremon, C., Raffaella Barbaro, M., Stranghellini, V., &amp; Barbara, G. (2023). Meta-analysis: Post-COVID-19 functional dyspepsia and irritable bowel syndrome. Aliment Pharmacol Ther, 58(1), 6&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1111/apt.17513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apt.17513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason, L. A., Islam, M. F., Conroy, K., Cotler, J., Torres, C., Johnson, M., &amp; Mabie, B. (2021). COVID-19 symptoms over time: Comparing long-haulers to ME/CFS. Fatigue Biomed Health Behav, 9(2), 59&#x2013;68. https://doi.org/10.1080/21641846.2021.1922140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21641846.2021.1922140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azcue, N., G&#xf3;mez-Esteban, J. C., Acera, M., Tijero, B., Fernandez, T., Ayo-Mentxakatorre, N., P&#xe9;rez-Concha, T., Murueta-Goyena, A., Lafuente, J. V., Prada, &#xc1;., de L&#xf3;pez, A., Ruiz-Irastorza, G., Ribacoba, L., Gabilondo, I., &amp; Del Pino, R. (2022). Brain fog of Post-COVID-19 Condition and Chronic Fatigue Syndrome, same medical disorder? J Transl Med, 20(1), 569. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967-022-03764-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-022-03764-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36474290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9724286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myalgic Encephalomyelitis - Adult and paediatric: International consensus primer for medical practitioners. Retrieved May 31, 2024, from http://www.investinme.org/Documents/Guidelines/Myalgic%20Encephalomyelitis%20International%20Consensus%20Primer%20-2012-11-26.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedberg, F., Bateman, L., Bested, A. C., Davenport, T., Friedman, K. J., Gurwitt, A., Jason, L. A., Lapp, C. W., Stevens, S. R., Underhill, R. A., &amp; Vallings, R. (2014). Chronic Fatigue Syndrome/Myalgic Encephalomyelitis - Primer for clinical practitioners. 2014 Edition. International Association of Chronic Fatigue Syndrome/Myalgic Encephalomyelitis. Retrieved June 17, 2024, from https://massmecfs.org/images/pdf/Primer_2014.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedberg, F., Dechene, L., McKenzie, M. J., II, &amp; Fontanetta, R. (2000). Symptom patterns in long-duration Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Journal of Psychosomatic Research, 48(1), 59&#x2013;68. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-3999(99)00077-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-3999(99)00077-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10750631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megari, K. (2013). Quality of life in chronic disease patients. Health Psychology Research, 1(3), e27. https://doi.org/10.4081/hpr.2013.e27</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/hpr.2013.e27</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26973912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4768563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda, K., Straus, S. E., Hickie, I., Sharpe, M. C., Dobbins, J. G., &amp; Komaroff, A. (1994). The Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: A comprehensive approach to its definition and study. Annals of Internal Medicine, 121(12), 953&#x2013;959. https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-121-12-199412150-00009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-121-12-199412150-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7978722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#x142;omko, J., Est&#xe9;vez-L&#xf3;pez, F., Kujawski, S., Zawadka-Kunikowska, M., Tafil-Klawe, M., Klawe, J. J., Morten, K. J., Szrajda, J., Murovska, M., Newton, J. L., &amp; Zalewski, P. (2020). Autonomic phenotypes in Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (CFS) are associated with illness severity: A cluster analysis. Journal of Clinical Medicine, 9, 2531. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm9082531 . &amp; The European Network on ME/CFS (EUROMENE).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm9082531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32764516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7464864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldhaber, N. H., Kohn, J. N., Ogan, W. S., Sitapati, A., Longhurst, C. A., Wang, A., Lee, S., Hong, S., &amp; Horton, L. E. (2022). Deep dive into the long haul: Analysis of symptom clusters and risk factors for post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 to inform clinical care. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19(24), 16841. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph192416841</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph192416841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36554723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9778884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer, A., Zhang, L., Elb&#xe9;ji, A., Wilmes, P., Oustric, P., Staub, T., Nazarov, P. V., Ollert, M., &amp; Fagherazzi, G. (2022). Long COVID symptomatology after 12 months and its impact on quality of life according to initial Coronavirus Disease 2019 disease severity. Open Forum Infectious Diseases, 9(8), ofac397. https://doi.org/10.1093/ofid/ofac397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ofid/ofac397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35983269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9379809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Houdt, S. C. M., Slurink, I. A. L., &amp; Mertens, G. (2024). Long COVID is not a uniform syndrome: Evidence from a person-level symptom clusters using latent class analysis. Journal of Infection and Public Health, 17(2), 321&#x2013;328. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiph.2023.12.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiph.2023.12.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38183882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>