<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37621592</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2307-8960</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of clinical cases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Clin Cases</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19-induced gastrointestinal autonomic dysfunction: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5252</StartPage><EndPage>5272</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5252-5272</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12998/wjcc.v11.i22.5252</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">It is common for severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection to occur in the gastrointestinal tract, which can present itself as an initial symptom. The severity of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) is often reflected in the prevalence of gastrointestinal symptoms. COVID-19 can damage the nerve supply to the digestive system, leading to gastrointestinal autonomic dysfunction. There is still much to learn about how COVID-19 affects the autonomic nervous system and the gastrointestinal tract.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To thoroughly explore the epidemiology and clinical aspects of COVID-19-induced gastrointestinal autonomic dysfunction, including its manifestations, potential mechanisms, diagnosis, differential diagnosis, impact on quality of life, prognosis, and management and prevention strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a thorough systematic search across various databases and performed an extensive literature review. Our review encompassed 113 studies published in English from January 2000 to April 18, 2023.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">According to most of the literature, gastrointestinal autonomic dysfunction can seriously affect a patient's quality of life and ultimate prognosis. Numerous factors can influence gastrointestinal autonomic nervous functions. Studies have shown that SARS-CoV-2 has a well-documented affinity for both neural and gastrointestinal tissues, and the virus can produce various gastrointestinal symptoms by reaching neural tissues through different pathways. These symptoms include anorexia, dysgeusia, heartburn, belching, chest pain, regurgitation, vomiting, epigastric burn, diarrhea, abdominal pain, bloating, irregular bowel movements, and constipation. Diarrhea is the most prevalent symptom, followed by anorexia, nausea, vomiting, and abdominal pain. Although COVID-19 vaccination may rarely induce autonomic dysfunction and gastrointestinal symptoms, COVID-19-induced autonomic effects significantly impact the patient's condition, general health, prognosis, and quality of life. Early diagnosis and proper recognition are crucial for improving outcomes. It is important to consider the differential diagnosis, as these symptoms may be induced by diseases other than COVID-19-induced autonomic dysfunction. Treating this dysfunction can be a challenging task.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">To ensure the best possible outcomes for COVID-19 patients, it is essential to take a multidisciplinary approach involving providing supportive care, treating the underlying infection, managing dysfunction, monitoring for complications, and offering nutritional support. Close monitoring of the patient's condition is crucial, and prompt intervention should be taken if necessary. Furthermore, conducting thorough research on the gastrointestinal autonomic dysfunction caused by COVID-19 is vital to manage it effectively.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2023. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elbeltagi</LastName><ForeName>Reem</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, The Royal College of Surgeons in Ireland-Medical University of Bahrain, Busiateen &#x200e;15503&#x200e;, Muharraq, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Beltagi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Faculty of Medicine, Tanta University, Tanta &#x200e;31511&#x200e;, Algharbia, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, University Medical Center, Arabian Gulf University, Manama &#x200e;26671&#x200e;, Manama, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, University Medical Center, King Abdulla Medical City, Arabian Gulf University, Dr &#x200e;Sulaiman Al Habib Medical Group, Manama &#x200e;26671&#x200e;, Manama, Bahrain. mbelrem@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saeed</LastName><ForeName>Nermin Kamal</ForeName><Initials>NK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Microbiology Section, Pathology Department, Salmaniya Medical Complex, Ministry of Health, Kingdom of Bahrain, Manama 12, Manama, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Microbiology Section, Pathology Department, The Royal College of Surgeons in Ireland-Medical University of Bahrain, Busaiteen 15503, Muharraq, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bediwy</LastName><ForeName>Adel Salah</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chest Disease, Faculty of Medicine, Tanta University, Tanta &#x200e;31527&#x200e;, Algharbia, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonology, University Medical Center, King Abdulla Medical City, Arabian Gulf University, Dr &#x200e;Sulaiman Al Habib Medical Group, Manama &#x200e;26671&#x200e;, Manama, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Clin Cases</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101618806</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2307-8960</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic nervous system&#x200e;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal autonomic dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-&#x200e;COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors declare no conflict of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37621592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10445067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12998/wjcc.v11.i22.5252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Al-Beltagi M, Saeed NK, Bediwy AS, El-Sawaf Y. Paediatric gastrointestinal disorders in SARS-CoV-2 infection: Epidemiological and clinical implications. World J Gastroenterol. 2021;27:1716&#x2013;1727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33967552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain U. Effect of COVID-19 on the Organs. Cureus. 2020;12:e9540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7470660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32905500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Chen X, Huang R, Li S, Lin D, Yang Z, Sun H, Liu G, Qiu J, Tang Y, Xiao J, Liao Y, Wu X, Wu R, Dai Z. Atypical presentations of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) from onset to readmission. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21:127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7844102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33514323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan L, Mu M, Yang P, Sun Y, Wang R, Yan J, Li P, Hu B, Wang J, Hu C, Jin Y, Niu X, Ping R, Du Y, Li T, Xu G, Hu Q, Tu L. Clinical Characteristics of COVID-19 Patients With Digestive Symptoms in Hubei, China: A Descriptive, Cross-Sectional, Multicenter Study. Am J Gastroenterol. 2020;115:766&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32287140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff A, Kavanaugh M, Ramgobin D, McClafferty B, Aggarwal CS, Golamari R, Jain R. Gastrointestinal Manifestations of COVID-19: A Review of What We Know. Ochsner J. 2021;21:177&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8238098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34239378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojetti V, Saviano A, Covino M, Acampora N, Troiani E, Franceschi F GEMELLI AGAINST COVID&#x2010;19 group. COVID-19 and intestinal inflammation: Role of fecal calprotectin. Dig Liver Dis. 2020;52:1231&#x2013;1233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33060042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng PK, Wong DA, Tong LK, Ip SM, Lo AC, Lau CS, Yeung EY, Lim WW. Viral shedding patterns of coronavirus in patients with probable severe acute respiratory syndrome. Lancet. 2004;363:1699&#x2013;1700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7112423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15158632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chelimsky G, Chelimsky TC. Evaluation and treatment of autonomic disorders of the gastrointestinal tract. Semin Neurol. 2003;23:453&#x2013;458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15088266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kornum DS, Terkelsen AJ, Bertoli D, Klinge MW, H&#xf8;yer KL, Kufaishi HHA, Borghammer P, Drewes AM, Brock C, Krogh K. Assessment of Gastrointestinal Autonomic Dysfunction: Present and Future Perspectives. J Clin Med. 2021;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8037288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P, Torocastro M, Panagopoulos D, Sutton R, Lim PB. Autonomic dysfunction in 'long COVID': rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin Med (Lond) 2021;21:e63&#x2013;e67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleming MA 2nd, Ehsan L, Moore SR, Levin DE. The Enteric Nervous System and Its Emerging Role as a Therapeutic Target. Gastroenterol Res Pract. 2020;2020:8024171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7495222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32963521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furness JB. The enteric nervous system and neurogastroenterology. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2012;9:286&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22392290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nezami BG, Srinivasan S. Enteric nervous system in the small intestine: pathophysiology and clinical implications. Curr Gastroenterol Rep. 2010;12:358&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3752592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20725870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browning KN, Travagli RA. Central nervous system control of gastrointestinal motility and secretion and modulation of gastrointestinal functions. Compr Physiol. 2014;4:1339&#x2013;1368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4858318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25428846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeulen W, De Man JG, Pelckmans PA, De Winter BY. Neuroanatomy of lower &#x200e;gastrointestinal pain disorders. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20:1005&#x2013;1020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3921524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24574773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altaf MA, Sood MR. The nervous system and gastrointestinal function. Dev Disabil Res Rev. 2008;14:87&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18646012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali MK, Saha S, Milkova N, Liu L, Sharma K, Huizinga JD, Chen JH. Modulation of the &#x200e;autonomic nervous system by one session of spinal low-level laser therapy in patients with &#x200e;chronic colonic motility dysfunction. Front Neurosci. 2022;16:882602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9477245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36117615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniela M, Catalina L, Ilie O, Paula M, Daniel-Andrei I, Ioana B. Effects of Exercise Training on the Autonomic Nervous System with a Focus on Anti-Inflammatory and Antioxidants Effects. Antioxidants (Basel) 2022;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8868289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35204231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhri O, Small C, Bloom S. Gastrointestinal hormones regulating appetite. Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci. 2006;361:1187&#x2013;1209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1642697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16815798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips RJ, Powley TL. Innervation of the gastrointestinal tract: patterns of aging. Auton Neurosci. 2007;136:1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2045700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17537681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carod-Artal FJ. Infectious diseases causing autonomic dysfunction. Clin Auton Res. 2018;28:67&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28730326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B, Guo H, Zhou P, Shi ZL. Characteristics of SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2021;19:141&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention: Long COVID or Post-COVID Conditions. &#x200e;Available at: Long COVID or Post-COVID Conditions | CDC last accessed on 7th of April &#x200e;&#x200e;2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundar Shrestha D, Love R. Long COVID Patient Symptoms and its Evaluation and Management. JNMA J Nepal Med Assoc. 2021;59:823&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9107834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34508486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohn MK, Hall A, Sepiashvili L, Jung B, Steele S, Adeli K. Pathophysiology of COVID-19: Mechanisms Underlying Disease Severity and Progression. Physiology (Bethesda) 2020;35:288&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7426542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32783610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Li Y, Liu Q, Yao Q, Wang X, Zhang H, Chen R, Ren L, Min J, Deng F, Yan B, Liu L, Hu Z, Wang M, Zhou Y. SARS-CoV-2 cell tropism and multiorgan infection. Cell Discov. 2021;7:17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7987126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33758165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi F, Qian S, Zhang S, Zhang Z. Single cell RNA sequencing of 13 human tissues identify cell types and receptors of human coronaviruses. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2020;526:135&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32199615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Kang Z, Gong H, Xu D, Wang J, Li Zhixiu, Li Zifu, Cui X, Xiao J, Zhan J, Meng T, &#x200e;Zhou W, Liu J, Xu H. Digestive system is a potential route of COVID-19: an analysis of &#x200e;single-cell coexpression pattern of key proteins in viral entry process. Gut. 2020;69:1010&#x2013;&#x200e;&#x200e;1018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hikmet F, M&#xe9;ar L, Edvinsson &#xc5;, Micke P, Uhl&#xe9;n M, Lindskog C. The protein expression profile of ACE2 in human tissues. Mol Syst Biol. 2020;16:e9610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed NK, Al-Biltagi M, Bediwy AS. Molecular Testing for COVID-19: What the Clinician &#x200e;Should Know. Dr. SulaimanAl Habib Medical Journal 2021; 53-59 [DOI: &#x200e;&#x200e;10.2991/dsahmj.k.210427.002] &#x200e;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer L, Laksono BM, de Vrij FMS, Kushner SA, Harschnitz O, van Riel D. The neuroinvasiveness, neurotropism, and neurovirulence of SARS-CoV-2. Trends Neurosci. 2022;45:358&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8890977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35279295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Felice FG, Tovar-Moll F, Moll J, Munoz DP, Ferreira ST. Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) and the Central Nervous System. Trends Neurosci. 2020;43:355&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32359765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanson PA 2nd, McGavern DB. Viral diseases of the central nervous system. Curr Opin Virol. 2015;11:44&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4456224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25681709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito G, Pesce M, Seguella L, Sanseverino W, Lu J, Sarnelli G. Can the enteric nervous system be an alternative entrance door in SARS-CoV2 neuroinvasion? Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:93&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7179488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32335192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deffner F, Scharr M, Klingenstein S, Klingenstein M, Milazzo A, Scherer S, Wagner A, Hirt B, Mack AF, Neckel PH. Histological Evidence for the Enteric Nervous System and the Choroid Plexus as Alternative Routes of Neuroinvasion by SARS-CoV2. Front Neuroanat. 2020;14:596439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33122999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews MG, Mukhtar T, Eze UC, Simoneau CR, Ross J, Parikshak N, Wang S, Zhou L, Koontz M, Velmeshev D, Siebert CV, Gemenes KM, Tabata T, Perez Y, Wang L, Mostajo-Radji MA, de Majo M, Donohue KC, Shin D, Salma J, Pollen AA, Nowakowski TJ, Ullian E, Kumar GR, Winkler EA, Crouch EE, Ott M, Kriegstein AR. Tropism of SARS-CoV-2 for human cortical astrocytes. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2022;119:e2122236119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9335272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35858406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benny M, Bandstra ES, Saad AG, Lopez-Alberola R, Saigal G, Paidas MJ, Jayakumar AR, Duara S. Maternal SARS-CoV-2, Placental Changes and Brain Injury in 2 Neonates. Pediatrics. 2023;151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10467358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37021494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veleri S. Neurotropism of SARS-CoV-2 and neurological diseases of the central nervous system in COVID-19 patients. Exp Brain Res. 2022;240:9&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8543422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34694467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troisi J, Venutolo G, Pujolassos Tany&#xe0; M, Delli Carri M, Landolfi A, Fasano A. COVID-19 and the gastrointestinal tract: Source of infection or merely a target of the inflammatory process following SARS-CoV-2 infection? World J Gastroenterol. 2021;27:1406&#x2013;1418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8047540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33911464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto T, Perlot T, Rehman A, Trichereau J, Ishiguro H, Paolino M, Sigl V, Hanada T, Hanada R, Lipinski S, Wild B, Camargo SM, Singer D, Richter A, Kuba K, Fukamizu A, Schreiber S, Clevers H, Verrey F, Rosenstiel P, Penninger JM. ACE2 links amino acid malnutrition to microbial ecology and intestinal inflammation. Nature. 2012;487:477&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22837003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Rigatto K, Gazzana MB, Knorst MM, Richards EM, Pepine CJ, Raizada MK. Altered Gut Microbiome Profile in Patients With Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension. Hypertension. 2020;75:1063&#x2013;1071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7067661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32088998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villapol S. Gastrointestinal symptoms associated with COVID-19: impact on the gut microbiome. Transl Res. 2020;226:57&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7438210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32827705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed NK, Al-Beltagi M, Bediwy AS, El-Sawaf Y, Toema O. Gut microbiota in various childhood disorders: Implication and indications. World J Gastroenterol. 2022;28:1875&#x2013;1901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9150060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35664966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marasco G, Lenti MV, Cremon C, Barbaro MR, Stanghellini V, Di Sabatino A, Barbara G. Implications of SARS-CoV-2 infection for neurogastroenterology. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2021;33:e14104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7995160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33591607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao R, Qiu Y, He JS, Tan JY, Li XH, Liang J, Shen J, Zhu LR, Chen Y, Iacucci M, Ng SC, Ghosh S, Chen MH. Manifestations and prognosis of gastrointestinal and liver involvement in patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;5:667&#x2013;678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7217643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32405603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chigr F, Merzouki M, Najimi M. Autonomic Brain Centers and Pathophysiology of COVID-19. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2020;11:1520&#x2013;1522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32427468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldstein LR, Rose EB, Horwitz SM, Collins JP, Newhams MM, Son MBF, Newburger JW, Kleinman LC, Heidemann SM, Martin AA, Singh AR, Li S, Tarquinio KM, Jaggi P, Oster ME, Zackai SP, Gillen J, Ratner AJ, Walsh RF, Fitzgerald JC, Keenaghan MA, Alharash H, Doymaz S, Clouser KN, Giuliano JS Jr, Gupta A, Parker RM, Maddux AB, Havalad V, Ramsingh S, Bukulmez H, Bradford TT, Smith LS, Tenforde MW, Carroll CL, Riggs BJ, Gertz SJ, Daube A, Lansell A, Coronado Munoz A, Hobbs CV, Marohn KL, Halasa NB, Patel MM, Randolph AG Overcoming COVID-19 Investigators; CDC COVID-19 Response Team. Multisystem Inflammatory Syndrome in U.S. Children and Adolescents. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:334&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7346765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32598831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L, Jiang X, Zhang Z, Huang S, Fang Z, Gu Z, Gao L, Shi H, Mai L, Liu Y, Lin X, Lai R, Yan Z, Li X, Shan H. Gastrointestinal symptoms of 95 cases with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Gut. 2020;69:997&#x2013;1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32241899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhayana R, Som A, Li MD, Carey DE, Anderson MA, Blake MA, Catalano O, Gee MS, Hahn PF, Harisinghani M, Kilcoyne A, Lee SI, Mojtahed A, Pandharipande PV, Pierce TT, Rosman DA, Saini S, Samir AE, Simeone JF, Gervais DA, Velmahos G, Misdraji J, Kambadakone A. Abdominal Imaging Findings in COVID-19: Preliminary Observations. Radiology. 2020;297:E207&#x2013;E215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32391742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga Z, Flammer AJ, Steiger P, Haberecker M, Andermatt R, Zinkernagel AS, Mehra MR, Schuepbach RA, Ruschitzka F, Moch H. Endothelial cell infection and endotheliitis in COVID-19. Lancet. 2020;395:1417&#x2013;1418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Y, Rong L. Letter: gastrointestinal symptoms pre-admission are associated with greater severity of COVID-19-authors' reply. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2020;52:1231&#x2013;1232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33016539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Laurent S, Onur OA, Kleineberg NN, Fink GR, Schweitzer F, Warnke C. A systematic review of neurological symptoms and complications of COVID-19. J Neurol. 2021;268:392&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7370630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32691236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-S&#xe1;nchez CM, D&#xed;az-Maroto I, Fern&#xe1;ndez-D&#xed;az E, S&#xe1;nchez-Larsen &#xc1;, Layos-Romero A, Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a J, Gonz&#xe1;lez E, Redondo-Pe&#xf1;as I, Perona-Moratalla AB, Del Valle-P&#xe9;rez JA, Gracia-Gil J, Rojas-Bartolom&#xe9; L, Feria-Vilar I, Monteagudo M, Palao M, Palaz&#xf3;n-Garc&#xed;a E, Alcahut-Rodr&#xed;guez C, Sopelana-Garay D, Moreno Y, Ahmad J, Segura T. Neurologic manifestations in hospitalized patients with COVID-19: The ALBACOVID registry. Neurology. 2020;95:e1060&#x2013;e1070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7668545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32482845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jammoul M, Naddour J, Madi A, Reslan MA, Hatoum F, Zeineddine J, Abou-Kheir W, Lawand N. Investigating the possible mechanisms of autonomic dysfunction post-COVID-19. Auton Neurosci. 2023;245:103071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9789535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36580747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmona-Torre F, M&#xed;nguez-Olaondo A, L&#xf3;pez-Bravo A, Tijero B, Grozeva V, Walcker M, &#x200e;Azkune-Galparsoro H, L&#xf3;pez de Munain A, Alcaide AB, Quiroga J, Del Pozo JL, G&#xf3;mez-&#x200e;Esteban JC. Dysautonomia in COVID-19 Patients: A Narrative Review on Clinical Course, &#x200e;Diagnostic and Therapeutic Strategies. Front Neurol . 2022;13:886609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9198643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35720084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, Cook JR, Nordvig AS, Shalev D, Sehrawat TS, Ahluwalia N, Bikdeli B, Dietz D, Der-Nigoghossian C, Liyanage-Don N, Rosner GF, Bernstein EJ, Mohan S, Beckley AA, Seres DS, Choueiri TK, Uriel N, Ausiello JC, Accili D, Freedberg DE, Baldwin M, Schwartz A, Brodie D, Garcia CK, Elkind MSV, Connors JM, Bilezikian JP, Landry DW, Wan EY. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdal Y, Atalar AC, Gunes T, Okluoglu T, Yavuz N, Emre U. Autonomic dysfunction in patients with COVID-19. Acta Neurol Belg. 2022;122:885&#x2013;891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8891732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35239131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varma-Doyle A, Villemarette-Pittman NR, Lelorier P, England J. Demonstrating new-onset or worsened sudomotor function post-COVID-19 on comparative analysis of autonomic function pre-and post-SARS-CoV-2 infection. eNeurologicalSci. 2023;30:100445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9877150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36718227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scala I, Bellavia S, Luigetti M, Brunetti V, Broccolini A, Gabrielli M, Zileri Dal Verme L, Calabresi P, Della Marca G, Frisullo G. Autonomic dysfunction in non-critically ill COVID-19 patients during the acute phase of disease: an observational, cross-sectional study. Neurol Sci. 2022;43:4635&#x2013;4643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35608736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan ND, Qiu Y, Xing XB, Ghosh S, Chen MH, Mao R. Associations Between Angiotensin-Converting Enzyme Inhibitors and Angiotensin II Receptor Blocker Use, Gastrointestinal Symptoms, and Mortality Among Patients With COVID-19. Gastroenterology. 2020;159:1170&#x2013;1172.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyoju SK, Zaborina O, van Goor H. SARS-CoV-2 and the sympathetic immune response: Dampening inflammation with antihypertensive drugs (Clonidine and Propranolol) Med Hypotheses. 2020;144:110039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32758881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porzionato A, Emmi A, Barbon S, Boscolo-Berto R, Stecco C, Stocco E, Macchi V, De Caro R. Sympathetic activation: a potential link between comorbidities and COVID-19. FEBS J. 2020;287:3681&#x2013;3688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7405290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32779891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz T, Szeles JC, Kitzberger R, Holbik J, Grieb A, Wolf H, Akyaman H, Lucny F, Tychera A, Neuhold S, Zoufaly A, Wenisch C, Kaniusas E. Percutaneous Auricular Vagus Nerve Stimulation Reduces Inflammation in Critical Covid-19 Patients. Front Physiol. 2022;13:897257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9289290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35860660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Kuraishy HM, Al-Gareeb AI, Qusti S, Alshammari EM, Gyebi GA, Batiha GE. Covid-19-Induced Dysautonomia: A Menace of Sympathetic Storm. ASN Neuro. 2021;13:17590914211057635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8586167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34755562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasanthakumar N. Beta-Adrenergic Blockers as a Potential Treatment for COVID-19 Patients. Bioessays. 2020;42:e2000094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7460992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32815593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Beltagi M, Saeed NK, Bediwy AS. COVID-19 disease and autoimmune disorders: A mutual pathway. World J Methodol. 2022;12:200&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9350728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36159097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadda KR, Blakey EE, Huang CL, Jeevaratnam K. Long COVID-19 and Postural Orthostatic Tachycardia Syndrome- Is Dysautonomia to Be Blamed? Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9:860198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8959615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35355961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavi Y, Vojdani A, Halpert G, Sharif K, Ostrinski Y, Zyskind I, Lattin MT, Zimmerman J, Silverberg JI, Rosenberg AZ, Shoenfeld Y, Amital H. Dysregulated Levels of Circulating Autoantibodies against Neuronal and Nervous System Autoantigens in COVID-19 Patients. Diagnostics (Basel) 2023;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9955917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36832180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson RW, Brown RL, Benjamin L, Nortley R, Wiethoff S, Bharucha T, Jayaseelan DL, &#x200e;Kumar G, Raftopoulos RE, Zambreanu L, Vivekanandam V, Khoo A, Geraldes R, &#x200e;Chinthapalli K, Boyd E, Tuzlali H, Price G, Christofi G, Morrow J, McNamara P, &#x200e;McLoughlin B, Lim ST, Mehta PR, Levee V, Keddie S, Yong W, Trip SA, Foulkes AJM, Hotton &#x200e;G, Miller TD, Everitt AD, Carswell C, Davies NWS, Yoong M, Attwell D, Sreedharan J, &#x200e;Silber E, Schott JM, Chandratheva A, Perry RJ, Simister R, Checkley A, Longley N, Farmer &#x200e;SF, Carletti F, Houlihan C, Thom M, Lunn MP, Spillane J, Howard R, Vincent A, Werring DJ, &#x200e;Hoskote C, J&#xe4;ger HR, Manji H, Zandi MS. The emerging spectrum of COVID-19 neurology: &#x200e;clinical, radiological and laboratory findings. Brain . 2020;143:3104&#x2013;3120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32637987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cholankeril G, Podboy A, Aivaliotis VI, Tarlow B, Pham EA, Spencer SP, Kim D, Hsing A, Ahmed A. High Prevalence of Concurrent Gastrointestinal Manifestations in Patients With Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2: Early Experience From California. Gastroenterology. 2020;159:775&#x2013;777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32283101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chigr F, Merzouki M, Najimi M. Comment on "The neuroinvasive potential of SARS-CoV-2 may play a role in the respiratory failure of COVID-19 patients". J Med Virol. 2020;92:703&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32352575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafra MA, Ag&#xfc;era AD, Molina F, Puerto A. Relevance of the nucleus of the solitary tract, gelatinous part, in learned preferences induced by intragastric nutrient administration. Appetite. 2017;118:90&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28789870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Follmer C. Gut Microbiome Imbalance and Neuroinflammation: Impact of COVID-19 on Parkinson's Disease. Mov Disord. 2020;35:1495&#x2013;1496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32822087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghazanfar H, Kandhi S, Shin D, Muthumanickam A, Gurjar H, Qureshi ZA, Shaban M, Farag M, Haider A, Budhathoki P, Bhatt T, Ghazanfar A, Jyala A, Patel H. Impact of COVID-19 on the Gastrointestinal Tract: A Clinical Review. Cureus. 2022;14:e23333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9017282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35464519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai Y, Qiang W, Gui Y, Tan X, Pei T, Lin K, Cai S, Sun L, Ning G, Wang J, Guo H, Sun Y, Cheng J, Xie L, Lan X, Wang D. A large-scale transcriptional study reveals inhibition of COVID-19 related cytokine storm by traditional Chinese medicines. Sci Bull (Beijing) 2021;66:884&#x2013;888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7803147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33457042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahgoub S, Kotb El-Sayed MI, El-Shehry MF, Mohamed Awad S, Mansour YE, Fatahala SS. Synthesis of novel calcium channel blockers with ACE2 inhibition and dual antihypertensive/anti-inflammatory effects: A possible therapeutic tool for COVID-19. Bioorg Chem. 2021;116:105272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8403975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34474305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofman K, Shenoy GN, Chak V, Balu-Iyer SV. Pharmaceutical Aspects and Clinical &#x200e;Evaluation of COVID-19 Vaccines. Immunol Invest. 2021;50:743&#x2013;779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8095160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33929280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg RK, Paliwal VK. Spectrum of neurological complications following COVID-19 vaccination. Neurol Sci. 2022;43:3&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8557950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34719776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermel M, Sweeney M, Abud E, Luskin K, Criado JP, Bonakdar R, Gray J, Ahern T. COVID-19 Vaccination Might Induce Postural Orthostatic Tachycardia Syndrome: A Case Report. Vaccines (Basel) 2022;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9323926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35891154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy S, Reddy S, Arora M. A Case of Postural Orthostatic Tachycardia Syndrome Secondary to the Messenger RNA COVID-19 Vaccine. Cureus. 2021;13:e14837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8101507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33968543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanman TA, Wu C, Cheung H, Goyal N, Greene M. Guillain-Barr&#xe9; Syndrome with Rapid Onset and Autonomic Dysfunction Following First Dose of Pfizer-BioNTech COVID-19 Vaccine: A Case Report. Neurohospitalist. 2022;12:388&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8977423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35401916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldokla AM, Numan MT. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome after mRNA COVID-19 vaccine. Clin Auton Res. 2022;32:307&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9308031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35870086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>83-&#x200e; Tahir N, Koorapati G, Prasad S, Jeelani HM, Sherchan R, Shrestha J, Shayuk M. SARS-CoV-2 &#x200e;Vaccination-Induced Transverse Myelitis. Cureus. 2021 Jul 25;13(7):e16624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8384391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34458035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilts A, Schreiber A, Singh A. A Clinical Case of COVID-19 Vaccine-Associated Guillain-Barr&#xe9; Syndrome. Am J Case Rep. 2022;23:e936896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9377719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35945825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzsimmons W, Nance CS.  Sudden Onset of Myelitis after COVID-19 &#x200e;Vaccination: An Under-Recognized Severe Rare Adverse Event. Cited May 2021. Available from: https://europepmc.org/article/PPR/PPR342408 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akaishi T, Onodera T, Takahashi T, Harigae H, Ishii T. Reports of acute adverse events in mRNA COVID-19 vaccine recipients after the first and second doses in Japan. Sci Rep. 2022;12:15510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9476447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36109582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Penfold RS, Merino J, Sudre CH, Molteni E, Berry S, Canas LS, Graham MS, Klaser K, Modat M, Murray B, Kerfoot E, Chen L, Deng J, &#xd6;sterdahl MF, Cheetham NJ, Drew DA, Nguyen LH, Pujol JC, Hu C, Selvachandran S, Polidori L, May A, Wolf J, Chan AT, Hammers A, Duncan EL, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk factors and disease profile of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection in UK users of the COVID Symptom Study app: a prospective, community-based, nested, case-control study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:43&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34480857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freise NF, Kivel M, Grebe O, Meyer C, Wafaisade B, Peiper M, Zeus T, Schmidt J, Neuwahl J, Jazmati D, Luedde T, B&#xf6;lke E, Feldt T, Jensen BEO, Bode J, Keitel V, Haussmann J, Tamaskovics B, Budach W, Fischer JC, Knoefel WT, Schneider M, Gerber PA, Pedoto A, H&#xe4;ussinger D, van Griensven M, Rezazadeh A, Flaig Y, Kirchner J, Antoch G, Schelzig H, Matuschek C. Acute cardiac side effects after COVID-19 mRNA vaccination: a case series. Eur J Med Res. 2022;27:80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9160507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35655235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naeem FN, Hasan SFS, Ram MD, Waseem S, Ahmed SH, Shaikh TG. The association between SARS-CoV-2 vaccines and transverse myelitis: A review. Ann Med Surg (Lond) 2022;79:103870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9181565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35702684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takase B, Hayashi K, Takei S, Hisada T, Masaki N, Nagata M. Delayed Vasovagal Reaction with Reflex Syncope Following COVID-19 Vaccination. Intern Med. 2022;61:2167&#x2013;2170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9381344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35569982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung KS, Hung IFN, Chan PPY, Lung KC, Tso E, Liu R, Ng YY, Chu MY, Chung TWH, Tam AR, Yip CCY, Leung KH, Fung AY, Zhang RR, Lin Y, Cheng HM, Zhang AJX, To KKW, Chan KH, Yuen KY, Leung WK. Gastrointestinal Manifestations of SARS-CoV-2 Infection and Virus Load in Fecal Samples From a Hong Kong Cohort: Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Gastroenterology. 2020;159:81&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Settanni CR, Ianiro G, Ponziani FR, Bibb&#xf2; S, Segal JP, Cammarota G, Gasbarrini A. COVID-19 as a trigger of irritable bowel syndrome: A review of potential mechanisms. World J Gastroenterol. 2021;27:7433&#x2013;7445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8613742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34887641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez C, Luque N, Blanco I, Sebastian L, Barber&#xe0; JA, Peinado VI, Tura-Ceide O. Pulmonary Endothelial Dysfunction and Thrombotic Complications in Patients with COVID-19. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol. 2021;64:407&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33180562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassani M, Fathi Jouzdani A, Motarjem S, Ranjbar A, Khansari N. How COVID-19 can cause autonomic dysfunctions and postural orthostatic syndrome? A Review of mechanisms and evidence. Neurol Clin Neurosci. 2021;9:434&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34909198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipriano M, Ruberti E, Giacalone A. Gastrointestinal Infection Could Be New Focus for Coronavirus Diagnosis. Cureus. 2020;12:e7422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7186097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32351807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira N, Mikocka-Walus A, van Tilburg MAL, Graff LA, Apputhurai P, Barreiro-de Acosta M, Bennebroek Evertsz F, Burisch J, Lo B, Petrik M, Trindade IA, Jedel S, Moser G, Mokrowiecka A, Bernstein CN, Dumitrascu D, Ford AC, Stengel A, Gearry R, Knowles SR. The impact of the coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic on individuals with gastrointestinal disorders: A protocol of an international collaborative study. J Psychosom Res. 2021;148:110561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8240440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34217956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt RH, East JE, Lanas A, Malfertheiner P, Satsangi J, Scarpignato C, Webb GJ. COVID-19 and Gastrointestinal Disease: Implications for the Gastroenterologist. Dig Dis. 2021;39:119&#x2013;139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7705947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33040064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogariu AM, Dumitrascu DL. Digestive involvement in the Long-COVID syndrome. Med Pharm Rep. 2022;95:5&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9177081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35720240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S, Whiteson JH, Abramoff B, Azola A, Bartels MN, Bhavaraju-Sanka R, Chung T, Fleming TK, Henning E, Miglis MG, Sampsel S, Silver JK, Tosto J, Verduzco-Gutierrez M, Putrino D. Multi-disciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of autonomic dysfunction in patients with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) PM R. 2022;14:1270&#x2013;1291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36169154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shouman K, Vanichkachorn G, Cheshire WP, Suarez MD, Shelly S, Lamotte GJ, Sandroni P, Benarroch EE, Berini SE, Cutsforth-Gregory JK, Coon EA, Mauermann ML, Low PA, Singer W. Autonomic dysfunction following COVID-19 infection: an early experience. Clin Auton Res. 2021;31:385&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8050227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33860871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheshire WP Jr, Goldstein DS. The physical examination as a window into autonomic disorders. Clin Auton Res. 2018;28:23&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8921977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29294184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westergren A, Wictorin K, Hansson O, Hagell P. Novel insights regarding the measurement properties of the SCOPA-AUT. BMC Neurol. 2022;22:478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9746092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36514012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellami L, Kacem I, Nasri A, Djebara MB, Sidhom Y, Gargouri A, Gouider R. Evaluation of an Arabic version of the non-motor symptoms scale in Parkinson's disease. Neurol Sci. 2016;37:963&#x2013;968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26932938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goudouris ES. Laboratory diagnosis of COVID-19. J Pediatr (Rio J) 2021;97:7&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7456621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32882235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourbagheri-Sigaroodi A, Bashash D, Fateh F, Abolghasemi H. Laboratory findings in &#x200e;COVID-19 diagnosis and prognosis. Clin Chim Acta. 2020;510:475&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7426219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32798514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez C, Marco A, Nogales A, Tebar R. Total and segmental colonic transit time and anorectal manometry in children with chronic idiopathic constipation. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2002;35:31&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12142807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zygmunt A, Stanczyk J. Methods of evaluation of autonomic nervous system function. Arch Med Sci. 2010;6:11&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3278937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22371714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Illigens BM, Gibbons CH. Sweat testing to evaluate autonomic function. Clin Auton Res. 2009;19:79&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3046462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18989618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrysant SG. The tilt table test is useful for the diagnosis of vasovagal syncope and should not be abolished. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2020;22:686&#x2013;689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8030070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32248628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peixoto A, Silva M, Pereira P, Macedo G. Biopsies in Gastrointestinal Endoscopy: When and How. GE Port J Gastroenterol. 2016;23:19&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5580003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28868426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelms DW, Kann BR. Imaging Modalities for Evaluation of Intestinal Obstruction. Clin Colon Rectal Surg. 2021;34:205&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8292005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34305469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caraiani C, Yi D, Petresc B, Dietrich C. Indications for abdominal imaging: When and what to choose? J Ultrason. 2020;20:e43&#x2013;e54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7266076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32320166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin S, Lu X, Xu C. COVID-19 induces gastrointestinal symptoms and affects patients' prognosis. J Int Med Res. 2022;50:3000605221129543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9575454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36238995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>