<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36148558</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1819</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>77</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Psychiatry and clinical neurosciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Psychiatry Clin Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neurological post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>72</StartPage><EndPage>83</EndPage><MedlinePgn>72-83</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/pcn.13481</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The novel coronavirus disease 19 (COVID-19), caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), can have two phases: acute (generally 4&#x2009;weeks after onset) and chronic (&gt;4&#x2009;weeks after onset). Both phases include a wide variety of signs and symptoms including neurological and psychiatric symptoms. The signs and symptoms that are considered sequelae of COVID-19 are termed post-COVID condition, long COVID-19, and post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC). PASC symptoms include fatigue, dyspnea, palpitation, dysosmia, subfever, hypertension, alopecia, sleep problems, loss of concentration, amnesia, numbness, pain, gastrointestinal symptoms, depression, and anxiety. Because the specific pathophysiology of PASC has not yet been clarified, there are no definite criteria of the condition, hence the World Health Organization's definition is quite broad. Consequently, it is difficult to correctly diagnose PASC. Approximately 50% of patients may show at least one PASC symptom up to 12&#xa0;months after COVID-19 infection; however, the exact prevalence of PASC has not been determined. Despite extensive research in progress worldwide, there are currently no clear diagnostic methodologies or treatments for PASC. In this review, we discuss the currently available information on PASC and highlight the neurological sequelae of COVID-19 infection. Furthermore, we provide clinical suggestions for diagnosing and caring for patients with PASC based on our outpatient clinic experience.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Psychiatry and Clinical Neurosciences published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd on behalf of Japanese Society of Psychiatry and Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takao</LastName><ForeName>Masaki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5392-996X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory and Internal Medicine, National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry (NCNP), National Center Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohira</LastName><ForeName>Masayuki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory and Internal Medicine, National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry (NCNP), National Center Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>3-8</GrantID><Agency>Intramural fund from NCNP</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>22dk0307115h0001</GrantID><Agency>Japan Agency for Medical Research and Development</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JP21wm0425019</GrantID><Agency>Japan Agency for Medical Research and Development</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>18K06506</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>21K06417</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>22H04923</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>NCNP</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>the Research Committee of Prion Disease and Slow Virus Infection</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Slow V</GrantID><Agency>Health and Labour Sciences Research Grants</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare, Japan</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Psychiatry Clin Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9513551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1323-1316</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000554" MajorTopicYN="N">Ambulatory Care Facilities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurological disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36148558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pcn.13481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Al-Sarraj S, Troakes C, Hanley B et al. Invited review: The spectrum of neuropathology in COVID-19. Neuropathol. Appl. Neurobiol. 2021; 47: 3-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Divani AA, Andalib S, Biller J et al. Central nervous system manifestations associated with COVID-19. Curr. Neurol. Neurosci. Rep. 2020; 20: 60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidar MA, Jourdi H, Haj Hassan Z et al. Neurological and neuropsychological changes associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection: New observations, new mechanisms. Neuroscientist 2021. https://doi.org/10.1177/1073858420984106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi M, Sahashi Y, Baba Y, Okura H, Shimohata T. COVID-19-associated mild encephalitis/encephalopathy with a reversible splenial lesion. J. Neurol. Sci. 2020; 415: 116941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J, Kremer S, Merdji H et al. Neurologic features in severe SARS-CoV-2 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020; 382: 2268-2270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homma Y, Watanabe M, Inoue K, Moritaka T. Coronavirus disease-19 pneumonia with facial nerve palsy and olfactory disturbance. Intern. Med. 2020; 59: 1773-1775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iadecola C, Anrather J, Kamel H. Effects of COVID-19 on the nervous system. Cell 2020; 183: 16-27.e11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M et al. Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol. 2020; 77: 683-690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro E, Priori A, Beghi E et al. The international European academy of neurology survey on neurological symptoms in patients with COVID-19 infection. Eur. J. Neurol. 2020; 27: 1727-1737.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valiuddin HM, Kalajdzic A, Rosati J, Boehm K, Hill D. Update on neurological manifestations of SARS-CoV-2. West. J. Emerg. Med. 2020; 21: 45-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wada S, Nagasaki Y, Arimizu Y et al. Neurological disorders identified during treatment of a SARS-CoV-2 infection. Intern. Med. 2020; 59: 2187-2189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera JA, Sabadia S, Lalchan R et al. A prospective study of neurologic disorders in hospitalized COVID-19 patients in New York City. Neurology 2021; 96: e575-e586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong W, Mu J, Guo J et al. New onset neurologic events in people with COVID-19 in 3 regions in China. Neurology 2020; 95: e1479-e1487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature 2021; 594: 259-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam MH, Wing YK, Yu MW et al. Mental morbidities and chronic fatigue in severe acute respiratory syndrome survivors: Long-term follow-up. Arch. Intern. Med. 2009; 169: 2142-2147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moldofsky H, Patcai J. Chronic widespread musculoskeletal pain, fatigue, depression and disordered sleep in chronic post-SARS syndrome; a case-controlled study. BMC Neurol. 2011; 11: 37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat. Med. 2021; 27: 601-615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Husain M, Harrison PJ. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: A 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 2021; 18: e1003773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236&#x2009;379 survivors of COVID-19: A retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry 2021; 8: 416-427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F, Gemelli against C-P-ACSG. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA 2020; 324: 603-605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couzin-Frankel J. The long haul. Science 2020; 369: 614-617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng N, Zhao YM, Yan W et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of long term physical and mental sequelae of COVID-19 pandemic: Call for research priority and action. Mol. Psychiatry 2022. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41380-022-01614-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE et al. Short-term and long-term rates of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: A systematic review. JAMA Netw. Open 2021; 4: e2128568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Munblit D, Pazukhina E et al. Post-COVID condition in adults and children living in the same household in Italy: A prospective cohort study using the ISARIC global follow-up protocol. Front. Pediatr. 2022; 10: 834875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efstathiou V, Stefanou MI, Demetriou M et al. Long COVID and neuropsychiatric manifestations (review). Exp. Ther. Med. 2022; 23: 363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KG-I, Brokstad KA et al. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat. Med. 2021; 27: 1607-1613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Coronavirus disease (COVID-19): Post COVID-19 condition. [cited 15 July 2022.] Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/questions-and-answers/item/coronavirus-disease-(covid-19)-post-covid-19-condition#:~:text=People%20with%20post%20COVID%2D19,as%20work%20or%20household%20chores.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill E, Mehta H, Sharma S et al. Risk factors associated with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 in an EHR cohort: A national COVID cohort collaborative (N3C) analysis as part of the NIH RECOVER program. medRxiv 2022. https://doi.org/10.1101/2022.08.15.22278603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijeratne T, Crewther S. Post-COVID 19 neurological syndrome (PCNS); a novel syndrome with challenges for the global neurology community. J. Neurol. Sci. 2020; 419: 117179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takao M. Important and unresolved aspects of neuropathologic analyses of COVID-19 individuals (in Japanese). Brain Nerve 2020; 72: 1061-1065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takao M, Ohira M. Outpatient clinic for long COVID (in Japanese). Brain Nerve 2022; 74: 885-891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favas TT, Dev P, Chaurasia RN et al. Neurological manifestations of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis of proportions. Neurol. Sci. 2020; 41: 3437-3470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-S&#xe1;nchez CM, D&#xed;az-Maroto I, Fern&#xe1;ndez-D&#xed;az E et al. Neurologic manifestations in hospitalized patients with COVID-19: The ALBACOVID registry. Neurology 2020; 95: e1060-e1070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liotta EM, Batra A, Clark JR et al. Frequent neurologic manifestations and encephalopathy-associated morbidity in COVID-19 patients. Ann. Clin. Transl. Neurol. 2020; 7: 2221-2230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon L, Varley J, Gontsarova A et al. COVID-19-related acute necrotizing encephalopathy with brain stem involvement in a patient with aplastic anemia. Neurol. Neuroimmunol. Neuroinflamm. 2020; 7: e789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poyiadji N, Shahin G, Noujaim D, Stone M, Patel S, Griffith B. COVID-19-associated acute hemorrhagic necrotizing encephalopathy: Imaging features. Radiology 2020; 296: E119-E120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virhammar J, Kumlien E, F&#xe4;llmar D et al. Acute necrotizing encephalopathy with SARS-CoV-2 RNA confirmed in cerebrospinal fluid. Neurology 2020; 95: 445-449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichard RR, Kashani KB, Boire NA, Constantopoulos E, Guo Y, Lucchinetti CF. Neuropathology of COVID-19: A spectrum of vascular and acute disseminated encephalomyelitis (ADEM)-like pathology. Acta Neuropathol. 2020; 140: 1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parauda SC, Gao V, Gewirtz AN et al. Posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome in patients with COVID-19. J. Neurol. Sci. 2020; 416: 117019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulko E, Oleksk ML, Gomes W et al. MRI brain findings in 126 patients with COVID-19: Initial observations from a descriptive literature review. Am. J. Neuroradiol. 2020; 41: 2199-2203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou JJ, Movassaghi M, Gordy D et al. Neuropathology of COVID-19 (neuro-COVID): Clinicopathological update. Free Neuropathol. 2021; 2: 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) clinical case definition working group on post COVID-19 condition. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021. [cited 15 July 2022.] Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, Nicholson T, Akrami A et al. A core outcome set for post-COVID-19 condition in adults for use in clinical practice and research: An international Delphi consensus study. Lancet Respir. Med. 2022; 10: 715-724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sneller MC, Liang CJ, Marques AR et al. A longitudinal study of COVID-19 sequelae and immunity: Baseline findings. Ann. Intern. Med 2022; 175: 969-979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navaratnam AMD, Shrotri M, Nguyen V et al. Nucleocapsid and spike antibody responses post virologically confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection: An observational analysis in the virus watch community cohort. Int. J. Infect. Dis. 2022; 123: 104-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaff ER, Girvin AT, Bennett TD et al. Identifying who has long COVID in the USA: A machine learning approach using N3C data. Lancet Digit. Health 2022; 4: e532-e541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T, Hittle M, Goodman SN. Assessment of the frequency and variety of persistent symptoms among patients with COVID-19: A systematic review. JAMA Netw. Open 2021; 4: e2111417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PHOSP-COVID Collaborative Group. Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: A prospective observational study. Lancet Respir. Med. 2022; 10: 761-775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali ST, Kang AK, Patel TR et al. Evolution of neurologic symptoms in non-hospitalized COVID-19 "long haulers". Ann. Clin. Transl. Neurol. 2022; 9: 950-961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazato Y, Tsuzuki S, Morioka S et al. Factors associated with development and persistence of post-COVID conditions: A cross-sectional study. J. Infect. Chemother. 2022; 28: 1242-1248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell 2022; 185: 881-895.e20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meulin VT, Massa PT, Dorries R. Coronaviruses. In: Vinken PJ, Bruyn GW, Klawans HL (eds). Handbook of Clinical Neurology. Elsevier Science Publishers, Amsterdam, 1989; 439-451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora-D&#xed;az JC, Pi&#xf1;eyro PE, Houston E, Zimmerman J, Gim&#xe9;nez-Lirola LG. Porcine hemagglutinating encephalomyelitis virus: A review. Front. Vet. Sci. 2019; 6: 53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stohlman SA, Hinton DR. Viral induced demyelination. Brain Pathol. 2001; 11: 92-106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J, Radke J, Dittmayer C et al. Olfactory transmucosal SARS-CoV-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with COVID-19. Nat. Neurosci. 2021; 24: 168-175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM, Khaleeq A, Ali U, Syeda H. Evidence of the COVID-19 virus targeting the CNS: Tissue distribution, host-virus interaction, and proposed neurotropic mechanisms. ACS Chem. Nerosci. 2020; 11: 995-998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morbini P, Benazzo M, Verga L et al. Ultrastructural evidence of direct viral damage to the olfactory complex in patients testing positive for SARS-CoV-2. JAMA Otolaryngol. Head Neck Surg. 2020; 146: 972-973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paniz-Mondolfi A, Bryce C, Grimes Z et al. Central nervous system involvement by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2). J. Med. Virol. 2020; 92: 699-702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghimi N, Di Napoli M, Biller J et al. The neurological manifestations of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Curr. Neurol. Neurosci. Rep. 2021; 21: 44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M. Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nat. Immunol. 2022; 23: 194-202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tate W, Walker M, Sweetman E et al. Molecular mechanisms of neuroinflammation in ME/CFS and long COVID to sustain disease and promote relapses. Front. Neurol. 2022; 13: 877772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickie I, Davenport T, Wakefield D et al. Post-infective and chronic fatigue syndromes precipitated by viral and non-viral pathogens: Prospective cohort study. BMJ 2006; 333: 575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Weyhern CH, Kaufmann I, Neff F, Kremer M. Early evidence of pronounced brain involvement in fatal COVID-19 outcomes. Lancet 2020; 395: e109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke J, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Hagel C et al. Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: A post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol. 2020; 19: 919-929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryce C, Grimes Z, Pujadas E et al. Pathophysiology of SARS-CoV-2: The Mount Sinai COVID-19 autopsy experience. Mod. Pathol. 2021; 34: 1456-1467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizutani MNY, Saitoh Y, Ariga H et al. Pathologic and neuropathologic study of a case of COVID-19. JMA J 2022; 5: 157-160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MH, Perl DP, Steiner J et al. Neurovascular injury with complement activation and inflammation in COVID-19. Brain 2022; 145: 2555-2568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beraki S, Aronsson F, Karlsson H, Ogren SO, Kristensson K. Influenza a virus infection causes alterations in expression of synaptic regulatory genes combined with changes in cognitive and emotional behaviors in mice. Mol. Psychiatry 2005; 10: 299-308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Sillett R, Zhu L et al. Neurological and psychiatric risk trajectories after SARS-CoV-2 infection: An analysis of 2-year retrospective cohort studies including 1&#x2008;284&#x2008;437 patients. Lancet Psychiatry 2022; 9: 815-827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker JH, Lin JJ, Doernberg M et al. Assessment of cognitive function in patients after COVID-19 infection. JAMA Netw. Open 2021; 4: e2130645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdes E, Fuchs B, Morrison C et al. Demographic and social determinants of cognitive dysfunction following hospitalization for COVID-19. J. Neurol. Sci. 2022; 438: 120146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F et al. SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK biobank. Nature 2022; 604: 697-707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimohata T. Neuro-COVID-19. Clin. Exp. Neuroimmunol. 2022; 13: 17-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelland GW. Gluten-induced cognitive impairment ("brain fog") in coeliac disease. J. Gastroenterol. Hepatol. 2017; 32: 90-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deumer US, Varesi A, Floris V et al. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS): An overview. J. Clin. Med. 2021; 10: 4786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puelles VG, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Lindenmeyer MT et al. Multiorgan and renal tropism of SARS-CoV-2. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020; 383: 590-592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoharides TC, Cholevas C, Polyzoidis K, Politis A. Long-COVID syndrome-associated brain fog and chemofog: Luteolin to the rescue. Biofactors 2021; 47: 232-241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silveira GR, Syed IU. Connecting the dots in emerging mast cell research: Do factors affecting mast cell activation provide a missing link between adverse COVID-19 outcomes and the social determinants of health? Med. Sci. (Basel) 2022; 10: 29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorff SR, Afrin LB. Mast cell activation syndrome in pregnancy, delivery, postpartum and lactation: A narrative review. J. Obstet. Gynaecol. 2020; 40: 889-901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul T, Ledderose S, Bartsch H et al. Adrenal tropism of SARS-CoV-2 and adrenal findings in a post-mortem case series of patients with severe fatal COVID-19. Nat. Commun. 2022; 13: 1589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson RW, Brown RL, Benjamin L et al. The emerging spectrum of COVID-19 neurology: Clinical, radiological and laboratory findings. Brain 2020; 143: 3104-3120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benameur K, Agarwal A, Auld SC et al. Encephalopathy and encephalitis associated with cerebrospinal fluid cytokine alterations and coronavirus disease, Atlanta, Georgia, USA, 2020. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 2020; 26: 2016-2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duong L, Xu P, Liu A. Meningoencephalitis without respiratory failure in a young female patient with COVID-19 infection in downtown Los Angeles, early April 2020. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020; 87: 33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye M, Ren Y, Lv T. Encephalitis as a clinical manifestation of COVID-19. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020; 88: 945-946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hugon J, Msika EF, Queneau M, Farid K, Paquet C. Long COVID: Cognitive complaints (brain fog) and dysfunction of the cingulate cortex. J. Neurol. 2022; 269: 44-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak P, Mukerji SS, Alabsi HS et al. Multisystem involvement in post-acute sequelae of coronavirus disease 19. Ann. Neurol. 2022; 91: 367-379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandadeva D, Young BE, Stephens BY et al. Blunted peripheral but not cerebral vasodilator function in young otherwise healthy adults with persistent symptoms following COVID-19. Am. J. Physiol. Heart Circ. Physiol. 2021; 321: H479-H484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffa RB, Duong PV, Finney J et al. Is 'chemo-fog'/'chemo-brain' caused by cancer chemotherapy? J. Clin. Pharm. Ther. 2006; 31: 129-138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell T, Turton P. 'Chemobrain': Concentration and memory effects in people receiving chemotherapy - A descriptive phenomenological study. Eur. J. Cancer Care (Engl.) 2011; 20: 539-548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wefel JS, Schagen SB. Chemotherapy-related cognitive dysfunction. Curr. Neurol. Neurosci. Rep. 2012; 12: 267-275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietrich J, Monje M, Wefel J, Meyers C. Clinical patterns and biological correlates of cognitive dysfunction associated with cancer therapy. Oncologist 2008; 13: 1285-1295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen LD, Ehrlich BE. Cellular mechanisms and treatments for chemobrain: Insight from aging and neurodegenerative diseases. EMBO Mol. Med. 2020; 12: e12075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang XM, Walitt B, Saligan L, Tiwari AF, Cheung CW, Zhang ZJ. Chemobrain: A critical review and causal hypothesis of link between cytokines and epigenetic reprogramming associated with chemotherapy. Cytokine 2015; 72: 86-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Kim SW, Chang HH, Kwon KT, Hwang S, Bae S. One year follow-up of COVID-19 related symptoms and patient quality of life: A prospective cohort study. Yonsei Med. J. 2022; 63: 499-510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fumagalli C, Zocchi C, Tassetti L et al. Factors associated with persistence of symptoms 1 year after COVID-19: A longitudinal, prospective phone-based interview follow-up cohort study. Eur. J. Intern. Med. 2022; 97: 36-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badenoch JB, Rengasamy ER, Watson C et al. Persistent neuropsychiatric symptoms after COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Commun. 2022; 4: fcab297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: A cohort study. Lancet 2021; 397: 220-232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik S, Haldar SN, Soneja M et al. Post COVID-19 sequelae: A prospective observational study from northern India. Drug Discov.Ther. 2021; 15: 254-260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Torres-Macho J, Velasco-Arribas M et al. Preexisting hypertension is associated with a greater number of long-term post-COVID symptoms and poor sleep quality: A case-control study. J. Hum. Hypertens. 2022; 36: 582-584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Campion JY, Dudouet P et al. (18)F-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in patients with long COVID. Eur. J. Nucl. Med. Mol. Imaging 2021; 48: 2823-2833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, De Lorenzo R, Conte C et al. Anxiety and depression in COVID-19 survivors: Role of inflammatory and clinical predictors. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020; 89: 594-600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamaki T, Oka N, Odaki M, Kobayashi S. Usability of intravenous thiamine injection test compared with odor stick identification test for Japanese patients with severe traumatic brain injury. Auris Nasus Larynx 2020; 47: 233-237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa M, Kamide M, Miwa T, Umeda R. Significance of intravenous olfaction test using thiamine propyldisulfide (Alinamin) in olfactometry. Auris Nasus Larynx 1988; 15: 25-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohira M, Sano T, Takao M. Clinical features of patients who visited the outpatient clinic for long COVID in Japan. eNeurologicalSci. 2022; 28: 100418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doty RL. Olfactory dysfunction in COVID-19: Pathology and long-term implications for brain health. Trends Mol. Med. 2022; 28: 781-794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eliezer M, Hamel AL, Houdart E et al. Loss of smell in patients with COVID-19: MRI data reveal a transient edema of the olfactory clefts. Neurology 2020; 95: e3145-e3152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zazhytska M, Kodra A, Hoagland DA et al. Non-cell-autonomous disruption of nuclear architecture as a potential cause of COVID-19-induced anosmia. Cell 2022; 185: 1052-1064.e1012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin E, Lantos JE, Strauss SB et al. Brain imaging of patients with COVID-19: Findings at an academic institution during the height of the outbreak in New York City. Am. J. Neuroradiol. 2020; 41: 2001-2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu A, Fischbein N, Wintermark M, Zaharchuk G, Yun PT, Zeineh M. COVID-19-induced anosmia associated with olfactory bulb atrophy. Neuroradiology 2021; 63: 147-148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galougahi MK, Ghorbani J, Bakhshayeshkaram M, Naeini AS, Haseli S. Olfactory bulb magnetic resonance imaging in SARS-CoV-2-induced anosmia: The first report. Acad. Radiol. 2020; 27: 892-893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffanti L, Raman B, Alfaro-Almagro F et al. Adapting the UK biobank brain imaging protocol and analysis pipeline for the C-MORE multi-organ study of COVID-19 survivors. Front. Neurol. 2021; 12: 753284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho CY, Salimian M, Hegert J et al. Postmortem assessment of olfactory tissue degeneration and microvasculopathy in patients with COVID-19. JAMA Neurol. 2022; 79: 544-553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampaio Rocha-Filho PA. Headache associated with COVID-19: Epidemiology, characteristics, pathophysiology, and management. Headache 2022; 62: 650-656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V et al. Headache as an acute and post-COVID-19 symptom in COVID-19 survivors: A meta-analysis of the current literature. Eur. J. Neurol. 2021; 28: 3820-3825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanares-Zapatero D, Chalon P, Kohn L et al. Pathophysiology and mechanism of long COVID: A comprehensive review. Ann. Med. 2022; 54: 1473-1487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams RMC, Simpson DM, Navis A, Jette N, Zhou L, Shin SC. Small fiber neuropathy associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Muscle Nerve 2022; 65: 440-443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finsterer J. Small fiber neuropathy underlying dysautonomia in COVID-19 and in post-SARS-CoV-2 vaccination and long-COVID syndromes. Muscle Nerve 2022; 65: e31-e32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR, Guzman JC, Harvey P et al. Canadian cardiovascular society position statement on postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) and related disorders of chronic orthostatic intolerance. Can. J. Cardiol. 2020; 36: 357-372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S, Tran VH. Postural Orthostatic Tachycardia Syndrome. StatPearls. StatPearls Publishing LLC, Treasure Island, FL, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruzieh M, Batizy L, Dasa O, Oostra C, Grubb B. The role of autoantibodies in the syndromes of orthostatic intolerance: A systematic review. Scand. Cardiovasc. J. 2017; 51: 243-247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eslami M, Mollazadeh R, Mirshafiee S et al. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome and orthostatic hypotension post COVID-19. Infect. Disord. Drug Targets 2022. https://doi.org/10.2174/1871526522666220610143504</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ormiston CK, &#x15a;wi&#x105;tkiewicz I, Taub PR. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome as a sequela of COVID-19. Heart Rhythm 2022. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hrthm.2022.07.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe5;hlberg M, Reistam U, Fedorowski A et al. Post-COVID-19 tachycardia syndrome: A distinct phenotype of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Am. J. Med. 2021; 134: 1451-1456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buoite Stella A, Furlanis G, Frezza NA, Valentinotti R, Ajcevic M, Manganotti P. Autonomic dysfunction in post-COVID patients with and witfhout neurological symptoms: A prospective multidomain observational study. J. Neurol. 2022; 269: 587-596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P et al. Autonomic dysfunction in 'long COVID': Rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin. Med. (Lond.) 2021; 21: e63-e67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miglis MG, Seliger J, Shaik R, Gibbons CH. A case series of cutaneous phosphorylated &#x3b1;-synuclein in long-COVID POTS. Clin. Auton. Res. 2022; 1-4: 209-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe4;ufer C, Schreiber CS, Hartke AS et al. Microgliosis and neuronal proteinopathy in brain persist beyond viral clearance in SARS-CoV-2 hamster model. EBioMedicine 2022; 79: 103999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki N, Kuroda R, Tsuno K, Kawakami N. Exposure to media and fear and worry about COVID-19. Psychiatry Clin. Neurosci. 2020; 74: 501-502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voiriot G, Oualha M, Pierre A et al. Chronic critical illness and post-intensive care syndrome: From pathophysiology to clinical challenges. Ann. Intensive Care 2022; 12: 58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addison AB, Wong B, Ahmed T et al. Clinical olfactory working group consensus statement on the treatment of postinfectious olfactory dysfunction. J. Allergy Clin. Immunol. 2021; 147: 1704-1719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hummel T, Rissom K, Reden J, H&#xe4;hner A, Weidenbecher M, H&#xfc;ttenbrink KB. Effects of olfactory training in patients with olfactory loss. Laryngoscope 2009; 119: 496-499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Othman BA, Maulud SQ, Jalal PJ et al. Olfactory dysfunction as a post-infectious symptom of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Ann. Med. Surg. (Lond.) 2022; 75: 103352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu TJ, Yu AC, Lee JT. Management of post-COVID-19 olfactory dysfunction. Curr. Treat. Options Allergy 2022; 9: 1-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori E, Merkonidis C, Cuevas M, Gudziol V, Matsuwaki Y, Hummel T. The administration of nasal drops in the "Kaiteki" position allows for delivery of the drug to the olfactory cleft: A pilot study in healthy subjects. Eur. Arch. Otorhinolaryngol. 2016; 273: 939-943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harless L, Liang J. Pharmacologic treatment for postviral olfactory dysfunction: A systematic review. Int. Forum Allergy Rhinol. 2016; 6: 760-767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balboni E, Zagnoli F, Filippini T, Fairweather-Tait SJ, Vinceti M. Zinc and selenium supplementation in COVID-19 prevention and treatment: A systematic review of the experimental studies. J. Trace Elem. Med. Biol. 2022; 71: 126956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan A, Yacoubian C, Watson N, Morrison I. The risk of copper deficiency in patients prescribed zinc supplements. J. Clin. Pathol. 2015; 68: 723-725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowin J, Lewis SL. Copper deficiency myeloneuropathy and pancytopenia secondary to overuse of zinc supplementation. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 2005; 76: 750-751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Arrones OM, Lobato-Berezo A, Gomez-Zubiaur A et al. SARS-CoV-2-induced telogen effluvium: A multicentric study. J. Eur. Acad. Dermatol. Venereol. 2021; 35: e181-e183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruenstein D, O'Mara M, Pa SH et al. Telogen effluvium caused by COVID-19 in Elmhurst, New York: Report of a cohort and review. Dermatol. Online J. 2021; 27: 6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen B, Tosti A. Alopecia in patients with COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. JAAD Int. 2022; 7: 67-77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebora A. Trichodynia: A review of the literature. Int. J. Dermatol. 2016; 55: 382-384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Landro A, Naldi L, Glaser E, Paus R, Tosti A. Pathobiology questions raised by telogen effluvium and trichodynia in COVID-19 patients. Exp. Dermatol. 2021; 30: 999-1000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmona-Torre F, M&#xed;nguez-Olaondo A, L&#xf3;pez-Bravo A et al. Dysautonomia in COVID-19 patients: A narrative review on clinical course, diagnostic and therapeutic strategies. Front. Neurol. 2022; 13: 886609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Bowe B, Xie Y. Long COVID after breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat. Med. 2022; 28: 1461-1467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Penfold RS, Merino J et al. Risk factors and disease profile of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection in UK users of the COVID symptom study app: A prospective, community-based, nested, case-control study. Lancet Infect. Dis. 2022; 22: 43-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Bermingham C, Pouwels KB et al. Trajectory of long covid symptoms after covid-19 vaccination: Community based cohort study. BMJ 2022; 377: e069676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azzolini E, Levi R, Sarti R et al. Association between BNT162b2 vaccination and long COVID after infections not requiring hospitalization in health care workers. JAMA 2022; 328: 676-678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Harrison PJ. Six-month sequelae of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection: A retrospective cohort study of 10,024 breakthrough infections. Brain Behav. Immun. 2022; 103: 154-162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wynberg E, Han AX, Boyd A et al. The effect of SARS-CoV-2 vaccination on post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): A prospective cohort study. Vaccine 2022; 40: 4424-4431. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vaccine.2022.05.090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisnivesky JP, Govindarajulu U, Bagiella E et al. Association of vaccination with the persistence of post-COVID symptoms. J. Gen. Intern. Med. 2022; 37: 1748-1753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold D, Milne A, Samms E, Stadon L, Maskell N, Hamilton F. Are vaccines safe in patients with long COVID? A prospective observational study. medRxiv 2021; 14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherlinger M, Pijnenburg L, Chatelus E et al. Effect of SARS-CoV-2 vaccination on symptoms from post-acute sequelae of COVID-19: Results from the Nationwide VAXILONG study. Vaccines (Basel). 2021; 10: 46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cozza A, Maggioni G, Thiene G, Bonati MR. The 1918 influenza pandemic versus COVID-19: A historical perspective from an Italian point of view. Am. J. Public Health 2021; 111: 1815-1823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilbourne ED. Influenza pandemics of the 20th century. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 2006; 12: 9-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman LA, Vilensky JA. Encephalitis lethargica: 100&#x2009;years after the epidemic. Brain 2017; 140: 2246-2251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson LL, Vilensky JA, Duvoisin RC. Review: Neuropathology of acute phase encephalitis lethargica: A review of cases from the epidemic period. Neuropathol. Appl. Neurobiol. 2009; 35: 462-472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honigsbaum M, Krishnan L. Taking pandemic sequelae seriously: From the Russian influenza to COVID-19 long-haulers. Lancet 2020; 396: 1389-1391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefano GB. Historical insight into infections and disorders associated with neurological and psychiatric sequelae similar to long COVID. Med. Sci. Monit. 2021; 27: e931447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekki M, Eley B, Hardie D, Wilmshurst JM. Subacute sclerosing panencephalitis: Clinical phenotype, epidemiology, and preventive interventions. Dev. Med. Child Neurol. 2019; 61: 1139-1144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takao M. Targeted therapy and progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy (PML): PML in the era of monoclonal antibody therapies (in Japanese). Brain Nerve 2013; 65: 1363-1374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xf6;hn N, Grote-Levi L, Hopfner F et al. Innovative therapeutic concepts of progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy. J. Neurol. 2022; 269: 2403-2413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izumo S, Umehara F, Osame M. HTLV-I-associated myelopathy. Neuropathology 2000; 20: S65-S68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frere JJ, Serafini RA, Pryce KD et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection in hamsters and humans results in lasting and unique systemic perturbations post recovery. Sci. Transl. Med. 2022; 14: eabq3059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soung AL, Vanderheiden A, Nordvig AS et al. COVID-19 induces CNS cytokine expression and loss of hippocampal neurogenesis. Brain 2022. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awac270</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano GE, Walker JE, Tremblay C et al. SARS-CoV-2 brain regional detection, histopathology, gene expression, and immunomodulatory changes in decedents with COVID-19. J. Neuropathol. Exp. Neurol. 2022 Aug 13; 81:666-695. Epub 2022 Aug 13.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>