<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38693641</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2796</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>296</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of internal medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Intern Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epigenetic reprograming in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: A narrative of latent viruses.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>93</StartPage><EndPage>115</EndPage><MedlinePgn>93-115</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/joim.13792</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) is a chronic disease presenting with severe fatigue, post-exertional malaise, and cognitive disturbances-among a spectrum of symptoms-that collectively render the patient housebound or bedbound. Epigenetic studies in ME/CFS collectively confirm alterations and/or malfunctions in cellular and organismal physiology associated with immune responses, cellular metabolism, cell death and proliferation, and neuronal and endothelial cell function. The sudden onset of ME/CFS follows a major stress factor that, in approximately 70% of cases, involves viral infection, and ME/CFS symptoms overlap with those of long COVID. Viruses primarily linked to ME/CFS pathology are the symbiotic herpesviruses, which follow a bivalent latent-lytic lifecycle. The complex interaction between viruses and hosts involves strategies from both sides: immune evasion and persistence by the viruses, and immune activation and viral clearance by the host. This dynamic interaction is imperative for herpesviruses that facilitate their persistence through epigenetic regulation of their own and the host genome. In the current article, we provide an overview of the epigenetic signatures demonstrated in ME/CFS and focus on the potential strategies that latent viruses-particularly Epstein-Barr virus-may employ in long-term epigenetic reprograming in ME/CFS. Epigenetic studies could aid in elucidating relevant biological pathways impacted in ME/CFS and reflect the physiological variations among the patients that stem from environmental triggers, including exogenous viruses and/or altered viral activity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors. Journal of Internal Medicine published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Association for Publication of The Journal of Internal Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Apostolou</LastName><ForeName>Eirini</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-2405-8243</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cell and Neurobiology, Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences, Link&#xf6;ping University, Link&#xf6;ping, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ros&#xe9;n</LastName><ForeName>Anders</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cell and Neurobiology, Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences, Link&#xf6;ping University, Link&#xf6;ping, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>4.3-2019-00201 GD-2020-138</GrantID><Agency>Swedish Research Council</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>211832Pj01H2</GrantID><Agency>Swedish Cancer Society</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Intern Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904841</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0954-6820</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015673" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fatigue Syndrome, Chronic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044127" MajorTopicYN="Y">Epigenesis, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017735" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Latency</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004854" MajorTopicYN="N">Herpesvirus 4, Human</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epigenetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38693641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joim.13792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Carruthers BM. Definitions and aetiology of myalgic encephalomyelitis: how the Canadian consensus clinical definition of myalgic encephalomyelitis works. J Clin Pathol. 2007;60(2):117&#x2013;119. https://doi.org/10.1136/jcp.2006.042754</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steiner S, Fehrer A, Hoheisel F, Schoening S, Aschenbrenner A, Babel N, et&#xa0;al. Understanding, diagnosing, and treating myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome &#x2010; state of the art: report of the 2nd international meeting at the Charite fatigue center. Autoimmun Rev. 2023;22:103452. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2023.103452</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg J, Gottfries CG, Elfaitouri A, Rizwan M, Ros&#xe9;n A. Infection elicited autoimmunity and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: an explanatory model. Front Immunol. 2018;9:229. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2018.00229</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choutka J, Jansari V, Hornig M, Iwasaki A. Unexplained post&#x2010;acute infection syndromes. Nat Med. 2022;28(5):911&#x2013;923. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591&#x2010;022&#x2010;01810&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz&#x2010;Pablos M, Paiva B, Zabaleta A. Epstein&#x2010;Barr virus&#x2010;acquired immunodeficiency in myalgic encephalomyelitis&#x2010;is it present in long COVID? J Transl Med. 2023;21(1):633. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967&#x2010;023&#x2010;04515&#x2010;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson MR. The viral origin of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. PLoS Pathog. 2023;19(8):e1011523. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.ppat.1011523</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL, Lipkin WI. Insights from myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome may help unravel the pathogenesis of postacute COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome. Trends Mol Med. 2021;27(9):895&#x2013;906. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molmed.2021.06.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL, Bateman L. Will COVID&#x2010;19 lead to myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome? Front Med (Lausanne). 2020;7:606824. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2020.606824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poenaru S, Abdallah SJ, Corrales&#x2010;Medina V, Cowan J. COVID&#x2010;19 and post&#x2010;infectious myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a narrative review. Ther Adv Infect Dis. 2021;8:20499361211009385. https://doi.org/10.1177/20499361211009385</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornig M, Montoya JG, Klimas NG, Levine S, Felsenstein D, Bateman L, et&#xa0;al. Distinct plasma immune signatures in ME/CFS are present early in the course of illness. Sci Adv. 2015;1(1):e1400121. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.1400121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher MA, Zeng XR, Barnes Z, Levis S, Klimas NG. Plasma cytokines in women with chronic fatigue syndrome. J Transl Med. 2009;7:96. https://doi.org/10.1186/1479&#x2010;5876&#x2010;7&#x2010;96</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montoya JG, Holmes TH, Anderson JN, Maecker HT, Rosenberg&#x2010;Hasson Y, Valencia IJ, et&#xa0;al. Cytokine signature associated with disease severity in chronic fatigue syndrome patients. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2017;114(34):E7150&#x2013;E7158. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1710519114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eaton&#x2010;Fitch N, du Preez S, Cabanas H, Staines D, Marshall&#x2010;Gradisnik S. A systematic review of natural killer cells profile and cytotoxic function in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Syst Rev. 2019;8(1):279. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13643&#x2010;019&#x2010;1202&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivas JL, Palencia T, Fernandez G, Garcia M. Association of T and NK cell phenotype with the diagnosis of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). Front Immunol. 2018;9:1028. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2018.01028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandarano AH, Maya J, Giloteaux L, Peterson DL, Maynard M, Gottschalk CG, et&#xa0;al. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients exhibit altered T cell metabolism and cytokine associations. J Clin Invest. 2020;130(3):1491&#x2013;1505. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI132185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos S, Brenu E, Broadley S, Kwiatek R, Ng J, Nguyen T, et&#xa0;al. Regulatory T, natural killer T and gammadelta T cells in multiple sclerosis and chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis: a comparison. Asian Pac J Allergy Immunol. 2016;34(4):300&#x2013;305. https://doi.org/10.12932/AP0733</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen CB, Alsoe L, Lindvall JM, Sulheim D, Fagermoen E, Winger A, et&#xa0;al. Whole blood gene expression in adolescent chronic fatigue syndrome: an exploratory cross&#x2010;sectional study suggesting altered B cell differentiation and survival. J Transl Med. 2017;15(1):102. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967&#x2010;017&#x2010;1201&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley AS, Ford B, Bansal AS. Altered functional B cell subset populations in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome compared to healthy controls. Clin Exp Immunol. 2013;172(1):73&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1111/cei.12043</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milivojevic M, Che X, Bateman L, Cheng A, Garcia BA, Hornig M, et&#xa0;al. Plasma proteomic profiling suggests an association between antigen driven clonal B cell expansion and ME/CFS. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(7):e0236148. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0236148</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cockshell SJ, Mathias JL. Cognitive functioning in chronic fatigue syndrome: a meta&#x2010;analysis. Psychol Med. 2010;40(8):1253&#x2013;1267. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291709992054</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijs J, Meeus M, Van Oosterwijck J, Ickmans K, Moorkens G, Hans G, et&#xa0;al. In the mind or in the brain? Scientific evidence for central sensitisation in chronic fatigue syndrome. Eur J Clin Invest. 2012;42(2):203&#x2013;212. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365&#x2010;2362.2011.02575.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnden LR, Shan ZY, Staines DR, Marshall&#x2010;Gradisnik S, Finegan K, Ireland T, et&#xa0;al. Hyperintense sensorimotor T1 spin echo MRI is associated with brainstem abnormality in chronic fatigue syndrome. Neuroimage Clin. 2018;20:102&#x2013;109. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nicl.2018.07.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook DB, O'Connor PJ, Lange G, Steffener J. Functional neuroimaging correlates of mental fatigue induced by cognition among chronic fatigue syndrome patients and controls. Neuroimage. 2007;36(1):108&#x2013;122. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2007.02.033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller C, Lin JC, Sheriff S, Maudsley AA, Younger JW. Evidence of widespread metabolite abnormalities in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: assessment with whole&#x2010;brain magnetic resonance spectroscopy. Brain Imaging Behav. 2020;14(2):562&#x2013;572. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11682&#x2010;018&#x2010;0029&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tak LM, Cleare AJ, Ormel J, Manoharan A, Kok IC, Wessely S, et&#xa0;al. Meta&#x2010;analysis and meta&#x2010;regression of hypothalamic&#x2010;pituitary&#x2010;adrenal axis activity in functional somatic disorders. Biol Psychol. 2011;87(2):183&#x2013;194. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsycho.2011.02.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris G, Anderson G, Maes M. Hypothalamic&#x2010;pituitary&#x2010;adrenal hypofunction in myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME)/chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS) as a consequence of activated immune&#x2010;inflammatory and oxidative and nitrosative pathways. Mol Neurobiol. 2017;54(9):6806&#x2013;6819. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12035&#x2010;016&#x2010;0170&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakatomi Y, Mizuno K, Ishii A, Wada Y, Tanaka M, Tazawa S, et&#xa0;al. Neuroinflammation in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis: an (1)(1)C&#x2010;(R)&#x2010;PK11195 PET study. J Nucl Med. 2014;55(6):945&#x2013;950. https://doi.org/10.2967/jnumed.113.131045</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gay CW, Robinson ME, Lai S, O'Shea A, Craggs JG, Price DD, et&#xa0;al. Abnormal resting&#x2010;state functional connectivity in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome: results of seed and data&#x2010;driven analyses. Brain Connect. 2016;6(1):48&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.1089/brain.2015.0366</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswal B, Kunwar P, Natelson BH. Cerebral blood flow is reduced in chronic fatigue syndrome as assessed by arterial spin labeling. J Neurol Sci. 2011;301(1&#x2013;2):9&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2010.11.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baraniuk JN, Casado B, Maibach H, Clauw DJ, Pannell LK, Hess SS. A chronic fatigue syndrome &#x2010; related proteome in human cerebrospinal fluid. BMC Neurol. 2005;5:22. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471&#x2010;2377&#x2010;5&#x2010;22</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loebel M, Grabowski P, Heidecke H, Bauer S, Hanitsch LG, Wittke K, et&#xa0;al. Antibodies to beta adrenergic and muscarinic cholinergic receptors in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. Brain Behav Immun. 2016;52:32&#x2013;39. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2015.09.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul BD, Lemle MD, Komaroff AL, Snyder SH. Redox imbalance links COVID&#x2010;19 and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2021;118(34):e2024358118. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2024358118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamano E, Sugimoto M, Hirayama A, Kume S, Yamato M, Jin G, et&#xa0;al. Index markers of chronic fatigue syndrome with dysfunction of TCA and urea cycles. Sci Rep. 2016;6:34990. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep34990</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Missailidis D, Annesley SJ, Allan CY, Sanislav O, Lidbury BA, Lewis DP, et&#xa0;al. An isolated complex V inefficiency and dysregulated mitochondrial function in immortalized lymphocytes from ME/CFS patients. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(3):1074. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms21031074</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomas C, Elson JL, Strassheim V, Newton JL, Walker M. The effect of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) severity on cellular bioenergetic function. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(4):e0231136. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0231136</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naviaux RK, Naviaux JC, Li K, Bright AT, Alaynick WA, Wang L, et&#xa0;al. Metabolic features of chronic fatigue syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2016;113(37):E5472&#x2013;E5480. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1607571113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M, Kubera M, Uytterhoeven M, Vrydags N, Bosmans E. Increased plasma peroxides as a marker of oxidative stress in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). Med Sci Monit. 2011;17(4):SC11&#x2013;SC115. https://doi.org/10.12659/msm.881699</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson M, Gray SR, Watson MS, Kennedy G, Hill A, Belch JJ, et&#xa0;al. Plasma IL&#x2010;6, its soluble receptors and F2&#x2010;isoprostanes at rest and during exercise in chronic fatigue syndrome. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(2):282&#x2013;290. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;0838.2009.00895.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjorklund G, Dadar M, Pen JJ, Chirumbolo S, Aaseth J. Chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS): suggestions for a nutritional treatment in the therapeutic approach. Biomed Pharmacother. 2019;109:1000&#x2013;1007. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2018.10.076</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miwa K, Fujita M. Increased oxidative stress suggested by low serum vitamin E concentrations in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. Int J Cardiol. 2009;136(2):238&#x2013;239. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijcard.2008.04.051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijs J, Nees A, Paul L, De Kooning M, Ickmans K, Meeus M, et&#xa0;al. Altered immune response to exercise in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis: a systematic literature review. Exerc Immunol Rev. 2014;20:94&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris G, Maes M. Oxidative and nitrosative stress and immune&#x2010;inflammatory pathways in patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME)/chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS). Curr Neuropharmacol. 2014;12(2):168&#x2013;185. https://doi.org/10.2174/1570159X11666131120224653</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suarez A, Guillamo E, Roig T, Blazquez A, Alegre J, Bermudez J, et&#xa0;al. Nitric oxide metabolite production during exercise in chronic fatigue syndrome: a case&#x2010;control study. J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2010;19(6):1073&#x2013;1077. https://doi.org/10.1089/jwh.2008.1255</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph P, Arevalo C, Oliveira RKF, Faria&#x2010;Urbina M, Felsenstein D, Oaklander AL, et&#xa0;al. Insights from invasive cardiopulmonary exercise testing of patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Chest. 2021;160(2):642&#x2013;651. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chest.2021.01.082</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason LA, Corradi K, Gress S, Williams S, Torres&#x2010;Harding S. Causes of death among patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. Health Care Women Int. 2006;27(7):615&#x2013;626. https://doi.org/10.1080/07399330600803766</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JM, Kell DB, Pretorius E. Cardiovascular and haematological pathology in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS): a role for viruses. Blood Rev. 2023;60:101075. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.blre.2023.101075</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Campen C, Verheugt FWA, Rowe PC, Visser FC. Cerebral blood flow is reduced in ME/CFS during head&#x2010;up tilt testing even in the absence of hypotension or tachycardia: a quantitative, controlled study using Doppler echography. Clin Neurophysiol Pract. 2020;5:50&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cnp.2020.01.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherbakov N, Szklarski M, Hartwig J, Sotzny F, Lorenz S, Meyer A, et&#xa0;al. Peripheral endothelial dysfunction in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. ESC Heart Fail. 2020;7(3):1064&#x2013;1071. https://doi.org/10.1002/ehf2.12633</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brewer JH, Berg D. Hypercoaguable state associated with active human herpesvirus&#x2010;6 (HHV&#x2010;6) viremia in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. J Chronic Fatigue Syndr. 2011;8(3&#x2013;4):111&#x2013;116. https://doi.org/10.1300/J092v08n03_10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JM, Kruger A, Proal A, Kell DB, Pretorius E. The occurrence of hyperactivated platelets and fibrinaloid microclots in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). Pharmaceuticals (Basel). 2022;15(8):931. https://doi.org/10.3390/ph15080931</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shikova E, Reshkova V, Kumanova A, Raleva S, Alexandrova D, Capo N, et&#xa0;al. Cytomegalovirus, Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus, and human herpesvirus&#x2010;6 infections in patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. J Med Virol. 2020;92(12):3682&#x2013;3688. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.25744</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ariza ME. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: the human herpesviruses are back! Biomolecules. 2021;11(2):185. https://doi.org/10.3390/biom11020185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loebel M, Strohschein K, Giannini C, Koelsch U, Bauer S, Doebis C, et&#xa0;al. Deficient EBV&#x2010;specific B&#x2010; and T&#x2010;cell response in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(1):e85387. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0085387</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apostolou E, Rizwan M, Moustardas P, Sj&#xf6;gren P, Bertilson BC, Brag&#xe9;e B, et&#xa0;al. Saliva antibody&#x2010;fingerprint of reactivated latent viruses after mild/asymptomatic COVID&#x2010;19 is unique in patients with myalgic&#x2010;encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Front Immunol. 2022;13:949787. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2022.949787</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannestad U, Apostolou E, Sj&#xf6;gren P, Brag&#xe9;e B, Polo O, Bertilson BC, et&#xa0;al. Post&#x2010;COVID sequelae effect in chronic fatigue syndrome: SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 triggers latent adenovirus in the oral mucosa. Front Med (Lausanne). 2023;10:1208181. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2023.1208181</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr JR. Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus induced gene&#x2010;2 upregulation identifies a particular subtype of chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis. Front Pediatr. 2019;7:59. https://doi.org/10.3389/fped.2019.00059</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz&#x2010;Pablos M, Paiva B, Montero&#x2010;Mateo R, Garcia N, Zabaleta A. Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus and the origin of myalgic encephalomyelitis or chronic fatigue syndrome. Front Immunol. 2021;12:656797. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.656797</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Lacerda EM, Nacul L, Kingdon CC, Norris J, O'Boyle S, et&#xa0;al. Salivary DNA loads for human herpesviruses 6 and 7 are correlated with disease phenotype in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Front Med (Lausanne). 2021;8:656692. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2021.656692</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasa&#x2010;Dzelzkaleja S, Krumina A, Capenko S, Nora&#x2010;Krukle Z, Gravelsina S, Vilmane A, et&#xa0;al. The persistent viral infections in the development and severity of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. J Transl Med. 2023;21(1):33. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967&#x2010;023&#x2010;03887&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasimir F, Toomey D, Liu Z, Kaiping AC, Ariza ME, Prusty BK. Tissue specific signature of HHV&#x2010;6 infection in ME/CFS. Front Mol Biosci. 2022;9:1044964. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmolb.2022.1044964</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamer J, Van Booven DJ, Zarnowski O, Arango S, Elias M, Kurian A, et&#xa0;al. Sex&#x2010;dependent transcriptional changes in response to stress in patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a pilot project. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(12):10255. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms241210255</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borza CM, Hutt&#x2010;Fletcher LM. Alternate replication in B cells and epithelial cells switches tropism of Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus. Nat Med. 2002;8(6):594&#x2013;599. https://doi.org/10.1038/nm0602&#x2010;594</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams Ph DM, Cox B, Lafuse Ph DW, Ariza ME. Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus dUTPase induces neuroinflammatory mediators: implications for myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Clin Ther. 2019;41(5):848&#x2013;863. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinthera.2019.04.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin P, Williams MV, Klimas NG, Fletcher MA, Barnes Z, Ariza ME. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome and gulf war illness patients exhibit increased humoral responses to the herpesviruses&#x2010;encoded dUTPase: implications in disease pathophysiology. J Med Virol. 2017;89(9):1636&#x2013;1645. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.24810</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox BS, Alharshawi K, Mena&#x2010;Palomo I, Lafuse WP, Ariza ME. EBV/HHV&#x2010;6A dUTPases contribute to myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome pathophysiology by enhancing TFH cell differentiation and extrafollicular activities. JCI Insight. 2022;7(11):e158193. https://doi.org/10.1172/jci.insight.158193</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerner AM, Beqaj SH, Deeter RG, Fitzgerald JT. IgM serum antibodies to Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus are uniquely present in a subset of patients with the chronic fatigue syndrome. In Vivo. 2004;18(2):101&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loebel M, Eckey M, Sotzny F, Hahn E, Bauer S, Grabowski P, et&#xa0;al. Serological profiling of the EBV immune response in chronic fatigue syndrome using a peptide microarray. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(6):e0179124. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0179124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr J. Early growth response gene upregulation in Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus (EBV)&#x2010;associated myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). Biomolecules. 2020;10(11):1484. https://doi.org/10.3390/biom10111484</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL. Chronic fatigue syndromes: relationship to chronic viral infections. J Virol Methods. 1988;21(1&#x2013;4):3&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.1016/0166&#x2010;0934(88)90047&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Putte EM, van Doornen LJ, Engelbert RH, Kuis W, Kimpen JL, Uiterwaal CS. Mirrored symptoms in mother and child with chronic fatigue syndrome. Pediatrics. 2006;117(6):2074&#x2013;2079. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2005&#x2010;2307</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deumer US, Varesi A, Floris V, Savioli G, Mantovani E, Lopez&#x2010;Carrasco P, et&#xa0;al. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS): an overview. J Clin Med. 2021;10(20):4786. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10204786</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tziastoudi M, Cholevas C, Stefanidis I, Theoharides TC. Genetics of COVID&#x2010;19 and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a systematic review. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2022;9(11):1838&#x2013;1857. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.51631</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helliwell AM, Sweetman EC, Stockwell PA, Edgar CD, Chatterjee A, Tate WP. Changes in DNA methylation profiles of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients reflect systemic dysfunctions. Clin Epigenet. 2020;12(1):167. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13148&#x2010;020&#x2010;00960&#x2010;z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vega WC, Vernon SD, McGowan PO. DNA methylation modifications associated with chronic fatigue syndrome. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(8):e104757. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0104757</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trivedi MS, Oltra E, Sarria L, Rose N, Beljanski V, Fletcher MA, et&#xa0;al. Identification of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome&#x2010;associated DNA methylation patterns. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(7):e0201066. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201066</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vega WC, Erdman L, Vernon SD, Goldenberg A, McGowan PO. Integration of DNA methylation &amp; health scores identifies subtypes in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Epigenomics. 2018;10(5):539&#x2013;557. https://doi.org/10.2217/epi&#x2010;2017&#x2010;0150</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helliwell AM, Stockwell PA, Edgar CD, Chatterjee A, Tate WP. Dynamic epigenetic changes during a relapse and recovery cycle in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(19):11852. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms231911852</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vega WC, Herrera S, Vernon SD, McGowan PO. Epigenetic modifications and glucocorticoid sensitivity in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). BMC Med Genomics. 2017;10(1):11. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12920&#x2010;017&#x2010;0248&#x2010;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera S, de Vega WC, Ashbrook D, Vernon SD, McGowan PO. Genome&#x2010;epigenome interactions associated with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Epigenetics. 2018;13(12):1174&#x2013;1190. https://doi.org/10.1080/15592294.2018.1549769</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenu EW, Staines DR, Marshall&#x2010;Gradisnik SM. Methylation profile of CD4+ T cells in chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis. J Clin Cell Immunol. 2014;5(3):1000228. https://doi.org/10.4172/2155&#x2010;9899.1000228</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polli A, Ghosh M, Bakusic J, Ickmans K, Monteyne D, Velkeniers B, et&#xa0;al. DNA methylation and brain&#x2010;derived neurotrophic factor expression account for symptoms and widespread hyperalgesia in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome and comorbid fibromyalgia. Arthritis Rheum. 2020;72(11):1936&#x2013;1944. https://doi.org/10.1002/art.41405</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falkenberg VR, Whistler T, Murray JR, Unger ER, Rajeevan MS. Acute psychosocial stress&#x2010;mediated changes in the expression and methylation of perforin in chronic fatigue syndrome. Genet Epigenet. 2013;5:1&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.4137/GEG.S10944</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vangeel E, Van Den Eede F, Hompes T, Izzi B, Del Favero J, Moorkens G, et&#xa0;al. Chronic fatigue syndrome and DNA hypomethylation of the glucocorticoid receptor gene promoter 1F region: associations with HPA axis hypofunction and childhood trauma. Psychosom Med. 2015;77(8):853&#x2013;862. https://doi.org/10.1097/PSY.0000000000000224</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vangeel EB, Kempke S, Bakusic J, Godderis L, Luyten P, Van Heddegem L, et&#xa0;al. Glucocorticoid receptor DNA methylation and childhood trauma in chronic fatigue syndrome patients. J Psychosom Res. 2018;104:55&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychores.2017.11.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falkenberg VR, Gurbaxani BM, Unger ER, Rajeevan MS. Functional genomics of serotonin receptor 2A (HTR2A): interaction of polymorphism, methylation, expression and disease association. Neuromolecular Med. 2011;13(1):66&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12017&#x2010;010&#x2010;8138&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polli A, Hendrix J, Ickmans K, Bakusic J, Ghosh M, Monteyne D, et&#xa0;al. Genetic and epigenetic regulation of catechol&#x2010;O&#x2010;methyltransferase in relation to inflammation in chronic fatigue syndrome and fibromyalgia. J Transl Med. 2022;20(1):487. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967&#x2010;022&#x2010;03662&#x2010;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason L, Sorenson M, Sebally K, Alkazemi D, Lerch A, Porter N, et&#xa0;al. Increased HDAC in association with decreased plasma cortisol in older adults with chronic fatigue syndrome. Brain Behav Immun. 2011;25(8):1544&#x2013;1547. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2011.04.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweetman E, Kleffmann T, Edgar C, de Lange M, Vallings R, Tate W. A SWATH&#x2010;MS analysis of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome peripheral blood mononuclear cell proteomes reveals mitochondrial dysfunction. J Transl Med. 2020;18(1):365. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967&#x2010;020&#x2010;02533&#x2010;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whistler T, Jones JF, Unger ER, Vernon SD. Exercise responsive genes measured in peripheral blood of women with chronic fatigue syndrome and matched control subjects. BMC Physiol. 2005;5(1):5. https://doi.org/10.1186/1472&#x2010;6793&#x2010;5&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGregor NR, Armstrong CW, Lewis DP, Gooley PR. Post&#x2010;exertional malaise is associated with hypermetabolism, hypoacetylation and purine metabolism deregulation in ME/CFS cases. Diagnostics (Basel). 2019;9(3):70. https://doi.org/10.3390/diagnostics9030070</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenu EW, Ashton KJ, Batovska J, Staines DR, Marshall&#x2010;Gradisnik SM. High&#x2010;throughput sequencing of plasma microRNA in chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(9):e102783. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0102783</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheema AK, Sarria L, Bekheit M, Collado F, Almenar&#x2010;Perez E, Martin&#x2010;Martinez E, et&#xa0;al. Unravelling myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS): gender&#x2010;specific changes in the microRNA expression profiling in ME/CFS. J Cell Mol Med. 2020;24(10):5865&#x2013;5877. https://doi.org/10.1111/jcmm.15260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nepotchatykh E, Elremaly W, Caraus I, Godbout C, Leveau C, Chalder L, et&#xa0;al. Profile of circulating microRNAs in myalgic encephalomyelitis and their relation to symptom severity, and disease pathophysiology. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):19620. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;020&#x2010;76438&#x2010;y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nepotchatykh E, Caraus I, Elremaly W, Leveau C, Elbakry M, Godbout C, et&#xa0;al. Circulating microRNA expression signatures accurately discriminate myalgic encephalomyelitis from fibromyalgia and comorbid conditions. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):1896. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;023&#x2010;28955&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soffritti I, Gravelsina S, D'Accolti M, Bini F, Mazziga E, Vilmane A, et&#xa0;al. Circulating miRNAs expression in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(13):10582. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms241310582</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almenar&#x2010;Perez E, Sarria L, Nathanson L, Oltra E. Assessing diagnostic value of microRNAs from peripheral blood mononuclear cells and extracellular vesicles in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):2064. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;020&#x2010;58506&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blauensteiner J, Bertinat R, Leon LE, Riederer M, Sepulveda N, Westermeier F. Altered endothelial dysfunction&#x2010;related miRs in plasma from ME/CFS patients. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):10604. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;021&#x2010;89834&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baraniuk JN, Shivapurkar N. Exercise &#x2010; induced changes in cerebrospinal fluid miRNAs in Gulf War Illness, chronic fatigue syndrome and sedentary control subjects. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):15338. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;017&#x2010;15383&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkarni V, Jayakumar S, Mohan M, Kulkarni S. Aid or antagonize: nuclear long noncoding RNAs regulate host responses and outcomes of viral infections. Cells. 2023;12(7):987. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells12070987</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang CA, Bauer S, Ho YC, Sotzny F, Chang JG, Scheibenbogen C. The expression signature of very long non&#x2010;coding RNA in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. J Transl Med. 2018;16(1):231. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967&#x2010;018&#x2010;1600&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y, Xu SM, Takenaka K, Lindner G, Curry&#x2010;Hyde A, Janitz M. A unique circular RNA expression pattern in the peripheral blood of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients. Gene. 2023;877:147568. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gene.2023.147568</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henle G, Henle W, Diehl V. Relation of Burkitt's tumor&#x2010;associated herpes&#x2010;type virus to infectious mononucleosis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1968;59(1):94&#x2013;101. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.59.1.94</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz BZ, Shiraishi Y, Mears CJ, Binns HJ, Taylor R. Chronic fatigue syndrome after infectious mononucleosis in adolescents. Pediatrics. 2009;124(1):189&#x2013;193. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2008&#x2010;1879</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straus SE, Tosato G, Armstrong G, Lawley T, Preble OT, Henle W, et&#xa0;al. Persisting illness and fatigue in adults with evidence of Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus infection. Ann Intern Med. 1985;102(1):7&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.7326/0003&#x2010;4819&#x2010;102&#x2010;1&#x2010;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Paschale M, Clerici P. Serological diagnosis of Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus infection: problems and solutions. World J Virol. 2012;1(1):31&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.5501/wjv.v1.i1.31</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varghese CS, Parish JL, Ferguson J. Lying low&#x2010;chromatin insulation in persistent DNA virus infection. Curr Opin Virol. 2022;55:101257. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coviro.2022.101257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y, Xie L, Shi F, Tang M, Li Y, Hu J, et&#xa0;al. Targeting the signaling in Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus&#x2010;associated diseases: mechanism, regulation, and clinical study. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6(1):15. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41392&#x2010;020&#x2010;00376&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locatelli M, Faure&#x2010;Dupuy S. Virus hijacking of host epigenetic machinery to impair immune response. J Virol. 2023;97(9):e0065823. https://doi.org/10.1128/jvi.00658&#x2010;23</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen JI. Herpesvirus latency. J Clin Invest. 2020;130(7):3361&#x2013;3369. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI136225</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott RS. Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus: a master epigenetic manipulator. Curr Opin Virol. 2017;26:74&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coviro.2017.07.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buschle A, Hammerschmidt W. Epigenetic lifestyle of Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus. Semin Immunopathol. 2020;42(2):131&#x2013;142. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00281&#x2010;020&#x2010;00792&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milavetz BI, Balakrishnan L. Viral epigenetics. Methods Mol Biol. 2015;1238:569&#x2013;596. https://doi.org/10.1007/978&#x2010;1&#x2010;4939&#x2010;1804&#x2010;1_30</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo R, Liang JH, Zhang Y, Lutchenkov M, Li Z, Wang Y, et&#xa0;al. Methionine metabolism controls the B cell EBV epigenome and viral latency. Cell Metab. 2022;34(9):1280&#x2013;1297.e9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2022.08.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehman UU, Ghafoor D, Ullah A, Ahmad R, Hanif S. Epigenetics regulation during virus&#x2010;host interaction and their effects on the virus and host cell. Microb Pathog. 2023;182:106271. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.micpath.2023.106271</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickerson SJ, Xing Y, Robinson AR, Seaman WT, Gruffat H, Kenney SC. Methylation&#x2010;dependent binding of the Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus BZLF1 protein to viral promoters. PLoS Pathog. 2009;5(3):e1000356. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.ppat.1000356</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Su X, Choi GC, Cao Y, Ambinder RF, Tao Q. Methylation profiling of Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus immediate&#x2010;early gene promoters, BZLF1 and BRLF1 in tumors of epithelial, NK&#x2010; and B&#x2010;cell origins. BMC Cancer. 2012;12:125. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471&#x2010;2407&#x2010;12&#x2010;125</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damania B, Kenney SC, Raab&#x2010;Traub N. Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus: biology and clinical disease. Cell. 2022;185(20):3652&#x2013;3670. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2022.08.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai K, Cullen BR. Epigenetic and epitranscriptomic regulation of viral replication. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2020;18(10):559&#x2013;570. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41579&#x2010;020&#x2010;0382&#x2010;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong MML, Lung ML. The impact of Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus infection on epigenetic regulation of host cell gene expression in epithelial and lymphocytic malignancies. Front Oncol. 2021;11:629780. https://doi.org/10.3389/fonc.2021.629780</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Gu B, Chen X, Wang Y, Li P, Wang K. The function and therapeutic potential of Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus&#x2010;encoded microRNAs in cancer. Mol Ther Nucleic Acids. 2019;17:657&#x2013;668. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.omtn.2019.07.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skalsky RL, Cullen BR. EBV noncoding RNAs. Curr Top Microbiol Immunol. 2015;391:181&#x2013;217. https://doi.org/10.1007/978&#x2010;3&#x2010;319&#x2010;22834&#x2010;1_6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, He C, Wu J, Yang D, Yi W. Epstein Barr virus encodes miRNAs to assist host immune escape. J Cancer. 2020;11(8):2091&#x2013;2100. https://doi.org/10.7150/jca.42498</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pegtel DM, Cosmopoulos K, Thorley&#x2010;Lawson DA, van Eijndhoven MA, Hopmans ES, Lindenberg JL, et&#xa0;al. Functional delivery of viral miRNAs via exosomes. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010;107(14):6328&#x2013;6333. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0914843107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie J, El&#x2010;Guindy A. Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus lytic cycle reactivation. Curr Top Microbiol Immunol. 2015;391:237&#x2013;261. https://doi.org/10.1007/978&#x2010;3&#x2010;319&#x2010;22834&#x2010;1_8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toptan T, Abere B, Nalesnik MA, Swerdlow SH, Ranganathan S, Lee N, et&#xa0;al. Circular DNA tumor viruses make circular RNAs. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2018;115(37):E8737&#x2013;E8745. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1811728115</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Zheng J, Zhang B, Tang X, Cun Y, Wu T, et&#xa0;al. Identification and characterization of virus&#x2010;encoded circular RNAs in host cells. Microb Genom. 2022;8(6):mgen000848. https://doi.org/10.1099/mgen.0.000848</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Liang Z, Wang C, Shen Z, Sun S, Gong C, et&#xa0;al. Viral circular RNAs and their possible roles in virus&#x2010;host interaction. Front Immunol. 2022;13:939768. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2022.939768</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiku V, Tan MW, Dikic I. Mitochondrial functions in infection and immunity. Trends Cell Biol. 2020;30(4):263&#x2013;275. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tcb.2020.01.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Wu K, Zeng S, Zhao F, Fan J, Li Z, et&#xa0;al. Viral infection modulates mitochondrial function. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(8):4260. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms22084260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer CS. Innate metabolic responses against viral infections. Nat Metab. 2022;4(10):1245&#x2013;1259. https://doi.org/10.1038/s42255&#x2010;022&#x2010;00652&#x2010;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandi M, Shokri S, Mahmoudvand S, Hosseinzadeh Adli A, Mohammadi R, Haddadi A. Interplay between cellular metabolism and DNA viruses. J Med Virol. 2022;94(11):5163&#x2013;5173. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.28018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LW, Shen H, Nobre L, Ersing I, Paulo JA, Trudeau S, et&#xa0;al. Epstein&#x2013;Barr&#x2010;virus&#x2010;induced one&#x2010;carbon metabolism drives B cell transformation. Cell Metab. 2019;30(3):539&#x2013;555.e11. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2019.06.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiner P, Harrer T, Scheibenbogen C, Lamer S, Schlosser A, Naviaux RK, et&#xa0;al. Human herpesvirus&#x2010;6 reactivation, mitochondrial fragmentation, and the coordination of antiviral and metabolic phenotypes in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Immunohorizons. 2020;4(4):201&#x2013;215. https://doi.org/10.4049/immunohorizons.2000006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid MA, Dai Z, Locasale JW. The impact of cellular metabolism on chromatin dynamics and epigenetics. Nat Cell Biol. 2017;19(11):1298&#x2013;1306. https://doi.org/10.1038/ncb3629</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu C, Thompson CB. Metabolic regulation of epigenetics. Cell Metab. 2012;16(1):9&#x2013;17. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2012.06.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abhimanyu, Ontiveros CO, Guerra&#x2010;Resendez RS, Nishiguchi T, Ladki M, Hilton IB, et&#xa0;al. Reversing post&#x2010;infectious epigenetic&#x2010;mediated immune suppression. Front Immunol. 2021;12:688132. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.688132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai X, Lv X, Thompson EW, Ostrikov KK. Histone lactylation: epigenetic mark of glycolytic switch. Trends Genet. 2022;38(2):124&#x2013;127. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tig.2021.09.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin Q, Wang H, Li Q, Liu S, Qu K, Liu C, et&#xa0;al. Lactylation: a passing fad or the future of posttranslational modification. Inflammation. 2022;45(4):1419&#x2013;1429. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10753&#x2010;022&#x2010;01637&#x2010;w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi W, Cassmann TJ, Bhagwate AV, Hitosugi T, Ip WKE. Lactic acid induces transcriptional repression of macrophage inflammatory response via histone acetylation. Cell Rep. 2024;43(2):113746. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2024.113746</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghali A, Lacout C, Ghali M, Gury A, Beucher AB, Lozac'h P, et&#xa0;al. Elevated blood lactate in resting conditions correlate with post&#x2010;exertional malaise severity in patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):18817. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;019&#x2010;55473&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fluge O, Mella O, Bruland O, Risa K, Dyrstad SE, Alme K, et&#xa0;al. Metabolic profiling indicates impaired pyruvate dehydrogenase function in myalgic encephalopathy/chronic fatigue syndrome. JCI Insight. 2016;1(21):e89376. https://doi.org/10.1172/jci.insight.89376</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkarni S, Arumugam T, Chuturgoon A, An P, Ramsuran V. Editorial: epigenetics of infectious diseases. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1054151. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2022.1054151</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassiotis G. The immunological conundrum of endogenous retroelements. Annu Rev Immunol. 2023;41:99&#x2013;125. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev&#x2010;immunol&#x2010;101721&#x2010;033341</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macchietto MG, Langlois RA, Shen SS. Virus&#x2010;induced transposable element expression up&#x2010;regulation in human and mouse host cells. Life Sci Alliance. 2020;3(2):e201900536. https://doi.org/10.26508/lsa.201900536</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Foroozesh M, Qin Z. Transactivation of human endogenous retroviruses by tumor viruses and their functions in virus&#x2010;associated malignancies. Oncogenesis. 2019;8(1):6. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41389&#x2010;018&#x2010;0114&#x2010;y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutkowski N, Conrad B, Thorley&#x2010;Lawson DA, Huber BT. Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus transactivates the human endogenous retrovirus HERV&#x2010;K18 that encodes a superantigen. Immunity. 2001;15(4):579&#x2013;589. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1074&#x2010;7613(01)00210&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marston JL, Greenig M, Singh M, Bendall ML, Duarte RRR, Feschotte C, et&#xa0;al. SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection mediates differential expression of human endogenous retroviruses and long interspersed nuclear elements. JCI Insight. 2021;6(24):e147170. https://doi.org/10.1172/jci.insight.147170</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitsou K, Kotanidou A, Paraskevis D, Karamitros T, Katzourakis A, Tedder R, et&#xa0;al. Upregulation of human endogenous retroviruses in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid of COVID&#x2010;19 patients. Microbiol Spectr. 2021;9(2):e0126021. https://doi.org/10.1128/Spectrum.01260&#x2010;21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandi N, Erbi MC, Scognamiglio S, Tramontano E. Human endogenous retrovirus (HERV) transcriptome is dynamically modulated during SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection and allows discrimination of COVID&#x2010;19 clinical stages. Microbiol Spectr. 2023;11(1):e0251622. https://doi.org/10.1128/spectrum.02516&#x2010;22</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balestrieri E, Minutolo A, Petrone V, Fanelli M, Iannetta M, Malagnino V, et&#xa0;al. Evidence of the pathogenic HERV&#x2010;W envelope expression in T lymphocytes in association with the respiratory outcome of COVID&#x2010;19 patients. EBioMedicine. 2021;66:103341. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ebiom.2021.103341</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temerozo JR, Fintelman&#x2010;Rodrigues N, Dos Santos MC, Hottz ED, Sacramento CQ, de Paula Dias da Silva A, et&#xa0;al. Human endogenous retrovirus K in the respiratory tract is associated with COVID&#x2010;19 physiopathology. Microbiome. 2022;10(1):65. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40168&#x2010;022&#x2010;01260&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gimenez&#x2010;Orenga K, Pierquin J, Brunel J, Charvet B, Martin&#x2010;Martinez E, Perron H, et&#xa0;al. HERV&#x2010;W ENV antigenemia and correlation of increased anti&#x2010;SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 immunoglobulin levels with post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 symptoms. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1020064. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2022.1020064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buttler CA, Chuong EB. Emerging roles for endogenous retroviruses in immune epigenetic regulation. Immunol Rev. 2022;305(1):165&#x2013;178. https://doi.org/10.1111/imr.13042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues LS, da Silva Nali LH, Leal COD, Sabino EC, Lacerda EM, Kingdon CC, et&#xa0;al. HERV&#x2010;K and HERV&#x2010;W transcriptional activity in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Auto Immun Highlights. 2019;10(1):12. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13317&#x2010;019&#x2010;0122&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almenar&#x2010;Perez E, Ovejero T, Sanchez&#x2010;Fito T, Espejo JA, Nathanson L, Oltra E. Epigenetic components of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome uncover potential transposable element activation. Clin Ther. 2019;41(4):675&#x2013;698. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinthera.2019.02.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russ E, Iordanskiy S. Endogenous retroviruses as modulators of innate immunity. Pathogens. 2023;12(2):162. https://doi.org/10.3390/pathogens12020162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attermann AS, Bjerregaard AM, Saini SK, Gronbaek K, Hadrup SR. Human endogenous retroviruses and their implication for immunotherapeutics of cancer. Ann Oncol. 2018;29(11):2183&#x2013;2191. https://doi.org/10.1093/annonc/mdy413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamdy A, Leonardi A. Superantigens and SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2. Pathogens. 2022;11(4):390. https://doi.org/10.3390/pathogens11040390</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douville RN, Nath A. Human endogenous retrovirus&#x2010;K and TDP&#x2010;43 expression bridges ALS and HIV neuropathology. Front Microbiol. 2017;8:1986. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2017.01986</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruchot J, Kremer D, Kury P. Neural cell responses upon exposure to human endogenous retroviruses. Front Genet. 2019;10:655. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2019.00655</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE, Ba DM, Parsons N, Poudel GR, et&#xa0;al. Short&#x2010;term and long&#x2010;term rates of postacute sequelae of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection: a systematic review. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(10):e2128568. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.28568</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastie CE, Lowe DJ, McAuley A, Winter AJ, Mills NL, Black C, et&#xa0;al. Outcomes among confirmed cases and a matched comparison group in the long&#x2010;COVID in Scotland study. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):5663. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467&#x2010;022&#x2010;33415&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Li X, Gu X, Zhang H, Ren L, Guo L, et&#xa0;al. Health outcomes in people 2 years after surviving hospitalisation with COVID&#x2010;19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10(9):863&#x2013;876. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213&#x2010;2600(22)00126&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL, Lipkin WI. ME/CFS and long COVID share similar symptoms and biological abnormalities: road map to the literature. Front Med (Lausanne). 2023;10:1187163. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2023.1187163</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Y, Riskedal E, Kalleberg KT, Istre M, Lind A, Lund&#x2010;Johansen F, et&#xa0;al. EWAS of post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 patients shows methylation differences in the immune&#x2010;response associated gene, IFI44L, three months after COVID&#x2010;19 infection. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):11478. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;022&#x2010;15467&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikesj&#xf6; F, Sayyab S, Karlsson L, Apostolou E, Ros&#xe9;n A, Hedman K, et&#xa0;al. Defining post&#x2010;acute COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome (PACS) by an epigenetic biosignature in peripheral blood mononuclear cells. Clin Epigenet. 2022;14(1):172. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13148&#x2010;022&#x2010;01398&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan FJ, Hope CM, Masavuli MG, Lynn MA, Mekonnen ZA, Yeow AEL, et&#xa0;al. Long&#x2010;term perturbation of the peripheral immune system months after SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection. BMC Med. 2022;20(1):26. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12916&#x2010;021&#x2010;02228&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao X, Li W, Wang T, Ran D, Davalos V, Planas&#x2010;Serra L, et&#xa0;al. Accelerated biological aging in COVID&#x2010;19 patients. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):2135. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467&#x2010;022&#x2010;29801&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peppercorn K, Edgar CD, Kleffmann T, Tate WP. A pilot study on the immune cell proteome of long COVID patients shows changes to physiological pathways similar to those in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):22068. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;023&#x2010;49402&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold JE, Okyay RA, Licht WE, Hurley DJ. Investigation of long COVID prevalence and its relationship to Epstein&#x2013;Barr virus reactivation. Pathogens. 2021;10(6):763. https://doi.org/10.3390/pathogens10060763</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deveau TM, Munter SE, Ryder D, Buck A, Beck&#x2010;Engeser G, et&#xa0;al. Chronic viral coinfections differentially affect the likelihood of developing long COVID. J Clin Invest. 2023;133(3):e163669. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI163669</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubchenko S, Kril I, Nadizhko O, Matsyura O, Chopyak V. Herpesvirus infections and post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 manifestations: a pilot observational study. Rheumatol Int. 2022;42(9):1523&#x2013;1530. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00296&#x2010;022&#x2010;05146&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altmann DM, Whettlock EM, Liu S, Arachchillage DJ, Boyton RJ. The immunology of long COVID. Nat Rev Immunol. 2023;23:618&#x2013;634. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41577&#x2010;023&#x2010;00904&#x2010;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K, Straus SE, Hickie I, Sharpe MC, Dobbins JG, Komaroff A. The chronic fatigue syndrome: a comprehensive approach to its definition and study. International chronic fatigue syndrome study group. Ann Intern Med. 1994;121(12):953&#x2013;959. https://doi.org/10.7326/0003&#x2010;4819&#x2010;121&#x2010;12&#x2010;199412150&#x2010;00009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyond myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: redefining an illness. Mil Med. 2015;180(7):721&#x2013;723. https://doi.org/10.7205/MILMED&#x2010;D&#x2010;15&#x2010;00085</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sotzny F, Blanco J, Capelli E, Castro&#x2010;Marrero J, Steiner S, Murovska M, et&#xa0;al. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome &#x2010; evidence for an autoimmune disease. Autoimmun Rev. 2018;17(6):601&#x2013;609. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2018.01.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakken IJ, Tveito K, Gunnes N, Ghaderi S, Stoltenberg C, Trogstad L, et&#xa0;al. Two age peaks in the incidence of chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis: a population&#x2010;based registry study from Norway 2008&#x2013;2012. BMC Med. 2014;12:167. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12916&#x2010;014&#x2010;0167&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takakura S, Oka T, Sudo N. Changes in circulating microRNA after recumbent isometric yoga practice by patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: an explorative pilot study. Biopsychosoc Med. 2019;13:29. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13030&#x2010;019&#x2010;0171&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenu EW, Ashton KJ, van Driel M, Staines DR, Peterson D, Atkinson GM, et&#xa0;al. Cytotoxic lymphocyte microRNAs as prospective biomarkers for chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis. J Affect Disord. 2012;141(2&#x2013;3):261&#x2013;269. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jad.2012.03.037</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>