<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36579288</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fatality Chooses Its Path Through the Orbit: A Study of Rhino-Orbito-Cerebral Mucormycosis as a Complication of COVID-19 Infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e31822</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e31822</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e31822</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.31822</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Introduction and aim Mucormycosis is a rare but serious angio-invasive infection caused by a group of fungi called mucormycetes and it mainly affects people who are immunocompromised, or patients already infected with other diseases.&#xa0;The dreaded mucormycosis infection has recently gained gross ill-repute for having claimed many lives in coronavirus disease (COVID-19) and/or post-COVID-19 patients. Hence a need was felt to study the development of mucormycosis in COVID-19 patients to better prevent and treat this fungal infection in anticipated future waves of the pandemic. This study also aims to establish an association between COVID-19 positivity, systemic comorbidities, and treatment modalities with the possibility of occurrence of vision and life-threatening mucor infection of the nose, paranasal sinuses, orbit, and brain. Methods This is a hospital-based, retrospective, case-control study. The study reviewed case files of all patients diagnosed with rhino-orbito-cerebral mucormycosis (ROCM) from April 1, 2021, to May 31, 2021. A set of age-matched COVID-19-positive patients hospitalized during the study period with moderate to severe disease were recruited as controls. We addressed factors that could be associated with the development of fungal infection and studied the period between COVID-19 positivity and the onset of ROCM. Results The age of patients in both groups ranged from 40-60 years with 13 females and 17 males. A statistically significant correlation (p-value = 0.032) was found between positive reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) history and use of intravenous (IV) corticosteroids (11 [73.3%] cases and all controls). The mean duration from COVID-19 positivity to the presentation of mucormycosis was 12.10&#xb1;7.27 days. Uncontrolled blood sugar was found to be the&#xa0;most significant correlation (p-value = 0.003). Mucormycosis is 13.678 times more likely in people with abnormal hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c). Co-morbidities like anemia, chronic kidney disease (CKD), coronary artery disease (CAD), and leukemia were found in controls, but none of these conditions were seen in patients who developed mucormycosis. Conclusion Judicious use of steroids and strict control of blood sugar levels should be emphasized in the management of COVID-19 patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022, Mehfooz et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehfooz</LastName><ForeName>Samreen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Shri Ram Murti Smarak Institute of Medical Sciences, Bareilly, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehrotra</LastName><ForeName>Neelima</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Shri Ram Murti Smarak Institute of Medical Sciences, Bareilly, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Usmani</LastName><ForeName>Tarim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiodiagnosis, Career Institute of Medical Sciences &amp; Hospital, Lucknow, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raj</LastName><ForeName>Vivek</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiodiagnosis, Career Institute of Medical Sciences &amp; Hospital, Lucknow, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">comorbidities and covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19 and diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19 in ophthalmology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19-associated mucormycosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">otolaryngology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post covid-19 rhino-orbito-cerebral mucormycosis (rocm)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post covid-19 sequelae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">steroids in covid 19</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36579288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9785374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.31822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chronic rhinocerebral mucormycosis. Harrill WC, Stewart MG, Lee AG, Cernoch P. Laryngoscope. 1996;106:1292&#x2013;1297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8849804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slowly progressive cutaneous, rhinofacial, and pulmonary mucormycosis caused by Mucor irregularis in an immunocompetent woman. Xia ZK, Wang WL, Yang RY. Clin Infect Dis. 2013;56:993&#x2013;995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23243187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology and outcome of zygomycosis: a review of 929 reported cases. Roden MM, Zaoutis TE, Buchanan WL, et al. Clin Infect Dis. 2005;41:634&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16080086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The epidemiology and clinical manifestations of mucormycosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of case reports. Jeong W, Keighley C, Wolfe R, Lee WL, Slavin MA, Kong DC, Chen SC. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2019;25:26&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30036666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mucormycosis: battle with the deadly enemy over a five-year period in India. Chander J, Kaur M, Singla N, et al. J Fungi (Basel) 2018;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6023269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29642408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mucormycosis with orbital compartment syndrome in a patient with COVID-19. Werthman-Ehrenreich A. Am J Emerg Med. 2021;42:264&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7493738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Invasive and non-invasive fungal rhinosinusitis-a review and update of the evidence. Deutsch PG, Whittaker J, Prasad S. Medicina (Kaunas) 2019;55</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6681352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31261788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Code mucor: guidelines for the diagnosis, staging and management of rhino-orbito-cerebral mucormycosis in the setting of COVID-19. Honavar SG. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2021;69:1361&#x2013;1365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8302268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology and clinical outcomes of invasive mould infections in Indian intensive care units (FISF study) Chakrabarti A, Kaur H, Savio J, et al. J Crit Care. 2019;51:64&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30769292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A multicentre observational study on the epidemiology, risk factors, management and outcomes of mucormycosis in India. Patel A, Kaur H, Xess I, et al. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2020;26:944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31811914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mucor in a viral land: a tale of two pathogens. Sen M, Lahane S, Lahane TP, Parekh R, Honavar SG. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2021;69:244&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7933891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33463566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rise of the phoenix: mucormycosis in COVID-19 times. Ravani SA, Agrawal GA, Leuva PA, Modi PH, Amin KD. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2021;69:1563&#x2013;1568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8302276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 and orbital mucormycosis. Sarkar S, Gokhale T, Choudhury SS, Deb AK. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2021;69:1002&#x2013;1004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8012924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33727483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fungal co-infections associated with global COVID-19 pandemic: a clinical and diagnostic perspective from China. Song G, Liang G, Liu W. Mycopathologia. 2020;185:599&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7394275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32737747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhino-orbital mucormycosis associated with COVID-19. Mehta S, Pandey A. Cureus. 2020;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7599039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33145132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>