<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37667865</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2037-7452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of translational myology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Transl Myol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of physical activity on long COVID fatigue: an unsolved enigma.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11639</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4081/ejtm.2023.11639</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Covid-19 disease is well documented and often the most common symptoms include myalgia and muscle fatigue. Approximately 10% of those infected complain of persistent fatigue even many months after the end of the acute phase of the disease. This gives rise to a condition different from the previous one and commonly known as 'post-acute COVID-19 syndrome' or simply Long-COVID. Although the origin of muscle fatigue is multifactorial, the state of prolonged fatigue observed in the Long-COVID syndrome suggests the existence of a possible state of atrophy or rather acute sarcopenia. Under these conditions, the use of physical activity programs can effectively counteract the state of atrophy underlying the fatigue phenomena observed. If this is also the situation during the Long-COVID, the muscular symptom should be positively influenced by the administration of programmed physical activity cycles. In fact, in patients with Long-COVID, the few published papers seem to indicate that patients who are physically active and who make an effort to engage in physical activity even during the illness have decreased duration and intensity of the illness. However, analysis of the studies in the literature also suggests that a small percentage of people with Long-COVID do not appear to benefit from the application of physical activity programs, so further studies on homogeneous samples are needed to provide a firm answer to the question: can planned physical activity help patients during the pathological course of Long-COVID?</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coscia</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine Service of the San Candido-Innichen and Brunico-Bruneck Hospitals, Bolzano-Bozen, San Candido. francesco.coscia1@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Filippo</LastName><ForeName>Ester Sara</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience Imaging and Clinical Sciences, University "G. d'Annunzio" of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti, Italy; IIM-Interuniversity Institute of Myology, University "G. d'Annunzio" of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti. es.difilippo@unich.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gigliotti</LastName><ForeName>Paola Virginia</ForeName><Initials>PV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Sport Physiology San Candido-Innichen, University of Perugia, San Candido. pao.gigliotti@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fano Illic</LastName><ForeName>Giorgio</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IIM-Interuniversity Institute of Myology, University "G. d'Annunzio" of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti, Italy; Campus of Free University of Alcatraz, Free University of Alcatraz, Santa Cristina di Gubbio, Gubbio, Italy; A&amp;C M-C Foundation for Translational Myology, Padova. fanoillic@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Transl Myol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2037-7452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>We confirm that we have read the Journal&#x2019;s position on issues involved in ethical publication and affirm that this report is consistent with those guidelines. <b>T</b>oday we live in a time when the COVID-19 pandemic seems to be loosening its grip, but as if to remind us of its existence, it is leaving behind a significant group of acute infection survivors who have not returned to pre-COVID normality, but who show symptoms of functional impairment from which they continue to suffer for weeks or months. This condition, known generically as Long-COVID, leaves those affected in a state of prostration and difficulty in carrying out normal daily activities and a return to the state that existed before the SARS-CoV-2 (severe acute respiratory syndrome by Corona virus 2) infection.<sup>,</sup> Further confusion arises from the different names used to define the condition. According to the UK's National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE), 'post-acute COVID-19 syndrome' (PACS) can be further subdivided into a subacute phase, in which the changes associated with the disease persist for at least 4-12 weeks, and a chronic phase, in which symptoms persist for more than 12 weeks after the onset of the disease, as reported by National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (UK). COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19, available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/ guidance/ng188. The World Health Organisation (WHO) defines Long-COVID as a condition of persistent, debilitating psychophysical alteration that is present at least 3 months after the onset of acute COVID-19 symptoms and persists for at least 2 months without being associated with another diagnosis (World Health Organization: https://www.who.int/publications/ i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1). In addition, the variety and severity of the functional changes that occur during this period are not well understood, nor are specific intervention plans, including pharmacological approaches, able to significantly influence the intensity and duration of the changes identified. However, this does not mean that there are no specific molecular and/or clinical markers to define the onset of the disease.<sup>,,</sup></CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37667865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10583148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/ejtm.2023.11639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Madhavan MV, Sehgal K, Nair N, Mahajan S, Sehrawat TS, Bikdeli B, Ahluwalia N, Ausiello JC, Wan EY, Freedberg DE, Kirtane AJ, Parikh SA, Maurer MS, Nordvig AS, Accili D, Bathon JM, Mohan S, Bauer KA, Leon MB, Krumholz HM, Uriel N, Mehra MR, Elkind MSV, Stone GW, Schwartz A, Ho DD, Bilezikian JP, Landry DW. Extrapulmonary manifestations of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2020. Jul;26(7):1017-1032. doi: 10.1038/s41591-020-0968-3. Epub 2020 Jul 10. PMID: 32651579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32651579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T, Hittle M, Goodman SN. Assessment of the Frequency and Variety of Persistent Symptoms Among Patients With COVID-19: A Systematic Review. JAMA Netw Open. 2021. May 3;4(5):e2111417. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.11417. PMID: 34037731; PMCID: PMC8155823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8155823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34037731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, Cook JR, Nordvig AS, Shalev D, Sehrawat TS, Ahluwalia N, Bikdeli B, Dietz D, Der-Nigoghossian C, Liyanage-Don N, Rosner GF, Bernstein EJ, Mohan S, Beckley AA, Seres DS, Choueiri TK, Uriel N, Ausiello JC, Accili D, Freedberg DE, Baldwin M, Schwartz A, Brodie D, Garcia CK, Elkind MSV, Connors JM, Bilezikian JP, Landry DW, Wan EY. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021. Apr;27(4):601-615. doi: 10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z. Epub 2021 Mar 22. PMID: 33753937; PMCID: PMC8893149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choutka J, Jansari V, Hornig M, Iwasaki A. Unexplained post-acute infection syndromes. Nat Med. 2022. May;28(5):911-923. doi: 10.1038/s41591-022-01810-6. Epub 2022 May 18. Erratum in: Nat Med. 2022. Aug;28(8): 1723. PMID: 35585196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35585196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honarmand A, Sheybani F, Aflatoonian E, Saberinia A. COVID-19 patients at referral to hospital during the first peak of disease: Common clinical findings including myalgia and fatigue. Eur J Transl Myol. 2022. Aug 12;32(3):10731. doi: 10.4081/ejtm.2022.10731. PMID: 36036352; PMCID: PMC9580529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36036352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, Pujol JC, Klaser K, Antonelli M, Canas LS, Molteni E, Modat M, Jorge Cardoso M, May A, Ganesh S, Davies R, Nguyen LH, Drew DA, Astley CM, Joshi AD, Merino J, Tsereteli N, Fall T, Gomez MF, Duncan EL, Menni C, Williams FMK, Franks PW, Chan AT, Wolf J, Ourselin S, Spector T, Steves CJ. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021. Apr;27(4):626-631. doi: 10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y. Epub 2021 Mar 10. Erratum in: Nat Med. 2021. Jun;27(6): 1116. PMID: 33692530; PMCID: PMC7611399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirwan R, McCullough D, Butler T, Perez de Heredia F, Davies IG, Stewart C. Sarcopenia during COVID-19 lockdown restrictions: long-term health effects of short-term muscle loss. GeroScience. 2020;42(6):1547-1578. doi:10.1007/s11357-020-00272-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7528158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33001410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constantin-Teodosiu D, Constantin D. Molecular Mechanisms of Muscle Fatigue. Int J Mol Sci. 2021. Oct 27;22(21):11587. doi: 10.3390/ijms222111587. PMID: 34769017; PMCID: PMC8584022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8584022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34769017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romanello V, Sandri M. The connection between the dynamic remodeling of the mitochondrial network and the regulation of muscle mass. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2021. Feb;78(4):1305-1328. doi: 10.1007/s00018-020-03662-0. Epub 2020 Oct 19. PMID: 33078210; PMCID: PMC7904552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7904552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33078210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman AB, Kupelian V, Visser M, et al. . Strength, but not muscle mass, is associated with mortality in the health, aging and body composition study cohort. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2006;61(1):72-77. doi:10.1093/gerona/61.1.72</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16456196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piotrowicz K, G&#x105;sowski J, Michel JP, Veronese N. Post-COVID-19 acute sarcopenia: physiopathology and management. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2021. Oct;33(10):2887-2898. doi: 10.1007/s40520-021-01942-8. Epub 2021 Jul 30. PMID: 34328636; PMCID: PMC8323089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8323089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34328636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao W, Sun Y, Zhang T, Zou L, Wu X, Wang D, Chen Z. Exercise Programs for Muscle Mass, Muscle Strength and Physical Performance in Older Adults with Sarcopenia: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Aging Dis. 2020. Jul 23;11(4):863-873. doi: 10.14336/AD.2019.1012. PMID: 32765951; PMCID: PMC7390512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7390512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32765951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matusewicz L, Golec M, Czogalla A, Kuliczkowski K, Konka A, Zembala-John J, Sikorski AF. COVID-19 therapies: do we see substantial progress? Cell Mol Biol Lett. 2022. May 31;27(1):42. doi: 10.1186/s11658-022-00341-9. PMID: 35641916; PMCID: PMC9152818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9152818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35641916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson WR, Sallis R, Joy E, Jaworski CA, Stuhr RM, Trilk JL. Exercise Is Medicine. Am J Lifestyle Med. 2020. Apr 22;14(5):511-523. doi: 10.1177/1559827620912192. PMID: 32922236; PMCID: PMC7444006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7444006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32922236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Feltz-Cornelis CM, Sweetman J, Edwards M, Gall N, Gilligan J, Hayle S, Kaul A, Moriarty AS, Perros P, Sampford J, Smith N, Elfeddali I, Varley D, Gower J. Identifying the top research priorities in medically not yet explained symptoms (MNYES): a James Lind Alliance priority setting partnership. BMJ Open. 2022. Jul 1;12(7):e061263. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-061263. PMID: 35777869; PMCID: PMC9252198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9252198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35777869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez A, Abrigo J, Achiardi O, Simon F, Cabello-Verrugio C. Intensive care unit-acquired weakness: A review from molecular mechanisms to its impact in COVID-2019. Eur J Transl Myol. 2022. Aug 26;32(3):10511. doi: 10.4081/ejtm.2022. 10511. PMID: 36036350; PMCID: PMC9580540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36036350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirmayer LJ, Groleau D, Looper KJ, Dao MD. Explaining medically unexplained symptoms. Can J Psychiatry. 2004. Oct;49(10):663-72. doi: 10.1177/070674370404901003. PMID: 15560312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15560312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkodaymi MS, Omrani OA, Fawzy NA, Shaar BA, Almamlouk R, Riaz M, Obeidat M, Obeidat Y, Gerberi D, Taha RM, Kashour Z, Kashour T, Berbari EF, Alkattan K, Tleyjeh IM. Prevalence of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome symptoms at different follow-up periods: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022. May;28(5):657-666. doi: 10.1016/j.cmi.2022.01. 014. Epub 2022 Feb 3. PMID: 35124265; PMCID: PMC8812092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8812092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M. Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nat Immunol. 2022. Feb;23(2):194-202. doi: 10.1038/s41590-021-01104-y. Epub 2022 Feb 1. PMID: 35105985; PMCID: PMC9127978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fawzy NA, Abou Shaar B, Taha RM, Arabi TZ, Sabbah BN, Alkodaymi MS, Omrani OA, Makhzoum T, Almahfoudh NE, Al-Hammad QA, Hejazi W, Obeidat Y, Osman N, Al-Kattan KM, Berbari EF, Tleyjeh IM. A systematic review of trials currently investigating therapeutic modalities for post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and registered on WHO International Clinical Trials Platform. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2023. May;29(5):570-577. doi: 10.1016/j.cmi.2023.01.007. Epub 2023 Jan 13. PMID: 36642173; PMCID: PMC9837206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9837206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36642173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Burden of Disease Long COVID Collaborators Wulf Hanson S, Abbafati C, et al. . Estimated Global Proportions of Individuals With Persistent Fatigue, Cognitive, and Respiratory Symptom Clusters Following Symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA. 2022. Oct 25;328(16):1604-1615. doi: 10.1001/jama.2022.18931. PMID: 36215063; PMCID: PMC9552043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherif ZA, Gomez CR, Connors TJ, Henrich TJ, Reeves WB; RECOVER Mechanistic Pathway Task Force. Pathogenic mechanisms of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC). Elife. 2023. Mar 22;12:e86002. doi: 10.7554/eLife.86002. PMID: 36947108; PMCID: PMC10032659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10032659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36947108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023. Mar;21(3):133-146. doi: 10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2. Epub 2023 Jan 13. Erratum in: Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023. Jun;21(6): 408. PMID: 36639608; PMCID: PMC9839201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Almeida K, Nogueira Alves IG, de Queiroz RS, de Castro MR, Gomes VA, Santos Fontoura FC, Brites C, Neto MG. A systematic review on physical function, activities of daily living and health-related quality of life in COVID-19 survivors. Chronic Illn. 2023. Jun;19(2):279-303. doi: 10.1177/17423953221089309. Epub 2022 Apr 11. PMID: 35404175; PMCID: PMC9006095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9006095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35404175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson EJ, Walker AJ, Bhaskaran K, Bacon S, Bates C, Morton CE, Curtis HJ, Mehrkar A, Evans D, Inglesby P, Cockburn J, McDonald HI, MacKenna B, Tomlinson L, Douglas IJ, Rentsch CT, Mathur R, Wong AYS, Grieve R, Harrison D, Forbes H, Schultze A, Croker R, Parry J, Hester F, Harper S, Perera R, Evans SJW, Smeeth L, Goldacre B. Factors associated with COVID-19-related death using OpenSAFELY. Nature. 2020. Aug;584(7821):430-436. doi: 10.1038/s41586-020-2521-4. Epub 2020 Jul 8. PMID: 32640463; PMCID: PMC7611074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32640463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kouhpayeh H. Clinical features predicting COVID-19 mortality risk. Eur J Transl Myol. 2022. Apr 12;32(2):10268. doi: 10.4081/ejtm.2022.10268. PMID: 35421918; PMCID: PMC9295175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9295175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35421918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu YW, Xu HS, Liu SJ. COVID-19 and neurodegenerative diseases. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2022. Jun;26(12):4535-4544. doi: 10.26355/eurrev_202206_29093. PMID: 35776055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35776055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denaro CA, Haloush YI, Hsiao SY, Orgera JJ, Osorio T, Riggs LM, Sassaman JW, Williams SA, Monte Carlo AR, 3rd, Da Costa RT, Grigoriev A, Solesio ME. COVID-19 and neurodegeneration: The mitochondrial connection. Aging Cell. 2022. Nov;21(11):e13727. doi: 10.1111/acel.13727. Epub 2022 Oct 11. PMID: 36219531; PMCID: PMC9649608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9649608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36219531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hull JH, Wootten M, Moghal M, Heron N, Martin R, Walsted ES, Biswas A, Loosemore M, Elliott N, Ranson C. Clinical patterns, recovery time and prolonged impact of COVID-19 illness in international athletes: the UK experience. Br J Sports Med. 2022. Jan;56(1):4-11. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2021-104392. Epub 2021 Aug 2. PMID: 34340972; PMCID: PMC8331321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34340972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wezenbeek E, Denolf S, Willems TM, Pieters D, Bourgois JG, Philippaerts RM, De Winne B, Wieme M, Van Hecke R, Markey L, Schuermans J, Witvrouw E, Verstockt S. Association between SARS-COV-2 infection and muscle strain injury occurrence in elite male football players: a prospective study of 29 weeks including three teams from the Belgian professional football league. Br J Sports Med. 2022. Apr 29:bjsports-2021-104595. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2021-104595. Epub ahead of print. PMID: 35487684; PMCID: PMC9062454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35487684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zsichla L, M&#xfc;ller V. Risk Factors of Severe COVID-19: A Review of Host, Viral and Environmental Factors. Viruses. 2023. Jan 7;15(1):175. doi: 10.3390/v15010175. PMID: 36680215; PMCID: PMC9863423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9863423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36680215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang PY, Li Y, Wang Q. Sarcopenia: An underlying treatment target during the COVID-19 pandemic. Nutrition. 2021. Apr;84:111104. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2020.111104. Epub 2020 Dec 5. PMID: 33421827; PMCID: PMC7833321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33421827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzywa&#x144;ski J, Mikulski T, Krysztofiak H, Pokrywka A, M&#x142;y&#x144;czak M, Ma&#x142;ek &#x141;A, Kwiatkowska D, Kuchar E. Elite athletes with COVID-19 - Predictors of the course of disease. J Sci Med Sport. 2022. Jan;25(1):9-14. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2021.07.003. Epub 2021 Jul 14. PMID: 34334321; PMCID: PMC8277540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8277540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34334321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coscia F, Mancinelli R, Gigliotti PV, Checcaglini F, Fan&#xf2;-Illic G. Physical Activity Effects on Muscle Fatigue in Sport in Active Adults with Long COVID-19: An Observational Study. Diagnostics (Basel). 2023. Apr 3;13(7):1336. doi: 10.3390/diagnostics13071336. PMID: 37046554; PMCID: PMC10093327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10093327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37046554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemes IR, Smaira FI, Ribeiro WJD, Favero NK, Matos LDNJ, Pinto ALS, Dolan E, Gualano B; Coalition SPORT-COVID-19. Acute and post-acute COVID-19 presentations in athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2022. Aug;56(16):941-947. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2022-105583. Epub 2022 May 27. PMID: 35623887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35623887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petek BJ, Moulson N, Baggish AL, Kliethermes SA, Patel MR, Churchill TW, Harmon KG, Drezner JA; ORCCA Investigators. Prevalence and clinical implications of persistent or exertional cardiopulmonary symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection in 3597 collegiate athletes: a study from the Outcomes Registry for Cardiac Conditions in Athletes (ORCCA). Br J Sports Med. 2022. Aug;56(16):913-918. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2021-104644. Epub 2021 Nov 1. PMID: 34725052; PMCID: PMC8561826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8561826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34725052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollbracht C, Kraft K. Oxidative Stress and Hyper-Inflammation as Major Drivers of Severe COVID-19 and Long COVID: Implications for the Benefit of High-Dose Intravenous Vitamin C. Front Pharmacol. 2022. Apr 29;13:899198. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2022.899198. PMID: 35571085; PMCID: PMC9100929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9100929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35571085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moldogazieva NT, Mokhosoev IM, Feldman NB, Lutsenko SV. ROS and RNS signalling: adaptive redox switches through oxidative/nitrosative protein modifications. Free Radic Res. 2018. May;52(5):507-543. doi: 10.1080/10715762.2018.1457217. Epub 2018 Apr 19. PMID: 29589770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29589770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul BD, Lemle MD, Komaroff AL, Snyder SH. Redox imbalance links COVID-19 and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2021. Aug 24;118(34):e2024358118. doi: 10.1073/pnas.2024358118. PMID: 34400495; PMCID: PMC8403932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8403932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34400495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohiuddin M, Kasahara K. The emerging role of oxidative stress in complications of COVID-19 and potential therapeutic approach to diminish oxidative stress. Respir Med. 2021. Oct;187:106605. doi: 10.1016/j.rmed.2021.106605. Epub 2021 Sep 6. PMID: 34507024; PMCID: PMC8420129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8420129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34507024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hakeim HK, Al-Rubaye HT, Al-Hadrawi DS, Almulla AF, Maes M. Long-COVID post-viral chronic fatigue and affective symptoms are associated with oxidative damage, lowered antioxidant defenses and inflammation: a proof of concept and mechanism study. Mol Psychiatry. 2023. Feb;28(2):564-578. doi: 10.1038/s41380-022-01836-9. Epub 2022 Oct 24. PMID: 36280755; PMCID: PMC9589528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9589528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36280755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, McAuley DF, Brown M, Sanchez E, Tattersall RS, Manson JJ; HLH Across Speciality Collaboration, UK. COVID-19: consider cytokine storm syndromes and immunosuppression. Lancet. 2020. Mar 28;395(10229):1033-1034. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30628-0. Epub 2020 Mar 16. PMID: 32192578; PMCID: PMC7270045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laforge M, Elbim C, Fr&#xe8;re C, H&#xe9;madi M, Massaad C, Nuss P, Benoliel JJ, Becker C. Tissue damage from neutrophil-induced oxidative stress in COVID-19. Nat Rev Immunol. 2020. Sep;20(9):515-516. doi: 10.1038/s41577-020-0407-1. Erratum in: Nat Rev Immunol. 2020. Aug 10;: PMID: 32728221; PMCID: PMC7388427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7388427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32728221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares MN, Eggelbusch M, Naddaf E, Gerrits KHL, van der Schaaf M, van den Borst B, Wiersinga WJ, van Vugt M, Weijs PJM, Murray AJ, W&#xfc;st RCI. Skeletal muscle alterations in patients with acute Covid-19 and post-acute sequelae of Covid-19. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022. Feb;13(1):11-22. doi: 10.1002/jcsm.12896. Epub 2022 Jan 7. PMID: 34997689; PMCID: PMC8818659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8818659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34997689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hakeim HK, Al-Rubaye HT, Almulla AF, Al-Hadrawi DS, Maes M. Chronic Fatigue, Depression and Anxiety Symptoms in Long COVID Are Strongly Predicted by Neuroimmune and Neuro-Oxidative Pathways Which Are Caused by the Inflammation during Acute Infection. J Clin Med. 2023. Jan 8;12(2):511. doi: 10.3390/jcm12020511. PMID: 36675440; PMCID: PMC9865328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9865328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36675440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuyama T, Yoshinaga SK, Shibue K, Mak TW. Comorbidity-associated glutamine deficiency is a predisposition to severe COVID-19. Cell Death Differ. 2021. Dec;28(12):3199-3213. doi: 10.1038/s41418-021-00892-y. Epub 2021 Oct 18. PMID: 34663907; PMCID: PMC8522258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8522258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34663907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G, Di Girolamo FG, McDonnell A, Fiotti N, Mearelli F, Situlin R, Gonelli A, Dapas B, Giordano M, Lainscak M, Grassi G, Zauli G, Secchiero P, Mekjavic I. Effects of Hypoxia and Bed Rest on Markers of Cardiometabolic Risk: Compensatory Changes in Circulating TRAIL and Glutathione Redox Capacity. Front Physiol. 2018. Jul 30;9:1000. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2018.01000. PMID: 30104982; PMCID: PMC6077233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6077233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30104982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Girolamo FG, Fiotti N, Sisto UG, Nunnari A, Colla S, Mearelli F, Vinci P, Schincariol P, Biolo G. Skeletal Muscle in Hypoxia and Inflammation: Insights on the COVID-19 Pandemic. Front Nutr. 2022. Apr 22;9:865402. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2022.865402. PMID: 35529457; PMCID: PMC9072827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9072827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35529457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitts RH. Cellular mechanisms of muscle fatigue. Physiol Rev. 1994. Jan;74(1):49-94. doi: 10.1152/physrev.1994.74.1.49. PMID: 8295935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8295935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sartori R, Romanello V, Sandri M. Mechanisms of muscle atrophy and hypertrophy: implications in health and disease. Nat Commun. 2021. Jan 12;12(1):330. doi: 10.1038/s41467-020-20123-1. PMID: 33436614; PMCID: PMC7803748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7803748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33436614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL, Lipkin WI. Insights from myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome may help unravel the pathogenesis of postacute COVID-19 syndrome. Trends Mol Med. 2021. Sep;27(9):895-906. doi: 10.1016/j.molmed.2021.06.002. Epub 2021 Jun 7. PMID: 34175230; PMCID: PMC8180841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8180841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34175230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M, Al-Rubaye HT, Almulla AF, Al-Hadrawi DS, Stoyanova K, Kubera M, Al-Hakeim HK. Lowered Quality of Life in Long COVID Is Predicted by Affective Symptoms, Chronic Fatigue Syndrome, Inflammation and Neuroimmunotoxic Pathways. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022. Aug 19;19(16):10362. doi: 10.3390/ijerph191610362. PMID: 36011997; PMCID: PMC9408685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9408685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36011997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth KJ, Scheibenbogen C. Pathophysiology of skeletal muscle disturbances in Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS). J Transl Med. 2021. Apr 21;19(1):162. doi: 10.1186/s12967-021-02833-2. PMID: 33882940; PMCID: PMC8058748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8058748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33882940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood E, Hall KH, Tate W. Role of mitochondria, oxidative stress and the response to antioxidants in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: A possible approach to SARS-CoV-2 'long-haulers'? Chronic Dis Transl Med. 2021. Mar;7(1):14-26. doi: 10.1016/j.cdtm.2020.11.002. Epub 2020 Nov 21. PMID: 33251031; PMCID: PMC7680046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7680046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33251031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrangelo T, Fulle S, Coscia F, Gigliotti PV, Fan&#xf2;-Illic G. Old muscle in young body: an aphorism describing the Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Eur J Transl Myol. 2018. Sep 7;28(3):7688. doi: 10.4081/ejtm.2018.7688. PMID: 30344981; PMCID: PMC6176399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6176399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30344981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sies H, Jones DP. Reactive oxygen species (ROS) as pleiotropic physiological signalling agents. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2020. Jul;21(7):363-383. doi: 10.1038/s41580-020-0230-3. Epub 2020 Mar 30. PMID: 32231263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32231263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Filippo ES, Checcaglini F, Fan&#xf2;-Illic G, Fulle S. H2O2/Ca2+/Zn2+ Complex Can Be Considered a &#x201c;Collaborative Sensor&#x201d; of the Mitochondrial Capacity? Antioxid Basel Switz. 2022;11(2):342. doi:10.3390/antiox11020342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8868167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35204224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trinity JD, Craig JC, Fermoyle CC, McKenzie AI, Lewis MT, Park SH, Rondina MT, Richardson RS. Impact of presymptomatic COVID-19 on vascular and skeletal muscle function: a case study. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2021. Jun 1;130(6):1961-1970. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00236.2021. Epub 2021 May 18. PMID: 34002634; PMCID: PMC8213510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8213510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34002634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancinelli R, Checcaglini F, Coscia F, Gigliotti P, Fulle S, Fan&#xf2;-Illic G. Biological Aspects of Selected Myokines in Skeletal Muscle: Focus on Aging. Int J Mol Sci. 2021. Aug 7;22(16):8520. doi: 10.3390/ijms22168520. PMID: 34445222; PMCID: PMC8395159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8395159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34445222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johann K, Kleinert M, Klaus S. The Role of GDF15 as a Myomitokine. Cells. 2021. Nov 3;10(11):2990. doi: 10.3390/cells10112990. PMID: 34831213; PMCID: PMC8616340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8616340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34831213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retornaz F, Rebaudet S, Stavris C, Jammes Y. Long-term neuromuscular consequences of SARS-Cov-2 and their similarities with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: results of the retrospective CoLGEM study. J Transl Med. 2022. Sep 24;20(1):429. doi: 10.1186/s12967-022-03638-7. PMID: 36153556; PMCID: PMC9509619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9509619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36153556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Zhou W, Yang L, You R. Physiological and pathological regulation of ACE2, the SARS-CoV-2 receptor. Pharmacol Res. 2020. Jul;157:104833. doi: 10.1016/j.phrs.2020.104833. Epub 2020 Apr 14. PMID: 32302706; PMCID: PMC7194807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32302706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Giorgio MR, Di Noia S, Morciano C, Conte D. The impact of SARS-CoV-2 on skeletal muscles. Acta Myol. 2020. Dec 1;39(4):307-312. doi: 10.36185/2532-1900-034. PMID: 33458586; PMCID: PMC7783438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7783438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33458586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamilloux Y, Henry T, Belot A, Viel S, Fauter M, El Jammal T, Walzer T, Fran&#xe7;ois B, S&#xe8;ve P. Should we stimulate or suppress immune responses in COVID-19? Cytokine and anti-cytokine interventions. Autoimmun Rev. 2020. Jul;19(7):102567. doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2020.102567. Epub 2020 May 4. PMID: 32376392; PMCID: PMC7196557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7196557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32376392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nigro E, Polito R, Alfieri A, Mancini A, Imperlini E, Elce A, Krustrup P, Orr&#xf9; S, Buono P, Daniele A. Molecular mechanisms involved in the positive effects of physical activity on coping with COVID-19. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020. Dec;120(12):2569-2582. doi: 10.1007/s00421-020-04484-5. Epub 2020 Sep 3. PMID: 32885275; PMCID: PMC7471545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7471545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32885275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajaz S, McPhail MJ, Singh KK, Mujib S, Trovato FM, Napoli S, Agarwal K. Mitochondrial metabolic manipulation by SARS-CoV-2 in peripheral blood mononuclear cells of patients with COVID-19. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2021. Jan 1;320(1):C57-C65. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.00426.2020. Epub 2020 Nov 5. PMID: 33151090; PMCID: PMC7816428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7816428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33151090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrandi PJ, Alway SE, Mohamed JS. The interaction between SARS-CoV-2 and ACE2 may have consequences for skeletal muscle viral susceptibility and myopathies. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2020. Oct 1;129(4):864-867. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00321.2020. Epub 2020 Jul 16. PMID: 32673162; PMCID: PMC7832004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32673162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reggiani C, Schiaffino S. Muscle hypertrophy and muscle strength: dependent or independent variables? A provocative review. Eur J Transl Myol. 2020. Sep 9;30(3):9311. doi: 10.4081/ejtm.2020.9311. PMID: 33117512; PMCID: PMC7582410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7582410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33117512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, Legarra-Gorgo&#xf1;on G, Oscoz-Ochandorena S, Garc&#xed;a-Alonso Y, Garc&#xed;a-Alonso N, Oteiza J, Ernaga Lorea A, Correa-Rodr&#xed;guez M, Izquierdo M. Reduced muscle strength in patients with long-COVID-19 syndrome is mediated by limb muscle mass. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2023 Jan 1;134(1):50-58. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00599.2022. Epub 2022 Nov 30. PMID: 36448687; PMCID: PMC9762963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9762963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36448687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantu N, Vyavahare S, Kumar S, Chen J, Kolhe R, Isales CM, Hamrick M, Fulzele S. Synergistic Effects of Multiple Factors Involved in COVID-19-dependent Muscle Loss. Aging Dis. 2022. Apr 1;13(2):344-352. doi: 10.14336/AD.2021.0817. PMID: 35371610; PMCID: PMC8947833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8947833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35371610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swarnakar R, Jenifa S, Wadhwa S. Musculoskeletal complications in long COVID-19: A systematic review. World J Virol. 2022. Nov 25;11(6):485-495. doi: 10.5501/wjv.v11.i6.485. PMID: 36483107; PMCID: PMC9724204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9724204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36483107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotler J, Holtzman C, Dudun C, Jason LA. A Brief Questionnaire to Assess Post-Exertional Malaise. Diagnostics (Basel). 2018. Sep 11;8(3):66. doi: 10.3390/diagnostics8030066. PMID: 30208578; PMCID: PMC6165517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6165517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30208578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xe9;cary S, Gaboury I, Poirier S, Garcia C, Simpson S, Bull M, Brown D, Daigle F. Humility and Acceptance: Working Within Our Limits With Long COVID and Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2021. May;51(5):197-200. doi: 10.2519/jospt.2021.0106. PMID: 33930983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33930983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larun L, Brurberg KG, Odgaard-Jensen J, Price JR. Exercise therapy for chronic fatigue syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017. Apr 25;4(4):CD003200. doi: 10.1002/14651858. CD003200.pub7. Update in: Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019. Oct 02;10: CD003200. PMID: 28444695; PMCID: PMC6419524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6419524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28444695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dannaway J, New CC, New CH, Maher CG. Exercise therapy is a beneficial intervention for chronic fatigue syndrome (PEDro synthesis). Br J Sports Med. 2018. Apr;52(8):542-543. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2017-098407. Epub 2017 Oct 5. PMID: 28982730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28982730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carraro U, Kern H, Gava P, Hofer C, Loefler S, Gargiulo P, Mosole S, Zampieri S, Gobbo V, Ravara B, Piccione F, Marcante A, Baba A, Schils S, Pond A, Gava F. Biology of Muscle Atrophy and of its Recovery by FES in Aging and Mobility Impairments: Roots and By-Products. Eur J Transl Myol. 2015. Aug 25;25(4):221-30. doi: 10.4081/ejtm.2015.5272. PMID: 26913160; PMCID: PMC4748978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4748978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26913160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosole S, Rossini K, Kern H, L&#xf6;fler S, Fruhmann H, Vogelauer M, Burggraf S, Grim-Stieger M, Cve&#x10d;ka J, Hamar D, Sedliak M, &#x160;arabon N, Pond A, Biral D, Carraro U, Zampieri S. Reinnervation of Vastus lateralis is increased significantly in seniors (70-years old) with a lifelong history of high-level exercise (2013, revisited here in 2022). Eur J Transl Myol. 2022. Feb 28;32(1):10420. doi: 10.4081/ejtm.2022.10420. PMID: 35234026; PMCID: PMC8992670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8992670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35234026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehy LM. Considerations for Postacute Rehabilitation for Survivors of COVID-19. JMIR Public Health Surveill. 2020. May 8;6(2):e19462. doi: 10.2196/19462. PMID: 32369030; PMCID: PMC7212817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7212817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32369030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grishechkina IA, Lobanov AA, Andronov SV, Rachin AP, Fesyun AD, Ivanova EP, Masiero S, Maccarone MC. Long-term outcomes of different rehabilitation programs in patients with long COVID syndrome: a cohort prospective study. Eur J Transl Myol. 2023. Apr 13;33(2):11063. doi: 10.4081/ejtm.2023.11063. PMID: 37052043; PMCID: PMC10388602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10388602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37052043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi Hekmatikar AH, Ferreira J&#xfa;nior JB, Shahrbanian S, Suzuki K. Functional and Psychological Changes after Exercise Training in Post-COVID-19 Patients Discharged from the Hospital: A PRISMA-Compliant Systematic Review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022. Feb 17;19(4):2290. doi: 10.3390/ijerph19042290. PMID: 35206483; PMCID: PMC8871540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8871540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35206483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cattadori G, Di Marco S, Baravelli M, Picozzi A, Ambrosio G. Exercise Training in Post-COVID-19 Patients: The Need for a Multifactorial Protocol for a Multifactorial Pathophysiology. J Clin Med. 2022. Apr 15;11(8):2228. doi: 10.3390/jcm11082228. PMID: 35456321; PMCID: PMC9028177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9028177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35456321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scurati R, Papini N, Giussani P, Alberti G, Tringali C. The Challenge of Long COVID-19 Management: From Disease Molecular Hallmarks to the Proposal of Exercise as Therapy. Int J Mol Sci. 2022. Oct 14;23(20):12311. doi: 10.3390/ijms232012311. PMID: 36293160; PMCID: PMC9603679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9603679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36293160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu Y, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Garc&#xed;a B, Lehmann HI, Li G, Kroemer G, L&#xf3;pez-Ot&#xed;n C, Xiao J. Exercise sustains the hallmarks of health. J Sport Health Sci. 2023. Jan;12(1):8-35. doi: 10.1016/j.jshs.2022.10.003. Epub 2022 Oct 29. PMID: 36374766; PMCID: PMC9923435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9923435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36374766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabello-Verrugio C, Morales MG, Rivera JC, Cabrera D, Simon F. Renin-angiotensin system: an old player with novel functions in skeletal muscle. Med Res Rev. 2015. May;35(3):437-63. doi: 10.1002/med.21343. Epub 2015 Mar 11. PMID: 25764065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25764065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales MG, Abrigo J, Acu&#xf1;a MJ, Santos RA, Bader M, Brandan E, Simon F, Olguin H, Cabrera D, Cabello-Verrugio C. Angiotensin-(1-7) attenuates disuse skeletal muscle atrophy in mice via its receptor, Mas. Dis Model Mech. 2016. Apr;9(4):441-9. doi: 10.1242/dmm.023390. Epub 2016 Feb 5. PMID: 26851244; PMCID: PMC4852504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4852504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26851244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>