<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34877576</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2699-9404</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Global medical genetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Glob Med Genet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>From Anti-Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 Immune Response to Cancer Onset via Molecular Mimicry and Cross-Reactivity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>176</StartPage><EndPage>182</EndPage><MedlinePgn>176-182</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/s-0041-1735590</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Background and Objectives</b> &#x2003;Whether exposure to severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) may predispose to the risk of cancer in individuals with no prior cancers is a crucial question that remains unclear. To confirm/refute possible relationships between exposure to the virus and ex novo insurgence of tumors, this study analyzed molecular mimicry and the related cross-reactive potential between SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein (gp) antigen and human tumor-suppressor proteins. <b>Materials and Methods</b> &#x2003;Tumor-associated proteins were retrieved from UniProt database and analyzed for pentapeptide sharing with SARS-CoV-2 spike gp by using publicly available databases. <b>Results</b> &#x2003;An impressively high level of molecular mimicry exists between SARS-CoV-2 spike gp and tumor-associated proteins. Numerically, 294 tumor-suppressor proteins share 308 pentapeptides with the viral antigen. Crucially, the shared peptides have a relevant immunologic potential by repeatedly occurring in experimentally validated epitopes. Such immunologic potential is of further relevancy in that most of the shared peptides are also present in infectious pathogens to which, in general, human population has already been exposed, thus indicating the possibility of immunologic imprint phenomena. <b>Conclusion</b> &#x2003;This article described a vast peptide overlap between SARS-CoV-2 spike gp and tumor-suppressor proteins, and supports autoimmune cross-reactivity as a potential mechanism underlying prospective cancer insurgence following exposure to SARS-CoV-2. Clinically, the findings call for close surveillance of tumor sequelae that possibly could result from the current coronavirus pandemic.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>The Author(s). This is an open access article published by Thieme under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, permitting unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction so long as the original work is properly cited. ( https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/ ).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kanduc</LastName><ForeName>Darja</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2111-4608</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences, Biotechnologies, and Biopharmaceutics, University of Bari, Bari, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Glob Med Genet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101769583</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2699-9404</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2 spike gp</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cancer epidemic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cross-reactivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">molecular mimicry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tumor-suppressor proteins</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34877576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8635832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0041-1735590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2100033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X.Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China Lancet 2020395(10223):497&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghzadeh-Bazargan A, Rezai M, Najar Nobari N, Mozafarpoor S, Goodarzi A. Skin manifestations as potential symptoms of diffuse vascular injury in critical COVID-19 patients. J Cutan Pathol. 2021 doi: 10.1111/cup.14059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cup.14059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33978234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boechat J L, Chora I, Morais A, Delgado L. The immune response to SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19 immunopathology - current perspectives. Pulmonology. 2021;27(05):423&#x2013;437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8040543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33867315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera Martimbianco A L, Pacheco R L, Bagattini &#xc2;M, Riera R. Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID-19: s systematic review. Int J Clin Pract. 2021:e14357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8236920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33977626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen H R, O'Connell C, Nadim M K. Extrapulmonary manifestations of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 infection. J Med Virol. 2021;93(05):2645&#x2013;2653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33090515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Casals M, Brito-Zer&#xf3;n P, Mariette X. Systemic and organ-specific immune-related manifestations of COVID-19. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2021;17(06):315&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33903743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su&#xe1;rez-Reyes A, Villegas-Valverde C A. Implications of low-grade inflammation in SARS-CoV-2 immunopathology. MEDICC Rev. 2021;23(02):42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33974614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han H J, Nwagwu C, Anyim O, Ekweremadu C, Kim S. COVID-19 and cancer: from basic mechanisms to vaccine development using nanotechnology. Int Immunopharmacol. 2021;90:107247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7709613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33307513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corti C, Curigliano G. Commentary: SARS-CoV-2 vaccines and cancer patients. Ann Oncol. 2021;32(04):569&#x2013;571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7831848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia P, Dubrovska A. Tumor markers as an entry for SARS-CoV-2 infection? FEBS J. 2020;287(17):3677&#x2013;3680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7436716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakravarty D, Ratnani P, Sobotka S. Increased hospitalization and mortality from COVID-19 in prostate cancer patients. Cancers (Basel) 2021;13(07):1630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8037308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33915795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanni G, Pellicciaro M, Materazzo M. Advanced stages and increased need for adjuvant treatments in breast cancer patients: the effect of the one-year COVID-19 pandemic. Anticancer Res. 2021;41(05):2689&#x2013;2696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33952500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J Y, Lee Y J, Kim T. Collateral effects of the coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic on lung cancer diagnosis in Korea. BMC Cancer. 2020;20(01):1040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7594984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33121456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor R, Omakobia E, Sood S, Glore R J. The impact of coronavirus disease 2019 on head and neck cancer services: a UK tertiary centre study. J Laryngol Otol. 2020;134(08):684&#x2013;687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7426614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32758307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derosa L, Melenotte C, Griscelli F. The immuno-oncological challenge of COVID-19. Nat Can. 2020;1:946&#x2013;964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natale C, Giannini T, Lucchese A, Kanduc D. Computer-assisted analysis of molecular mimicry between human papillomavirus 16 E7 oncoprotein and human protein sequences. Immunol Cell Biol. 2000;78(06):580&#x2013;585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11114967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanduc D, Stufano A, Lucchese G, Kusalik A. Massive peptide sharing between viral and human proteomes. Peptides. 2008;29(10):1755&#x2013;1766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7115663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18582510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucchese G, Capone G, Kanduc D. Peptide sharing between influenza A H1N1 hemagglutinin and human axon guidance proteins. Schizophr Bull. 2014;40(02):362&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3932078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23378012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanduc D. Peptide cross-reactivity: the original sin of vaccines. Front Biosci (Schol Ed) 2012;4:1393&#x2013;1401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22652881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucchese G, Kanduc D. Potential crossreactivity of human immune responses against HCMV glycoprotein B. Curr Drug Discov Technol. 2016;13(01):16&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26825175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucchese G, Kanduc D. Zika virus and autoimmunity: from microcephaly to Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome, and beyond. Autoimmun Rev. 2016;15(08):801&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27019049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanduc D. From anti-SARS-CoV-2 immune responses to COVID-19 via molecular mimicry. Antibodies (Basel) 2020;9(03):33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7551747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32708525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanduc D. Pentapeptides as minimal functional units in cell biology and immunology. Curr Protein Pept Sci. 2013;14(02):111&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23305312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanduc D. Homology, similarity, and identity in peptide epitope immunodefinition. J Pept Sci. 2012;18(08):487&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22696298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UniProt Consortium UniProt: a worldwide hub of protein knowledge Nucleic Acids Res 201947(D1):D506&#x2013;D515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6323992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30395287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vita R, Mahajan S, Overton J A.The Immune Epitope Database (IEDB): 2018 update Nucleic Acids Res 201947(D1):D339&#x2013;D343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6324067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30357391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutierrez A, Kentsis A, Sanda T. The BCL11B tumor suppressor is mutated across the major molecular subtypes of T-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Blood. 2011;118(15):4169&#x2013;4173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3204734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21878675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartram I, G&#xf6;kbuget N, Schlee C. Low expression of T-cell transcription factor BCL11b predicts inferior survival in adult standard risk T-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia patients. J Hematol Oncol. 2014;7:51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4223626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25023966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang P, Kollmeyer T M, Buckner K, Bamlet W, Ballman K V, Jenkins R B. Polymorphisms in GLTSCR1 and ERCC2 are associated with the development of oligodendrogliomas. Cancer. 2005;103(11):2363&#x2013;2372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15834925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark S L, Rodriguez A M, Snyder R R, Hankins G D, Boehning D. Structure-function of the tumor suppressor BRCA1. Comput Struct Biotechnol J. 2012;1(01):e201204005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3380633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22737296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angeli D, Salvi S, Tedaldi G. Genetic predisposition to breast and ovarian cancers: how many and which genes to test? Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(03):1128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7038038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32046255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai R, Sharma K L, Tiwari S, Misra S, Kumar A, Mittal B. DCC (deleted in colorectal carcinoma) gene variants confer increased susceptibility to gallbladder cancer (Ref. No.: Gene-D-12-01446) Gene. 2013;518(02):303&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23353777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis C A, Vos M D, Howell H, Vallecorsa T, Fults D W, Clark G J. Rig is a novel Ras-related protein and potential neural tumor suppressor. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2002;99(15):9876&#x2013;9881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC125049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12107278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan G, McCormick C, Tufaro F. The link between heparan sulfate and hereditary bone disease: finding a function for the EXT family of putative tumor suppressor proteins. J Clin Invest. 2001;108(04):511&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC209410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11518722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang E Y, Madireddi M T, Gopalkrishnan R V. Genomic structure, chromosomal localization and expression profile of a novel melanoma differentiation associated (mda-7) gene with cancer specific growth suppressing and apoptosis inducing properties. Oncogene. 2001;20(48):7051&#x2013;7063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11704829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen M, Pratscher B, Roka F. Loss of novel mda-7 splice variant (mda-7s) expression is associated with metastatic melanoma. J Invest Dermatol. 2004;123(03):583&#x2013;588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15304100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hisaoka M, Tanaka A, Hashimoto H. Molecular alterations of h-warts/LATS1 tumor suppressor in human soft tissue sarcoma. Lab Invest. 2002;82(10):1427&#x2013;1435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12379777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murakami H, Mizuno T, Taniguchi T. LATS2 is a tumor suppressor gene of malignant mesothelioma. Cancer Res. 2011;71(03):873&#x2013;883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21245096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Benedetto M, Pineau P, Nouet S.Mutation analysis of the 8p22 candidate tumor suppressor gene ATIP/MTUS1 in hepatocellular carcinoma Mol Cell Endocrinol 2006252(1-2):207&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16650523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y, Zhang C, Dai D Q. Identification of DNA methylation-regulated differentially-expressed genes and related pathways using Illumina 450K BeadChip and bioinformatic analysis in gastric cancer. Pathol Res Pract. 2019;215(10):152570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31378454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazarenko I, Sch&#xe4;fer R, Sers C.Mechanisms of the HRSL3 tumor suppressor function in ovarian carcinoma cells J Cell Sci 2007120(Pt 8):1393&#x2013;1404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17374643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J J, Razfar A, Delgado I. 3p21.3 tumor suppressor gene H37/Luca15/RBM5 inhibits growth of human lung cancer cells through cell cycle arrest and apoptosis. Cancer Res. 2006;66(07):3419&#x2013;3427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16585163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandt D T, Baarlink C, Kitzing T M. SCAI acts as a suppressor of cancer cell invasion through the transcriptional control of beta1-integrin. Nat Cell Biol. 2009;11(05):557&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19350017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramakrishna S, Suresh B, Bae S M, Ahn W S, Lim K H, Baek K H. Hyaluronan binding motifs of USP17 and SDS3 exhibit anti-tumor activity. PLoS One. 2012;7(05):e37772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3360616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22662218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacobas D A, Mgbemena V E, Iacobas S, Menezes K M, Wang H, Saganti P B. Genomic fabric remodeling in metastatic clear cell renal cell carcinoma (ccRCC): a new paradigm and proposal for a personalized gene therapy approach. Cancers (Basel) 2020;12(12):3678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7762545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33302383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Everdink W J, Baranova A, Lummen C. RFP2, c13ORF1, and FAM10A4 are the most likely tumor suppressor gene candidates for B-cell chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Cancer Genet Cytogenet. 2003;146(01):48&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14499696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Wu Q, Zhou X, Wu Q, Fang M. TRIM13 inhibited cell proliferation and induced cell apoptosis by regulating NF-&#x3ba;B pathway in non-small-cell lung carcinoma cells. Gene. 2019;715:144015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31357025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis T, Salk J E, Quilligan J J. Experience with vaccination against influenza in the spring of 1947: a preliminary report. Am J Public Health Nations Health. 1947;37(08):1013&#x2013;1016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1623895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18016577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenport F M, Hennessy A V, Francis T., Jr Epidemiologic and immunologic significance of age distribution of antibody to antigenic variants of influenza virus. J Exp Med. 1953;98(06):641&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2136340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13109114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucchese G, Kanduc D. The Guillain&#x2013;Barr&#xe8; peptide signatures: from Zika virus to Campylobacter , and beyond . Virus Adaptation and Treatment. 2017;9:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucchese G, Kanduc D. Minimal immune determinants connect Zika virus, human cytomegalovirus, and Toxoplasma gondii to microcephaly-related human proteins . Am J Reprod Immunol. 2017;77(02):e12608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27878897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanduc D. Immunobiology: on the inexistence of a negative selection process. Adv Stud Biol. 2020;12(01):19&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanduc D. Anti-SARS-CoV-2 Immune response and sudden death: titin as a link. Adv Stud Biol. 2021;13(01):37&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanduc D, Shoenfeld Y. Inter-pathogen peptide sharing and the original antigenic sin: solving a paradox. Open Immunol J. 2018;8:16&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanduc D. Thromboses and hemostasis disorders associated with coronavirus disease 2019: the possible causal role of cross-reactivity and immunological imprinting. Glob Med Genet. 2021 doi: 10.1055/s-0041-1731068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0041-1731068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8635820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34877574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trost B, Lucchese G, Stufano A, Bickis M, Kusalik A, Kanduc D. No human protein is exempt from bacterial motifs, not even one. Self Nonself. 2010;1(04):328&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3062388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21487508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanduc D. The comparative biochemistry of viruses and humans: an evolutionary path towards autoimmunity. Biol Chem. 2019;400(05):629&#x2013;638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30504522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Europe's Beating Cancer Plan: A new EU approach to prevention, treatment and care[Internet] Accessed on May 2021 at:https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_21_342</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>