<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37071080</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-4683</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiology in review</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiol Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cardiovascular Manifestations of the Long COVID Syndrome.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000552</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>While most coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) survivors have had complete resolution of symptoms, a significant proportion have suffered from incomplete recovery. Cardiopulmonary symptoms, such as dyspnea, chest pain, and palpitations are responsible for a substantial symptom burden in COVID-19 survivors. Studies have revealed persistent myocardial injury with late gadolinium enhancement and myocardial scar on cardiac magnetic resonance in a significant proportion of patients. Evidence of myocardial edema, active inflammation, left ventricular dysfunction, and right ventricular dysfunction, is limited to a minority of patients. Large observational studies of COVID-19 survivors have indicated an increased risk of cardiovascular disease compared to the general population, including the risk of coronary artery disease, cardiomyopathy, and arrhythmias. Management of long COVID is focused on supportive therapy to reduce systemic inflammation. Patients with high cardiovascular risk, namely, those who had cardiovascular complications during acute illness, patients who have new onset cardiopulmonary symptoms in the postinfectious period, and competitive athletes, should be evaluated by a cardiovascular specialist. Management of cardiovascular sequelae is currently based on general expert guideline recommendations given the lack of evidence specific to long COVID syndrome. In this review, we outline the cardiovascular manifestations of long COVID, the current evidence supporting cardiac abnormalities in the postinfectious period, and the recommended management of these patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lorente-Ros</LastName><ForeName>Marta</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Medicine, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, Mount Sinai Morningside Hospital, New York, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Das</LastName><ForeName>Subrat</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, New York Medical College, Westchester Medical Center, Valhalla, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elias</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Medicine, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, Mount Sinai Morningside Hospital, New York, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frishman</LastName><ForeName>William H</ForeName><Initials>WH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Westchester Medical Center and New York Medical College, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aronow</LastName><ForeName>Wilbert S</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, New York Medical College, Westchester Medical Center, Valhalla, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiol Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9304686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1061-5377</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37071080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00045415-990000000-00097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO COVID-19 Dashboard. Geneva: World Health Organization. 2020. Available at: https://covid19.who.int/. (last cited: [Dec 17,2022]).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magadum A, Kishore R. Cardiovascular manifestations of COVID-19 infection. Cells. 2020;9:25082508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Madhavan MV, Sehgal K, et al. Extrapulmonary manifestations of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2020;26:1017&#x2013;1032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Sullivan O. Long-term sequelae following previous coronavirus epidemics. Clin Med Lond Engl. 2021;21:e68&#x2013;e70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, et al.; WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Rapid Guideline: Managing the Long-Term Effects of COVID-19. National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2020. Available at: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK567261/. Accessed December 12, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Bluemke DA, L&#xfc;scher TF, et al. Long COVID: post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 with a cardiovascular focus. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:1157&#x2013;1172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logue JK, Franko NM, McCulloch DJ, et al. Sequelae in adults at 6 months after COVID-19 infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e210830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschtick JL, Titus AR, Slocum E, et al. Population-based estimates of post-acute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection (PASC) prevalence and characteristics. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:2055&#x2013;2064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>See&#xdf;le J, Waterboer T, Hippchen T, et al. Persistent symptoms in adult patients 1 year after coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a prospective cohort study. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;74:1191&#x2013;1198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin M, Schommers P, Stecher M, et al. Post-COVID syndrome in non-hospitalised patients with COVID-19: a longitudinal prospective cohort study. Lancet Reg Health - Eur. 2021;6:100122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KGI, Brokstad KA, et al.; Bergen COVID-19 Research Group. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med. 2021;27:1607&#x2013;1613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venturelli S, Benatti SV, Casati M, et al. Surviving COVID-19 in Bergamo province: a post-acute outpatient re-evaluation. Epidemiol Infect. 2021;149:e32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellan M, Soddu D, Balbo PE, et al. Respiratory and psychophysical sequelae among patients with COVID-19 four months after hospital discharge. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2036142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmud R, Rahman MM, Rassel MA, et al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome among symptomatic COVID-19 patients: a prospective cohort study in a tertiary care center of Bangladesh. Zivkovic AR, ed. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0249644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain MA, Hossain KMA, Saunders K, et al. Prevalence of long COVID symptoms in Bangladesh: a prospective inception cohort study of COVID-19 survivors. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6:e006838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, et al. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398:747&#x2013;758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik S, Haldar SN, Soneja M, et al. Post COVID-19 sequelae: a prospective observational study from Northern India. Drug Discov Ther. 2021;15:254&#x2013;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra N, Chowdhury M, Singh AK, et al. Clinical predictors of long COVID-19 and phenotypes of mild COVID-19 at a tertiary care centre in India. Drug Discov Ther. 2021;15:156&#x2013;161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai AD, Lavelle M, Boursiquot BC, et al. Long-term complications of COVID-19. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2022;322:C1&#x2013;C11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, et al.; ARC Study Group. &#x201c;Long-COVID&#x201d;: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F; Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez O, Merino E, Leon-Ramirez JM, et al.; COVID-19-ALC research group. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: a Mediterranean cohort study. J Infect. 2021;82:378&#x2013;383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Tan C, Wu J, et al. Impact of coronavirus disease 2019 on pulmonary function in early convalescence phase. Respir Res. 2020;21:163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez R, Latorre A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Jim&#xe9;nez P, et al. Reduced diffusion capacity in COVID-19 survivors. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2021;18:1253&#x2013;1255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, De Lorenzo R, Conte C, et al.; COVID-19 BioB Outpatient Clinic Study group. Anxiety and depression in COVID-19 survivors: role of inflammatory and clinical predictors. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;89:594&#x2013;600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li X, Geng D, et al. Cerebral micro-structural changes in COVID-19 patients - an MRI-based 3-month follow-up study. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson EJ, Williams DM, Walker AJ, et al. Long COVID burden and risk factors in 10 UK longitudinal studies and electronic health records. Nat Commun. 2022;13:3528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27:626&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitaker M, Elliott J, Chadeau-Hyam M, et al. Persistent COVID-19 symptoms in a community study of 606,434 people in England. Nat Commun. 2022;13:1957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber B, Siddiqi H, Zhou G, et al. Relationship between myocardial injury during index hospitalization for SARS-CoV-2 infection and longer-term outcomes. J Am Heart Assoc. 2022;11:e022010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohm TV, Meier DT, Olefsky JM, et al. Inflammation in obesity, diabetes, and related disorders. Immunity. 2022;55:31&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594:259&#x2013;264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boglione L, Meli G, Poletti F, et al. Risk factors and incidence of long-COVID syndrome in hospitalized patients: does remdesivir have a protective effect? QJM Mon J Assoc Physicians. 2022;114:865&#x2013;871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myhre PL, Heck SL, Skranes JB, et al. Cardiac pathology 6 months after hospitalization for COVID-19 and association with the acute disease severity. Am Heart J. 2021;242:61&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntmann VO, Carerj ML, Wieters I, et al. Outcomes of cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in patients recently recovered from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:1265&#x2013;1273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Alberts J, et al. Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e048391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M, Wong CK, Un KC, et al. Cardiovascular sequalae in uncomplicated COVID-19 survivors. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0246732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, et al. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28:583&#x2013;590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao P, Liu J, Liu M. Effect of COVID-19 vaccines on reducing the risk of long COVID in the real world: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:12422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustino G, Croft LB, Stefanini GG, et al. Characterization of myocardial injury in patients with COVID-19. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76:2043&#x2013;2055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnesi M, Baldetti L, Beneduce A, et al. Pulmonary hypertension and right ventricular involvement in hospitalised patients with COVID-19. Heart Br Card Soc. 2020;106:1324&#x2013;1331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty SE, Guo Y, Heath K, et al. Risk of clinical sequelae after the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;373:n1098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Khunti K, Nafilyan V, et al. Post-covid syndrome in individuals admitted to hospital with covid-19: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;372:n693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestre-Mu&#xf1;iz MM, Arias A, Mata-V&#xe1;zquez E, et al. Long-term outcomes of patients with coronavirus disease 2019 at one year after hospital discharge. J Clin Med. 2021;10:2945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldo RF, Mondoni M, Parazzini EM, et al. Deconditioning as main mechanism of impaired exercise response in COVID-19 survivors. Eur Respir J. 2021;58:2100870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Cassar MP, Tunnicliffe EM, et al. Medium-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on multiple vital organs, exercise capacity, cognition, quality of life and mental health, post-hospital discharge. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;31:100683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clavario P, De Marzo V, Lotti R, et al. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing in COVID-19 patients at 3 months follow-up. Int J Cardiol. 2021;340:113&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, McAuley H, Harrison EM, et al.; PHOSP-COVID Collaborative Group. Physical, cognitive, and mental health impacts of COVID-19 after hospitalisation (PHOSP-COVID): a UK multicentre, prospective cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:1275&#x2013;1287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buoite Stella A, Furlanis G, Frezza NA, et al. Autonomic dysfunction in post-COVID patients with and witfhout neurological symptoms: a prospective multidomain observational study. J Neurol. 2022;269:587&#x2013;596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotecha T, Knight DS, Razvi Y, et al. Patterns of myocardial injury in recovered troponin-positive COVID-19 patients assessed by cardiovascular magnetic resonance. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:1866&#x2013;1878.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight DS, Kotecha T, Razvi Y, et al. COVID-19: myocardial injury in survivors. Circulation. 2020;142:1120&#x2013;1122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joy G, Artico J, Kurdi H, et al.; COVIDsortium Investigators. Prospective case-control study of cardiovascular abnormalities 6 months following mild COVID-19 in healthcare workers. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2021;14:2155&#x2013;2166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzi V, Castrichini M, Collini V, et al. Impaired right ventricular longitudinal strain without pulmonary hypertension in patients who have recovered from COVID-19. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging. 2021;14:e012166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sechi LA, Colussi G, Bulfone L, et al. Short-term cardiac outcome in survivors of COVID-19: a systematic study after hospital discharge. Clin Res Cardiol Off J Ger Card Soc. 2021;110:1063&#x2013;1072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catena C, Colussi G, Bulfone L, et al. Echocardiographic comparison of COVID-19 patients with or without prior biochemical evidence of cardiac injury after recovery. J Am Soc Echocardiogr Off Publ Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2021;34:193&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Graaf MA, Antoni ML, Ter Kuile MM, et al. Short-term outpatient follow-up of COVID-19 patients: a multidisciplinary approach. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;32:100731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moody WE, Liu B, Mahmoud-Elsayed HM, et al. Persisting adverse ventricular remodeling in COVID-19 survivors: a longitudinal echocardiographic study. J Am Soc Echocardiogr Off Publ Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2021;34:562&#x2013;566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnweber T, Sahanic S, Pizzini A, et al. Cardiopulmonary recovery after COVID-19: an observational prospective multicentre trial. Eur Respir J. 2021;57:2003481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Zhao P, Tang D, et al. Cardiac involvement in patients recovered from COVID-2019 identified using magnetic resonance imaging. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2020;13:2330&#x2013;2339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassar MP, Tunnicliffe EM, Petousi N, et al. Symptom persistence despite improvement in cardiopulmonary health - insights from longitudinal CMR, CPET and lung function testing post-COVID-19. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;41:101159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rungjirajittranon T, Owattanapanich W, Leelakanok N, et al. Thrombotic and hemorrhagic incidences in patients after discharge from COVID-19 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Appl Thromb Off J Int Acad Clin Appl Thromb. 2021;27:10760296211069082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelen MM, Vandenbriele C, Balthazar T, et al. Venous thromboembolism in patients discharged after COVID-19 hospitalization. Semin Thromb Hemost. 2021;47:362&#x2013;371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts LN, Whyte MB, Georgiou L, et al. Postdischarge venous thromboembolism following hospital admission with COVID-19. Blood. 2020;136:1347&#x2013;1350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patell R, Bogue T, Koshy A, et al. Postdischarge thrombosis and hemorrhage in patients with COVID-19. Blood. 2020;136:1342&#x2013;1346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Volodarskiy A, Sultana R, et al. Prognostic utility of right ventricular remodeling over conventional risk stratification in patients with COVID-19. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76:1965&#x2013;1977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dweck MR, Bularga A, Hahn RT, et al. Global evaluation of echocardiography in patients with COVID-19. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2020;21:949&#x2013;958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Fogarty H, Dyer A, et al. Prolonged elevation of D-dimer levels in convalescent COVID-19 patients is independent of the acute phase response. J Thromb Haemost JTH. 2021;19:1064&#x2013;1070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty H, Townsend L, Morrin H, et al. Persistent endotheliopathy in the pathogenesis of long COVID syndrome. J Thromb Haemost JTH. 2021;19:2546&#x2013;2553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Meijenfeldt FA, Havervall S, Adelmeijer J, et al. Sustained prothrombotic changes in COVID-19 patients 4 months after hospital discharge. Blood Adv. 2021;5:756&#x2013;759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR, Guzman JC, Harvey P, et al. Canadian cardiovascular society position statement on postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) and related disorders of chronic orthostatic intolerance. Can J Cardiol. 2020;36:357&#x2013;372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S, Whitelaw S. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) and other autonomic disorders after COVID-19 infection: a case series of 20 patients. Immunol Res. 2021;69:205&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson FA, Mihealsick RP, Wagener BM, et al. Role of angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 and pericytes in cardiac complications of COVID-19 infection. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2020;319:H1059&#x2013;H1068.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindner D, Fitzek A, Br&#xe4;uninger H, et al. Association of cardiac infection with SARS-CoV-2 in confirmed COVID-19 autopsy cases. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:1281&#x2013;1285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Xie X, Tu Z, et al. The signal pathways and treatment of cytokine storm in COVID-19. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6:255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Liu L, Zhang D, et al. SARS-CoV-2 and viral sepsis: observations and hypotheses. Lancet Lond Engl. 2020;395:1517&#x2013;1520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bois MC, Boire NA, Layman AJ, et al. COVID-19-associated nonocclusive fibrin microthrombi in the heart. Circulation. 2021;143:230&#x2013;243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu SX, Tyagi T, Jain K, et al. Thrombocytopathy and endotheliopathy: crucial contributors to COVID-19 thromboinflammation. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2021;18:194&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrales-Medina VF, Alvarez KN, Weissfeld LA, et al. Association between hospitalization for pneumonia and subsequent risk of cardiovascular disease. JAMA. 2015;313:264&#x2013;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Zhou L, Sun X, et al. Altered lipid metabolism in recovered SARS patients twelve years after infection. Sci Rep. 2017;7:9110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePace NL, Colombo J. Long-COVID syndrome and the cardiovascular system: A Review of Neurocardiologic Effects on Multiple Systems. Curr Cardiol Rep. 2022;24:1711&#x2013;1726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePace NL, Colombo J. Clinical Autonomic and Mitochondrial Disorders: Diagnosis, Prevention, and Treatment for Mind-Body Wellness. Springer International Publishing; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burtscher J, Cappellano G, Omori A, et al. Mitochondria: in the cross fire of SARS-CoV-2 and immunity. iScience. 2020;23:101631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfaddagh A, Martin SS, Leucker TM, et al. Inflammation and cardiovascular disease: from mechanisms to therapeutics. Am J Prev Cardiol. 2020;4:100130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blagova O, Varionchik N, Zaidenov V, et al. Anti-heart antibodies levels and their correlation with clinical symptoms and outcomes in patients with confirmed or suspected diagnosis COVID-19. Eur J Immunol. 2021;51:893&#x2013;902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter D, Guasti L, Koehler F, et al. Late phase of COVID-19 pandemic in general cardiology. A position paper of the ESC council for cardiology practice. ESC Heart Fail. 2021;8:3483&#x2013;3494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gloeckl R, Leitl D, Jarosch I, et al. Benefits of pulmonary rehabilitation in COVID-19: a prospective observational cohort study. ERJ Open Res. 2021;7:00108&#x2013;02021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daynes E, Gerlis C, Chaplin E, et al. Early experiences of rehabilitation for individuals post-COVID to improve fatigue, breathlessness exercise capacity and cognition - a cohort study. Chron Respir Dis. 2021;18:14799731211015691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulson N, Petek BJ, Drezner JA, et al.; Outcomes Registry for Cardiac Conditions in Athletes Investigators. SARS-CoV-2 cardiac involvement in young competitive athletes. Circulation. 2021;144:256&#x2013;266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels CJ, Rajpal S, Greenshields JT, et al.; Big Ten COVID-19 Cardiac Registry Investigators. Prevalence of clinical and subclinical myocarditis in competitive athletes with recent SARS-CoV-2 infection: results from the big ten COVID-19 cardiac registry. JAMA Cardiol. 2021;6:1078&#x2013;1087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phelan D, Kim JH, Elliott MD, et al. Screening of potential cardiac involvement in competitive athletes recovering from COVID-19: an expert consensus statement. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2020;13:2635&#x2013;2652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelliccia A, Solberg EE, Papadakis M, et al. Recommendations for participation in competitive and leisure time sport in athletes with cardiomyopathies, myocarditis, and pericarditis: position statement of the Sport Cardiology Section of the European Association of Preventive Cardiology (EAPC). Eur Heart J. 2019;40:19&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR, Arnold AC, Barboi A, et al. Long-COVID postural tachycardia syndrome: an American Autonomic Society statement. Clin Auton Res Off J Clin Auton Res Soc. 2021;31:365&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sletten DM, Suarez GA, Low PA, et al. COMPASS 31: a refined and abbreviated composite autonomic symptom score. Mayo Clin Proc. 2012;87:1196&#x2013;1201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low PA, Sandroni P, Joyner M, et al. Postural tachycardia syndrome (POTS). J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2009;20:352&#x2013;358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Q, VanGundy TB, Galbreath MM, et al. Cardiac origins of the postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2010;55:2858&#x2013;2868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Q, Vangundy TB, Shibata S, et al. Exercise training versus propranolol in the treatment of the postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. Hypertens Dallas Tex 1979. 2011;58:167&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR, Black BK, Biaggioni I, et al. Propranolol decreases tachycardia and improves symptoms in the postural tachycardia syndrome: less is more. Circulation. 2009;120:725&#x2013;734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh TA, Metra M, Adamo M, et al.; ESC Scientific Document Group. 2021 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:3599&#x2013;3726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidenreich PA, Bozkurt B, Aguilar D, et al. 2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA guideline for the management of heart failure: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation. 2022;145:e895&#x2013;e1032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammirati E, Frigerio M, Adler ED, et al. Management of acute myocarditis and chronic inflammatory cardiomyopathy: an expert consensus document. Circ Heart Fail. 2020;13:e007405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caforio ALP, Pankuweit S, Arbustini E, et al.; European Society of Cardiology Working Group on Myocardial and Pericardial Diseases. Current state of knowledge on aetiology, diagnosis, management, and therapy of myocarditis: a position statement of the European Society of Cardiology Working Group on Myocardial and Pericardial Diseases. Eur Heart J. 2013;34:2636&#x2013;48, 2648a.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marc-Alexander O, Christoph M, Chen TH, et al. Predictors of long-term outcome in patients with biopsy proven inflammatory cardiomyopathy. J Geriatr Cardiol JGC. 2018;15:363&#x2013;371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peretto G, Sala S, Rizzo S, et al. Ventricular arrhythmias in myocarditis: characterization and relationships with myocardial inflammation. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;75:1046&#x2013;1057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannis D, Allen SL, Tsang J, et al. Postdischarge thromboembolic outcomes and mortality of hospitalized patients with COVID-19: the CORE-19 registry. Blood. 2021;137:2838&#x2013;2847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai MF, Xin WX, Kong S, et al. Effectiveness and safety of extended thromboprophylaxis in post-discharge patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Thromb Res. 2022;221:105&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramacciotti E, Barile Agati L, Calderaro D, et al. Rivaroxaban versus no anticoagulation for post-discharge thromboprophylaxis after hospitalisation for COVID-19 (MICHELLE): an open-label, multicentre, randomised, controlled trial. Lancet Lond Engl. 2022;399:50&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narasimhan B, Lorente-Ros M, Aguilar-Gallardo JS, et al. Anticoagulation in COVID-19: a review of current literature and guidelines. Hosp Pract 1995. 2021;49:307&#x2013;324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Treatment Guidelines Panel. Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Treatment Guidelines. National Institutes of Health. Available at: https://www.covid19treatmentguidelines.nih.gov/. Accessed March 18, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulman S, Sholzberg M, Spyropoulos AC, et al. ISTH guidelines for antithrombotic treatment in COVID-19. J Thromb Haemost JTH. 2022;20:2214&#x2013;2225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BTS Guidance on Venous Thromboembolic Disease in patients with COVID-19. Published online February 8, 2021. Available at: https://www.evidence.nhs.uk/document?id=2233799&amp;returnUrl=search%3fpa%3d2%26q%3dd%2bdimer%2bpe&amp;q=d+dimer+pe. Accessed July 15, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strain WD, Sherwood O, Banerjee A, et al. The impact of COVID vaccination on symptoms of long COVID: an international survey of people with lived experience of long COVID. Vaccines. 2022;10:652652.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>