<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36728728</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-4683</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2024 Sep-Oct 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiology in review</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiol Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cardiovascular Manifestations of Long COVID: A Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>402</StartPage><EndPage>407</EndPage><MedlinePgn>402-407</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000520</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The acute phase of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 [coronavirus disease (COVID)] infection has many well-documented cardiovascular manifestations, however, the long-term sequelae are less understood. In this focused review, we explore the risk factors, character, and rates of cardiovascular events in patients with Long COVID, which is defined as symptoms occurring more than 4 weeks following initial infection. Research has identified increased rates of cerebrovascular disease, dysrhythmias, ischemic and inflammatory heart disease, cardiopulmonary symptoms, and thrombotic events among those with Long COVID, though the risk rates and potential mechanisms behind each cardiovascular event vary. Finally, we discuss the current gaps in the literature as well as how COVID compares to other viral infections when it comes to causing long-term cardiovascular sequelae.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krug</LastName><ForeName>Ethan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Medicine, New York Medical College, Valhalla, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geckeler</LastName><ForeName>Keara C</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Tufts University School of Medicine, Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frishman</LastName><ForeName>William H</ForeName><Initials>WH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, New York Medical College, Valhalla, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiol Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9304686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1061-5377</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002318" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiovascular Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36728728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00045415-990000000-00065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Callard F, Perego E. How and why patients made Long Covid. Soc Sci Med. 2021;268:113426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gy&#xf6;ngy&#xf6;si M, Alcaide P, Asselbergs FW, et al. Long COVID and the cardiovascular system-elucidating causes and cellular mechanisms in order to develop targeted diagnostic and therapeutic strategies: a joint Scientific Statement of the ESC Working Groups on Cellular Biology of the Heart and Myocardial &amp; Pericardial Diseases. Cardiovasc Res. 2022:cvac115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khetpal V, Berkowitz J, Vijayakumar S, et al. Long-term cardiovascular manifestations and complications of COVID-19: spectrum and approach to diagnosis and management. R I Med J (2013). 2022;105:16&#x2013;22. (In eng).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M. Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nat Immunol. 2022;23:194&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM. Chronic COVID syndrome: Need for an appropriate medical terminology for long-COVID and COVID long-haulers. J Med Virol. 2020;93: 2555&#x2013;2556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine RL. Addressing the long-term effects of COVID-19. JAMA. 2022;328:823&#x2013;824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID or Post-COVID Conditions. Center for Disease Control and Prevention. September 1, 2022. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html . Accessed September 15, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, et al.; TLC Study Group. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med. 2021;114:428&#x2013;442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q, Zheng B, Daines L, et al. Long-Term sequelae of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of one-year follow-up studies on post-COVID symptoms. Pathogens. 2022;11:269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang DH, Roy DJ, Gu BJ, et al. Postacute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection: a state-of-the-art review. JACC Basic Transl Sci. 2021;6:796&#x2013;811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull-Otterson L, Baca S, Saydah S, et al. Post&#x2013;COVID conditions among adult COVID-19 survivors aged 18&#x2013;64 and &#x2265;65 years&#x2014;United States, March 2020&#x2013;November 2021. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71:713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robineau O, Zins M, Touvier M, et al.; Sant&#xe9;, Pratiques, Relations et In&#xe9;galit&#xe9;s Sociales en Population G&#xe9;n&#xe9;rale Pendant la Crise COVID-19&#x2013;S&#xe9;rologie (SAPRIS-SERO) Study Group. Long-lasting symptoms after an acute COVID-19 infection and factors associated with their resolution. JAMA Network Open. 2022;5:e2240985&#x2013;e2240985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan BE, Umapathi T, Chua K, et al. Delayed catastrophic thrombotic events in young and asymptomatic post COVID-19 patients. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2021;51:971&#x2013;977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Bluemke DA, Luscher TF, et al. Long COVID: post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 with a cardiovascular focus. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:1157&#x2013;1172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlis RH, Simonson MD, Green J, et al. Prevalence of firearm ownership among individuals with major depressive symptoms. JAMA Network open. 2022;5:e223245&#x2013;e223245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson SW, Abbafati C, Aerts JG, et al. Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA. 2022;328: 1604&#x2013;1615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, et al. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398:747&#x2013;758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F, Tomasoni D, Falcinella C, et al. Female gender is associated with long COVID syndrome: a prospective cohort study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28:611.e9611&#x2013;61611.e16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Wang CY, Wang SI, et al. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes in COVID-19 survivors among non-vaccinated population: a retrospective cohort study from the TriNetX US collaborative networks. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;53:101619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, et al. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28:583&#x2013;590. (In eng).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsivgoulis G, Palaiodimou L, Zand R, et al. COVID-19 and cerebrovascular diseases: a comprehensive overview. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2020;13:1756286420978004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhamoon MS, Thaler A, Gururangan K, et al.; Mount Sinai Stroke Investigators*. Acute cerebrovascular events with COVID-19 infection. Stroke. 2021;52:48&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe5;hlberg M, Reistam U, Fedorowski A, et al. Post-COVID-19 tachycardia syndrome: a distinct phenotype of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Am J Med. 2021;134:1451&#x2013;1456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P, et al. Autonomic dysfunction in &#x201c;long COVID&#x201d;: rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin Med. 2021;21:e63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR, Arnold AC, Barboi A, et al. Long-COVID postural tachycardia syndrome: an American Autonomic Society statement. Clin Auton Res. 2021;31:365&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein DS. The possible association between COVID-19 and postural tachycardia syndrome. Heart rhythm. 2021;18:508&#x2013;509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farshidfar F, Koleini N, Ardehali H. Cardiovascular complications of COVID-19. JCI Insight. 2021;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aranyo J, Bazan V, Llados G, et al. Inappropriate sinus tachycardia in post-COVID-19 syndrome. Sci Rep. 2022;12:298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wollborn J, Karamnov S, Fields KG, et al. COVID-19 increases the risk for the onset of atrial fibrillation in hospitalized patients. Sci Rep. 2022;12:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patone M, Mei XW, Handunnetthi L, et al. Risks of myocarditis, pericarditis, and cardiac arrhythmias associated with COVID-19 vaccination or SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med. 2022;28:410&#x2013;422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leentjens J, van Haaps TF, Wessels PF, et al. COVID-19-associated coagulopathy and antithrombotic agents-lessons after 1 year. Lancet Haematol. 2021;8:e524&#x2013;e533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha SA, Russo AM, Chung MK, et al. COVID-19 and cardiac arrhythmias: a contemporary review. Curr Treat Options Cardiovasc Med. 2022;1:21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tse G, Yeo JM, Chan YW, et al. What is the arrhythmic substrate in viral myocarditis? Insights from clinical and animal studies. Front Physiol. 2016;7:308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babapoor-Farrokhran S, Rasekhi RT, Gill D, et al. Arrhythmia in COVID-19. SN Compr Clin Med. 2020;2:1430&#x2013;1435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mele D, Flamigni F, Rapezzi C, et al. Myocarditis in COVID-19 patients: current problems. Intern Emerg Med. 2021;16:1123&#x2013;1129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agdamag ACC, Edmiston JB, Charpentier V, et al. Update on COVID-19 myocarditis. Medicina. 2020;56:678678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramadan MS, Bertolino L, Zampino R, et al.; Monaldi Hospital Cardiovascular Infection Study Group. Cardiac sequelae after coronavirus disease 2019 recovery: a systematic review. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:1250&#x2013;1261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishiga M, Wang DW, Han Y, et al. COVID-19 and cardiovascular disease: from basic mechanisms to clinical perspectives. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2020;17:543&#x2013;558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox SE, Falgout L, Vander Heide RS. COVID-19 myocarditis: quantitative analysis of the inflammatory infiltrate and a proposed mechanism. Cardiovasc Pathol. 2021;54:107361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khandaker MH, Espinosa RE, Nishimura RA, et al. Pericardial Disease: Diagnosis and Management. Mayo Clinic Proceedings: Elsevier; 2010:572&#x2013;593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seferovi&#x107; PM, Risti&#x107; AD, Maksimovi&#x107; R, et al. Pericardial syndromes: an update after the ESC guidelines 2004. Heart Fail Rev. 2013;18:255&#x2013;266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carubbi F, Alunno A, Leone S, et al. Pericarditis after SARS-CoV-2 infection: another pebble in the mosaic of long COVID? Viruses. 2021;13:1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furqan MM, Verma BR, Cremer PC, et al. Pericardial diseases in COVID19: a contemporary review. Curr Cardiol Rep. 2021;23:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menees DS, Bates ER. Evaluation of patients with suspected coronary artery disease. Coron Artery Dis. 2010;21:386&#x2013;390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotecha T, Knight DS, Razvi Y, et al. Patterns of myocardial injury in recovered troponin-positive COVID-19 patients assessed by cardiovascular magnetic resonance. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:1866&#x2013;1878.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adao R, Guzik TJ. Inside the heart of COVID-19. Cardiovasc Res. 2020;116:e59&#x2013;e61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin C, Zhou L, Hu Z, et al. Dysregulation of immune response in patients with coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) in Wuhan, China. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71:762&#x2013;768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Liu M, Sun R, et al. Myocardial infarction: symptoms and treatments. Cell Biochem Biophys. 2015;72:865&#x2013;867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McSweeney JC, Cody M, O&#x2019;Sullivan P, et al. Women&#x2019;s early warning symptoms of acute myocardial infarction. Circulation. 2003;108:2619&#x2013;2623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong SW, Fan BE, Huang W, et al. ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction in post-COVID-19 patients: a case series. Ann Acad Med Singap. 2021;50:425&#x2013;430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capaccione KM, Leb JS, D&#x2019;souza B, et al. Acute myocardial infarction secondary to COVID-19 infection: a case report and review of the literature. Clin Imaging. 2021;72:178&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modin D, Claggett B, Sindet-Pedersen C, et al. Acute COVID-19 and the incidence of ischemic stroke and acute myocardial infarction. Circulation. 2020;142:2080&#x2013;2082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga Z, Flammer AJ, Steiger P, et al. Endothelial cell infection and endotheliitis in COVID-19. Lancet. 2020;395:1417&#x2013;1418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masi P, H&#xe9;kimian G, Lejeune M, et al. Systemic inflammatory response syndrome is a major contributor to COVID-19&#x2013;associated coagulopathy: insights from a prospective, single-center cohort study. Circulation. 2020;142:611&#x2013;614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F; Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyrle PA, Eichinger S. Deep vein thrombosis. Lancet. 2005;365:1163&#x2013;1174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhassan S, Pelinescu A, Gandhi V, et al. Clinical presentation and risk factors of venous thromboembolic disease. Crit Care Nurs Q. 2017;40:201&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok F, Kruip M, Van der Meer N, et al. Incidence of thrombotic complications in critically ill ICU patients with COVID-19. Thromb Res. 2020;191:148145&#x2013;148150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg A, Goyal S, Patel P. A case of COVID-19 infection with delayed thromboembolic complication on warfarin. Cureus. 2020;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts LN, Whyte MB, Georgiou L, et al. Postdischarge venous thromboembolism following hospital admission with COVID-19. Blood. 2020;136:1347&#x2013;1350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasha AK, McBane RD, Chaudhary R, et al. Timing of venous thromboembolism diagnosis in hospitalized and non-hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Thromb Res. 2021;207:150&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzeffi MA, Chow JH, Tanaka K. COVID-19 associated hypercoagulability: manifestations, mechanisms, and management. Shock (Augusta, Ga). 2021;55:465&#x2013;471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594:259&#x2013;264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Vaccinations in the United States. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. October 27, 2022. Available at: https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#vaccinations_vacc-people-booster-percent-pop5 . Accessed October 27, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tazare J, Walker AJ, Tomlinson L, et al. Rates of serious clinical outcomes in survivors of hospitalisation with COVID-19 in England: a descriptive cohort study within the OpenSAFELY platform. Welcome Open Res. 2022;7:142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty SE, Guo Y, Heath K, et al. Risk of clinical sequelae after the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, et al. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet. 2022;399:2263&#x2013;2264.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>