<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38989384</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Diagnosis of Graves' Disease and Methimazole-Induced Lupus Erythematosus in an Adolescent Male During the COVID-19 Era: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e62023</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e62023</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e62023</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.62023</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Graves' disease is the most common form of hyperthyroidism in the pediatric population. Methimazole is the recommended regimen that is well-tolerated in most patients. Treatment with methimazole leading to drug-induced lupus erythematosus (DILE) is not well reported in the pediatric population, especially in the COVID-19 era. We present a case of a 14-year-old Caucasian male who presented with concerns of long COVID due to shortness of breath, hypertension, and fatigue. He was not noted to have significant weight loss, exophthalmos, or sleeping difficulties. He was followed by his general pediatrician, pediatric endocrinologist, cardiologist, and rheumatologist. Laboratory tests confirmed the diagnosis of Graves' disease, and treatment was initiated with methimazole and atenolol. One month into treatment, the patient developed polyarthritis, urticarial rash, and difficulty with gait. Based on clinical suspicion and antibody panels, he was diagnosed with DILE secondary to treatment with methimazole. The patient was then started on a potassium iodide (Lugol) solution to promote the euthyroid state and proceed&#xa0;with total thyroidectomy. Post surgery, the patient developed hypothyroidism, which was managed with oral levothyroxine, to which the patient responded well. By discussing the clinical presentation and treatment of this patient, the goal is to raise awareness and increase clinical suspicion in diagnosing Graves' and DILE in adolescents with upper respiratory presentations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Kumar et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Tanya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development, Edward Via College of Osteopathic Medicine, Monroe, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>White</LastName><ForeName>Ashley M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics and Child Health, Willis Knighton Pediatric Healthcare Associates, Shreveport, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescent covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescent endocrinology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmune disease and covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">drug-induced-lupus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">graves&#xb4;disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyperthyroid</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Consent was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38989384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11233457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.62023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Assessing American Thyroid Association guidelines for total thyroidectomy in Graves' disease. Akram S, Elfenbein DM, Chen H, Schneider DF, Sippel RS. J Surg Res. 2020;245:64&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7108813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31401249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The treatment of Graves' disease in children and adolescents. Lee HS, Hwang JS. Ann Pediatr Endocrinol Metab. 2014;19:122&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4208256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25346915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors for development or deterioration of Graves' ophthalmopathy. Stan MN, Bahn RS. Thyroid. 2010;20:777&#x2013;783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3357079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20578901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graves' disease in children: an update. Metwalley KA, Farghaly HS. Clin Med Insights Endocrinol Diabetes. 2023;16:11795514221150615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10161304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37151843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delineating the autoimmune mechanisms in Graves' disease. Morshed SA, Latif R, Davies TF. Immunol Res. 2012;54:191&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4504182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22434518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awosika AO, Singh G, Correa Correa, R R. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; 2023. Methimazole.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antithyroid drug-induced lupus erythematosus and immunoglobulin A deficiency. Beernaert L, Vanderhulst J. Am J Case Rep. 2020;21:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7767573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33349625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug-induced lupus erythematosus. Antonov D, Kazandjieva J, Etugov D, Gospodinov D, Tsankov N. Clin Dermatol. 2004;22:157&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15234017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pediatric thyroid disease: when is surgery necessary, and who should be operating on our children? Breuer C, Tuggle C, Solomon D, Sosa JA. J Clin Res Pediatr Endocrinol. 2013;5 Suppl 1:79&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3608013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23149389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 triggering autoimmune diseases. Mobasheri L, Nasirpour MH, Masoumi E, Azarnaminy AF, Jafari M, Esmaeili SA. Cytokine. 2022;154:155873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8979824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35461172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reaction of human monoclonal antibodies to SARS-CoV-2 proteins with tissue antigens: implications for autoimmune diseases. Vojdani A, Vojdani E, Kharrazian D. Front Immunol. 2020;11:617089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33584709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characteristics of Graves' disease in children and adolescents in Nanjing: a retrospective investigation study. Xie H, Chen D, Zhang J, Yang R, Gu W, Wang X. Front Public Health. 2022;10:993733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9592843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36304250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thyroid disease post-COVID-19 infection: report of a case with new-onset autoimmune thyroid disease. Trinh AN, Nguyen KH, Nguyen DV. Asia Pac Allergy. 2023;13:54&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10166241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37389097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The prevalence, incidence and natural course of positive antithyroperoxidase antibodies in a population-based study: Tehran thyroid study. Amouzegar A, Gharibzadeh S, Kazemian E, Mehran L, Tohidi M, Azizi F. PLoS One. 2017;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5215694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28052092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug-induced lupus erythematosus: an update on drugs and mechanisms. He Y, Sawalha AH. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2018;30:490&#x2013;497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7299070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29870500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minocycline-induced lupus in adolescents. Akin E, Miller LC, Tucker LB. Pediatrics. 1998;101:926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9565427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minocycline-induced lupus in adolescents. Paller AS. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1999;41:1027&#x2013;1028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug-induced lupus erythematosus with emphasis on skin manifestations and the role of anti-TNF&#x3b1; agents. Dalle Vedove C, Simon JC, Girolomoni G. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges. 2012;10:889&#x2013;897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3561694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22937775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2022 European Thyroid Association Guideline for the management of pediatric Graves' disease. Mooij CF, Cheetham TD, Verburg FA, Eckstein A, Pearce SH, L&#xe9;ger J, van Trotsenburg AS. Eur Thyroid J. 2022;11:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9142815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34981748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>