<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36447953</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2471-2531</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Season>Nov-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pain reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pain Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection altered the factors associated with headache: evidence from a multicenter community-based case-control study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e1051</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e1051</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e1051</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PR9.0000000000001051</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Headache is one of the significant global public health concerns. Furthermore, it is a standard feature of patients with acute and postacute COVID-19.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study aimed to estimate and compare the prevalence of headaches among postacute COVID and non-COVID individuals and identify and contrast the risk factors between both groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This was a multicenter case-control study. Individuals who had recovered from acute SARS-CoV-2 infection were considered "case", and those who never tested positive for COVID-19 were considered "control." Headaches were measured using the musculoskeletal subscale of the subjective health complaints scale. Multiple logistic regression analysis was used to identify the predictors of headaches.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 878 individuals (439 cases) aged 38.30 &#xb1; 12.77 years (mean &#xb1; standard deviation) participated in this study. The prevalence of headaches was 26.2% among COVID-19 survivors; however, only 10.7% of unaffected participants reported headaches at the same time. Regression analyses suggested that the recovery duration from acute COVID-19 &#x2264; 90 days (adjusted odds ratio [AOR] = 2.03, CI = 1.13-3.65) was the only predictor of headache among postacute COVID-19 survivors. However, the female gender (AOR = 3.09, 95% CI = 1.51-6.32), members of a joint family (AOR = 1.99, 95% CI = 1.02-3.90), and city dwellers (AOR = 2.43, 95% CI = 0.94-6.25) were the predictor of headache among non-COVID participants.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study found a higher prevalence of headaches among COVID-19 survivors. In addition, predictors of headache among cases and controls were unmatched, indicating heterogenous impact of COVID-19 on human health. The health care providers should be informed of the study's results when discussing better practices to mitigate the burden of headaches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of The International Association for the Study of Pain.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4685-5050</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, Uttara Adhunik Medical College and Hospital, Uttara Model Town, Dhaka, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hasna Hena Pain Physiotherapy and Public Health Research Center (HPRC), Uttara Model Town, Dhaka, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, International Institute of Health Sciences, Mirpur, Dhaka, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pain Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101683899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2471-2531</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Case&#x2013;control study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Global burden of diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Headache</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemic</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author has no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36447953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9699507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PR9.0000000000001051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PAINREPORTS-D-22-0053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbafati C, Abbas KM, Abbasi-Kangevari M, Abd-Allah F, Abdelalim A, Abdollahi M, Abdollahpour I, Abegaz KH, Abolhassani H, Aboyans V, Abreu LG, Abrigo MRM, Abualhasan A, Abu-Raddad LJ, Abushouk AI, Adabi M, Adekanmbi V, Adeoye AM, Adetokunboh OO, Adham D, Advani SM, Afshin A, Agarwal G, Aghamir SMK, Agrawal A, Ahmad T, Ahmadi K, Ahmadi M, Ahmadieh H, Ahmed MB, Akalu TY, Akinyemi RO, Akinyemiju T, Akombi B, Akunna CJ, Alahdab F, Al-Aly Z, Alam K, Alam S, Alam T, Alanezi FM, Alanzi TM, Alemu BW, Alhabib KF, Ali M, Ali S, Alicandro G, Alinia C, Alipour V, Alizade H, Aljunid SM, Alla F, Allebeck P, Almasi-Hashiani A, Al-Mekhlafi HM, Alonso J, Altirkawi KA, Amini-Rarani M, Amiri F, Amugsi DA, Ancuceanu R, Anderlini D, Anderson JA, Andrei CL, Andrei T, Angus C, Anjomshoa M, Ansari F, Ansari-Moghaddam A, Antonazzo IC, Antonio CAT, Antony CM, Antriyandarti E, Anvari D, Anwer R, Appiah SCY, Arabloo J, Arab-Zozani M, Aravkin AY, Ariani F, Armoon B, &#xc4;rnl&#xf6;v J, Arzani A, Asadi-Aliabadi M, Asadi-Pooya AA, Ashbaugh C, Assmus M, Atafar Z, Atnafu DD, Atout MMdW, Ausloos F, Ausloos M, Ayala Quintanilla BP, Ayano G, Ayanore MA, Azari S, Azarian G, Azene ZN, Badawi A, Badiye AD, Bahrami MA, Bakhshaei MH, Bakhtiari A, Bakkannavar SM, Baldasseroni A, Ball K, Ballew SH, Balzi D, Banach M, Banerjee SK, Bante AB, Baraki AG, Barker-Collo SL, B&#xe4;rnighausen TW, Barrero LH, Barthelemy CM, Barua L, Basu S, Baune BT, Bayati M, Becker JS, Bedi N, Beghi E, B&#xe9;jot Y, Bell ML, Bennitt FB, Bensenor IM, Berhe K, Berman AE, Bhagavathula AS, Bhageerathy R, Bhala N, Bhandari D, Bhattacharyya K, Bhutta ZA, Bijani A, Bikbov B, Bin Sayeed MS, Biondi A, Birihane BM, Bisignano C, Biswas RK, Bitew H, Bohlouli S, Bohluli M, Boon-Dooley AS, Borges G, Borz&#xec; AM, Borzouei S, Bosetti C, Boufous S, Braithwaite D, Brauer M, Breitborde NJK, Breitner S, Brenner H, Briant PS, Briko AN, Briko NI, Britton GB, Bryazka D, Bumgarner BR, Burkart K, Burnett RT, Burugina Nagaraja S, Butt ZA, Caetano Dos Santos FL, Cahill LE, C&#xe1;mera LA, Campos-Nonato IR, C&#xe1;rdenas R, Carreras G, Carrero JJ, Carvalho F, Castaldelli-Maia JM, Casta&#xf1;eda-Orjuela CA, Castelpietra G, Castro F, Causey K, Cederroth CR, Cercy KM, Cerin E, Chandan JS, Chang KL, Charlson FJ, Chattu VK, Chaturvedi S, Cherbuin N, Chimed-Ochir O, Cho DY, Choi JYJ, Christensen H, Chu DT, Chung MT, Chung SC, Cicuttini FM, Ciobanu LG, Cirillo M, Classen TKD, Cohen AJ, Compton K, Cooper OR, Costa VM, Cousin E, Cowden RG, Cross DH, Cruz JA, Dahlawi SMA, Damasceno AAM, Damiani G, Dandona L, Dandona R, Dangel WJ, Danielsson AK, Dargan PI, Darwesh AM, Daryani A, Das JK, Das Gupta R, das Neves J, D&#xe1;vila-Cervantes CA, Davitoiu DV, De Leo D, Degenhardt L, DeLang M, Dellavalle RP, Demeke FM, Demoz GT, Demsie DG, Denova-Guti&#xe9;rrez E, Dervenis N, Dhungana GP, Dianatinasab M, Dias da Silva D, Diaz D, Dibaji Forooshani ZS, Djalalinia S, Do HT, Dokova K, Dorostkar F, Doshmangir L, Driscoll TR, Duncan BB, Duraes AR, Eagan AW, Edvardsson D, El Nahas N, El Sayed I, El Tantawi M, Elbarazi I, Elgendy IY, El-Jaafary SI, Elyazar IRF, Emmons-Bell S, Erskine HE, Eskandarieh S, Esmaeilnejad S, Esteghamati A, Estep K, Etemadi A, Etisso AE, Fanzo J, Farahmand M, Fareed M, Faridnia R, Farioli A, Faro A, Faruque M, Farzadfar F, Fattahi N, Fazlzadeh M, Feigin VL, Feldman R, Fereshtehnejad SM, Fernandes E, Ferrara G, Ferrari AJ, Ferreira ML, Filip I, Fischer F, Fisher JL, Flor LS, Foigt NA, Folayan MO, Fomenkov AA, Force LM, Foroutan M, Franklin RC, Freitas M, Fu W, Fukumoto T, Furtado JM, Gad MM, Gakidou E, Gallus S, Garcia-Basteiro AL, Gardner WM, Geberemariyam BS, Ayalew Gebreslassie AAA, Geremew A, Gershberg Hayoon A, Gething PW, Ghadimi M, Ghadiri K, Ghaffarifar F, Ghafourifard M, Ghamari F, Ghashghaee A, Ghiasvand H, Ghith N, Gholamian A, Ghosh R, Gill PS, Ginindza TG, Giussani G, Gnedovskaya EV, Goharinezhad S, Gopalani SV, Gorini G, Goudarzi H, Goulart AC, Greaves F, Grivna M, Grosso G, Gubari MIM, Gugnani HC, Guimar&#xe3;es RA, Guled RA, Guo G, Guo Y, Gupta R, Gupta T, Haddock B, Hafezi-Nejad N, Hafiz A, Haj-Mirzaian A, Haj-Mirzaian A, Hall BJ, Halvaei I, Hamadeh RR, Hamidi S, Hammer MS, Hankey GJ, Haririan H, Haro JM, Hasaballah AI, Hasan MM, Hasanpoor E, Hashi A, Hassanipour S, Hassankhani H, Havmoeller RJ, Hay SI, Hayat K, Heidari G, Heidari-Soureshjani R, Henrikson HJ, Herbert ME, Herteliu C, Heydarpour F, Hird TR, Hoek HW, Holla R, Hoogar P, Hosgood HD, Hossain N, Hosseini M, Hosseinzadeh M, Hostiuc M, Hostiuc S, Househ M, Hsairi M, Hsieh VCR, Hu G, Hu K, Huda TM, Humayun A, Huynh CK, Hwang BF, Iannucci VC, Ibitoye SE, Ikeda N, Ikuta KS, Ilesanmi OS, Ilic IM, Ilic MD, Inbaraj LR, Ippolito H, Iqbal U, Irvani SSN, Irvine CMS, Islam MM, Islam SMS, Iso H, Ivers RQ, Iwu CCD, Iwu CJ, Iyamu IO, Jaafari J, Jacobsen KH, Jafari H, Jafarinia M, Jahani MA, Jakovljevic M, Jalilian F, James SL, Janjani H, Javaheri T, Javidnia J, Jeemon P, Jenabi E, Jha RP, Jha V, Ji JS, Johansson L, John O, John-Akinola YO, Johnson CO, Jonas JB, Joukar F, Jozwiak JJ, J&#xfc;risson M, Kabir A, Kabir Z, Kalani H, Kalani R, Kalankesh LR, Kalhor R, Kanchan T, Kapoor N, Matin BK, Karch A, Karim MA, Kassa GM, Katikireddi SV, Kayode GA, Kazemi Karyani A, Keiyoro PN, Keller C, Kemmer L, Kendrick PJ, Khalid N, Khammarnia M, Khan EA, Khan M, Khatab K, Khater MM, Khatib MN, Khayamzadeh M, Khazaei S, Kieling C, Kim YJ, Kimokoti RW, Kisa A, Kisa S, Kivim&#xe4;ki M, Knibbs LD, Knudsen AKS, Kocarnik JM, Kochhar S, Kopec JA, Korshunov VA, Koul PA, Koyanagi A, Kraemer MUG, Krishan K, Krohn KJ, Kromhout H, Kuate Defo B, Kumar GA, Kumar V, Kurmi OP, Kusuma D, La Vecchia C, Lacey B, Lal DK, Lalloo R, Lallukka T, Lami FH, Landires I, Lang JJ, Langan SM, Larsson AO, Lasrado S, Lauriola P, Lazarus JV, Lee PH, Lee SWH, Legrand KE, Leigh J, Leonardi M, Lescinsky H, Leung J, Levi M, Li S, Lim LL, Linn S, Liu S, Liu S, Liu Y, Lo J, Lopez AD, Lopez JCF, Lopukhov PD, Lorkowski S, Lotufo PA, Lu A, Lugo A, Maddison ER, Mahasha PW, Mahdavi MM, Mahmoudi M, Majeed A, Maleki A, Maleki S, Malekzadeh R, Malta DC, Mamun AA, Manda AL, Manguerra H, Mansour-Ghanaei F, Mansouri B, Mansournia MA, Mantilla Herrera AM, Maravilla JC, Marks A, Martin RV, Martini S, Martins-Melo FR, Masaka A, Masoumi SZ, Mathur MR, Matsushita K, Maulik PK, McAlinden C, McGrath JJ, McKee M, Mehndiratta MM, Mehri F, Mehta KM, Memish ZA, Mendoza W, Menezes RG, Mengesha EW, Mereke A, Mereta ST, Meretoja A, Meretoja TJ, Mestrovic T, Miazgowski B, Miazgowski T, Michalek IM, Miller TR, Mills EJ, Mini GK, Miri M, Mirica A, Mirrakhimov EM, Mirzaei H, Mirzaei M, Mirzaei R, Mirzaei-Alavijeh M, Misganaw AT, Mithra P, Moazen B, Mohammad DK, Mohammad Y, Mohammad Gholi Mezerji N, Mohammadian-Hafshejani A, Mohammadifard N, Mohammadpourhodki R, Mohammed AS, Mohammed H, Mohammed JA, Mohammed S, Mokdad AH, Molokhia M, Monasta L, Mooney MD, Moradi G, Moradi M, Moradi-Lakeh M, Moradzadeh R, Moraga P, Morawska L, Morgado-Da-Costa J, Morrison SD, Mosapour A, Mosser JF, Mouodi S, Mousavi SM, Khaneghah AM, Mueller UO, Mukhopadhyay S, Mullany EC, Musa KI, Muthupandian S, Nabhan AF, Naderi M, Nagarajan AJ, Nagel G, Naghavi M, Naghshtabrizi B, Naimzada MD, Najafi F, Nangia V, Nansseu JR, Naserbakht M, Nayak VC, Negoi I, Ngunjiri JW, Nguyen CT, Nguyen HLT, Nguyen M, Nigatu YT, Nikbakhsh R, Nixon MR, Nnaji CA, Nomura S, Norrving B, Noubiap JJ, Nowak C, Nunez-Samudio V, Oancea B, Odell CM, Ogbo FA, Oh IH, Okunga EW, Oladnabi M, Olagunju AT, Olusanya BO, Olusanya JO, Omer MO, Ong KL, Onwujekwe OE, Orpana HM, Ortiz A, Osarenotor O, Osei FB, Ostroff SM, Otoiu A, Otstavnov N, Otstavnov SS, &#xd8;verland S, Owolabi MO, Mahesh PA, Padubidri JR, Palladino R, Panda-Jonas S, Pandey A, Parry CDH, Pasovic M, Pasupula DK, Patel SK, Pathak M, Patten SB, Patton GC, Toroudi HP, Peden AE, Pennini A, Pepito VCF, Peprah EK, Pereira DM, Pesudovs K, Pham HQ, Phillips MR, Piccinelli C, Pilz TM, Piradov MA, Pirsaheb M, Plass D, Polinder S, Polkinghorne KR, Pond CD, Postma MJ, Pourjafar H, Pourmalek F, Pozna&#xf1;ska A, Prada SI, Prakash V, Pribadi DRA, Pupillo E, Syed ZQ, Rabiee M, Rabiee N, Radfar A, Rafiee A, Raggi A, Rahman MA, Rajabpour-Sanati A, Rajati F, Rakovac I, Ram P, Ramezanzadeh K, Ranabhat CL, Rao PC, Rao SJ, Rashedi V, Rathi P, Rawaf DL, Rawaf S, Rawal L, Rawassizadeh R, Rawat R, Razo C, Redford SB, Reiner RC, Reitsma MB, Remuzzi G, Renjith V, Renzaho AMN, Resnikoff S, Rezaei N, Rezaei N, Rezapour A, Rhinehart PA, Riahi SM, Ribeiro DC, Ribeiro D, Rickard J, Rivera JA, Roberts NLS, Rodr&#xed;guez-Ram&#xed;rez S, Roever L, Ronfani L, Room R, Roshandel G, Roth GA, Rothenbacher D, Rubagotti E, Rwegerera GM, Sabour S, Sachdev PS, Saddik B, Sadeghi E, Sadeghi M, Saeedi R, Saeedi Moghaddam S, Safari Y, Safi S, Safiri S, Sagar R, Sahebkar A, Sajadi SM, Salam N, Salamati P, Salem H, Salem MR, Salimzadeh H, Salman OM, Salomon JA, Samad Z, Samadi Kafil H, Sambala EZ, Samy AM, Sanabria J, S&#xe1;nchez-Pimienta TG, Santomauro DF, Santos IS, Santos JV, Santric-Milicevic MM, Saraswathy SYI, Sarmiento-Su&#xe1;rez R, Sarrafzadegan N, Sartorius B, Sarveazad A, Sathian B, Sathish T, Sattin D, Saxena S, Schaeffer LE, Schiavolin S, Schlaich MP, Schmidt MI, Schutte AE, Schwebel DC, Schwendicke F, Senbeta AM, Senthilkumaran S, Sepanlou SG, Serdar B, Serre ML, Shadid J, Shafaat O, Shahabi S, Shaheen AA, Shaikh MA, Shalash AS, Shams-Beyranvand M, Shamsizadeh M, Sharafi K, Sheikh A, Sheikhtaheri A, Shibuya K, Shield KD, Shigematsu M, Shin JIl, Shin MJ, Shiri R, Shirkoohi R, Shuval K, Siabani S, Sierpinski R, Sigfusdottir ID, Sigurvinsdottir R, Silva JP, Simpson KE, Singh JA, Singh P, Skiadaresi E, Skou ST, Skryabin VY, Smith EUR, Soheili A, Soltani S, Soofi M, Sorensen RJD, Soriano JB, Sorrie MB, Soshnikov S, Soyiri IN, Spencer CN, Spotin A, Sreeramareddy CT, Srinivasan V, Stanaway JD, Stein C, Stein DJ, Steiner C, Stockfelt L, Stokes MA, Straif K, Stubbs JL, Sufiyan MB, Suleria HAR, Suliankatchi Abdulkader R, Sulo G, Sultan I, Tabar&#xe9;s-Seisdedos R, Tabb KM, Tabuchi T, Taherkhani A, Tajdini M, Takahashi K, Takala JS, Tamiru AT, Taveira N, Tehrani-Banihashemi A, Temsah MH, Tesema GA, Tessema ZT, Thurston GD, Titova MV, Tohidinik HR, Tonelli M, Topor-Madry R, Topouzis F, Torre AE, Touvier M, Tovani-Palone MR, Tran BX, Travillian R, Tsatsakis A, Tudor Car LT, Tyrovolas S, Uddin R, Umeokonkwo CD, Unnikrishnan B, Upadhyay E, Vacante M, Valdez PR, van Donkelaar A, Vasankari TJ, Vasseghian Y, Veisani Y, Venketasubramanian N, Violante FS, Vlassov V, Vollset SE, Vos T, Vukovic R, Waheed Y, Wallin MT, Wang Y, Wang YP, Watson A, Wei J, Wei MYW, Weintraub RG, Weiss J, Werdecker A, West JJ, Westerman R, Whisnant JL, Whiteford HA, Wiens KE, Wolfe CDA, Wozniak SS, Wu AM, Wu J, Wulf Hanson S, Xu G, Xu R, Yadgir S, Yahyazadeh Jabbari SH, Yamagishi K, Yaminfirooz M, Yano Y, Yaya S, Yazdi-Feyzabadi V, Yeheyis TY, Yilgwan CS, Yilma MT, Yip P, Yonemoto N, Younis MZ, Younker TP, Yousefi B, Yousefi Z, Yousefinezhadi T, Yousuf AY, Yu C, Yusefzadeh H, Moghadam TZ, Zamani M, Zamanian M, Zandian H, Zastrozhin MS, Zhang Y, Zhang ZJ, Zhao JT, Zhao XJG, Zhao Y, Zheng P, Zhou M, Davletov K, Ziapour A, Mondello S, Lim SS, Murray CJL, Wiangkham T, Amini S. Global burden of 369 diseases and injuries in 204 countries and territories, 1990&#x2013;2019: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. Lancet 2020;396:1204&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7567026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Ramadan A, Rabab'h O, Shah J, Gharaibeh A. Acute and post-acute neurological complications of COVID-19. Neurol Int 2021;13:102&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33803475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Ahsan GU, Hossain A. Prevalence and associated occupational factors of low back pain among the bank employees in Dhaka City. J Occup Health 2020;62:12131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, GU Ahsan, Uddin Z, Hossain A. Road traffic delays in commuting workplace and musculoskeletal health among sedentary workers: a cross-sectional study in Dhaka city. J Occup Health 2021;63:e12289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8577272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34751983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Bonna AS, Sarkar A, Islam A. Is coronavirus infection associated with musculoskeletal health complaints? Results from a comprehensive case-control study. J Prim Care Community Health 2022;13:215013192211142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9310274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35869693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Bonna AS, Sarkar A, Islam MA, Rahman NAS. SARS-CoV-2 infection is associated with low back pain: findings from a community-based case-control study. Int J Infect Dis 2022;122:144&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35643305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Uddin Z, Ahsan NF, Haque MZ, Bairagee M, Khan SA, Hossain A. Prevalence of mental health symptoms and its effect on insomnia among healthcare workers who attended hospitals during COVID-19 pandemic: a survey in Dhaka city. Heliyon 2021;7:e06985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8120937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34027184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Uddin Z, Hossain A. Economic stressors and mental health symptoms among Bangladeshi rehabilitation professionals: a cross-sectional study amid COVID-19 pandemic. Heliyon 2021;7:e06715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33898834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sherbiny NA, Masoud M, Shalaby NM, Shehata HS. Prevalence of primary headache disorders in Fayoum Governorate, Egypt. J Headache Pain 2015;16. doi:10.1186/S10194-015-0569-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/S10194-015-0569-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4593989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26438329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksen HR, Ihleb&#xd7;k C, Ursin H. A scoring system for subjective health complaints (SHC). J Public Heal 1999;1:63&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10847674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Pellicer-Valero &#xd3;J, Navarro-Pardo E, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Arias-Naval&#xf3;n JA, Cigar&#xe1;n-M&#xe9;ndez M, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Barrera V, Arendt-Nielsen L. Female sex is a risk factor Associated with long-term post-COVID related-symptoms but not with COVID-19 symptoms: the LONG-COVID-EXP-CM multicenter study. J Clin Med 2022;11:413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8778106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35054108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Arendt-Nielsen L, Plaza-Manzano G. Headache as an acute and post-COVID-19 symptom in COVID-19 survivors: a meta-analysis of the current literature. Eur J Neurol 2021;28:3820&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34327787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, Plaza-Manzano G, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, Arendt-Nielsen L. Time course prevalence of post-COVID pain symptoms of musculoskeletal origin in patients who had survived to severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection. PAIN 2022;163;1220-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34561390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Fuensalida-Novo S, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a M, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Florencio LL, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Barrera V, Arendt-Nielsen L. Myalgia as a symptom at hospital admission by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection is associated with persistent musculoskeletal pain as long-term post-COVID sequelae: a case-control study. PAIN 2021;162:2832&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33863864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamming I, Timens W, Bulthuis MLC, Lely AT, Navis GJ, van Goor H. Tissue distribution of ACE2 protein, the functional receptor for SARS coronavirus. A first step in understanding SARS pathogenesis. J Pathol 2004;203:631&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7167720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15141377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y, Yuan K, Wang Z, Liu WJ, Lu ZA, Liu L, Shi L, Yan W, Yuan JL, Li JL, Shi J, Liu ZC, Wang GH, Kosten T, Bao YP, Lu L. Neuropsychiatric manifestations of COVID-19, potential neurotropic mechanisms, and therapeutic interventions. Transl Psychiatry 2021;11:499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34593760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal FM, Lam K, Sounderajah V, Clarke JM, Ashrafian H, Darzi A. Characteristics and predictors of acute and chronic post-COVID syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine 2021;36. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.100899</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.100899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8141371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34036253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam M, Sultana ZZ, Iqbal A, Ali M, Hossain A. Effect of in-house crowding on childhood hospital admissions for acute respiratory infection: a matched case&#x2013;control study in Bangladesh. Int J Infect Dis 2021;105:639&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33684561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YC, Bai WZ, Hashikawa T. The neuroinvasive potential of SARS-CoV2 may play a role in the respiratory failure of COVID-19 patients. J Med Virol 2020;92:552&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32104915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, Villapol S. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep 2021;11:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchioni E, Tavazzi E, Bono G, Minoli L, Bastianello S, Sinforiani E, Sances G, Tinelli C, Nappi G. Headache attributed to infection: observations on the IHS classification (ICHD-II). Cephalalgia 2006;26:1427&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17116092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutiawati E, Syahrul S, Fahriani M, Fajar JK, Mamada SS, Maliga HA, Samsu N, Ilmawan M, Purnamasari Y, Asmiragani AA, Ichsan I, Emran TBin, Rabaan AA, Masyeni S, Nainu F, Harapan H. Global prevalence and pathogenesis of headache in COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. F1000 Res 2020;9:1316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8063523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33953911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, Cook JR, Nordvig AS, Shalev D, Sehrawat TS, Ahluwalia N, Bikdeli B, Dietz D, Der-Nigoghossian C, Liyanage-Don N, Rosner GF, Bernstein EJ, Mohan S, Beckley AA, Seres DS, Choueiri TK, Uriel N, Ausiello JC, Accili D, Freedberg DE, Baldwin M, Schwartz A, Brodie D, Garcia CK, Elkind MSV, Connors JM, Bilezikian JP, Landry DW, Wan EY. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med 2021;27:601&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peres MFP, Mercante JPP, Tobo PR, Kamei H, Bigal ME. Anxiety and depression symptoms and migraine: a symptom-based approach research. J Headache Pain 2017;18:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5360747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28324317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj L, Kannapadi NV, Briggs J, Seal SM, Battaglini D, Fanning J, Suen J, Robba C, Fraser J, Cho S-M. Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: a meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci 2022;434:120162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8798975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubio-Rivas M, Corbella X, Mora-Luj&#xe1;n JM, Loureiro-Amigo J, L&#xf3;pez Sampalo A, Yera Bergua C, Esteve Ati&#xe9;nzar PJ, D&#xed;ez Garc&#xed;a LF, Gonzalez Ferrer R, Plaza Canteli S, P&#xe9;rez Pi&#xf1;eiro A, Cort&#xe9;s Rodr&#xed;guez B, Jorquer Vidal L, P&#xe9;rez Catal&#xe1;n I, Le&#xf3;n T&#xe9;llez M, Oterino J&#xc1; Mart&#xed;n, Mart&#xed;n Gonz&#xe1;lez MC, Serrano Carrillo de Albornoz JL, Garc&#xed;a Sardon E, Alcal&#xe1; Pedrajas JN, Martin-Urda Diez-Canseco A, Esteban Giner MJ, Teller&#xed;a G&#xf3;mez P, Ramos-Rinc&#xf3;n JM, G&#xf3;mez-Huelgas R. Predicting clinical outcome with phenotypic clusters in COVID-19 pneumonia: an analysis of 12, 066 hospitalized patients from the Spanish Registry SEMI-COVID-19. J Clin Med 2020;9:3488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7693215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33137919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steardo L, Steardo L, Zorec R, Verkhratsky A. Neuroinfection may contribute to pathophysiology and clinical manifestations of COVID-19. Acta Physiol 2020;229:e13473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32223077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stovner LJ, Hagen K, Linde M, Steiner TJ. The global prevalence of headache: an update, with analysis of the influences of methodological factors on prevalence estimates. J Headache Pain 2022;23:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9004186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35410119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tana C, Bentivegna E, Cho S-J, Harriott AM, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Labastida-Ramirez A, Ornello R, Raffaelli B, Beltr&#xe1;n ER, Ruscheweyh R, Martelletti P. Long COVID headache. J Headache Pain 2022;23:93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9340759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35915417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard. WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard with vaccination data. WHO; 
2021:1&#x2013;5. Available at: https://covid19.who.int/. Accessed April 8, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie W, Li R, He M, Cui F, Sun T, Xiong J, Zhao D, Na W, Liu R, Yu S. Prevalence and risk factors associated with headache amongst medical staff in South China. J Headache Pain 2020;21:5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6961346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31937239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubair AS, McAlpine LS, Gardin T, Farhadian S, Kuruvilla DE, Spudich S. Neuropathogenesis and neurologic manifestations of the coronaviruses in the age of coronavirus disease 2019: a review. JAMA Neurol 2020;77:1018&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7484225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>