<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34103194</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1535-6280</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>47</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current problems in cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Probl Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An Evolving Approach to Assessing Cardiorespiratory Fitness, Muscle Function and Bone and Joint Health in the COVID-19 Era.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100879</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100879</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.cpcardiol.2021.100879</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0146-2806(21)00094-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cardiorespiratory fitness (CRF) is now an established vital sign. CRF, along with muscle function and bone and joint health is related to functional independence and a higher quality of life. Wasserman and colleagues proposed a gear model illustrating the integrated role of the respiratory, cardiovascular, and skeletal muscle systems during aerobic exercise; in 2015, a revision to the original model was proposed. Our understanding of the effects and challenges associated with the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) are rapidly evolving. Initial evidence indicates higher levels of CRF, and muscle function protect individuals infected with COVID-19 from a complicated medical course. Moreover, for those individuals infected with COVID-19, there are initial signs of a reduction in CRF following the initial phase of recovery. We are also gaining an understanding of long COVID syndrome, where individuals who have recovered from the acute phase of viral infection present with lasting symptoms, which include but are not limited to reduced CRF, shortness of breath, and fatigue. Clearly, these individuals will require rehabilitation to restore and/or improve CRF, muscle function, bone and joint health, functional capacity (ie, the ability to perform activities of daily living), and quality of life. The importance of assessing the synergistic function of systems essential to performing activities that require physical exertion is a health care imperative. This graphical narrative provides an update to the gear model initially proposed by Wasserman and updated to a gear and circuit in 2015. External CRF, muscle function, and bone and joint health influencers and an approach to clinical assessment are also introduced.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arena</LastName><ForeName>Ross</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Myers</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ozemek</LastName><ForeName>Cemal</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hall</LastName><ForeName>Grenita</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Severin</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laddu</LastName><ForeName>Deepika</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaminsky</LastName><ForeName>Leonard A</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stoner</LastName><ForeName>Lee</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Conners</LastName><ForeName>Ryan T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faghy</LastName><ForeName>Mark A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>HL-PIVOT Network</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Probl Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7701802</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-2806</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000203" MajorTopicYN="N">Activities of Daily Living</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072599" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiorespiratory Fitness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009132" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscles</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34103194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8093163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpcardiol.2021.100879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0146-2806(21)00094-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Blair SN, Arena R, Church TS, Despres JP, Franklin BA, et al. Importance of assessing cardiorespiratory fitness in clinical practice: a case for fitness as a clinical vital sign: A scientific statement from the american heart association. Circulation. 2016;134:e653-e699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27881567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLeod JC, Stokes T, Phillips SM. Resistance exercise training as a primary countermeasure to age-related chronic disease. Front Physiol. 2019;10:645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6563593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31244666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thayer SW, Stolshek BS, Gomez Rey G, Seare JG. Impact of osteoporosis on high-cost chronic diseases. Value Health. 2014;17:43&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24438716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasserman K, Hansen JE, Sue DY, Stringer WW, Whipp BJ. 4th ed. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; Philadelphia: 2005. Principles of exercise testing and interpretation: including pathophysiology and clinical applications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers J, Arena R, Cahalin LP, Labate V, Guazzi M. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing in heart failure. Curr Probl Cardiol. 2015;40:322&#x2013;372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26096801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng C, Huang WY, Sheridan S, Sit CH, XK Chen, Wong SH. COVID-19 pandemic brings a sedentary lifestyle in young adults: A cross-sectional and longitudinal study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020:17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7503726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32825092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consortium OBotE-C. Ammar A, Brach M, Trabelsi K, Chtourou H, Boukhris O, Masmoudi L, et al. Effects of COVID-19 home confinement on eating behaviour and physical activity: Results of the ECLB-COVID19 international online survey. Nutrients. 2020;12:1583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7352706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32481594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall G, Laddu DR, Phillips SA, Lavie CJ, Arena R. A tale of two pandemics: How will COVID-19 and global trends in physical inactivity and sedentary behavior affect one another? Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2021;64:108&#x2013;110. doi: 10.1016/j.pcad.2020.04.005. Epub 2020 Apr 8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcad.2020.04.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32277997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sassone B, Mandini S, Grazzi G, Mazzoni G, Myers J, Pasanisi G. Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on physical activity in patients with implantable cardioverter-defibrillators. J Cardiopulm Rehabil. 2020;40:285&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7720812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32804796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro T, Paoli A. When COVID-19 affects muscle: effects of quarantine in older adults. Eur J Transl Myol. 2020;30:9069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32782767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girgis CM, Clifton-Bligh RJ. Osteoporosis in the age of COVID-19. Osteoporos Int. 2020;31:1189&#x2013;1191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32346775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brawner CA, Ehrman JK, Bole S, Kerrigan DJ, Parikh SS, Lewis BK, et al. Inverse relationship of maximal exercise capacity to hospitalization secondary to coronavirus disease 2019. Mayo Clin Proc. 2021;96:32&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7547590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheval B, Sieber S, Maltagliati S, Millet GP, Form&#xe1;nek T, Chalabaev A, et al. Muscle strength is associated with COVID-19 hospitalization in adults 50 years of age and older. medRxiv: the preprint server for health sciences. 2021 doi: 10.1101/2021.02.02.21250909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.02.02.21250909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8426913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34363345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salgado-Aranda R, P&#xe9;rez-Castellano N, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez-Gil I, Orozco AJ, Torres-Esquivel N, Flores-Soler J, et al. Influence of baseline physical activity as a modifying factor on COVID-19 mortality: A single-center, retrospective study. Infect Dis Ther. 2021;10:801&#x2013;810. doi: 10.1007/s40121-021-00418-6. Epub 2021 Mar 14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40121-021-00418-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7955903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33715099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamer M, Kivim&#xe4;ki M, Gale CR, Batty GD. Lifestyle risk factors, inflammatory mechanisms, and COVID-19 hospitalization: A community-based cohort study of 387,109 adults in UK. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:184&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32454138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Cassar MP, Tunnicliffe EM, Filippini N, Griffanti L, Alfaro-Almagro F, et al. Vol. 31. 2021. Medium-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on multiple vital organs, exercise capacity, cognition, quality of life and mental health, post-hospital discharge. (EClinicalMedicine).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33490928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27:626&#x2013;631. doi: 10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y. Epub 2021 Mar 10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphreys H, Kilby L, Kudiersky N, Copeland R. Long COVID and the role of physical activity: a qualitative study. BMJ open. 2021;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7948149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Lv F, Huang Y, Xiao K. Follow-Up study of the chest CT Characteristics of COVID-19 survivors seven months after recovery. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021;8:636298. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2021.636298. eCollection 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.636298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7956974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33732719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debeaumont D, Boujibar F, Ferrand-Devouge E, Artaud-Macari E, Tamion F, Gravier FE, et al. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing to assess persistent symptoms at 6 months in people with COVID-19 who survived hospitalization - A pilot study. Phys Ther. 2021;18 doi: 10.1093/ptj/pzab099. Online ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/pzab099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7989156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33735374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva RN, Goulart CDL, Oliveira MR, Tacao GY, Back GD, Severin R, et al. Cardiorespiratory and skeletal muscle damage due to COVID-19: making the urgent case for rehabilitation. Expert Rev Respir Med. 2021:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1080/17476348.2021.1893169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17476348.2021.1893169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33606567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghy MA, Ashton RE, Maden-Wilkinson TM, Copeland RJ, Bewick T, Smith A, et al. Integrated sports and respiratory medicine in the aftermath of COVID-19. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8:852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7347343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32653073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balady GJ, Arena R, Sietsema K, Myers J, Coke L, Fletcher GF, et al, American heart association exercise CR, prevention committee of the council on clinical C, council on E, prevention, council on peripheral vascular D, interdisciplinary council on quality of c and outcomes R. clinician's guide to cardiopulmonary exercise testing in adults: a scientific statement from the american heart association. Circulation. 2010;122:191-225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20585013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaminsky LA, Myers J, Arena R. Determining cardiorespiratory fitness with precision: Compendium of findings from the FRIEND registry. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2019;62:76&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30385268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghy MA, Sylvester KP, Cooper BG, Hull JH. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing in the COVID-19 endemic phase. Br J Anaesth. 2020;125:447&#x2013;449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7287473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32571569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher GF, Ades PA, Kligfield P, Arena R, Balady GJ, Bittner VA, et al. Exercise standards for testing and training: A scientific statement from the american heart association. Circulation. 2013;128:873-934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23877260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guazzi M, Bandera F, Ozemek C, Systrom D, Arena R. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing: What is its value? J Am Coll Cardiol. 2017;70:1618&#x2013;1636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28935040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guazzi M, Arena R, Halle M, Piepoli MF, Myers J, Lavie CJ. 2016 focused update: Clinical recommendations for cardiopulmonary exercise testing data assessment in specific patient populations. Circulation. 2016;133:e694&#x2013;e711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27143685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guazzi M, Adams V, Conraads V, Halle M, Mezzani A, Vanhees L, et al. European association for cardiovascular P, rehabilitation and american heart A. EACPR/AHA scientific statement. Clinical recommendations for cardiopulmonary exercise testing data assessment in specific patient populations. Circulation. 2012;126:2261&#x2013;2274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4777325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22952317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severin R, Arena R, Lavie CJ, Bond S, Phillips SA. Respiratory muscle performance screening for infectious disease management following COVID-19: A highly pressurized situation. Am J Med. 2020;133:1025&#x2013;1032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7182755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32343947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laveneziana P, Albuquerque A, Aliverti A, Babb T, Barreiro E, Dres M, et al. Vogiatzis I and Verges S. ERS statement on respiratory muscle testing at rest and during exercise. Eur Respir J. 2019;53</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30956204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Mayor J, Moreno-Llamas A, la Cruz-S&#xe1;nchez E. High educational attainment redresses the effect of occupational social class on health-related lifestyle: Findings from four Spanish national health surveys. Ann Epidemiol. 2021;58:29&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1016/j.annepidem.2021.02.010. Online ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annepidem.2021.02.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33640485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnaswami J, Sardana J, Daxini A. Community-engaged lifestyle medicine as a framework for health equity: Principles for lifestyle medicine in low-resource settings. Am J Lifestyle Med. 2019;13:443&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6732871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31523209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph RJ, Alonso-Alonso M, Bond DS, Pascual-Leone A, Blackburn GL. The neurocognitive connection between physical activity and eating behaviour. Obes Rev. 2011;12:800&#x2013;812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3535467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21676151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumenthal JA, Smith PJ, Mabe S, Hinderliter A, Welsh-Bohmer K, Browndyke JN, et al. Lifestyle and neurocognition in older adults with cardiovascular risk factors and cognitive impairment. Psychosom Med. 2017;79:719&#x2013;727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5493327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28437380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strauss RS, Rodzilsky D, Burack G, Colin M. Psychosocial correlates of physical activity in healthy children. Arch Pediatr. 2001;155:897&#x2013;902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11483116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Y, Wang H, Zhang T, Ren X. Psychosocial predictors of physical activity and health-related quality of life among Shanghai working adults. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2019;17:72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6485148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31023310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RE Lee, Cubbin C. Striding toward social justice: the ecologic milieu of physical activity. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2009;37:10&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2757772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19098519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wardle J, Steptoe A. Socioeconomic differences in attitudes and beliefs about healthy lifestyles. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2003;57:440&#x2013;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1732468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12775791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghy MA, Arena R, Stoner L, Haraf RH, Josephson R, Hills AP, et al. The need for exercise sciences and an integrated response to COVID-19: A position statement from the international HL-PIVOT network. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2021 doi: 10.1016/j.pcad.2021.01.004. S0033-0620(21)00013-X. Online ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcad.2021.01.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7859729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33549590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burtscher J, Millet GP, Burtscher M. Low cardiorespiratory and mitochondrial fitness as risk factors in viral infections: implications for COVID-19. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55:413&#x2013;415. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2020-103572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-103572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33234508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filgueira TO, Castoldi A, Santos LER, de Amorim GJ, de Sousa Fernandes MS, Anast&#xe1;cio WdLdN, et al. The relevance of a physical active lifestyle and physical fitness on immune defense: Mitigating disease burden, with focus on COVID-19 consequences. Front Immunol. 2021;12:587146. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2021.587146. eCollection 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.587146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7892446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33613573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laddu DR, Lavie CJ, Phillips SA, Arena R. Physical activity for immunity protection: Inoculating populations with healthy living medicine in preparation for the next pandemic. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2021;64:102&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/j.pcad.2020.04.006. Epub 2020 Apr 9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcad.2020.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32278694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieman DC. Coronavirus disease-2019: A tocsin to our aging, unfit, corpulent, and immunodeficient society. J Sport Health Sci. 2020;9:293&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7205734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32389882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jae SY, Heffernan KS, Kurl S, Kunutsor SK, Kim CH, Johnson BD, et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness, inflammation, and the incident risk of pneumonia. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2021;41:199&#x2013;201. doi: 10.1097/HCR.0000000000000581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HCR.0000000000000581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33560044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Palen J, Rea TD, Manolio TA, Lumley T, Newman AB, Tracy RP, et al. Respiratory muscle strength and the risk of incident cardiovascular events. Thorax. 2004;59:1063&#x2013;1067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1746892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15563706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal C, Mani S, Pal AK, Ramuni K, Hassan HC. Assessment of risk factors and occurrence of osteoporotic fractures among low impact trauma clients in West Bengal, India. Enfermeria clinica. 2020;30 Suppl 5:6-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veronese N, Smith L, Barbagallo M, Yang L, Zou L, Haro JM, et al. Sarcopenia and fall-related injury among older adults in five low- and middle-income countries. Exp Gerontol. 2021;147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33516908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arena R, Myers J, Kaminsky L. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing algorithm for viral infection: Assessment of acute health risk and short- to long-term effects. J Cardiopulm Rehabil. 2021 In Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33990532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagarra-Romero L, Vi&#xf1;as-Barros A. COVID-19: Short and long-term effects of hospitalization on muscular weakness in the elderly. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020:17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33255233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curry SJ, Krist AH, Owens DK, Barry MJ, Caughey AB, Davidson KW, et al. Screening for osteoporosis to prevent fractures: us preventive services task force recommendation statement. Jama. 2018;319:2521&#x2013;2531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rennou D, Decavel P, Manckoundia P, Penven Y, Mourey F, Launay F, et al. Evaluation of balance in neurologic and geriatric disorders. Ann Readapt Med Phys. 2005;48:317&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15932776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horak FB, Wrisley DM, Frank J. The balance evaluation systems test (BESTest) to differentiate balance deficits. Phys Ther. 2009;89:484&#x2013;498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2676433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19329772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arena R, Lavie CJ. The global path forward - Healthy Living for Pandemic Event Protection (HL - PIVOT) Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2021;64:96&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32485186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer M, Clair S. Syndemics and public health: reconceptualizing disease in bio-social context. Med Anthropol Q. 2003;17:423&#x2013;441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14716917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arena R, McNeil A, Sagner M, Lavie CJ. Healthy living: The universal and timeless medicine for healthspan. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2017;59:419&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28126607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>