<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38098317</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4644</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>125</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cellular biochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cell Biochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intrinsic factors behind long COVID: III. Persistence of SARS-CoV-2 and its components.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>22</StartPage><EndPage>44</EndPage><MedlinePgn>22-44</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcb.30514</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Considerable research has been done in investigating SARS-CoV-2 infection, its characteristics, and host immune response. However, debate is still ongoing over the emergence of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC). A multitude of long-lasting symptoms have been reported several weeks after the primary acute SARS-CoV-2 infection that resemble several other viral infections. Thousands of research articles have described various post-COVID-19 conditions. Yet, the evidence around these ongoing health problems, the reasons behind them, and their molecular underpinnings are scarce. These persistent symptoms are also known as long COVID-19. The persistence of SARS-CoV-2 and/or its components in host tissues can lead to long COVID. For example, the presence of viral nucleocapsid protein and RNA was detected in the skin, appendix, and breast tissues of some long COVID patients. The persistence of viral RNA was reported in multiple anatomic sites, including non-respiratory tissues such as the adrenal gland, ocular tissue, small intestine, lymph nodes, myocardium, and sciatic nerve. Distinctive viral spike sequence variants were also found in non-respiratory tissues. Interestingly, prolonged detection of viral subgenomic RNA was observed across all tissues, sometimes in multiple tissues of the same patient, which likely reflects recent but defective viral replication. Moreover, the persistence of SARS-CoV-2 RNA was noticed throughout the brain at autopsy, as late as 230 days following symptom onset among unvaccinated patients who died of severe infection. Here, we review the persistence of SARS-CoV-2 and its components as an intrinsic factor behind long COVID. We also highlight the immunological consequences of this viral persistence.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Baky</LastName><ForeName>Nawal Abd</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Protein Research Department, Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology Research Institute (GEBRI), City of Scientific Research and Technological Applications (SRTA-City), New Borg El-Arab City, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amara</LastName><ForeName>Amro A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Protein Research Department, Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology Research Institute (GEBRI), City of Scientific Research and Technological Applications (SRTA-City), New Borg El-Arab City, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uversky</LastName><ForeName>Vladimir N</ForeName><Initials>VN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4037-5857</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine, USF Health Byrd Alzheimer's Research Institute, Morsani College of Medicine, University of South Florida, Tampa, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Redwan</LastName><ForeName>Elrashdy M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8246-0075</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biological Sciences Department, Faculty of Science, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cell Biochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8205768</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0730-2312</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9008-12-2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007437">Intrinsic Factor</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007437" MajorTopicYN="N">Intrinsic Factor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic immune activation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunocompromised</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">persistent viral shedding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute sequelae of SARS-COV-2 infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sustained antigenemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viral persistence</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38098317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcb.30514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603-605. doi:10.1001/jama.2020.12603</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramakrishnan RK, Kashour T, Hamid Q, Halwani R, Tleyjeh IM. Unraveling the mystery surrounding post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2021;12:686029. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.686029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrell CJ, Howard CR, Murphy FA. Viral syndromes. Fenner White's Medical Virology. 2017;537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballering AV, van Zon SKR, Olde Hartman TC, Rosmalen JGM, Lifelines Corona Research Initiative. Persistence of somatic symptoms after COVID-19 in the Netherlands: an observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022;400(10350):452-461. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(22)01214-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra V, Flanders SA, O'Malley M, Malani AN, Prescott HC. Sixty-day outcomes among patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174(4):576-578. doi:10.7326/M20-5661</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nature Med. 2021;27(4):601-615. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell ML, Catalfamo CJ, Farland LV, et al. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 in a non-hospitalized cohort: results from the Arizona CoVHORT. PLoS One. 2021;16(8):e0254347. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0254347</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2023;401(10393):e21-e33. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(23)00810-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Pawelek P. Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK: 1 April 2021. Off Natl Stat. 2021;1-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Bowe B, Xie Y. Long COVID after breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nature Med. 2022;28(7):1461-1467. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-01840-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Bosworth ML, King S, et al. Risk of long COVID in people infected with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 after 2 doses of a coronavirus disease 2019 vaccine: community-based, matched cohort study. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2022;9(9):ofac464. doi:10.1093/ofid/ofac464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): an overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front Microbiol. 2021;12:698169. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2021.698169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swank Z, Senussi Y, Manickas-Hill Z, et al. Persistent circulating severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 spike is associated with post-acute coronavirus disease 2019 sequelae. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76(3):e487-e490. doi:10.1093/cid/ciac722</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur JM, Forrest JC, Boehme KW, et al. Development of ACE2 autoantibodies after SARS-CoV-2 infection. PLoS One. 2021;16(9):e0257016. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0257016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter AG, Shields AM, Karim A, et al. Establishing the prevalence of common tissue-specific autoantibodies following severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection. Clin&#xa0;Exper&#xa0;Immunol. 2021;205(2):99-105. doi:10.1111/cei.13623</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallukat G, Hohberger B, Wenzel K, et al. Functional autoantibodies against G-protein coupled receptors in patients with persistent Long-COVID-19 symptoms. J&#xa0;Trans&#xa0;Autoimm. 2021;4:100100. doi:10.1016/j.jtauto.2021.100100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P, Tahmasebi N, Gant V, Gupta R. Long COVID following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: characteristic T cell alterations and response to antihistamines. J Investig Med. 2022;70(1):61-67. doi:10.1136/jim-2021-002051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J, Wood J, Jaycox J, et al. Distinguishing features of Long COVID identified through immune profiling. medRxiv. 2022. doi:10.1101/2022.08.09.22278592</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB, et al. Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nature Immunol. 2022;23(2):210-216. doi:10.1038/s41590-021-01113-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manoharan S, Ying LY. Epstein barr virus reactivation during COVID-19 hospitalization significantly increased mortality/death in SARS-CoV-2(+)/EBV(+) than SARS-CoV-2(+)/EBV(&#x2212;) patients: a comparative meta-analysis. Int J Clin Pract. 2023;2023:1-8. doi:10.1155/2023/1068000</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubchenko S, Kril I, Nadizhko O, Matsyura O, Chopyak V. Herpesvirus infections and post-COVID-19 manifestations: a pilot observational study. Rheumatol Int. 2022;42(9):1523-1530. doi:10.1007/s00296-022-05146-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Almeida VM, Engel DF, Ricci MF, et al.&#xa0;Gut microbiota from patients with mild COVID-19 cause alterations in mice that resemble post-COVID syndrome. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Mak JWY, Su Q, et al. Gut microbiota dynamics in a prospective cohort of patients with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Gut. 2022;71(3):544-552. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2021-325989</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeoh YK, Zuo T, Lui GCY, et al. Gut microbiota composition reflects disease severity and dysfunctional immune responses in patients with COVID-19. Gut. 2021;70(4):698-706. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2020-323020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charfeddine S, Ibn Hadj Amor H, Jdidi J, et al. Long COVID 19 syndrome: is it related to microcirculation and endothelial dysfunction? Insights from TUN-EndCOV study. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2021;8:745758. doi:10.3389/fcvm.2021.745758</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haffke M, Freitag H, Rudolf G, et al. Endothelial dysfunction and altered endothelial biomarkers in patients with post-COVID-19 syndrome and chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). J Transl Med. 2022;20(1):138. doi:10.1186/s12967-022-03346-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E, Venter C, Laubscher GJ, et al. Prevalence of symptoms, comorbidities, fibrin amyloid microclots and platelet pathology in individuals with Long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):148. doi:10.1186/s12933-022-01579-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spudich S, Nath A. Nervous system consequences of COVID-19. Science. 2022;375(6578):267-269. doi:10.1126/science.abm2052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong AC, Devason AS, Umana IC, et al. Serotonin reduction in post-acute sequelae of viral infection. Cell. 2023;186(22):4851-4867. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2023.09.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agergaard J, Gunst JD, Schi&#xf8;ttz-Christensen B, &#xd8;stergaard L, Wejse C. Long-term prognosis at 1.5 years after infection with wild-type strain of SARS-CoV-2 and Alpha, Delta, as well as Omicron variants. Int J Infect Dis. 2023;137:126-133. doi:10.1016/j.ijid.2023.10.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Gu S, Chen Y, et al. Six-month follow-up of gut microbiota richness in patients with COVID-19. Gut. 2022;71(1):222-225. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2021-324090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung CCL, Goh D, Lim X, et al. Residual SARS-CoV-2 viral antigens detected in GI and hepatic tissues from five recovered patients with COVID-19. Gut. 2022;71(1):226-229. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2021-324280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurath MF, &#xdc;berla K, Ng SC. Gut as viral reservoir: lessons from gut viromes, HIV and COVID-19. Gut. 2021;70(9):1605-1608. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2021-324622</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Kang Z, Gong H, et al. Digestive system is a potential route of COVID-19: an analysis of single-cell coexpression pattern of key proteins in viral entry process. Gut. 2020;69(6):1010-1018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh D, Lim JCT, Ferna&#xed;ndez SB, et al. Case report: persistence of residual antigen and RNA of the SARS-CoV-2 virus in tissues of two patients with long COVID. Front Immunol. 2022;13:939989. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2022.939989</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein SR, Ramelli SC, Grazioli A, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence in the human body and brain at autopsy. Nature. 2022;612(7941):758-763. doi:10.1038/s41586-022-05542-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, et al. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398(10302):747-758. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(21)01755-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liotti FM, Menchinelli G, Marchetti S, et al. Assessment of SARS-CoV-2 RNA test results among patients who recovered from COVID-19 with prior negative results. JAMA Internal Med. 2021;181(5):702-704. doi:10.1001/jamainternmed.2020.7570</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salmon-Ceron D, Slama D, De Broucker T, et al. Clinical, virological and imaging profile in patients with prolonged forms of COVID-19: a cross-sectional study. J Infect. 2021;82(2):e1-e4. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2020.12.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vibholm LK, Nielsen SSF, Pahus MH, et al. SARS-CoV-2 persistence is associated with antigen-specific CD8 T-cell responses. EBioMedicine. 2021;64:103230. doi:10.1016/j.ebiom.2021.103230</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133-146. doi:10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao B, Zhong M, Yang Q, et al. Alterations in phenotypes and responses of T cells within 6 months of recovery from COVID-19: a cohort study. Virologica Sinica. 2021;36(5):859-868. doi:10.1007/s12250-021-00348-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ariza ME, Glaser R, Williams MV. Human herpesviruses-encoded dUTPases: a family of proteins that modulate dendritic cell function and innate immunity. Front Microbiol. 2014;5:504. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2014.00504</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs JJL. Persistent SARS-2 infections contribute to long COVID-19. Med Hypotheses. 2021;149:110538. doi:10.1016/j.mehy.2021.110538</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renz-Polster H, Tremblay ME, Bienzle D, Fischer JE. The pathobiology of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: the case for neuroglial failure. Front Cell Neurosci. 2022;16:888232. doi:10.3389/fncel.2022.888232</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merzon E, Weiss M, Krone B, et al. Clinical and socio-demographic variables associated with the diagnosis of long COVID syndrome in youth: a population-based study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(10):5993. doi:10.3390/ijerph19105993</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Penfold RS, Merino J, et al. Risk factors and disease profile of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection in UK users of the COVID symptom study app: a prospective, community-based, nested, case-control study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(1):43-55. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00460-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648. doi:10.1136/bmj.n1648</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAIR_Health. White paper: patients diagnosed with post-COVID conditions: an analysis of private healthcare claims using the official ICD-10 diagnostic code. 2022.&#xa0;http://resource.nlm.nih.gov/9918504887106676</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC. Long COVID-household pulse survey. 2022.&#xa0;https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/covid19/pulse/long-covid.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson AE, Tydeman F, Miners A, Pyper K, Martineau AR. Short-term and long-term impacts of COVID-19 on economic vulnerability: a population-based longitudinal study (COVIDENCE UK). BMJ Open. 2022;12(8):e065083. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2022-065083</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choutka J, Jansari V, Hornig M, Iwasaki A. Unexplained post-acute infection syndromes. Nature Med. 2022;28(5):911-923. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-01810-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL, Lipkin WI. Insights from myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome may help unravel the pathogenesis of postacute COVID-19 syndrome. Trends Mol Med. 2021;27(9):895-906. doi:10.1016/j.molmed.2021.06.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg-Morris L, Leach S, Xu Y, et al. Covid-19 vaccine effectiveness against post-covid-19 condition among 589 722 individuals in Sweden: population based cohort study. BMJ. 2023;383:e076990. doi:10.1136/bmj-2023-076990</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Ormerod M, Maini R. Does Timely Vaccination Help Prevent Post-Viral Conditions? Vol 383. British Medical Journal Publishing Group; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Piazza M, Boner AL, Bellanti JA. Long COVID: a proposed hypothesis-driven model of viral persistence for the pathophysiology of the syndrome. Allergy Asthma Proc. 2022;43(3):187-193. doi:10.2500/aap.2022.43.220018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nienhold R, Ciani Y, Koelzer VH, et al. Two distinct immunopathological profiles in autopsy lungs of COVID-19. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):5086. doi:10.1038/s41467-020-18854-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BK, Francisco EB, Yogendra R, et al. Persistence of SARS CoV-2 S1 protein in CD16+ monocytes in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) up to 15 months post-infection. Front Immunol. 2022;12:746021. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.746021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao XH, He ZC, Li TY, et al. Pathological evidence for residual SARS-CoV-2 in pulmonary tissues of a ready-for-discharge patient. Cell Res. 2020;30(6):541-543. doi:10.1038/s41422-020-0318-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Li S, Pan Y, et al. An immunocompetent patient with high neutralizing antibody titers who shed COVID-19 virus for 169 days-China. China CDC Weekly. 2021;3(32):688-691. doi:10.46234/ccdcw2021.163</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan A, Zlitni S, Brooks EF, et al. Gastrointestinal symptoms and fecal shedding of SARS-CoV-2 RNA suggest prolonged gastrointestinal infection. Med. 2022;3(6):371-387. doi:10.1016/j.medj.2022.04.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmani A, Dini G, Leso V, et al. Duration of SARS-CoV-2 shedding and infectivity in the working age population: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Med Lav. 2022;113(2):2022014. doi:10.23749/mdl.v113i2.12724</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zollner A, Koch R, Jukic A, et al. Postacute COVID-19 is characterized by gut viral antigen persistence in inflammatory bowel diseases. Gastroenterology. 2022;163(2):495-506. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2022.04.037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis. 2021;53(10):737-754. doi:10.1080/23744235.2021.1924397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omololu A, Ojelade B, Ajayi O, et al. Long COVID: a case report of persistent symptoms in a patient with prolonged SARS-CoV-2 shedding for over 110 days. SAGE Open Med Case Rep. 2021;9:2050313X2110154. doi:10.1177/2050313X211015494</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viszlayov&#xe1; D, Sojka M, Dobrodenkov&#xe1; S, et al. SARS-CoV-2 RNA in the cerebrospinal fluid of a patient with long COVID. Ther Adv Infect Dis. 2021;8:204993612110485. doi:10.1177/20499361211048572</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Guo C, Tang L, et al. Prolonged presence of SARS-CoV-2 viral RNA in faecal samples. Lancet Gastroenterol&#xa0;Hepatol. 2020;5(5):434-435. doi:10.1016/S2468-1253(20)30083-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Zhang Y, Moorman JP, Jia ZS, Jia ZS. Viral (hepatitis C virus, hepatitis B virus, HIV) persistence and immune homeostasis. Immunology. 2014;143(3):319-330. doi:10.1111/imm.12349</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deen GF, Broutet N, Xu W, et al. Ebola RNA persistence in semen of ebola virus disease survivors-final report. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(15):1428-1437. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1511410</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#xf6;lfel R, Corman VM, Guggemos W, et al. Virological assessment of hospitalized patients with COVID-2019. Nature. 2020;581(7809):465-469. doi:10.1038/s41586-020-2196-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Yu T, Du R, et al. Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet. 2020;395(10229):1054-1062. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30566-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M, Kleine-Weber H, Schroeder S, et al. SARS-CoV-2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and is blocked by a clinically proven protease inhibitor. Cell. 2020;181(2):271-280. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melms JC, Biermann J, Huang H, et al. A molecular single-cell lung atlas of lethal COVID-19. Nature. 2021;595(7865):114-119. doi:10.1038/s41586-021-03569-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delorey TM, Ziegler CGK, Heimberg G, et al. COVID-19 tissue atlases reveal SARS-CoV-2 pathology and cellular targets. Nature. 2021;595(7865):107-113. doi:10.1038/s41586-021-03570-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Madhavan MV, Sehgal K, et al. Extrapulmonary manifestations of COVID-19. Nature Med. 2020;26(7):1017-1032. doi:10.1038/s41591-020-0968-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puelles VG, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Lindenmeyer MT, et al. Multiorgan and renal tropism of SARS-CoV-2. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(6):590-592. doi:10.1056/NEJMc2011400</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E, Zhang C, Israelow B, et al. Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 in human and mouse brain. J Exp Med. 2021;218(3):e20202135. doi:10.1084/jem.20202135</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke J, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Hagel C, et al. Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19(11):919-929. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30308-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J, Radke J, Dittmayer C, et al. Olfactory transmucosal SARS-CoV-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with COVID-19. Nature Neurosci. 2021;24(2):168-175. doi:10.1038/s41593-020-00758-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desimmie BA, Raru YY, Awadh HM, He P, Teka S, Willenburg KS. Insights into SARS-CoV-2 persistence and its relevance. Viruses. 2021;13(6):1025. doi:10.3390/v13061025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon DE, Jang GM, Bouhaddou M, et al. A SARS-CoV-2 protein interaction map reveals targets for drug repurposing. Nature. 2020;583(7816):459-468. doi:10.1038/s41586-020-2286-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stukalov A, Girault V, Grass V, et al. Multilevel proteomics reveals host perturbations by SARS-CoV-2 and SARS-CoV. Nature. 2021;594(7862):246-252. doi:10.1038/s41586-021-03493-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullard J, Dust K, Funk D, et al. Predicting infectious severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 from diagnostic samples. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71(10):2663-2666. doi:10.1093/cid/ciaa638</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu WD, Chang SY, Wang JT, et al. Prolonged virus shedding even after seroconversion in a patient with COVID-19. J Infect. 2020;81(2):318-356. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2020.03.063</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontana LM, Villamagna AH, Sikka MK, McGregor JC. Understanding viral shedding of severe acute respiratory coronavirus virus 2 (SARS-CoV-2): review of current literature. Infection Cont&#xa0;Hospital Epidemiol. 2021;42(6):659-668. doi:10.1017/ice.2020.1273</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sia SF, Yan LM, Chin AWH, et al. Pathogenesis and transmission of SARS-CoV-2 in golden hamsters. Nature. 2020;583(7818):834-838. doi:10.1038/s41586-020-2342-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Kampen JJA, van de Vijver DAMC, Fraaij PLA, et al. Duration and key determinants of infectious virus shedding in hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):267. doi:10.1038/s41467-020-20568-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandrashekar A, Liu J, Martinot AJ, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection protects against rechallenge in rhesus macaques. Science. 2020;369(6505):812-817. doi:10.1126/science.abc4776</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng W, Bao L, Liu J, et al. Primary exposure to SARS-CoV-2 protects against reinfection in rhesus macaques. Science. 2020;369(6505):818-823. doi:10.1126/science.abc5343</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks M, Millat-Martinez P, Ouchi D, et al. Transmission of COVID-19 in 282 clusters in Catalonia, Spain: a cohort study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21(5):629-636. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30985-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fung M, Babik JM. COVID-19 in immunocompromised hosts: what we know so far. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;72(2):340-350. doi:10.1093/cid/ciaa863</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijenthira A, Gong IY, Fox TA, et al. Outcomes of patients with hematologic malignancies and COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of 3377 patients. Blood. 2020;136(25):2881-2892. doi:10.1182/blood.2020008824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood WA, Neuberg DS, Thompson JC, et al. Outcomes of patients with hematologic malignancies and COVID-19: a report from the ASH Research Collaborative Data Hub. Blood Adv. 2020;4(23):5966-5975. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2020003170</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group RC, Horby P, Lim WS, et al. Dexamethasone in hospitalized patients with Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2021;384(8):693-704. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2021436</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaskaran K, Rentsch CT, MacKenna B, et al. HIV infection and COVID-19 death: a population-based cohort analysis of UK primary care data and linked national death registrations within the OpenSAFELY platform. Lancet HIV. 2021;8(1):e24-e32. doi:10.1016/S2352-3018(20)30305-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies MA. HIV and risk of COVID-19 death: a population cohort study from the Western Cape Province, South Africa. medRxiv. 2020. doi:10.1101/2020.07.02.20145185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geretti AM, Stockdale AJ, Kelly SH, et al. Outcomes of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) related hospitalization among people with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) in the ISARIC world health organization (WHO) clinical characterization protocol (UK): a prospective observational study. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73(7):e2095-e2106. doi:10.1093/cid/ciaa1605</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown LB, Spinelli MA, Gandhi M. The interplay between HIV and COVID-19: summary of the data and responses to date. Current Op&#xa0;HIV&#xa0;AIDS. 2021;16(1):63-73. doi:10.1097/COH.0000000000000659</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calza L, Bon I, Borderi M, et al. COVID-19 outcomes in patients with uncontrolled HIV-1 infection. JAIDS J&#xa0;Acq&#xa0;Immune Def&#xa0;Synd. 2021;86(1):e15-e17. doi:10.1097/QAI.0000000000002537</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avanzato VA, Matson MJ, Seifert SN, et al. Case study: prolonged infectious SARS-CoV-2 shedding from an asymptomatic immunocompromised individual with cancer. Cell. 2020;183(7):1901-1912. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2020.10.049</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydillo T, Gonzalez-Reiche AS, Aslam S, et al. Shedding of viable SARS-CoV-2 after immunosuppressive therapy for cancer. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(26):2586-2588. doi:10.1056/NEJMc2031670</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baang JH, Smith C, Mirabelli C, et al. Prolonged severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 replication in an immunocompromised patient. J Infect Dis. 2021;223(1):23-27. doi:10.1093/infdis/jiaa666</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi B, Choudhary MC, Regan J, et al. Persistence and evolution of SARS-CoV-2 in an immunocompromised host. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(23):2291-2293. doi:10.1056/NEJMc2031364</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helleberg M, Niemann CU, Moestrup KS, et al. Persistent COVID-19 in an immunocompromised patient temporarily responsive to two courses of remdesivir therapy. J Infect Dis. 2020;222(7):1103-1107. doi:10.1093/infdis/jiaa446</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sepulcri C, Dentone C, Mikulska M, et al. The longest persistence of viable SARS-CoV-2 with recurrence of viremia and relapsing symptomatic COVID-19 in an immunocompromised patient-a case study. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8(11):ofab217. doi:10.1093/ofid/ofab217</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beigel JH, Tomashek KM, Dodd LE, et al. Remdesivir for the treatment of Covid-19-final report. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(19):1813-1826. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2007764</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rausch JW, Capoferri AA, Katusiime MG, Patro SC, Kearney MF. Low genetic diversity may be an Achilles heel of SARS-CoV-2. Proc&#xa0;Natl Acad&#xa0;Sci. 2020;117(40):24614-24616. doi:10.1073/pnas.2017726117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabre AL, Colotte M, Luis A, Tuffet S, Bonnet J. An efficient method for long-term room temperature storage of RNA. Eur J Human Genet. 2014;22(3):379-385. doi:10.1038/ejhg.2013.145</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta SK, Haigh BJ, Griffin FJ, Wheeler TT. The mammalian secreted RNases: mechanisms of action in host defence. Innate Immun. 2013;19(1):86-97. doi:10.1177/1753425912446955</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houseley J, Tollervey D. The many pathways of RNA degradation. Cell. 2009;136(4):763-776. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2009.01.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorrentino S. The eight human &#x201c;canonical&#x201d; ribonucleases: molecular diversity, catalytic properties, and special biological actions of the enzyme proteins. FEBS Lett. 2010;584(11):2194-2200. doi:10.1016/j.febslet.2010.04.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardi N, Hogan MJ, Porter FW, Weissman D. mRNA vaccines-a new era in vaccinology. Nat Rev Drug Discovery. 2018;17(4):261-279. doi:10.1038/nrd.2017.243</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemp SA, Collier DA, Datir RP, et al. SARS-CoV-2 evolution during treatment of chronic infection. Nature. 2021;592(7853):277-282. doi:10.1038/s41586-021-03291-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancman G, Mascarenhas J, Bar-Natan M. Severe COVID-19 virus reactivation following treatment for B cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia. J Hematol Oncol. 2020;13(1):131. doi:10.1186/s13045-020-00968-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tehrani HA, Darnahal M, Nadji SA, Haghighi S. COVID-19 re-infection or persistent infection in patient with acute myeloid leukaemia M3: a mini review. New Microbes New Infect. 2021;39:100830. doi:10.1016/j.nmni.2020.100830</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark SA, Clark LE, Pan J, et al. SARS-CoV-2 evolution in an immunocompromised host reveals shared neutralization escape mechanisms. Cell. 2021;184(10):2605-2617. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2021.03.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motozono C, Toyoda M, Zahradnik J, et al. SARS-CoV-2 spike L452R variant evades cellular immunity and increases infectivity. Cell Host Microbe. 2021;29(7):1124-1136. doi:10.1016/j.chom.2021.06.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Planas D, Bruel T, Grzelak L, et al. Sensitivity of infectious SARS-CoV-2 B.1.1.7 and B.1.351 variants to neutralizing antibodies. Nature Med. 2021;27(5):917-924. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01318-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doi T, Kwon HJ, Honda T, Sato H, Yoneda M, Kai C. Measles virus induces persistent infection by autoregulation of viral replication. Sci Rep. 2016;6:37163. doi:10.1038/srep37163</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ireland DDC, Manangeeswaran M, Lewkowicz AP, et al. Long-term persistence of infectious Zika virus: inflammation and behavioral sequela in mice. PLoS Pathog. 2020;16(12):e1008689. doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1008689</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randall RE, Griffin DE. Within host RNA virus persistence: mechanisms and consequences. Current Op&#xa0;Virol. 2017;23:35-42. doi:10.1016/j.coviro.2017.03.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riddell MA, Moss WJ, Hauer D, Monze M, Griffin DE. Slow clearance of measles virus RNA after acute infection. J Clin Virol. 2007;39(4):312-317. doi:10.1016/j.jcv.2007.05.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viola MV, Scott C, Duffy PD. Persistent measles virus infection in vitro and in man. Arthritis&#xa0;Rheumatism. 1978;21(5 suppl):S46-S51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensson K, Norrby E. Persistence of RNA viruses in the central nervous system. Annu Rev Microbiol. 1986;40:159-184. doi:10.1146/annurev.mi.40.100186.001111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Masaki T, Yamane D, McGivern DR, Lemon SM. Competing and noncompeting activities of miR-122 and the 5&#x2032; exonuclease Xrn1 in regulation of hepatitis C virus replication. Proc&#xa0;Natl Acad&#xa0;Sci. 2013;110(5):1881-1886. doi:10.1073/pnas.1213515110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KS, Tracy S, Tapprich W, et al. 5&#x2019;-Terminal deletions occur in coxsackievirus B3 during replication in murine hearts and cardiac myocyte cultures and correlate with encapsidation of negative-strand viral RNA. J Virol. 2005;79(11):7024-7041. doi:10.1128/JVI.79.11.7024-7041.2005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer BJ, Schmaljohn CS. Persistent hantavirus infections: characteristics and mechanisms. TIM. 2000;8(2):61-67. doi:10.1016/s0966-842x(99)01658-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbour N, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; G, Lachance C, Tardieu M, Cashman NR, Talbot PJ. Acute and persistent infection of human neural cell lines by human coronavirus OC43. J Virol. 1999;73(4):3338-3350. doi:10.1128/JVI.73.4.3338-3350.1999</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan PKS, To KF, Lo AWI, et al. Persistent infection of SARS coronavirus in colonic cells in vitro. J Med Virol. 2004;74(1):1-7. doi:10.1002/jmv.20138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray RS, Cai GY, Hoel K, Zhang JY, Soike KF, Cabirac GF. Coronavirus infects and causes demyelination in primate central nervous system. Virology. 1992;188(1):274-284. doi:10.1016/0042-6822(92)90757-g</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray RS, Brown B, Brain D, Cabirac GF. Detection of coronavirus RNA and antigen in multiple sclerosis brain. Ann Neurol. 1992;31(5):525-533. doi:10.1002/ana.410310511</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cevik M, Tate M, Lloyd O, Maraolo AE, Schafers J, Ho A. SARS-CoV-2, SARS-CoV, and MERS-CoV viral load dynamics, duration of viral shedding, and infectiousness: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Microbe. 2021;2(1):e13-e22. doi:10.1016/S2666-5247(20)30172-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185(5):881-895. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2022.01.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B, Julg B, Mohandas S, Bradfute SB. Viral persistence, reactivation, and mechanisms of long COVID. eLife. 2023;12:12. doi:10.7554/eLife.86015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tejerina F, Catalan P, Rodriguez-Grande C, et al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome. SARS-CoV-2 RNA detection in plasma, stool, and urine in patients with persistent symptoms after COVID-19. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22(1):211. doi:10.1186/s12879-022-07153-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craddock V, Mahajan A, Krishnamachary B, Spikes L, Chalise P, Dhillon NK. Persistent presence of spike protein and viral RNA in the circulation of individuals with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. medRxiv; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craddock V, Mahajan A, Spikes L, et al. Persistent circulation of soluble and extracellular vesicle-linked spike protein in individuals with postacute sequelae of COVID-19. J Med Virol. 2023;95(2):e28568. doi:10.1002/jmv.28568</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Melo GD, Lazarini F, Levallois S, et al. COVID-19-related anosmia is associated with viral persistence and inflammation in human olfactory epithelium and brain infection in hamsters. Sci Transl Med. 2021;13(596):eabf8396. doi:10.1126/scitranslmed.abf8396</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaebler C, Wang Z, Lorenzi JCC, et al. Evolution of antibody immunity to SARS-CoV-2. Nature. 2021;591(7851):639-644. doi:10.1038/s41586-021-03207-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharova LV, Sharov AA, Nedorezov T, Piao Y, Shaik N, Ko MSH. Database for mRNA half-life of 19 977 genes obtained by DNA microarray analysis of pluripotent and differentiating mouse embryonic stem cells. DNA Res. 2009;16(1):45-58. doi:10.1093/dnares/dsn030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassedy A, Parle-McDermott A, O'Kennedy R. Virus detection: a review of the current and emerging molecular and immunological methods. Front Mol Biosci. 2021;8:637559. doi:10.3389/fmolb.2021.637559</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Munblit D, De Rose C, et al. Preliminary evidence on long COVID in children. Acta Paediatr. 2021;110(7):2208-2211. doi:10.1111/apa.15870</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara&#xfa;jo NM, Ferreira LC, Dantas DP, et al. First report of SARS-CoV-2 detection in cerebrospinal fluid in a child with Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40(7):e274-e276. doi:10.1097/INF.0000000000003146</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesieur E, Torrents J, Fina F, et al. Congenital infection of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 with intrauterine fetal death: a clinicopathological study with molecular analysis. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;75(1):e1092-e1100. doi:10.1093/cid/ciab840</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz DA, Avvad-Portari E, Bab&#xe1;l P, et al. Placental tissue destruction and insufficiency from COVID-19 causes still birth and neonatal death from hypoxic-ischemic injury. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 2022;146(6):660-676. doi:10.5858/arpa.2022-0029-SA</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reagan-Steiner S, Bhatnagar J, Martines RB, et al. Detection of SARS-CoV-2 in neonatal autopsy tissues and placenta. Emerging Infect Dis. 2022;28(3):510-517. doi:10.3201/eid2803.211735</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miura CS, Lima TM, Martins RB, et al. Asymptomatic SARS-COV-2 infection in children's tonsils. Brazilian J&#xa0;Otorhinolaryngol. 2022;88(S2):9. doi:10.1016/j.bjorl.2022.10.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Q, Milanez-Almeida P, Martins AJ, et al. Adaptive immune responses to SARS-CoV-2 persist in the pharyngeal lymphoid tissue of children. Nature Immunol. 2023;24(1):186-199. doi:10.1038/s41590-022-01367-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Martino L, Morello R, Mariani F, Fearnley K, Valentini P. Viral persistence in children infected with SARS-CoV-2: current evidence and future research strategies. Lancet Microbe. 2023;4:e745-e756. doi:10.1016/S2666-5247(23)00115-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng YB, Zeng N, Yuan K, et al. Prevalence and risk factor for long COVID in children and adolescents: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J&#xa0;Infection&#xa0;Public Health. 2023;16(5):660-672. doi:10.1016/j.jiph.2023.03.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Gennaro LD, Rose CD, et al. Long-term outcomes of pediatric infections: from traditional infectious diseases to long Covid. Future Microbiol. 2022;17:551-571. doi:10.2217/fmb-2022-0031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Ayuzo Del Valle NC, et al. Long-COVID in children and adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):9950. doi:10.1038/s41598-022-13495-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan SA, Mulcahy Levy J, Moss A, et al. SARS-CoV-2 persistence in immunocompromised children. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2021;68(12):e29277. doi:10.1002/pbc.29277</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin C, Zhou L, Hu Z, et al. Dysregulation of immune response in patients with coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) in Wuhan, China. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71(15):762-768. doi:10.1093/cid/ciaa248</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva Andrade B, Siqueira S, de Assis Soares WR, et al. Long-COVID and post-COVID health complications: an up-to-date review on clinical conditions and their possible molecular mechanisms. Viruses. 2021;13(4):700. doi:10.3390/v13040700</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiale C, Greene TT, Zuniga EI. Interferon induction, evasion, and paradoxical roles during SARS-CoV-2 infection. Immunol Rev. 2022;309(1):12-24. doi:10.1111/imr.13113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan PH, Ji J, Hsing CH, Tan R, Ji RR. Emerging roles of type-I interferons in neuroinflammation, neurological diseases, and long-haul COVID. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(22):14394. doi:10.3390/ijms232214394</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan FJ, Hope CM, Masavuli MG, et al. Long-term perturbation of the peripheral immune system months after SARS-CoV-2 infection. BMC Med. 2022;20(1):26. doi:10.1186/s12916-021-02228-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumi T, Harada K. Immune response to SARS-CoV-2 in severe disease and long COVID-19. iScience. 2022;25(8):104723. doi:10.1016/j.isci.2022.104723</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeniji OS, Giron LB, Purwar M, et al. COVID-19 severity is associated with differential antibody Fc-mediated innate immune functions. mBio. 2021;12(2):e00281-21. doi:10.1128/mBio.00281-21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cugno M, Meroni PL, Gualtierotti R, et al. Complement activation and endothelial perturbation parallel COVID-19 severity and activity. J Autoimmun. 2021;116:102560. doi:10.1016/j.jaut.2020.102560</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Y, Yalavarthi S, Navaz SA, et al. Autoantibodies stabilize neutrophil extracellular traps in COVID-19. JCI Insight. 2021;6(15):e159111. doi:10.1172/jci.insight.150111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu F, Chen F, Ou Z, et al. A compromised specific humoral immune response against the SARS-CoV-2 receptor-binding domain is related to viral persistence and periodic shedding in the gastrointestinal tract. Cell Mol Immunol. 2020;17(11):1119-1125. doi:10.1038/s41423-020-00550-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilich T, Nelde A, Heitmann JS, et al. T cell and antibody kinetics delineate SARS-CoV-2 peptides mediating long-term immune responses in COVID-19 convalescent individuals. Sci Transl Med. 2021;13(590):eabf7517. doi:10.1126/scitranslmed.abf7517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Yasuhara A, Ito M, et al. Antibody titers against SARS-CoV-2 decline, but do not disappear for several months. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;32:100734. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.100734</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho A, Muecksch F, Schaefer-Babajew D, et al. Anti-SARS-CoV-2 receptor-binding domain antibody evolution after mRNA vaccination. Nature. 2021;600(7889):517-522. doi:10.1038/s41586-021-04060-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin K, Peluso MJ, Luo X, et al. Long COVID manifests with T cell dysregulation, inflammation, and an uncoordinated adaptive immune response to SARS-CoV-2. bioRxiv. 2023. doi:10.1101/2023.02.09.527892</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishna BA, Lim EY, Mactavous L, et al. Evidence of previous SARS-CoV-2 infection in seronegative patients with long COVID. EBioMedicine. 2022;81:104129. doi:10.1016/j.ebiom.2022.104129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson RC, Simons NW, Wilkins L, et al. Molecular states during acute COVID-19 reveal distinct etiologies of long-term sequelae. Nature Med. 2023;29(1):236-246. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-02107-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam MS, Wang Z, Abdel-Mohsen M, Chen X, Montaner LJ. Tissue injury and leukocyte changes in post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2: review of 2833 post-acute patient outcomes per immune dysregulation and microbial translocation in long COVID. J Leukoc Biol. 2023;113(3):236-254. doi:10.1093/jleuko/qiac001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deveau TM, Munter SE, et al. Impact of pre-existing chronic viral infection and reactivation on the development of Long COVID. medRxiv; 2022. doi:10.1101/2022.06.21.22276660</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruger A, Vlok M, Turner S, et al. Proteomics of fibrin amyloid microclots in long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) shows many entrapped pro-inflammatory molecules that may also contribute to a failed fibrinolytic system. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):190. doi:10.1186/s12933-022-01623-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi R, Rassenti LZ, Meisenholder G, Carson DA, Kipps TJ. Autoantigen inhibits apoptosis of a human B cell leukemia that produces pathogenic rheumatoid factor. J&#xa0;Immunol. 1993;151(12):7273-7283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo L, Liang W, Pang J, et al. Dynamics of TCR repertoire and T cell function in COVID-19 convalescent individuals. Cell Discov. 2021;7(1):89. doi:10.1038/s41421-021-00321-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan Y, Xia M, Ren L, et al. Deficiency of Tfh cells and germinal center in deceased COVID-19 patients. Current Med&#xa0;Sci. 2020;40(4):618-624. doi:10.1007/s11596-020-2225-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen KW, Linderman SL, Moodie Z, et al. Longitudinal analysis shows durable and broad immune memory after SARS-CoV-2 infection with persisting antibody responses and memory B and T cells. Cell Rep&#xa0;Med. 2021;2(7):100354. doi:10.1016/j.xcrm.2021.100354</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisberg SP, Ural BB, Farber DL. Tissue-specific immunity for a changing world. Cell. 2021;184(6):1517-1529. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2021.01.042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visvabharathy L, Hanson B, Orban Z, et al. Neuro-COVID long-haulers exhibit broad dysfunction in T cell memory generation and responses to vaccination. medRxiv; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deitchman AN, Torres L, et al. Long-term SARS-CoV-2-specific immune and inflammatory responses in individuals recovering from COVID-19 with and without post-acute symptoms. Cell Rep. 2021;36(6):109518. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2021.109518</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Littlefield KM, Watson RO, Schneider JM, et al. SARS-CoV-2-specific T cells associate with inflammation and reduced lung function in pulmonary post-acute sequalae of SARS-CoV-2. PLoS Pathog. 2022;18(5):e1010359. doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1010359</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang D, Han Z, Oppenheim JJ. Alarmins and immunity. Immunol Rev. 2017;280(1):41-56. doi:10.1111/imr.12577</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giani M, Seminati D, Lucchini A, Foti G, Pagni F. Exuberant plasmocytosis in bronchoalveolar lavage specimen of the first patient requiring extracorporeal membrane oxygenation for SARS-CoV-2 in Europe. J Thorac Oncol. 2020;15(5):e65-e66. doi:10.1016/j.jtho.2020.03.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteleone G, Sarzi-Puttini PC, Ardizzone S. Preventing COVID-19-induced pneumonia with anticytokine therapy. Lancet Rheumatol. 2020;2(5):e255-e256. doi:10.1016/S2665-9913(20)30092-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gindlhuber J, Tomin T, Wiesenhofer F, et al. Proteomic profiling of end-stage COVID-19 lung biopsies. Clin Proteomics. 2022;19(1):46. doi:10.1186/s12014-022-09386-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen B, Yi X, Sun Y, et al. Proteomic and metabolomic characterization of COVID-19 patient sera. Cell. 2020;182(1):59-72. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2020.05.032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutmann C, Takov K, Burnap SA, et al. SARS-CoV-2 RNAemia and proteomic trajectories inform prognostication in COVID-19 patients admitted to intensive care. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):3406. doi:10.1038/s41467-021-23494-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Yue L, Ju Y, et al. Serum proteomic analysis for new types of long-term persistent COVID-19 patients in wuhan. Microbiology Spectrum. 2022;10(6):e0127022. doi:10.1128/spectrum.01270-22</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Melo GD, Lazarini F, Levallois S, et al. COVID-19-associated olfactory dysfunction reveals SARS-CoV-2 neuroinvasion and persistence in the olfactory system. bioRxiv; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao F, Tang M, Zheng X, Liu Y, Li X, Shan H. Evidence for gastrointestinal infection of SARS-CoV-2. Gastroenterology. 2020;158(6):1831-1833. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2020.02.055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley BT, Maioli H, Johnston R, et al. Histopathology and ultrastructural findings of fatal COVID-19 infections in Washington state: a case series. Lancet. 2020;396(10247):320-332. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31305-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chertow D, Stein S, Ramelli S, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence throughout the human body and brain. Res Square. 2021. doi:10.21203/rs.3.rs-1139035/v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L, Jiang X, Zhang Z, et al. Gastrointestinal symptoms of 95 cases with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Gut. 2020;69(6):997-1001. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2020-321013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Q, Fan L, Liu W, et al. Direct evidence of active SARS-CoV-2 replication in the intestine. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73(3):361-366. doi:10.1093/cid/ciaa925</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceulemans LJ, Khan M, Yoo SJ, et al. Persistence of SARS-CoV-2 RNA in lung tissue after mild COVID-19. Lancet Respiratory Med. 2021;9(8):e78-e79. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00240-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi E, Courcoubetis G, Liljegren E, et al. Investigation of liquid biopsy analytes in peripheral blood of individuals after SARS-CoV-2 infection. EBioMedicine. 2023;90:104519. doi:10.1016/j.ebiom.2023.104519</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa Dos Santos J, Ximenes Rabelo M, Mattana Sebben L, et al. Persistence of SARS-CoV-2 antigens in the nasal mucosa of eight patients with inflammatory rhinopathy for over 80 days following mild COVID-19 diagnosis. Viruses. 2023;15(4):899. doi:10.3390/v15040899</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, et al. &#x2018;Long-COVID&#x2019;: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76(4):396-398. doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-215818</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun B, Tang N, Peluso MJ, et al. Characterization and biomarker analyses of post-COVID-19 complications and neurological manifestations. Cells. 2021;10(2):386. doi:10.3390/cells10020386</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-De-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Florencio LL. Defining post-COVID symptoms (post-acute COVID, Long COVID, persistent post-COVID): an integrative classification. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(5):2621. doi:10.3390/ijerph18052621</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadjadj J, Yatim N, Barnabei L, et al. Impaired type I interferon activity and inflammatory responses in severe COVID-19 patients. Science. 2020;369(6504):718-724. doi:10.1126/science.abc6027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nature Med. 2021;27(4):626-631. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoodsma M, de Nooijer AH, Grondman I, et al. Targeted proteomics identifies circulating biomarkers associated with active COVID-19 and post-COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1027122. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2022.1027122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss RB, Mercandetti A, Vojdani A. TNF-alpha and chronic fatigue syndrome. J Clin Immunol. 1999;19(5):314-316. doi:10.1023/a:1020595709352</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu ZH, Zhou HW, Wu WK, et al. Alterations in the composition of intestinal DNA virome in patients with COVID-19. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2021;11:790422. doi:10.3389/fcimb.2021.790422</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vestad B, Ueland T, Lerum TV, et al. Respiratory dysfunction three months after severe COVID-19 is associated with gut microbiota alterations. J Intern Med. 2022;291(6):801-812. doi:10.1111/joim.13458</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farsi Y, Tahvildari A, Arbabi M, et al. Diagnostic, prognostic, and therapeutic roles of gut microbiota in COVID-19: a comprehensive systematic review. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2022;12:804644. doi:10.3389/fcimb.2022.804644</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Chen L, Deng Q, et al. The presence of SARS-CoV-2 RNA in the feces of COVID-19 patients. J Med Virol. 2020;92(7):833-840. doi:10.1002/jmv.25825</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heerdt PM, Shelley B, Singh I. Impaired systemic oxygen extraction long after mild COVID-19: potential perioperative implications. Br J Anaesth. 2022;128(3):e246-e249. doi:10.1016/j.bja.2021.12.036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE. Myalgic encephalomyelitis (or encephalopathy)/chronic fatigue syndrome: diagnosis and management; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright J, Astill S, Sivan M. The relationship between physical activity and Long COVID: a cross-sectional study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(9):5093. doi:10.3390/ijerph19095093</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng LN, Bonilla HF, Shafer RW, Miglis MG, Yang PC. Case report of breakthrough long COVID and the use of nirmatrelvir-ritonavir. Res Square. 2022. doi:10.21203/rs.3.rs-1443341/v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Choi T, Al-Aly Z. Nirmatrelvir and the risk of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. medRxiv; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visvabharathy L, Orban ZS, Koralnik IJ. Case report: treatment of long COVID with a SARS-CoV-2 antiviral and IL-6 blockade in a patient with rheumatoid arthritis and SARS-CoV-2 antigen persistence. Front Med. 2022;9:1003103. doi:10.3389/fmed.2022.1003103</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>