<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36092770</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2667-3215</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>SSM. Qualitative research in health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>SSM Qual Res Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long covid and medical gaslighting: Dismissal, delayed diagnosis, and deferred treatment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100167</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100167</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ssmqr.2022.100167</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>While we know a lot more about Long Covid today, patients who were infected with Covid-19 early on in the pandemic and developed Long Covid had to contend with medical professionals who lacked awareness of the potential for extended complications from Covid-19. Long Covid patients have responded by labeling their contentious interactions with medical professionals, organizations, and the broader medical system as "gaslighting." We argue that the charge of medical gaslighting can be understood as a form of ontological politics. Not only do patients demand that their version of reality be recognized, but they also blame the experts who hold gatekeeping power over their medical care for producing a distorted version of said reality. By analyzing results from an online survey of Long Covid patients active on social media in the United States (n&#xa0;&#x200b;=&#xa0;&#x200b;334), we find that experiences of contention and their reframing as "gaslighting" were common amongst our respondents. In short answer responses about their experience obtaining medical care for Long Covid, our respondents described encountering medical professionals who dismissed their experience, leading to lengthy diagnostic odysseys and lack of treatment options for Long Covid. Even though we are limited by characteristics of our sample, there is good reason to believe that these experiences and their contentious reframing as medical gaslighting are exacerbated by gender, class, and racial inequalities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Au</LastName><ForeName>Larry</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sociology, The City College of New York, NAC 6/135, 160 Convent Ave, New York, NY, 10031, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Capotescu</LastName><ForeName>Cristian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Center for Innovative Theory and Empirics, Columbia University, Suite 1300, 61 Claremont Avenue, New York, NY, 10115, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eyal</LastName><ForeName>Gil</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sociology, Columbia University, Suite 501, 606 W 122nd St, New York, NY, 10027, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Finestone</LastName><ForeName>Gabrielle</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sociology, Columbia University, Suite 501, 606 W 122nd St, New York, NY, 10027, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>SSM Qual Res Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918300877606676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2667-3215</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic illness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnostic odyssey</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gaslighting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient-physician relationship</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36092770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9448633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssmqr.2022.100167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2667-3215(22)00129-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Au L., Eyal G. Whose advice is credible? claiming lay expertise in a Covid-19 online community. Qualitative Sociology. 2022;45(1):31&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8564268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34744215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker K.K. Temple University Press; 2005. The fibromyalgia story: Medical authority and women's worlds of pain.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker K.K. Electronic support groups, patient-consumers, and medicalization: The case of contested illness. Journal of Health and Social Behavior. 2008;49(1):20&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18418983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blease C., Carel H., Geraghty K. Epistemic injustice in healthcare encounters: Evidence from chronic fatigue syndrome. Journal of Medical Ethics. 2017;43(8):549&#x2013;557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27920164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broom A. &#x2019;I'd forgotten about me in all of this': Discourses of self-healing, positivity and vulnerability in cancer patients' experiences of complementary and alternative medicine. Journal of Sociology. 2009;45(1):71&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchman D.Z., Ho A., Goldberg D.S. Investigating trust, expertise, and epistemic injustice in chronic pain. Journal of bioethical inquiry. 2017;14(1):31&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28005251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callard F., Perego E. How and why patients made long covid. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2021;268(January)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7539940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33199035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camero K. Long COVID patients feel gaslighted, ignored, and dismissed by medical professionals. BuzzFeed News. 2022, April 29. https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/katiecamero/long-covid</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC  Nearly one in five American adults who have had COVID-19 still have &#x2018;long COVID.&#x2019; national center for health statistics. 2022, June 22. https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/pressroom/nchs_press_releases/2022/20220622.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collyer F.M., Willis K.F., Lewis S. Gatekeepers in the healthcare sector: Knowledge and Bourdieu's concept of field. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2017;186(August):96&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28603078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooney E. From medical gaslighting to death threats, long covid tests patients. 2021, November 22. https://www.statnews.com/2021/11/22/long-covid-patients-medical-gaslighting-death-threats/ STAT (blog)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper A. Puzzling, often debilitating after-effects plaguing COVID-19 &#x2018;long-haulers.&#x2019; 60 minutes. 2020. https://www.cbsnews.com/news/covid-long-haulers-60-minutes-2020-11-22/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Survivor Corps Post-COVID care: Guidelines for multidisciplinary care centers. 2021. https://www.survivorcorps.com/s/PCCC-Standard-of-Practice-3_23.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H.E., Assaf G.S., McCorkell L., Wei H., Low R.J., Re&#x2019;em Y., Redfield S., Austin J.P., Akrami A. MedRxiv; 2021. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 Months of symptoms and their impact. 2020.12.24.20248802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumes A.A. Duke University Press; 2020. Divided bodies: Lyme disease, contested illness, and evidence-based medicine.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumit J. Illnesses you have to fight to get: Facts as forces in uncertain, emergent illnesses. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2006;62(3):577&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16085344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein S. The construction of lay expertise: AIDS activism and the forging of credibility in the reform of clinical trials. Science, Technology &amp; Human Values. 1995;20(4):408&#x2013;437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11653331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eysenbach G. Improving the quality of web surveys: The checklist for reporting results of Internet E-surveys (CHERRIES) Journal of Medical Internet Research. 2004;6(3):e132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1550605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15471760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eysenbach G., Powell J., Englesakis M., Rizo C., Stern A. Health related virtual communities and electronic support groups: Systematic Review of the effects of online peer to peer interactions. BMJ. 2004;328(7449):1166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC411092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15142921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eysenbach G., Till J.E. Ethical issues in qualitative research on Internet communities. BMJ. 2001;323(7321):1103&#x2013;1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC59687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11701577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fricker M. In: Routledge handbook of epistemic injustice. Kidd I.J., Medina J., Pohlhaus G. Jr., editors. Routledge; 2017. Evolving concepts of epistemic injustice; pp. 53&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gale N. The sociology of traditional, complementary and alternative medicine. Sociology Compass. 2014;8(6):805&#x2013;822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4146620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25177359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg E.  2020, September 7. For long-haulers, covid-19 takes a toll on mind as well as body. The New York times.https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/07/health/coronavirus-mental-health-long-hauler.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greaves L., Ritz S.A. Sex, gender and health: Mapping the landscape of research and policy. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2022;19(5):2563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8909483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35270255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green J., Hibbard J.H., Sacks R.M. Does the race/ethnicity or gender of a physician's name impact patient selection of the physician? Journal of the National Medical Association. 2018;110(3):206&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29778121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hacker J.S. 2nd ed. Oxford University Press; 2019. The great risk shift: The new economic insecurity and the decline of the American dream.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jutel A. Sociology of diagnosis: A preliminary Review. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness. 2009;31(2):278&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19220801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser J.  2021, September 15. Study of up to 40,000 people will probe mysteries of long covid. Science.https://www.science.org/content/article/study-40-000-people-will-probe-mysteries-long-covid</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kempner J. University Of Chicago Press; Chicago: 2014. Not tonight: Migraine and the politics of gender and health.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr A., Cunningham-Burley S., Amos A. The new genetics and health: Mobilizing lay expertise. Public Understanding of Science. 1998;7(1):41&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11657071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidd I.J., Carel H. Epistemic injustice and illness. Journal of Applied Philosophy. 2017;34(2):172&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5324700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28303075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Link B.G., Phelan J. Social conditions as fundamental causes of disease. Journal of Health and Social Behavior. 1995:80&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7560851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S., Wegman-Ostrosky T., Perelman C., Sepulveda R., Rebolledo P.A., Cuapio A., Villapol S. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: A systematic Review and meta-analysis. Scientific Reports. 2021;11(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowenstein F. The Experiment; New York: 2022. The long COVID survival guide: Stories and advice from twenty long-haulers and experts.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;wy I.  2021, May 25. Long covid, chronic fatigue syndrome and women: The shadow of hysteria.http://somatosphere.net/2021/long-covid.html/ Somatosphere (blog)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariani M.  The Guardian; 2022, February 3. The great gaslighting: How covid longhaulers are still fighting for recognition.https://www.theguardian.com/society/2022/feb/03/long-covid-fight-recognition-gaslighting-pandemic</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maslen S., Lupton D. &#x2018;Keeping it real&#x2019;: Women's enactments of lay health knowledges and expertise on Facebook. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness. 2019;41(8):1637&#x2013;1651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31392762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauldin L., Brown R.L. Missing pieces: Engaging sociology of disability in medical sociology. Journal of Health and Social Behavior. 2021;62(4):477&#x2013;492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34100666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyake E., Martin S. Long covid: Online patient narratives, public health communication and vaccine hesitancy. Digital Health. 2021;7(January)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8638072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34868622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mol A. Ontological politics: A word and some questions. The Sociological Review. 1999;47(S1):74&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mol A. Duke University Press; Durham: 2003. The body multiple: Ontology in medical practice.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D., O&#x2019;Hara M.E., Akrami A., Perego E., Olliaro P., Needham D.M. Long COVID: Aiming for a consensus. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine. 2022;10(7):632&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9067938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35525253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newshub . 2021. Dismissed by doctors, sufferers of long COVID struggle with &#x201c;medical gaslighting&#x201d; | newshub nation.https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6UwMwwM5oYg</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen A., Schermuly A., Anderson A. Feeling less alone online: Patients' ambivalent engagements with digital media. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32525577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prior L. Belief, knowledge and expertise: The emergence of the lay expert in medical sociology. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness. 2003;25(3):41&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14498929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reich A.D. Princeton University Press; 2014. Selling our souls: The commodification of hospital care in the United States.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rushforth A., Ladds E., Wieringa S., Taylor S., Husain L., Greenhalgh T. Long covid &#x2013; the illness narratives. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2021;286(October)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34425522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebring J.C.H. Towards a sociological understanding of medical gaslighting in western health care. Sociology of Health &amp; Illness. 2021;43(9):1951&#x2013;1964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34432297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim J.K. Cultural health capital: A theoretical approach to understanding health care interactions and the dynamics of unequal treatment. Journal of Health and Social Behavior. 2010;51(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10658877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20420291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sills S.J., Song C. Innovations in survey research: An application of web-based surveys. Social Science Computer Review. 2002;20(1):22&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweet P.L. The sociology of gaslighting. American Sociological Review. 2019;84(5):851&#x2013;875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavory I., Timmermans S. University of Chicago Press; 2014. Abductive analysis: Theorizing qualitative research.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmermans S., Buchbinder M. Patients-in-Waiting: Living between sickness and health in the genomics era. Journal of Health and Social Behavior. 2010;51(4):408&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vaan M., Stuart T. Gender in the markets for expertise. American Sociological Review. 2022;87(3):443&#x2013;477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinson A.H., Underman K. Clinical empathy as emotional labor in medical work. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2020;251(April)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32151886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter K. An inside look at a post&#x2013;COVID-19 clinic. JAMA. 2021;325(20):2036&#x2013;2037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33950195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>