<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35272262</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-3064</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>195</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Respiratory medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Respir Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effectiveness of pulmonary rehabilitation for Post-COVID symptoms: A rapid review of the literature.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>106782</StartPage><MedlinePgn>106782</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.rmed.2022.106782</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0954-6111(22)00047-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Multi-disciplinary rehabilitation is recommended for individuals with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 infection (i.e., symptoms 3-4 weeks after acute infection). There are emerging reports of use of pulmonary rehabilitation (PR) in the post-acute stages of COVID-19, however the appropriateness of PR for managing post-COVID symptoms remains unclear. To offer practical guidance with regards to post-COVID PR, a greater understanding of the clinical effectiveness literature is required.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A rapid review of the published literature was completed. An electronic database search of the literature published between July 1, 2020 and June 1, 2021 was performed in MEDLINE, Pubmed, and EMBASE. Primary studies evaluating the clinical effectiveness of PR for individuals with post-COVID symptoms were included.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Nine studies evaluating the effectiveness of PR were identified; most were small, experimental or quasi-experimental studies, including 1 RCT, and were primarily of low quality. After attending PR, all studies reported improvements in exercise capacity, pulmonary function, and/or quality of life for individuals with post-COVID symptoms who had been hospitalized for their acute COVID-19 infection. Few studies evaluated changes in post-COVID symptom severity or frequency and, of these, improvements in dyspnea, fatigue, anxiety and depression were observed following PR. Further, no studies evaluated non-hospitalized patients or long-term outcomes beyond 3 months after initiating PR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">With limited high-quality evidence, any recommendations or practical guidance for PR programmes for those with post-COVID symptoms should consider factors such as feasibility, current PR capacity, and resource constraints.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soril</LastName><ForeName>Lesley J J</ForeName><Initials>LJJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine Strategic Clinical Network - Respiratory Health Section, Alberta Health Services, Edmonton, AB, Canada; Division of General Internal Medicine, Department of Medicine, University of Alberta, Edmonton, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Damant</LastName><ForeName>Ronald W</ForeName><Initials>RW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine Strategic Clinical Network - Respiratory Health Section, Alberta Health Services, Edmonton, AB, Canada; Division of Pulmonary Medicine, Department of Medicine, and Alberta Respiratory Centre, University of Alberta, Edmonton, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lam</LastName><ForeName>Grace Y</ForeName><Initials>GY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary Medicine, Department of Medicine, and Alberta Respiratory Centre, University of Alberta, Edmonton, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Maeve P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary Medicine, Department of Medicine, and Alberta Respiratory Centre, University of Alberta, Edmonton, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weatherald</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Respirology and Libin Cardiovascular Institute, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bourbeau</LastName><ForeName>Jean</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of the McGill University Health Centre, McGill University, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hernandez</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Dalhousie University, Halifax, NS, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stickland</LastName><ForeName>Michael K</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine Strategic Clinical Network - Respiratory Health Section, Alberta Health Services, Edmonton, AB, Canada; Division of Pulmonary Medicine, Department of Medicine, and Alberta Respiratory Centre, University of Alberta, Edmonton, AB, Canada. Electronic address: michael.stickland@ualberta.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Respir Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8908438</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0954-6111</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35272262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8887973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2022.106782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0954-6111(22)00047-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dong E., Du H., Gardner L. An interactive web-based dashboard to track COVID-19 in real time. Lancet Infect. Dis. 2020;20(5):533&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32087114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A., Sehgal K., Gupta A., Madhavan M.V., McGroder C., Stevens J.S., et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat. Med. 2021;27(4):601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T., Hittle M., Goodman S.N. Assessment of the frequency and variety of persistent symptoms among patients with COVID-19: a systematic review. JAMA Netw. Open. 2021;4(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8155823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34037731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal F.M., Lam K., Sounderajah V., Clarke J.M., Ashrafian H., Darzi A. Characteristics and predictors of acute and chronic post-COVID syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;36:100899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8141371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34036253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO . 2021. WHO. COVID-19 Clinical Management: Living Guidance.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page M.J., McKenzie J.E., Bossuyt P.M., Boutron I., Hoffmann T.C., Mulrow C.D., et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spruit M.A., Singh S.J., Garvey C., ZuWallack R., Nici L., Rochester C., et al. An official American Thoracic Society/European Respiratory Society statement: key concepts and advances in pulmonary rehabilitation. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 2013;188(8):e13&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24127811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertacchini L., Paneroni M., Comini L., Scalvini S., Vitacca M. Recovering of oxygenation, physical function and disability in patients with COVID-19. Monaldi Arch. Chest Dis. 2021;91(4):449&#x2013;452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33840181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betschart M., Rezek S., Unger I., Beyer S., Gisi D., Shannon H., et al. Feasibility of an outpatient training program after COVID-19. Int. J. Environ. Res. Publ. Health. 2021;18(8)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8069591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33918887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickton F.M., Chisati E., Rylance J., Morton B. An improvised pulmonary telerehabilitation program for postacute COVID-19 patients would Be feasible and acceptable in a low-resource setting. Am. J. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 2021;100(3):209&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7886367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33395048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daynes E., Gerlis C., Chaplin E., Gardiner N., Singh S.J. Early experiences of rehabilitation for individuals post-COVID to improve fatigue, breathlessness exercise capacity and cognition - a cohort study. Chron. Respir. Dis. 2021;18 14799731211015691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8114752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33957805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K., Zhang W., Yang Y., Zhang J., Li Y., Chen Y. Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: a randomized controlled study. Compl. Ther. Clin. Pract. 2020;39:101166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maniscalco M., Fuschillo S., Ambrosino P., Martucci M., Papa A., Matera M.G., et al. Preexisting cardiorespiratory comorbidity does not preclude the success of multidisciplinary rehabilitation in post-COVID-19 patients. Respir. Med. 2021;184:106470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8123366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34022502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paneroni M., Vitacca M., Bernocchi P., Bertacchini L., Scalvini S. Feasibility of tele-rehabilitation in survivors of COVID-19 pneumonia. Pulmonology. 2021;28(2):152&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8045455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33893061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spielmanns M., Pekacka-Egli A.M., Schoendorf S., Windisch W., Hermann M. Effects of a comprehensive pulmonary rehabilitation in severe post-COVID-19 patients. Int. J. Environ. Res. Publ. Health. 2021;18(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33800094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tozato C., Ferreira B.F.C., Dalavina J.P., Molinari C.V., Alves V. Cardiopulmonary rehabilitation in post-COVID-19 patients: case series. Rev Bras Ter Intensiva. 2021;33(1):167&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8075336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33886866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spruit M.A., Holland A.E., Singh S.J., Tonia T., Wilson K.C., Troosters T. COVID-19: interim guidance on rehabilitation in the hospital and post-hospital phase from a European respiratory society and American thoracic society-coordinated international task force. Eur. Respir. J. 2020;56(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32817258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam G.Y., Befus A.D., Damant R.W., Ferrara G., Fuhr D.P., Stickland M.K., et al. Exertional intolerance and dyspnea with preserved lung function: an emerging long COVID phenotype? Respir. Res. 2021;22(1):222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8343348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34362372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>