<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34913540</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2702</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Symptoms and management of long COVID: A scoping review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>11</StartPage><EndPage>28</EndPage><MedlinePgn>11-28</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocn.16150</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This scoping review aims to describe published work on the symptoms and management of long COVID conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Symptoms and management of COVID-19 have focused on the acute stage. However, long-term consequences have also been observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A scoping review was performed based on the framework suggested by Arksey and O'Malley. We conducted a literature search to retrieve articles published from May 2020 to March 2021 in CINHAL, Cochrane library, Embase, PubMed and Web of science, including backward and forward citation tracking from the included articles. Among the 1880 articles retrieved, 34 articles met our criteria for review: 21 were related to symptom presentation and 13 to the management of long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Long COVID symptoms were described in 21 articles. Following COVID-19 treatment, hospitalised patients most frequently reported dyspnoea, followed by anosmia/ageusia, fatigue and cough, while non-hospitalised patients commonly reported cough, followed by fever and myalgia/arthralgia. Thirteen studies described management for long COVID: Focused on a multidisciplinary approach in seven articles, pulmonary rehabilitation in three articles, fatigue management in two articles and psychological therapy in one study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">People experience varied COVID-19 symptoms after treatment. However, guidelines on evidence-based, multidisciplinary management for long COVID conditions are limited in the literature. The COVID-19 pandemic may extend due to virus mutations; therefore, it is crucial to develop and disseminate evidence-based, multidisciplinary management guidelines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RELEVANCE TO CLINICAL PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A rehabilitation care plan and community healthcare plans are necessary for COVID-19 patients before discharge. Remote programmes could facilitate the monitoring and screening of people with long COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cha</LastName><ForeName>Chiyoung</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0115-1348</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing &amp; System Health &amp; Engineering Graduate School, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baek</LastName><ForeName>Gumhee</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1999-0158</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9207302</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0962-1067</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000093485" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Drug Treatment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003371" MajorTopicYN="N">Cough</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scoping review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">symptoms</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34913540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.16150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, H., Patel, K., Greenwood, D. C., Halpin, S., Lewthwaite, P., Salawu, A., Eyre, L., Breen, A., O'Connor, R., Jones, A., &amp; Sivan, M. (2020). Long-term clinical outcomes in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus outbreaks after hospitalisation or ICU admission: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Rehabilitation Medicine, 52(5), jrm00063. https://doi.org/10.2340/16501977-2694</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli, M., &amp; Donelli, D. (2020). Respiratory rehabilitation for post-COVID19 patients in spa centers: First steps from theory to practice. International Journal of Biometeorology, 64(10), 1811-1813. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00484-020-01962-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey, H., &amp; O'Malley, L. (2005). Scoping studies: Towards a methodological framework. International Journal of Society Research Methodol, 8(1), 19-32. https://doi.org/10.1080/1364557032000119616</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold, D. T., Hamilton, F. W., Milne, A., Morley, A. J., Viner, J., Attwood, M., Noel, A., Gunning, S., Hatrick, J., Hamilton, S., Elvers, K. T., Hyams, C., Bibby, A., Moran, E., Adamali, H. I., Dodd, J. W., Maskell, N. A., &amp; Barratt, S. L. (2020). Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up: results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax, 76(4), 399-401. https://doi.org/10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216086</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callard, F., &amp; Perego, E. (2021). How and why patients made Long Covid. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 268, 113426. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113426</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec;, A., Bernabei, R., Landi, F., &amp; Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. (2020). Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA, 324(6), 603-605. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.12603</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Schneider, C., Laurent, E., Lemaignen, A., Beaufils, E., Bourbao-Tournois, C., Laribi, S., Flament, T., Ferreira-Maldent, N., Bruy&#xe8;re, F., Stefic, K., Gaudy-Graffin, C., Grammatico-Guillon, L., &amp; Bernard, L. (2021). Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 27(2), 258-263. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2020.09.052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra, V., Flanders, S. A., O'Malley, M., Malani, A. N., &amp; Prescott, H. C. (2021). Sixty-day outcomes among patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Annals of Internal Medicine, 174(4), 576-578. https://doi.org/10.7326/M20-5661</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curci, C., Pisano, F., Bonacci, E., Camozzi, D. M., Ceravolo, C., Bergonzi, R., De Franceschi, S., Moro, P., Guarnieri, R., Ferrillo, M., Negrini, F., &amp; de Sire, A. (2020). Early rehabilitation in post-acute COVID-19 patients: data from an Italian COVID-19 rehabilitation unit and proposal of a treatment protocol. European Journal of Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine, 56(5), 633-641. https://doi.org/10.23736/S1973-9087.20.06339-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher, A., Balfanz, P., Cornelissen, C., M&#xfc;ller, A., Bergs, I., Marx, N., M&#xfc;ller-Wieland, D., Hartmann, B., Dreher, M., &amp; M&#xfc;ller, T. (2020). Follow up of patients with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): Pulmonary and extrapulmonary disease sequelae. Respiratory Medicine, 174, 106197. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rmed.2020.106197</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doykov, I., H&#xe4;llqvist, J., Gilmour, K. C., Grandjean, L., Mills, K., &amp; Heywood, W. E. (2020). &#x2018;The long tail of Covid-19&#x2019; - The detection of a prolonged inflammatory response after a SARS-CoV-2 infection in asymptomatic and mildly affected patients. F1000Research, 9, 1349. https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.27287.2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraro, F., Calafiore, D., Dambruoso, F., Guidarini, S., &amp; de Sire, A. (2021). COVID-19 related fatigue: Which role for rehabilitation in long COVID patients? A case series. Journal of Medical Virology, 93(4), 1896-1899. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.26717</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galv&#xe1;n-Tejada, C. E., Herrera-Garc&#xed;a, C. F., Godina-Gonz&#xe1;lez, S., Villagrana-Ba&#xf1;uelos, K. E., Amaro, J., Herrera-Garc&#xed;a, K., Rodr&#xed;guez-Qui&#xf1;ones, C., Zanella-Calzada, L. A., Ram&#xed;rez-Barranco, J., Avila, J., Reyes-Escobedo, F., Celaya-Padilla, J. M., Galv&#xe1;n-Tejada, J. I., Gamboa-Rosales, H., Mart&#xed;nez-Acu&#xf1;a, M., Cervantes-Villagrana, A., Rivas-Santiago, B., &amp; Gonzalez-Curiel, I. E. (2020). Persistence of COVID-19 symptoms after recovery in Mexican population. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 17(24), 9367. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17249367</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues, E., Janvier, P., Kherabi, Y., Le Bot, A., Hamon, A., Gouze, H., Doucet, L., Berkani, S., Oliosi, E., Mallart, E., Corre, F., Zarrouk, V., Moyer, J. D., Galy, A., Honsel, V., Fantin, B., &amp; Nguyen, Y. (2020). Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. The Journal of Infection, 81(6), e4-e6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2020.08.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go&#xeb;rtz, Y., Van Herck, M., Delbressine, J. M., Vaes, A. W., Meys, R., Machado, F., Houben-Wilke, S., Burtin, C., Posthuma, R., Franssen, F., van Loon, N., Hajian, B., Spies, Y., Vijlbrief, H., vant&#x2019;t Hul, A. J., Janssen, D., &amp; Spruit, M. A. (2020). Persistent symptoms 3 months after a SARS-CoV-2 infection: the long COVID syndrome? ERJ Open Research, 6(4), 00542-2020. https://doi.org/10.1183/23120541.00542-2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh, T., Knight, M., A'Court, C., Buxton, M., &amp; Husain, L. (2020). Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ, 370, m3026. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m3026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin, S. J., McIvor, C., Whyatt, G., Adams, A., Harvey, O., McLean, L., Walshaw, C., Kemp, S., Corrado, J., Singh, R., Collins, T., O'Connor, R. J., &amp; Sivan, M. (2021). Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. Journal of Medical Virology, 93(2), 1013-1022. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.26368</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickie, I., Davenport, T., Wakefield, D., Vollmer-Conna, U., Cameron, B., Vernon, S. D., Reeves, W. C., Lloyd, A., &amp; Dubbo Infection Outcomes Study Group. (2006). Post-infective and chronic fatigue syndromes precipitated by viral and non-viral pathogens: prospective cohort study. BMJ, 333(7568), 575. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.38933.585764.AE</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui, D. S., Joynt, G. M., Wong, K. T., Gomersall, C. D., Li, T. S., Antonio, G., Ko, F. W., Chan, M. C., Chan, D. P., Tong, M. W., Rainer, T. H., Ahuja, A. T., Cockram, C. S., &amp; Sung, J. J. (2005). Impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) on pulmonary function, functional capacity and quality of life in a cohort of survivors. Thorax, 60(5), 401-409. https://doi.org/10.1136/thx.2004.030205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C., Huang, L., Wang, Y., Li, X., Ren, L., Gu, X., Kang, L., Guo, L. I., Liu, M., Zhou, X., Luo, J., Huang, Z., Tu, S., Zhao, Y., Chen, L. I., Xu, D., Li, Y., Li, C., Peng, L. U., &#x2026; Cao, B. (2021). 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: A cohort study. Lancet, 397(10270), 220-232. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam, M. S., Ferdous, M. Z., Islam, U. S., Mosaddek, A., Potenza, M. N., &amp; Pardhan, S. (2021). Treatment, persistent symptoms, and depression in people infected with COVID-19 in Bangladesh. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 18(4), 1453. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18041453</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs, L. G., Gourna Paleoudis, E., Lesky-Di Bari, D., Nyirenda, T., Friedman, T., Gupta, A., Rasouli, L., Zetkulic, M., Balani, B., Ogedegbe, C., Bawa, H., Berrol, L., Qureshi, N., &amp; Aschner, J. L. (2020). Persistence of symptoms and quality of life at 35 days after hospitalization for COVID-19 infection. PLoS One, 15(12), e0243882. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0243882</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson, K. B., Rao, M., Bonilla, H., Subramanian, A., Hack, I., Madrigal, M., Singh, U., Jagannathan, P., &amp; Grant, P. (2021). Patients with uncomplicated COVID-19 have long-term persistent symptoms and functional impairment similar to patients with severe COVID-19: A cautionary tale during a global pandemic. Clinical Infectious Diseases, 73(3), e826-e829. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciab103</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal, M., Abo Omirah, M., Hussein, A., &amp; Saeed, H. (2021). Assessment and characterisation of long COVID manifestations. International Journal of Clinical Practice, 75(3), e13746. https://doi.org/10.1111/ijcp.13746</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooij, L., Groen, W. G., &amp; van Harten, W. H. (2017). The effectiveness of information technology-supported shared care for patients with chronic disease: A systematic review. Journal of Medical Internet Research, 19(6), e221. https://doi.org/10.2196/jmir.7405</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladds, E., Rushforth, A., Wieringa, S., Taylor, S., Rayner, C., Husain, L., &amp; Greenhalgh, T. (2021). Developing services for long COVID: Lessons from a study of wounded healers. Clinical Medicine, 21(1), 59-65. https://doi.org/10.7861/clinmed.2020-0962</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S. H., Shin, H. S., Park, H. Y., Kim, J. L., Lee, J. J., Lee, H., Won, S. D., &amp; Han, W. (2019). Depression as a mediator of chronic fatigue and post-traumatic stress symptoms in middle east respiratory syndrome survivors. Psychiatry Investigation, 16(1), 59-64. https://doi.org/10.30773/pi.2018.10.22.3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levac, D., Colquhoun, H., &amp; O'Brien, K. K. (2010). Scoping studies: Advancing the methodology. Implementation Science, 5, 69. https://doi.org/10.1186/1748-5908-5-69</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., Geng, M., Peng, Y., Meng, L., &amp; Lu, S. (2020). Molecular immune pathogenesis and diagnosis of COVID-19. Journal of Pharmaceutical Analysis, 10(2), 102-108. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpha.2020.03.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S., Yang, L., Zhang, C., Xiang, Y. T., Liu, Z., Hu, S., &amp; Zhang, B. (2020). Online mental health services in China during the COVID-19 outbreak. The Lancet Psychiatry, 7(4), e17-e18. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30077-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, K., Wang, X., Feng, S., Xia, X., Zhang, H., Rahaman, A., Dong, Z., Lu, Y., Li, X., Zhou, X., Zhao, H., Wang, Y., Wang, S., &amp; Baloch, Z. (2020). From the perspective of traditional Chinese medicine: Treatment of mental disorders in COVID-19 survivors. Biomedicine &amp; Pharmacotherapy, 132, 110810. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2020.110810</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal, S., Barnett, J., Brill, S. E., Brown, J. S., Denneny, E. K., Hare, S. S., Heightman, M., Hillman, T. E., Jacob, J., Jarvis, H. C., Lipman, M., Naidu, S. B., Nair, A., Porter, J. C., Tomlinson, G. S., Hurst, J. R. &amp; ARC Study Group. (2020). &#x2018;Long-COVID&#x2019;: A cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax, 76(4), 396-398. https://doi.org/10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-215818</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez, O., Merino, E., Leon-Ramirez, J. M., Andres, M., Ramos, J. M., Arenas-Jim&#xe9;nez, J., Asensio, S., Sanchez, R., Ruiz-Torregrosa, P., Galan, I., Scholz, A., Amo, A., Gonz&#xe1;lez-delaAleja, P., Boix, V., Gil, J., &amp; COVID19-ALC Research Group. (2021). Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: A Mediterranean cohort study. The Journal of Infection, 82(3), 378-383. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2021.01.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS. (2020, September 8). Post-COVID syndrome (Long COVID). https://www.england.nhs.uk/coronavirus/post-covid-syndrome-long-covid/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, H. Y., Park, W. B., Lee, S. H., Kim, J. L., Lee, J. J., Lee, H., &amp; Shin, H. S. (2020). Posttraumatic stress disorder and depression of survivors 12 months after the outbreak of Middle East respiratory syndrome in South Korea. BMC Public Health, 20(1), 605. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-020-08726-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, J. I. (2021). 31% of people who have recovered from COVID-19 continue to suffer from &#x2018;brainfog'. https://view.asiae.co.kr/article/2021011922141224070</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, W. B., Jun, K. I., Kim, G., Choi, J. P., Rhee, J. Y., Cheon, S., Lee, C. H., Park, J. S., Kim, Y., Joh, J. S., Chin, B. S., Choe, P. G., Bang, J. H., Park, S. W., Kim, N. J., Lim, D. G., Kim, Y. S., Oh, M. D., &amp; Shin, H. S. (2018). Correlation between pneumonia severity and pulmonary complications in middle east respiratory syndrome. Journal of Korean Medical Science, 33(24), e169. https://doi.org/10.3346/jkms.2018.33.e169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pastora-Bernal, J. M., Estebanez-P&#xe9;rez, M. J., Molina-Torres, G., Garc&#xed;a-L&#xf3;pez, F. J., Sobrino-S&#xe1;nchez, R., &amp; Mart&#xed;n-Valero, R. (2021). Telerehabilitation intervention in patients with COVID-19 after hospital discharge to improve functional capacity and quality of life. Study Protocol for a Multicenter Randomized Clinical Trial. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 18(6), 2924. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18062924</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen, M. S., Kristiansen, M. F., Hanusson, K. D., Danielsen, M. E., &#xc1; Steig, B., Gaini, S., Str&#xf8;m, M., &amp; Weihe, P. (2020). Long COVID in the Faroe Islands: A Longitudinal Study among nonhospitalized patients. Clinical infectious diseases : an official publication of the Infectious Diseases Society of America, ciaa1792. Advance online publication. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciaa1792</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto, M., Gimigliano, F., De Simone, S., Costa, M., Bianchi, A., &amp; Iolascon, G. (2020). Post-acute COVID-19 rehabilitation network proposal: From intensive to extensive and home-based IT supported services. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 17(24), 9335. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17249335</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiq, M., Rathore, F. A., Clegg, D., &amp; Rasker, J. J. (2020). Pulmonary rehabilitation in COVID-19 patients: A scoping review of current practice and its application during the pandemic. Turkish Journal of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, 66(4), 480-494. https://doi.org/10.5606/tftrd.2020.6889</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan, M., &amp; Taylor, S. (2020). NICE guideline on long COVID. BMJ, 371, m4938. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m4938</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smits, M., Staal, J. B., &amp; van Goor, H. (2020). Could virtual reality play a role in the rehabilitation after COVID-19 infection? BMJ Open Sport &amp; Exercise Medicine, 6(1), e000943. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjsem-2020-000943</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su&#xe1;rez-Robles, M., Iguaran-Berm&#xfa;dez, M., Garc&#xed;a-Klepizg, J. L., Lorenzo-Villalba, N., &amp; M&#xe9;ndez-Bail&#xf3;n, M. (2020). Ninety days post-hospitalization evaluation of residual COVID-19 symptoms through a phone call check list. The Pan African Medical Journal, 37, 289. https://doi.org/10.11604/pamj.2020.37.289.27110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suliman, Y. A., Dobrota, R., Huscher, D., Nguyen-Kim, T. D., Maurer, B., Jordan, S., Speich, R., Frauenfelder, T., &amp; Distler, O. (2015). Brief Report: Pulmonary Function Tests: High Rate of False-Negative Results in the Early Detection and Screening of Scleroderma-Related Interstitial Lung Disease. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology (Hoboken, N.J.), 67(12), 3256-3261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes, D. L., Holdsworth, L., Jawad, N., Gunasekera, P., Morice, A. H., &amp; Crooks, M. G. (2021). Long COVID symptom burden: What is Long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung, 199(2), 113-119. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00408-021-00423-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venturelli, S., Benatti, S. V., Casati, M., Binda, F., Zuglian, G., Imeri, G., Conti, C., Biffi, A. M., Spada, M. S., Bondi, E., Camera, G., Severgnini, R., Giammarresi, A., Marinaro, C., Rossini, A., Bonaffini, P. A., Guerra, G., Bellasi, A., Cesa, S., &amp; Rizzi, M. (2021). Surviving COVID-19 in Bergamo province: A post-acute outpatient re-evaluation. Epidemiology and Infection, 149, e32. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0950268821000145</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO (2021). Coronavirus disease (COVID-19). https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, T. L., &amp; Weitzer, D. J. (2021). Long COVID and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS)-A systemic review and comparison of clinical presentation and symptomatology. Medicina, 57(5), 418. https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina57050418</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worsowicz, G., &amp; Stone, J. (2020). Post-COVID rehabilitation services emphasizing telemedicine. Missouri Medicine, 117(4), 319-320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong, Q., Xu, M., Li, J., Liu, Y., Zhang, J., Xu, Y., &amp; Dong, W. (2021). Clinical sequelae of COVID-19 survivors in Wuhan, China: A single-centre longitudinal study. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 27(1), 89-95. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2020.09.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, J., Ji, P., Pang, J., Zhong, Z., Li, H., He, C., Zhang, J., &amp; Zhao, C. (2020). Clinical characteristics of 3062 COVID-19 patients: A meta-analysis. Journal of Medical Virology, 92(10), 1902-1914. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.25884</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>