<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37915075</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1479-5876</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of translational medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Transl Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Genetic risk factors for severe and fatigue dominant long COVID and commonalities with ME/CFS identified by combinatorial analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>775</StartPage><MedlinePgn>775</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">775</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12967-023-04588-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Long COVID is a debilitating chronic condition that has affected over 100 million people globally. It is characterized by a diverse array of symptoms, including fatigue, cognitive dysfunction and respiratory problems. Studies have so far largely failed to identify genetic associations, the mechanisms behind the disease, or any common pathophysiology with other conditions such as myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) that present with similar symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We used a combinatorial analysis approach to identify combinations of genetic variants significantly associated with the development of long COVID and to examine the biological mechanisms underpinning its various symptoms. We compared two subpopulations of long COVID patients from Sano Genetics' Long COVID GOLD study cohort, focusing on patients with severe or fatigue dominant phenotypes. We evaluated the genetic signatures previously identified in an ME/CFS population against this long COVID population to understand similarities with other fatigue disorders that may be triggered by a prior viral infection. Finally, we also compared the output of this long COVID analysis against known genetic associations in other chronic diseases, including a range of metabolic and neurological disorders, to understand the overlap of pathophysiological mechanisms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Combinatorial analysis identified 73 genes that were highly associated with at least one of the long COVID populations included in this analysis. Of these, 9 genes have prior associations with acute COVID-19, and 14 were differentially expressed in a transcriptomic analysis of long COVID patients. A pathway enrichment analysis revealed that the biological pathways most significantly associated with the 73 long COVID genes were mainly aligned with neurological and cardiometabolic diseases. Expanded genotype analysis suggests that specific SNX9 genotypes are a significant contributor to the risk of or protection against severe long COVID infection, but that the gene-disease relationship is context dependent and mediated by interactions with KLF15 and RYR3. Comparison of the genes uniquely associated with the Severe and Fatigue Dominant long COVID patients revealed significant differences between the pathways enriched in each subgroup. The genes unique to Severe long COVID patients were associated with immune pathways such as myeloid differentiation and macrophage foam cells. Genes unique to the Fatigue Dominant subgroup were enriched in metabolic pathways such as MAPK/JNK signaling. We also identified overlap in the genes associated with Fatigue Dominant long COVID and ME/CFS, including several involved in circadian rhythm regulation and insulin regulation. Overall, 39 SNPs associated in this study with long COVID can be linked to 9 genes identified in a recent combinatorial analysis of ME/CFS patient from UK Biobank. Among the 73 genes associated with long COVID, 42 are potentially tractable for novel drug discovery approaches, with 13 of these already targeted by drugs in clinical development pipelines. From this analysis for example, we identified TLR4 antagonists as repurposing candidates with potential to protect against long term cognitive impairment pathology caused by SARS-CoV-2. We are currently evaluating the repurposing potential of these drug targets for use in treating long COVID and/or ME/CFS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This study demonstrates the power of combinatorial analytics for stratifying heterogeneous populations in complex diseases that do not have simple monogenic etiologies. These results build upon the genetic findings from combinatorial analyses of severe acute COVID-19 patients and an ME/CFS population and we expect that access to additional independent, larger patient datasets will further improve the disease insights and validate potential treatment options in long COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Krystyna</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PrecisionLife Ltd, Unit 8B Bankside, Hanborough Business Park, Oxford, OX29 8LJ, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pearson</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PrecisionLife Ltd, Unit 8B Bankside, Hanborough Business Park, Oxford, OX29 8LJ, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Das</LastName><ForeName>Sayoni</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PrecisionLife Ltd, Unit 8B Bankside, Hanborough Business Park, Oxford, OX29 8LJ, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sardell</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PrecisionLife Ltd, Unit 8B Bankside, Hanborough Business Park, Oxford, OX29 8LJ, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chocian</LastName><ForeName>Karolina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PrecisionLife Ltd, Unit 8B Bankside, Hanborough Business Park, Oxford, OX29 8LJ, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gardner</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5490-3358</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PrecisionLife Ltd, Unit 8B Bankside, Hanborough Business Park, Oxford, OX29 8LJ, UK. steve@precisionlife.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Transl Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101190741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1479-5876</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015673" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fatigue Syndrome, Chronic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Combinatorial analytics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ME/CFS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PASC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">POTS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient stratification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute COVID syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>K.T., M.P., S.D., K.C., J.S, and S.G. are employees of PrecisionLife, Ltd. S.G. is a shareholder of PrecisionLife, Ltd.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37915075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10621206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-023-04588-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12967-023-04588-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization WHO Fact Sheets Post COVID-19 condition (Long COVID) available from https://www.who.int/europe/news-room/fact-sheets/item/post-covid-19-condition. Accessed 8 Oct 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Mahoney LL, Routen A, Gillies C, Ekezie W, Welford A, Zhang A, Karamchandani U, Simms-Williams N, Cassambai S, et al. The prevalence and long-term health effects of long Covid among hospitalised and non-hospitalised populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;1(55):101762. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2022.101762.Erratum.In:EClinicalMedicine.2023May;59:101959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2022.101762.Erratum.In:EClinicalMedicine.2023May;59:101959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9714474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36474804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard https://covid19.who.int/, last Accessed 4 June 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallick D, Goyal L, Chourasia P, Zapata MR, Yashi K, Surani S. COVID-19 induced postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS): a review. Cureus. 2023;15(3):e36955. doi: 10.7759/cureus.36955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.36955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10065129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37009342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballouz T, Menges D, Anagnostopoulos A, Domenghino A, Aschmann HE, Frei A, Fehr JS, Puhan MA. Recovery and symptom trajectories up to two years after SARS-CoV-2 infection: population based, longitudinal cohort study. BMJ. 2023;31(381):e074425. doi: 10.1136/bmj-2022-074425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2022-074425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10230608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37257891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kothari AS, Bhatt G, Gupta N, Ali AE, Najam N, Mazroua M, Mansoor T, Amal T, Elsaban M, Deo R. Cardiac complications among long COVID patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023;81(8):2115&#x2013;2115. doi: 10.1016/S0735-1097(23)02559-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0735-1097(23)02559-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2013;146. doi: 10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Ling S, Lui LMW, Lee Y, Gill H, Teopiz KM, Rodrigues NB, Subramaniapillai M, Di Vincenzo JD, Cao B, Lin K, Mansur RB, Ho RC, Rosenblat JD, Miskowiak KW, Vinberg M, Maletic V, McIntyre RS. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in Post-COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun. 2022;101:93&#x2013;135. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2021.12.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2021.12.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison PJ, Taquet M. Neuropsychiatric disorders following SARS-CoV-2 infection. Brain. 2023;146(6):2241&#x2013;2247. doi: 10.1093/brain/awad008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awad008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10232232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36729559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubota T, Kuroda N, Sone D. Neuropsychiatric aspects of long COVID: a comprehensive review. Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2023;77(2):84&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1111/pcn.13508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pcn.13508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10108156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36385449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanichkachorn G, Newcomb R, Cowl CT, Murad MH, Breeher L, Miller S, Trenary M, Neveau D, Higgins S. Post-COVID-19 syndrome (long haul syndrome): description of a multidisciplinary clinic at mayo clinic and characteristics of the initial patient cohort. Mayo Clin Proc. 2021;96(7):1782&#x2013;1791. doi: 10.1016/j.mayocp.2021.04.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mayocp.2021.04.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8112396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34218857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley SE, Karlson EW, Levitan EB, Levy B, McComsey GA, McCorkell L, Nadkarni GN, Parthasarathy S, RECOVER Consortium et al. Development of a definition of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA. 2023;329(22):1934&#x2013;1946. doi: 10.1001/jama.2023.8823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2023.8823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10214179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lammi V, Ollila HM, Long COVID Host Genetics Initiative Tackling long COVID using international host genetics research collaboration. Sleep Med. 2022;100:S64&#x2013;S65. doi: 10.1016/j.sleep.2022.05.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2022.05</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lammi V, Nakanishi T, Jones SE, Long COVID Host Genetics Initiative et al. Genome-wide association study of long COVID. Preprint at medRxiv. 2023 doi: 10.1101/2023.06.29.23292056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.06.29.23292056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor K, Das S, Pearson M, Kozubek J, Pawlowski M, Jensen CE, Skowron Z, M&#xf8;ller GL, Strivens M, Gardner S. Analysis of genetic host response risk factors in severe COVID-19 patients. Preprint at medRxiv. 2020 doi: 10.1101/2020.06.17.20134015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.06.17.20134015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das S, Taylor K, Kozubek J, Sardell J, Gardner S. Genetic risk factors for ME/CFS identified using combinatorial analysis. J Transl Med. 2022;20(1):598. doi: 10.1186/s12967-022-03815-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-022-03815-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9749644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36517845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner S. Combinatorial analytics: an essential tool for the delivery of precision medicine and precision agriculture. Artif Intell Life Sci. 2021;1:100003. doi: 10.1016/j.ailsci.2021.100003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ailsci.2021.100003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tam V, Patel N, Turcotte M, Boss&#xe9; Y, Par&#xe9; G, Meyre D. Benefits and limitations of genome-wide association studies. Nat Rev Genet. 2019;20(8):467&#x2013;484. doi: 10.1038/s41576-019-0127-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41576-019-0127-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31068683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh R, Tadros R, Bezzina CR. When genetic burden reaches threshold. Eur Heart J. 2020;41(39):3849&#x2013;3855. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7599032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32350504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sano Genetics GOLD Study Overview available from https://sanogenetics.com/study/gold/. Accessed 8 Oct 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UK Government Guidance COVID-19 Response: Living with COVID-19 available from https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/covid-19-response-living-with-covid-19/covid-19-response-living-with-covid-19. Accessed 8 Oct 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamini Y, Hochberg Y. Controlling the false discovery rate: a practical and powerful approach to multiple hypothesis testing. J R Stat Soc B. 1995;57:289&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howe KL, Achuthan P, Allen J, Allen J, Alvarez-Jarreta J, Amode MR, Armean IM, Azov AG, Bennett R, Bhai J, et al. Ensembl 2021. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021;49(D1):D884&#x2013;D891. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkaa942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkaa942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7778975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33137190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y, Sch&#xe4;ffer AA, Sherry ST, Feolo M. Quickly identifying identical and closely related subjects in large databases using genotype data. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(6):e0179106. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0179106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0179106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5469481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28609482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacFarland TW, Yates JM, MacFarland TW, Yates JM. Mann&#x2013;whitney u test. In: MacFarland TW, Yates JM, editors. Introduction to nonparametric statistics for the biological sciences using R. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2016. pp. 103&#x2013;132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochoa D, Hercules A, Carmona M, Suveges D, Baker J, Malangone C, Lopez I, Miranda A, Cruz-Castillo C, Fumis L, Bernal-Llinares M, Tsukanov K, Cornu H, Tsirigos K, Razuvayevskaya O, Buniello A, Schwartzentruber J, Karim M, Ariano B, Martinez Osorio RE, Ferrer J, Ge X, Machlitt-Northen S, Gonzalez-Uriarte A, Saha S, Tirunagari S, Mehta C, Rold&#xe1;n-Romero JM, Horswell S, Young S, Ghoussaini M, Hulcoop DG, Dunham I, McDonagh EM. The next-generation open targets platform: reimagined, redesigned, rebuilt. Nucleic Acids Res. 2023;51(D1):D1353&#x2013;D1359. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkac1046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkac1046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9825572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36399499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raudvere U, Kolberg L, Kuzmin I, Arak T, Adler P, Peterson H, Vilo J. g:Profiler: a web server for functional enrichment analysis and conversions of gene lists (2019 update) Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;47(W1):W191&#x2013;W198. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkz369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkz369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6602461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31066453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purcell S, Neale B, Todd-Brown K, Thomas L, Ferreira MA, Bender D, Maller J, Sklar P, De Bakker PI, Daly MJ, Sham PC. PLINK: a tool set for whole-genome association and population-based linkage analyses. Am J Hum Genet. 2007;81(3):559&#x2013;575. doi: 10.1086/519795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/519795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1950838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17701901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Goede KE, Harber KJ, Gorki FS, Verberk SGS, Groh LA, Keuning ED, Struys EA, van Weeghel M, Haschemi A, de Winther MPJ, van Dierendonck XAMH, Van den Bossche J. d-2-Hydroxyglutarate is an anti-inflammatory immunometabolite that accumulates in macrophages after TLR4 activation. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Basis Dis. 2022;1868(9):166427. doi: 10.1016/j.bbadis.2022.166427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbadis.2022.166427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35526742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosharaf MP, Reza MS, Kibria MK, Ahmed FF, Kabir MH, Hasan S, Mollah MNH. Computational identification of host genomic biomarkers highlighting their functions, pathways and regulators that influence SARS-CoV-2 infections and drug repurposing. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):4279. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-08073-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-08073-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8915158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35277538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi Y. Metabolic impact of glucagon deficiency. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2011;13(Suppl 1):151&#x2013;157. doi: 10.1111/j.1463-1326.2011.01456.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1463-1326.2011.01456.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21824269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hakeim HK, Al-Rubaye HT, Jubran AS, Almulla AF, Moustafa SR, Maes M. Increased insulin resistance due to Long COVID is associated with depressive symptoms and partly predicted by the inflammatory response during acute infection. Braz J Psychiatry. 2023;45(3):205&#x2013;215. doi: 10.47626/1516-4446-2022-3002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47626/1516-4446-2022-3002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10288478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36917827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ustinova M, Peculis R, Rescenko R, Rovite V, Zaharenko L, Elbere I, Silamikele L, Konrade I, Sokolovska J, Pirags V, Klovins J. Novel susceptibility loci identified in a genome-wide association study of type 2 diabetes complications in population of Latvia. BMC Med Genomics. 2021;14(1):18. doi: 10.1186/s12920-020-00860-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12920-020-00860-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7802349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33430853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav A, Kataria MA, Saini V, Yadav A. Role of leptin and adiponectin in insulin resistance. Clin Chim Acta. 2013;18(417):80&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1016/j.cca.2012.12.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cca.2012.12.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23266767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Kuraishy HM, Al-Gareeb AI, Bungau SG, Radu AF, Batiha GE. The potential molecular implications of adiponectin in the evolution of SARS-CoV-2: Inbuilt tendency. J King Saud Univ Sci. 2022;34(8):102347. doi: 10.1016/j.jksus.2022.102347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksus.2022.102347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9524222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36211634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorighello GG, Assis LHP, Rentz T, Morari J, Santana MFM, Passarelli M, Ridgway ND, Vercesi AE, Oliveira HCF. Novel Role of CETP in macrophages: reduction of mitochondrial oxidants production and modulation of cell immune-metabolic profile. Antioxidants. 2022;11(9):1734. doi: 10.3390/antiox11091734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox11091734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9495589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36139808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Li G. A tumor suppressor DLC1: The functions and signal pathways. J Cell Physiol. 2020;235(6):4999&#x2013;5007. doi: 10.1002/jcp.29402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcp.29402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31773748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma M, Brunal AA, Clark KC, Studtmann C, Stebbins K, Higashijima SI, Pan YA. Deficiency in the cell-adhesion molecule dscaml1 impairs hypothalamic CRH neuron development and perturbs normal neuroendocrine stress axis function. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2023;16(11):1113675. doi: 10.3389/fcell.2023.1113675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcell.2023.1113675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9978177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36875755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan KR, Koh CWT, Ng DHL, Qin S, Ooi JSG, Ong EZ, Zhang SLX, Sam H, Kalimuddin S, Low JGH, Ooi EE. Early peripheral blood MCEMP1 and HLA-DRA expression predicts COVID-19 prognosis. EBioMedicine. 2023;89:104472. doi: 10.1016/j.ebiom.2023.104472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2023.104472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9934388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36801619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulos KI, Papadopoulou A, Aw TC. Beauty and the beast: host microRNA-155 versus SARS-CoV-2. Hum Cell. 2023;36(3):908&#x2013;922. doi: 10.1007/s13577-023-00867-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13577-023-00867-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9969954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36847920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed FF, Reza MS, Sarker MS, Islam MS, Mosharaf MP, Hasan S, Mollah MNH. Identification of host transcriptome-guided repurposable drugs for SARS-CoV-1 infections and their validation with SARS-CoV-2 infections by using the integrated bioinformatics approaches. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(4):e0266124. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0266124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0266124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8989220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35390032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao Y, Kong N, Wang H, Sun D, Dong S, Chen X, Zheng H, Tong W, Yu H, Yu L, Huang Y, Wang H, Sui B, Zhao L, Liao Y, Zhang W, Tong G, Shan T. PABPC4 broadly inhibits coronavirus replication by degrading nucleocapsid protein through selective autophagy. Microbiol Spectr. 2021;9(2):e0090821. doi: 10.1128/Spectrum.00908-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/Spectrum.00908-21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8510267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34612687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Ozono S, Tada T, Tobiume M, Kameoka M, Kishigami S, Fujita H, Tokunaga K. MARCH8 targets cytoplasmic lysine residues of various viral envelope glycoproteins. Microbiol Spectr. 2022;10(1):e0061821. doi: 10.1128/spectrum.00618-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/spectrum.00618-21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8754143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35019698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CH, Chen YC, Huang CH, Wang SH, Lin JS, Lo SC, Huang CC. Exploring potential proteomic biomarkers for prognosis of infective endocarditis through profiled autoantibodies by an immunomics protein array technique. Heart Surg Forum. 2020;23(5):E555&#x2013;E573. doi: 10.1532/hsf.3017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1532/hsf.3017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32990583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ish-Shalom E, Meirow Y, Sade-Feldman M, Kanterman J, Wang L, Mizrahi O, Klieger Y, Baniyash M. Impaired SNX9 expression in immune cells during chronic inflammation: prognostic and diagnostic implications. J Immunol. 2016;196(1):156&#x2013;167. doi: 10.4049/jimmunol.1402877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.1402877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26608909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendris N, Schmid SL. Endocytosis, metastasis and beyond: multiple facets of SNX9. Trends Cell Biol. 2017;27(3):189&#x2013;200. doi: 10.1016/j.tcb.2016.11.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tcb.2016.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5318277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27989654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontes-Dantas FL, Fernandes GG, Gutman EG, De Lima EV, Antonio LS, Hammerle MB, Mota-Araujo HP, Colodeti LC, Ara&#xfa;jo SMB, Froz GM, da Silva TN, Duarte LA, Salvio AL, Pires KL, Leon LAA, Vasconcelos CCF, Rom&#xe3;o L, Savio LEB, Silva JL, da Costa R, Clarke JR, Da Poian AT, Alves-Leon SV, Passos GF, Figueiredo CP. SARS-CoV-2 Spike protein induces TLR4-mediated long-term cognitive dysfunction recapitulating post-COVID-19 syndrome in mice. Cell Rep. 2023;42(3):112189. doi: 10.1016/j.celrep.2023.112189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.celrep.2023.112189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9935273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36857178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Mukherjee S. In silico studies on the comparative characterization of the interactions of SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein with ACE-2 receptor homologs and human TLRs. J Med Virol. 2020;92(10):2105&#x2013;2113. doi: 10.1002/jmv.25987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.25987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32383269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piehler A, Kaminski WE, Wenzel JJ, Langmann T, Schmitz G. Molecular structure of a novel cholesterol-responsive A subclass ABC transporter, ABCA9. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2002;295(2):408&#x2013;416. doi: 10.1016/s0006-291x(02)00659-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0006-291x(02)00659-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12150964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S, Song J, Baek IJ, Jang KY, Han CY, Jun DW, Kim PK, Raught B, Jin EJ. Loss of Acot12 contributes to NAFLD independent of lipolysis of adipose tissue. Exp Mol Med. 2021;53(7):1159&#x2013;1169. doi: 10.1038/s12276-021-00648-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s12276-021-00648-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8333268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34285335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu R, Liu X, Bai X, Xiao C, Dong Y. Different expression of lipid metabolism-related genes in Shandong black cattle and Luxi cattle based on transcriptome analysis. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):21915. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-79086-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-79086-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33318614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Deveire KN, Scranton SK, Kostek MA, Angelopoulos TJ, Clarkson PM, Gordon PM, Moyna NM, Visich PS, Zoeller RF, Thompson PD, Devaney JM, Gordish-Dressman H, Hoffman EP, Maresh CM, Pescatello LS. Variants of the ankyrin repeat domain 6 gene (ANKRD6) and muscle and physical activity phenotypes among European-derived American adults. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(7):1740&#x2013;1748. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31825c2bef.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31825c2bef</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4147939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22580979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dibley MG, Formosa LE, Lyu B, Reljic B, McGann D, Muellner-Wong L, Kraus F, Sharpe AJ, Stroud DA, Ryan MT. The mitochondrial acyl-carrier protein interaction network highlights important roles for LYRM family members in complex I and mitoribosome assembly. Mol Cell Proteomics. 2020;19(1):65&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1074/mcp.RA119.001784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/mcp.RA119.001784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6944232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31666358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen T, Miao Y, Ding C, Fan W, Liu S, Lv Y, Gao X, De Boevre M, Yan L, Okoth S, De Saeger S, Song S. Activation of the p38/MAPK pathway regulates autophagy in response to the CYPOR-dependent oxidative stress induced by zearalenone in porcine intestinal epithelial cells. Food Chem Toxicol. 2019;131:110527. doi: 10.1016/j.fct.2019.05.035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fct.2019.05.035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31173817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killackey SA, Bi Y, Soares F, Hammi I, Winsor NJ, Abdul-Sater AA, Philpott DJ, Arnoult D, Girardin SE. Mitochondrial protein import stress regulates the LC3 lipidation step of mitophagy through NLRX1 and RRBP1. Mol Cell. 2022;82(15):2815&#x2013;2831.e5. doi: 10.1016/j.molcel.2022.06.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcel.2022.06.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35752171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larhammar M, Huntwork-Rodriguez S, Rudhard Y, Sengupta-Ghosh A, Lewcock JW. The Ste20 family kinases MAP4K4, MINK1, and TNIK converge to regulate stress-induced JNK signaling in neurons. J Neurosci. 2017;37(46):11074&#x2013;11084. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0905-17.2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0905-17.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6596808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28993483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgiadou M, Ivaska J. Tensins: bridging AMP-activated protein kinase with integrin activation. Trends Cell Biol. 2017;27(10):703&#x2013;711. doi: 10.1016/j.tcb.2017.06.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tcb.2017.06.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28698049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westmuckett AD, Thacker KM, Moore KL. Tyrosine sulfation of native mouse Psgl-1 is required for optimal leukocyte rolling on P-selectin in vivo. PLoS ONE. 2011;6(5):e20406. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0020406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0020406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3102115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21633705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulte E. 68. Untangling genetic risk factors of long covid: work of the international covid-19 host genetics initiative. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2022;63:e82. doi: 10.1016/j.euroneuro.2022.07.155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2022.07.155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satu MS, Khan MI, Rahman MR, Howlader KC, Roy S, Roy SS, Quinn JMW, Moni MA. Diseasome and comorbidities complexities of SARS-CoV-2 infection with common malignant diseases. Brief Bioinform. 2021;22(2):1415&#x2013;1429. doi: 10.1093/bib/bbab003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bib/bbab003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33539530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>OpenTargets Evidence for GPC6 in COVID-19 available from https://platform.opentargets.org/evidence/ENSG00000183098/MONDO_0100096. Accessed 8 Oct 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulthei&#xdf; C, Paschold L, Willscher E, Simnica D, W&#xf6;stemeier A, Muscate F, Wass M, Eisenmann S, Dutzmann J, Key&#xdf;er G, Gagliani N, Binder M. Maturation trajectories and transcriptional landscape of plasmablasts and autoreactive B cells in COVID-19. iScience. 2021;24(11):103325. doi: 10.1016/j.isci.2021.103325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isci.2021.103325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8536484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34723157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glessner JT, Chang X, Mentch F, Qu H, Abrams DJ, Thomas A, Sleiman PMA, Hakonarson H. COVID-19 in pediatrics: genetic susceptibility. Front Genet. 2022;16(13):928466. doi: 10.3389/fgene.2022.928466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fgene.2022.928466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9425045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36051697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson RC, Simons NW, Wilkins L, Cheng E, Del Valle DM, Hoffman GE, Cervia C, Fennessy B, Mouskas K, Francoeur NJ, et al. Molecular states during acute COVID-19 reveal distinct etiologies of long-term sequelae. Nat Med. 2023;29(1):236&#x2013;246. doi: 10.1038/s41591-022-02107-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-02107-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9873574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36482101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashburner M, Ball CA, Blake JA, Botstein D, Butler H, Cherry JM, Davis AP, Dolinski K, Dwight SS, Eppig JT, Harris MA, Hill DP, Issel-Tarver L, Kasarskis A, Lewis S, Matese JC, Richardson JE, Ringwald M, Rubin GM, Sherlock G. Gene ontology: tool for the unification of biology. Gene Ontol Consort Nat Genet. 2000;25(1):25&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1038/75556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/75556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3037419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10802651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Gene Ontology Consortium The gene ontology knowledgebase in 2023. Genetics. 2023;224(1):031. doi: 10.1093/genetics/iyad031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/genetics/iyad031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10158837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36866529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stopford MJ, Allen SP, Ferraiuolo L. A high-throughput and pathophysiologically relevant astrocyte-motor neuron co-culture assay for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis therapeutic discovery. Bio Protoc. 2019;9(17):e3353. doi: 10.21769/BioProtoc.3353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21769/BioProtoc.3353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6774773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31579294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das S, Taylor K, Beaulah S, Gardner S. Systematic indication extension for drugs using patient stratification insights generated by combinatorial analytics. Patterns. 2022;3(6):100496. doi: 10.1016/j.patter.2022.100496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.patter.2022.100496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35755863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee S. Toll-like receptor&#xa0;4 in COVID-19: friend or foe? Future Virol. 2022 doi: 10.2217/fvl-2021-0249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/fvl-2021-0249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9017673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35462619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu ZM, Yang MH, Yu K, Lian ZX, Deng SL. Toll-like receptor (TLRs) agonists and antagonists for COVID-19 treatments. Front Pharmacol. 2022;7(13):989664. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2022.989664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.989664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9518217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36188605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GlobalData Pharma Market Data and Insights available from https://www.globaldata.com/industries-we-cover/pharmaceutical/. Accessed 8 Oct 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical Development of EB05 for the Treatment of ARDS presented at ARDS Drug Development Summit July 14, 2022, available from https://www.edesabiotech.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Edesa-ARDS-Summit-July2022-web.pdf. Accessed 8 Oct 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabas I, Bornfeldt KE. Macrophage phenotype and function in different stages of atherosclerosis. Circ Res. 2016;118(4):653&#x2013;667. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.115.306256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.115.306256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4762068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26892964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wendisch D, Dietrich O, Mari T, von Stillfried S, Ibarra IL, Mittermaier M, Mache C, Chua RL, Knoll R, Timm S, Brumhard S, Deutsche COVID-19 OMICS Initiative (DeCOI) et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection triggers profibrotic macrophage responses and lung fibrosis. Cell. 2021;184(26):6243&#x2013;6261.e27. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2021.11.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2021.11.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8626230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34914922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomas C, Brown A, Strassheim V, Elson JL, Newton J, Manning P. Cellular bioenergetics is impaired in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(10):e0186802. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0186802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0186802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5655451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29065167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trotta R, Fettucciari K, Azzoni L, Abebe B, Puorro KA, Eisenlohr LC, Perussia B. Differential role of p38 and c-Jun N-terminal kinase 1 mitogen-activated protein kinases in NK cell cytotoxicity. J Immunol. 2000;165(4):1782&#x2013;1789. doi: 10.4049/jimmunol.165.4.1782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.165.4.1782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10925255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huth TK, Staines D, Marshall-Gradisnik S. ERK1/2, MEK1/2 and p38 downstream signalling molecules impaired in CD56 dim CD16+ and CD56 bright CD16 dim/- natural killer cells in chronic fatigue Syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis patients. J Transl Med. 2016;21(14):97. doi: 10.1186/s12967-016-0859-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-016-0859-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4839077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27098723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Goede P, Wefers J, Brombacher EC, Schrauwen P, Kalsbeek A. Circadian rhythms in mitochondrial respiration. J Mol Endocrinol. 2018;60(3):R115&#x2013;R130. doi: 10.1530/JME-17-0196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/JME-17-0196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5854864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29378772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt K, Grimm A, Dallmann R, Oettinghaus B, Restelli LM, Witzig M, Ishihara N, Mihara K, Ripperger JA, Albrecht U, Frank S, Brown SA, Eckert A. Circadian control of DRP1 activity regulates mitochondrial dynamics and bioenergetics. Cell Metab. 2018;27(3):657&#x2013;666.e5. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2018.01.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2018.01.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29478834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oosterman JE, Wopereis S, Kalsbeek A. The circadian clock, shift work, and tissue-specific insulin resistance. Endocrinology. 2020;161(12):bqaa180. doi: 10.1210/endocr/bqaa180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/endocr/bqaa180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33142318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orozco-Solis R, Aguilar-Arnal L. Circadian regulation of immunity through epigenetic mechanisms. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2020;13(10):96. doi: 10.3389/fcimb.2020.00096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcimb.2020.00096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7082642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32232012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labrecque N, Cermakian N. Circadian clocks in the immune system. J Biol Rhythms. 2015;30(4):277&#x2013;290. doi: 10.1177/0748730415577723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0748730415577723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25900041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannou L, B&#xe9;langer-Nelson E, O'Callaghan EK, Dufort-Gervais J, Ballester Roig MN, Roy PG, Beaulieu JM, Cermakian N, Mongrain V. Regulation of the neuroligin-1 gene by clock transcription factors. J Biol Rhythms. 2018;33(2):166&#x2013;178. doi: 10.1177/0748730418761236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0748730418761236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29671709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Ahlford A, J&#xe4;rvinen TM, Nordmark G, Eloranta ML, Gunnarsson I, Svenungsson E, Padyukov L, Sturfelt G, J&#xf6;nsen A, Bengtsson AA, Truedsson L, Eriksson C, Rantap&#xe4;&#xe4;-Dahlqvist S, Sj&#xf6;wall C, Julkunen H, Criswell LA, Graham RR, Behrens TW, Kere J, R&#xf6;nnblom L, Syv&#xe4;nen AC, Sandling JK. Genes identified in Asian SLE GWASs are also associated with SLE in caucasian populations. Eur J Hum Genet. 2013;21(9):994&#x2013;999. doi: 10.1038/ejhg.2012.277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ejhg.2012.277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3746253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23249952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He CF, Liu YS, Cheng YL, Gao JP, Pan TM, Han JW, Quan C, Sun LD, Zheng HF, Zuo XB, Xu SX, Sheng YJ, Yao S, Hu WL, Li Y, Yu ZY, Yin XY, Zhang XJ, Cui Y, Yang S. TNIP1, SLC15A4, ETS1, RasGRP3 and IKZF1 are associated with clinical features of systemic lupus erythematosus in a Chinese Han population. Lupus. 2010;19(10):1181&#x2013;1186. doi: 10.1177/0961203310367918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203310367918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20516000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi T, Nguyen-Tien D, Ohshima D, Karyu H, Shimabukuro-Demoto S, Yoshida-Sugitani R, Toyama-Sorimachi N. Human SLC15A4 is crucial for TLR-mediated type I interferon production and mitochondrial integrity. Int Immunol. 2021;33(7):399&#x2013;406. doi: 10.1093/intimm/dxab006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intimm/dxab006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33560415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherer PE, Kirwan JP, Rosen CJ. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19: a metabolic perspective. Elife. 2022;23(11):e78200. doi: 10.7554/eLife.78200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.78200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8942467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35318939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Risks and burdens of incident diabetes in long COVID: a cohort study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2022;10(5):311&#x2013;321. doi: 10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00044-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00044-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8937253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35325624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montefusco L, Ben Nasr M, D'Addio F, Loretelli C, Rossi A, Pastore I, Daniele G, Abdelsalam A, Maestroni A, Dell'Acqua M, Ippolito E, Assi E, Usuelli V, Seelam AJ, Fiorina RM, Chebat E, Morpurgo P, Lunati ME, Bolla AM, Finzi G, Abdi R, Bonventre JV, Rusconi S, Riva A, Corradi D, Santus P, Nebuloni M, Folli F, Zuccotti GV, Galli M, Fiorina P. Acute and long-term disruption of glycometabolic control after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Metab. 2021;3(6):774&#x2013;785. doi: 10.1038/s42255-021-00407-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42255-021-00407-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9931026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34035524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Chen Y, Wu C, Wei M, Xu J, Chao YC, Song J, Hou D, Zhang Y, Du C, Li X, Song Y. Coagulopathy is a major extrapulmonary risk factor for mortality in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 with type 2 diabetes. BMJ Open Diabetes Res Care. 2020;8(2):e001851. doi: 10.1136/bmjdrc-2020-001851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjdrc-2020-001851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7677866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33214191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj L, Kannapadi NV, Briggs J, Seal SM, Battaglini D, Fanning J, Suen J, Robba C, Fraser J, Cho SM. Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: a meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci. 2022;434:120162. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2022.120162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2022.120162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8798975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampasian V, Elghazaly H, Chattopadhyay R, et al. Risk factors associated with post&#x2212;COVID-19 condition:&#xa0;a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Intern Med. 2023 doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.0750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.0750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10037203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byambasuren O, Stehlik P, Clark J, Alcorn K, Glasziou P. Effect of covid-19 vaccination on long covid: systematic review. BMJ Med. 2023;2(1):e000385. doi: 10.1136/bmjmed-2022-000385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjmed-2022-000385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9978692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36936268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet. 2022;399(10343):2263&#x2013;2264. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(22)00941-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(22)00941-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35717982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>