<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36790825</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1654</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Reviews in medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rev Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Human brain organoids to explore SARS-CoV-2-induced effects on the central nervous system.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2430</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2430</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/rmv.2430</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus type 2 (SARS-CoV-2) is the causative agent of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). In less than three years, an estimated 600 million infections with SARS-CoV-2 occurred worldwide, resulting in a pandemic with tremendous impact especially on economic and health sectors. Initially considered a respiratory disease, COVID-19, along with its long-term sequelae (long-COVID) rather is a systemic disease. Neurological symptoms like dementia or encephalopathy were reported early during the pandemic as concomitants of the acute phase and as characteristics of long-COVID. An excessive inflammatory immune response is hypothesized to play a major role in this context. However, direct infection of neural cells may also contribute to the neurological aspects of (long)-COVID-19. To mainly explore such direct effects of SARS-CoV-2 on the central nervous system, human brain organoids provide a useful platform. Infecting these three-dimensional tissue cultures allows the study of viral neurotropism as well as of virus-induced effects on single cells or even the complex cellular network within the organoid. In this review, we summarize the&#xa0;experimental studies that used SARS-CoV-2-infected human brain organoids&#xa0;to&#xa0;unravel the complex nature of (long)-COVID-19-related neurological manifestations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Reviews in Medical Virology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ostermann</LastName><ForeName>Philipp Niklas</ForeName><Initials>PN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4419-6119</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Virology, University Hospital D&#xfc;sseldorf, Medical Faculty, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schaal</LastName><ForeName>Heiner</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1636-4365</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Virology, University Hospital D&#xfc;sseldorf, Medical Faculty, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Rev Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1052-9276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002490" MajorTopicYN="N">Central Nervous System</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009940" MajorTopicYN="N">Organoids</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood brain barrier</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood cerebrospinal fluid barrier</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">central nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">choroid plexus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">human brain organoids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroinvasion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurotropism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">organoids</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36790825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rmv.2430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Wu F, Zhao S, Yu B, et&#xa0;al. A new coronavirus associated with human respiratory disease in China. Nature. 2020;579(7798):265-269. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2008-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu N, Zhang D, Wang W, et&#xa0;al. A novel coronavirus from patients with pneumonia in China, 2019. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(8):727-733. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa2001017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui J, Li F, Shi ZL. Origin and evolution of pathogenic coronaviruses. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2019;17(3):181-192. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41579-018-0118-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong E, Du H, Gardner L. An interactive web-based dashboard to track COVID-19 in real time. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harcourt J, Tamin A, Lu X, et&#xa0;al. Severe acute respiratory syndrome Coronavirus 2 from patient with 2019 Novel Coronavirus disease, United States. Emerg Infect Dis. 2020;26(6):1266-1273. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid2606.200516</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park WB, Kwon NJ, Choi SJ, et&#xa0;al. Virus isolation from the first patient with SARS-CoV-2 in Korea. J Kor Med Sci. 2020;35(7):e84. https://doi.org/10.3346/jkms.2020.35.e84</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramani A, M&#xfc;ller L, Ostermann PN, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 targets neurons of 3D human brain organoids. EMBO J. 2020;39(20):e106230. https://doi.org/10.15252/embj.2020106230</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopfer H, Herzig MC, Gosert R, et&#xa0;al. Hunting Coronavirus by transmission electron microscopy - a guide to SARS-CoV-2-associated ultrastructural pathology in COVID-19 tissues. Histopathology. 2021;78(3):358-370. https://doi.org/10.1111/his.14264</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-On YM, Flamholz A, Phillips R, Milo R. SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19) by the numbers. Elife. 2020;9. https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.57309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masters PS. The molecular biology of coronaviruses. Adv Virus Res. 2006;66:193-292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M, Kleine-Weber H, Schroeder S, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and is blocked by a clinically proven protease inhibitor. Cell. 2020;181(2):271-280 e8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choppin PW, Scheid A. The role of viral glycoproteins in adsorption, penetration, and pathogenicity of viruses. Rev Infect Dis. 1980;2(1):40-61. https://doi.org/10.1093/clinids/2.1.40</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skehel JJ, Waterfield MD. Studies on the primary structure of the influenza virus hemagglutinin. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1975;72(1):93-97. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.72.1.93</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheid A, Choppin PW. Identification of biological activities of paramyxovirus glycoproteins. Activation of cell fusion, hemolysis, and infectivity of proteolytic cleavage of an inactive precursor protein of Sendai virus. Virology. 1974;57(2):475-490. https://doi.org/10.1016/0042-6822(74)90187-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheid A, Choppin PW. Protease activation mutants of sendai virus. Activation of biological properties by specific proteases. Virology. 1976;69(1):265-277. https://doi.org/10.1016/0042-6822(76)90213-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gething MJ, White JM, Waterfield MD. Purification of the fusion protein of Sendai virus: analysis of the NH2-terminal sequence generated during precursor activation. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1978;75(6):2737-2740. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.75.6.2737</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCune JM, Rabin LB, Feinberg MB, et&#xa0;al. Endoproteolytic cleavage of gp160 is required for the activation of human immunodeficiency virus. Cell. 1988;53(1):55-67. https://doi.org/10.1016/0092-8674(88)90487-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freed EO, Delwart EL, Buchschacher GL, Panganiban AT. A mutation in the human immunodeficiency virus type 1 transmembrane glycoprotein gp41 dominantly interferes with fusion and infectivity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1992;89:70-74. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.89.1.70</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallenberger S, Bosch V, Angliker H, Shaw E, Klenk HD, Garten W. Inhibition of furin-mediated cleavage activation of HIV-1 glycoprotein gp160. Nature. 1992;360(6402):358-361. https://doi.org/10.1038/360358a0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaal H, Klein M, Gehrmann P, Adams O, Scheid A. Requirement of N-terminal amino acid residues of gp41 for human immunodeficiency virus type 1-mediated cell fusion. J Virol. 1995;69(6):3308-3314. https://doi.org/10.1128/jvi.69.6.3308-3314.1995</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin I, Schaal H, Scheid A, Ruysschaert JM. Lipid membrane fusion induced by the human immunodeficiency virus type 1 gp41 N-terminal extremity is determined by its orientation in the lipid bilayer. J Virol. 1996;70:298-304. https://doi.org/10.1128/jvi.70.1.298-304.1996</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou X, Liu Y, Lei X, et&#xa0;al. Characterization of spike glycoprotein of SARS-CoV-2 on virus entry and its immune cross-reactivity with SARS-CoV. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):1620. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-15562-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch J, Uckeley ZM, Doldan P, Stanifer M, Boulant S, Lozach PY. TMPRSS2 expression dictates the entry route used by SARS-CoV-2 to infect host cells. EMBO J. 2021;40(16):e107821. https://doi.org/10.15252/embj.2021107821</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang J, Wan Y, Luo C, et&#xa0;al. Cell entry mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2020;117(21):11727-11734. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2003138117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson CB, Farzan M, Chen B, Choe H. Mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2 entry into cells. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2022;23(1):3-20. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41580-021-00418-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baltimore D. Expression of animal virus genomes. Bacteriol Rev. 1971;35(3):235-241. https://doi.org/10.1128/br.35.3.235-241.1971</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartenian E, Nandakumar D, Lari A, Ly M, Tucker JM, Glaunsinger BA. The molecular virology of Coronaviruses. J Biol Chem. 2020;295(37):12910-12934. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.rev120.013930</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flint SJ, Racaniello VR, Rall GF, Skalka AM, Enquist LW. Principles of Virology. 4th ed. ASM Press; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eymieux S, Uzbekov R, Rouill&#xe9; Y, et&#xa0;al. Secretory vesicles are the principal means of SARS-CoV-2 egress. Cells. 2021;10(8):2047. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells10082047</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendon&#xe7;a L, Howe A, Gilchrist JB, et&#xa0;al. Correlative multi-scale cryo-imaging unveils SARS-CoV-2 assembly and egress. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):4629. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-24887-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortese M, Lee JY, Cerikan B, et&#xa0;al. Integrative imaging reveals SARS-CoV-2-induced reshaping of subcellular morphologies. Cell Host Microbe. 2020;28(6):853-866. e5. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chom.2020.11.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu Y, Wang X, Zhu Y, et&#xa0;al. ORF3a-Mediated incomplete autophagy facilitates severe acute respiratory syndrome Coronavirus-2 replication. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2021;9:716208. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcell.2021.716208</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twu WI, Lee JY, Kim H, et&#xa0;al. Contribution of autophagy machinery factors to HCV and SARS-CoV-2 replication organelle formation. Cell Rep. 2021;37(8):110049. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2021.110049</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Sun H, Pei R, et&#xa0;al. The SARS-CoV-2 protein ORF3a inhibits fusion of autophagosomes with lysosomes. Cell Discov. 2021;7(1):31. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41421-021-00268-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson LA, Anderson EJ, Rouphael NG, et&#xa0;al. An mRNA vaccine against SARS-CoV-2 - preliminary report. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(20):1920-1931. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa2022483</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polack FP, Thomas SJ, Kitchin N, et&#xa0;al. Safety and efficacy of the BNT162b2 mRNA Covid-19 vaccine. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(27):2603-2615. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa2034577</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voysey M, Clemens SAC, Madhi SA, et&#xa0;al. Safety and efficacy of the ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccine (AZD1222) against SARS-CoV-2: an interim analysis of four randomised controlled trials in Brazil, South Africa, and the UK. Lancet. 2021;397:99-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amanat F, Krammer F. SARS-CoV-2 vaccines: status report. Immunity. 2020;52(4):583-589. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.immuni.2020.03.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Liu J, Plante KS, et&#xa0;al. The N501Y spike substitution enhances SARS-CoV-2 infection and transmission. Nature. 2021;602(7896):294-299. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-021-04245-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syed AM, Taha TY, Tabata T, et&#xa0;al. Rapid assessment of SARS-CoV-2-evolved variants using virus-like particles. Science. 2021;374(6575):1626-1632. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.abl6184</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulrich L, Halwe NJ, Taddeo A, et&#xa0;al. Enhanced fitness of SARS-CoV-2 variant of concern Alpha but not Beta. Nature. 2021;602(7896):307-313. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-021-04342-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller L, Andr&#xe9;e M, Ostermann PN, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 infection in fully vaccinated individuals of old age strongly boosts the humoral immune response. Front Med. 2021;8:746644. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2021.746644</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller L, Andr&#xe9;e M, Moskorz W, et&#xa0;al. Age-dependent immune response to the Biontech/Pfizer BNT162b2 COVID-19 vaccination. Clin Infect Dis. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolb T, Fischer S, M&#xfc;ller L, et&#xa0;al. Impaired immune response to SARS-CoV-2 vaccination in dialysis patients and in kidney transplant recipients. Kidney. 2021;2(9):1491-1498. https://doi.org/10.34067/kid.0003512021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, et&#xa0;al. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 Novel Coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020;395(10223):497-506. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(20)30183-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B, Guo H, Zhou P, Shi ZL. Characteristics of SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2021;19(3):141-154. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41579-020-00459-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungnak W, Huang N, B&#xe9;cavin C, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 entry factors are highly expressed in nasal epithelial cells together with innate immune genes. Nat Med. 2020;26(5):681-687. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-020-0868-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatton CF, Botting RA, Due&#xf1;as ME, et&#xa0;al. Delayed induction of type I and III interferons mediates nasal epithelial cell permissiveness to SARS-CoV-2. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):7092. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-27318-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liotta EM, Batra A, Clark JR, et&#xa0;al. Frequent neurologic manifestations and encephalopathy-associated morbidity in Covid-19 patients. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2020;7(11):2221-2230. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.51210</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seow JJW, Pai R, Mishra A, et&#xa0;al. Single-cell RNA-seq reveals angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 and transmembrane serine protease 2 expression in TROP2. Front Med. 2021;8:603374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey AL, Dmytrenko O, Greenberg L, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 infects human engineered heart tissues and models COVID-19 myocarditis. JACC Basic Transl Sci. 2021;6(4):331-345. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacbts.2021.01.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deinhardt-Emmer S, Wittschieber D, Sanft J, et&#xa0;al. Early postmortem mapping of SARS-CoV-2 RNA in patients with COVID-19 and the correlation with tissue damage. Elife. 2021;10. https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.60361</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Li Y, Liu Q, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 cell tropism and multiorgan infection. Cell Discov. 2021;7(1):17. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41421-021-00249-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaussen A, Hornby L, Rockl G, et&#xa0;al. Evidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection in cells, tissues, and organs and the risk of transmission through transplantation. Transplantation. 2021;105(7):1405-1422. https://doi.org/10.1097/tp.0000000000003744</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baggen J, Vanstreels E, Jansen S, Daelemans D. Cellular host factors for SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Microbiol. 2021;6(10):1219-1232. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41564-021-00958-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh M, Bansal V, Feschotte C. A single-cell RNA expression map of human coronavirus entry factors. Cell Rep. 2020;32(12):108175. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2020.108175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Y, Cao J, Zhang X, et&#xa0;al. Receptome profiling identifies KREMEN1 and ASGR1 as alternative functional receptors of SARS-CoV-2. Cell Res. 2022;32(1):24-37. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41422-021-00595-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamers MM, Beumer J, van der Vaart J, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 productively infects human gut enterocytes. Science. 2020;369(6499):50-54. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.abc1669</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteil V, Kwon H, Prado P, et&#xa0;al. Inhibition of SARS-CoV-2 infections in engineered human tissues using clinical-grade soluble human ACE2. Cell. 2020;181(4):905-913. e7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2020.04.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Han Y, Nilsson-Payant BE, et&#xa0;al. A human pluripotent stem cell-based platform to study SARS-CoV-2 tropism and model virus infection in human cells and organoids. Cell Stem Cell. 2020;27(1):125-136. e7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2020.06.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giobbe GG, Bonfante F, Jones BC, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 infection and replication in human gastric organoids. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):6610. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-26762-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mithal A, Hume AJ, Lindstrom-Vautrin J, et&#xa0;al. Human pluripotent stem cell-derived intestinal organoids model SARS-CoV-2 infection revealing a common epithelial inflammatory response. Stem Cell Rep. 2021;16(4):940-953. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stemcr.2021.02.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kr&#xfc;ger J, Gro&#xdf; R, Conzelmann C, et&#xa0;al. Drug inhibition of SARS-CoV-2 replication in human pluripotent stem cell-derived intestinal organoids. Cell Mol Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;11(4):935-948. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcmgh.2020.11.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao B, Ni C, Gao R, et&#xa0;al. Recapitulation of SARS-CoV-2 infection and cholangiocyte damage with human liver ductal organoids. Protein Cell. 2020;11(10):771-775. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13238-020-00718-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteil V, Dyczynski M, Lauschke VM, et&#xa0;al. Human soluble ACE2 improves the effect of remdesivir in SARS-CoV-2 infection. EMBO Mol Med. 2021;13(1):e13426. https://doi.org/10.15252/emmm.202013426</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei R, Feng J, Zhang Y, et&#xa0;al. Host metabolism dysregulation and cell tropism identification in human airway and alveolar organoids upon SARS-CoV-2 infection. Protein Cell. 2021;12(9):717-733. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13238-020-00811-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari SK, Wang S, Smith D, Carlin AF, Rana TM. Revealing tissue-specific SARS-CoV-2 infection and host responses using human stem cell-derived lung and cerebral organoids. Stem Cell Rep. 2021;16(3):437-445. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stemcr.2021.02.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ianevski A, Yao R, Zusinaite E, et&#xa0;al. Synergistic interferon-alpha-based combinations for treatment of SARS-CoV-2 and other viral infections. Viruses. 2021;13(12):2489. https://doi.org/10.3390/v13122489</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan X, Tang X, Nair MS, et&#xa0;al. An airway organoid-based screen identifies a role for the HIF1&#x3b1;-glycolysis axis in SARS-CoV-2 infection. Cell Rep. 2021;37(6):109920. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2021.109920</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Zhang N, Fan S, et&#xa0;al. Establishment of human distal lung organoids for SARS-CoV-2 infection. Cell Discov. 2021;7(1):108. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41421-021-00346-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Liu J, Gao D, et&#xa0;al. Establishment of human pluripotent stem cell-derived skin organoids enabled pathophysiological model of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Adv Sci. 2021;9(7):e2104192. https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202104192</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y, Zhang M, Chen Y, Zhu D. Application of human induced pluripotent stem cell-derived cellular and organoid models for COVID-19 research. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2021;9:720099. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcell.2021.720099</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezankhani R, Solhi R, Chai YC, Vosough M, Verfaillie C. Organoid and microfluidics-based platforms for drug screening in COVID-19. Drug Discov Today. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larijani B, Foroughi-Heravani N, Abedi M, et&#xa0;al. Recent advances of&#xa0;COVID-19 modeling based on regenerative medicine. Front Cell&#xa0;Dev Biol. 2021;9:683619. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcell.2021.683619</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM. Neurological manifestations in COVID-19 caused by SARS-CoV-2. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2020;26(5):499-501. https://doi.org/10.1111/cns.13372</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M, et&#xa0;al. Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with Coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(6):683-690. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.1127</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J, Kremer S, Merdji H, et&#xa0;al. Neurologic features in severe SARS-CoV-2 infection. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(23):2268-2270. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmc2008597</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Husain M, Harrison PJ. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 2021;18(9):e1003773. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1003773</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Ling S, Lui LMW, et&#xa0;al. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in post-COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker AM, Brigham E, Connolly B, et&#xa0;al. Addressing the post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a multidisciplinary model of care. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9(11):1328-1341. https://doi.org/10.1016/s2213-2600(21)00385-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatr. 2021;8(5):416-427. https://doi.org/10.1016/s2215-0366(21)00084-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camargo-Mart&#xed;nez W, Lozada-Mart&#xed;nez I, Escobar-Collazos A, et&#xa0;al. Post-COVID 19 neurological syndrome: implications for sequelae's treatment. J Clin Neurosci. 2021;88:219-225. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jocn.2021.04.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad SJ, Feigen CM, Vazquez JP, Kobets AJ, Altschul DJ. Neurological sequelae of COVID-19. J Integr Neurosci. 2022;21(3):77. https://doi.org/10.31083/j.jin2103077</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harapan BN, Yoo HJ. Neurological symptoms, manifestations, and complications associated with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) and Coronavirus disease 19 (COVID-19). J Neurol. 2021;268:3059-3071. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-021-10406-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramani A, Pranty AI, Gopalakrishnan J. Neurotropic effects of SARS-CoV-2 modeled by the human brain organoids. Stem Cell Rep. 2021;16(3):373-384. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stemcr.2021.02.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keyhanian K, Umeton RP, Mohit B, Davoudi V, Hajighasemi F, Ghasemi M. SARS-CoV-2 and nervous system: from pathogenesis to clinical manifestation. J Neuroimmunol. 2020;350:577436. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2020.577436</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favas TT, Dev P, Chaurasia RN, et&#xa0;al. Neurological manifestations of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of proportions. Neurol Sci. 2020;41(12):3437-3470. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10072-020-04801-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian S, Hu N, Lou J, et&#xa0;al. Characteristics of COVID-19 infection in beijing. J Infect. 2020;80(4):401-406. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2020.02.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim ES, Chin BS, Kang CK, et&#xa0;al. Clinical course and outcomes of patients with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection: a preliminary report of the first 28 patients from the Korean cohort study on COVID-19. J Kor Med Sci. 2020;35(13):e142. https://doi.org/10.3346/jkms.2020.35.e142</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belvis R. Headaches during COVID-19: my clinical case and review of the literature. Headache. 2020;60(7):1422-1426. https://doi.org/10.1111/head.13841</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinzon RT, Wijaya VO, Buana RB, Al Jody A, Nunsio PN. Neurologic characteristics in Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Neurol. 2020;11:565. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2020.00565</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigin VL, Forouzanfar MH, Krishnamurthi R, et&#xa0;al. Global and regional burden of stroke during 1990-2010: findings from the global burden of disease study 2010. Lancet. 2014;383(9913):245-254. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(13)61953-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langhorne P, Coupar F, Pollock A. Motor recovery after stroke: a systematic review. Lancet Neurol. 2009;8:741-754. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1474-4422(09)70150-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siow I, Lee KS, Zhang JJY, Saffari SE, Ng A. Encephalitis as a neurological complication of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of incidence, outcomes, and predictors. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28(10):3491-3502. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.14913</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baseler HA, Aksoy M, Salawu A, Green A, Asghar AUR. The negative impact of COVID-19 on working memory revealed using a rapid online quiz. PLoS One. 2022;17(11):e0269353. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0269353</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham EL, Clark JR, Orban ZS, et&#xa0;al. Persistent neurologic symptoms and cognitive dysfunction in non-hospitalized Covid-19 long haulers. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2021;8(5):1073-1085. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.51350</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Divani AA, Andalib S, Biller J, et&#xa0;al. Central nervous system manifestations associated with COVID-19. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2020;20(12):60. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11910-020-01079-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta D, Liu J, Xiong H. NLRP3 inflammasome activation and SARS-CoV-2-mediated hyperinflammation, cytokine storm and neurological syndromes. Int J Physiol Pathophysiol Pharmacol. 2022;14:138-160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esp&#xed;ndola OM, Gomes YCP, Brand&#xe3;o CO, et&#xa0;al. Inflammatory cytokine patterns associated with neurological diseases in Coronavirus disease 2019. Ann Neurol. 2021;89(5):1041-1045. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.26041</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunai C, Collie C, Michael BD. Immune-mediated mechanisms of COVID-19 neuropathology. Front Neurol. 2022;13:882905. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2022.882905</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paniz-Mondolfi A, Bryce C, Grimes Z, et&#xa0;al. Central nervous system involvement by severe acute respiratory syndrome Coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2). J Med Virol. 2020;92(7):699-702. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.25915</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puelles VG, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Lindenmeyer MT, et&#xa0;al. Multiorgan and renal tropism of SARS-CoV-2. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(6):590-592. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmc2011400</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke J, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Hagel C, et&#xa0;al. Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19(11):919-929. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1474-4422(20)30308-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Xu X, Chen Z, et&#xa0;al. Nervous system involvement after infection with COVID-19 and other Coronaviruses. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:18-22. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2020.03.031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YC, Bai WZ, Hashikawa T. The neuroinvasive potential of SARS-CoV2 may play a role in the respiratory failure of COVID-19 patients. J Med Virol. 2020;92(6):552-555. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.25728</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukiw WJ, Pogue A, Hill JM. SARS-CoV-2 infectivity and neurological targets in the brain. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2020;42(1):217-224. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10571-020-00947-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R, Wang K, Yu J, et&#xa0;al. The spatial and cell-type distribution of SARS-CoV-2 receptor ACE2 in the human and mouse brains. Front Neurol. 2020;11:573095. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2020.573095</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uhl&#xe9;n M, Fagerberg L, Hallstr&#xf6;m BM, et&#xa0;al. Proteomics. Tissue-based map of the human proteome. Science. 2015;347:1260419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf6;stedt E, Zhong W, Fagerberg L, et&#xa0;al. An atlas of the protein-coding genes in the human, pig, and mouse brain. Science. 2020;367(6482). https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aay5947</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly JL, Simonetti B, Klein K, et&#xa0;al. Neuropilin-1 is a host factor for SARS-CoV-2 infection. Science. 2020;370(6518):861-865. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.abd3072</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantuti-Castelvetri L, Ojha R, Pedro LD, et&#xa0;al. Neuropilin-1 facilitates SARS-CoV-2 cell entry and infectivity. Science. 2020;370(6518):856-860. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.abd2985</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antipenko A, Himanen JP, van Leyen K, et&#xa0;al. Structure of the semaphorin-3A receptor binding module. Neuron. 2003;39(4):589-598. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0896-6273(03)00502-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krasemann S, Haferkamp U, Pfefferle S, et&#xa0;al. The blood-brain barrier is dysregulated in COVID-19 and serves as a CNS entry route for SARS-CoV-2. Stem Cell Rep. 2022;17(2):307-320. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stemcr.2021.12.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swain O, Romano SK, Miryala R, Tsai J, Parikh V, Umanah GKE. SARS-CoV-2 neuronal invasion and complications: potential mechanisms and therapeutic approaches. J Neurosci. 2021;41(25):5338-5349. https://doi.org/10.1523/jneurosci.3188-20.2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pepe A, Pietropaoli S, Vos M, Barba-Spaeth G, Zurzolo C. Tunneling nanotubes provide a route for SARS-CoV-2 spreading. Sci Adv. 2022;8(29):eabo0171. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.abo0171</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>John CC, Carabin H, Montano SM, Bangirana P, Zunt JR, Peterson PK. Global research priorities for infections that affect the nervous system. Nature. 2015;527(7578):S178-S186. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature16033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward AC. Neurovirulence of influenza A virus. J Neurovirol. 1996;2(3):139-151. https://doi.org/10.3109/13550289609146876</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AC, Fu ZF. Chapter 8 - pathogenesis. In: Jackson AC, ed. Rabies. 3rd ed. Academic Press; 2013:299-349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weissenb&#xf6;ck H, Bakonyi T, Chvala S, Nowotny N. Experimental Usutu virus infection of suckling mice causes neuronal and glial cell apoptosis and demyelination. Acta Neuropathol. 2004;108(5):453-460. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-004-0916-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller KD, Matullo CM, Milora KA, Williams RM, O'Regan KJ, Rall GF. Immune-mediated control of a dormant neurotropic RNA virus infection. J Virol. 2019;93(18). https://doi.org/10.1128/jvi.00241-19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicoll MP, Proen&#xe7;a JT, Efstathiou S. The molecular basis of herpes simplex virus latency. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2012;36(3):684-705. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1574-6976.2011.00320.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura T, Sasaki M, Okumura M, Kim E, Sawa H. Flavivirus encephalitis: pathological aspects of mouse and other animal models. Vet Pathol. 2010;47(5):806-818. https://doi.org/10.1177/0300985810372507</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari P, Rothan HA, Natekar JP, et&#xa0;al. Neuroinvasion and encephalitis following intranasal inoculation of SARS-CoV-2 in K18-hACE2 mice. Viruses. 2021;13(1):132. https://doi.org/10.3390/v13010132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckman D, Bonillas A, Diniz GB, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 infects neurons and induces neuroinflammation in a non-human primate model of COVID-19. Cell Rep. 2022;41(5):111573. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2022.111573</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stodola JK, Dubois G, Le Coupanec A, Desforges M, Talbot PJ. The OC43 human Coronavirus envelope protein is critical for infectious virus production and propagation in neuronal cells and is a determinant of neurovirulence and CNS pathology. Virology. 2018;515:134-149. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.virol.2017.12.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-San Mart&#xed;n C, Li T, Bouquet J, et&#xa0;al. Differentiation enhances Zika virus infection of neuronal brain cells. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):14543. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-32400-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura T, Okumura M, Kim E, Sasaki M, Orba Y, Sawa H. Characterization of Japanese encephalitis virus infection in an immortalized mesencephalic cell line, CSM14.1. Microbiol Immunol. 2013;57(10):723-731. https://doi.org/10.1111/1348-0421.12085</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CY, Li JR, Ou YC, et&#xa0;al. Enterovirus 71 infection caused neuronal cell death and cytokine expression in cultured rat neural cells. IUBMB Life. 2015;67(10):789-800. https://doi.org/10.1002/iub.1434</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundaramoorthy V, Godde N, Farr RJ, et&#xa0;al. Modelling lyssavirus infections in human stem cell-derived neural cultures. Viruses. 2020;12(4):359. https://doi.org/10.3390/v12040359</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawes BE, Gao J, Atkins C, et&#xa0;al. Human neural stem cell-derived neuron/astrocyte co-cultures respond to La Crosse virus infection with proinflammatory cytokines and chemokines. J Neuroinflammation. 2018;15(1):315. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12974-018-1356-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadaoka T, Schwartz CL, Rajbhandari L, Venkatesan A, Cohen JI. Human embryonic stem cell-derived neurons are highly permissive for varicella-zoster virus lytic infection. J Virol. 2018;92(1). https://doi.org/10.1128/jvi.01108-17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gugliandolo A, Chiricosta L, Calcaterra V, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 infected pediatric cerebral cortical neurons: transcriptomic analysis and potential role of toll-like receptors in pathogenesis. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(15):8059. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms22158059</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herdy J, Schafer S, Kim Y, et&#xa0;al. Chemical modulation of transcriptionally enriched signaling pathways to optimize the conversion of fibroblasts into neurons. Elife. 2019;8. https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.41356</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mertens J, Paquola ACM, Ku M, et&#xa0;al. Directly reprogrammed human neurons retain aging-associated transcriptomic signatures and reveal age-related nucleocytoplasmic defects. Cell Stem Cell. 2015;17(6):705-718. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2015.09.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mertens J, Herdy JR, Traxler L, et&#xa0;al. Age-dependent instability of mature neuronal fate in induced neurons from Alzheimer's patients. Cell Stem Cell. 2021;28(9):1533-1548.e6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2021.04.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenfeld AB, Warren AL, Racaniello VR. Neurotropism of enterovirus D68 isolates is independent of sialic acid and is not a recently acquired phenotype. mBio. 2019;10(5). https://doi.org/10.1128/mbio.02370-19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eiraku M, Watanabe K, Matsuo-Takasaki M, et&#xa0;al. Self-organized formation of polarized cortical tissues from ESCs and its active manipulation by extrinsic signals. Cell Stem Cell. 2008;3(5):519-532. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2008.09.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelava I, Lancaster MA. Dishing out mini-brains: current progress and future prospects in brain organoid research. Dev Biol. 2016;420(2):199-209. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ydbio.2016.06.037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadoshima T, Sakaguchi H, Nakano T, et&#xa0;al. Self-organization of axial polarity, inside-out layer pattern, and species-specific progenitor dynamics in human ES cell-derived neocortex. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2013;110(50):20284-20289. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1315710110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz EM, Jones TJ, Xu S, Dean DD, Zechmann B, Barr KL. Cerebral organoids derived from a Parkinson's patient exhibit unique pathogenesis from Chikungunya virus infection when compared to a non-Parkinson's patient. Pathogens. 2021;10(7):913. https://doi.org/10.3390/pathogens10070913</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrini L, Albecka A, Mallery DL, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 infects the brain choroid plexus and disrupts the blood-CSF barrier in human brain organoids. Cell Stem Cell. 2020;27(6):951-961. e5. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2020.10.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob F, Pather SR, Huang WK, et&#xa0;al. Human pluripotent stem cell-derived neural cells and brain organoids reveal SARS-CoV-2 neurotropism predominates in choroid plexus epithelium. Cell Stem Cell. 2020;27(6):937-950. e9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2020.09.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel E, Albanna W, Pasquini G, et&#xa0;al. Human brain organoids assemble functionally integrated bilateral optic vesicles. Cell Stem Cell. 2021;28(10):1740-1757. e8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2021.07.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancaster MA, Knoblich JA. Generation of cerebral organoids from human pluripotent stem cells. Nat Protoc. 2014;9(10):2329-2340. https://doi.org/10.1038/nprot.2014.158</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancaster MA, Renner M, Martin CA, et&#xa0;al. Cerebral organoids model human brain development and microcephaly. Nature. 2013;501(7467):373-379. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature12517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancaster MA, Knoblich JA. Organogenesis in a dish: modeling development and disease using organoid technologies. Science. 2014;345(6194):1247125. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1247125</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel E, Ramani A, Karow U, et&#xa0;al. Recent Zika virus isolates induce premature differentiation of neural progenitors in human brain organoids. Cell Stem Cell. 2017;20(3):397-406. e5. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2016.12.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian X, Nguyen HN, Song MM, et&#xa0;al. Brain-region-specific organoids using mini-bioreactors for modeling ZIKV exposure. Cell. 2016;165(5):1238-1254. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2016.04.032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cugola FR, Fernandes IR, Russo FB, et&#xa0;al. The Brazilian Zika virus strain causes birth defects in experimental models. Nature. 2016;534(7606):267-271. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature18296</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Aiuto L, Bloom DC, Naciri JN, et&#xa0;al. Modeling herpes simplex virus 1 infections in human central nervous system neuronal cells using two- and three-dimensional cultures derived from induced pluripotent stem cells. J Virol. 2019;93(9). https://doi.org/10.1128/jvi.00111-19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, He Y, Xu Y, et&#xa0;al. Differential antiviral immunity to Japanese encephalitis virus in developing cortical organoids. Cell Death Dis. 2018;9(7):719. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41419-018-0763-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreras P, Pamies D, Monaco MC, et&#xa0;al. A human-derived 3D brain organoid model to study JC virus infection. J Neurovirol. 2022;28(1):17-26. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13365-022-01062-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sridhar A, Depla JA, Mulder LA, et&#xa0;al. Enterovirus D68 infection in human primary airway and brain organoids: No additional role for heparan sulfate binding for neurotropism. Microbiol Spectr. 2022;10(5):e0169422. https://doi.org/10.1128/spectrum.01694-22</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Depla JA, Mulder LA, de S&#xe1; RV, et&#xa0;al. Human brain organoids as models for central nervous system viral infection. Viruses. 2022;14(3):634. https://doi.org/10.3390/v14030634</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostermann PN, Ramani A, Bergmann AK, Adams O, Gopalakrishnan J, Schaal H. Infection of 3D brain organoids with human pathogenic viruses under biosafety level-3 conditions with subsequent inactivation to study viral replication, pathomechanisms, and other viral infection-mediated effects. In: Gopalakrishnan J, ed. Brain Organoid Research. Springer US; 2023:191-220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krenn V, Higa LM, Garcez PP. Brain organoids as a model to study Zika virus and SARS-CoV-2 infections. In: Gopalakrishnan J, ed. Brain Organoid Research. Springer US; 2023:173-190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E, Zhang C, Israelow B, et&#xa0;al. Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 in human and mouse brain. J Exp Med. 2021;218(3). https://doi.org/10.1084/jem.20202135</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesci P, de Souza JS, Martin-Sancho L, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 infects human brain organoids causing cell death and loss of synapses that can be rescued by treatment with Sofosbuvir. PLoS Biol. 2022;20(11):e3001845. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.3001845</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Sievert D, Clark AE, et&#xa0;al. A human three-dimensional neural-perivascular &#x2018;assembloid&#x2019; promotes astrocytic development and enables modeling of SARS-CoV-2 neuropathology. Nat Med. 2021;27(9):1600-1606. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-021-01443-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng JH, Sun A, Je HS, Tan EK. Unravelling pathophysiology of neurological and psychiatric complications of COVID-19 using brain organoids. Neuroscientist. 2021;29(1):10738584211015136. https://doi.org/10.1177/10738584211015136</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi SA, Nam KH, Yun J, et&#xa0;al. Infection of brain organoids and 2D cortical neurons with SARS-CoV-2 pseudovirus. Viruses. 2020;12(9):1004. https://doi.org/10.3390/v12091004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon CL, Staples H, Gazi M, Carrion R, Hsieh J. SARS-CoV-2 targets glial cells in human cortical organoids. Stem Cell Rep.&#xa0;2021;16(5):1156-1164. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stemcr.2021.01.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang BZ, Chu H, Han S, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 infects human neural progenitor cells and brain organoids. Cell Res. 2020;30(10):928-931. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41422-020-0390-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong W, Montano M, Corley MJ, et&#xa0;al. Neuropilin-1 mediates SARS-CoV-2 infection of astrocytes in brain organoids, inducing inflammation leading to dysfunction and death of neurons. mBio. 2022;13(6):e0230822. https://doi.org/10.1128/mbio.02308-22</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Cerde&#xf1;o V, Noctor SC. Neural progenitor cell terminology. Front Neuroanat. 2018;12:104. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnana.2018.00104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Zhang M, Garcia G, Jr., et&#xa0;al. ApoE-isoform-dependent SARS-CoV-2 neurotropism and cellular response. Cell Stem Cell. 2021;28(2):331e5-342. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2020.12.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchrieser J, Dufloo J, Hubert M, et&#xa0;al. Syncytia formation by SARS-CoV-2-infected cells. EMBO J. 2020;39(23):e106267. https://doi.org/10.15252/embj.2020106267</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braga L, Ali H, Secco I, et&#xa0;al. Drugs that inhibit TMEM16 proteins block SARS-CoV-2 spike-induced syncytia. Nature. 2021;594(7861):88-93. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-021-03491-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajah MM, Bernier A, Buchrieser J, Schwartz O. The mechanism and consequences of SARS-CoV-2 spike-mediated fusion and syncytia formation. J Mol Biol. 2022;434(6):167280. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmb.2021.167280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azarfar A, Calcini N, Huang C, Zeldenrust F, Celikel T. Neural coding: a single neuron's perspective. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2018;94:238-247. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2018.09.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;imi&#x107; G, Tkal&#x10d;i&#x107; M, Vuki&#x107; V, et&#xa0;al. Understanding emotions: origins and roles of the Amygdala. Biomolecules. 2021;11(6):823. https://doi.org/10.3390/biom11060823</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opitz B. Memory function and the hippocampus. Front Neurol Neurosci. 2014;34:51-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magee JC, Grienberger C. Synaptic plasticity forms and functions. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2020;43(1):95-117. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-neuro-090919-022842</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonanomi D. Axon pathfinding for locomotion. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2019;85:26-35. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.semcdb.2017.11.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraira VE, Ginty DD. The sensory neurons of touch. Neuron. 2013;79(4):618-639. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2013.07.051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarov O, Hollands C. Hippocampal neurogenesis: learning to remember. Prog Neurobiol. 2016;138(140):1-18. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pneurobio.2015.12.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones G, Power C. Regulation of neural cell survival by HIV-1 infection. Neurobiol Dis. 2006;21:1-17. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2005.07.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marino J, Maubert ME, Mele AR, Spector C, Wigdahl B, Nonnemacher MR. Functional impact of HIV-1 Tat on cells of the CNS and its role in hand. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2020;77(24):5079-5099. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00018-020-03561-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaul M, Lipton SA. Mechanisms of neuronal injury and death in HIV-1 associated dementia. Curr HIV Res. 2006;4(3):307-318. https://doi.org/10.2174/157016206777709384</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreone BJ, Larhammar M, Lewcock JW. Cell death and neurodegeneration. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2020;12(2):a036434. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a036434</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holper S, Watson R, Yassi N. Tau as a biomarker of neurodegeneration. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(13):7307. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms23137307</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini S, Michaelsen-Preusse K, Schughart K, Korte M. Long-term consequence of non-neurotropic H3N2 influenza A virus infection for the progression of Alzheimer's disease symptoms. Front Cell Neurosci. 2021;15:643650. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2021.643650</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piekut T, Hur&#x142;a M, Banaszek N, et&#xa0;al. Infectious agents and Alzheimer's disease. J Integr Neurosci. 2022;21(2):73. https://doi.org/10.31083/j.jin2102073</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornevik K, Cortese M, Healy BC, et&#xa0;al. Longitudinal analysis reveals high prevalence of Epstein-Barr virus associated with multiple sclerosis. Science. 2022;375(6578):296-301. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.abj8222</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin SJ, Grimwood PD, Morris RG. Synaptic plasticity and memory: an evaluation of the hypothesis. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2000;23(1):649-711. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.neuro.23.1.649</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neves G, Cooke SF, Bliss TV. Synaptic plasticity, memory and the hippocampus: a neural network approach to causality. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2008;9(1):65-75. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn2303</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safdari Lord J, Soltani Rezaiezadeh J, Yekaninejad MS, Izadi P. The association of APOE genotype with COVID-19 disease severity. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):13483. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-17262-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo CL, Pilling LC, Atkins JL, et&#xa0;al. APOE e4 Genotype Predicts Severe COVID-19 in the UK Biobank Community Cohort. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2020;75(11):2231-2232. https://doi.org/10.1093/gerona/glaa131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard JW, Akay LA, Davila-Velderrain J, et&#xa0;al. APOE4 impairs myelination via cholesterol dysregulation in oligodendrocytes. Nature. 2022;611(7937):769-779. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-022-05439-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corder EH, Saunders AM, Strittmatter WJ, et&#xa0;al. Gene dose of apolipoprotein E type 4 allele and the risk of Alzheimer's disease in late onset families. Science. 1993;261(5123):921-923. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.8346443</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert JC, Ibrahim-Verbaas CA, Harold D, et&#xa0;al. Meta-analysis of 74,046 individuals identifies 11 new susceptibility loci for Alzheimer's disease. Nat Genet. 2013;45(12):1452-1458. https://doi.org/10.1038/ng.2802</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurki SN, Kantonen J, Kaivola K, et&#xa0;al. APOE &#x3b5;4 associates with increased risk of severe COVID-19, cerebral microhaemorrhages and post-COVID mental fatigue: a Finnish biobank, autopsy and clinical study. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2021;9(1):199. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40478-021-01302-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen NJ, Lyons DA. Glia as architects of central nervous system formation and function. Science. 2018;362(6411):181-185. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aat0473</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Bartheld CS, Bahney J, Herculano-Houzel S. The search for true numbers of neurons and glial cells in the human brain: a review of 150 years of cell counting. J Comp Neurol. 2016;524(18):3865-3895. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24040</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen NJ, Eroglu C. Cell biology of astrocyte-synapse interactions. Neuron. 2017;96(3):697-708. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2017.09.056</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nortley R, Attwell D. Control of brain energy supply by astrocytes. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2017;47:80-85. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conb.2017.09.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandebura AN, Paumier A, Onur TS, Allen NJ. Astrocyte contribution to dysfunction, risk and progression in neurodegenerative disorders. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2022;24(1):23-39. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41583-022-00641-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeney MD, Ayyadurai S, Zlokovic BV. Pericytes of the neurovascular unit: key functions and signaling pathways. Nat Neurosci. 2016;19(6):771-783. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4288</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall CN, Reynell C, Gesslein B, et&#xa0;al. Capillary pericytes regulate cerebral blood flow in health and disease. Nature. 2014;508(7494):55-60. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature13165</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenzel J, Lampe J, M&#xfc;ller-Fielitz H, et&#xa0;al. The SARS-CoV-2 main protease M. Nat Neurosci. 2021;24(11):1522-1533. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-021-00926-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Alejandro B, Hetman M, et&#xa0;al. Zika virus infects pericytes in the choroid plexus and enters the central nervous system through the blood-cerebrospinal fluid barrier. PLoS Pathog. 2020;16(5):e1008204. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.ppat.1008204</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwerk C, Tenenbaum T, Kim KS, Schroten H. The choroid plexus-a multi-role player during infectious diseases of the CNS. Front Cell Neurosci. 2015;9:80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Xu Y, Gao R, et&#xa0;al. Detection of SARS-CoV-2 in different types of clinical specimens. JAMA. 2020;323:1843-1844. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.3786</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrini L, Bonfio C, Chadwick J, Begum F, Skehel M, Lancaster MA. Human CNS barrier-forming organoids with cerebrospinal fluid production. Science. 2020;369(6500). https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aaz5626</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cakir B, Xiang Y, Tanaka Y, et&#xa0;al. Engineering of human brain organoids with a functional vascular-like system. Nat Methods. 2019;16(11):1169-1175. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41592-019-0586-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham MT, Pollock KM, Rose MD, et&#xa0;al. Generation of human vascularized brain organoids. Neuroreport. 2018;29(7):588-593. https://doi.org/10.1097/wnr.0000000000001014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmann S, Lawler SE, Qu Y, et&#xa0;al. Blood-brain-barrier organoids for investigating the permeability of CNS therapeutics. Nat Protoc. 2018;13(12):2827-2843. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41596-018-0066-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun XY, Ju XC, Li Y, et&#xa0;al. Generation of vascularized brain organoids to study neurovascular interactions. Elife. 2022;11. https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.76707</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giandomenico SL, Sutcliffe M, Lancaster MA. Generation and long-term culture of advanced cerebral organoids for studying later stages of neural development. Nat Protoc. 2021;16(2):579-602. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41596-020-00433-w</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>