<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37185834</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of nirmatrelvir and ritonavir for post-acute COVID-19 sequelae beyond 3 months of SARS-CoV-2 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e28750</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e28750</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.28750</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The effect of nirmatrelvir plus ritonavir (NMV-r) on post-acute COVID-19 sequelae beyond 3 months of SARS-CoV-2 infection remains unknown. This retrospective cohort study utilized data from the TriNetX Research Network. We identified nonhospitalized adult patients with COVID-19 receiving a diagnosis between January 1 and July 31, 2022. Propensity score matching (PSM) was used to create two matched cohorts: NMV-r and non-NMV-r groups, respectively. We measured the primary outcomes using a composite of all-cause emergency room (ER) visits or hospitalization and a composite of post-COVID-19 symptoms according to the WHO Delphi consensus, which also stated that post COVID-19 condition occurs usually 3 months from the onset of COVID-19, during the follow-up period between 90 days after the index diagnosis of COVID-19 and the end of follow-up (180 days). Initially, we identified 12&#x2009;247 patients that received NMV-r within 5 days of diagnosis and 465&#x2009;135 that did not. After PSM, 12&#x2009;245 patients remained in each group. During the follow-up period, patients treated with NMV-r had a lower risk of all-cause hospitalization and ER visits compared with untreated patients (659 vs. 955; odds ratio [OR], 0.672; 95% confidence interval [CI], 0.607-0.745; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.0001). However, the overall risk of post-acute COVID-19 symptoms did not significantly differ between the two groups (2265 vs. 2187; OR, 1.043; 95% CI, 0.978-1.114; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.2021). The reduced risk of all-cause ER visits or hospitalization in the NMV-r group and the similarities in the risk of post-acute COVID-19 symptoms between the two groups were consistent in the subgroups stratified by sex, age, and vaccination status. Early NMV-r treatment of nonhospitalized patients with COVID-19 was associated with reduced risk of hospitalization and ER visits during the period of 90-180 days after diagnosis compared with no NMV-r treatment; however, post-acute COVID-19 symptoms and mortality risk did not differ significantly between the groups.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chuang</LastName><ForeName>Min-Hsiang</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Chi Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Jheng-Yan</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3290-1909</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Chi Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Ting-Hui</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Chi Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsu</LastName><ForeName>Wan-Hsuan</ForeName><Initials>WH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Chi Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsai</LastName><ForeName>Ya-Wen</ForeName><Initials>YW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4630-3923</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Integrative Medicine, Chi Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Sciences and Biotechnology, Fooyin University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Po-Yu</ForeName><Initials>PY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8682-1322</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Chi Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Chih-Cheng</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6334-2388</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine,&#xa0;Division of Hospital Medicine, Chi Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, College of Medicine, National Sun Yat-sen University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>O3J8G9O825</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019438">Ritonavir</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019438" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ritonavir</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000093485" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Drug Treatment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nirmatrelvir and ritonavir</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute sequelae</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37185834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>WHO. Accessed February 11,&#xa0;2023. https://covid19.who.int/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CC, Hsu CK, Yen MY, Lee PI, Ko WC, Hsueh PR. Long COVID: an inevitable sequela of SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Microbiol Immunol Infect=Wei mian yu gan ran za zhi. 2023;56(1):1-9. doi:10.1016/j.jmii.2022.10.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat&#xa0;Med. 2021;27(4):601-615. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:1-14. doi:10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballering AV, van Zon SKR, Olde Hartman TC, Rosmalen JGM. Persistence of somatic symptoms after COVID-19 in the Netherlands: an observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022;400(10350):452-461. doi:10.1016/s0140-6736(22)01214-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demko ZO, Yu T, Mullapudi SK, et al. Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (PASC) impact quality of life at 6, 12 and 18 months post-infection.&#xa0;medRxiv.&#xa0;Preprint. 2022. doi:10.1101/2022.08.08.22278543</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammond J, Leister-Tebbe H, Gardner A, et al. Oral nirmatrelvir for high-risk, nonhospitalized adults with Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2022;386(15):1397-1408. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2118542</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dryden-Peterson S, Kim A, Kim AY, et al. Nirmatrelvir plus ritonavir for early COVID-19 in a large U.S. health system: a population-based cohort study. Ann Intern Med. 2023;176(1):77-84. doi:10.7326/m22-2141</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganatra S, Dani SS, Ahmad J, et al. Oral nirmatrelvir and ritonavir in nonhospitalized vaccinated patients with coronavirus disease 2019. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;76:563-572. doi:10.1093/cid/ciac673</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Gao M, You H, et al. Association of nirmatrelvir/ritonavir treatment on upper respiratory severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (SARS-Cov-2 RT-PCR) negative conversion rates among high-risk patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76(3):148. doi:10.1093/cid/ciac600</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wai AKC, Chan CY, Cheung AWL, et al. Association of molnupiravir and nirmatrelvir-ritonavir with preventable mortality, hospital admissions and related avoidable healthcare system cost among high-risk patients with mild to moderate COVID-19. Lancet Reg&#xa0;Health&#xa0;West Pac. 2023;30:100602. doi:10.1016/j.lanwpc.2022.100602</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong CKH, Au ICH, Lau KTK, Lau EHY, Cowling BJ, Leung GM. Real-world effectiveness of early molnupiravir or nirmatrelvir-ritonavir in hospitalised patients with COVID-19 without supplemental oxygen requirement on admission during Hong Kong's omicron BA.2 wave: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(12):1681-1693. doi:10.1016/s1473-3099(22)00507-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Choi T, Al-Aly Z. Association of treatment with nirmatrelvir and the risk of post-COVID-19 condition. JAMA Intern Med. 2023:e230743. doi:10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.0743</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajema KL, Berry K, Streja E, et al. Effectiveness of COVID-19 treatment with nirmatrelvir-ritonavir or molnupiravir among U.S. veterans: target trial emulation studies with one-month and six-month outcomes. medRxiv. Preprint.&#xa0;2022. doi:10.1101/2022.12.05.22283134</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu TH, Wu JY, Huang PY, Tsai YW, Lai CC. The effect of nirmatrelvir plus ritonavir on the long-term risk of epilepsy and seizure following COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study including 91,528 patients. J Infect. 2023;86:256-308. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2023.01.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu WH, Tsai YW, Wu JY, Liu TH, Lai CC. Post-acute hospitalization and mortality of nirmatrelvir plus ritonavir for COVID-19 survivors. J Infect. 2023;86:e107-e110. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2023.02.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV, Condition WHOCCDWGoP-C. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(4):e102-e107. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>TriNetX. Accessed February 11,&#xa0;2023. https://trinetx.com</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Fact sheet for healthcare providers: emergency use authorization for Paxlovid (nirmatrelvir and ritonavir). &#xa0;Accessed March 24,&#xa0;2023. https://www.fda.gov/media/155050/download</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GISAID. Tracking of hCoV-19 variants. Accessed March 24,&#xa0;2023. https://gisaid.org/hcov19-variants/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khandia R, Singhal S, Alqahtani T, et al. Emergence of SARS-CoV-2 Omicron (B.1.1.529) variant, salient features, high global health concerns and strategies to counter it amid ongoing COVID-19 pandemic. Environ Res. 2022;209:112816. doi:10.1016/j.envres.2022.112816</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Husain M, Harrison PJ. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 2021;18(9):e1003773. doi:10.1371/journal.pmed.1003773</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbel R, Wolff Sagy Y, Hoshen M, et al. Nirmatrelvir use and severe Covid-19 outcomes during the Omicron surge. N Engl J Med. 2022;387(9):790-798. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2204919</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong CKH, Au ICH, Lau KTK, Lau EHY, Cowling BJ, Leung GM. Real-world effectiveness of molnupiravir and nirmatrelvir plus ritonavir against mortality, hospitalisation, and in-hospital outcomes among community-dwelling, ambulatory patients with confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection during the omicron wave in Hong Kong: an observational study. Lancet. 2022;400(10359):1213-1222. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(22)01586-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najjar-Debbiny R, Gronich N, Weber G, et al. Effectiveness of paxlovid in reducing severe coronavirus disease 2019 and mortality in high-risk patients. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76(3):e342-e349. doi:10.1093/cid/ciac443</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28(3):583-590. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-01689-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu E, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Long-term neurologic outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28(11):2406-2415. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-02001-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Risks and burdens of incident diabetes in long COVID: a cohort study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2022;10(5):311-321. doi:10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00044-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Xu E, Al-Aly Z. Kidney outcomes in long COVID. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;32(11):2851-2862. doi:10.1681/ASN.2021060734</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q, Zheng B, Daines L, Sheikh A. Long-term sequelae of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of one-year Follow-Up studies on post-COVID symptoms. Pathogens. 2022;11(2):269. doi:10.3390/pathogens11020269</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunti K, Del Prato S, Mathieu C, Kahn SE, Gabbay RA, Buse JB. COVID-19, hyperglycemia, and new-onset diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2021;44(12):2645-2655. doi:10.2337/dc21-1318</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merkler AE, Parikh NS, Mir S, et al. Risk of ischemic stroke in patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) vs patients with influenza. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(11):1366. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.2730</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wulf Hanson S, Abbafati C, Aerts JG, et al. Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA. 2022;328(16):1604-1615. doi:10.1001/jama.2022.18931</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis. 2022;226(9):1593-1607. doi:10.1093/infdis/jiac136</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>