<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37364815</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-7492</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>334</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Virus research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Virus Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Incidence of Epstein-Barr virus reactivation is elevated in COVID-19 patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>199157</StartPage><MedlinePgn>199157</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">199157</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.virusres.2023.199157</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0168-1702(23)00119-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>COVID-19, an infectious respiratory illness, is caused by infection with the SARS-CoV-2 virus. Individuals with underlying medical conditions are at increased risk of developing serious illnesses such as long COVID. Recent studies have observed Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) reactivation in patients with severe illness or long COVID, which may contribute to associated symptoms. We determined the frequency of EBV reactivation in COVID-19 positive patients compared to COVID-19 negative patients. 106 blood plasma samples were collected from COVID-19 positive and negative patients and EBV reactivation was determined by detection of EBV DNA and antibodies against EBV lytic genes in individuals with previous EBV infection. 27.1% (13/48) of EBV reactivations, based on qPCR detection of EBV genomes, are from the COVID positive group while only 12.5% (6/48) of reactivations belonged to the negative group. 20/52 (42.30%) of the COVID PCR negative group had detectable antibodies against SARS-CoV-2 nucleoprotein (Np); indicative of past infection. A significantly higher SARS-CoV-2 Np protein level was found in the COVID-19 positive group. In conclusion, COVID-19 patients experienced increased reactivation of EBV in comparison to COVID negative patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bernal</LastName><ForeName>Keishanne Danielle E</ForeName><Initials>KDE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Microbiology, and Immunology, New York Medical College, Basic Medical Sciences Building, 15 Dana Rd. Valhalla, NY 10595; Westlake High School, 825 Westlake Dr., Thornwood, NY 10594.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whitehurst</LastName><ForeName>Christopher B</ForeName><Initials>CB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Microbiology, and Immunology, New York Medical College, Basic Medical Sciences Building, 15 Dana Rd. Valhalla, NY 10595. Electronic address: cwhitehu@NYMC.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Virus Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8410979</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0168-1702</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020031" MajorTopicYN="Y">Epstein-Barr Virus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004854" MajorTopicYN="N">Herpesvirus 4, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014775" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Activation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EBV</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epstein-Barr virus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reactivation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37364815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10292739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.virusres.2023.199157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0168-1702(23)00119-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aiello AE, Simanek AM, Galea S. Population levels of psychological stress, herpesvirus reactivation and HIV. AIDS Behav. 2010;14:308&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4156100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18264753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali N. Elevated level of C-reactive protein may be an early marker to predict risk for severity of COVID-19. J. Med. Virol. 2020;92:2409&#x2013;2411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32516845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B, Tancredi C, Song Y, Mogus AT, Huang MW, Zhu H, Phan TL, Zhu H, Kadl A, Woodfolk J, Jerome KR, Zeichner SL. Epstein-Barr virus and human herpesvirus-6 reactivation in acute COVID-19 patients. Viruses. 2022;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9504756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36146679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callaway E. Beyond Omicron: what's next for COVID's viral evolution. Nature. 2021;600:204&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34876665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention  . 2022. Interim Guidelines for COVID-19 Antibody Testing.https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/testing/antibody-tests-guidelines.html Accessed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention  . 2022. Nearly One in Five American Adults Who Have Had COVID-19 Still Have &#x201c;Long COVID&#x201d;.https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/pressroom/nchs_press_releases/2022/20220622.htm Accessed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention  . 2022. More Than 3,500 Americans Have Died from Long COVID-Related Illness in the First 30 Months of the Pandemic.https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/pressroom/nchs_press_releases/2022/20221214.htm Accessed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Song J, Liu H, Zheng H, Chen C. Positive Epstein-Barr virus detection in coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) patients. Sci. Rep. 2021;11:10902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8149409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34035353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dochi H, Kondo S, Murata T, Fukuyo M, Nanbo A, Wakae K, Jiang WP, Hamabe-Horiike T, Tanaka M, Nishiuchi T, Mizokami H, Moriyama-Kita M, Kobayashi E, Hirai N, Komori T, Ueno T, Nakanishi Y, Hatano M, Endo K, Sugimoto H, Wakisaka N, Juang SH, Muramatsu M, Kaneda A, Yoshizaki T. Estrogen induces the expression of EBV lytic protein ZEBRA, a marker of poor prognosis in nasopharyngeal carcinoma. Cancer Sci. 2022;113:2862&#x2013;2877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9357606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35633182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiwara S, Kimura H, Imadome K, Arai A, Kodama E, Morio T, Shimizu N, Wakiguchi H. Current research on chronic active Epstein-Barr virus infection in Japan. Pediatr. Int. 2014;56:159&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24528553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues E, Janvier P, Kherabi Y, Le Bot A, Hamon A, Gouze H, Doucet L, Berkani S, Oliosi E, Mallart E, Corre F, Zarrouk V, Moyer JD, Galy A, Honsel V, Fantin B, Nguyen Y. Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. J. Infect. 2020;81:e4&#x2013;e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold JE, Okyay RA, Licht WE, Hurley DJ. Investigation of long COVID prevalence and its relationship to Epstein-Barr virus reactivation. Pathogens. 2021;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8233978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34204243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan WJ, Ni ZY, Hu Y, Liang WH, Ou CQ, He JX, Liu L, Shan H, Lei CL, Hui DSC, Du B, Li LJ, Zeng G, Yuen KY, Chen RC, Tang CL, Wang T, Chen PY, Xiang J, Li SY, Wang JL, Liang ZJ, Peng YX, Wei L, Liu Y, Hu YH, Peng P, Wang JM, Liu JY, Chen Z, Li G, Zheng ZJ, Qiu SQ, Luo J, Ye CJ, Zhu SY, Zhong NS, China Medical Treatment Expert Group for C. Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020;382:1708&#x2013;1720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32109013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulley ML. Molecular diagnosis of Epstein-Barr virus-related diseases. J. Mol. Diagn. 2001;3:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1907346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11227065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Im JH, Nahm CH, Je YS, Lee JS, Baek JH, Kwon HY, Chung MH, Jang JH, Kim JS, Lim JH, Park MH. The effect of Epstein-Barr virus viremia on the progression to severe COVID-19. Medicine (Baltimore). 2022;101:e29027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9276369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35550458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imai K, Kitagawa Y, Tabata S, Kubota K, Nagura-Ikeda M, Matsuoka M, Miyoshi K, Sakai J, Ishibashi N, Tarumoto N, Takeuchi S, Ito T, Maesaki S, Tamura K, Maeda T. Antibody response patterns in COVID-19 patients with different levels of disease severity in Japan. J. Med. Virol. 2021;93:3211&#x2013;3218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33620098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanakry JA, Hegde AM, Durand CM, Massie AB, Greer AE, Ambinder RF, Valsamakis A. The clinical significance of EBV DNA in the plasma and peripheral blood mononuclear cells of patients with or without EBV diseases. Blood. 2016;127:2007&#x2013;2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4841041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26744460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr JR. Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) reactivation and therapeutic inhibitors. J. Clin. Pathol. 2019;72:651&#x2013;658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31315893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koc HC, Xiao J, Liu W, Li Y, Chen G. Long COVID and its Management. Int J Biol Sci. 2022;18:4768&#x2013;4780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9305273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35874958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam WKJ, Jiang P, Chan KCA, Cheng SH, Zhang H, Peng W, Tse OYO, Tong YK, Gai W, Zee BCY, Ma BBY, Hui EP, Chan ATC, Woo JKS, Chiu RWK, Lo YMD. Sequencing-based counting and size profiling of plasma Epstein-Barr virus DNA enhance population screening of nasopharyngeal carcinoma. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2018;115:E5115&#x2013;E5124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5984543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29760067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lennette E HW. Epstein-Barr virus infections: clinical and serologic features. Lab. Manag. 1987;25:23&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallett S, Allen AJ, Graziadio S, Taylor SA, Sakai NS, Green K, Suklan J, Hyde C, Shinkins B, Zhelev Z, Peters J, Turner PJ, Roberts NW, di Ruffano LF, Wolff R, Whiting P, Winter A, Bhatnagar G, Nicholson BD, Halligan S. At what times during infection is SARS-CoV-2 detectable and no longer detectable using RT-PCR-based tests? A systematic review of individual participant data. BMC Med. 2020;18:346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7609379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33143712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manoharan S, Ying LY. Epstein Barr virus reactivation during COVID-19 hospitalization significantly increased mortality/death in SARS-CoV-2(+)/EBV(+) than SARS-CoV-2(+)/EBV(-) Patients: a comparative meta-analysis. Int. J. Clin. Pract. 2023;2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9904914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36793928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng M, Zhang S, Dong X, Sun W, Deng Y, Li W, Li R, Annane D, Wu Z, Chen D. COVID-19 associated EBV reactivation and effects of ganciclovir treatment. Immun Inflamm Dis. 2022;10:e597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8959425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35349757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murata T, Sugimoto A, Inagaki T, Yanagi Y, Watanabe T, Sato Y, Kimura H. Molecular basis of Epstein-Barr virus latency establishment and Lytic reactivation. Viruses. 2021;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8706188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34960613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naendrup JH, Garcia Borrega J, Eichenauer DA, Shimabukuro-Vornhagen A, Kochanek M, Boll B. Reactivation of EBV and CMV in severe COVID-19-epiphenomena or trigger of hyperinflammation in need of treatment? A large case series of critically ill patients. J. Intensive Care Med. 2022;37:1152&#x2013;1158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9396115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34791940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>New York City Department of Health and Mental Hygiene  . 2022. Omicron Variant: NYC Report for January 13, 2022.https://www1.nyc.gov/assets/doh/downloads/pdf/covid/omicron-variant-report-jan-13-22.pdf Accessed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paolucci S, Cassaniti I, Novazzi F, Fiorina L, Piralla A, Comolli G, Bruno R, Maserati R, Gulminetti R, Novati S, Mojoli F, Baldanti F, San Matteo, Pavia C-TF. EBV DNA increase in COVID-19 patients with impaired lymphocyte subpopulation count. Int. J. Infect. Dis. 2021;104:315&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deveau TM, Munter SE, Ryder D, Buck A, Beck-Engeser G, Chan F, Lu S, Goldberg SA, Hoh R, Tai V, Torres L, Iyer NS, Deswal M, Ngo LH, Buitrago M, Rodriguez A, Chen JY, Yee BC, Chenna A, Winslow JW, Petropoulos CJ, Deitchman AN, Hellmuth J, Spinelli MA, Durstenfeld MS, Hsue PY, Kelly JD, Martin JN, Deeks SG, Hunt PW, Henrich TJ. Chronic viral coinfections differentially affect the likelihood of developing long COVID. J. Clin. Invest. 2023:133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9888380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36454631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pepys MB, Hirschfield GM. C-reactive protein: a critical update. J. Clin. Invest. 2003;111:1805&#x2013;1812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC161431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12813013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi F, Talebi Bezmin Abadi A. Omicron: a highly transmissible SARS-CoV-2 variant. Gene Rep. 2022;27</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8828449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35165664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan JL, Fan H, Glaser SL, Schichman SA, Raab-Traub N, Gulley ML. Epstein-Barr virus quantitation by real-time PCR targeting multiple gene segments: a novel approach to screen for the virus in paraffin-embedded tissue and plasma. J. Mol. Diagn. 2004;6:378&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1867486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15507678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saade A, Moratelli G, Azoulay E, Darmon M. Herpesvirus reactivation during severe COVID-19 and high rate of immune defect. Infect. Dis. Now. 2021;51:676&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8317452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34332165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sausen DG, Bhutta MS, Gallo ES, Dahari H, Borenstein R. Stress-induced Epstein-Barr virus reactivation. Biomolecules. 2021;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8470332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34572593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>She RC, Stevenson J, Phansalkar AR, Hillyard DR, Litwin CM, Petti CA. Limitations of polymerase chain reaction testing for diagnosing acute Epstein-Barr virus infections. Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis. 2007;58:333&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17376631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonnet A, Engelmann I, Moreau AS, Garcia B, Six S, El Kalioubie A, Robriquet L, Hober D, Jourdain M. High incidence of Epstein-Barr virus, cytomegalovirus, and human-herpes virus-6 reactivations in critically ill patients with COVID-19. Infect. Dis. Now. 2021;51:296&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7816954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33495765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, Ng RH, Wang K, Choi J, Li S, Hong S, Zhang R, Xie J, Kornilov SA, Scherler K, Pavlovitch-Bedzyk AJ, Dong S, Lausted C, Lee I, Fallen S, Dai CL, Baloni P, Smith B, Duvvuri VR, Anderson KG, Li J, Yang F, Duncombe CJ, McCulloch DJ, Rostomily C, Troisch P, Zhou J, Mackay S, DeGottardi Q, May DH, Taniguchi R, Gittelman RM, Klinger M, Snyder TM, Roper R, Wojciechowska G, Murray K, Edmark R, Evans S, Jones L, Zhou Y, Rowen L, Liu R, Chour W, Algren HA, Berrington WR, Wallick JA, Cochran RA, et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185:881&#x2013;895.e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson MP, Kurzrock R. Epstein-Barr virus and cancer. Clin. Cancer Res. 2004;10:803&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14871955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian D, Sun Y, Xu H, Ye Q. The emergence and epidemic characteristics of the highly mutated SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variant. J. Med. Virol. 2022;94:2376&#x2013;2383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9015498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35118687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzellos S, Farrell PJ. Epstein-barr virus sequence variation-biology and disease. Pathogens. 2012;1:156&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4235690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25436768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Elslande J, Oyaert M, Ailliet S, Van Ranst M, Lorent N, Vande Weygaerde Y, Andre E, Lagrou K, Vandendriessche S, Vermeersch P. Longitudinal follow-up of IgG anti-nucleocapsid antibodies in SARS-CoV-2 infected patients up to eight months after infection. J. Clin. Virol. 2021;136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7891078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33636554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma D, Church TM, Swaminathan S. Epstein-Barr virus lytic replication induces ACE2 expression and enhances SARS-CoV-2 pseudotyped virus entry in epithelial cells. J. Virol. 2021;95</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8316011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33853968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigon L, Garcia-Perez J, Rodriguez-Mora S, Torres M, Mateos E, Castillo de la Osa M, Cervero M, Malo De Molina R, Navarro C, Murciano-Anton MA, Garcia-Gutierrez V, Planelles V, Alcami J, Perez-Olmeda M, Coiras M, Lopez-Huertas MR. Impaired antibody-dependent cellular cytotoxicity in a Spanish cohort of patients with COVID-19 admitted to the ICU. Front. Immunol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8488389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34616404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vojdani A, Vojdani E, Saidara E, Maes M. Persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection, EBV, HHV-6 and other factors may contribute to inflammation and autoimmunity in long COVID. Viruses. 2023;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9967513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36851614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vouloumanou EK, Rafailidis PI, Falagas ME. Current diagnosis and management of infectious mononucleosis. Curr. Opin. Hematol. 2012;19:14&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22123662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton AH, Muenzer JT, Rasche D, Boomer JS, Sato B, Brownstein BH, Pachot A, Brooks TL, Deych E, Shannon WD, Green JM, Storch GA, Hotchkiss RS. Reactivation of multiple viruses in patients with sepsis. PLoS One. 2014;9:e98819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4053360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24919177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  . 2023. WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard.https://covid19.who.int/ Accessed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Cao S, Dong H, Lv H, Teng X, Zhang J, Wang T, Zhang X, Qin Y, Chai Y, Yang L, Liu J, Wang R. Clinical characteristics and outcomes of critically ill patients with acute COVID-19 with Epstein-Barr virus reactivation. BMC Infect. Dis. 2021;21:955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8441951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34525962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Yu Y, Xu J, Shu H, Xia J, Liu H, Wu Y, Zhang L, Yu Z, Fang M, Yu T, Wang Y, Pan S, Zou X, Yuan S, Shang Y. Clinical course and outcomes of critically ill patients with SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a single-centered, retrospective, observational study. Lancet Respir. Med. 2020;8:475&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32105632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubchenko S, Kril I, Nadizhko O, Matsyura O, Chopyak V. Herpesvirus infections and post-COVID-19 manifestations: a pilot observational study. Rheumatol. Int. 2022;42:1523&#x2013;1530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9159383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35650445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>zur Hausen H, Schulte-Holthausen H, Klein G, Henle W, Henle G, Clifford P, Santesson L. EBV DNA in biopsies of Burkitt tumours and anaplastic carcinomas of the nasopharynx. Nature. 1970;228:1056&#x2013;1058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4320657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>