<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36649955</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1488-2329</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>195</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>CMAJ : Canadian Medical Association journal = journal de l'Association medicale canadienne</Title><ISOAbbreviation>CMAJ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Diagnosing post-COVID-19 condition (long COVID) in adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>E78</StartPage><EndPage>E79</EndPage><MedlinePgn>E78-E79</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1503/cmaj.220818</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quinn</LastName><ForeName>Kieran L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Institute of Health Policy, Management, and Evaluation (Quinn, Razak, Cheung), University of Toronto; ICES Central (Quinn); Department of Medicine (Quinn, Cheung), Sinai Health System and University Health Network; Temmy Latner Centre for Palliative Care (Quinn); Department of Medicine (Razak), Li Ka Shing Knowledge Institute, Unity Health Toronto; Department of Medicine (Razak), St. Michael's Hospital, Unity Health Toronto; Toronto General Hospital Research Institute and Schroeder Arthritic Institute (Cheung), University Health Network, Toronto, Ont. kieran.quinn@sinaihealth.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Razak</LastName><ForeName>Fahad</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Institute of Health Policy, Management, and Evaluation (Quinn, Razak, Cheung), University of Toronto; ICES Central (Quinn); Department of Medicine (Quinn, Cheung), Sinai Health System and University Health Network; Temmy Latner Centre for Palliative Care (Quinn); Department of Medicine (Razak), Li Ka Shing Knowledge Institute, Unity Health Toronto; Department of Medicine (Razak), St. Michael's Hospital, Unity Health Toronto; Toronto General Hospital Research Institute and Schroeder Arthritic Institute (Cheung), University Health Network, Toronto, Ont.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheung</LastName><ForeName>Angela M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Institute of Health Policy, Management, and Evaluation (Quinn, Razak, Cheung), University of Toronto; ICES Central (Quinn); Department of Medicine (Quinn, Cheung), Sinai Health System and University Health Network; Temmy Latner Centre for Palliative Care (Quinn); Department of Medicine (Razak), Li Ka Shing Knowledge Institute, Unity Health Toronto; Department of Medicine (Razak), St. Michael's Hospital, Unity Health Toronto; Toronto General Hospital Research Institute and Schroeder Arthritic Institute (Cheung), University Health Network, Toronto, Ont.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>CMAJ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9711805</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0820-3946</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>CMAJ. 195:E76.</RefSource></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>CMAJ. 195:E80.</RefSource></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086742" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Testing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: Kieran Quinn is a former assistant scientific director of the Ontario COVID-19 Science Advisory Table from Aug. 8, 2022, to Sept. 30, 2022. He is the current assistant scientific director of the Ontario Public Health Emergencies Science Advisory Committee and has received Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR) grants (awarded to his institution) to study the long-term effects of COVID-19. He has served as an advisor for the chief science advisor of the Canada Task Force on Post-COVID-19 Condition. Fahad Razak holds a salary award as the Graham Farquharson knowledge translation fellow from the PSI Foundation and is an employee of Ontario Health. He was also an employee of Public Health Ontario during the writing of this manuscript. Fahad Razak has received grants (outside the current article) to study COVID-19 from CIHR, Canadian Frailty Network, University of Toronto (including the Department of Medicine, St. Michael&#x2019;s Hospital and the Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre), Digital Research Alliance of Canada (Data Champions Pilot Project) and Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons of Canada. Angela Cheung has received CIHR grants (awarded to her institution) for CANCOV (platform observational study of COVID-19 in Canada) and RECLAIM (adaptive platform randomized controlled trials for long COVID interventions). MediciNova is providing a study drug and placebo for the RECLAIM trial, a multicentre study across Canada. Angela Cheung has served as an advisor for the Ontario COVID-19 Science Advisory Table, Public Health Agency of Canada, Canadian Agency for Drugs and Technologies in Health, COVID-19 Immunity Task Force and chief science advisor of the Canada Task Force on Post-COVID-19 Condition. No other competing interests were declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36649955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9851644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/cmaj.220818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">195/2/E78</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, et al. . Condition WCCDWG on PC 19. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis 2022;22:e102&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frequency and impact of longer-term symptoms following COVID-19 in Canadian adults. Ottawa: Government of Canada; 2022. Available: https://health-infobase.canada.ca/covid-19/post-covid-condition/results.html (accessed 2022 Oct. 24).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, et al. . Global prevalence of post COVID-19 condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis 2022 2022;226:1593&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. . Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med 2021;27:601&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Li X, Gu X, et al. . Health outcomes in people 2 years after surviving hospitalisation with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Respir Med 2022;10: 863&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9094732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35568052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>