<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34899105</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1568-4156</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Season>Oct-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of integrated care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Integr Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>What does Success Look Like for Leaders of Integrated Health and Social Care Systems? a Realist Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>26</StartPage><MedlinePgn>26</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">26</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5334/ijic.5936</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Health and social care services in England are moving towards greater integration, yet little is known about how leadership of integrated care teams and systems can be supported and improved. This realist review explores what works about the leadership of integrated care teams and systems, for whom, in what circumstances and why.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A realist synthesis approach was undertaken in 2020 to explore English language literature on the leadership of integrated care teams and systems, complemented by ongoing stakeholder consultation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Evidence was identified for seven potentially important components of leadership in integrated care teams and systems: 'inspiring intent to work together'; 'creating the conditions'; 'balancing multiple perspectives'; 'working with power'; 'taking a wider view'; 'a commitment to learning and development' and 'clarifying complexity'.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Research into the leadership of integrated care teams and systems is limited, with ideas often reverting to existing framings of leadership, where teams and organisations are less complex. Research also often focuses on the importance of who the leader is rather than what they do.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This review has generated new perspectives on the leadership of integrated care teams and systems that can be built upon, developed, and tested further.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2021 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sims</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7494-9030</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>King's College London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fletcher</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5905-1553</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kingston University and St George's University London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brearley</LastName><ForeName>Sally</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7918-7485</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kingston University and St George's University London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ross</LastName><ForeName>Fiona</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0909-6988</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kingston University and St George's University London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manthorpe</LastName><ForeName>Jill</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9006-1410</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>King's College London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harris</LastName><ForeName>Ruth</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4377-5063</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>King's College London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Integr Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101214424</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">integrated care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">integration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">leadership</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social care</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Ruth Harris is a member of the National Institute for Health Research (NIHR) Trainees Coordinating Centre Doctoral Research Fellowship Panel (TCCDRF). Fiona Ross is an Independent Governor at Westminster University and a member REF England Equality and Diversity Advisory Panel. Jill Manthorpe is Panel Chair for the NIHR Policy Research Programme (PRP) (ended Jan 2021), Health &amp; Social Care Research &amp; Development Division of the Public Health Agency (Northern Ireland). She is a panel member for NIHR Research for Social Care; NIHR Academy Senior Fellowships; NIHR PRP Covid Response (Renew, Reset and Recover); NIHR Long Covid programme; NIHR Research for Patient Benefit; NIHR Strategy Board; Chief Social Worker for Adult Research Reference Group UK Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC); Adult Social Care Strategy Forum, DHSC; NIHR Multiple Long-term Conditions Oversight Group; NIHR Policy Research Unit Older People and Frailty Advisory Group; NIHR Health Service and Delivery Research (HS&amp;DR); NIHR Dementia Strategy Advisory Group and a board member of NIHR Applied Research Collaboration (ARC) South London; NIHR National Priority Area Social Care and Social Work Applied Research Collaboration (ARC).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34899105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8622249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/ijic.5936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>NHS England. The NHS five-year forward view. https://wwwenglandnhsuk/publication/nhs-five-year-forward-view/ [Last accessed 26/02/21]; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England. The NHS long term plan. https://wwwlongtermplannhsuk/. [Last accessed 26/02/21]; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England. Integrating care &#x2013; Next steps to building strong and effective integrated care systems across England. https://www.england.nhs.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/integrating-care-next-steps-to-building-strong-and-effective-integrated-care-systems.pdf [Last accessed 26/02/21]; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health and Social Care. Working together to improve health and social care for all: White paper setting out legislative proposals for a health and care bill. https://assetspublishingservicegovuk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/960549/integration-and-innovation-working-together-to-improve-health-and-social-care-for-all-print-versionpdf. [Last accessed 26/02/21]; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ham C. A progress report on integrated care systems. https://wwwkingsfundorguk/blog/2018/03/progressreport-integrated-care-systems [Last accessed 26/02/21]; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dopson S, Annabelle M. Leading Health Care Organizations. Basingstoke: Palgrave Macmillan; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dopson S, Ferlie E, McGivern G, Fischer M, Ledger J, Behrens S, et al. The impact of leadership and leadership development in higher education: A review of the literature and evidence. London: Leadership Foundation for Higher Education; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS Leadership Academy. Clinical Leadership Competency Framework. Coventry: Institute for Innovation and Improvement; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drucker P. Managing in the Next Society. New York: Truman Talley Books, St Martin&#x2019;s Griffin; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed N, Ahmed F, Anis H, Carr P, Gauher S, Rahman F. An NHS leadership team for the future. London: Reform Research Trust; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith T, Fowler-Davis S, Nancarrow S, Ariss S, Enderby P. Leadership in interprofessional health and social care teams: A literature review. Leadership in Health Services; 2018. DOI: 10.1108/LHS-06-2016-0026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/LHS-06-2016-0026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30234446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis R. Report of the Mid Staffordshire NHS Foundation Trust Public Inquiry, (Chair Robert Francis QC), London: The Stationery Office; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves S, MacMillan K, van Soeren M. Leadership within interprofessional health and social care teams: a socio-historical overview of some key trials and tribulations. Journal of Nursing Management. 2010a; 18: 258&#x2013;64. DOI: 10.1111/j.1365-2834.2010.01077.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2834.2010.01077.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20546465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borkowski N. Organizational behavior in health care. Burlington MA: Jones &amp; Barlett Learning; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The King&#x2019;s Fund. The future of leadership and management in the NHS &#x2013; no more heroes. London: The King&#x2019;s Fund; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naylor R, Dorrell S, Everington S. Ending the crisis in NHS leadership a plan for renewal. London: HSJ Future of NHS Leadership; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fillingham D, Weir B. System leadership: lessons and learning from AQuA&#x2019;s integrated care discovery communities. London: The King&#x2019;s Fund. www.kingsfund.org.uk/publications/system-leadership [Last accessed 26/02/21]; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawson R, Greenhalgh T, Harvey G, Walshe K. Realist Synthesis: An Introduction. RMP Methods Paper 2/2004; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Wong G, Westhorp G, Pawson R. Protocol &#x2013; realist and meta-narrative evidence synthesis: Evolving Standards (RAMESES). BMC Medical Research Methodology. 2011; 11(1): 115. DOI: 10.1186/1471-2288-11-115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-11-115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3173389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21843376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawson R. Evidence-based Policy: a realist perspective. London: Sage; 2006. DOI: 10.4135/9781849209120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4135/9781849209120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong G, Greenhalgh T, Westhorp G. RAMESES publication standards: realist syntheses. BMC Med. 2013; 11. DOI: 10.1186/1741-7015-11-21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1741-7015-11-21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3558331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23360677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris R, Fletcher S, Sims S. Understanding key mechanisms of successfully leading integrated teambased services in health and social care: protocol for a realist synthesis. BMJ Open. 2020; 10. DOI: 10.1136/bmjopen-2020-038591</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-038591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7351270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32647024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw A, Levenson R. Towards integrated care in Trafford The Nuffield Trust; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aitken K, Von Treuer K. Organisational and leadership competencies for successful service integration. Leadership in Health Services. 2014; 27: 150&#x2013;80. DOI: 10.1108/LHS-08-2012-0028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/LHS-08-2012-0028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson M, Wilkin A, Stott A, Kinder K. Multiagency working: A detailed study. Berkshire: National Foundation for Educational Research; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander JA, Comfort ME, Weiner BJ, Bogue R. Leadership in Collaborative Community Health Partnerships. Nonprofit Management and Leadership. 2001; 12(2): 159&#x2013;75. DOI: 10.1002/nml.12203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nml.12203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen R, Mountford J, Lewis G, Lewis R, Shand J, Shaw S. Integration in action: Four international case studies. Nuffied Trust; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Best S. Facilitating integrated delivery of services across organisational boundaries: essential enablers to integration.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunts P. Change management in integrated care: what helps and hinders middle managers &#x2013; a case study. Journal of Integrated Care. 2012; 20(4): 246&#x2013;56. DOI: 10.1108/14769011211255285</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/14769011211255285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Axelsson SB, Axelsson R. From territoriality to altruism in interprofessional collaboration and leadership. Journal of Interprofessional Care. 2009; 23(4): 320&#x2013;30. DOI: 10.1080/13561820902921811</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13561820902921811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19517284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chreim S. Change agency in a primary health care context: The case of distributed leadership.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20234224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asakawa T, Kawabata H, Kisa K, Terashita T, Murakami M, Otaki J. Establishing community-based integrated care for elderly patients through interprofessional teamwork: A qualitative analysis. Journal of Multidisciplinary Healthcare. 2017; 10: 399&#x2013;407. DOI: 10.2147/JMDH.S144526</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JMDH.S144526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5644561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29066908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramm J, Nieboer A. Disease-management partnership functioning, synergy and effectiveness in delivering chronic-illness care. International journal for quality in health care: journal of the International Society for Quality in Health Care/ISQua. 2012; 24: 279&#x2013;85. DOI: 10.1093/intqhc/mzs004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzs004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22302071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams P. The role of leadership in learning and knowledge for integration; 2012a. DOI: 10.1108/14769011211237500</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/14769011211237500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickinson H. Opportunity seized or missed? A case study of leadership and organizational change in the creation of a Care Trust. Journal of Interprofessional Care. 2007; 21(5): 503&#x2013;13. DOI: 10.1080/13561820701585353</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13561820701585353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17891624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson C, Hepworth J, Burridge L, Marley J, Jackson C. Translating the Elements of Health Governance for Integrated Care from Theory to Practice: A Case Study Approach. Int J Integr Care. 2018; 18(1): 11&#x2013;. DOI: 10.5334/ijic.3106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/ijic.3106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5854213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29588645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen JR, Dowling M, Gallagher JST. The trials, tribulations, and relative success of the ongoing clinical merger of two large academic hospital systems. Academic Medicine. 2006; 81(10 SUPPL.): 11&#x2013;7. DOI: 10.1097/01.ACM.0000235601.35726.db</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.ACM.0000235601.35726.db</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11448820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi S, Holmberg I, Lowstedt J, Brommels M. Managing clinical integration: A comparative case study in a merged university hospital. Journal of Health, Organisation and Management. 2012; 26(4): 486&#x2013;507. DOI: 10.1108/14777261211251544</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/14777261211251544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23115901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayan M, Heenan D. Change or collapse: Lessons from the drive to reform health and social care in Northern Ireland. The Nuffield Trust; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karam M, Tricas-Sauras S, Darras E, Macq J. Interprofessional Collaboration between General Physicians and Emergency Department Teams in Belgium: A Qualitative Study. Int J Integr Care. 2017; 17(4): 9&#x2013;. DOI: 10.5334/ijic.2520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/ijic.2520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5853879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29588632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rees G, Huby G, McDade L, McKechnie L. Joint working in community mental health teams: Implementation of an integrated care pathway. Health and Social Care in the Community. 2004; 12(6): 527&#x2013;36. DOI: 10.1111/j.1365-2524.2004.00523.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2524.2004.00523.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15717899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams PM. Integration of health and social care: A case of learning and knowledge management. Health and Social Care in the Community. 2012b; 20(5): 550&#x2013;60. DOI: 10.1111/j.1365-2524.2012.01076.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2524.2012.01076.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22741611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benzer JK, Cramer IE, Burgess JF, Mohr DC, Sullivan JL, Charns MP. How personal and standardized coordination impact implementation of integrated care. BMC health services research. 2015; 15: 448. DOI: 10.1186/s12913-015-1079-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-015-1079-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4592548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26432790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kharicha K, Iliffe S, Levin E, Davey B, Fleming C. Tearing down the Berlin Wall: social workers&#x2019; perspectives on joint working with general practice. Family practice. 2005; 22: 399&#x2013;405. DOI: 10.1093/fampra/cmi010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/fampra/cmi010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15824057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willumsen E. Leadership in interprofessional collaboration &#x2013; the case of childcare in Norway. Journal of Interprofessional Care. 2006; 20(4): 403&#x2013;13. DOI: 10.1080/13561820600874692</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13561820600874692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16905488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling T, Brereton L, Conklin A, Newbould J, Roland M. Barriers and facilitators to integrating care: experiences from the English Integrated Care Pilots. Int J Integr Care. 2012; 12: e129&#x2013;e. DOI: 10.5334/ijic.982</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/ijic.982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3601528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23593044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll V, Reeve C, Humphreys J, Wakerman J, Carter M. Re-orienting a remote acute care model towards a primary health care approach: Key enablers. Rural and remote health. 2015; 15: 2942. DOI: 10.22605/RRH2942</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22605/RRH2942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26195023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grenier C. Structuring an integrated care system: interpreted through the enacted diversity of the actors involved-the case of a French healthcare network. Int J Integr Care. 2011; 11: e003&#x2013;e. DOI: 10.5334/ijic.526</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/ijic.526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3107087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21637706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scragg T. An Evaluation of Integrated Team Management. Journal of Integrated Care. 2006; 14(3): 39&#x2013;48. DOI: 10.1108/14769018200600023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/14769018200600023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvesson M, Jonsson A. The bumpy road to exercising leadership: Fragmentations in meaning and practice. Leadership. 2018; 14(1): 40&#x2013;57. DOI: 10.1177/1742715016644671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1742715016644671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schweiger S, M&#xfc;ller B, G&#xfc;ttel W. Barriers to leadership development: Why is it so difficult to abandon the hero? Leadership. 2020; 16(4): 411&#x2013;33. DOI: 10.1177/1742715020935742</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1742715020935742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collinson D, Smolovic-Jones O, Grint K. &#x2018;No More Heroes&#x2019;: Critical perspectives on leadership romanticism. Organization Studies. 2018; 39(11): 1625&#x2013;47. DOI: 10.1177/0170840617727784</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0170840617727784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tourish D. Leadership, more or less? A processual, communication perspective on the role of agency in leadership theory. Leadership. 2014; 10(1): 79&#x2013;98. DOI: 10.1177/1742715013509030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1742715013509030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>