<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36187895</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2164-7712</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of clinical and experimental immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Clin Exp Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Immunological features of the multisystem inflammatory syndrome associated with SARS-CoV-2 in children.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>64</StartPage><EndPage>71</EndPage><MedlinePgn>64-71</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>A particular group of children developed severe multisystem inflammation associated with current or recent SARS-CoV-2 infection or contact with a COVID-19 patient in the previous few weeks. The condition was defined as multisystem inflammatory syndrome (MIS) in children (MIS-C). As the definition of CDC and WHO is fast widely accepted, the lack of an international consensus on the definition of the syndrome cases, however, leads to some difficulties for clinicians. Additionally, MIS-C shares some immunological, pathological features with the conditions, such as cytokine storm, long COVID and/or post-COVID syndrome. The picture is further complicated by the existence of the syndrome in adults (MIS-A). Therefore, we have compared these conditions from the immunological point of view in our review based on the published case reports, studies, systematic reviews and metaanalyses. This knowledge is essential not only for immunologists. The paediatricians must be familiar with the immunological bases of the syndrome and implement it in on-time recognition and diagnosis and minimize systemic damage of this life-threatening condition at the earliest stage possible. Further investigations still need to be done to find and develop the best effective therapy and prophylactics.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJCEI Copyright &#xa9; 2022.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lazova</LastName><ForeName>Snezhina</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Department, University Hospital "N. I. Pirogov" General Eduard I. Totleben Blvd 21, 1606, Pette Kyosheta, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healthcare Department, Faculty of Public Health, Medical University Sofia Bialo More 8 Street, 1527, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gerenska</LastName><ForeName>Dilyana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PPD, Part of Thermo Fisher Scientific, Department of Pharmacovigilance Boulevard "Tsarigradsko Shoes" 115&#x433;, 1784 Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Slabakova</LastName><ForeName>Yoanna</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical University Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Velikova</LastName><ForeName>Tsvetelina</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Immunology, University Hospital Lozenetz, Medical Faculty, Sofia University St. Kliment Ohridski, Kozyak 1 Street, 1407 Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Clin Exp Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101587157</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MIS-A</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MIS-C</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cytokine storm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cytokines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36187895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9520186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO Director-General&#x2019;s opening remarks at the media briefing on COVID-19-11 March 2020. Last access at https://www.who.int/dg/speeches/detail/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-the-media-briefing-on-covid-19---11-march-2020 on 2022-Jan-03.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim L, Whitaker M, O&#x2019;Halloran A, Kambhampati A, Chai SJ, Reingold A, Armistead I, Kawasaki B, Meek J, Yousey-Hindes K, Anderson EJ, Openo KP, Weigel A, Ryan P, Monroe ML, Fox K, Kim S, Lynfield R, Bye E, Shrum Davis S, Smelser C, Barney G, Spina NL, Bennett NM, Felsen CB, Billing LM, Shiltz J, Sutton M, West N, Talbot HK, Schaffner W, Risk I, Price A, Brammer L, Fry AM, Hall AJ, Langley GE, Garg S COVID-NET Surveillance Team. Hospitalization rates and characteristics of children aged &lt;18 years hospitalized with laboratory-confirmed COVID-19 - COVID-NET, 14 states, March 1-July 25, 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69:1081&#x2013;1088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7440125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludvigsson JF. Systematic review of COVID-19 in children shows milder cases and a better prognosis than adults. Acta Paediatr. 2020;109:1088&#x2013;1095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32202343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heald-Sargent T, Muller WJ, Zheng X, Rippe J, Patel AB, Kociolek LK. Age-related differences in nasopharyngeal severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) levels in patients with mild to moderate coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) JAMA Pediatr. 2020;174:902&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7393583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32745201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carsetti R, Quintarelli C, Quinti I, Piano Mortari E, Zumla A, Ippolito G, Locatelli F. The immune system of children: the key to understanding SARS-CoV-2 susceptibility? Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2020;4:414&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7202830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32458804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabinowicz S, Leshem E, Pessach IM. COVID-19 in the pediatric population-review and current evidence. Curr Infect Dis Rep. 2020;22:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7501762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32982599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdoni L, Mazza A, Gervasoni A, Martelli L, Ruggeri M, Ciuffreda M, Bonanomi E, D&#x2019;Antiga L. An outbreak of severe Kawasaki-like disease at the Italian epicentre of the SARS-CoV-2 epidemic: an observational cohort study. Lancet. 2020;395:1771&#x2013;1778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7220177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32410760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafferty MS, Burrows H, Joseph JP, Leveille J, Nihtianova S, Amirian ES. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) and the coronavirus pandemic: current knowledge and implications for public health. J Infect Public Health. 2021;14:484&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7813487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33743370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne AB, Gilani Z, Godfred-Cato S, Belay ED, Feldstein LR, Patel MM, Randolph AG, Newhams M, Thomas D, Magleby R, Hsu K, Burns M, Dufort E, Maxted A, Pietrowski M, Longenberger A, Bidol S, Henderson J, Sosa L, Edmundson A, Tobin-D&#x2019;Angelo M, Edison L, Heidemann S, Singh AR, Giuliano JS Jr, Kleinman LC, Tarquinio KM, Walsh RF, Fitzgerald JC, Clouser KN, Gertz SJ, Carroll RW, Carroll CL, Hoots BE, Reed C, Dahlgren FS, Oster ME, Pierce TJ, Curns AT, Langley GE, Campbell AP MIS-C Incidence Authorship Group. Balachandran N, Murray TS, Burkholder C, Brancard T, Lifshitz J, Leach D, Charpie I, Tice C, Coffin SE, Perella D, Jones K, Marohn KL, Yager PH, Fernandes ND, Flori HR, Koncicki ML, Walker KS, Di Pentima MC, Li S, Horwitz SM, Gaur S, Coffey DC, Harwayne-Gidansky I, Hymes SR, Thomas NJ, Ackerman KG, Cholette JM. Incidence of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children among US persons infected with SARS-CoV-2. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2116420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8193431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34110391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riphagen S, Gomez X, Gonzalez-Martinez C, Wilkinson N, Theocharis P. Hyperinflammatory shock in children during COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet. 2020;395:1607&#x2013;1608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7204765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32386565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paediatric multisystem inflammatory syndrome temporally associated with COVID-19 (PIMS) - guidance for clinicians. Available at https://www.rcpch.ac.uk/resources/paediatric-multisystem-inflammatory-syndrome-temporally-associated-covid-19-pims-guidance. Last access on 10th of Jan, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) 2020. https://www.cdc.gov/mis-c/Last access 2021-Dec-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children and adolescents with COVID-19. 2020. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/multisystem-inflammatory-syndrome-in-children-and-adolescents-with-covid-19 Last access 2022-Jan-03.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazova S, Alexandrova T, Gorelyova-Stefanova N, Atanasov K, Tzotcheva I, Velikova T. Liver involvement in children with COVID-19 and multisystem inflammatory syndrome: a single-center Bulgarian observational study. Microorganisms. 2021;9:1958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8467138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34576853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrindle BW, Manlhiot C. SARS-CoV-2-related inflammatory multisystem syndrome in children: different or shared etiology and pathophysiology as Kawasaki disease? JAMA. 2020;324:246&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32511667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittaker E, Bamford A, Kenny J, Kaforou M, Jones CE, Shah P, Ramnarayan P, Fraisse A, Miller O, Davies P, Kucera F, Brierley J, McDougall M, Carter M, Tremoulet A, Shimizu C, Herberg J, Burns JC, Lyall H, Levin M PIMS-TS Study Group and EUCLIDS and PERFORM Consortia. Clinical characteristics of 58 children with a pediatric inflammatory multisystem syndrome temporally associated with SARS-CoV-2. JAMA. 2020;324:259&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7281356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32511692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma C, Ganigara M, Galeotti C, Burns J, Berganza FM, Hayes DA, Singh-Grewal D, Bharath S, Sajjan S, Bayry J. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children and Kawasaki disease: a critical comparison. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2021;17:731&#x2013;748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8554518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34716418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomov LP, Velikova TV, Batselova HM. Health risk management in kindergartens, schools and universities, during covid-19 pandemic: a heuristic framework. American International Journal of Biology and Life Sciences. 2021;3:40&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazova S, Tzotcheva I, Alexandrova T, Gorelyova N, Rangelov E, Ganev B, Velikova T. Acute gastrointestinal symptoms in children with multisystem inflammatory syndrome - a literature review with the presentation of two clinical cases. A Pediatr. 2021;2:64&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldstein LR, Rose EB, Horwitz SM, Collins JP, Newhams MM, Son MBF, Newburger JW, Kleinman LC, Heidemann SM, Martin AA, Singh AR, Li S, Tarquinio KM, Jaggi P, Oster ME, Zackai SP, Gillen J, Ratner AJ, Walsh RF, Fitzgerald JC, Keenaghan MA, Alharash H, Doymaz S, Clouser KN, Giuliano JS Jr, Gupta A, Parker RM, Maddux AB, Havalad V, Ramsingh S, Bukulmez H, Bradford TT, Smith LS, Tenforde MW, Carroll CL, Riggs BJ, Gertz SJ, Daube A, Lansell A, Coronado Munoz A, Hobbs CV, Marohn KL, Halasa NB, Patel MM, Randolph AG Overcoming COVID-19 Investigators; CDC COVID-19 Response Team. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in U. S. children and adolescents. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:334&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7346765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32598831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodsky NN, Ramaswamy A, Lucas CL. The mystery of MIS-C post-SARS-CoV-2 infection. Trends Microbiol. 2020;28:956&#x2013;958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7556780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33190685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennon TR, Penque MD, Abdul-Aziz R, Alibrahim OS, McGreevy MB, Prout AJ, Schaefer BA, Ambrusko SJ, Pastore JV, Turkovich SJ, Gomez-Duarte OG, Hicar MD. COVID-19 associated multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) guidelines; a Western New York approach. Prog Pediatr Cardiol. 2020:101232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7244417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32837142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowell AC, Butler MS, Jinks E, Tut G, Lancaster T, Sylla P, Begum J, Bruton R, Pearce H, Verma K, Logan N, Tyson G, Spalkova E, Margielewska-Davies S, Taylor GS, Syrimi E, Baawuah F, Beckmann J, Okike IO, Ahmad S, Garstang J, Brent AJ, Brent B, Ireland G, Aiano F, Amin-Chowdhury Z, Jones S, Borrow R, Linley E, Wright J, Azad R, Waiblinger D, Davis C, Thomson EC, Palmarini M, Willett BJ, Barclay WS, Poh J, Amirthalingam G, Brown KE, Ramsay ME, Zuo J, Moss P, Ladhani S. Children develop robust and sustained cross-reactive spike-specific immune responses to SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Immunol. 2022;23:40&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8709786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34937928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radtke T, Ulyte A, Puhan MA, Kriemler S. Long-term symptoms after SARS-CoV-2 infection in children and adolescents. JAMA. 2021;326:869&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8283661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34264266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond) 2021;53:737&#x2013;754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed M, Advani S, Moreira A, Zoretic S, Martinez J, Chorath K, Acosta S, Naqvi R, Burmeister-Morton F, Burmeister F, Tarriela A, Petershack M, Evans M, Hoang A, Rajasekaran K, Ahuja S, Moreira A. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children: a systematic review. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;26:100527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7473262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32923992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cases/deaths by region. Available at https://coronavirus.jhu.edu/map.html Last access 2022-Jan-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC Data tracker. Available at https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#new-hospital-admissions, last access 2022-Jan-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow EJ. The multisystem inflammatory syndrome in adults with SARS-CoV-2 infection-another piece of an expanding puzzle. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2110344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34009354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogel TP, Top KA, Karatzios C, Hilmers DC, Tapia LI, Moceri P, Giovannini-Chami L, Wood N, Chandler RE, Klein NP, Schlaudecker EP, Poli MC, Muscal E, Munoz FM. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children and adults (MIS-C/A): case definition &amp; guidelines for data collection, analysis, and presentation of immunization safety data. Vaccine. 2021;39:3037&#x2013;3049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7904456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33640145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB, Schwartz NG, Patel P, Abbo L, Beauchamps L, Balan S, Lee EH, Paneth-Pollak R, Geevarughese A, Lash MK, Dorsinville MS, Ballen V, Eiras DP, Newton-Cheh C, Smith E, Robinson S, Stogsdill P, Lim S, Fox SE, Richardson G, Hand J, Oliver NT, Kofman A, Bryant B, Ende Z, Datta D, Belay E, Godfred-Cato S. Case series of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in adults associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection - United Kingdom and United States, March-August 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69:1450&#x2013;1456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7561225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alunno A, Carubbi F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Carrio J. Storm, typhoon, cyclone or hurricane in patients with COVID-19? Beware of the same storm that has a different origin. RMD Open. 2020;6:e001295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7299508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32423970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon Junior H, Sakano TMS, Rodrigues RM, Eisencraft AP, Carvalho VEL, Schvartsman C, Reis AGADC. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome associated with COVID-19 from the pediatric emergency physician&#x2019;s point of view. J Pediatr (Rio J) 2021;97:140&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32946801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velikova TV, Kotsev SV, Georgiev DS, Batselova HM. Immunological aspects of COVID-19: what do we know? World J Biol Chem. 2020;11:14&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7520644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazova S, Dimitrova Y, Hristova D, Tzotcheva I, Velikova T. Cellular, antibody and cytokine pathways in children with acute SARS-CoV-2 infection and MIS-C-can we match the puzzle? Antibodies (Basel) 2022;11:25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9036295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35466278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buszko M, Nita-Lazar A, Park JH, Schwartzberg PL, Verthelyi D, Young HA, Rosenberg AS. Lessons learned: new insights on the role of cytokines in COVID-19. Nat Immunol. 2021;22:404&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9317654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33723418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>