<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39047785</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1439-4421</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Gesundheitswesen (Bundesverband der Arzte des Offentlichen Gesundheitsdienstes (Germany))</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Gesundheitswesen</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating the Usefulness of Population-Wide COVID-19 Testing in the Omicron Era: Insights from a German Model.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/a-2328-4165</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The Omicron variant of SARS-CoV-2, which has become dominant worldwide since late 2021, presents a unique challenge due to its high rate of asymptomatic transmission. This study evaluates the efficacy and value of population-wide testing, including self-testing, in the context of COVID-19, particularly under the Omicron variant, using data from Germany.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A decision-analytical model and secondary data was used for assessing the impact of systematic screening and testing for COVID-19. Various scenarios were taken into consideration including seasonal patterns of COVID-19 transmission and the potential for annual waves. The model assessed the clinical benefits of testing against the backdrop of vaccine effectiveness, transmission rates, and the potential to prevent severe clinical events, including death, ICU admission, and long COVID syndrome.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The study found that the value of mass testing and self-testing for private use was highly contingent on the transmission rate and the scenario of COVID-19 waves (seasonal vs. continuous). For winter waves, a very high incidence rate was required to justify testing, while for continuous waves, testing could be valuable for those in contact with individuals in their last decade of life. The analysis highlighted the limitations of mass testing when community transmission rates were low and the potential value of testing in high-risk contacts or amidst new outbreaks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The findings suggest that the resumption of testing during winter waves is unlikely to provide significant clinical benefits given the current understanding of Omicron's transmission and immunity waning. This study underscores the need for a nuanced approach to COVID-19 testing policies, considering both the epidemiological context and the practical implications of testing strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gandjour</LastName><ForeName>Afschin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frankfurt School of Finance &amp; Management gGmbH Economics Department, Frankfurt, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><VernacularTitle>Bewertung des Nutzens von fl&#xe4;chendeckenden COVID-19-Tests in der Omikron-&#xc4;ra.</VernacularTitle><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Gesundheitswesen</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9204210</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0941-3790</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger"><AbstractText Label="HINTERGRUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Die Omikron-Variante von SARS-CoV-2, die seit Ende 2021 weltweit vorherrschend ist, stellt aufgrund ihrer hohen Rate an asymptomatischer &#xdc;bertragung eine besondere Herausforderung dar. Diese Studie bewertet die Wirksamkeit und den Nutzen von fl&#xe4;chendeckenden Tests, einschlie&#xdf;lich Selbsttests, im Kontext von COVID-19, insbesondere unter der Omikron-Variante, anhand von Daten aus Deutschland.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODEN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Unter Verwendung eines entscheidungsanalytischen Modells und sekund&#xe4;rer Daten untersucht diese Analyse die Auswirkungen systematischer Screening- und Testverfahren f&#xfc;r COVID-19. Dabei werden verschiedene Szenarien ber&#xfc;cksichtigt, einschlie&#xdf;lich saisonaler Muster der COVID-19-&#xdc;bertragung und der M&#xf6;glichkeit j&#xe4;hrlicher Wellen. Das Modell bewertet die klinischen Vorteile des Testens vor dem Hintergrund der Wirksamkeit von Impfstoffen, &#xdc;bertragungsraten und der M&#xf6;glichkeit, schwere klinische Ereignisse, einschlie&#xdf;lich Tod, Aufnahme auf die Intensivstation und das Long-COVID-Syndrom, zu verhindern.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ERGEBNISSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Die Studie stellt fest, dass der Wert von Massentests und Selbsttests f&#xfc;r den privaten Gebrauch stark von der &#xdc;bertragungsrate und dem Szenario der COVID-19-Wellen (saisonal vs. kontinuierlich) abh&#xe4;ngt. F&#xfc;r Winterwellen ist eine sehr hohe Inzidenzrate erforderlich, um Tests zu rechtfertigen, w&#xe4;hrend f&#xfc;r kontinuierliche Wellen Tests bei Individuen mit Kontaktpersonen im letzten Lebensjahrzehnt wertvoll sein k&#xf6;nnten. Die Analyse hebt die Grenzen des Massentestens hervor, wenn die &#xdc;bertragungsraten in der Gemeinschaft niedrig sind, und den potenziellen Wert des Testens bei Hochrisikokontakten oder inmitten neuer Ausbr&#xfc;che.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISKUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Die Ergebnisse deuten darauf hin, dass die Wiederaufnahme von Tests w&#xe4;hrend der Winterwellen angesichts des aktuellen Verst&#xe4;ndnisses von Omikrons &#xdc;bertragung und nachlassender Immunit&#xe4;t wahrscheinlich keine signifikanten klinischen Vorteile bietet. Diese Studie unterstreicht die Notwendigkeit eines differenzierten Ansatzes bei den COVID-19-Teststrategien, unter Ber&#xfc;cksichtigung sowohl des epidemiologischen Kontexts als auch der praktischen Implikationen von Teststrategien.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39047785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2328-4165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>