<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37771866</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2222-0682</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of methodology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Methodol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Potential long-term neurological and gastrointestinal effects of COVID-19: A review of adult cohorts.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>323</StartPage><EndPage>336</EndPage><MedlinePgn>323-336</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5662/wjm.v13.i4.323</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The respiratory infection caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) has evolved into a multi-organ disorder, with long-term effects known as post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection or long coronavirus disease (COVID).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To examine the current knowledge and outcomes of long-term neurological and gastrointestinal (GI) symptoms in adult cohorts, including United States minority populations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">PubMed and Google Scholar were searched using relevant terms, and data from five studies were analyzed, comprising 27383 patients with persistent neurological and GI sequelae.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The main symptoms included anxiety, depression, dysphagia, headache, vomiting, nausea, gastroesophageal reflux, fatigue, and abdominal pain. Patients with comorbidities and metabolic syndromes were at higher risk for long COVID. While most patients were European Americans, there was a need for further study on African Americans.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The underlying causes of these symptoms remain unclear, warranting more investigation into the long-term impact of the SARS-CoV-2 on different populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2023. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sherif</LastName><ForeName>Zaki A</ForeName><Initials>ZA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry &amp; Molecular Biology, Howard University College of Medicine, Washington, DC 20059, United States. zaki.sherif@howard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deverapalli</LastName><ForeName>Mrinalini</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Howard University Cancer Center, Howard University, Washington, DC 20060, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Challa</LastName><ForeName>Suryanarayana Reddy</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Howard University Hospital, Washington, DC 20060, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martirosyan</LastName><ForeName>Zara</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Howard University Hospital, Washington, DC 20060, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whitesell</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Disease/Sleep Medicine, Howard University Hospital, Washington, DC 20060, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pizuorno</LastName><ForeName>Antonio Machado</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, Houston, TX 77030, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naqvi</LastName><ForeName>Zainab</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Center, Georgetown University, Washington, DC 20007, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tulloch</LastName><ForeName>Ingrid K</ForeName><Initials>IK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Morgan State University, Baltimore, MD 21251, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oskrochi</LastName><ForeName>Gholamreza</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering and Technology, American University of the Middle East, Kuwait Egaila 54200, Kuwait.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brim</LastName><ForeName>Hassan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pathology &amp; Cancer Center, Howard University College of Medicine, Washington, DC 20060, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashktorab</LastName><ForeName>Hassan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine &amp; Cancer Center, Howard University College of Medicine, Washington, DC 20060, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Methodol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101628739</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2222-0682</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Angiotensin converting enzyme</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long coronavirus disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurological</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-acute sequalae of SARS-CoV-2 infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-viral syndromes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors declare no conflict of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37771866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10523249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5662/wjm.v13.i4.323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, Rivera SC, McMullan C, Chandan JS, Haroon S, Price G, Davies EH, Nirantharakumar K, Sapey E, Calvert MJ TLC Study Group. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med . 2021;114:428&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL, Lipkin WI. Insights from myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome may help unravel the pathogenesis of postacute COVID-19 syndrome. Trends Mol Med . 2021;27:895&#x2013;906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8180841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34175230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or Post-acute Sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): An Overview of Biological Factors That May Contribute to Persistent Symptoms. Front Microbiol . 2021;12:698169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choutka J, Jansari V, Hornig M, Iwasaki A. Unexplained post-acute infection syndromes. Nat Med . 2022;28:911&#x2013;923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35585196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varanasi S, Sathyamoorthy M, Chamakura S, Shah SA. Management of Long-COVID Postural Orthostatic Tachycardia Syndrome With Enhanced External Counterpulsation. Cureus . 2021;13:e18398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8555928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34729276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Florencio LL. Defining Post-COVID Symptoms (Post-Acute COVID, Long COVID, Persistent Post-COVID): An Integrative Classification. Int J Environ Res Public Health . 2021;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurnher MM, Reith W, Thurnher AP, Rommer P. [Long COVID: long-term symptoms and morphological/radiological correlates] Radiologe . 2021;61:915&#x2013;922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34554270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Bluemke DA, L&#xfc;scher TF, Neubauer S. Long COVID: post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 with a cardiovascular focus. Eur Heart J . 2022;43:1157&#x2013;1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8903393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35176758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kell DB, Laubscher GJ, Pretorius E. A central role for amyloid fibrin microclots in long COVID/PASC: origins and therapeutic implications. Biochem J . 2022;479:537&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8883497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35195253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sotzny F, Blanco J, Capelli E, Castro-Marrero J, Steiner S, Murovska M, Scheibenbogen C European Network on ME/CFS (EUROMENE) Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome - Evidence for an autoimmune disease. Autoimmun Rev . 2018;17:601&#x2013;609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29635081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw BH, Stiles LE, Bourne K, Green EA, Shibao CA, Okamoto LE, Garland EM, Gamboa A, Diedrich A, Raj V, Sheldon RS, Biaggioni I, Robertson D, Raj SR. The face of postural tachycardia syndrome - insights from a large cross-sectional online community-based survey. J Intern Med . 2019;286:438&#x2013;448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6790699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30861229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heming M, Li X, R&#xe4;uber S, Mausberg AK, B&#xf6;rsch AL, Hartlehnert M, Singhal A, Lu IN, Fleischer M, Szepanowski F, Witzke O, Brenner T, Dittmer U, Yosef N, Kleinschnitz C, Wiendl H, Stettner M, Meyer Zu H&#xf6;rste G. Neurological Manifestations of COVID-19 Feature T Cell Exhaustion and Dedifferentiated Monocytes in Cerebrospinal Fluid. Immunity . 2021;54:164&#x2013;175.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7831653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33382973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visvabharathy L, Hanson BA, Orban ZS, Lim PH, Palacio NM, Jimenez M, Clark JR, Graham EL, Liotta EM, Tachas G, Penaloza-MacMaster P, Koralnik IJ. T cell responses to SARS-CoV-2 in people with and without neurologic symptoms of long COVID. medRxiv . 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghimi N, Di Napoli M, Biller J, Siegler JE, Shekhar R, McCullough LD, Harkins MS, Hong E, Alaouieh DA, Mansueto G, Divani AA. The Neurological Manifestations of Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep . 2021;21:44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8237541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34181102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che Mohd Nassir CMN, Zolkefley MKI, Ramli MD, Norman HH, Abdul Hamid H, Mustapha M. Neuroinflammation and COVID-19 Ischemic Stroke Recovery-Evolving Evidence for the Mediating Roles of the ACE2/Angiotensin-(1-7)/Mas Receptor Axis and NLRP3 Inflammasome. Int J Mol Sci . 2022;23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8949282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35328506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Kuraishy HM, Al-Gareeb AI, Qusti S, Alshammari EM, Gyebi GA, Batiha GE. Covid-19-Induced Dysautonomia: A Menace of Sympathetic Storm. ASN Neuro . 2021;13:17590914211057635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8586167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34755562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavallieri F, Sellner J, Zedde M, Moro E. Neurologic complications of coronavirus and other respiratory viral infections. Handb Clin Neurol . 2022;189:331&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9418023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36031313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostanc&#x131;kl&#x131;o&#x11f;lu M. Temporal Correlation Between Neurological and Gastrointestinal Symptoms of SARS-CoV-2. Inflamm Bowel Dis . 2020;26:e89&#x2013;e91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7313997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32440692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y, Li Z, Yang C, Liu C. The role of gut-brain axis in SARA-CoV-2 neuroinvasion: Culprit or innocent bystander? Brain Behav Immun . 2021;94:476&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7883713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33600935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanne JH. Covid-19: US studies show racial and ethnic disparities in long covid. BMJ . 2023;380:535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36878599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liotta EM, Batra A, Clark JR, Shlobin NA, Hoffman SC, Orban ZS, Koralnik IJ. Frequent neurologic manifestations and encephalopathy-associated morbidity in Covid-19 patients. Ann Clin Transl Neurol . 2020;7:2221&#x2013;2230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7664279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33016619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingery JR, Safford MM, Martin P, Lau JD, Rajan M, Wehmeyer GT, Li HA, Alshak MN, Jabri A, Kofman A, Babu CS, Benitez EK, Palacardo F, Das IG, Kaylor K, Woo KM, Roberts NL, Rahiel S, Gali V, Han L, Lee J, Roszkowska N, Kim YE, Bakshi S, Hogan C, McNairy M, Pinheiro LC, Goyal P. Health Status, Persistent Symptoms, and Effort Intolerance One Year After Acute COVID-19 Infection. J Gen Intern Med . 2022;37:1218&#x2013;1225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35075531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoucri SM, Purpura L, DeLaurentis C, Adan MA, Theodore DA, Irace AL, Robbins-Juarez SY, Khedagi AM, Letchford D, Harb AA, Zerihun LM, Lee KE, Gambina K, Lauring MC, Chen N, Sperring CP, Mehta SS, Myers EL, Shih H, Argenziano MG, Bruce SL, Slater CL, Tiao JR, Natarajan K, Hripcsak G, Chen R, Yin MT, Sobieszczyk ME, Castor D, Zucker JE. Characterising the long-term clinical outcomes of 1190 hospitalised patients with COVID-19 in New York City: a retrospective case series. BMJ Open . 2021;11:e049488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8182750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34083350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Foer D, MacPhaul E, Lo YC, Bates DW, Zhou L. PASCLex: A comprehensive post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) symptom lexicon derived from electronic health record clinical notes. J Biomed Inform . 2022;125:103951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8590503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34785382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sneller MC, Liang CJ, Marques AR, Chung JY, Shanbhag SM, Fontana JR, Raza H, Okeke O, Dewar RL, Higgins BP, Tolstenko K, Kwan RW, Gittens KR, Seamon CA, McCormack G, Shaw JS, Okpali GM, Law M, Trihemasava K, Kennedy BD, Shi V, Justement JS, Buckner CM, Blazkova J, Moir S, Chun TW, Lane HC. A Longitudinal Study of COVID-19 Sequelae and Immunity: Baseline Findings. Ann Intern Med . 2022;175:969&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9128805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35605238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs LG, Gourna Paleoudis E, Lesky-Di Bari D, Nyirenda T, Friedman T, Gupta A, Rasouli L, Zetkulic M, Balani B, Ogedegbe C, Bawa H, Berrol L, Qureshi N, Aschner JL. Persistence of symptoms and quality of life at 35 days after hospitalization for COVID-19 infection. PLoS One . 2020;15:e0243882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7732078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go&#xeb;rtz YMJ, Van Herck M, Delbressine JM, Vaes AW, Meys R, Machado FVC, Houben-Wilke S, Burtin C, Posthuma R, Franssen FME, van Loon N, Hajian B, Spies Y, Vijlbrief H, van 't Hul AJ, Janssen DJA, Spruit MA. Persistent symptoms 3 months after a SARS-CoV-2 infection: the post-COVID-19 syndrome? ERJ Open Res . 2020;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llorens S, Nava E, Mu&#xf1;oz-L&#xf3;pez M, S&#xe1;nchez-Larsen &#xc1;, Segura T. Neurological Symptoms of COVID-19: The Zonulin Hypothesis. Front Immunol . 2021;12:665300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8107207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33981312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebrahim Nakhli R, Shanker A, Sarosiek I, Boschman J, Espino K, Sigaroodi S, Al Bayati I, Elhanafi S, Sadeghi A, Sarosiek J, Zuckerman MJ, Rezaie A, McCallum RW, Schmulson MJ, Bashashati A, Bashashati M. Gastrointestinal symptoms and the severity of COVID-19: Disorders of gut-brain interaction are an outcome. Neurogastroenterol Motil . 2022;34:e14368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35383423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Z, Xiao Y, Kang L, Ma W, Shi L, Zhang L, Zhou Z, Yang J, Zhong J, Yang D, Guo L, Zhang G, Li H, Xu Y, Chen M, Gao Z, Wang J, Ren L, Li M. Corrigendum to: Genomic Diversity of Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome-Coronavirus 2 in Patients With Coronavirus Disease 2019. Clin Infect Dis . 2021;73:2374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8689987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34791120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogariu AM, Dumitrascu DL. Digestive involvement in the Long-COVID syndrome. Med Pharm Rep . 2022;95:5&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9177081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35720240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, Villapol S. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep . 2021;11:16144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, Walshaw C, Kemp S, Corrado J, Singh R, Collins T, O'Connor RJ, Sivan M. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol . 2021;93:1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein S, Davis F, Berman A, Koti S, D'Angelo J, Kwon N. A Case Report of Coronavirus Disease 2019 Presenting with Tremors and Gait Disturbance. Clin Pract Cases Emerg Med . 2020;4:324&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7434239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32926677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>