<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38086949</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A pilot study on the immune cell proteome of long COVID patients shows changes to physiological pathways similar to those in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>22068</StartPage><MedlinePgn>22068</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">22068</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-023-49402-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Of those infected with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), ~&#x2009;10% develop the chronic post-viral debilitating condition, long COVID (LC). Although LC is a heterogeneous condition, about half of cases have typical post-viral fatigue with onset and symptoms that are very similar to myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). A key question is whether these conditions are closely related. ME/CFS is a post-stressor fatigue condition that arises from multiple triggers. To investigate the pathophysiology of LC, a pilot study of patients (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;6) and healthy controls (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;5) has used quantitative proteomics to discover changes in peripheral blood mononuclear cell (PBMC) proteins. A principal component analysis separated all long COVID patients from healthy controls. Analysis of 3131 proteins identified 162 proteins differentially regulated, of which 37 were related to immune functions, and 21 to mitochondrial functions. Markov cluster analysis identified clusters involved in immune system processes, and two aspects of gene expression-spliceosome and transcription. These results were compared with an earlier dataset of 346 differentially regulated proteins in PBMC's from ME/CFS patients (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;9) analysed by the same methodology. There were overlapping protein clusters and enriched molecular pathways particularly in immune functions, suggesting the two conditions have similar immune pathophysiology as a prominent feature, and mitochondrial functions involved in energy production were affected in both conditions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peppercorn</LastName><ForeName>Katie</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Health Sciences, Department of Biochemistry, School of Biomedical Sciences, University of Otago, Dunedin, 9016, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Edgar</LastName><ForeName>Christina D</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Health Sciences, Department of Biochemistry, School of Biomedical Sciences, University of Otago, Dunedin, 9016, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kleffmann</LastName><ForeName>Torsten</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Health Sciences, Department of Biochemistry, School of Biomedical Sciences, University of Otago, Dunedin, 9016, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tate</LastName><ForeName>Warren P</ForeName><Initials>WP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Health Sciences, Department of Biochemistry, School of Biomedical Sciences, University of Otago, Dunedin, 9016, New Zealand. warren.tate@otago.ac.nz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020543">Proteome</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015673" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fatigue Syndrome, Chronic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007963" MajorTopicYN="N">Leukocytes, Mononuclear</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020543" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014777" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38086949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10716514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-49402-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-023-49402-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: Major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2013;146. doi: 10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. WHO Coronoavirus (COVID-19) dashboard Accessed 10th May, 2023. https://covid19.who.int</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. WHO https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1: WHO REFERENCE NUMBER: WHO/2019-nCoV/Post_COVID-19_condition/Clinical_case_definition/2021.1 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, H. E., McCorkell, L., Vogel, J. M. &amp; Topol, E. J. Long COVID: Major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 1&#x2013;14 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentilotti E, G&#xf3;rska A, Tami A, Gusinow R, Mirandola M, Rodr&#xed;guez Ba&#xf1;o J, Palacios Baena ZR, Rossi E, Hasenauer J, Lopes-Rafegas I, Righi E, Caroccia N, Cataudella S, Pasquini Z, Osmo T, Del Piccolo L, Savoldi A, Kumar-Singh S, Mazzaferri F, Caponcello MG, de Boer G, Hara GL, Pinho Guedes MN, Maccarrone G, Pezzani MD, Sibani M, Davies RJ, Vitali S, Franchina G, Tomassini G, Sciammarella C, Cecchetto R, Gibellini D, De Toffoli CK, Rosini G, Perlini C, Meroi M, Puviani FC, Fasan D, Micheletto C, Montemezzi S, Cardobi N, Vantini G, Mazzali G, Stabile G, Marcanti M, Zonta MP, Cal&#xec; D, Mason A, Perlini C, Gisondi P, Mongardi M, Sorbello S, Wold KI, Vincenti-Gonz&#xe1;lez MF, Veloo ACM, Harmsma VPR, Pantano D, van der Meer M, Gard L, Lizarazo EF, Knoester M, Friedrich AW, Niesters HGM, Viale P, Marzolla D, Cosentino F, Di Chiara M, Fornaro G, Bonazzetti C, Tazza B, Toschi A, Vetamanu O, Giacomini ME, Trapani F, Marconi L, Attard L, Tedeschi S, Gabrielli L, Lazzarotto T, Olivares P, Castilla J, V&#xe9;lez J, Almadana V, Mart&#xed;n-Barrera L, Mart&#xed;n-Guti&#xe9;rrez AB, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Campos D, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Rega&#xf1;a M, Silva-Campos A, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Riejos P, Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;nchez MI, Giuliano CV, L&#xf3;pez C, Neumann G, Camporro J, de Vedia L, Agugliaro H, Scipione G, Dellacasa C, Chandramouli B, Gioiosa S, Naranjo JM, Ortali M, Konnova A, Gupta A, Smet M, Hotterbeekx A, Berkell M, Sicuri E, Bachelet D, Bouadma L, Cervantes-Gonzalez M, Chair A, Charpentier C, Chenard L, Descamps D, Doan H, Duval X, Esposito-Farese M, Hoffmann I, Kafif O, Le Hingrat Q, Letrou S, Mentr&#xe9; F, Schneider M, Tardivon C, Timsit J-F, Tubiana S, Abrous A, Couffin-Cadiergues S, Da Silva FD, Esperou H, Houas I, Jaafoura S, Papadopoulos A, Ansart S, Auvet A, Bani-Sadr F, Bernard L, Bissuel F, Botelho-Nevers E, Bouhour D, Cabi&#xe9; A, Caraux Paz P, Chidiac C, Chirouze C, Chroboczek T, Cordel H, Courtois R, De Castro N, Diamamntis S, Diehl J-L, Djossou F, Dorival C, Epaulard O, Gaborieau V, Goehringer F, Gousseff M, Jamard S, Joseph C, Lacombe K, Le Mestre S, Le Moing V, Lelievre J-D, Lesens O, Machado M, Maillet M, Manda V, Martin-Blondel G, Martinot M, Meysonnier V, Molina J-M, Oziol E, Pestre V, Piroth L, Poissy J, Rabaud C, Raffi F, Rammaert B, Rapp C, Rebaudet S, Roger P-M, Roux D, Senneville E, Tattevin P, Wiedemann A, Zucman D, De Nardo P, Malhotra S, Canziani LM, Ghosn J, Florence A-M, Lafhej N, van der Gun BTF, Giannella M, Laou&#xe9;nan C, Tacconelli E. Clinical phenotypes and quality of life to define post-COVID-19 syndrome: A cluster analysis of the multinational, prospective ORCHESTRA cohort. eClinicalMedicine. 2023;62:102107. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2023.102107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2023.102107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10466236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37654668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tate WP, Walker MOM, Peppercorn K, Blair ALH, Edgar CD. Towards a better understanding of the complexities of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome and long COVID. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2023;24(6):5124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10048882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36982194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geraghty KJ, Adeniji C. The importance of accurate diagnosis of ME/CFS in children and adolescents: A commentary. Perspective. Front. Pediatr. 2019 doi: 10.3389/fped.2018.00435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2018.00435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6348258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30719431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fainardi V, Meoli A, Chiopris G, Motta M, Skenderaj K, Grandinetti R, Bergomi A, Antodaro F, Zona S, Esposito S. Long COVID in children and adolescents. Life (Basel) 2022 doi: 10.3390/life12020285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/life12020285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8876679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35207572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman L, Bested AC, Bonilla HF, Chheda BV, Chu L, Curtin JM, Dempsey TT, Dimmock ME, Dowell TG, Felsenstein D, Kaufman DL, Klimas NG, Komaroff AL, Lapp CW, Levine SM, Montoya JG, Natelson BH, Peterson DL, Podell RN, Rey IR, Ruhoy IS, Vera-Nunez MA, Yellman BP. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: Essentials of diagnosis and management. Mayo Clin. Proc. 2021;96(11):2861&#x2013;2878. doi: 10.1016/j.mayocp.2021.07.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mayocp.2021.07.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallings, R. Chronic Fatigue Syndrome M.E. Symptoms, Diagnosis, Management (Calico Publishing, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles Shepherd, A. C. ME/CFS/PVFS&#x2014;An Exploration of the Key Clinical Issues&#x2014;New Zealand Edition 7th edn (John Eley The Printers, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL, Lipkin WI. ME/CFS and long COVID share similar symptoms and biological abnormalities: Road map to the literature. Front. Med. (Lausanne) 2023;10:1187163. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2023.1187163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2023.1187163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10278546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37342500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ME-PEDIA. List of myalgic encephalomyelitis and chronic fatigue syndrome outbreaks. Accessed 30 August 2023. https://me-pedia.org/wiki/List_of_myalgic_encephalomyelitis_and_chronic_fatigue_syndrome_outbreaks</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tate W, Walker M, Sweetman E, Helliwell A, Peppercorn K, Edgar C, Blair A, Chatterjee A. Molecular mechanisms of neuroinflammation in ME/CFS and long COVID to sustain disease and promote relapses. Front. Neurol. 2022;13:877772. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2022.877772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2022.877772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9174654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35693009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landay AL, Jessop C, Lennette ET, Levy JA. Chronic fatigue syndrome: Clinical condition associated with immune activation. Lancet. 1991;338(8769):707&#x2013;712. doi: 10.1016/0140-6736(91)91440-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0140-6736(91)91440-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1679864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL, Buchwald DS. Chronic fatigue syndrome: An update. Annu. Rev. Med. 1998;49:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1146/annurev.med.49.1.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.med.49.1.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9509246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenu EW, van Driel ML, Staines DR, Ashton KJ, Ramos SB, Keane J, Klimas NG, Marshall-Gradisnik SM. Immunological abnormalities as potential biomarkers in chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis. J. Transl. Med. 2011;9:81. doi: 10.1186/1479-5876-9-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1479-5876-9-81</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3120691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21619669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornig M, Montoya JG, Klimas NG, Levine S, Felsenstein D, Bateman L, Peterson DL, Gottschalk CG, Schultz AF, Che X, Eddy ML, Komaroff AL, Lipkin WI. Distinct plasma immune signatures in ME/CFS are present early in the course of illness. Sci. Adv. 2015 doi: 10.1126/sciadv.1400121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.1400121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26079000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandarano AH, Maya J, Giloteaux L, Peterson DL, Maynard M, Gottschalk CG, Hanson MR. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients exhibit altered T cell metabolism and cytokine associations. J. Clin. Investig. 2020;130(3):1491&#x2013;1505. doi: 10.1172/JCI132185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI132185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7269566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31830003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montoya JG, Holmes TH, Anderson JN, Maecker HT, Rosenberg-Hasson Y, Valencia IJ, Chu L, Younger JW, Tato CM, Davis MM. Cytokine signature associated with disease severity in chronic fatigue syndrome patients. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2017;114(34):E7150&#x2013;E7158. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1710519114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1710519114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5576836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28760971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker MOM, Peppercorn K, Kleffmann T, Edgar CD, Tate WP. An understanding of the immune dysfunction in susceptible people who develop the post-viral fatigue syndromes myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome and long COVID. Med. Res. Arch. 2023 doi: 10.18103/mra.v11i7.1.4083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18103/mra.v11i7.1.4083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): An overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front. Microbiol. 2021;12:698169. doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2021.698169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2021.698169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulthei&#xdf; C, Willscher E, Paschold L, Gottschick C, Klee B, Henkes SS, Bosurgi L, Dutzmann J, Sedding D, Frese T, Girndt M, H&#xf6;ll JI, Gekle M, Mikolajczyk R, Binder M. The IL-1&#x3b2;, IL-6, and TNF cytokine triad is associated with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Cell Rep. Med. 2022;3(6):100663. doi: 10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35732153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Queiroz MAF, Neves P, Lima SS, Lopes JDC, Torres M, Vallinoto I, Bichara CDA, Dos Santos EF, de Brito M, da Silva ALS, Leite MM, da Costa FP, Viana M, Rodrigues FBB, de Sarges KML, Cantanhede MHD, da Silva R, Bichara CNC, van den Berg AVS, Ver&#xed;ssimo AOL, Carvalho MDS, Henriques DF, Dos Santos CP, Nunes JAL, Costa IB, Viana GMR, Carneiro FRO, Palacios V, Quaresma JAS, Brasil-Costa I, Dos Santos EJM, Falc&#xe3;o LFM, Vallinoto ACR. Cytokine profiles associated with acute COVID-19 and long COVID-19 syndrome. Front. Cell. Infect. Microbiol. 2022;12:922422. doi: 10.3389/fcimb.2022.922422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcimb.2022.922422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9279918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35846757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, E. S., Martins, T. B., Shah, K. S., Hill, H. R., Coiras, M., Spivak, A. M. &amp; Planelles, V. Cytokine deficiencies in patients with long-COVID. J. Clin. Cell Immunol. 13(6) (2022)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9894377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36742994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweetman E, Ryan M, Edgar C, MacKay A, Vallings R, Tate W. Changes in the transcriptome of circulating immune cells of a New Zealand cohort with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Int. J. Immunopathol. Pharmacol. 2019;33:2058738418820402. doi: 10.1177/2058738418820402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2058738418820402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6350121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30791746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraz, A., Luyen Tien, V., Hongya, Z., David Shing Huk, I., Elizabeth, A. F., Yeonui, K., Weizhong, C., Carl, J. F., Paul, R. M., Susan, M. L., Jared, S., Xiangling, M., Dikoma, C. S., Geoffrey, E. M., Betsy, A. K., Maureen, R. H., Jennifer, K. G. &amp; Andrew, G. Single-cell transcriptomics of the immune system in ME/CFS at baseline and following symptom provocation. bioRxiv. 2022:2022.10.13.512091. 10.1101/2022.10.13.512091</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Booven DJ, Gamer J, Joseph A, Perez M, Zarnowski O, Pandya M, Collado F, Klimas N, Oltra E, Nathanson L. Stress-induced transcriptomic changes in females with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome reveal disrupted immune signatures. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2023 doi: 10.3390/ijms24032698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms24032698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9916639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36769022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweetman E, Kleffmann T, Edgar C, de Lange M, Vallings R, Tate W. A SWATH-MS analysis of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome peripheral blood mononuclear cell proteomes reveals mitochondrial dysfunction. J. Transl. Med. 2020;18(1):365. doi: 10.1186/s12967-020-02533-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-020-02533-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7512220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Guerra P, Gonzalez-Ebsen AC, Boonen SE, Courraud J, Gregersen N, Mehlsen J, Palmfeldt J, Olsen RKJ, Brinth LS. Bioenergetic and proteomic profiling of immune cells in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients: An exploratory study. Biomolecules. 2021 doi: 10.3390/biom11070961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom11070961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8301912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34209852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Germain A, Levine SM, Hanson MR. In-depth analysis of the plasma proteome in ME/CFS exposes disrupted Ephrin-Eph and immune system signaling. Proteomes. 2021 doi: 10.3390/proteomes9010006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/proteomes9010006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7931008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33572894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helliwell AM, Sweetman EC, Stockwell PA, Edgar CD, Chatterjee A, Tate WP. Changes in DNA methylation profiles of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients reflect systemic dysfunctions. Clin. Epigenetics. 2020;12(1):167. doi: 10.1186/s13148-020-00960-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13148-020-00960-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7641803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33148325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vega WC, Vernon SD, McGowan PO. DNA methylation modifications associated with chronic fatigue syndrome. PLoS One. 2014;9(8):e104757. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0104757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0104757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4128721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25111603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera S, de Vega WC, Ashbrook D, Vernon SD, McGowan PO. Genome-epigenome interactions associated with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Epigenetics. 2018;13(12):1174&#x2013;1190. doi: 10.1080/15592294.2018.1549769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15592294.2018.1549769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6986787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30516085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenu, E. W. S., D.R. &amp; Marshall-Gradisnik, S. M. Methylation profile of CD4+ T cells in chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis. J. Clin. Cell Immunol. 5(228) (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trivedi MS, Oltra E, Sarria L, Rose N, Beljanski V, Fletcher MA, Klimas NG, Nathanson L. Identification of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome-associated DNA methylation patterns. PLoS One. 2018;13(7):e0201066. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0201066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0201066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6056050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30036399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sen P, Kemppainen E, Ore&#x161;i&#x10d; M. Perspectives on systems modeling of human peripheral blood mononuclear cells. Review. Front. Mol. Biosci. 2018 doi: 10.3389/fmolb.2017.00096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmolb.2017.00096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5767226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29376056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peppercorn K, Kleffmann T, Jones O, Hughes S, Tate W. Secreted amyloid precursor protein alpha, a neuroprotective protein in the brain has widespread effects on the transcriptome and proteome of human inducible pluripotent stem cell-derived glutamatergic neurons related to memory mechanisms. Front. Neurosci. 2022;16:858524. doi: 10.3389/fnins.2022.858524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2022.858524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9179159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35692428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peppercorn K, Kleffmann T, Hughes SM, Tate WP. Secreted Amyloid Precursor Protein Alpha (sAPP&#x3b1;) Regulates the Cellular Proteome and Secretome of Mouse Primary Astrocytes. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2023 doi: 10.3390/ijms24087165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms24087165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10138557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37108327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szklarczyk D, Kirsch R, Koutrouli M, Nastou K, Mehryary F, Hachilif R, Gable AL, Fang T, Doncheva Nadezhda T, Pyysalo S, Bork P, Jensen Lars J, von Mering C. The STRING database in 2023: Protein&#x2013;protein association networks and functional enrichment analyses for any sequenced genome of interest. Nucleic Acids Res. 2022;51(D1):D638&#x2013;D646. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkac1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkac1000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9825434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36370105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanehisa M, Goto S. KEGG: Kyoto encyclopedia of genes and genomes. Nucleic Acids Res. 2000;28(1):27&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1093/nar/28.1.27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/28.1.27</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC102409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10592173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasello E, Vivier E. KARAP/DAP12/TYROBP: Three names and a multiplicity of biological functions. Eur. J. Immunol. 2005;35(6):1670&#x2013;1677. doi: 10.1002/eji.200425932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eji.200425932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15884055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broh&#xe9;e S, van Helden J. Evaluation of clustering algorithms for protein-protein interaction networks. BMC Bioinform. 2006;7:488. doi: 10.1186/1471-2105-7-488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2105-7-488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1637120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17087821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rath S, Sharma R, Gupta R, Ast T, Chan C, Durham TJ, Goodman RP, Grabarek Z, Haas ME, Hung WHW, Joshi PR, Jourdain AA, Kim SH, Kotrys AV, Lam SS, McCoy JG, Meisel JD, Miranda M, Panda A, Patgiri A, Rogers R, Sadre S, Shah H, Skinner OS, To TL, Walker MA, Wang H, Ward PS, Wengrod J, Yuan CC, Calvo SE, Mootha VK. MitoCarta3.0: An updated mitochondrial proteome now with sub-organelle localization and pathway annotations. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021;49(D1):D1541&#x2013;d1547. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkaa1011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkaa1011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7778944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33174596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein, J., Wood, J., Jaycox, J., Peiwen, L., Dhodapkar, R. M., R JRGJ, Tabachnikova, A., L.Tabacof, Malik, A. A., Kamath, K., Greene, K., Monteiro, V. S., Pe&#xf1;a-Hernandez, M., Mao, T., Bhattacharjee, B., Takahashi, T., Lucas, C., Silva, J., Mccarthy, D., Breyman, E., Tosto-Mancuso, J., Dai, Y., Perotti, E., Akduman, K., Tiffany, J., Tzeng, T. J., Xu, L., Yildirim, I., Krumholz, H. M., Shon, J., Medzhitov, R., Omer, S. B., Dijk, D., Ring, A. M., Putrino, D. &amp; Iwasaki, A. Distinguishing features of long COVID identified through immune profiling. medRxiv. 2022:2022.08.09.22278592. 10.1101/2022.08.09.22278592</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, K., Peluso, M. J., Thomas, R., Shin, M. G., Neidleman, J., Luo, X., Hoh, R., Anglin, K., Huang, B., Argueta, U., Lopez, M., Valdivieso, D., Asare, K., Ibrahim, R., St&#xe4;ndker, L., Lu, S., Goldberg, S. A., Lee, S. A., Lynch, K. L., Kelly, J. D., Martin, J. N., M&#xfc;nch, J., Deeks, S. G., Henrich, T. J. &amp; Roan, N. R. Long COVID manifests with T cell dysregulation, inflammation, and an uncoordinated adaptive immune response to SARS-CoV-2. bioRxiv. 10.1101/2023.02.09.527892 (2023)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan FJ, Hope CM, Masavuli MG, Lynn MA, Mekonnen ZA, Yeow AEL, Garcia-Valtanen P, Al-Delfi Z, Gummow J, Ferguson C, O'Connor S, Reddi BAJ, Hissaria P, Shaw D, Kok-Lim C, Gleadle JM, Beard MR, Barry SC, Grubor-Bauk B, Lynn DJ. Long-term perturbation of the peripheral immune system months after SARS-CoV-2 infection. BMC Med. 2022;20(1):26. doi: 10.1186/s12916-021-02228-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-021-02228-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8758383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P, Tahmasebi N, Gant V, Gupta R. Long COVID following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: Characteristic T cell alterations and response to antihistamines. J. Investig. Med. 2022;70(1):61&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1136/jim-2021-002051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jim-2021-002051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8494538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB, Howe A, Munier CML, Patel SK, Juno JA, Burrell LM, Kent SJ, Dore GJ, Kelleher AD, Matthews GV. Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat. Immunol. 2022;23(2):210&#x2013;216. doi: 10.1038/s41590-021-01113-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-021-01113-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordquist, H. &amp; Jamil, R. T. Biochemistry, HLA Antigens. StatPearls. StatPearls Publishing. Copyright &#xa9; 2023, StatPearls Publishing LLC. (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31536268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B, Shao Y, Fu R. Current research status of HLA in immune-related diseases. Immun. Inflamm. Dis. 2021;9(2):340&#x2013;350. doi: 10.1002/iid3.416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/iid3.416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8127548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks AG, Borrego F, Posch PE, Patamawenu A, Scorzelli CJ, Ulbrecht M, Weiss EH, Coligan JE. Specific recognition of HLA-E, but not classical, HLA class I molecules by soluble CD94/NKG2A and NK cells. J. Immunol. 1999;162(1):305&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Monaco E, Tremante E, Cerboni C, Melucci E, Sibilio L, Zingoni A, Nicotra MR, Natali PG, Giacomini P. Human leukocyte antigen E contributes to protect tumor cells from lysis by natural killer cells. Neoplasia. 2011;13(9):822&#x2013;830. doi: 10.1593/neo.101684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1593/neo.101684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21969815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Su G, Gao J, Tian Y, Liu X, Zhang Z. Effects of peroxiredoxin 2 in neurological disorders: A review of its molecular mechanisms. Neurochem. Res. 2020;45(4):720&#x2013;730. doi: 10.1007/s11064-020-02971-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11064-020-02971-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32002772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demarquoy J, Le Borgne F. Crosstalk between mitochondria and peroxisomes. World J. Biol. Chem. 2015;6(4):301&#x2013;309. doi: 10.4331/wjbc.v6.i4.301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4331/wjbc.v6.i4.301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4657118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26629313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che X, Brydges CR, Yu Y, Price A, Joshi S, Roy A, Lee B, Barupal DK, Cheng A, Palmer DM, Levine S, Peterson DL, Vernon SD, Bateman L, Hornig M, Montoya JG, Komaroff AL, Fiehn O, Lipkin WI. Metabolomic evidence for peroxisomal dysfunction in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2022 doi: 10.3390/ijms23147906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23147906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9320121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35887252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanazawa N, Hemmi H, Kinjo N, Ohnishi H, Hamazaki J, Mishima H, Kinoshita A, Mizushima T, Hamada S, Hamada K, Kawamoto N, Kadowaki S, Honda Y, Izawa K, Nishikomori R, Tsumura M, Yamashita Y, Tamura S, Orimo T, Ozasa T, Kato T, Sasaki I, Fukuda-Ohta Y, Wakaki-Nishiyama N, Inaba Y, Kunimoto K, Okada S, Taketani T, Nakanishi K, Murata S, Yoshiura KI, Kaisho T. Heterozygous missense variant of the proteasome subunit &#x3b2;-type 9 causes neonatal-onset autoinflammation and immunodeficiency. Nat. Commun. 2021;12(1):6819. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-27085-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-27085-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8613290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34819510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfaro E, D&#xed;az-Garc&#xed;a E, Garc&#xed;a-Tovar S, Zamarr&#xf3;n E, Mangas A, Galera R, L&#xf3;pez-Collazo E, Garc&#xed;a-Rio F, Cubillos-Zapata C. Upregulated proteasome subunits in COVID-19 patients: A link with hypoxemia lymphopenia and inflammation. Biomolecules. 2022 doi: 10.3390/biom12030442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom12030442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8946050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35327634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr JR, Petty R, Burke B, Gough J, Fear D, Sinclair LI, Mattey DL, Richards SC, Montgomery J, Baldwin DA, Kellam P, Harrison TJ, Griffin GE, Main J, Enlander D, Nutt DJ, Holgate ST. Gene expression subtypes in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis. J. Infect. Dis. 2008;197(8):1171&#x2013;1184. doi: 10.1086/533453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/533453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18462164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoothoff J, Gleason K, McManimen S, Thorpe T, Jason LA. Subtyping patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME) and chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS) by course of illness. J. Biosens. Biomark. Diagn. 2017 doi: 10.15226/2575-6303/2/1/00113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15226/2575-6303/2/1/00113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5710812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29204592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nacul L, O'Boyle S, Palla L, Nacul FE, Mudie K, Kingdon CC, Cliff JM, Clark TG, Dockrell HM, Lacerda EM. How myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) progresses: The natural history of ME/CFS. Front. Neurol. 2020;11:826. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2020.00826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2020.00826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7431524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32849252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murga I, Aranburu L, Gargiulo PA, G&#xf3;mez Esteban JC, Lafuente JV. Clinical heterogeneity in ME/CFS. A way to understand long-COVID19 fatigue. Front. Psychiatry. 2021;12:735784. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2021.735784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2021.735784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8542754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34707521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carruthers BM, Jain AK, De Meirleir KL, Peterson DL, Klimas NG, Lerner AM, Bested AC, Flor-Henry P, Joshi P, Powles ACP, Sherkey JA, van de Sande MI. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. J. Chronic Fatigue Syndr. 2003;11(1):7&#x2013;115. doi: 10.1300/J092v11n01_02.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1300/J092v11n01_02</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carruthers BM, van de Sande MI, De Meirleir KL, Klimas NG, Broderick G, Mitchell T, Staines D, Powles ACP, Speight N, Vallings R, Bateman L, Baumgarten-Austrheim B, Bell DS, Carlo-Stella N, Chia J, Darragh A, Jo D, Lewis D, Light AR, Marshall-Gradisnik S, Mena I, Mikovits JA, Miwa K, Murovska M, Pall ML, Stevens S. Myalgic encephalomyelitis: International consensus criteria. J. Intern. Med. 2011;270(4):327&#x2013;338. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2796.2011.02428.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2796.2011.02428.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3427890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21777306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>