<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37881207</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1177-9322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Bioinformatics and biology insights</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Bioinform Biol Insights</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrated Transcriptomics and Network Analysis of Potential Mechanisms and Health Effects of Convalescent COVID-19 Patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>11779322231206684</StartPage><MedlinePgn>11779322231206684</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11779322231206684</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/11779322231206684</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Coronaviral disease 2019 (COVID-19) is a recent pandemic disease caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2). Currently, there are still cases of COVID-19 around the world that can develop into persistent symptoms after discharge. The constellation of symptoms, termed long COVID, persists for months and can lead to various diseases such as lung inflammation and cardiovascular disease, which may lead to considerable financial burden and possible risk to human health. Moreover, the molecular mechanisms underlying the post-pandemic syndrome of COVID-19 remain unclear. In this study, we aimed to explore the molecular mechanism, disease association, and possible health risks in convalescent COVID-19 patients. Gene expression data from a human convalescent COVID-19 data set was compared with a data set from healthy normal individuals in order to identify differentially expressed genes (DEGs). To determine biological function and potential pathway alterations, the GO and KEGG databases were used to analyze the DEGs. Disease association, tissue, and organ-specific analyses were used to identify possible health effects. A total of 250 DEGs were identified between healthy and convalescent COVID-19 subjects. The biological function alterations identified revealed cytokine interactions and increased inflammation through NF-&#x3ba;B1, RELA, JUN, STAT3, and SP1. Interestingly, the most significant pathways were cytokine-cytokine receptor interaction, altered lipid metabolism, and atherosclerosis that play a crucial role in convalescent COVID-19. In addition, we also found pneumonitis, dermatitis, and autoimmune diseases. Based on our study, convalescent COVID-19 is associated with inflammation in a variety of organs that could lead to autoimmune and inflammatory diseases, as well as atherosclerosis. These findings are a first step toward fully exploring the disease mechanisms in depth to understand the relationship between post-COVID-19 infection and potential health risks. This is necessary for the development of appropriate strategies for the prevention and treatment of long COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chujan</LastName><ForeName>Suthipong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Pharmacology, Chulabhorn Research Institute, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence on Environmental Health and Toxicology (EHT), OPS, MHESI, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakareangrit</LastName><ForeName>Watanyoo</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Research Unit, Chulabhorn Research Institute, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suriyo</LastName><ForeName>Tawit</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Pharmacology, Chulabhorn Research Institute, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence on Environmental Health and Toxicology (EHT), OPS, MHESI, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Satayavivad</LastName><ForeName>Jutamaad</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Pharmacology, Chulabhorn Research Institute, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence on Environmental Health and Toxicology (EHT), OPS, MHESI, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Bioinform Biol Insights</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101467187</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1177-9322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bioinformatics analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">convalescent COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37881207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10594973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/11779322231206684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_11779322231206684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pal M, Berhanu G, Desalegn C, Kandi V. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2): an update. Cureus. 2020;12:e7423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7182166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32337143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konishi T. Mutations in SARS-CoV-2 are on the increase against the acquired immunity. PLoS ONE. 2022;17:e0271305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9273074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35816505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfortmueller CA, Spinetti T, Urman RD, Luedi MM, Schefold JC. COVID-19-associated acute respiratory distress syndrome (CARDS): current knowledge on pathophysiology and ICU treatment&#x2014;a narrative review. Best Pract Res Clin Anaesthesiol. 2021;35:351-368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7831801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34511224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Mutair A, Alhumaid S, Layqah L, et al.. Clinical outcomes and severity of acute respiratory distress syndrome in 1154 COVID-19 patients: an experience multicenter retrospective cohort study. COVID. 2022;2:1102-1115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Liu J, Zhang D, Xu Z, Ji J, Wen C. Cytokine storm in COVID-19: the current evidence and treatment strategies. Front Immunol. 2020;11:1708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7365923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32754163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murugan R, Kellum JA. Acute kidney injury: what&#x2019;s the prognosis? Nat Rev Nephrol. 2011;7:209-217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3547642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21343898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Chen C, Chen F, Lan R, Lin G, Xu Y. Bioinformatics analysis of potential pathogenesis and risk genes of immunoinflammation-promoted renal injury in severe COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2022;13:950076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9424635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36052061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan MI, Rahman MH, Islam MB, Islam MZ, Hossain MA, Moni MA. Systems biology and bioinformatics approach to identify blood based signatures molecules and drug targets of patient with COVID-19. Inform Med Unlocked. 2022;28:100840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8716147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34981034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moni MA, Quinn JMW, Sinmaz N, Summers MA. Gene expression profiling of SARS-CoV-2 infections reveal distinct primary lung cell and systemic immune infection responses that identify pathways relevant in COVID-19 disease. Brief Bioinform. 2021;22:1324-1337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7799202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33333559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ENCODE Project Consortium, Birney E, Stamatoyannopoulos JA, et al.. Identification and analysis of functional elements in 1% of the human genome by the ENCODE pilot project. Nature. 2007;447:799-816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2212820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17571346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barab&#xe1;si AL, Gulbahce N, Loscalzo J. Network medicine: a network-based approach to human disease. Nat Rev Genet. 2011;12:56-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3140052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21164525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Li R, Cheng J, Zhen P. Transcriptome analysis of peripheral blood mononuclear cells response in patients with severe COVID-19 reveals crucial genes regulating protein ubiquitination. Med Sci Monit. 2022;28:e937532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9438463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36031751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gedda MR, Danaher P, Shao L, et al.. Longitudinal transcriptional analysis of peripheral blood leukocytes in COVID-19 convalescent donors. J Transl Med. 2022;20:587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9742656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36510222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis S, Meltzer PS. GEOquery: a bridge between the gene expression omnibus (GEO) and BioConductor. Bioinformatics. 2007;23:1846-1847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17496320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis G, Jr, Sherman BT, Hosack DA, et al.. DAVID: database for annotation, visualization, and integrated discovery. Genome Biol. 2003;4:P3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12734009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szklarczyk D, Gable AL, Nastou KC, et al.. The STRING database in 2021: customizable protein-protein networks, and functional characterization of user-uploaded gene/measurement sets. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021;49:D605-D612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7779004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33237311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon P, Markiel A, Ozier O, et al.. Cytoscape: a software environment for integrated models of biomolecular interaction networks. Genome Res. 2003;13:2498-2504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC403769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14597658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pi&#xf1;ero J, Bravo &#xc0;, Queralt-Rosinach N, et al.. DisGeNET: a comprehensive platform integrating information on human disease associated genes and variants. Nucleic Acids Res. 2017;45:D833-D839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5210640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27924018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Zhou B, Pache L, et al.. Metascape provides a biologist oriented resource for the analysis of systems-level datasets. Nat Commun. 2019;10:1523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6447622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30944313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin CH, Chen SH, Wu HH, Ho CW, Ko MT, Lin CY. CytoHubba: identifying hub objects and sub-networks from complex interactome. BMC Syst Biol. 2014;8:S11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4290687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25521941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han H, Cho JW, Lee S, et al.. TRRUST v2: an expanded reference database of human and mouse transcriptional regulatory interactions. Nucleic Acids Res. 2018;46:D380-D386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5753191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29087512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong N, Wang X. miRDB: an online resource for microRNA target prediction and functional annotations. Nucleic Acids Res. 2015;43:D146-D152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4383922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25378301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CC, Shih TP, Ko WC, Tang HJ, Hsueh PR. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) and coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19): the epidemic and the challenges. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2020;55:105924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7127800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32081636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaim S, Chong JH, Sankaranarayanan V, Harky A. COVID-19 and multiorgan response. Curr Probl Cardiol. 2020;45:100618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32439197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Alberts J, et al.. Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e048391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng H, Tang TX, Chen D, Tang LS, Yang XP, Tang ZH. Endothelial dysfunction and SARS-CoV-2 infection: association and therapeutic strategies. Pathogens. 2021;10:582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8151812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34064553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tessmer MS, Fatima A, Paget C, Trottein F, Brossay L. NKT cell immune responses to viral infection. Expert Opin Ther Targets. 2009;13:153-162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2921843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19236234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabaan AA, Al-Ahmed SH, Muhammad J, et al.. Role of inflammatory cytokines in COVID-19 patients: a review on molecular mechanisms, immune functions, immunopathology and immunomodulatory drugs to counter cytokine storm. Vaccines (Basel). 2021;9:436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8145892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33946736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thepmankorn P, Bach J, Lasfar A, et al.. Cytokine storm induced by SARS-CoV-2 infection: the spectrum of its neurological manifestations. Cytokine. 2021;138:155404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33360025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darif D, Hammi I, Kihel A, El Idrissi Saik I, Guessous F, Akarid K. The pro-inflammatory cytokines in COVID-19 pathogenesis: what goes wrong? Microb Pathog. 2021;153:104799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7889464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33609650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Declercq J, De Leeuw E, Lambrecht BN. Inflammasomes and IL-1 family cytokines in SARS-CoV-2 infection: from prognostic marker to therapeutic agent. Cytokine. 2022;157:155934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9170572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35709568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung SS, Wu Y, Okobi Q, et al.. Proinflammatory cytokines IL-6 and TNF-&#x3b1; increased telomerase activity through NF-&#x3ba;B/STAT1/STAT3 activation, and withaferin A inhibited the signaling in colorectal cancer cells. Mediators Inflamm. 2017;2017:5958429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5476880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28676732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinarello CA, Novick D, Kim S, Kaplanski G. Interleukin-18 and IL-18 binding protein. Front Immunol. 2013;4:289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3792554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24115947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei Y, Liu H. IL-37: an anti-inflammatory cytokine with antitumor functions. Cancer Rep (Hoboken). 2019;2:e1151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7941439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32935478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang DI, Lee AH, Shin HY, et al.. The role of tumor necrosis factor alpha (TNF-&#x3b1;) in autoimmune disease and current TNF-&#x3b1; inhibitors in therapeutics. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:2719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7962638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33800290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parameswaran N, Patial S. Tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1; signaling in macrophages. Crit Rev Eukaryot Gene Expr. 2010;20:87-103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3066460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21133840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holbrook J, Lara-Reyna S, Jarosz-Griffiths H, McDermott M. Tumour necrosis factor signalling in health and disease. F1000Res. 2019;88:F1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6352924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30755793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y, Hu K, Li Y, et al.. Targeting TNF-&#x3b1; for COVID-19: recent advanced and controversies. Front Public Health. 2022;10:833967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8873570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35223745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hariharan A, Hakeem AR, Radhakrishnan S, Reddy MS, Rela M. The role and therapeutic potential of NF-kappa-B pathway in severe COVID-19 patients. Inflammopharmacology. 2021;29:91-100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7648206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33159646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillaiyar T, Laufer S. Kinases as potential therapeutic targets for anti-coronaviral therapy. J Med Chem. 2022;65:955-982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34081439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nan Y, Wu C, Zhang YJ. Interplay between Janus Kinase signal transducer and activator of transcription signaling activated by type I interferons and viral antagonism. Front Immunol. 2017;8:1758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5732261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29312301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson DE, O&#x2019;Keefe RA, Grandis JR. Targeting the IL-6/JAK/STAT3 signaling axis in cancer. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2018;15:234-248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5858971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29405201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsoukkary SS, Mostyka M, Dillard A, et al.. Autopsy findings in 32 patients with COVID-19: a single-institution experience. Pathobiology. 2021;88: 56-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32942274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholami M, Larijani B, Zahedi Z, et al.. Inflammation related miRNAs as an important player between obesity and cancers. J Diabetes Metab Disord. 2019;18:675-692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6915181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31890692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao J, Zhao X, Tao J. C-MYC-miRNA circuitry: a central regulator of aggressive B-cell malignancies. Cell Cycle. 2014;13:191-198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3906236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24394940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ott G, Rosenwald A, Campo E. Understanding MYC-driven aggressive B-cell lymphomas: pathogenesis and classification. Blood. 2013;122:3884-3891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24009228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malekmohammad K, Bezsonov EE, Rafieian-Kopaei M. Role of lipid accumulation and inflammation in atherosclerosis: focus on molecular and cellular mechanisms. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2021;8:707529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34552965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surma S, Banach M, Lewek J. COVID-19 and lipids. the role of lipid disorders and statin use in the prognosis of patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Lipids Health Dis. 2021;20:141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8542506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34689776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Deng H, Cui H, et al.. Inflammatory responses and inflammation-associated diseases in organs. Oncotarget. 2017;9:7204-7218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5805548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29467962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cioccari L, Luethi N, Masoodi M. Lipid mediators in critically ill patients: a step towards precision medicine. Front Immunol. 2020;11:599853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7724037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33324417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang DX, Liu H, Yan LR, et al.. The relationship between serum amyloid A and apolipoprotein A-I in high-density lipoprotein isolated from patients with coronary heart disease. Chin Med J (Engl). 2013;126:3656-3661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24112159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barter PJ, Nicholls S, Rye KA, Anantharamaiah GM, Navab M, Fogelman AM. Antiinflammatory properties of HDL. Circ Res. 2004;95:764-772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15486323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamialahmadi T, Baratzadeh F, Reiner &#x17d;, et al.. The effects of statin therapy on oxidized LDL and its antibodies: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2022;2022:7850659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9359854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35958018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cococcia S, Lenti MV, Santacroce G, et al.. Liver-spleen axis dysfunction in COVID-19. World J Gastroenterol. 2021;27:5919-5931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8475007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34629809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Cleemput J, van Snippenberg W, Lambrechts L, et al.. Organ-specific genome diversity of replication-competent SARS-CoV-2. Nat Commun. 2021;12:6612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8595628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34785663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian JY, Wang B, Lv LL, Liu BC. Pathogenesis of acute kidney injury in coronavirus disease 2019. Front Physiol. 2021;12:586589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7928360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33679428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk LE, Binkhorst M, Bourgonje AR, et al.. COVID-19: immunopathology, pathophysiological mechanisms, and treatment options. J Pathol. 2021;254:307-331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33586189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>