<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37288652</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A systematic review and meta-analysis of long-term sequelae of COVID-19 2-year after SARS-CoV-2 infection: A call to action for neurological, physical, and psychological sciences.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e28852</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e28852</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.28852</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long-term sequelae conditions of COVID-19 at least 2-year following SARS-CoV-2 infection are unclear and little is known about their prevalence, longitudinal trajectory, and potential risk factors. Therefore, we conducted a comprehensive meta-analysis of survivors' health-related consequences and sequelae at 2-year following SARS-CoV-2 infection. PubMed/MEDLINE, CENTRAL, and EMBASE were systematically searched up to February 10, 2023. A systematic review and meta-analysis were performed to calculate the pooled effect size, expressed as event rate (ER) with corresponding 95% confidence interval (CI) of each outcome. Twelve studies involving 1&#x2009;289&#x2009;044 participants from 11 countries were included. A total of 41.7% of COVID-19 survivors experienced at least one unresolved symptom and 14.1% were unable to return to work at 2-year after SARS-CoV-2 infection. The most frequent symptoms and investigated findings at 2-year after SARS-CoV-2 infection were fatigue (27.4%; 95% CI 17%-40.9%), sleep difficulties (25.1%; 95% CI 22.4%-27.9%), impaired diffusion capacity for carbon monoxide (24.6%; 95% CI 10.8%-46.9%), hair loss (10.2%; 95% CI 7.3%-14.2%), and dyspnea (10.1%; 95% CI 4.3%-21.9%). Individuals with severe infection suffered more from anxiety (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.69, 95% CI 1.17-2.44) and had more impairments in forced vital capacity (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;9.70, 95% CI 1.94-48.41), total lung capacity (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.51, 95% CI 1.77-6.99), and residual volume (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.35, 95% CI 1.85-6.07) after recovery. Existing evidence suggest that participants with a higher risk of long-term sequelae were older, mostly female, had pre-existing medical comorbidities, with more severe status, underwent corticosteroid therapy, and higher inflammation at acute infection. Our findings suggest that 2-year after recovery from SARS-CoV-2 infection, 41.7% of survivors still suffer from either neurological, physical, and psychological sequela. These findings indicate that there is an urgent need to preclude persistent or emerging long-term sequelae and provide intervention strategies to reduce the risk of long COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rahmati</LastName><ForeName>Masoud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4792-027X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Faculty of Literature and Human Sciences, Lorestan University, Khoramabad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Udeh</LastName><ForeName>Raphael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, Faculty of Science, University of Technology Sydney, Ultimo, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yon</LastName><ForeName>Dong Keon</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1628-9948</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Digital Health, Medical Science Research Institute, Kyung Hee University Medical Center, Kyung Hee University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Kyung Hee University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Seung Won</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5632-5208</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Precision Medicine, Sungkyunkwan University College of Medicine, Suwon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dolja-Gore</LastName><ForeName>Xenia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McEVoy</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>La Trobe Rural Health School, College of Science, Health and Engineering, La Trobe University, Bendigo, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kenna</LastName><ForeName>Tony</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Immunology &amp; Infection Control, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacob</LastName><ForeName>Louis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development Unit, Parc Sanitari Sant Joan de D&#xe9;u, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n Biom&#xe9;dica en Red de Salud Mental (CIBERSAM), ISCIII, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Lariboisi&#xe8;re-Fernand Widal Hospital, AP-HP, Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xf3;pez S&#xe1;nchez</LastName><ForeName>Guillermo F</ForeName><Initials>GF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9897-5273</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Preventive Medicine and Public Health, Department of Public Health Sciences, School of Medicine, University of Murcia, Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koyanagi</LastName><ForeName>Ai</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development Unit, Parc Sanitari Sant Joan de D&#xe9;u, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n Biom&#xe9;dica en Red de Salud Mental (CIBERSAM), ISCIII, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituci&#xf3; Catalana de Recerca i Estudis Avan&#xe7;ats (ICREA), Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Jae Il</ForeName><Initials>JI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2326-1820</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Lee</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Health, Performance, and Wellbeing, Anglia Ruskin University, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7U1EE4V452</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002248">Carbon Monoxide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002248" MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon Monoxide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevalence</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37288652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kim SY, Yeniova A&#xd6;. Global, regional, and national incidence and mortality of COVID-19 in 237 countries and territories, January 2022: a systematic analysis for World Health Organization COVID-19 dashboard. Life Cycle. 2022;2:e10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Normile D. China is flying blind as the pandemic rages. Science. 2023;379(6627):11-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Li X, Gu X, et al. Health outcomes in people 2 years after surviving hospitalisation with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10(9):863-876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):16144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, et al. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6(9):e005427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q, Zheng B, Daines L, Sheikh A. Long-term sequelae of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of one-year follow-up studies on post-COVID symptoms. Pathogens. 2022;11(2):269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Cancela-Cilleruelo I, et al. Post-COVID-19 symptoms 2 years after SARS-CoV-2 infection among hospitalized vs nonhospitalized patients. JAMA netw open. 2022;5(11):e2242106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker-Davies RM, O'Sullivan O, Senaratne KPP, et al. The Stanford Hall consensus statement for post-COVID-19 rehabilitation. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(16):949-959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceravolo MG, Arienti C, de Sire A, et al. Rehabilitation and COVID-19: the Cochrane Rehabilitation 2020 rapid living systematic review. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2020;56(5):642-651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ, Liu S. Proposed subtypes of post-COVID-19 syndrome (or long-COVID) and their respective potential therapies. Rev Med Virol. 2022;32(4):e2315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SW, Koo MJ. PRISMA 2020 statement and guidelines for systematic review and meta-analysis articles, and their underlying mathematics: life cycle committee recommendations. Life Cycle. 2022;2:e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksen MB, Frandsen TF. The impact of patient, intervention, comparison, outcome (PICO) as a search strategy tool on literature search quality: a systematic review. J Med Libr Assoc. 2018;106(4):420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stang A. Critical evaluation of the Newcastle-Ottawa scale for the assessment of the quality of nonrandomized studies in meta-analyses. Eur J Epidemiol. 2010;25(9):603-605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SW. Methods for testing statistical differences between groups in medical research: statistical standard and guideline of Life Cycle Committee. Life Cycle. 2022;2:e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Y, Zhao W, Huang S, et al. Two-year follow-up of brain structural changes in patients who recovered from COVID-19: a prospective study. Psychiatry Res. 2023;319:114969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helmsdal G, Hanusson DK, Kristiansen DF, et al. Long COVID in the long run-23-month follow-up study of persistent symptoms. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2022;9(7):ofac270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S, Zhou X, Zhao W, et al. Dynamic white matter changes in recovered COVID-19 patients: a two-year follow-up study. Theranostics. 2023;13(2):724-735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Liao X, Liu Z, et al. Healthy outcomes of patients with COVID-19 two years after the infection: a prospective cohort study. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2022;11(1):2680-2688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet C, Narvaneni S, Roman S, et al. Symptoms persist in patients two years after COVID-19 infection: a prospective follow-up study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28(11):1505-1507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Sillett R, Zhu L, et al. Neurological and psychiatric risk trajectories after SARS-CoV-2 infection: an analysis of 2-year retrospective cohort studies including 1 284 437 patients. Lancet Psychiatry. 2022;9(10):815-827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herridge MS, Tansey CM, Matt&#xe9; A, et al. Functional disability 5 years after acute respiratory distress syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2011;364(14):1293-1304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JY, Zong XY, Wu GH, et al. 3-to 24-month follow-up on COVID-19 with pulmonary tuberculosis survivors after discharge: results from a prospective, multicenter study. Biomed Environ Sci. 2022;35(12):1091-1099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Hou C, Shen Y, et al. Two-year health outcomes in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors in China. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(9):e2231790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Li X, Huang L, et al. Lung-function trajectories in COVID-19 survivors after discharge: a two-year longitudinal cohort study. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;54:101668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Wambeke E, Bezler C, Kasprowicz AM, Charles AL, Andres E, Geny B. Two-years follow-up of symptoms and return to work in complex post-COVID-19 patients. J Clin Med. 2023;12(3):741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Sullivan O. Long-term sequelae following previous coronavirus epidemics. Clin Med. 2021;21(1):e68-e70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tansey CM, Louie M, Loeb M, et al. One-year outcomes and health care utilization in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome. Arch Intern Med. 2007;167(12):1312-1320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam MH-B, Wing YK, Yu MW, et al. Mental morbidities and chronic fatigue in severe acute respiratory syndrome survivors: long-term follow-up. Arch Intern Med. 2009;169(22):2142-2147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boldrini M, Canoll PD, Klein RS. How COVID-19 affects the brain. JAMA psychiatry. 2021;78(6):682-683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellul MA, Benjamin L, Singh B, et al. Neurological associations of COVID-19. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19(9):767-783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgul E, Bener A, Atak M, et al. COVID-19 pandemic and psychological fatigue in Turkey. Int J Soc Psychiatry. 2021;67(2):128-135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi L, Lu ZA, Que JY, et al. Prevalence of and risk factors associated with mental health symptoms among the general population in China during the coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3(7):e2014053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Shi L, Que J, et al. The impact of quarantine on mental health status among general population in China during the COVID-19 pandemic. Mol Psychiatry. 2021;26(9):4813-4822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alimoradi Z, Brostr&#xf6;m A, Tsang HWH, et al. Sleep problems during COVID-19 pandemic and its' association to psychological distress: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;36:100916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin C-Y, Brostr&#xf6;m A, Griffiths MD, Pakpour AH. Investigating mediated effects of fear of COVID-19 and COVID-19 misunderstanding in the association between problematic social media use, psychological distress, and insomnia. Internet Interv. 2020;21:100345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broughan J, McCombe G, O'Kelly B, et al. Mental health and alcohol use among patients attending a post-COVID-19 follow-up clinic: a cohort study. HRB Open Research. 2022;5:16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britton A, Fat LN, Neligan A. The association between alcohol consumption and sleep disorders among older people in the general population. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):5275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung AM, Tansey CM, Tomlinson G, et al. Two-year outcomes, health care use, and costs of survivors of acute respiratory distress syndrome. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2006;174(5):538-544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herridge MS, Cheung AM, Tansey CM, et al. One-year outcomes in survivors of the acute respiratory distress syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2003;348(8):683-693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojo AS, Balogun SA, Williams OT, Ojo OS. Pulmonary fibrosis in COVID-19 survivors: predictive factors and risk reduction strategies. Pulm Med. 2020;2020:6175964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng N, Zhao YM, Yan W, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of long term physical and mental sequelae of COVID-19 pandemic: call for research priority and action. Mol Psychiatry. 2023;28(1):423-433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Pinto MD, Borelli JL, et al. COVID symptoms, symptom clusters, and predictors for becoming a Long-Hauler looking for clarity in the haze of the pandemic. Clin Nurs Res. 2022;31(8):1390-1398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Sire A, Moggio L, Marotta N, et al. Impact of rehabilitation on fatigue in post-COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Appl Sci. 2022;12(17):8593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133-146.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>