<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35797144</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-6963</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in rheumatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Complications of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection in children.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>267</StartPage><EndPage>273</EndPage><MedlinePgn>267-273</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/BOR.0000000000000892</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Although during the initial stages of COVID-19 pandemic, the pediatric population seemed to be less affected, a number of SARS-CoV-2-related manifestations emerged over time, the principal of which is the multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C). Here we provide an update on the main pediatric disorders associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">MIS-C is novel postinfectious manifestation with clinical features similar to Kawasaki disease and characterized by intense systemic inflammation affecting multiple organs. Many children required intensive care therapy because of circulatory shock, usually of myocardial origin. Appropriate treatment with immunomodulatory therapies led to favorable outcomes in most patients, with recovery of overall health and cardiac dysfunction. In addition to MIS-C, a variety of other complications of COVID-19 in children have been described, including thrombotic events, neurologic manifestations, and chilblain-like lesions. There is still uncertainty about the true prevalence of long COVID in children and its distinction from pandemic-related complaints.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">The experience gained so far with MIS-C and the other SARS-CoV-2-related complications in children and adolescents will facilitate accurate diagnosis and appropriate treatment. Further studies are needed to elucidate the pathophysiology of MIS-C and to determine the real impact of long-COVID in the pediatric age group.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caorsi</LastName><ForeName>Roberta</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinica Pediatrica e Reumatologia, IRCCS Istituto Giannina Gaslini, Genoa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Civino</LastName><ForeName>Adele</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UOSD Reumatologia e Immunologia Pediatrica, Ospedale Vito Fazzi, Lecce.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ravelli</LastName><ForeName>Angelo</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Direzione Scientifica, IRCCS Istituto Giannina Gaslini.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dipartimento di Neuroscienze, Riabilitazione, Oftalmologia, Genetica e Scienze Materno-Infantili (DINOGMI), Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Genova, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Rheumatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9000851</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1040-8711</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C000705967">pediatric multisystem inflammatory disease, COVID-19 related</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018746" MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic Inflammatory Response Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35797144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BOR.0000000000000892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00002281-202209000-00005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, et al. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet 2020; 395:497&#x2013;506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. United States COVID-19 cases, deaths, and testing by state. Available at: https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#trends_dailycases . [Accessed 7 May 2022]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parri N, Lenge M, Buonsenso D. Coronavirus Infection in Pediatric Emergency Departments (CONFIDENCE) Research Group. Children with Covid-19 in pediatric emergency departments in Italy. N Engl J Med 2020; 383:187&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riphagen S, Gomez X, Gonzalez-Martinez C, et al. Hyperinflammatory shock in children during COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet 2020; 395:1607&#x2013;1608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdoni L, Mazza A, Gervasoni A, et al. An outbreak of severe Kawasaki-like disease at the Italian epicentre of the SARS-CoV-2 epidemic: an observational cohort study. Lancet 2020; 395:1771&#x2013;1778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiff DD, Cron RQ. Who would have predicted multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children? Curr Rheumatol Rep 2022; 24:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldstein LR, Tenforde MW, Friedman KG, et al. Overcoming COVID-19 Investigators. Characteristics and outcomes of US Children and adolescents with multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) compared with severe acute COVID-19. JAMA 2021; 325:1074&#x2013;1087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belay ED, Abrams J, Oster ME, et al. Trends in geographic and temporal distribution of US children with multisystem inflammatory syndrome during the COVID-19 pandemic. JAMA Pediatr 2021; 175:837&#x2013;845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts JE, Henderson LA. Clinical features of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children. Curr Opin Rheumatol 2021; 33:378&#x2013;386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoste L, Van Paemel R, Haerynck F. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children related to COVID-19: a systematic review. Eur J Pediatr 2021; 180:2019&#x2013;2034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne AB, Gilani Z, Godfred-Cato S, et al. Incidence of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children among US persons infected with SARS-CoV-2. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4:e2116420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son MBF, Murray N, Friedman K, et al. Overcoming COVID-19 Investigators. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children - initial therapy and outcomes. N Engl J Med 2021; 385:23&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouldali N, Toubiana J, Antona D, et al. French Covid-19 Paediatric Inflammation Consortium. Association of intravenous immunoglobulins plus methylprednisolone vs immunoglobulins alone with course of fever in multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children. JAMA 2021; 325:855&#x2013;864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villacis-Nunez DS, Jones K, Jabbar A, et al. Short-term outcomes of corticosteroid monotherapy in multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children. JAMA Pediatr 2022; 176:576&#x2013;584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brisca G, Consolaro A, Caorsi R, et al. Timely recognition and early multistep antinflammatory therapy may prevent ICU admission of patients with MIS-C: proposal for a severity score. Front Pediatr 2021; 9:783745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson LA, Canna SW, Friedman KG, et al. American College of Rheumatology clinical guidance for multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children associated with SARS-CoV-2 and yperinflammation in pediatric COVID-19: version 3. Arthritis Rheumatol 2022; 74:e1&#x2013;e20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cattalini M, Taddio A, Bracaglia C, et al. Rheumatology Study Group of the Italian Society of Pediatrics. Childhood multisystem inflammatory syndrome associated with COVID-19 (MIS-C): a diagnostic and treatment guidance from the Rheumatology Study Group of the Italian Society of Pediatrics. Ital J Pediatr 2021; 47:24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsubara D, Chang J, Kauffman HL, et al. Longitudinal assessment of cardiac outcomes of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children associated with COVID-19 infections. J Am Heart Assoc 2022; 11:e023251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowley AH. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children and Kawasaki disease: two different illnesses with overlapping clinical features. J Pediatr 2020; 224:129&#x2013;132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma C, Ganigara M, Galeotti C, et al. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children and Kawasaki disease: a critical comparison. Nat Rev Rheumatol 2021; 17:731&#x2013;748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bukulmez H. Current understanding of multisystem inflammatory syndrome (MIS-C) following COVID-19 and its distinction from Kawasaki disease. Curr Rheumatol Rep 2021; 23:58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung RS, Ferguson PJ. Is multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children on the Kawasaki syndrome spectrum? J Clin Invest 2020; 130:5681&#x2013;5684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matucci-Cerinic C, Caorsi R, Consolaro A, et al. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children: unique disease or part of the Kawasaki disease spectrum? Front Pediatr 2021; 9:680813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sancho-Shimizu V, Brodin P, Cobat A, et al. SARS-CoV-2-related MIS-C: a key to the viral and genetic causes of Kawasaki disease? J Exp Med 2021; 218:e20210446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh P, Katkar GD, Shimizu C, et al. Pediatric Emergency Medicine Kawasaki Disease Research Group. An Artificial Intelligence-guided signature reveals the shared host immune response in MIS-C and Kawasaki disease. Nat Commun 2022; 13:2687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bikdeli B, Madhavan MV, Jimenez D, et al. COVID-19 and thrombotic or thromboembolic disease: implications for prevention, antithrombotic therapy, and follow-up: JACC state-of-the-art review. J Am Coll Cardiol 2020; 75:2950&#x2013;2973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loi M, Branchford B, Kim J, et al. COVID-19 anticoagulation recommendations in children. Pediatr Blood Cancer 2020; 67:e28485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenberg NA, Sochet A, Albisetti M, et al. Pediatric/Neonatal Hemostasis and Thrombosis Subcommittee of the ISTH SSC. Consensus-Based clinical recommendations and research priorities for anticoagulant thromboprophylaxis in children hospitalized for COVID-19-related illness. J Thromb Haemost 2020; 18:3099&#x2013;3105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilera-Alonso D, Murias S, Mart&#xed;nez-de-Azagra Garde A, et al. EPICO-AEP Working Group. Prevalence of thrombotic complications in children with SARS-CoV-2. Arch Dis Child 2021; 106:1129&#x2013;1132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitworth H, Sartain SE, Kumar R, et al. Rate of thrombosis in children and adolescents hospitalized with COVID-19 or MIS-C. Blood 2021; 138:190&#x2013;198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beslow LA, Linds AB, Fox CK, et al. International Pediatric Stroke Study Group. Pediatric ischemic stroke: an infrequent complication of SARS-CoV-2. Ann Neurol 2021; 89:657&#x2013;665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaffanello M, Piacentini G, Nosetti L, et al. Thrombotic risk in children with COVID-19 infection: a systematic review of the literature. Thromb Res 2021; 205:92&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Loughlin L, Alvarez Toledo N, Budrie L, et al. A systematic review of severe neurological manifestations in pediatric patients with coexisting SARS-CoV-2 infection. Neurol Int 2021; 13:410&#x2013;427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray STJ, Abdel-Mannan O, Sa M, et al. Neurological manifestations of SARS-CoV-2 infection in hospitalised children and adolescents in the UK: a prospective national cohort study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2021; 5:631&#x2013;641. [published correction appears in Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2021 Jul 28;:].[published correction appears in Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2021 Dec;5(12):e46].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E, Zhang C, Israelow B, et al. Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 in human and mouse brain. J Exp Med 2021; 218:e20202135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink EL, Robertson CL, Wainwright MS, et al. Prevalence and risk factors of neurologic manifestations in hospitalized children diagnosed with acute SARS-CoV-2 or MIS-C. Pediatr Neurol 2022; 128:33&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan SW, Tam YC, Oh CC. Skin manifestations of COVID-19: a worldwide review. JAAD Int 2021; 2:119&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farajzadeh S, Khalili M, Dehghani S, et al. Top 10 acral skin manifestations associated with COVID-19: a scoping review. Dermatol Ther 2021; 34:e15157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassi A, Russo T, Argenziano G, et al. Chilblain-like lesions during COVID-19 pandemic: the state of the art. Life 2021; 11:23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andina D, Belloni-Fortina A, Bodemer C, et al. ESPD Group for the Skin Manifestations of COVID-19. Skin manifestations of COVID-19 in children: part 1. Clin Exp Dermatol 2021; 46:444&#x2013;450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, Bunker CB, Ciurtin C, et al. Chilblain-like acral lesions in long COVID-19: management and implications for understanding microangiopathy. Lancet Infect Dis 2021; 21:912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha KO, Zanuncio VV, Freitas BAC, Lima LM. &#x2018;COVID toes&#x2019;: a meta-analysis of case and observational studies on clinical, histopathological, and laboratory findings. Pediatr Dermatol 2021; 38:1143&#x2013;1149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suarez-Valle A, Fernandez-Nieto D, Diaz-Guimaraens B, et al. Acro-ischaemia in hospitalized COVID-19 patients. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2020; 34:e455&#x2013;e457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Signa S, Sementa AR, Coccia MC, et al. Recurrence of previous chilblain lesions during the second wave of COVID-19: can we still doubt the correlation with SARS-CoV-2? J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2021; 35:e475&#x2013;e477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021. Available at: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1 . [Accessed 13 May 2022]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Pittet LF, Curtis N. Long covid in children and adolescents. BMJ 2022; 376:o143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fainardi V, Meoli A, Chiopris G, et al. Long COVID in children and adolescents. Life 2022; 12:285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borch L, Holm M, Knudsen M, et al. Long COVID symptoms and duration in SARS-CoV-2 positive children - a nationwide cohort study. Eur J Pediatr 2022; 181:1597&#x2013;1607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikkenborg Berg S, Dam Nielsen S, Nygaard U, et al. Long COVID symptoms in SARS-CoV-2-positive adolescents and matched controls (LongCOVIDKidsDK): a national, cross-sectional study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2022; 6:240&#x2013;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Shafran R, De Stavola B, et al. CLoCk Consortium members. Long COVID and the mental and physical health of children and young people: national matched cohort study protocol (the CLoCk study). BMJ Open 2021; 11:e052838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson K, Skyrud KD, Suren P, et al. Healthcare use in 700 000 children and adolescents for six months after covid-19: before and after register based cohort study. BMJ 2022; 376:e066809.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>