<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37293829</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2173-9110</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>97</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Revista espanola de salud publica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rev Esp Salud Publica</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Evaluation of patients with long covid in the canarian population: study protocol.].</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e202306047</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The current COVID-19 pandemic has generated a relevant changes in the normal development of human performance. Some changes detected in SARS-CoV-2 infected people have to do with possible effects of the infection in the bio-psycho-social sphere. The population in the Autonomous Community of the Canary Islands has not been oblivious to it and, therefore, a need demanded by society has roared. A multicentre observational study will be carried out to assess the physical and functional status of people from the Canary Islands who, after being infected with the SARS-CoV-2 virus, suffer sequelae that persist after twelve weeks of infection. With help from the Official Association of Physiotherapists of the Canary Islands a call will be made to the population. This association will oversee the dissemination of the information and will recruit among its members the collaborating/evaluating physiotherapists, also ensuring the protection and preservation of the data to be collected. People meeting the established criteria will be referred to the more accessible collaborating centre of the canarian community, where, after a preliminary interview, participating patients will self-complete scientifically validated questionnaires, and will be subjected to different validated tests to evaluate their physical and functional status. Patients will be individually informed of the results of their evaluation, and they will receive a dossier with individualized recommendations. After this evaluation, a follow-up of the participants for up to 6 months is anticipated. Data will be recorded, analysed, and interpreted, and the results will be disseminated through conventional means of communication to society and also by attempting publication in scientific journals.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>B&#xe1;ez-Su&#xe1;rez</LastName><ForeName>An&#xed;bal</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Ciencias M&#xe9;dicas y Quir&#xfa;rgicas, Universidad de Las Palmas de Gran Canaria. Las Palmas de Gran Canaria. Espa&#xf1;a.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonz&#xe1;lez Monta&#xf1;ez</LastName><ForeName>Carolina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Rehabilitaci&#xf3;n, Hospital Universitario de Canarias. Tenerife. Espa&#xf1;a.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esparza Ferrera</LastName><ForeName>Carlos Eusebio</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Atenci&#xf3;n Primaria Tacoronte, Gerencia de Atenci&#xf3;n Primaria de Tenerife. Tenerife. Espa&#xf1;a.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dorta Mart&#xed;n</LastName><ForeName>Gara</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Rehabilitaci&#xf3;n, Hospital Universitario Nuestra Se&#xf1;ora de la Candelaria. Tenerife. Espa&#xf1;a.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quintana-Montesdeoca</LastName><ForeName>Mar&#xed;a Del Pino</ForeName><Initials>MDP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Ciencias M&#xe9;dicas y Quir&#xfa;rgicas, Universidad de Las Palmas de Gran Canaria. Las Palmas de Gran Canaria. Espa&#xf1;a.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>spa</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><VernacularTitle>Evaluaci&#xf3;n de pacientes con covid persistente en la poblaci&#xf3;n canaria: protocolo de estudio.</VernacularTitle><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Spain</Country><MedlineTA>Rev Esp Salud Publica</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9600212</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1135-5727</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Population" UI="C000724508">Canary Islanders</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064887" MajorTopicYN="N">Observational Studies as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013030" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Spain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa"><AbstractText>La pandemia actual de la COVID-19 ha generado un cambio relevante en el desarrollo habitual del desempe&#xf1;o del ser humano. Una de las consecuencias detectadas en las personas contagiadas por el virus SARS-CoV-2 tiene que ver con posibles secuelas desde el punto de vista bio-psico-social. La poblaci&#xf3;n en la comunidad aut&#xf3;noma canaria no ha sido ajena a ello y, por ende, ha surgido una necesidad demandada por la sociedad. Se llevar&#xe1; a cabo un estudio observacional multic&#xe9;ntrico para evaluar el estado f&#xed;sico funcional de personas de la comunidad canaria que, tras ser contagiadas por el SARS-CoV-2, padecen secuelas que persisten tras doce semanas del contagio. Se har&#xe1; un llamamiento a la poblaci&#xf3;n con la colaboraci&#xf3;n del Colegio Oficial de Fisioterapeutas de Canarias, que se encargar&#xe1; de la divulgaci&#xf3;n de la informaci&#xf3;n, as&#xed; como de establecer el contacto con los fisioterapeutas que colaboradore/eval&#xfa;en, y de preservar y proteger los datos que se registren. A aquellas personas que re&#xfa;nan los criterios establecidos se les derivar&#xe1; al centro colaborador m&#xe1;s accesible de la comunidad canaria. All&#xed;, tras una entrevista, autocumplimentar&#xe1;n cuestionarios cient&#xed;ficamente validados y se les realizar&#xe1;n diferentes pruebas validadas de evaluaci&#xf3;n del estado f&#xed;sico-funcional. Finalizado este proceso se les informar&#xe1; individualizadamente, facilit&#xe1;ndoles un dossier con recomendaciones. Se estima realizar seguimiento a los seis meses posteriores a esta primera evaluaci&#xf3;n. Una vez realizado el registro, an&#xe1;lisis e interpretaci&#xf3;n de datos, se pretende divulgar los resultados, tanto a trav&#xe9;s de medios de comunicaci&#xf3;n convencionales como someti&#xe9;ndolos para publicaci&#xf3;n en revistas cient&#xed;ficas.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Observational Study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physiotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spain</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Los autores declaran que no existe conflicto de intereses.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37293829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10541259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">e202306047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re&#x2019;em Y et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. Agosto de 2021;38:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re&#x2019;em Y. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021 Aug;38:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. Abril de 2021;27(4):601-615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021 Apr;27(4):601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV, WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 21 de diciembre de 2021;S1473-3099(21)00703-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV, HO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021 Dec 21;:S1473-3099(21)00703-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal FM, Lam K, Sounderajah V, Clarke JM, Ashrafian H, Darzi A. Characteristics and predictors of acute and chronic post-COVID syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. Junio de 2021;36:100899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8141371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34036253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal FM, Lam K, Sounderajah V, Clarke JM, Ashrafian H, Darzi A. Characteristics and predictors of acute and chronic post-COVID syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2021 Jun;(36):100899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8141371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34036253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolet&#xed;n Oficial del Parlamento 287/2021, de 16/6/2021 - Parlamento de Canarias [Internet]. [Consultado 25 de diciembre de 2021]. Disponible en: https://www.parcan.es/pub/bop.py?l=10&amp;n=287&amp;=2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parlamento de Canarias  . Bolet&#xed;n Oficial del Parlamento 287/2021, de 16/6/2021. Parlamento de Canarias; Jun 16, 2021.  [25-12-2021].  
 https://www.parcan.es/pub/bop.py?l=10&amp;n=287&amp;=2021
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Schneider C, Laurent E, Lemaignen A, Beaufils E, Bourbao-Tournois C, Laribi S et al. Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Clin Microbiol Infect. Febrero de 2021;27(2):258-263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Schneider C, Laurent E, Lemaignen A, Beaufils E, Bourbao-Tournois C, Laribi S. Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021 Feb;27(2):258&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go&#xeb;rtz YMJ, Van Herck M, Delbressine JM, Vaes AW, Meys R, Machado FVC et al. Persistent symptoms 3 months after a SARS-CoV-2 infection: the post-COVID-19 syndrome? ERJ Open Res. Octubre de 2020;6(4):00542-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go&#xeb;rtz YMJ, Van Herck M, Delbressine JM, Vaes AW, Meys R, Machado FVC. Persistent symptoms 3 months after a SARS-CoV-2 infection: the post-COVID-19 syndrome? ERJ Open Res. 2020 Oct;6(4):00542-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson KB, Rao M, Bonilla H, Subramanian A, Hack I, Madrigal M et al. Patients With Uncomplicated Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Have Long-Term Persistent Symptoms and Functional Impairment Similar to Patients with Severe COVID-19: A Cautionary Tale During a Global Pandemic. Clin Infect Dis. 2 de agosto de 2021;73(3):e826-829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33624010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson KB, Rao M, Bonilla H, Subramanian A, Hack I, Madrigal M. Patients With Uncomplicated Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Have Long-Term Persistent Symptoms and Functional Impairment Similar to Patients with Severe COVID-19: A Cautionary Tale During a Global Pandemic. Clin Infect Dis. 2021 Aug 02;73(3):e826&#x2013;e829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33624010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, Ghanima W, Olsen MK, Gilboe HM, Einvik G. Prevalence and Determinants of Fatigue after COVID-19 in Non-Hospitalized Subjects: A Population-Based Study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 19 de febrero de 2021;18(4):2030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7921928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33669714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, Ghanima W, Olsen MK, Gilboe HM, Einvik G. Prevalence and Determinants of Fatigue after COVID-19 in Non-Hospitalized Subjects: A Population-Based Study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021 Feb 19;18(4):2030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7921928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33669714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP et al. The Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) Statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Int J Surg. diciembre de 2014;12(12):1495-1499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP. The Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) Statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Int J Surg. 2014 Dec;12(12):1495&#x2013;1499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilagut G, Ferrer M, Rajmil L, Rebollo P, Permanyer-Miralda G, Quintana JM et al. The Spanish version of the Short Form 36 Health Survey: a decade of experience and new developments. Gac Sanit. Abril de 2005;19(2):135-150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15860162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilagut G, Ferrer M, Rajmil L, Rebollo P, Permanyer-Miralda G, Quintana JM. The Spanish version of the Short Form 36 Health Survey: a decade of experience and new developments. Gac Sanit. 2005 Apr;19(2):135&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15860162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Boon GJAM, Barco S, Endres M, Geelhoed JJM, Knauss S et al. The Post-COVID-19 Functional Status scale: a tool to measure functional status over time after COVID-19. Eur Respir J. Julio de 2020;56(1):2001494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Boon GJAM, Barco S, Endres M, Geelhoed JJM, Knauss S. The Post-COVID-19 Functional Status scale: a tool to measure functional status over time after COVID-19. Eur Respir J. 2020 Jul;56(1):2001494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorca LA, Le&#xe3;o Ribeiro I, Torres-Castro R, Sacomori C, Rivera C. Propiedades psicom&#xe9;tricas de la escala Post-COVID-19 Functional Status para adultos sobrevivientes de COVID-19. Rehabilitaci&#xf3;n (Madr) [Internet]. [Consultado 25 de diciembre de 2021]. Disponible en: https://www.elsevier.es/es-revista-rehabilitacion-120-avance-resumen-propiedades-psicometricas-escala-post-covid-19-functional-S0048712021000748</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8324401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34426013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorca LA, Le&#xe3;o Ribeiro I, Torres-Castro R, Sacomori C, Rivera C. Propiedades psicom&#xe9;tricas de la escala Post-COVID-19 Functional Status para adultos sobrevivientes de COVID-19.  [25-12-2021];Rehabilitaci&#xf3;n (Madr) 2021  
 https://www.elsevier.es/es-revista-rehabilitacion-120-avance-resumen-propiedades-psicometricas-escala-post-covid-19-functional-S0048712021000748
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8324401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34426013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorca LA, Torres-Castro R, Ribeiro IL, Benavente P, Pizarro M, San Cristobal B et al. Linguistic Validation and Cross-Cultural Adaptation of the Post-COVID-19 Functional Status Scale for the Chilean Population. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 1 de abril de 2021;100(4):313-320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33496442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorca LA, Torres-Castro R, Ribeiro I, Benavente P, Pizarro M, San Cristobal B. Linguistic Validation and Cross-Cultural Adaptation of the Post-COVID-19 Functional Status Scale for the Chilean Population. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2021 Apr 01;100(4):313&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33496442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Torres LA, Ventura-Alfaro CE. Validation of the Post-Covid-19 Functional Status Scale into Mexican-Spanish. J Rehabil Med Clin Commun. 2021;4:1000070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8505751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34659654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Torres LA, Ventura-Alfaro CE. Validation of the Post-Covid-19 Functional Status Scale into Mexican-Spanish. Rehabil Med Clin Commun. 2021;4:1000070</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8505751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34659654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez JF, Curcio CL, Alvarado B, Zunzunegui MV, Guralnik J. Validity and reliability of the Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB): a pilot study on mobility in the Colombian Andes. Colomb Med (Cali). Julio de 2013;44(3):165-171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4002038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24892614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez JF, Curcio CL, Alvarado B, Zunzunegui MV, Guralnik J. Validity and reliability of the Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB): a pilot study on mobility in the Colombian Andes. Colomb Med (Cali) 2013 Jul;44(3):165&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4002038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24892614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treacy D, Hassett L. The Short Physical Performance Battery. J Physiother. Enero de 2018;64(1):61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28645532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treacy D, Hassett L. The Short Physical Performance Battery. Physiother. 2018;64(1):61&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28645532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briand J, Behal H, Chenivesse C, W&#xe9;meau-Stervinou L, Wallaert B. The 1-minute sit-to-stand test to detect exercise-induced oxygen desaturation in patients with interstitial lung disease. Ther Adv Respir Dis. Diciembre de 2018;12:1753466618793028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6088463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30091679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briand J, Behal H, Chenivesse C, W&#xe9;meau-Stervinou L, Wallaert B. The 1-minute sit-to-stand test to detect exercise-induced oxygen desaturation in patients with interstitial lung disease. Ther Adv Respir Dis. 2018 Dec;12:1753466618793028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6088463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30091679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paternostro-Sluga T, Grim-Stieger M, Posch M, Schuhfried O, Vacariu G, Mittermaier C et al. Reliability and validity of the Medical Research Council (MRC) scale and a modified scale for testing muscle strength in patients with radial palsy. J Rehabil Med. Agosto de 2008;40(8):665-671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19020701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paternostro-Sluga T, Grim-Stieger M, Posch M, Schuhfried O, Vacariu G, Mittermaier C. Reliability and validity of the Medical Research Council (MRC) scale and a modified scale for testing muscle strength in patients with radial palsy. J Rehabil Med. 2008 Dec;40(8):665&#x2013;671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19020701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerum TV, Aal&#xf8;kken TM, Br&#xf8;nstad E, Aarli B, Ikdahl E, Lund KMA et al. Dyspnoea, lung function and CT findings 3 months after hospital admission for COVID-19. Eur Respir J. Abril de 2021;57(4):2003448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerum TV, Aal&#xf8;kken TM, Br&#xf8;nstad E, Aarli B, Ikdahl E, Lund KMA. Dyspnoea, lung function and CT findings 3 months after hospital admission for COVID-19. Eur Respir J. 2021 Apr;57(4):2003448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards JB. Calculated decisions: mMRC (Modified Medical Research Council) Dyspnea Scale. Emerg Med Pract. 25 de octubre de 2017;19(Suppl 10):1-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29068638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards JB. Calculated decisions: mMRC (Modified Medical Research Council) Dyspnea Scale. Emerg Med Pract. 2017 Oct 25;19(Suppl 10):1&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29068638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santus P, Tursi F, Croce G, Di Simone C, Frassanito F, Gaboardi P et al. Changes in quality of life and dyspnoea after hospitalization in COVID-19 patients discharged at home. Multidiscip Respir Med. 28 de enero de 2020;15(1):713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7582021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33117535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santus P, Tursi F, Croce G, Di Simone C, Frassanito F, Gaboardi P. Changes in quality of life and dyspnoea after hospitalization in COVID-19 patients discharged at home. Multidiscip Respir Med. 2020 Jan 28;15(1):713&#x2013;713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7582021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33117535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cano-Climent A, Oliver-Roig A, Cabrero-Garc&#xed;a J, de Vries J, Richart-Mart&#xed;nez M. The Spanish version of the Fatigue Assessment Scale: reliability and validity assessment in postpartum women. PeerJ. 2017;5:e3832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5622603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28970968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cano-Climent A, Oliver-Roig A, Cabrero-Garc&#xed;a J, de Vries J, Richart-Mart&#xed;nez M. The Spanish version of the Fatigue Assessment Scale: reliability and validity assessment in postpartum women. PeerJ. 2017;5:e3832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5622603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28970968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuesta-Vargas AI, Gonz&#xe1;lez-S&#xe1;nchez M. Spanish version of the screening &#xd6;rebro musculoskeletal pain questionnaire: a cross-cultural adaptation and validation. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 29 de octubre de 2014;12:157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4219048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25358630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuesta-Vargas AI, Gonz&#xe1;lez-S&#xe1;nchez M. Spanish version of the screening &#xd6;rebro musculoskeletal pain questionnaire: a cross-cultural adaptation and validation. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2014 Oct 29;12:157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4219048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25358630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rom&#xe1;n Vi&#xf1;as B, Ribas Barba L, Ngo J, Serra Majem L. Validity of the international physical activity questionnaire in the Catalan population (Spain). Gac Sanit. Junio de 2013;27(3):254-257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23103093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rom&#xe1;n Vi&#xf1;as B, Ribas Barba L, Ngo J, Serra Majem L. Validity of the international physical activity questionnaire in the Catalan population (Spain). Gac Sanit. 2013 Jun;27(3):254&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23103093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>