<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37363499</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2049-0801</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>85</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of medicine and surgery (2012)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Med Surg (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence and predictors of neck pain among Bangladeshi community dwellers during COVID-19 pandemic: analysis of a matched case-control data.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2304</StartPage><EndPage>2312</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2304-2312</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MS9.0000000000000851</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Extant literature has established a significant association between COVID-19 and musculoskeletal health complaints. Despite this, there remains a paucity of data regarding the relationship between COVID-19 and neck pain among community-dwelling individuals. The primary objective of this study was to ascertain the prevalence and predictors of neck pain in this population in Bangladesh. This was achieved via screening the musculoskeletal health of post-acute COVID-19 survivors and their age and sex-matched unaffected counterparts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study employs a case-control design and includes 878 Bangladeshi individuals aged 18 years or older, of which 439 were post-acute COVID-19 patients. Data were collected between 24 February and 7 April 2022. Neck pain was assessed using the musculoskeletal subscale of subjective health complaints. Descriptive analysis was conducted to determine the prevalence of neck pain and to compare its prevalence across subgroups. Furthermore, multiple logistic regression analysis was utilized to identify the predictors of neck pain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Out of 878 participants, 15.1% reported experiencing neck pain. However, neck pain was significantly higher among those with post-acute COVID-19 than those without the infection (21.4% vs. 8.9%, <i>P</i>&lt;0.001). An adjusted analysis found that COVID-19 infection was independently associated with neck pain (adjusted odds ratio=2.626%, 95% CI=1.666-4.140).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The results of this study suggest a link between COVID-19 and neck pain. Therefore, it is recommended that healthcare service providers are prepared to manage the increased incidence of neck pain among patients who have recovered from COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4685-5050</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, Uttara Adhunik Medical College and Hospital, Uttara Model Town.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department Physiotherapy, International Institute of Health Sciences, Mirpur, Dhaka6, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehjabin</LastName><ForeName>Tajnuva</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Uttara Homeopathic Medical College and Hospital, Uttara, Dhaka.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Med Surg (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101616869</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2049-0801</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bangladesh</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronavirus infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neck pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pandemic</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) proclaimed no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37363499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10289559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MS9.0000000000000851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">AMSU-D-23-00534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Carroll LJ, Cassidy JD, Peloso PM, et al. . Methods for the Best Evidence Synthesis on Neck Pain and Its Associated Disorders: The Bone and Joint Decade 2000&#x2013;2010 Task Force on Neck Pain and Its Associated Disorders. J Manipulative Physiol Ther 2009;32:S39&#x2013;S45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19251072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen SP. Epidemiology, diagnosis, and treatment of neck pain. Mayo Clin Proc 2015;90:284&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25659245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanpied PR, Gross AR, Elliott JM, et al. . Clinical practice guidelines linked to the international classification of functioning, disability and health from the orthopaedic section of the American physical therapy association. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 2017;47:A1&#x2013;A83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18758050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>March L, Smith EUR, Hoy DG, et al. . Burden of disability due to musculoskeletal (MSK) disorders. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol 2014;28:353&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25481420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borghouts JAJ, Koes BW, Vondeling H, et al. . Cost-of-illness of neck pain in The Netherlands in 1996. Pain 1999;80:629&#x2013;636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10342424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rempel DM, Harrison RJ, Barnhart S. Work-related cumulative trauma disorders of the upper extremity. JAMA 1992;267:838&#x2013;842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1732657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoy DG, Protani M, De R, et al. . The epidemiology of neck pain. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol 2010;24:783&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21665126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Impact of Musculoskeletal Disorders on Americans &#x2013; Opportunities for Action | Scoliosis Research Society, (n.d.).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govaerts R, Tassignon B, Ghillebert J, et al. . Prevalence and incidence of work-related musculoskeletal disorders in secondary industries of 21st century Europe: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2021;22:1&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8408961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34465326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vos T, Abajobir AA, Abbafati C, et al. . Global, regional, and national incidence, prevalence, and years lived with disability for 328 diseases and injuries for 195 countries, 1990&#x2013;2016: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2016. Lancet 2017;390:1211&#x2013;1259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5605509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28919117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
(No Title), (n.d.). Accessed 11 August, 2020. https://d197for5662m48.cloudfront.net/documents/publicationstatus/44403/preprint_pdf/06c07cdf426c3fe2b063528be776c805.pdf
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization, WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard. WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard With Vaccination Data, Who. (2021) 1&#x2013;5. Accessed 8 April 2022.
https://covid19.who.int/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nat 2021;594:259&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, De-la-Llave-Rinc&#xf3;n AI, Ortega-Santiago R, et al. . Prevalence and risk factors of musculoskeletal pain symptoms as long-term post-COVID sequelae in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors. Pain 2021. Publish Ah (2021). 10.1097/j.pain.0000000000002564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000002564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34913880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet Id M, Dercon Id Q, Luciano S, et al. . Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. 2021;18(e1003773) 10.1371/journal.pmed.1003773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1003773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari R, Russell AS, Carroll LJ, et al. . A re-examination of the whiplash associated disorders (WAD) as a systemic illness 2005. 10.1136/ard.2004.034447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard.2004.034447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1755634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15731286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-De-las-pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, et al. . Defining post-covid symptoms (Post-acute covid, long covid, persistent post-covid): an integrative classification. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021;18:2621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Uddin Z, Banik PC, et al. . Knowledge, Attitude, Practice, and Fear of COVID-19: an Online-Based Cross-cultural Study. Int J Ment Health Addict 2021. 10.1007/s11469-021-00638-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11469-021-00638-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8404540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34483782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Ahsan GU, Khan R, et al. . Immediate impact of stay-at-home orders to control COVID-19 transmission on mental well-being in Bangladeshi adults: Patterns, Explanations, and future directions. BMC Res Notes 2020;13:494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7578585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33092649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Uddin Z, Amran Hossain KM, et al. . Depression, anxiety, stress, and suicidal behavior among Bangladeshi undergraduate rehabilitation students: An observational study amidst the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic. Heal Sci Reports 2022;5:e549. 10.1002/hsr2.549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hsr2.549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8905129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35284647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Bonna AS, Sarkar A, et al. . Is Coronavirus infection associated with musculoskeletal health complaints? Results from a comprehensive case-control study. J Prim Care Community Health 2022;13:215013192211142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9310274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35869693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK - Office for National Statistics, (n.d.).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Siddiq MAB, Pranto NK, et al. . Prevalence and predictors of musculoskeletal health complaints among sedentary, monotonous urban workers: a survey in Bangladesh. PLoS One 2023;18:e0282922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10120926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37083655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Bonna AS, Sarkar A, et al. . SARS-CoV-2 infection is associated with low back pain: findings from a community-based case-control study. Int J Infect Dis 2022;122:144&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35643305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Uddin Z, Hossain A. Combined effect of vitamin d supplementation and physiotherapy on reducing pain among adult patients with musculoskeletal disorders: a quasi-experimental clinical trial. Front Nutr 2021;8:739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8523800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34676231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Uddin Z, Ahsan NF, et al. . Prevalence of mental health symptoms and its effect on insomnia among healthcare workers who attended hospitals during COVID-19 pandemic: a survey in Dhaka city. Heliyon 2021;7:e06985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8120937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34027184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathew G, Agha R, Albrecht J, et al. . STROCSS 2021: Strengthening the reporting of cohort, cross-sectional and case-control studies in surgery. Int J Surg 2021;96:106165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34774726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Hossain A. What is the extent of COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy in Bangladesh? A cross-sectional rapid national survey. BMJ Open 2021;11:e050303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8387740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34429316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saiful Islam M, Zannatul Ferdous M, Soumayia Islam U, et al. . Treatment, persistent symptoms, and depression in people infected with COVID-19 in Bangladesh. Int J Environ Res Public Heal 2021;18:1453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7914967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33562427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overview | COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19 | Guidance | NICE, (n.d.).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term effects of coronavirus (long COVID) - NHS, (n.d.).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmud R, Rahman MM, Rassel MA, et al. . Post-COVID-19 syndrome among symptomatic COVID-19 patients: a prospective cohort study in a tertiary care center of Bangladesh. PLoS One 2021;16:e0249644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8031743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33831043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksen HR, Ihleb&#xe6;k C, Ursin H. A scoring system for subjective health complaints (SHC. Scand J Public Health 1999;27:63&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10847674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Ahsan GU, Uddin Z, et al. . Road traffic delays in commuting workplace and musculoskeletal health among sedentary workers: a cross-sectional study in Dhaka city. J Occup Health 2021;63:e12289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8577272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34751983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Uddin Z, Hossain A. Economic stressors and mental health symptoms among Bangladeshi rehabilitation professionals: a cross-sectional study amid COVID-19 pandemic. Heliyon 2021;7:e06715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33898834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karateev AE, Amirdzhanova VN, Nasonov EL, et al. . &#x201c;Post-COVID syndrome&#x201d;: The focus is on musculoskeletal pain. Nauchno-Prakticheskaya Revmatol 2021;59:255&#x2013;262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, Plaza-Manzano G, et al. . Time course prevalence of post-COVID pain symptoms of musculoskeletal origin in patients who had survived severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pain 2022;163:1220&#x2013;1231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34561390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Ahsan GU. Prevalence and associated occupational factors of low back pain among the bank employees in Dhaka City. J Occup Heal 2020;62:12131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Uddin Z, Ahsan GU, et al. . Association between daily commute and subjective health complaints among the office workers in an urban community. Heliyon 2021;7:e07841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8383055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34466705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredriksson K, Alfredsson L, Ahlberg G, et al. . Work environment and neck and shoulder pain: the influence of exposure time. Results from a population based case-control study. Occup Environ Med 2002;59:182&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1763625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11886949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao SS, Jones GT, MacFarlane GJ, et al. . Association between comorbidities and disease activity in axial spondyloarthritis: results from the BSRBR-AS. Rheumatol (United Kingdom) 2021;60:3189&#x2013;3198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8516505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33331904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>