<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37248500</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1472-6955</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the health and working conditions of nurses and its implications for policies: a cross-sectional study in Slovakia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>185</StartPage><MedlinePgn>185</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">185</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12912-023-01356-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Increased workload and of the health workforce (HW) strained the capacity to maintain essential health services (EHS) during the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic, while putting them at increased risk of COVID-19 and other consequences to their health. The aim of this study was to assess the impact of COVID-19 on the health, wellbeing, and working conditions of nurses in Slovakia and to identify gaps in policies to be addressed to increase preparedness of the HW for future emergencies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A nation-wide cross-sectional study was conducted among nurses during November-December 2021, referring to the period of January&#xa0;2021 to November 2021. To assess the differences between impact on HW on various levels of care, respondents were grouped by type of facility: hospital-COVID-19 wards; Hospital-non-covid ward; Outpatient or ER; Other care facilities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">1170 nurses participated, about 1/3 of them tested positive for COVID-19 by November 2021, mostly developing mild disease. Almost 2/3 reported long-covid symptoms and about 13% reported that they do not plan to get vaccinated against COVID-19. The&#xa0;median of the score of the impact of workload on health was 2.8 (56% of the maximum 5), the median score of mental health-wellbeing was 1.9 (63% of a maximum of 3). The studied impacts in all domains were highest in nurses working in COVID-19 hospital wards. Significant disruptions of health care were reported, with relatively high use of telemedicine to mitigate them. Overall, about 70% of the respondents thought of leaving their job, mostly due to working stress or inadequate pay.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our study showed that the COVID-19 pandemic poses a substantial burden on the health, wellbeing and working conditions of nurses in Slovakia and that a large proportion of nurses considered leaving their jobs because of work overload or low salaries. Human resource strategies should be adopted to attract, retain and continuously invest in HW development including in emergency preparedness and response. Such an approach may improve the resilience and preparedness of the health system in Slovakia for future emergencies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Putekova</LastName><ForeName>Silvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences and Social Work, Department of Nursing, Trnava University, Trnava, Slovakia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martinkova</LastName><ForeName>Jana</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences and Social Work, Department of Nursing, Trnava University, Trnava, Slovakia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Urickova</LastName><ForeName>Alena</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences and Social Work, Department of Nursing, Trnava University, Trnava, Slovakia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kober</LastName><ForeName>Lukas</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, Department of Nursing, Catholic University, Ruzomberok, Slovakia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Slovak Chamber of Nurses and Midwives, Bratislava, Slovakia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reichertova</LastName><ForeName>Stanislava</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paramedic Science, Medical Diagnostic Studies and Public Health, Faculty of Health Care Studies, University of West Bohemia, Pilsen, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plancikova</LastName><ForeName>Dominika</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Global Health and Epidemiology, Department of Public Health, Faculty of Health Sciences and Social Work, Trnava University, Hornopotocna 23, 91843, Trnava, Slovakia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Majdan</LastName><ForeName>Marek</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Global Health and Epidemiology, Department of Public Health, Faculty of Health Sciences and Social Work, Trnava University, Hornopotocna 23, 91843, Trnava, Slovakia. mmajdan@truni.sk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088683</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6955</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health Impact</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health Policies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthcare Workers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing Personnel</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37248500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10226785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-023-01356-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12912-023-01356-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation (WHO). WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard. Geneva: WHO; 2023. Available from: https://covid19.who.int.&#xa0; Accessed 16 Apr 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation (WHO). Second round of the national pulse survey on continuity of essential health services during the COVID-19 pandemic. Interim report. Geneva: WHO; 2021. Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-EHS-continuity-survey-2021.1.&#xa0; Accessed 16 Mar 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation (WHO). Health workforce policy and management in the context of the COVID-19 pandemic response: interim guidance. Geneva: WHO; 2020. Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-health_workforce-2020.1. Accessed 16 Mar 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation (WHO). Maintaining essential health services: operational guidance for the COVID-19 context: interim guidance. Geneva: WHO; 2020. Available from: https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/332240. Accessed 16 Mar 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Chen Z, Azman AS, Deng X, Sun R, Zhao Z, Zheng N, Chen X, Lu W, Zhuang T, et al. Serological evidence of human infection with SARS-CoV-2: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Glob Health. 2021;9(5):e598&#x2013;e609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8049592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33705690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobrovitz N, Arora RK, Cao C, Boucher E, Liu M, Donnici C, Yanes-Lane M, Whelan M, Perlman-Arrow S, Chen J, et al. Global seroprevalence of SARS-CoV-2 antibodies: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(6):e0252617. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0252617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0252617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34161316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation (WHO). The impact of COVID-19 on health and care workers: a closer look at deaths. Geneva: WHO; 2021. Available from: https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/345300. Accessed 16 Mar 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta S, Machado F, Kwizera A, Papazian L, Moss M, Azoulay E, Herridge M. COVID-19: a heavy toll on health-care workers. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9(3):226&#x2013;228. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00068-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00068-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7906726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33556317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manchia M, Gathier AW, Yapici-Eser H, Schmidt MV, de Quervain D, van Amelsvoort T, Bisson JI, Cryan JF, Howes OD, Pinto L, et al. The impact of the prolonged COVID-19 pandemic on stress resilience and mental health: A critical review across waves. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2022;55:22&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.10.864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.10.864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8554139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34818601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cilovic-Lagarija S, Musa S, Hasanica N, Cerkez G, Palo M, Majdan M, Scherzer M, Habersaat KB, Smallwood C, Tahirukaj A, et al. Population Perspectives on Impact of the COVID-19 Pandemic on Essential Health Services-Behavioral Insights from the Federation of Bosnia and Herzegovina. Behav Sci (Basel). 2022;12(12):495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9774738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36546978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nj C, Bi H. Psychometric Theory. 3. New York: McGraw&amp;Hill; 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A language and environment for statistical computing. Vienna: R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2023. Available from: https://www.R-project.org/. Accessed 15 Mar 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant R, Dub T, Andrianou X, Nohynek H, Wilder-Smith A, Pezzotti P, Fontanet A. SARS-CoV-2 population-based seroprevalence studies in Europe: a scoping review. BMJ Open. 2021;11(4):e045425. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2020-045425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-045425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8021754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33795310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He S, Hecimovic A, Matijasevic V, Mai HT, Heslop L, Foster J, Alexander KE, Pal N, Alexandrou E, Davidson PM, et al. Prevalence of SARS-CoV-2 antibodies among nurses: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Nurs. 2021;31(11-12):1557&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34570947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayi I, Madran B, Keske S, Karanfil O, Arribas JR, Pshenismall es CN, Petrosillo N, Gonen M, Ergonul O: The seroprevalence of SARS-CoV-2 antibodies among health care workers before the era of vaccination: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021; 27(9):1242&#x2013;1249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8186944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34116205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain A, Nasrullah SM, Tasnim Z, Hasan MK, Hasan MM. Seroprevalence of SARS-CoV-2 IgG antibodies among health care workers prior to vaccine administration in Europe, the USA and East Asia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;33:100770. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.100770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.100770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7938754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33718853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaselli NM, Hungerford D, Shenton B, Khashkhusha A, Cunliffe NA, French N. The seroprevalence of SARS-CoV-2 during the first wave in Europe 2020: A systematic review. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(11):e0250541. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0250541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0250541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8562786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34727115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saragih ID, Tonapa SI, Saragih IS, Advani S, Batubara SO, Suarilah I, Lin CJ. Global prevalence of mental health problems among healthcare workers during the Covid-19 pandemic: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Nurs Stud. 2021;121:104002. doi: 10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2021.104002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2021.104002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9701545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34271460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur B, Pathak M. Burden of Predominant Psychological Reactions Among the Healthcare Workers and General Population During COVID-19 Pandemic Phase: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Indian J Community Med. 2021;46(4):600&#x2013;605. doi: 10.4103/ijcm.IJCM_1007_20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijcm.IJCM_1007_20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8729270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35068717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang SX, Chen RZ, Xu W, Yin A, Dong RK, Chen BZ, Delios AY, Miller S, McIntyre RS, Ye W, et al. A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Symptoms of Anxiety, Depression, and Insomnia in Spain in the COVID-19 Crisis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(2):1018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8775436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35055841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smallwood N, Harrex W, Rees M, Willis K, Bennett CM. COVID-19 infection and the broader impacts of the pandemic on healthcare workers. Respirology. 2022;27(6):411&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35048469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock A, Campbell P, Cheyne J, Cowie J, Davis B, McCallum J, McGill K, Elders A, Hagen S, McClurg D, et al. Interventions to support the resilience and mental health of frontline health and social care professionals during and after a disease outbreak, epidemic or pandemic: a mixed methods systematic review. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020; 11:CD013779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8226433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33150970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Governmental committee for mental health. The Government of Slovak Republic. 2022. Available at: https://www.vlada.gov.sk//rada-vlady-sr-pre-dusevne-zdravie/. Accessed 15 Mar 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health of the Slovak Republic. The government of Slovakia approves the establishment of the Governmental Committee for Mental Health. Bratislava. 2021. Available at: https://www.health.gov.sk/Clanok?rada-dusevne-zdravie-vlada. Accessed 15 Mar 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slovak Chamber of Nurses and Midwives. Analysis of the current status of payments to nurses in Slovakia - Proposal of the Slovak Chamber of Nurses and Midwives for adjusting the payment policy. Bratislava. 2021. Available at: https://www.sksapa.sk/data1/Analyza%20mzdy%20%20a%20navrh.pdf. Accessed 15 Mar 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Association of Critical-Care Nurses. Hear Us Out Campaign Reports Nurses' COVID-19 Reality. Aliso Viejo. 2021. Available at: https://www.aacn.org/newsroom/hear-us-out-campaign-reports-nurses-covid-19-reality. Accessed 15 Mar 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantor JH, McBain RK, Pera MF, Bravata DM, Whaley CM. Who Is (and Is Not) Receiving Telemedicine Care During the COVID-19 Pandemic. Am J Prev Med. 2021;61(3):434&#x2013;438. doi: 10.1016/j.amepre.2021.01.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2021.01.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7936544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer SH, Uscher-Pines L, Roth E, Breslau J. The Transition to Telehealth during the First Months of the COVID-19 Pandemic: Evidence from a National Sample of Patients. J Gen Intern Med. 2021;36(3):849&#x2013;851. doi: 10.1007/s11606-020-06358-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-020-06358-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7787420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33409884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bokolo AJ. Application of telemedicine and eHealth technology for clinical services in response to COVID19 pandemic. Health Technol (Berl) 2021;11(2):359&#x2013;366. doi: 10.1007/s12553-020-00516-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12553-020-00516-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33469474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SM, Lee D. Opportunities and challenges for contactless healthcare services in the post-COVID-19 Era. Technol Forecast Soc Change. 2021;167:120712. doi: 10.1016/j.techfore.2021.120712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.techfore.2021.120712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7908833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33654330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langella J, Magnuson B, Finkelman MD, Amato R. Clinical Response to COVID-19 and Utilization of an Emergency Dental Clinic in an Academic Institution. J Endod. 2021;47(4):566&#x2013;571. doi: 10.1016/j.joen.2020.11.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2020.11.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7772583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33387553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health of the Slovak Republic. Standard operating procedures for health workers relating to COVID-19. Bratislava. 2020. Available at: https://www.standardnepostupy.sk/covid-19/. Accessed 15 Mar 2022.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>