<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35686389</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-2165</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cosmetic dermatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cosmet Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The significant transformation of life into health and beauty in metaverse era.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6575</StartPage><EndPage>6583</EndPage><MedlinePgn>6575-6583</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocd.15151</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In 2019, coronavirus disease-19 (COVID-19) continues, and it is evolving and starting again. It is a situation to keep in mind that now is the era of With Corona (WC) and Long-COVID. "WC" will be a transformation of the quarantine system. The current situation is associated with health and beauty. Sustainability of healthy beauty is giving new meaning to well-being and well-dying.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Therefore, in this study, we empirically analyzed the changes in the perception of health and beauty among cosmetic consumers in the metaverse, which are recently becoming an issue in the WC era.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">It was created by searching keywords such as "With Corona," "Health," "Life Beauty," "Customized inner beauty," "Customized cosmetics," "Metaverse," "DTC GT," etc. This study was conducted with reference to PubMed, Google Scholar, Riss, Scopus, and ResearchGate. Accordingly, a total of 472 papers were researched, and among them, 32 papers, which are the focus of the study, were finally included in this study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">As the era of WC changes, a new paradigm of converting the customer experience of the beauty market into a metaverse will be beginning. Accordingly, it is necessary to pay attention to changes in the cosmetic industry by reflecting the needs of consumers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">It is necessary to create a new mobile platform that encompasses three-dimensional health and beauty life using direct-to-customer genetic testing (DTC GT) with Web 3.0 in the metaverse that integrates life health and beauty in the WC era. Accordingly, it is expected that this article will be used as an invaluable marketing material in preparation for new changes in the metaverse cosmetics market in the future by clearly understanding the needs of consumers in the cosmetics industry, which are changing as they transformation to WC era.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jinkyung</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Beauty Arts Care, Department of Beauty Arts Care, Graduate School, Dongguk University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Beauty and Health Care, Namseoul University, Cheonan, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwon</LastName><ForeName>Ki Han</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of General Education, Kookmin University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Cosmet Dermatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101130964</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1473-2130</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003358">Cosmetics</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003358" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cosmetics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040541" MajorTopicYN="N">Marketing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">customized cosmetics DTC GT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">customized inner beauty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metaverse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">with corona</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35686389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocd.15151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Hadizadeh F. Supplementation with vitamin D in the COVID-19 pandemic? Nutr Rev. 2021;79(2):200-208. doi:10.1093/nutrit/nuaa081</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S. Coexisting with the coronavirus, how to prepare for it. Health Policy Manag. 2021;31(3):241-243. http://www.riss.kr/link?id=A107881010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin K. The direction of cultural content education in the with/post Corona era. Korea Humanit Content Soc. 2020;(59):107-129. http://www.riss.kr/link?id=A107257936</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kwon KH. Changes in the use of cosmetics worldwide due to increased use of masks in the coronavirus disease-19 pandemic. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2022;21(7):2708-2712. doi:10.1111/jocd.14515</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Techasatian L, Lebsing S, Uppala R, et al. The effects of the face mask on the skin underneath: a prospective survey during the COVID-19 pandemic. J Prim Care Community Health. 2020;11:2150132720966167. doi:10.1177/2150132720966167</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kwon KH. Development of customized inner beauty products and customized cosmetics apps according to the use of NRF2 through DTC genetic testing after the COVID-19 pandemic. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2022;21(6):2288-2297. doi:10.1111/jocd.14467</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kwon KH. DTC genetic test for customized cosmetics in COVID-19 pandemic: focused on women in their 40s and 60s in Seoul, Republic of Korea. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2021;20(10):3085-3092. doi:10.1111/jocd.14377</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siyaev A, Jo GS. Towards aircraft maintenance metaverse using speech interactions with virtual objects in mixed reality. Sensors (Basel). 2021;21(6):2066. doi:10.3390/s21062066</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kye B, Han N, Kim E, Park Y, Jo S. Educational applications of metaverse: possibilities and limitations. J Educ Eval Health Prof. 2021;18:32. doi:10.3352/jeehp.2021.18.32</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kwon KH. Future value and direction of cosmetics in the era of metaverse. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2022. doi:10.1111/jocd.14794</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han HJ, Nwagwu C, Anyim O, Ekweremadu C, Kim S. COVID-19 and cancer: from basic mechanisms to vaccine development using nanotechnology. Int Immunopharmacol. 2021;90:107247. doi:10.1016/j.intimp.2020.107247</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muralidar S, Ambi SV, Sekaran S, Krishnan UM. The emergence of COVID-19 as a global pandemic: understanding the epidemiology, immune response and potential therapeutic targets of SARS-CoV-2. Biochimie. 2020;179:85-100. doi:10.1016/j.biochi.2020.09.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain MM, Sultana A, Purohit N. Mental health outcomes of quarantine and isolation for infection prevention: a systematic umbrella review of the global evidence. Epidemiol Health. 2020;42:e2020038. doi:10.4178/epih.e2020038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kwon KH. Sustainable changes in beauty market trends focused on the perspective of safety in the post-coronavirus disease-19 period. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2022;21(7):2700-2707. doi:10.1111/jocd.14493</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Pan L, Tang S, Ji JS, Shi X. Mask use during COVID-19: a risk adjusted strategy. Environ Pollut. 2020;266(Pt 1):115099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szepietowski JC, Matusiak &#x141;, Szepietowska M, Krajewski PK, Bia&#x142;ynicki-Birula R. Face mask-induced itch: a self-questionnaire study of 2,315 responders during the COVID-19 pandemic. Acta Derm Venereol. 2020;100(10):adv00152. doi:10.2340/00015555-3536</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Althobaiti HM, Althobaiti H, Khan M, Alsatti H, Samarkandy SJ. The association between facial dermatosis and face-mask wearing during COVID-19 in Saudi Arabia. Cureus. 2022;14(2):e22265. doi:10.7759/cureus.22265</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanfilippo PG, Kearns LS, Wright P, Mackey DA, Hewitt AW. Current landscape of direct-to-consumer genetic testing and its role in ophthalmology: a review. Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2015;43(6):578-590. doi:10.1111/ceo.12508</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niemiec E, Kalokairinou L, Howard HC. Current ethical and legal issues in health-related direct-to-consumer genetic testing. Per Med. 2017;14(5):433-445. doi:10.2217/pme-2017-0029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahon SM. Direct-to-consumer genetic testing: helping patients make informed choices. Clin J Oncol Nurs. 2018;22(1):33-36. doi:10.1188/18.CJON.33-36</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohidon C, Cardinaux R, Cornuz J, et al. May direct-to-consumer genetic testing have an impact on general practitioners' daily practice? A cross-sectional study of patients' intentions towards this approach. BMC Fam Pract. 2021;22(1):79. doi:10.1186/s12875-021-01428-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kwon KH. A cross-sectional study on the use of big data for the past H1N1 influenza epidemic in obesity after COVID-19: focused on the body slimming cream and leptin via DTC gene test. J Cosmet Dermatol. doi:10.1111/jocd.14585</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathur S, Sutton J. Personalized medicine could transform healthcare. Biomed Rep. 2017;7(1):3-5. doi:10.3892/br.2017.922</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Valvo A, Croce D, Garlisi D, Giuliano F, Giarr&#xe9; L, Tinnirello I. A navigation and augmented reality system for visually impaired people. Sensors (Basel). 2021;21(9):3061. doi:10.3390/s21093061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skalidis I, Muller O, Fournier S. CardioVerse: the cardiovascular medicine in the era of metaverse. Trends Cardiovasc Med. 2022;S1050-1738(22)00071-8. doi:10.1016/j.tcm.2022.05.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ham J. Paradigm change and response of sports safety in the era of with Corona. Korean Secur J. 2021;(67):99-122. http://www.riss.kr/link?id=A107779646</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte ML, Santos LR, Guimar&#xe3;es J&#xfa;nior JB, Peccin MS. Learning anatomy by virtual reality and augmented reality. A scope review. Morphologie. 2020;104(347):254-266. doi:10.1016/j.morpho.2020.08.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madhi SA. COVID-19 herd immunity v. learning to live with the virus. S Afr Med J. 2021;111(9):852-856. doi:10.7196/SAMJ.2021.v111i9.16005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konaszewski K, Muszy&#x144;ska J, Skalski SB, Surzykiewicz J. Development and psychometric properties of the health belief scales toward COVID-19 vaccine: a cross-sectional study in north-eastern Poland. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(9):5424. doi:10.3390/ijerph19095424</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullins VA, Bresette W, Johnstone L, Hallmark B, Chilton FH. Genomics in personalized nutrition: can you "eat for your genes"? Nutrients. 2020;12(10):3118. doi:10.3390/nu12103118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locurcio LL. Dental education in the metaverse. Br Dent J. 2022;232(4):191. doi:10.1038/s41415-022-3990-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kwon KH. Good ingredients from foods to vegan cosmetics after COVID-19 pandemic. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2022:21(8):3190-3199. doi:10.1111/jocd.15028</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>