<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36636645</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1828-695X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Multidisciplinary respiratory medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Multidiscip Respir Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nebivolol: an effective option against long-lasting dyspnoea following COVID-19 pneumonia - a pivotal double-blind, cross-over controlled study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>886</StartPage><MedlinePgn>886</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">886</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4081/mrm.2022.886</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Pulmonary microvascular occlusions can aggravate SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia and result in a variable decrease in capillary blood volume (Vc). Dyspnoea may persist for several weeks after hospital discharge in many patients who have "radiologically recovered" from COVID-19 pneumonia. Dyspnoea is frequently "unexplained" in these cases because abnormalities in lung vasculature are understudied. Furthermore, even when they are identified, therapeutic options are still lacking in clinical practice, with nitric oxide (NO) supplementation being used only for severe respiratory failure in the hospital setting. Nebivolol is the only selective &#x3b2;<sup>1</sup> adrenoceptor antagonist capable of inducing nitric oxide-mediated vasodilation by stimulating endothelial NO synthase <i>via</i> &#x3b2;<sub>3</sub> agonism. The purpose of this study was to compare the effect of nebivolol <i>versus</i> placebo in patients who had low Vc and complained of dyspnoea for several weeks after COVID-19 pneumonia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patients of both genders, aged &#x2265;18 years, non-smokers, who had a CT scan that revealed no COVID-related parenchymal lesions but still complaining of dyspnoea 12-16 weeks after hospital discharge, were recruited. Spirometrical volumes, blood haemoglobin, SpO<sub>2</sub>, simultaneous diffusing capacity for carbon monoxide (CO) and NO (DL<sub>CO</sub> and DL<sub>NO</sub>, respectively), DL<sub>NO</sub>/DL<sub>CO</sub> ratio, Vc and exhaled NO (eNO) were measured together with their dyspnoea score (DS), heart frequency (HF), and blood arterial pressure (BAP). Data were collected before and one week after both placebo (P) and nebivolol (N) (2.5 mg od) double-blind cross-over administered at a two-week interval. Data were statistically compared, and p&lt;0.05 assumed as statistically significant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Eight patients (3 males) were investigated. In baseline, their mean DS was 2.5&#xb1;0.6 SD, despite the normality of lung volumes. DL<sub>CO</sub> and DL<sub>NO</sub> mean values were lower than predicted, while mean DL<sub>NO</sub>/DL<sub>CO</sub> ratio was higher. Mean Vc proved substantially reduced. Placebo did not modify any variable (all p=ns) while N improved DLco and Vc significantly (+8.5%, p&lt;0.04 and +17.7%, p&lt;0.003, respectively). eNO also was significantly increased (+17.6%, p&lt;0.002). Only N lowered the dyspnoea score (-76%, p&lt;0.001). Systolic and diastolic BAP were slightly lowered (-7.5%, p&lt;0.02 and -5.1%, p&lt;0.04, respectively), together with HF (-16.8%, p&lt;0.03).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The simultaneous assessment of DL<sub>NO</sub>, DL<sub>CO</sub>, DL<sub>NO</sub>/DL<sub>CO</sub> ratio, and Vc confirmed that long-lasting dyspnoea is related to hidden abnormalities in the lung capillary vasculature. These abnormalities can persist even after the complete resolution of parenchymal lesions regardless of the normality of lung volumes. Nebivolol, but not placebo, improves DS and Vc significantly. The mechanism suggested is the NO-mediated vasodilation <i>via</i> the &#x3b2;3 adrenoceptor stimulation of endothelial NO synthase. This hypothesis is supported by the substantial increase of eNO only assessed after nebivolol. As the nebivolol tolerability in these post-COVID normotensive patients was very good, the therapeutic use of nebivolol against residual and symptomatic signs of long-COVID can be suggested in out-patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Copyright: the Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dal Negro</LastName><ForeName>Roberto W</ForeName><Initials>RW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Respiratory Pharmacoeconomics and Pharmacoepidemiology - CESFAR, Verona.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turco</LastName><ForeName>Paola</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research &amp; Clinical Governance, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Povero</LastName><ForeName>Massimiliano</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research &amp; Clinical Governance, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Multidiscip Respir Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101477642</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1828-695X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nebivolol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">capillary blood volume (Vc)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lung perfusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">simultaneous DLCO and DLNO assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vascular effects</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36636645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9830396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/mrm.2022.886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhu N, Zhang D, Wang W, Li X, Yang B, Song J, et al. . A novel coronavirus from patients with pneumonia in China, 2019. N Engl J Med 2020;382:727-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31978945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matricardi PM, Dal Negro RW, Nisini R. The first, holistic immunological model of COVID-19: implications for prevention, diagnosis, and public health measures. Pediatr Allergy Immunol 2020;31:454-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32359201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorbalenya AE, Baker SC, Baric RS, de Groot RJ, Drosten C, Gulyaeva AA, et al. . The species severe acute respiratory syndrome- related coronavirus: classifying 2019-nCoV and naming it SARS-CoV-2. Nat Microbiol 2020;5:536-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32123347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woelfel R, Corman VM, Guggemos W, Seilmaier M, Zange S, Mueller MA, et al. . Clinical presentation and virological assessment of hospitalized cases of coronavirus disease 2019. medRxiv 2020.03.05.20030502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Hu B, Hu C, Zhu F, Liu X, Zhang J, et al. . Clinical characteristics of 138 hospitalized patients with 2019 novel coronavirus-infected pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA 2020;323:1061-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan W, Ni Z, Hu Y, Liang WH, Ou CQ, He JX, et al. . Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N Engl J Med 2020;382:1708-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32109013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet 2020;395:497-506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okba NMA, Muller MA, Li W, Wang C, Geurtsvan Kessel CH, Corman VM, et al. . Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2&#x2212;specific antibody responses in coronavirus disease patients. Emerg Infect Dis 2020;26:1478-88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32267220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Karoui K, Hill GS, Karras A, Jacquot C, Moulonguet L, Kourilsky O, et al. . A clinicopathologic study of thrombotic microangiopathy in IgA nephropathy. J Am Soc Nephrol 2012;23:137-48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3269921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22052055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian S, Xiong Y, Liu H, Niu L, Guo J, Liao M, et al. . Pathological study of the 2019 novel coronavirus disease (COVID-19) through postmortem core biopsies. Med Pathol 2020;33:1007-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32291399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orwoll BE, Spicer AC, Zinter MS, Alkhouli MF, Khemani RG, Flori HR, et al. . Elevated soluble thrombomodulin is associated with organ failure and mortality in children with acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS): a prospective observational cohort study. Crit Care 2015;19:435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4699329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26652251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang N, Li D, Wang X, Sun Z. Abnormal coagulation parameters are associated with poor prognosis in patients with novel coronavirus pneumonia. J Thromb Haemost 2020;18:844-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7166509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32073213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Hajizadeh N, Moore EE, McIntyre RC, Moore PK, Veress LA, et al. . Tissue plasminogen activator (tPA) treatment for COVID-19 associated acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS): A case series. J Thromb Haemost 2020;18:1752-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32267998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes JMB, Pride NB. Examination of the carbon monoxide diffusing capacity (DLCO) in relation to its KCO and VA components. Am J Respr. Crit Care Med 2012;186:132&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22538804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Lin X, Zhou Y, Yu H, Li R, Zhan Q, et al. . 3-month, 6- month. 9-month. And 12-month respiratory outcomes in patients following COVID-19 related hospitalization: a prospective study. Lancet Respir Med 2021;9:747-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8099316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33964245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frija-Masson J, Debray M-P, Gilbert M, Lescure FX, Travert F, Borie R, et al. . Functional characteristics of patients with SARS-CoV- 2 pneumonia at 30 days post-infection. Eur Resp J 2020;56:2001754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32554533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo X, Jian W, Su Z, Chen MU, Peng H, Peng P, et al. . Abnormal pulmonary function in COVID-19 patients at time of hospital discharge. Eur Respir J 2020;55:2001217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32381497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Tan C, Wu J, Chen M, Wang Z, Luo L, et al. . Impact of coronavirus disease 2019 on pulmonary function in early convalescence phase. Respir Res 2020;1:163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32600344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B, Peters JB, Brink M, Schoon Y, Bleeker-Rovers CP, Schers H, et al. . Comprehensive health assessment three months after recovery from acute COVID-19. Clin Infect Dis 2021;73:e1089-98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guenard H, Varene N, Vaida P. Determination of lung capillary blood volume and membrane diffusing capacity by measurement of NO and CO transfer. Resp Physiol 1987;70,113&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3659606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borland CDR, Hughes JMB. Lung diffusing capacities (DL) for nitric oxide (NO) and carbon monoxide (CO): The evolving story. Compr Physiol 2019;10:73&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31853952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson QH, Roughton FJW. The kinetics and equilibria of the reactions of nitric oxide with sheep haemoglobin. J Physiol 1957;136:507-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1358871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13429517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barisone G, Brusasco V. Lung diffusing capacity for nitric oxide and carbon monoxide following mild-to-severe COVID-19. Physiol Rep 2021;9:e14748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33625799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borland CD, Dunningham H, Bottrill F, Vuylsteke A, Yilmaz C, Dane DM, et al. . Significant blood resistance to nitric oxide transfer in the lung. J Appl Physiol 1985;108:1052-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20150569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zavorsky GS, Hsia CCW, Hughes JMB, Borland CDR, Guenard H, van der Lee I, et al. . Standardisation and application of the single-breath determination of nitric oxide uptake in the lung. Eur Respir J 2017;49:1600962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28179436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roughton FJ, Forster RE. Relative importance of diffusion and chemical reaction in determining rate of exchange of gases in the human lung. J Appl Physiol 1957;11:290-302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13475180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Negro RW, Turco P, Povero M. Long-lasting dyspnoea in patients otherwise clinically and radiologically recovered from COVID pneumonia: a probe for checking persisting disorders in capillary lung volume as a cause. Multidiscip Respir Med 2022;17:875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9577559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36268261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossaint R, Gerlach H, Schmidt-Ruhnke H, Pappert D, Lewandowski K, Steudel W, et al. . &#x2013; Efficacy of inhaled nitric oxide in patients with severe ARDS. Chest 1995;107:1107-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7705124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichinose F, Roberts JD, Zapol WM. Inhaled nitric oxide: a selective pulmonary vasodilator: currents uses and therapeutic potential. Circulation 2004;109:3106-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15226227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bristow M, Nelson P, Minobe W, Johnson C. Characterization of &#x3b2;1-adrenergic receptor selectivity of nebivolol and various other beta-blockers in human myocardium. Am J Hypertens 2005;18;51A-52A.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen ME, Cockroft J. The vasodilatory beta-blockers. Curr Hypertens Rep 2007;9:269-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17686376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munzel T, Gori T. Nebivolol: the somewhat different betaadrenergic receptor blocker. J Am Coll Cardiol 2009;54:1491-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19815121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fongemie J, Felix-Getzik E. A review of nebivolol pharmacology and clinical evidence. Drugs 2015;75:1349-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4541699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26177892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham BL, Brusasco V, Burgos F, Cooper BG, Jensen R, Kendrick A, et al. . ERS/ATS standards for single-breath carbon monoxide uptake in the lung. Eur Respir J 2017;49:1600016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28049168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahler DA, Wells CK. Evaluation of clinical methods for rating dyspnoea. Chest 1988;93:580-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3342669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ignarro IJ, Napoli C, Loscalzo J. Nitric oxide donors and cardiovascular agents modulating the bioactivity of nitric oxide: an overview. Circ Res 2002;90:21-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11786514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeble JE, Moore PK. Pharmacology and potential therapeutic applications of nitric oxide-releasing non-steroideal antiinflammatory and related nitric oxide-donating drugs. Br J Pharmacol 2002;137:295-310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1573498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12237248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scatena R, Bottoni P, Martorana GE, Giardina B. Nitric oxide donor drugs: an update on pathophysiology and therapeutic potential. Expert Opin Investig Drugs 2005;14:835-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16022573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason RP, Cockroft JR. Targeting nitric oxide with drug therapy. J Clin Hypert 2006;8:40-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8109704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17170605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalinowski I, Dobrocki LW, Szczepanska-Konkel M, Konkel M, Jankowski M, Martyniec L, et al. . Third-generation &#x3b2;-blockers stimulate nitric oxide release from endothelial cells through ATP efflux: a novel mechanism for antihypertensive action. Circulation 2003;107:2747-514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12742996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzemos N, Lim PO, MacDonald TM. Nebivolol reverses endothelial dysfunction in essential hypertension: a randomized, double-blind, cross-over study. Circulation 2001;104:511-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11479245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritter JM. Nebivolol: endothelium-mediasted vasodilating effect. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol 2001;38:s13-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11811387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollnau H, Schulz E, Daiber A, Baldus S, Oelze M, August M, et al. . Nebivolol prevents vascular NOS III uncoupling in experimental hyperlipidemia and inhibits NADPH oxidase activity in inflammatory cells. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 2003;23:615-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12692005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang H, Vanderpool RR, Wang J, Yuan JX. Targeting L-arginine- nitric oxide-cGMP pathway in pulmonary arterial hypertension. Pulm Circul 2017;7:569-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5841892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28895506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Alvarez A, Pereda D, Garcia-Lunar I, Sanz-Rosa A, Fernandez-Jimenez R, Garcia-Prito J, et al. . Beta-3 adrenergic agonists reduce pulmonary vascular resistance and improve right ventricular performance in a porcine model of chronic pulmonary hypertension. Basic Res Cardiol 2016;111:49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4916192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27328822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>