<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39450880</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0274</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of industrial medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Ind Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Functional disabilities and adverse well-being by COVID-19 and Long COVID history and employment status: 2022 Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ajim.23669</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Long COVID can lead to functional disabilities and decreased well-being and limit the ability to work. No study has yet assessed associations of SARS-CoV-2-infection and Long COVID with specific measures of well-being and functional disabilities among workers by employment status.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Using data from the U.S. Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System, we assessed the prevalence of functional disabilities and well-being measures among adults of prime working age (25-54 years) by employment status and self-reported COVID-19 and Long COVID history. Within each employment status, we generated adjusted prevalence ratios (aPRs) comparing respondents from each 2022 COVID-19/Long COVID category to respondents in that employment status before the pandemic (2019).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In 2022, prevalences of each functional disability except vision and all adverse well-being measures were highest among the 9.2% of respondents reporting a history of Long COVID. For each outcome, prevalences were lowest for workers and highest among those unable to work. 2022 prevalence of cognitive disability (16.4% of employees, 21.4% of the self-employed) and depression (31.2% and 36.4%, respectively) among workers reporting a history of Long COVID were more than double 2019 levels. Increases in cognitive disability and depression were lower but statistically significant among workers not reporting a history of Long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The high prevalence of functional disabilities and adverse well-being among workers reporting a history of Long COVID have implications for workers and employers. Also concerning are smaller increases among workers not reporting a history of Long COVID, given the large number of affected workers. Mitigating the effects of Long COVID on workers will involve efforts in multiple domains: reducing incidence, increasing healthcare practitioner awareness, improving diagnosis and treatments, and increasing employer awareness of best practices for accommodating workers with Long COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silver</LastName><ForeName>Sharon R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7679-5028</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Field Studies and Engineering, National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, Cincinnati, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0692-5103</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Field Studies and Engineering, National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, Cincinnati, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ford</LastName><ForeName>Nicole D</ForeName><Initials>ND</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6463-5094</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Coronaviruses and Other Respiratory Viruses Division, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, Georgia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saydah</LastName><ForeName>Sharon H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6350-5300</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Coronaviruses and Other Respiratory Viruses Division, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, Georgia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Ind Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8101110</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0271-3586</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID&#x2010;19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">employment status</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional disability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">well&#x2010;being</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39450880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajim.23669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Parotto M, Gy&#xf6;ngy&#xf6;si M, Howe K, et al. Post&#x2010;acute sequelae of COVID&#x2010;19: understanding and addressing the burden of multisystem manifestations. Lancet Respir Med. 2023;11(8):739&#x2010;754. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(23)00239-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2010;146. doi:10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheiner L, Salwati N How much is long COVID reducing labor force participation? Not much (so far). Vol. 80. 2022. Hutchins Center Working Paper. Accessed 01/15/2024. https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/WP80-Sheiner-Salwati_10.27.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tak CR. The health impact of long COVID: a cross&#x2010;sectional examination of health&#x2010;related quality of life, disability, and health status among individuals with self&#x2010;reported post&#x2010;acute sequelae of SARS CoV&#x2010;2 infection at various points of recovery. J Patient&#x2010;Reported Outcomes. 2023;7(1):31. doi:10.1186/s41687-023-00572-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe9;lez&#x2010;Santamar&#xed;a R, Fern&#xe1;ndez&#x2010;Solana J, M&#xe9;ndez&#x2010;L&#xf3;pez F, et al. Functionality, physical activity, fatigue and quality of life in patients with acute COVID&#x2010;19 and long COVID infection. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):19907. doi:10.1038/s41598-023-47218-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach K New data shows long Covid is keeping as many as 4 million people out of work. 2022. Accessed 01/15/2024. https://www.brookings.edu/articles/new-data-shows-long-covid-is-keeping-as-many-as-4-million-people-out-of-work/#:~:text=This%20report%20uses%20the%20new,work%20due%20to%20long%20Covid.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green CE, Leeds JS, Leeds CM. Occupational effects in patients with post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome. Occup Med. 2023;74(1):86&#x2010;92. doi:10.1093/occmed/kqad118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ham DI. Long&#x2010;haulers and labor market outcomes. Vol. 60 2022; Working Papers https://www.minneapolisfed.org/research/institute-working-papers/long-haulers-and-labor-market-outcomes.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon J, Milne R, Rayner C, et al Impact of long COVID on productivity and informal caregiving. Eur J Health Econ. 2023;25:1019&#x2010;1115. doi:10.1007/s10198-023-01653-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen K, Yarker J. &#x201c;It's a rollercoaster&#x201d;: the recovery and return to work experiences of workers with long COVID. Work Stress. 2023;38(2):202&#x2010;230. doi:10.1080/02678373.2023.2286654</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunt J, Hemming S, Elander J, Baraniak A, Burton K, Ellington D. Experiences of workers with post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 symptoms can signpost suitable workplace accommodations. Int J Workplace Health Manag. 2022;15(3):359&#x2010;374. doi:10.1108/IJWHM-03-2021-0075</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallegos M, Morgan ML, Burgos&#x2010;Videla C, Caycho&#x2010;Rodr&#xed;guez T, Martino P, Cervigni M. The impact of long covid on people's capacity to work. Ann Work Expo Health. 2023;67(7):801&#x2010;804. doi:10.1093/annweh/wxad029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksieck P, Ballouz T, Haile SR, et al. Post COVID&#x2010;19 condition, work ability and occupational changes in a population&#x2010;based cohort. Lancet Region Health Eur. 2023;31(23):100671. doi:10.1016/j.lanepe.2023.100671</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemh&#xf6;fer C, Sturm C, Loudovici&#x2010;Krug D, et al. Quality of life and ability to work of patients with Post&#x2010;COVID syndrome in relation to the number of existing symptoms and the duration since infection up to 12 months: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. Qual Life Res. 2023;32(7):1991&#x2010;2002. doi:10.1007/s11136-023-03369-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hair NL, Urban C. Association of severe COVID&#x2010;19 and persistent COVID&#x2010;19 symptoms with economic hardship among US families. JAMA Network Open. 2023;6(12):e2347318&#x2010;e2347318. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.47318</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ne'eman A, Maestas N. How has COVID&#x2010;19 impacted disability employment? Disabil Health J. 2023;16(2):101429. doi:10.1016/j.dhjo.2022.101429</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. Civilian labor force participation rate by age,sex, race, and ethnicity. Table 3.3. 2002, 2012, 2022, and projected 2032. Accessed 04/05/2024. https://www.bls.gov/emp/tables/civilian-labor-force-participation-rate.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonner C, Ghouralal S&#x2010;L. Long COVID and chronic conditions in the US workforce: prevalence, productivity loss, and disability. J Occup Environ Med. 2024;66(3):e80&#x2010;e86. doi:10.1097/JOM.0000000000003026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffrey K, Woolford L, Maini R, et al. Prevalence and risk factors for long COVID among adults in Scotland using electronic health records: a national, retrospective, observational cohort study. eClinicalMedicine. 2024;71:102590. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2024.102590</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell JA, Sabia S, Singh&#x2010;Manoux A, Hamer M, Kivim&#xe4;ki M. Healthy obesity and risk of accelerated functional decline and disability. Int J Obes. 2017;41(6):866&#x2010;872. doi:10.1038/ijo.2017.51</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirtori A, Brunani A, Villa V, et al. Obesity is a marker of reduction in QoL and disability. Sci World J. 2012;2012:167520. https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/action/showCitFormats?doi=10.1100%2F2012%2F167520</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ul&#x2010;Haq Z, Mackay DF, Fenwick E, Pell JP. Meta&#x2010;analysis of the association between body mass index and health&#x2010;related quality of life among adults, assessed by the SF&#x2010;36. Obesity. 2013;21(3):E322&#x2010;E327. doi:10.1002/oby.20107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graubard BI, Korn EL. Predictive margins with survey data. Biometrics. 1999;55:652&#x2010;659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou G. A modified poisson regression approach to prospective studies with binary data. Am J Epidemiol. 2004;159(7):702&#x2010;706. doi:10.1093/aje/kwh090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver SR, Li J, Quay B. Employment status, unemployment duration, and health&#x2010;related metrics among US adults of prime working age: behavioral risk factor surveillance system, 2018&#x2010;2019. Am J Ind Med. 2022;65(1):59&#x2010;71. doi:10.1002/ajim.23308</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karpman M, Zuckerman S, Morriss S. Health care access and affordability among US adults aged 18 to 64 years with self&#x2010;reported Post&#x2013;COVID&#x2010;19 condition. JAMA Network Open. 2023;6(4):e237455. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.7455</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karpman M, Fiol O, Popkin SJ, McCorkell L, Waxman E, Morriss S Employment and material hardship among adults with long COVID in December 2022. 2023. July 2023. https://www.urban.org/research/publication/employment-and-material-hardship-among-adults-long-covid-december-2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldstein LR, Edwards D, Cope JR, Hagen MB, Saydah S. Differences in report of Post&#x2010;COVID conditions among adults tested for SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 by race and ethnicity: 2022 porter novelli SummerStyles survey, U.S. AJPM Focus. 2024;3(2):100181. doi:10.1016/j.focus.2023.100181</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlis RH, Santillana M, Ognyanova K, et al. Prevalence and correlates of long COVID symptoms among US adults. JAMA Network Open. 2022;5(10):e2238804. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.38804</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlis RH, Trujillo KL, Safarpour A, et al. Research Letter: Association between long COVID symptoms and employment status. medRxiv. 2022. doi:10.1101/2022.11.17.22282452</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miskowiak KW, Pedersen JK, Gunnarsson DV, et al. Cognitive impairments among patients in a long&#x2010;COVID clinic: prevalence, pattern and relation to illness severity, work function and quality of life. J Affect Disord. 2023;324:162&#x2010;169. doi:10.1016/j.jad.2022.12.122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S, Martin EM, Reuken PA, et al. Long COVID is associated with severe cognitive slowing: a multicentre cross&#x2010;sectional study. eClinicalMedicine. 2024;68:102434. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2024.102434</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA). A Preliminary Look at the Mental Health and Substance Use&#x2010;related Effects of the COVID&#x2010;19 Pandemic (2021). Accessed 05/24/24. https://www.samhsa.gov/sites/default/files/dtac/mental-health-substance-use-effects-covid-pandemic-srb.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchflower DG, Bryson A. Long COVID in the United States. PLoS One. 2023;18(11):e0292672. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0292672</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drieskens S, Demarest S, Bel S, De Ridder K, Tafforeau J. Correction of self&#x2010;reported BMI based on objective measurements: a Belgian experience. Arch Public Health. 2018;76:10. doi:10.1186/s13690-018-0255-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connor Gorber S, Shields M, Tremblay MS, McDowell I. The feasibility of establishing correction factors to adjust self&#x2010;reported estimates of obesity. Health Rep. 2008;19(3):71&#x2010;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes AJ, Kortt MA, Clarke PM, Brandrup JD. Estimating equations to correct self&#x2010;reported height and weight: implications for prevalence of overweight and obesity in Australia. Aust N Z J Public Health. 2008;32(6):542&#x2010;545. doi:10.1111/j.1753-6405.2008.00306.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholes S, Ng Fat L, Moody A, Mindell JS. Does the use of prediction equations to correct self&#x2010;reported height and weight improve obesity prevalence estimates? A pooled cross&#x2010;sectional analysis of health survey for england data. BMJ Open. 2023;13(1):e061809. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2022-061809</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keramat SA, Alam K, Rana RH, et al. Obesity and the risk of developing chronic diseases in middle&#x2010;aged and older adults: findings from an Australian longitudinal population survey, 2009&#x2010;2017. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(11):e0260158. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0260158</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballouz T, Menges D, Anagnostopoulos A, et al. Recovery and symptom trajectories up to two years after SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection: population based, longitudinal cohort study. BMJ. 2023;381:e074425. doi:10.1136/bmj-2022-074425</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agergaard J, Gunst JD, Schi&#xf8;ttz&#x2010;Christensen B, &#xd8;stergaard L, Wejse C. Long&#x2010;term prognosis at 1.5 years after infection with wild&#x2010;type strain of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 and alpha, delta, as well as omicron variants. Int J Infect Dis. 2023;137:126&#x2010;133. doi:10.1016/j.ijid.2023.10.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montoy JCC, Ford J, Yu H, et al. Prevalence of symptoms &#x2264;12 months after acute illness, by COVID&#x2010;19 testing status among adults &#x2010; United States, December 2020&#x2010;March 2023. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2023;72(32):859&#x2010;865. doi:10.15585/mmwr.mm7232a2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford ND, Slaughter D, Edwards D, et al. Long COVID and significant activity limitation among adults, by age &#x2010; United States, June 1&#x2010;13, 2022, to June 7&#x2010;19, 2023. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2023;72(32):866&#x2010;870. doi:10.15585/mmwr.mm7232a3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez&#x2010;Pozas O, Mel&#xe9;ndez&#x2010;Oliva E, Rolando LM. et. al. the pulmonary rehabilitation effect on long covid&#x2010;19 syndrome: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Physiother Res Int. 2024;29(2):e2077. doi:10.1002/pri.2077</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astin R, Banerjee A, Baker MR, et al. Long COVID: mechanisms, risk factors and recovery. Exp Physiol. 2023;108:12&#x2010;27. doi:10.1113/EP090802</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bland AR, Barraclough M, Trender WR, et al. Profiles of objective and subjective cognitive function in Post&#x2010;COVID syndrome, COVID&#x2010;19 recovered, and COVID&#x2010;19 na&#xef;ve individuals. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):13368. doi:10.1038/s41598-024-62050-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Academy of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation. Multidisciplinary Quality Improvement Initiative: Published Guidance. https://www.aapmr.org/advocacy/current-priorities/long-covid-pasc/multidisciplinary-quality-improvement-initiative?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=AAPMR Accessed 08/20/2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Boon GJAM, Barco S, et al. The Post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 functional status scale: a tool to measure functional status over time after COVID&#x2010;19. Eur Respir J. 2020;56(1):2001494. doi:10.1183/13993003.01494-2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fancourt D, Steptoe A, Bu F. Psychological consequences of long COVID: comparing trajectories of depressive and anxiety symptoms before and after contracting SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 between matched long&#x2010; and short&#x2010;COVID groups. Br J Psychiatry. 2023;222(2):74&#x2010;81. doi:10.1192/bjp.2022.155</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB, L&#xf6;we B. An ultra&#x2010;brief screening scale for anxiety and depression: the PHQ&#x2010;4. Psychosomatics. 2009;50(6):613&#x2010;621. doi:10.1097/PSY.0000000000000322</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones JM, Manrique IM, Stone MS, et al. Estimates of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 seroprevalence and incidence of primary SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infections among blood donors, by COVID&#x2010;19 vaccination status &#x2010; United States, April 2021&#x2010;September 2022. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2023;72(22):601&#x2010;605. doi:10.15585/mmwr.mm7222a3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg&#x2010;Morris L, Leach S, Xu Y, et al. Covid&#x2010;19 vaccine effectiveness against post&#x2010;covid&#x2010;19 condition among 589&#x2009;722 individuals in Sweden: population based cohort study. BMJ. 2023;383:e076990. doi:10.1136/bmj-2023-076990</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Z, Stallings&#x2010;Smith S, Patel S, Case S, Hong Y&#x2010;R. COVID&#x2010;19 booster vaccine uptake and reduced risks for long&#x2010;COVID: A cross&#x2010;sectional study of a U.S. adult population. Vaccine. 2024;42(16):3529&#x2010;3535. doi:10.1016/j.vaccine.2024.04.070</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Zhao H, Shannon CP, Tebbutt SJ. Omicron variants of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 and long COVID. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1061686. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2022.1061686</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boufidou F, Medi&#x107; S, Lampropoulou V, Siafakas N, Tsakris A, Anastassopoulou C. SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 reinfections and long COVID in the Post&#x2010;Omicron phase of the pandemic. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(16):12962. doi:10.3390/ijms241612962</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, MacIntyre CR, Baker MG, et al. Masks and respirators for prevention of respiratory infections: a state of the science review. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2024;37:e00124&#x2010;23. doi:10.1128/cmr.00124-23</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izadyar N, Miller W. Ventilation strategies and design impacts on indoor airborne transmission: A review. Building Environ. 2022;218:109158. doi:10.1016/j.buildenv.2022.109158</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards CH, Tomba GS, de Blasio BF. Influenza in workplaces: transmission, workers&#x2019; adherence to sick leave advice and European sick leave recommendations. Eur J Public Health. 2016;26(3):478&#x2010;485. doi:10.1093/eurpub/ckw031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packard SE, Susser E. Association of long COVID with housing insecurity in the United States, 2022&#x2013;2023. SSM &#x2010; Population Health. 2024;25:101586. doi:10.1016/j.ssmph.2023.101586</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford ND, Slaughter D, Dalton AF, et al. Health insurance and access to care in U.S. working age adults experiencing long COVID. Am J Prev Med. 2024;67:530&#x2010;539. doi:10.1016/j.amepre.2024.05.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Li Y, Wang Z, Liu N, He L, Zhang H. Increased risk of new&#x2010;onset diabetes in patients with COVID&#x2010;19: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1170156. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2023.1170156</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollop C, Zingel R, Jacob L, Smith L, Koyanagi A, Kostev K. Incidence of newly&#x2010;diagnosed dementia after COVID&#x2010;19 infection versus acute upper respiratory infection: A retrospective cohort study. J Alzheimer's Dis. 2023;93:1033&#x2010;1040. doi:10.3233/JAD-221271</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koyama AK, Imperatore G, Rolka DB, et al. Risk of cardiovascular disease after COVID&#x2010;19 diagnosis among adults with and without diabetes. J Am Heart Assoc. 2023;12(13):e029696. doi:10.1161/jaha.123.029696</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marjenberg Z, Leng S, Tascini C, et al. Risk of long COVID main symptoms after SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):15332. doi:10.1038/s41598-023-42321-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez Jimenez B, Sterling T, Brown A, et al. Wastewater surveillance in the COVID&#x2010;19 post&#x2010;emergency pandemic period: A promising approach to monitor and predict SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 surges and evolution. Heliyon. 2023;9(11):e22356. doi:10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e22356</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>