<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36274177</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1751-0759</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BioPsychoSocial medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biopsychosoc Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Global prevalence of chronic fatigue syndrome among long COVID-19 patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>21</StartPage><MedlinePgn>21</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">21</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13030-022-00250-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Chronic fatigue syndrome is a persistent and debilitating disorder. According to several studies, chronic fatigue syndrome has been identified among recovered COVID-19 patients as the most common symptom of long COVID. The aim of this systematic review and meta-analysis study was to obtain the prevalence of chronic fatigue syndrome in long COVID cases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this systematic review and meta-analysis, we analysed reported results of studies that assessed the occurrence of chronic fatigue syndrome among COVID-19 patients four weeks after the onset of symptoms. The study selection was commenced by searching PubMed, Web of Science, Science Direct, Scopus, Embase, and Google scholar using the keywords of Chronic fatigue syndrome, COVID-19, and post-COVID-19 syndrome. The searches were without a lower time limit and until April 2022. Heterogeneity of studies was assessed using the I<sup>2</sup> index, and a random effects model was used for analysis. Data analysis was performed within the Comprehensive Meta-Analysis software (version 2).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The pooled prevalence of chronic fatigue syndrome four weeks after the onset of COVID-19 symptoms, in 52 studies with a sample size of 127,117, was 45.2% (95% CI: 34.1-56.9%). Meta-regression analysis in examining the effects of the two factors of sample size, and year of study on the changes in the overall prevalence, showed that with increasing sample size, and year of study, the prevalence of chronic fatigue syndrome among long COVID patients (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results show that the overall prevalence of chronic fatigue syndrome as a long COVID symptom is 45.2%. Chronic fatigue after infection with COVID-19 can negatively affect personal and social lives. Given such significant negative consequences caused by the syndrome, it is recommended that health policymakers allocate funds to reduce the adverse effects of this syndrome, by creating programs to support long COVID patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salari</LastName><ForeName>Nader</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, School of Health, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khodayari</LastName><ForeName>Yassaman</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosseinian-Far</LastName><ForeName>Amin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Business Systems &amp; Operations, University of Northampton, Northampton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zarei</LastName><ForeName>Hosna</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rasoulpoor</LastName><ForeName>Shabnam</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatric Nursing, School of Nursing and Midwifery, Urmia University of Medical Sciences, Urmia, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akbari</LastName><ForeName>Hakimeh</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cellular and Molecular Research Center, Gerash University of Medical Sciences, Gerash, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammadi</LastName><ForeName>Masoud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5722-8300</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cellular and Molecular Research Center, Gerash University of Medical Sciences, Gerash, Iran. Masoud.mohammadi1989@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Biopsychosoc Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101286572</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1751-0759</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic fatigue syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36274177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9589726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13030-022-00250-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13030-022-00250-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pollard CA, Morran MP, Nestor-Kalinoski AL. The COVID-19 pandemic: a global health crisis. Physiol Genom. 2020;52(11):549&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7686876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Clinical management of severe acute respiratory infection (SARI) when COVID-19 disease is suspected: interim guidance, 13 March 2020. World Health Organization; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuki K, Fujiogi M, Koutsogiannaki S. COVID-19 pathophysiology: A review. Clin Immunol. 2020;215:108427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7169933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian S, Chang Z, Wang Y, Wu M, Zhang W, Zhou G, et al. Clinical characteristics and reasons for differences in duration from symptom onset to release from quarantine among patients with COVID-19 in Liaocheng, China. Front Med. 2020;7:210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7235406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32574322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Gennaro F, Pizzol D, Marotta C, Antunes M, Racalbuto V, Veronese N, et al. Coronavirus diseases (COVID-19) current status and future perspectives: a narrative review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(8):2690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32295188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somani S, Agnihotri SP. Emerging neurology of COVID-19. The Neurohospitalist. 2020;10(4):281&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7495702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32983347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao R, Qiu Y, He J-S, Tan J-Y, Li X-H, Liang J, et al. Manifestations and prognosis of gastrointestinal and liver involvement in patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;5(7):667&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7217643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32405603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCorkell L, Assaf GS, Davis HE, Wei H, Akrami A. Patient-Led Research Collaborative: embedding patients in the Long COVID narrative. Pain reports. 2021;6(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8112577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33987484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havervall S, Rosell A, Phillipson M, Mangsbo SM, Nilsson P, Hober S, et al. Symptoms and functional impairment assessed 8 months after mild COVID-19 among health care workers. JAMA. 2021;325(19):2015&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8027932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33825846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin L, Savale L, Pham T, Colle R, Figueiredo S, Harrois A, et al. Four-month clinical status of a cohort of patients after hospitalization for COVID-19. JAMA. 2021;325(15):1525&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7970386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33729425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alpert O, Begun L, Garren P, Solhkhah R. Cytokine storm induced new onset depression in patients with COVID-19. A new look into the association between depression and cytokines-two case reports. Brain, Behavior, &amp; Immunity-Health. 2020;9:100173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7606074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33163979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dicpinigaitis PV, Canning BJ. Is there (will there be) a post-COVID-19 chronic cough? Springer; 2020. pp.863&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33188436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KG-I, Brokstad KA, Zhou F, Linchausen DW, Hansen B-A, et al. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med. 2021;27(9):1607&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K, Straus SE, Hickie I, Sharpe MC, Dobbins JG, Komaroff A, et al. The chronic fatigue syndrome: a comprehensive approach to its definition and study. Ann Intern Med. 1994;121(12):953&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7978722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pendergrast T, Brown A, Sunnquist M, Jantke R, Newton JL, Strand EB, et al. Housebound versus nonhousebound patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis and chronic fatigue syndrome. Chronic Illn. 2016;12(4):292&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5464362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27127189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts D. Chronic fatigue syndrome and quality of life. Patient Relat outcome measures. 2018;9:253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6078083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30123017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carruthers BM, Jain AK, De Meirleir KL, Peterson DL, Klimas NG, Lerner AM, et al. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: clinical working case definition, diagnostic and treatment protocols. J chronic fatigue syndrome. 2003;11(1):7&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clayton EW. Beyond myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: an IOM report on redefining an illness. JAMA. 2015;313(11):1101&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25668027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carruthers BM, van de Sande MI, De Meirleir KL, Klimas NG, Broderick G, Mitchell T, et al. Myalgic encephalomyelitis: international consensus criteria. J Intern Med. 2011;270(4):327&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3427890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21777306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brurberg KG, F&#xf8;nhus MS, Larun L, Flottorp S, Malterud K. Case definitions for chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME): a systematic review. BMJ open. 2014;4(2):e003973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3918975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24508851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bombardier CH, Buchwald D. Chronic fatigue, chronic fatigue syndrome, and fibromyalgia: disability and health-care use. Medical care. 1996:924 &#x2013; 30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8792781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchwald D, Pearlman T, Umali J, Schmaling K, Katon W. Functional status in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome, other fatiguing illnesses, and healthy individuals. Am J Med. 1996;101(4):364&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8873506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bierle DM, Aakre CA, Grach SL, Salonen BR, Croghan IT, Hurt RT, et al. Central Sensitization Phenotypes in Post Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection (PASC): Defining the Post COVID Syndrome. J Prim care community health. 2021;12:21501327211030826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8267019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34231404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aly MAEG, Saber HG. Long COVID and chronic fatigue syndrome: A survey of elderly female survivors in Egypt. International Journal of Clinical Practice. 2021;75(12).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8646426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34537995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anjana NKN, Annie TT, Siba S, Meenu MS, Chintha S, Anish TSN. Manifestations and risk factors of post COVID syndrome among COVID-19 patients presented with minimal symptoms - A study from Kerala, India. J Family Med Prim Care. 2021;10(11):4023&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8797119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35136762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA, Nemati H, Shahisavandi M, Akbari A, Emami A, Lotfi M, et al. Long COVID in children and adolescents. World J Pediatr. 2021;17(5):495&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8414448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34478045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin M, Schommers P, Stecher M, Dewald F, Gieselmann L, Gruell H, et al. Post-COVID syndrome in non-hospitalised patients with COVID-19: a longitudinal prospective cohort study. Lancet Regional Health-Europe. 2021;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8129613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34027514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell ML, Catalfamo CJ, Farland LV, Ernst KC, Jacobs ET, Klimentidis YC, et al. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 in a non-hospitalized cohort: Results from the Arizona CoVHORT. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(8 August).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8336814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34347785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bliddal S, Banasik K, Pedersen OB, Nissen J, Cantwell L, Schwinn M, et al. Acute and persistent symptoms in non-hospitalized PCR-confirmed COVID-19 patients. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):13153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8222239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34162913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KGI, Brokstad KA, Zhou F, Linchausen DW, Hansen BA, et al. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med. 2021;27(9):1607&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouteleux B, Henrot P, Ernst R, Grassion L, Raherison-Semjen C, Beaufils F, et al. Respiratory rehabilitation for COVID-19 related persistent dyspnoea: A one-year experience. Respiratory Medicine. 2021;189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8511554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34689061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brackel CLH, Lap CR, Buddingh EP, van Houten MA, van der Sande LJTM, Langereis EJ, et al. Pediatric long-COVID: An overlooked phenomenon? Pediatr Pulmonol. 2021;56(8):2495&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34102037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra N, Chowdhury M, Singh AK, Khan MA, Kumar A, Ranjan P, et al. Clinical predictors of long COVID-19 and phenotypes of mild COVID-19 at a tertiary care centre in India. Drug Discoveries and Therapeutics. 2021;15(3):156&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34234065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;il B, Kabak M. Persistent Post-COVID Symptoms and the Related Factors. Turk Thorac J. 2022;23(1):6&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9449913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35110194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erol N, Alpinar A, Erol C, Sari E, Alkan K. Persistent Post-COVID Symptoms and the Related Factors. Cardiology in the Young. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesh R, Ghosh AK, Nyman MA, Croghan IT, Grach SL, Anstine CV, et al. PROMIS Scales for Assessment of Persistent Post-COVID Symptoms: A Cross Sectional Study. J Prim care community health. 2021;12:21501327211030413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8267017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34231395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Andrade F. Post-COVID-19 conditions in Ecuadorian patients: an observational study. Lancet Reg Health Americas. 2022;5:100088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8633922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34870261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal A, Iqbal K, Ali SA, Azim D, Farid E, Baig MD, et al. The COVID-19 sequelae: a cross-sectional evaluation of post-recovery symptoms and the need for rehabilitation of COVID-19 survivors. Cureus. 2021;13(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7932827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33680620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam MS, Ferdous MZ, Islam US, Mosaddek ASM, Potenza MN, Pardhan S. Treatment, persistent symptoms, and depression in people infected with COVID-19 in bangladesh. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(4):1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7914967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33562427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayaaslan B, Eser F, Kalem AK, Kaya G, Kaplan B, Kacar D, et al. Post-COVID syndrome: A single-center questionnaire study on 1007 participants recovered from COVID-19. J Med Virol. 2021;93(12):6566&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8426910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34255355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemh&#xf6;fer C, Sturm C, Loudovici-Krug D, Best N, Gutenbrunner C. The impact of Post-COVID-Syndrome on functioning - results from a community survey in patients after mild and moderate SARS-CoV-2-infections in Germany. J Occup Med Toxicol (London England) 2021;16(1):45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8495185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34620202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirfazeli F, Sarabi-Jamab A, Shariati B, Shariat SV, Bahrami S, Nohesara S, et al. Acute phase clinical manifestation of COVID-19 is linked to long-COVID symptoms; A 9-month follow-up study. medRxiv. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8776380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35059902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, Bobkova P, Spiridonova E, Shikhaleva A, Gamirova A, Blyuss O, et al. Incidence and risk factors for persistent symptoms in adults previously hospitalized for COVID-19. Clin experimental allergy: J Br Soc Allergy Clin Immunol. 2021;51(9):1107&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34351016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nesan GSCQ, Keerthana D, Yamini R, Jain T, Kumar D, Eashwer A, et al. 3-Month Symptom-Based Ambidirectional Follow-up Study Among Recovered COVID-19 Patients from a Tertiary Care Hospital Using Telehealth in Chennai, India. Inquiry. 2021;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8721686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34915771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parisi GF, Diaferio L, Brindisi G, Indolfi C, Umano GR, Klain A, et al. Cross-Sectional Survey on Long Term Sequelae of Pediatric COVID-19 among Italian Pediatricians. Children. 2021;8(9):769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8467017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34572201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razai MS, Al-Bedaery R, Anand L, Fitch K, Okechukwu H, Saraki TM, et al. Patients&#x2019; Experiences of &#x201c;Long COVID&#x201d; in the Community and Recommendations for Improving Services: A Quality Improvement Survey. J Prim care community health. 2021;12:21501327211041846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8427922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34488505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Righi E, Mirandola M, Mazzaferri F, Dossi G, Razzaboni E, Zaffagnini A, et al. Determinants of persistence of symptoms and impact on physical and mental wellbeing in Long COVID: A prospective cohort study. J Infect. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8828388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35150765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roge I, Smane L, Kivite-Urtane A, Pucuka Z, Racko I, Klavina L, et al. Comparison of Persistent Symptoms After COVID-19 and Other Non-SARS-CoV-2 Infections in Children. Frontiers in pediatrics. 2021;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8586002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34778143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>See&#xdf;le J, Waterboer T, Hippchen T, Simon J, Kirchner M, Lim A, et al. Persistent symptoms in adult patients one year after COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Clinical infectious diseases: an official publication of the Infectious Diseases Society of America; 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34223884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultana S, Islam MT, Salwa M, Zakir Hossain SM, Hasan MN, Masum AA, et al. Duration and Risk Factors of Post-COVID Symptoms Following Recovery Among the Medical Doctors in Bangladesh. Cureus. 2021;13(5):e15351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8245646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34239785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Husain M, Harrison PJ. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: A 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Medicine. 2021;18(9).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor RR, Trivedi B, Patel N, Singh R, Ricketts WM, Elliott K, et al. Post-COVID symptoms reported at asynchronous virtual review and stratified follow-up after COVID-19 pneumonia. Clinical medicine (London, England). 2021;21(4):e384-e91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8313189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34103378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titze-de-Almeida R, da Cunha TR, dos Santos Silva LD, Ferreira CS, Silva CP, Ribeiro AP, et al. Persistent, new-onset symptoms and mental health complaints in Long COVID in a Brazilian cohort of non-hospitalized patients. BMC Infectious Diseases. 2022;22(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8821794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35135496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomar BS, Singh M, Nathiya D, Sharma A, Sharma E, Bareth H, et al. Prevalence of symptoms in patients discharged from COVID care facility of nims hospital: Is rt pcr negativity truly reflecting recovery? A single-centre observational study. Int J Gen Med. 2021;14:1069&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33790636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanichkachorn G, Newcomb R, Cowl CT, Murad MH, Breeher L, Miller S, et al. Post-COVID-19 Syndrome (Long Haul Syndrome): Description of a Multidisciplinary Clinic at Mayo Clinic and Characteristics of the Initial Patient Cohort. Mayo Clin Proc. 2021;96(7):1782-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8112396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34218857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanga V, Chevinsky JR, Dimitrov LV, Gerdes ME, Whitfield GP, Bonacci RA, et al. Long-Term Symptoms Among Adults Tested for SARS-CoV-2 - United States, January 2020-April 2021. MMWR Morbidity and mortality weekly report. 2021;70(36):1235&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8437054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34499626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F, Tomasoni D, Falcinella C, Barbanotti D, Castoldi R, Mul&#xe8; G, et al. Female gender is associated with long COVID syndrome: a prospective cohort study. Clinical microbiology and infection: the official publication of the European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik S, Haldar SN, Soneja M, Mundadan NG, Garg P, Mittal A, et al. Post COVID-19 sequelae: A prospective observational study from Northern India. Drug discoveries &amp; therapeutics. 2021;15(5):254&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34719599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaksi N, Teker AG, Imre A, Long COVID in Hospitalized COVID-19 Patients: A Retrospective Cohort Study. Iran J Public Health. 2022;51(1):88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8837882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35223629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simani L, Ramezani M, Darazam IA, Sagharichi M, Aalipour MA, Ghorbani F, et al. Prevalence and correlates of chronic fatigue syndrome and post-traumatic stress disorder after the outbreak of the COVID-19. J Neurovirol. 2021;27(1):154&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7852482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33528827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Herck M, Go&#xeb;rtz YMJ, Houben-Wilke S, Machado FVC, Meys R, Delbressine JM, et al. Severe fatigue in long COVID: Web-based quantitative follow-up study in members of online long COVID support groups. Journal of Medical Internet Research. 2021;23(9).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8457337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34494964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bungenberg J, Humkamp K, Hohenfeld C, Rust MI, Ermis U, Dreher M, et al. Long COVID-19: Objectifying most self-reported neurological symptoms. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2022;9(2):141&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8862437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35060361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Yu T, Du R, Fan G, Liu Y, Liu Z, et al. Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a retrospective cohort study. The lancet. 2020;395(10229):1054&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32171076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, Brown JS, Denneny EK, Hare SS, et al. &#x2018;Long-COVID&#x2019;: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76(4):396&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a M, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, de-la-Llave-Rinc&#xf3;n AI, et al. Fatigue and dyspnoea as main persistent post-COVID-19 symptoms in previously hospitalized patients: related functional limitations and disability. Respiration. 2022;101(2):132&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8678253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34569550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Q, Xu M, Li J, Liu Y, Zhang J, Xu Y, et al. Clinical sequelae of COVID-19 survivors in Wuhan, China: a single-centre longitudinal study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27(1):89&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7510771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32979574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson KB, Rao M, Bonilla H, Subramanian A, Hack I, Madrigal M, et al. Patients with uncomplicated coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) have long-term persistent symptoms and functional impairment similar to patients with severe COVID-19: a cautionary tale during a global pandemic. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73(3):e826-e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33624010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzat MM, Elsherif AA. Prevalence of fatigue in patients post COVID-19. Eur J Mol Clin Med. 2021;8(3):1330&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hermosillo JA, Mart&#xed;nez-L&#xf3;pez JP, Carrillo-Lamp&#xf3;n SA, Ruiz-Ojeda D, Herrera-Ram&#xed;rez S, Amezcua-Guerra LM, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 symptoms, a potential link with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a 6-month survey in a Mexican cohort. Brain Sci. 2021;11(6):760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8227652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34201087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross&#x2010;sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93(2):1013&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D, Zhang W, Pan F, Li L, Yang L, Zheng D, et al. The pulmonary sequalae in discharged patients with COVID-19: a short-term observational study. Respir Res. 2020;21(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32448391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabacof L, Tosto-Mancuso J, Wood J, Cortes M, Kontorovich A, McCarthy D, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome negatively impacts health and wellbeing despite less severe acute infection. MedRxiv. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs LG, Gourna Paleoudis E, Lesky-Di Bari D, Nyirenda T, Friedman T, Gupta A, et al. Persistence of symptoms and quality of life at 35 days after hospitalization for COVID-19 infection. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(12):e0243882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7732078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou S, Liu Z-H, Yan X, Wang H, Li Y, Xu X, et al. Prevalence and correlates of fatigue and its association with quality of life among clinically stable older psychiatric patients during the COVID-19 outbreak: a cross-sectional study. Globalization and Health. 2020;16(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7748982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33339523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salari N, Hosseinian-Far A, Jalali R, Vaisi-Raygani A, Rasoulpoor S, Mohammadi M, et al. Prevalence of stress, anxiety, depression among the general population during the COVID-19 pandemic: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Globalization and health. 2020;16(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7338126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32631403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George PM, Barratt SL, Condliffe R, Desai SR, Devaraj A, Forrest I, et al. Respiratory follow-up of patients with COVID-19 pneumonia. Thorax. 2020;75(11):1009&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32839287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, Rose EB, Shapiro NI, Files DC, et al. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network&#x2014;United States, March&#x2013;June 2020. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69(30):993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaes AW, Go&#xeb;rtz YM, Van Herck M, Machado FV, Meys R, Delbressine JM, et al. Recovery from COVID-19: a sprint or marathon? 6-month follow-up data from online long COVID-19 support group members. ERJ open research. 2021;7(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8012818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34041295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belli S, Balbi B, Prince I, Cattaneo D, Masocco F, Zaccaria S, et al. Low physical functioning and impaired performance of activities of daily life in COVID-19 patients who survived hospitalisation. European Respiratory Journal. 2020;56(4).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7411272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32764112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, Dunne J, Mooney A, Gaffney F, et al. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(11):e0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner P. COVID-19 and fatigue&#x2014;a game of snakes and ladders. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphreys H, Kilby L, Kudiersky N, Copeland R. Long COVID and the role of physical activity: a qualitative study. BMJ open. 2021;11(3):e047632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7948149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabes-Figuera R, McCrone P, Hurley M, King M, Donaldson AN, Ridsdale L. The hidden cost of chronic fatigue to patients and their families. BMC Health Serv Res. 2010;10(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2845126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20202216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrone P, Darbishire L, Ridsdale L, Seed P. The economic cost of chronic fatigue and chronic fatigue syndrome in UK primary care. Psychol Med. 2003;33(2):253&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12622304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brackel CL, Lap CR, Buddingh EP, van Houten MA, van der Sande LJ, Langereis EJ, et al. Pediatric long-COVID: An overlooked phenomenon? Pediatr Pulmonol. 2021;56(8):2495&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34102037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez O, Merino E, Leon-Ramirez J-M, Andres M, Ramos JM, Arenas-Jim&#xe9;nez J, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Incidence and risk factors: A Mediterranean cohort study. J Infect. 2021;82(3):378&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7802523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra V, Flanders SA, O&#x2019;Malley M, Malani AN, Prescott HC. Sixty-day outcomes among patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174(4):576&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7707210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher A, Balfanz P, Cornelissen C, M&#xfc;ller A, Bergs I, Marx N, et al. Follow up of patients with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): Pulmonary and extrapulmonary disease sequelae. Respir Med. 2020;174:106197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33120193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westerlind E, Palstam A, Sunnerhagen KS, Persson HC. Patterns and predictors of sick leave after COVID-19 and long COVID in a national Swedish cohort. BMC Public Health. 2021;21(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8164957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34059034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>