<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35787539</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Movement disorders in COVID-19 times: impact on care in movement disorders and Parkinson disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>494</StartPage><EndPage>501</EndPage><MedlinePgn>494-501</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001075</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">The purpose of this review is to outline the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on movement disorder holistic care, particularly in the care of people with Parkinson disease (PWP).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">As the pandemic unfolds, a flurry of literature was published regarding the impact of COVID-19 on people with Parkinson disease including the direct impact of infection, availability of ambulatory care, loss of community-based team care, and acceptability of telemedicine.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">COVID-19 has impacted the care of PWP in numerous ways. Recognizing infection in PWP poses challenges. Specific long-term complications, including emerging reports of long COVID syndrome is a growing concern. Caregivers and PWP have also been impacted by COVID-19 social isolation restrictions, with radical changes to the structure of social networks and support systems globally. In a matter of weeks, the global community saw an incredible uptake in telemedicine, which brought benefits and pitfalls. As PWP adapted to virtual platforms and the changing architecture of care delivery, the pandemic amplified many preexisting inequities amongst populations and countries, exposing a new 'digital divide'.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poonja</LastName><ForeName>Sabrina</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaudhuri</LastName><ForeName>K Ray</ForeName><Initials>KR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Basic and Clinical Neurosciences, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp; Neuroscience, King's College London, and. Parkinson's Foundation Centre of Excellence, King's College Hospital, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyasaki</LastName><ForeName>Janis M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009069" MajorTopicYN="Y">Movement Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="Y">Telemedicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35787539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202208000-00009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Schwartz AE, Munsell EGS, Schmidt EK, et al. Impact of COVID-19 on services for people with disabilities and chronic health conditions. Disabil Health J 2021; 14:101090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budu MO, Rugel EJ, Nocos R, et al. Psychological impact of COVID-19 on people with pre-existing chronic disease. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021; 18:5972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian I, Hinkle JT, Chaudhuri KR, et al. Mind the gap: Inequalities in mental healthcare and lack of social support in Parkinson disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2021; 93:97&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes-S&#xe1;nchez F, Basto-Abreu A, Torres-Alvarez R, et al. Fraction of COVID-19 hospitalizations and deaths attributable to chronic diseases. medRxiv 2021; 155:106917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherbaum R, Kwon EH, Richter D, et al. Clinical profiles and mortality of COVID-19 inpatients with Parkinson's disease in Germany. Mov Disord 2021; 36:1049&#x2013;1057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonini A, Leta V, Teo J, et al. Outcome of Parkinson's disease patients affected by COVID-19. Mov Disord 2020; 35:905&#x2013;908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagano G, Ferrara N, Brooks DJ, et al. Age at onset and Parkinson disease phenotype. Neurology 2016; 86:1400&#x2013;1407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artusi CA, Romagnolo A, Imbalzano G, et al. COVID-19 in Parkinson's disease: report on prevalence and outcome. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2020; 80:7&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoshnood RJ, Zali A, Tafreshinejad A, et al. Parkinson's disease and COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurol Sci 2022; 43:775&#x2013;783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambergo-Michilot D, Barros-Sevillano S, Rivera-Torrej&#xf3;n O, et al. Factors associated with COVID-19 in people with Parkinson's disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Neurol 2021; 28:3467&#x2013;3477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Qushayri AE, Ghozy S, Reda A, et al. The impact of Parkinson's disease on manifestations and outcomes of Covid-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Rev Med Virol 2022; 32:e2278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leta V, Rodr&#xed;guez-Violante M, Abundes A, et al. Parkinson's disease and post-COVID-19 syndrome: the Parkinson's Long-COVID Spectrum. Mov Disord 2021; 36:1287&#x2013;1289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nouchi A, Chastang J, Miyara M, et al. Prevalence of hyposmia and hypogeusia in 390 COVID-19 hospitalized patients and outpatients: a cross-sectional study. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis 2021; 40:691&#x2013;697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Ghebremedhin E, R&#xfc;b U, et al. Stages in the development of Parkinson's disease-related pathology. Cell Tissue Res 2004; 318:121&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z, Zhang X, Huang Z, Ma K. SARS-CoV-2 proteins interact with alpha synuclein and induce lewy body-like pathology in vitro. Int J Mol Sci 2022; 23:3394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bantle CM, Phillips AT, Smeyne RJ, et al. Infection with mosquito-borne alphavirus induces selective loss of dopaminergic neurons, neuroinflammation and widespread protein aggregation. NPJ Parkinsons Dis 2019; 5:20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolzenberg E, Berry D, Yang D, et al. A role for neuronal alpha-synuclein in gastrointestinal immunity. J Innate Immun 2017; 9:456&#x2013;463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labrie V, Brundin P. Alpha-synuclein to the rescue: immune cell recruitment by alpha-synuclein during gastrointestinal infection. J Innate Immun 2017; 9:437&#x2013;440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross GW, Petrovitch H, Abbott RD, et al. Association of olfactory dysfunction with risk for future Parkinson's disease. Ann Neurol 2008; 63:167&#x2013;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F, et al. SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature 2022; 604:697&#x2013;707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Rus Jacquet A, Bogard S, Normandeau CP, et al. Clinical perception and management of Parkinson's disease during the COVID-19 pandemic: a Canadian experience. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2021; 91:66&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhuri KR, Rukavina K, McConvey V, et al. The impact of COVID-19 on palliative care for people with Parkinson's and response to future pandemics. Expert Rev Neurother 2021; 21:615&#x2013;623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian I, Farahnik J, Mischley LK. Synergy of pandemics-social isolation is associated with worsened Parkinson severity and quality of life. NPJ Parkinsons Dis 2020; 6:28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macchi ZA, Ayele R, Dini M, et al. Lessons from the COVID-19 pandemic for improving outpatient neuropalliative care: a qualitative study of patient and caregiver perspectives. Palliat Med 2021; 35:1258&#x2013;1266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duits AA, Boots LMM, Mulders AEP, et al. Covid proof self-management training for caregivers of patients with Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord 2021; 36:529&#x2013;530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oppo V, Serra G, Fenu G, et al. Parkinson's disease symptoms have a distinct impact on caregivers&#x2019; and patients&#x2019; stress: a study assessing the consequences of the COVID-19 lockdown. Mov Disord Clin Pract 2020; 7:865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalash A, Spindler M, Cubo E. Global perspective on telemedicine for Parkinson's disease. J Parkinsons Dis 2021; 11:S11&#x2013;S18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novara G, Checcucci E, Crestani A, et al. Telehealth in urology: a systematic review of the literature. how much can telemedicine be useful during and after the COVID-19 pandemic? Eur Urol 2020; 78:786&#x2013;811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan E-K, Albanese A, Chaudhuri K, et al. Adapting to post-COVID19 research in Parkinson's disease: lessons from a multinational experience. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2021; 82:146&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdolahi A, Scoglio N, Killoran A, et al. Potential reliability and validity of a modified version of the Unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale that could be administered remotely. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2013; 19:218&#x2013;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetz CG, Stebbins GT, Luo S. Movement Disorder Society-Unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale use in the covid-19 era. Mov Disord 2020; 35:911&#x2013;1911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartella SM, Terranova C, Rizzo V, et al. Covid-19 and Parkinson's disease: an overview. J Neurol 2021; 268:4415&#x2013;4421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberts JL, Koop MM, McGinley MP, et al. Use of a smartphone to gather Parkinson's disease neurological vital signs during the covid-19 pandemic. Parkinsons Dis 2021; 2021:5534282&#x2013;15534282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian I. Virtual Parkinson's disease support groups in the covid-19 era: social connection in the time of social distancing. Mov Disord Clin Pract 2020; 7:739&#x2013;740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Prete E, Francesconi A, Palermo G, et al. Prevalence and impact of COVID-19 in Parkinson's disease: evidence from a multicenter survey in Tuscany region. J Neurol 2021; 268:1179&#x2013;1187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeb W, Hess CW, Gamez N, et al. Response to telemedicine visits from patients with parkinsonism during the COVID-19 pandemic on postvisit surveys. J Patient Exp 2021; 8:2374373521997224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riggare S, Stamford J, H&#xe4;gglund M. A long way to go: patient perspectives on digital health for Parkinson's disease. J Parkinsons Dis 2021; 11:S5&#x2013;S10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motolese F, Magliozzi A, Puttini F, et al. Parkinson's disease remote patient monitoring during the COVID-19 lockdown. Front Neurol 2020; 11:567413&#x2013;567413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaskar S, Bradley S, Israeli-Korn S, et al. Chronic neurology in COVID-19 era: clinical considerations and recommendations from the REPROGRAM Consortium. Front Neurol 2020; 11:664&#x2013;664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piano C, Bove F, Tufo T, et al. Effects of COVID-19 lockdown on movement disorders patients with deep brain stimulation: a multicenter survey. Front Neurol 2020; 11:616550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erro R, Scannapieco S, Russo M, et al. Impact of COVID-19 on neurological patients attending a botulinum toxin service. Neurol Sci 2021; 42:433&#x2013;435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqui MS, Jimenez-Shahed J, Mari Z, et al. North American survey on impact of the COVID-19 pandemic shutdown on DBS care. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2021; 92:41&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash N, Zadikoff C. Telemedicine aids in initial deep brain stimulation programming for dystonia. Mov Disord Clin Pract 2020; 7:1002&#x2013;1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado C, Pare&#xe9;s I, Kurtis MM. Patients&#x2019; perspective of dystonia symptoms during the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. Mov Disord 2021; 36:1485&#x2013;1486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadzadeh S, Brauns R, Rosenthal D, et al. The impact of SARS-CoV-2 pandemic lockdown on a botulinum toxin outpatient clinic in Germany. Toxins (Basel) 2021; 13:101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teuschl Y, Bancher C, Brainin M, et al. COVID-19-related delays of botulinum toxin injections have a negative impact on the quality of life of patients with dystonia and spasticity: a single-center ambulatory care study. J Neural Transm (Vienna) 2022; 129:49&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>York MK, Farace E, Pollak L, et al. The global pandemic has permanently changed the state of practice for pre-DBS neuropsychological evaluations. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2021; 86:135&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langer A, Gassner L, Flotz A, et al. How COVID-19 will boost remote exercise-based treatment in Parkinson's disease: a narrative review. NPJ Parkinsons Dis 2021; 7:25&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastav AK, Samuel AJ. E-rehabilitation: one solution for patients with Parkinson's disease in COVID-19 era. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2020; 75:128&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva Rocha Paz T, Silva de Macedo AR, Lemos Silva AE, et al. Challenges in treating people with Parkinson's disease during the COVID-19 pandemic. Bulletin of Faculty Phys Ther 2020; 25:17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zipprich HM, Teschner U, Witte OW, et al. Knowledge, attitudes, practices, and burden during the COVID-19 pandemic in people with Parkinson's disease in Germany. J Clin Med 2020; 9:1643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubota T, Kuroda N. Exacerbation of neurological symptoms and COVID-19 severity in patients with preexisting neurological disorders and COVID-19: a systematic review. Clin Neurol Neurosurg 2021; 200:106349&#x2013;1106349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sennott B, Woo K, Hess S, et al. Novel outreach program and practical strategies for patients with parkinsonism in the COVID-19 pandemic. J Parkinsons Dis 2020; 10:1383&#x2013;1388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau YH, Lau KM, Ibrahim NM. Management of Parkinson's disease in the COVID-19 pandemic and future perspectives in the era of vaccination. J Mov Disord 2021; 14:177&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Indu S, Christina LV. Hoping for the best, planning for the worst: palliative care approach to Parkinson disease during the COVID-19 pandemic. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2020; 80:203&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saldivar RT, Tew WP, Shahrokni A, et al. Goals of care conversations and telemedicine. J Geriatr Oncol 2021; 12:995&#x2013;999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantri S, Mitchell KT. Falling down the digital divide: a cautionary tale. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2021; 93:33&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolen L, Mejia NI. Inequities in neurology amplified by the COVID-19 pandemic. Nat Rev Neurol 2021; 17:67&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown EG, Chahine LM, Goldman SM, et al. The effect of the COVID-19 pandemic on people with Parkinson's disease. J Parkinsons Dis 2020; 10:1365&#x2013;1377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janiri D, Petracca M, Moccia L, et al. COVID-19 pandemic and psychiatric symptoms: the impact on Parkinson's disease in the elderly. Front Psychiatry 2020; 11:581144&#x2013;1581144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baschi R, Luca A, Nicoletti A, et al. Changes in motor, cognitive, and behavioral symptoms in Parkinson's disease and mild cognitive impairment during the COVID-19 lockdown. Front Psychiatry 2020; 11:590134&#x2013;1590134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chirra M, Marsili L, Wattley L, et al. Telemedicine in neurological disorders: opportunities and challenges. Telemed J E Health 2019; 25:541&#x2013;550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsamis KI, Rigas G, Nikolaos K, et al. Accurate monitoring of Parkinson's disease symptoms with a wearable device during COVID-19 pandemic. In Vivo 2021; 35:2327&#x2013;2330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalash A, Fathy M, Dawood NL, et al. Adopting virtual visits for Parkinson's disease patients during the COVID-19 pandemic in a developing country. Front Neurol 2020; 11:582613&#x2013;1582613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg D, Dhamija RK. The challenge of managing Parkinson's disease patients during the COVID-19 pandemic. Ann Indian Acad Neurol 2020; 23:S24&#x2013;S27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva-Batista C, Coelho DB, J&#xfa;nior RCF, et al. Multidimensional factors can explain the clinical worsening in people with Parkinson's disease during the COVID-19 pandemic: a multicenter cross-sectional trial. Front Neurol 2021; 12:708433&#x2013;1708433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayele BA, Zenebe Y, Demissie H, et al. Impact of COVID-19 on the clinical care of Ethiopian PD patients: a glimpse into the burden. eNeurologicalSci 2020; 21:100273&#x2013;1100273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad S, Holla VV, Neeraja K, et al. Parkinson's disease and COVID-19: perceptions and implications in patients and caregivers. Mov Disord 2020; 35:912&#x2013;914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodich A, Papagno C, Turella L, et al. The role of social cognition abilities in Parkinson's disease in the era of COVID-19 emergency. Front Psychol 2021; 12:571991&#x2013;1571991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fearon C, Fasano A. Parkinson's disease and the COVID-19 pandemic. J Parkinsons Dis 2021; 11:431&#x2013;444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado M, Tarrano C, Mesrati F, et al. Functional movement disorders during the COVID-19 pandemic: back to Charcot's era at the Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re. Mov Disord 2022; 37:432&#x2013;434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandri A, Di Vico IA, Riello M, et al. The impact of recurrent Covid-19 waves on patients with functional movement disorders: a follow-up study. Clin Park Relat Disord 2022; 6:100139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zea Vera A, Bruce A, Garris J, et al. The phenomenology of tics and tic-like behavior in TikTok. Pediatr Neurol 2022; 130:14&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olvera C, Stebbins GT, Goetz CG, et al. TikTok Tics: a pandemic within a pandemic. Mov Disord Clin Pract 2021; 8:1200&#x2013;1205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider SA, Hennig A, Martino D. Relationship between COVID-19 and movement disorders: a narrative review. Eur J Neurol 2022; 29:1243&#x2013;1253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han VX, Kozlowska K, Kothur K, et al. Rapid onset functional tic-like behaviours in children and adolescents during COVID-19: clinical features, assessment and biopsychosocial treatment approach. J Paediatr Child Health 2022; Mar 5;10.1111/jpc.15932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jpc.15932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pringsheim T, Ganos C, McGuire JF, et al. Rapid onset functional tic-like behaviors in young females during the COVID-19 pandemic. Mov Disord 2021; 36:2707&#x2013;2713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hull M, Parnes M, Jankovic J. Increased incidence of functional (psychogenic) movement disorders in children and adults amid the COVID-19 pandemic: a cross-sectional study. Neurol Clin Pract 2021; 11:e686&#x2013;e690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pringsheim T, Martino D. Rapid onset of functional tic-like behaviours in young adults during the COVID-19 pandemic. Eur J Neurol 2021; 28:3805&#x2013;3808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhoundi FH, Lang AE, Ghazvinian S, et al. A novel COVID era-related oromandibular dyskinesia: surgical mask-induced dyskinesia? Can J Neurol Sci 2021; 49:470&#x2013;471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erbguth F, Lange R. Sensory trick effect in craniofacial dystonia as one of the possible impacts of wearing face masks during the COVID-19 pandemic. Neurol Res Pract 2021; 3:24.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>