<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37665334</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2292-9495</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR human factors</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Hum Factors</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Digital Patient Reported Outcome Measures Platform for Post-COVID-19 Condition and Other Long-Term Conditions: User-Centered Development and Technical Description.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e48632</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e48632</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e48632</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/48632</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Post-COVID-19 condition (PCC), colloquially known as long COVID, is a multisystem condition characterized by persistent symptoms beyond 4 weeks after the SARS-CoV-2 infection. More than 60 million people with PCC worldwide need prompt assessment, diagnosis, and monitoring, with many requiring specialist help from a multidisciplinary team of health care professionals (HCPs). Consequently, a scalable digital system is required for both people with PCC and HCPs to capture the breadth of symptoms and their impact on health, using patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs) and patient-reported experience measures (PREMs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">We aim to develop and implement a novel PCC digital PROM (DPROM) platform for (1) securely collecting PROM and PREM data from people with PCC, (2) enabling users to monitor symptoms longitudinally and assess response to treatment, (3) generating reports for the electronic health records (EHRs), (4) providing summary reports on PCC services based on national requirements, and (5) facilitating the sharing of relevant data with authorized research teams to accelerate our understanding of this new condition and evaluate new strategies to manage PCC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We (1) undertook requirement analysis with people with PCC, HCPs, and researchers to identify the needs of the DPROM platform and determine its required functionalities; (2) designed and developed a clinically useful web portal for staff and a mobile app for patients, with a web-based alternative app to improve patient and staff choice, limit the risk of digital exclusion, and account for variability across services; (3) determined the PROMs and PREMs that PCC services would prefer to use on the platform; and (4) designed the summary report function that can be generated for each user for the EHR and for reporting to national health authorities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A DPROM platform to record PCC symptom profile, condition severity, functional disability, and quality of life, based on the C19-YRS (Yorkshire Rehabilitation Scale) and other PROMs and PREMs, was developed. Individual-level medical information and details on the COVID-19 illness can be captured systematically. The platform generates easy-to-understand scores, radar plots and line graphs for people with PCC to self-monitor their condition and for HCPs to assess the natural course of the condition and the response to interventions. Clinics can configure a suite of PROMs and PREMs based on their local and national service and commissioning requirements and support research studies which require large-scale data collection on PROMs. The DPROM platform enables automatic aggregate data analysis for services to undertake service evaluation and cost-effectiveness analysis. The DPROM platform generated summary report can be uploaded to the EHRs of people with PCC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">A multifunctional DPROM platform to assess, grade, and monitor PCC has been developed. Future research will analyze the system's usability in specialist PCC clinical services and other long-term conditions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Manoj Sivan, Rom&#xe1;n Rocha Lawrence, Paul O'Brien. Originally published in JMIR Human Factors (https://humanfactors.jmir.org), 20.10.2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sivan</LastName><ForeName>Manoj</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0334-2968</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Leeds Institute of Rheumatic and Musculoskeletal Medicine, University of Leeds, Leeds, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rocha Lawrence</LastName><ForeName>Rom&#xe1;n</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1913-9825</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Leeds Institute of Rheumatic and Musculoskeletal Medicine, University of Leeds, Leeds, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Brien</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0019-4760</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ELAROS 24/7 Ltd, Sheffield, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Hum Factors</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101666561</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2292-9495</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071066" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Reported Outcome Measures</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">C19-YRS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ELAROS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sars-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Yorkshire Rehabilitation Scale</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic conditions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">data sharing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital technology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health record</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health records</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">information sharing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile app</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile phone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outcome measure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outcome measures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient-reported</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">platform</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post&#x2013;COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reports</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smartphone</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: MS is an advisor to the World Health Organization for post&#x2013;COVID-19 condition policy in Europe.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37665334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10592725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/48632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v10i1e48632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN) Royal College of General Practitioners (RCGP) Covid-19 rapid guideline: Managing the long-term effects of covid-19. London: NICE; 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Geneva: WHO;  [2023-09-14]. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus, 6 October 2021. 
 https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_&#x200b;definition-2021.1
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitaker MJ, Elliott J, Chadeau-Hyam M. Persistent symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection in a random community sample of 508,707 people. medRxiv. 2021 doi: 10.1038/s41467-022-29521-z. 
 
10.1038/s41467-022-29521-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-29521-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2013;146. doi: 10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2. 
 
10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re'em Y, Redfield S, Austin JP, Akrami A. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019. 
 
S2589-5370(21)00299-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown DA, O'Brien KK. Conceptualising long COVID as an episodic health condition. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6(9):e007004. doi: 10.1136/bmjgh-2021-007004. 
 
bmjgh-2021-007004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2021-007004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8460526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34551971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black N. Patient reported outcome measures could help transform healthcare. BMJ. 2013;346:f167. doi: 10.1136/bmj.f167. 
 
bmj.f167</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.f167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23358487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snyder CF, Aaronson NK, Choucair AK, Elliott TE, Greenhalgh J, Halyard MY, Hess R, Miller DM, Reeve BB, Santana M. Implementing patient-reported outcomes assessment in clinical practice: a review of the options and considerations. Qual Life Res. 2012;21(8):1305&#x2013;1314. doi: 10.1007/s11136-011-0054-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-011-0054-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22048932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvert M, Kyte D, Price G, Valderas JM, Hjollund NH. Maximising the impact of patient reported outcome assessment for patients and society. BMJ. 2019;364:k5267. doi: 10.1136/bmj.k5267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.k5267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30679170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Wright S, Hughes S, Calvert M. Using condition specific patient reported outcome measures for long covid. BMJ. 2022;376:o257. doi: 10.1136/bmj.o257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.o257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35091425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Halpin S, Hollingworth L, Snook N, Hickman K, Clifton IJ. Development of an integrated rehabilitation pathway for individuals recovering from COVID-19 in the community. J Rehabil Med. 2020;52(8):jrm00089. doi: 10.2340/16501977-2727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/16501977-2727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32830284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Halpin S, Gee J. Assessing long-term rehabilitation needs in COVID-19 survivors using a telephone screening tool (C19-YRS tool) ACNR. 2020;19(4):14&#x2013;17. doi: 10.47795/nele5960. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47795/nele5960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Halpin S, Gees J, Makower S, Parkin A, Ross D, Horton M, O'Connor R. The self-report version and digital format of the COVID-19 Yorkshire Rehabilitation Scale (C19-YRS) for Long COVID or Post-COVID syndrome assessment and monitoring. ACNR. 2021;20(3):1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.47795/qroo4168. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47795/qroo4168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Parkin A, Makower S, Greenwood DC. Post-COVID syndrome symptoms, functional disability, and clinical severity phenotypes in hospitalized and nonhospitalized individuals: a cross-sectional evaluation from a community COVID rehabilitation service. J Med Virol. 2022;94(4):1419&#x2013;1427. doi: 10.1002/jmv.27456. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.27456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34783052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, Adams A, Harvey O, McLean L, Walshaw C, Kemp S, Corrado J, Singh R, Collins T, O'Connor RJ, Sivan M. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93(2):1013&#x2013;1022. doi: 10.1002/jmv.26368. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straudi S, Manfredini F, Baroni A, Milani G, Fregna G, Schincaglia N, Androni R, Occhi A, Sivan M, Lamberti N. Construct validity and responsiveness of the COVID-19 Yorkshire Rehabilitation Scale (C19-YRS) in a cohort of Italian hospitalized COVID-19 patients. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(11):6696. doi: 10.3390/ijerph19116696. 
 
ijerph19116696</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19116696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9180312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35682280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel K, Straudi S, Sien NY, Fayed N, Melvin JL, Sivan M. Applying the WHO ICF framework to the outcome measures used in the evaluation of long-term clinical outcomes in coronavirus outbreaks. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(18):6476. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17186476. 
 
ijerph17186476</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17186476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7558385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32899534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Preston N, Parkin A, Makower S, Gee J, Ross D, Tarrant R, Davison J, Halpin S, O'Connor RJ, Horton M. The modified COVID-19 Yorkshire Rehabilitation Scale (C19-YRSm) patient-reported outcome measure for Long COVID or Post-COVID-19 syndrome. J Med Virol. 2022;94(9):4253&#x2013;4264. doi: 10.1002/jmv.27878. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.27878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9348420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35603810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National commissioning guidance for post-COVID services. NHS England. 2022.  [2023-09-27].  
 https://www.england.nhs.uk/publication/national-commissioning-guidance-for-post-covid-services/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National guidance for post-COVID syndrome assessment clinics. NHS England. 2021.  [2023-09-27].  
 https://www.england.nhs.uk/coronavirus/your-covid-recovery/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ELAROS.  [2023-09-19].  
 https://elaros.com
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangera A, Marzo A, Heron N, Fernando D, Hameed K, Soliman AHA, Bradley M, Hosking I, Abdel-Maguid M, Levermore M, Tindale WB, Chapple C. Development of two electronic bladder diaries: a patient and healthcare professionals pilot study. Neurourol Urodyn. 2014;33(7):1101&#x2013;1109. doi: 10.1002/nau.22469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nau.22469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24000163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown J. Independent evaluation of the ELAROS digital bladder diary. Aston Research Centre for Healthy Ageing (ARCHA) 2022.  [2023-09-14].  
 https://www.elaros.com/solutions/the-digital-bladder-diary/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Greenhalgh T, Darbyshire JL, Mir G, O'Connor RJ, Dawes H, Greenwood D, O'Connor D, Horton M, Petrou S, de Lusignan S, Curcin V, Mayer E, Casson A, Milne R, Rayner C, Smith N, Parkin A, Preston N, Delaney B, LOCOMOTION consortium  Long COVID multidisciplinary consortium optimising treatments and services across the NHS (LOCOMOTION): protocol for a mixed-methods study in the UK. BMJ Open. 2022;12(5):e063505. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-063505. 
 
bmjopen-2022-063505</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-063505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9114312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35580970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen AS, Kidholm K, Kayser L. Patients' reasons for non-use of digital patient-reported outcome concepts: a scoping review. Health Informatics J. 2020;26(4):2811&#x2013;2833. doi: 10.1177/1460458220942649. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1460458220942649?url_ver=Z39.88-2003&amp;rfr_id=ori:rid:crossref.org&amp;rfr_dat=cr_pub0pubmed</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1460458220942649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32731773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Yazdany J, Trupin L, Izadi Z, Gianfrancesco M, Goglin S, Schmajuk G. Capturing a patient-reported measure of physical function through an online electronic health record patient portal in an ambulatory clinic: implementation study. JMIR Med Inform. 2018;6(2):e31. doi: 10.2196/medinform.8687. 
 
v6i2e31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/medinform.8687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5966655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29743158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker D, Rickard N. Engagement in mobile phone app for self-monitoring of emotional wellbeing predicts changes in mental health: MoodPrism. J Affect Disord. 2018;227:432&#x2013;442. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.016.S0165-0327(17)31678-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min YH, Lee JW, Shin YW, Jo MW, Sohn G, Lee JH, Lee G, Jung KH, Sung J, Ko BS, Yu JH, Kim HJ, Son BH, Ahn SH. Daily collection of self-reporting sleep disturbance data via a smartphone app in breast cancer patients receiving chemotherapy: a feasibility study. J Med Internet Res. 2014;16(5):e135. doi: 10.2196/jmir.3421. 
 
v16i5e135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.3421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4051741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24860070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kj&#xe6;r ASHKK, Rasmussen TA, Hjollund NH, Rodkjaer LO, Storgaard M. Patient-reported outcomes in daily clinical practise in HIV outpatient care. Int J Infect Dis. 2018;69:108&#x2013;114. doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2018.02.015. 
 
S1201-9712(18)30051-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2018.02.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29476900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brochmann N, Zwisler AD, Kjerholt M, Flachs EM, Hasselbalch HC, Andersen CL. A new internet-based tool for reporting and analysing patient-reported outcomes and the feasibility of repeated data collection from patients with myeloproliferative neoplasms. Qual Life Res. 2016;25(4):835&#x2013;846. doi: 10.1007/s11136-015-1125-1.10.1007/s11136-015-1125-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-015-1125-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26358064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray CS, Gill A, Khan AI, Hans PK, Kuluski K, Cott C. The electronic patient reported outcome tool: testing usability and feasibility of a mobile app and portal to support care for patients with complex chronic disease and disability in primary care settings. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2016;4(2):e58. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.5331. 
 
v4i2e58</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.5331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4911509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27256035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard JS, Toonstra JL, Meade AR, Conley CEW, Mattacola CG. Feasibility of conducting a web-based survey of patient-reported outcomes and rehabilitation progress. Digit Health. 2016;2:2055207616644844. doi: 10.1177/2055207616644844. 
 
10.1177_2055207616644844</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2055207616644844?url_ver=Z39.88-2003&amp;rfr_id=ori:rid:crossref.org&amp;rfr_dat=cr_pub0pubmed</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2055207616644844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6001185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29942553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melissant HC, Verdonck-de Leeuw IM, Lissenberg-Witte BI, Konings IR, Cuijpers P, Van Uden-Kraan CF. 'Oncokompas', a web-based self-management application to support patient activation and optimal supportive care: a feasibility study among breast cancer survivors. Acta Oncol. 2018;57(7):924&#x2013;934. doi: 10.1080/0284186X.2018.1438654. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0284186X.2018.1438654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0284186X.2018.1438654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29451059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gossec L, Cantagrel A, Soubrier M, Berthelot JM, Joubert JM, Combe B, Czarlewski W, Wendling D, Dernis E, Grange L, Beauvais C, Perdriger A, Nataf H, Dougados M, Servy H. An e-health interactive self-assessment website (Sanoia&#xae;) in rheumatoid arthritis. A 12-month randomized controlled trial in 320 patients. Joint Bone Spine. 2018;85(6):709&#x2013;714. doi: 10.1016/j.jbspin.2017.11.015. 
 
S1297-319X(17)30205-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbspin.2017.11.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29246532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basch E, Dueck AC, Rogak LJ, Minasian LM, Kelly WK, O'Mara AM, Denicoff AM, Seisler D, Atherton PJ, Paskett E, Carey L, Dickler M, Heist RS, Himelstein A, Rugo HS, Sikov WM, Socinski MA, Venook AP, Weckstein DJ, Lake DE, Biggs DD, Freedman RA, Kuzma C, Kirshner JJ, Schrag D. Feasibility assessment of patient reporting of symptomatic adverse events in multicenter cancer clinical trials. JAMA Oncol. 2017;3(8):1043&#x2013;1050. doi: 10.1001/jamaoncol.2016.6749. 
 
2603225</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoncol.2016.6749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5553624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28208174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer AM, Iles-Shih M, Ghomi RH, Rue T, Grover T, Kincler N, Miller M, Katon WJ. Acceptability of mHealth augmentation of collaborative care: a mixed methods pilot study. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2018;51:22&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2017.11.010. 
 
S0163-8343(17)30287-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2017.11.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6512981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29272712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron J, Hirani S, Newman S. Challenges in patient recruitment, implementation, and fidelity in a mobile telehealth study. Telemed J E Health. 2016;22(5):400&#x2013;409. doi: 10.1089/tmj.2015.0095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/tmj.2015.0095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26540238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, Nicholson T, Akrami A, Apfelbacher C, Chen J, De Groote W, Diaz J, Gorst SL, Harman N, Kokorina A, Olliaro PL, Parr C, Preller J, Schiess N, Schmitt J, Seylanova N, Simpson F, Tong A, Needham DM, Williamson PR, PC-COS project steering committee  A core outcome set for post-COVID-19 condition in adults for use in clinical practice and research: an international Delphi consensus study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10(7):715&#x2013;724. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(22)00169-2. 
 
S2213-2600(22)00169-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(22)00169-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9197249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35714658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan M, Lawrence RR, Francis E. Digital interactive patient reported outcome measures for long term conditions. BMJ. 2023;382:1816. doi: 10.1136/bmj.p1816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.p1816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37562815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>