<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33458558</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2471-2531</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Season>Jan-Feb</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pain reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pain Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neurobiology of SARS-CoV-2 interactions with the peripheral nervous system: implications for COVID-19 and pain.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e885</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e885</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e885</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PR9.0000000000000885</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>SARS-CoV-2 is a novel coronavirus that infects cells through the angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 receptor, aided by proteases that prime the spike protein of the virus to enhance cellular entry. Neuropilin 1 and 2 (NRP1 and NRP2) act as additional viral entry factors. SARS-CoV-2 infection causes COVID-19 disease. There is now strong evidence for neurological impacts of COVID-19, with pain as an important symptom, both in the acute phase of the disease and at later stages that are colloquially referred to as "long COVID." In this narrative review, we discuss how COVID-19 may interact with the peripheral nervous system to cause pain in the early and late stages of the disease. We begin with a review of the state of the science on how viruses cause pain through direct and indirect interactions with nociceptors. We then cover what we currently know about how the unique cytokine profiles of moderate and severe COVID-19 may drive plasticity in nociceptors to promote pain and worsen existing pain states. Finally, we review evidence for direct infection of nociceptors by SARS-CoV-2 and the implications of this potential neurotropism. The state of the science points to multiple potential mechanisms through which COVID-19 could induce changes in nociceptor excitability that would be expected to promote pain, induce neuropathies, and worsen existing pain states.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of The International Association for the Study of Pain.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McFarland</LastName><ForeName>Amelia J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Center for Advanced Pain Studies, University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yousuf</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Center for Advanced Pain Studies, University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shiers</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Center for Advanced Pain Studies, University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Price</LastName><ForeName>Theodore J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Center for Advanced Pain Studies, University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pain Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101683899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2471-2531</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nociceptor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to declare. This work was supported by NIH grants NS065926 and NS111929 to T.J. Price. T.J. Price is a co-founder of 4E Therapeutics, a company developing MNK inhibitors for neuropathic pain.Sponsorships or competing interests that may be relevant to content are disclosed at the end of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33458558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7803673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PR9.0000000000000885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PAINREPORTS-D-20-0109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbadie C, Lindia JA, Cumiskey AM, Peterson LB, Mudgett JS, Bayne EK, DeMartino JA, MacIntyre DE, Forrest MJ. Impaired neuropathic pain responses in mice lacking the chemokine receptor CCR2. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2003;100:7947&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC164693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12808141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez P, Green PG, Levine JD. Role for monocyte chemoattractant protein-1 in the induction of chronic muscle pain in the rat. PAIN 2014;155:1161&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4303347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24637038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andoh T, Maki T, Li S, Uta D. &#x3b2;2-Microglobulin elicits itch-related responses in mice through the direct activation of primary afferent neurons expressing transient receptor potential vanilloid 1. Eur J Pharmacol 2017;810:134&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28687195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arunachalam PS, Wimmers F, Mok CKP, Perera R, Scott M, Hagan T, Sigal N, Feng Y, Bristow L, Tak-Yin Tsang O, Wagh D, Coller J, Pellegrini KL, Kazmin D, Alaaeddine G, Leung WS, Chan JMC, Chik TSH, Choi CYC, Huerta C, Paine McCullough M, Lv H, Anderson E, Edupuganti S, Upadhyay AA, Bosinger SE, Maecker HT, Khatri P, Rouphael N, Peiris M, Pulendran B. Systems biological assessment of immunity to mild versus severe COVID-19 infection in humans. Science 2020;369:1210&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balachandran S, Barber GN. PKR in innate immunity, cancer, and viral oncolysis. Methods Mol Biol 2007;383:277&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barragan-Iglesias P, Franco-Enzastiga U, Jeevakumar V, Shiers S, Wangzhou A, Granados-Soto V, Campbell ZT, Dussor G, Price TJ. Type I interferons act directly on nociceptors to produce pain sensitization: implications for viral infection-induced pain. J Neurosci 2020;40:3517&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7189756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32245829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barragan-Iglesias P, Kuhn J, Vidal-Cantu GC, Salinas-Abarca AB, Granados-Soto V, Dussor GO, Campbell ZT, Price TJ. Activation of the integrated stress response in nociceptors drives methylglyoxal-induced pain. PAIN 2019;160:160&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6800106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30157134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastard P, Rosen LB, Zhang Q, Michailidis E, Hoffmann HH, Zhang Y, Dorgham K, Philippot Q, Rosain J, Beziat V, Manry J, Shaw E, Haljasmagi L, Peterson P, Lorenzo L, Bizien L, Trouillet-Assant S, Dobbs K, de Jesus AA, Belot A, Kallaste A, Catherinot E, Tandjaoui-Lambiotte Y, Le Pen J, Kerner G, Bigio B, Seeleuthner Y, Yang R, Bolze A, Spaan AN, Delmonte OM, Abers MS, Aiuti A, Casari G, Lampasona V, Piemonti L, Ciceri F, Bilguvar K, Lifton RP, Vasse M, Smadja DM, Migaud M, Hadjadj J, Terrier B, Duffy D, Quintana-Murci L, van de Beek D, Roussel L, Vinh DC, Tangye SG, Haerynck F, Dalmau D, Martinez-Picado J, Brodin P, Nussenzweig MC, Boisson-Dupuis S, Rodriguez-Gallego C, Vogt G, Mogensen TH, Oler AJ, Gu J, Burbelo PD, Cohen JI, Biondi A, Bettini LR, D'Angio M, Bonfanti P, Rossignol P, Mayaux J, Rieux-Laucat F, Husebye ES, Fusco F, Ursini MV, Imberti L, Sottini A, Paghera S, Quiros-Roldan E, Rossi C, Castagnoli R, Montagna D, Licari A, Marseglia GL, Duval X, Ghosn J, Lab H; Group N- UIRtC, Clinicians C, Clinicians C-S, Imagine CG, French CCSG, Milieu Interieur C, Co VCC, Amsterdam UMCCB, Effort CHG, Tsang JS, Goldbach-Mansky R, Kisand K, Lionakis MS, Puel A, Zhang SY, Holland SM, Gorochov G, Jouanguy E, Rice CM, Cobat A, Notarangelo LD, Abel L, Su HC, Casanova JL. Autoantibodies against type I IFNs in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science 2020;370:eabd4585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battle CE, Lovett S, Hutchings H. Chronic pain in survivors of critical illness: a retrospective analysis of incidence and risk factors. Crit Care 2013;17:R101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4057262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23718685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck DB, Aksentijevich I. Susceptibility to severe COVID-19. Science 2020;370:404&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33093097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binshtok AM, Wang H, Zimmermann K, Amaya F, Vardeh D, Shi L, Brenner GJ, Ji RR, Bean BP, Woolf CJ, Samad TA. Nociceptors are interleukin-1beta sensors. J Neurosci 2008;28:14062&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2690713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19109489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce E, Barlow-Pay F, Short R, Vilches-Moraga A, Price A, McGovern A, Braude P, Stechman MJ, Moug S, McCarthy K. Prior routine use of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) and important outcomes in hospitalised patients with COVID-19. J Clin Med 2020;9:2586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7465199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32785086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantuti-Castelvetri L, Ojha R, Pedro LD, Djannatian M, Franz J, Kuivanen S, van der Meer F, Kallio K, Kaya T, Anastasina M, Smura T, Levanov L, Szirovicza L, Tobi A, Kallio-Kokko H, Osterlund P, Joensuu M, Meunier FA, Butcher SJ, Winkler MS, Mollenhauer B, Helenius A, Gokce O, Teesalu T, Hepojoki J, Vapalahti O, Stadelmann C, Balistreri G, Simons M. Neuropilin-1 facilitates SARS-CoV-2 cell entry and infectivity. Science 2020;370:856&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33082293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caso F, Costa L, Ruscitti P, Navarini L, Del Puente A, Giacomelli R, Scarpa R. Could Sars-coronavirus-2 trigger autoimmune and/or autoinflammatory mechanisms in genetically predisposed subjects? Autoimmun Rev 2020;19:102524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32220633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen BP, Kuziel WA, Lane TE. Lack of CCR2 results in increased mortality and impaired leukocyte activation and trafficking following infection of the central nervous system with a neurotropic coronavirus. J Immunol 2001;167:4585&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11591787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu IM, Heesters BA, Ghasemlou N, Von Hehn CA, Zhao F, Tran J, Wainger B, Strominger A, Muralidharan S, Horswill AR, Bubeck Wardenburg J, Hwang SW, Carroll MC, Woolf CJ. Bacteria activate sensory neurons that modulate pain and inflammation. Nature 2013;501:52&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3773968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23965627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu IM, Pinho-Ribeiro FA, Woolf CJ. Pain and infection: pathogen detection by nociceptors. PAIN 2016;157:1192&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4874496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27183444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutard B, Valle C, de Lamballerie X, Canard B, Seidah NG, Decroly E. The spike glycoprotein of the new coronavirus 2019-nCoV contains a furin-like cleavage site absent in CoV of the same clade. Antivir Res 2020;176:104742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7114094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32057769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly JL, Simonetti B, Klein K, Chen KE, Williamson MK, Anton-Plagaro C, Shoemark DK, Simon-Gracia L, Bauer M, Hollandi R, Greber UF, Horvath P, Sessions RB, Helenius A, Hiscox JA, Teesalu T, Matthews DA, Davidson AD, Collins BM, Cullen PJ, Yamauchi Y. Neuropilin-1 is a host factor for SARS-CoV-2 infection. Science 2020;370:861&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7612957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33082294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, Wang H, Shen H, Li Z, Geng J, Han H, Cai J, Li X, Kang W, Weng D. The clinical pathology of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS): a report from China. J Pathol 2003;200:282&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7168017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12845623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang L, Karakiulakis G, Roth M. Are patients with hypertension and diabetes mellitus at increased risk for COVID-19 infection?. Lancet Respir Med 2020;8:e21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32171062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garza Carbajal A, Ebersberger A, Thiel A, Ferrari L, Acuna J, Brosig S, Isensee J, Moeller K, Siobal M, Rose-John S, Levine J, Schaible H-G, Hucho T. Oncostatin M induces hyperalgesic priming and amplifies signaling of cAMP to ERK by RapGEF2 and PKA. J Neurochem 2020. doi: 10.1111/jnc.15172 [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnc.15172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32885411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girardi E, L&#xf3;pez P, Pfeffer S. On the importance of host MicroRNAs during viral infection. Front Genet 2018;9:439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6176045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30333857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon CJ, Tchesnokov EP, Feng JY, Porter DP, Gotte M. The antiviral compound remdesivir potently inhibits RNA-dependent RNA polymerase from Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus. J Biol Chem 2020;295:4773&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7152756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32094225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadjadj J, Yatim N, Barnabei L, Corneau A, Boussier J, Smith N, P&#xe9;r&#xe9; H, Charbit B, Bondet V, Chenevier-Gobeaux C, Breillat P, Carlier N, Gauzit R, Morbieu C, Pene F, Marin N, Roche N, Szwebel TA, Merkling SH, Treluyer JM, Veyer D, Mouthon L, Blanc C, Tharaux PL, Rozenberg F, Fischer A, Duffy D, Rieux-Laucat F, Kerneis S, Terrier B. Impaired type I interferon activity and inflammatory responses in severe COVID-19 patients. Science 2020;369:718&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7402632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Cai S, Feng H, Cai B, Lin L, Mai Y, Fan Y, Zhu A, Huang H, Shi J, Li D, Wei Y, Li Y, Zhao Y, Pan Y, Liu H, Mo X, He X, Cao S, Hu F, Zhao J, Wang J, Zhong N, Chen X, Deng X, Chen J. Single-cell analysis reveals bronchoalveolar epithelial dysfunction in COVID-19 patients. Protein &amp; Cell 2020;11:680&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7363016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32671793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson NT, Dalva MB. EphBs and ephrin-Bs: trans-synaptic organizers of synapse development and function. Mol Cell Neurosci 2018;91:108&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6159941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30031105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess DC, Eldahshan W, Rutkowski E. COVID-19-Related stroke. Transl Stroke Res 2020;11:322&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7202903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32378030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hockley JRF, Taylor TS, Callejo G, Wilbrey AL, Gutteridge A, Bach K, Winchester WJ, Bulmer DC, McMurray G, Smith ESJ. Single-cell RNAseq reveals seven classes of colonic sensory neuron. Gut 2019;68:633&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6580772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29483303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsiao CH, Chang MF, Hsueh PR, Su IJ. Immunohistochemical study of severe acute respiratory syndrome-associated coronavirus in tissue sections of patients. J Formos Med Assoc 2005;104:150&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15818427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y, Zhang L, Fan G, Xu J, Gu X, Cheng Z, Yu T, Xia J, Wei Y, Wu W, Xie X, Yin W, Li H, Liu M, Xiao Y, Gao H, Guo L, Xie J, Wang G, Jiang R, Gao Z, Jin Q, Wang J, Cao B. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet 2020;395:497&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Ou R, Rabelo de Souza G, Cunha TM, Lemos H, Mohamed E, Li L, Pacholczyk G, Randall J, Munn DH, Mellor AL. Virus infections incite pain hypersensitivity by inducing indoleamine 2,3 dioxygenase. Plos Pathog 2016;12:e1005615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4863962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27168185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs B, Dussor G. Neurovascular contributions to migraine: moving beyond vasodilation. Neuroscience 2016;338:130&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5083225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27312704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan AAK, Sany RU, Islam S, Islam ABMK. Epigenetic regulator miRNA pattern differences among SARS-CoV, SARS-CoV-2, and SARS-CoV-2 world-wide isolates delineated the mystery behind the epic pathogenicity and distinct clinical characteristics of pandemic COVID-19. Front Genet 2020;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7381279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32765592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S, Amin FM, Christensen CE, Ghanizada H, Younis S, Olinger ACR, de Koning PJH, Larsson HBW, Ashina M. Meningeal contribution to migraine pain: a magnetic resonance angiography study. Brain 2019;142:93&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30590467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoutorsky A, Sorge RE, Prager-Khoutorsky M, Pawlowski SA, Longo G, Jafarnejad SM, Tahmasebi S, Martin LJ, Pitcher MH, Gkogkas CG, Sharif-Naeini R, Ribeiro-da-Silva A, Bourque CW, Cervero F, Mogil JS, Sonenberg N. eIF2alpha phosphorylation controls thermal nociception. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2016;113:11949&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5081582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27698114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konno Y, Kimura I, Uriu K, Fukushi M, Irie T, Koyanagi Y, Sauter D, Gifford RJ, Nakagawa S, Sato K. SARS-CoV-2 ORF3b is a potent interferon antagonist whose activity is increased by a naturally occurring elongation variant. Cell Reports 2020;32:108185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7473339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32941788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koyuncu OO, Hogue IB, Enquist LW. Virus infections in the nervous system. Cell Host Microbe 2013;13:379&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3647473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23601101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer PR, Strand J, Stinson C, Bellinger LL, Kinchington PR, Yee MB, Umorin M, Peng YB. Role for the ventral posterior medial/posterior lateral thalamus and anterior cingulate cortex in affective/motivation pain induced by varicella zoster virus. Front Integr Neurosci 2017;11:27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5651084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29089872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuba K, Imai Y, Rao S, Gao H, Guo F, Guan B, Huan Y, Yang P, Zhang Y, Deng W, Bao L, Zhang B, Liu G, Wang Z, Chappell M, Liu Y, Zheng D, Leibbrandt A, Wada T, Slutsky AS, Liu D, Qin C, Jiang C, Penninger JM. A crucial role of angiotensin converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) in SARS coronavirus-induced lung injury. Nat Med 2005;11:875&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16007097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lafon M. Rabies virus receptors. J Neurovirol 2005;11:82&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15804965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai NY, Musser MA, Pinho-Ribeiro FA, Baral P, Jacobson A, Ma P, Potts DE, Chen Z, Paik D, Soualhi S, Yan Y, Misra A, Goldstein K, Lagomarsino VN, Nordstrom A, Sivanathan KN, Wallrapp A, Kuchroo VK, Nowarski R, Starnbach MN, Shi H, Surana NK, An D, Wu C, Huh JR, Rao M, Chiu IM. Gut-innervating nociceptor neurons regulate peyer's patch microfold cells and SFB levels to mediate Salmonella host defense. Cell 2020;180:33&#x2013;49 e22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6954329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31813624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langeslag M, Constantin CE, Andratsch M, Quarta S, Mair N, Kress M. Oncostatin M induces heat hypersensitivity by gp130-dependent sensitization of TRPV1 in sensory neurons. Mol Pain 2011;7:102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3275481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22196363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latronico N, Filosto M, Fagoni N, Gheza L, Guarneri B, Todeschini A, Lombardi R, Padovani A, Lauria G. Small nerve fiber pathology in critical illness. PLoS One 2013;8:e75696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3787101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24098716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laumet G, Zhou W, Dantzer R, Edralin JD, Huo X, Budac DP, O'Connor JC, Lee AW, Heijnen CJ, Kavelaars A. Upregulation of neuronal kynurenine 3-monooxygenase mediates depression-like behavior in a mouse model of neuropathic pain. Brain Behav Immun 2017;66:94&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5650931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28709913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Park S, Jeong HW, Ahn JY, Choi SJ, Lee H, Choi B, Nam SK, Sa M, Kwon JS. Immunophenotyping of COVID-19 and influenza highlights the role of type I interferons in development of severe COVID-19. Sci Immunol 2020;5:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7402635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32651212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei X, Dong X, Ma R, Wang W, Xiao X, Tian Z, Wang C, Wang Y, Li L, Ren L, Guo F, Zhao Z, Zhou Z, Xiang Z, Wang J. Activation and evasion of type I interferon responses by SARS-CoV-2. Nat Commun 2020;11:3810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32733001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung TW, Wong KS, Hui AC, To KF, Lai ST, Ng WF, Ng HK. Myopathic changes associated with severe acute respiratory syndrome: a postmortem case series. Arch Neurol 2005;62:1113&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16009768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao M, Liu Y, Yuan J, Wen Y, Xu G, Zhao J, Cheng L, Li J, Wang X, Wang F. Single-cell landscape of bronchoalveolar immune cells in patients with COVID-19. Nat Med 2020;26:842&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund LC, Kristensen KB, Reilev M, Christensen S, Thomsen RW, Christiansen CF, St&#xf8;vring H, Johansen NB, Brun NC, Hallas J, Potteg&#xe5;rd A. Adverse outcomes and mortality in users of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs who tested positive for SARS-CoV-2: a Danish nationwide cohort study. PLoS Med 2020;17:e1003308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7478808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32898149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey K, King VJ, Gurley S, Kiefer M, Liederbauer E, Vela K, Sonnen P, Kansagara D. Risks and impact of angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitors or angiotensin-receptor blockers on SARS-CoV-2 infection in adults: a living systematic review. Ann Intern Med 2020;173:195&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7249560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malsch P, Andratsch M, Vogl C, Link AS, Alzheimer C, Brierley SM, Hughes PA, Kress M. Deletion of interleukin-6 signal transducer gp130 in small sensory neurons attenuates mechanonociception and down-regulates TRPA1 expression. J Neurosci 2014;34:9845&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4107403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25057188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L, Jin H, Wang M, Hu Y, Chen S, He Q, Chang J, Hong C, Zhou Y, Wang D, Miao X, Li Y, Hu B. Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 in wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol 2020;77:683&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7149362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin LJ, Smith SB, Khoutorsky A, Magnussen CA, Samoshkin A, Sorge RE, Cho C, Yosefpour N, Sivaselvachandran S, Tohyama S, Cole T, Khuong TM, Mir E, Gibson DG, Wieskopf JS, Sotocinal SG, Austin JS, Meloto CB, Gitt JH, Gkogkas C, Sonenberg N, Greenspan JD, Fillingim RB, Ohrbach R, Slade GD, Knott C, Dubner R, Nackley AG, Ribeiro-da-Silva A, Neely GG, Maixner W, Zaykin DV, Mogil JS, Diatchenko L. Epiregulin and EGFR interactions are involved in pain processing. J Clin Invest 2017;127:3353&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5669538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28783046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathew D, Giles JR, Baxter AE, Oldridge DA, Greenplate AR, Wu JE, Alanio C, Kuri-Cervantes L, Pampena MB, D'Andrea K, Manne S, Chen Z, Huang YJ, Reilly JP, Weisman AR, Ittner CAG, Kuthuru O, Dougherty J, Nzingha K, Han N, Kim J, Pattekar A, Goodwin EC, Anderson EM, Weirick ME, Gouma S, Arevalo CP, Bolton MJ, Chen F, Lacey SF, Ramage H, Cherry S, Hensley SE, Apostolidis SA, Huang AC, Vella LA, Unit UPCP, Betts MR, Meyer NJ, Wherry EJ. Deep immune profiling of COVID-19 patients reveals distinct immunotypes with therapeutic implications. Science 2020;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7402624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32669297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto M, Funami K, Oshiumi H, Seya T. Toll-like receptor 3: a link between toll-like receptor, interferon and viruses. Microbiol Immunol 2004;48:147&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15031527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNicholl JM, Smith DK, Qari SH, Hodge T. Host genes and HIV: the role of the chemokine receptor gene CCR5 and its allele. Emerg Infect Dis 1997;3:261&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2627644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9284370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megat S, Ray PR, Moy JK, Lou TF, Barragan-Iglesias P, Li Y, Pradhan G, Wanghzou A, Ahmad A, Burton MD, North RY, Dougherty PM, Khoutorsky A, Sonenberg N, Webster KR, Dussor G, Campbell ZT, Price TJ. Nociceptor translational profiling reveals the ragulator-rag GTPase complex as a critical generator of neuropathic pain. J Neurosci 2019;39:393&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6335757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30459229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meysman P, Ogunjimi B, Naulaerts S, Beutels P, Van Tendeloo V, Laukens K. Varicella-zoster virus-derived major histocompatibility complex class I-restricted peptide affinity is a determining factor in the HLA risk profile for the development of postherpetic neuralgia. J Virol 2015;89:962&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4300672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25355886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael BD, Griffiths MJ, Granerod J, Brown D, Keir G, Wn&#x119;k M, Cox DJ, Vidyasagar R, Borrow R, Parkes LM, Solomon T. The interleukin-1 balance during encephalitis is associated with clinical severity, blood-brain barrier permeability, neuroimaging changes, and disease outcome. J Infect Dis 2016;213:1651&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4837908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26712949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mody PH, Dos Santos NL, Barron LR, Price TJ, Burton MD. eIF4E phosphorylation modulates pain and neuroinflammation in the aged. Geroscience 2020. doi: 10.1007/s11357-020-00220-1 [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11357-020-00220-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7732936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moldofsky H, Patcai J. Chronic widespread musculoskeletal pain, fatigue, depression and disordered sleep in chronic post-SARS syndrome; a case-controlled study. BMC Neurol 2011;11:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3071317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21435231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montalvan V, Lee J, Bueso T, De Toledo J, Rivas K. Neurological manifestations of COVID-19 and other coronavirus infections: a systematic review. Clin Neurol Neurosurg 2020;194:105921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7227498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moutal A, Martin LF, Boinon L, Gomez K, Ran D, Zhou Y, Stratton HJ, Cai S, Luo S, Gonzalez KB, Perez-Miller S, Patwardhan A, Ibrahim MM, Khanna R. SARS-CoV-2 Spike protein co-opts VEGF-A/Neuropilin-1 receptor signaling to induce analgesia. PAIN 2020. doi: 10.1097/j.pain.0000000000002097 [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000002097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7737878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33009246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moy JK, Khoutorsky A, Asiedu MN, Black BJ, Kuhn JL, Barragan-Iglesias P, Megat S, Burton MD, Burgos-Vega CC, Melemedjian OK, Boitano S, Vagner J, Gkogkas CG, Pancrazio JJ, Mogil JS, Dussor G, Sonenberg N, Price TJ. The MNK-eIF4E signaling Axis contributes to injury-induced nociceptive plasticity and the development of chronic pain. J Neurosci 2017;37:7481&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5546114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28674170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moy JK, Khoutorsky A, Asiedu MN, Dussor G, Price TJ. eIF4E phosphorylation influences bdnf mRNA translation in mouse dorsal root ganglion neurons. Front Cel Neurosci 2018;12:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5808250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29467623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>North RY, Li Y, Ray P, Rhines LD, Tatsui CE, Rao G, Johansson CA, Zhang H, Kim YH, Zhang B, Dussor G, Kim TH, Price TJ, Dougherty PM. Electrophysiological and transcriptomic correlates of neuropathic pain in human dorsal root ganglion neurons. Brain 2019;142:1215&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6487328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30887021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oaklander AL. Clinical significance of angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 receptors for severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (COVID-19) on peripheral small-fiber sensory neurons is unknown today. PAIN 2020;161:2431&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10034827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park A, Iwasaki A. Type I and type III interferons - induction, signaling, evasion, and application to combat COVID-19. Cell Host Microbe 2020;27:870&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32464097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao W, Wang C, Chen B, Zhang F, Liu Y, Lu Q, Guo H, Yan C, Sun H, Hu G, Yin X. Ibuprofen attenuates cardiac fibrosis in streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats. Cardiology 2015;131:97&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25896805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray P, Torck A, Quigley L, Wangzhou A, Neiman M, Rao C, Lam T, Kim JY, Kim TH, Zhang MQ, Dussor G, Price TJ. Comparative transcriptome profiling of the human and mouse dorsal root ganglia: an RNA-seq-based resource for pain and sensory neuroscience research. PAIN 2018;159:1325&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6008200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29561359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray PR, Wangzhou A, Ghneim N, Yousuf MS, Paige C, Tavares-Ferreira D, Mwirigi JM, Shiers S, Sankaranarayanan I, McFarland AJ, Neerukonda SV, Davidson S, Dussor G, Burton MD, Price TJ. A pharmacological interactome between COVID-19 patient samples and human sensory neurons reveals potential drivers of neurogenic pulmonary dysfunction. Brain Behav Immun 2020;89:559&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7263237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32497778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruhl CR, Pasko BL, Khan HS, Kindt LM, Stamm CE, Franco LH, Hsia CC, Zhou M, Davis CR, Qin T, Gautron L, Burton MD, Mejia GL, Naik DK, Dussor G, Price TJ, Shiloh MU. Mycobacterium tuberculosis sulfolipid-1 activates nociceptive neurons and induces cough. Cell 2020;181:293&#x2013;305 e211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rulli NE, Melton J, Wilmes A, Ewart G, Mahalingam S. The molecular and cellular aspects of arthritis due to alphavirus infections: lesson learned from Ross River virus. Ann N Y Acad Sci 2007;1102:96&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17470914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiers S, Mwirigi J, Pradhan G, Kume M, Black B, Barragan-Iglesias P, Moy JK, Dussor G, Pancrazio JJ, Kroener S, Price TJ. Reversal of peripheral nerve injury-induced neuropathic pain and cognitive dysfunction via genetic and tomivosertib targeting of MNK. Neuropsychopharmacology 2020;45:524&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6969143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31590180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiers S, Ray PR, Wangzhou A, Sankaranarayanan I, Tatsui CE, Rhines LD, Li Y, Uhelski ML, Dougherty PM, Price TJ. ACE2 and SCARF expression in human dorsal root ganglion nociceptors: implications for SARS-CoV-2 virus neurological effects. PAIN 2020;161:2494&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7572821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiers S, Ray PR, Wangzhou A, Sankaranarayanan I, Tatsui CE, Rhines LD, Li Y, Uhelski ML, Dougherty PM, Price TJ. ACE2 and SCARF expression in human DRG nociceptors: implications for SARS-CoV-2 virus neurological effects. PAIN 2020;161:2494&#x2013;2501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7572821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skorna M, Kopacik R, Vlckova E, Adamova B, Kostalova M, Bednarik J. Small-nerve-fiber pathology in critical illness documented by serial skin biopsies. Muscle Nerve 2015;52:28&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25307783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon IH, Normandin E, Bhattacharyya S, Mukerji SS, Keller K, Ali AS, Adams G, Hornick JL, Padera RF, Sabeti P. Neuropathological features of covid-19. New Engl J Med 2020;383:989&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7304421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E, Zhang C, Israelow B, Lu-Culligan A, Prado AV, Skriabine S, Lu P, Weizman OE, Liu F, Dai Y, Szigeti-Buck K, Yasumoto Y, Wang G, Castaldi C, Heltke J, Ng E, Wheeler J, Alfajaro MM, Levavasseur E, Fontes B, Ravindra NG, Van Dijk D, Mane S, Gunel M, Ring A, Jaffar Kazmi SA, Zhang K, Wilen CB, Horvath TL, Plu I, Haik S, Thomas JL, Louvi A, Farhadian SF, Huttner A, Seilhean D, Renier N, Bilguvar K, Iwasaki A. Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 in human and mouse brain. bioRxiv 2020. doi: 10.1101/2020.06.25.169946 [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.06.25.169946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stinson C, Deng M, Yee MB, Bellinger LL, Kinchington PR, Kramer PR. Sex differences underlying orofacial varicella zoster associated pain in rats. BMC Neurol 2017;17:95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5436469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28514943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Lancet Haematology. COVID-19 coagulopathy: an evolving story. Lancet Haematol 2020;7:e425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7250563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32470428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas T, Stefanoni D, Reisz JA, Nemkov T, Bertolone L, Francis RO, Hudson KE, Zimring JC, Hansen KC, Hod EA, Spitalnik SL, D'Alessandro A. COVID-19 infection alters kynurenine and fatty acid metabolism, correlating with IL-6 levels and renal status. JCI Insight 2020;5:e140327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7453907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32559180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trifilo MJ, Bergmann CC, Kuziel WA, Lane TE. CC chemokine ligand 3 (CCL3) regulates CD8+-T-cell effector function and migration following viral infection. J Virol 2003;77:4004&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC150617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12634360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trouillet-Assant S, Viel S, Gaymard A, Pons S, Richard J-C, Perret M, Villard M, Brengel-Pesce K, Lina B, Mezidi M, Bitker L, Belot A, group CHS . Type I IFN immunoprofiling in COVID-19 patients. J Allergy Clin Immunol 2020;146:206&#x2013;8.e202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7189845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32360285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unterman A, Sumida TS, Nouri N, Yan X, Zhao AY, Gasque V, Schupp JC, Asashima H, Liu Y, Cosme C, Deng W, Chen M, Brickman Raredon MS, Hoehn K, Wang G, Wang Z, Deiuliis G, Ravindra NG, Li N, Castaldi C, Wong P, Fournier J, Bermejo S, Sharma L, Casanovas-Massana A, Vogels CBF, Wyllie AL, Grubaugh ND, Melillo A, Meng H, Minasyan M, Niklason LE, Ko AI, Montgomery RR, Farhadian SF, Iwasaki A, Shaw AC, van Dijk D, Zhao H, Kleinstein SH, Hafler DA, Kaminski N, Dela Cruz CS. Single-cell omics reveals dyssynchrony of the innate and adaptive immune system in progressive COVID-19. medRxiv 2020. doi: 10.1101/2020.07.16.20153437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.07.16.20153437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8782894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35064122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vishnubalaji R, Shaath H, Alajez NM. Protein coding and long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) transcriptional landscape in SARS-CoV-2 infected bronchial epithelial cells highlight a role for interferon and inflammatory response. Genes (Basel) 2020;11:760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7397219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32646047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Buchholtz LJ, Lam RM, Emrick JJ, Chesler AT, Ryba NJP. Assigning transcriptomic class in the trigeminal ganglion using multiplex in situ hybridization and machine learning. PAIN 2020;161:2212&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7606614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Town T, Alexopoulou L, Anderson JF, Fikrig E, Flavell RA. Toll-like receptor 3 mediates West Nile virus entry into the brain causing lethal encephalitis. Nat Med 2004;10:1366&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15558055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wangzhou A, McIlvried LA, Paige C, Barragan-Iglesias P, Shiers S, Ahmad A, Guzman CA, Dussor G, Ray PR, Gereau RWt, Price TJ. Pharmacological target-focused transcriptomic analysis of native vs cultured human and mouse dorsal root ganglia. PAIN 2020;161:1497&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7305999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32197039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wangzhou A, Paige C, Neerukonda SV, Dussor G, Ray PR, Price TJ. A pharmacological interactome platform for discovery of pain mechanisms and targets. Science Signaling 2020. doi: 10.1101/2020.04.14.041715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.04.14.041715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8097872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33727337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk AJ, Rustagi A, Zhao NQ, Roque J, Mart&#xed;nez-Col&#xf3;n GJ, McKechnie JL, Ivison GT, Ranganath T, Vergara R, Hollis T, Simpson LJ, Grant P, Subramanian A, Rogers AJ, Blish CA. A single-cell atlas of the peripheral immune response in patients with severe COVID-19. Nat Med 2020;26:1070&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7382903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32514174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JG, Simpson LJ, Ferreira A-M, Rustagi A, Roque JA, Asuni A, Ranganath T, Grant PM, Subramanian AK, Rosenberg-Hasson Y, Maecker H, Holmes S, Levitt JE, Blish C, Rogers AJ. Cytokine profile in plasma of severe COVID-19 does not differ from ARDS and sepsis. JCI Insight 2020;5:e140289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7526438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32706339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolf CJ, Allchorne A, Safieh-Garabedian B, Poole S. Cytokines, nerve growth factor and inflammatory hyperalgesia: the contribution of tumour necrosis factor alpha. Br J Pharmacol 1997;121:417&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1564704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9179382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu A, Peng Y, Huang B, Ding X, Wang X, Niu P, Meng J, Zhu Z, Zhang Z, Wang J, Sheng J, Quan L, Xia Z, Tan W, Cheng G, Jiang T. Genome composition and divergence of the novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV) originating in China. Cell host &amp; microbe 2020;27:325&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7154514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32035028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wysocki J, Lores E, Ye M, Soler MJ, Batlle D. Kidney and lung ACE2 expression after an ACE inhibitor or an ang II receptor blocker: implications for COVID-19. J Am Soc Nephrol 2020;31:1941&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32669323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia H, Cao Z, Xie X, Zhang X, Chen JY, Wang H, Menachery VD, Rajsbaum R, Shi PY. Evasion of type I interferon by SARS-CoV-2. Cell Rep 2020;33:108234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7501843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32979938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y, Liu Y, Cao L, Wang D, Guo M, Jiang A, Guo D, Hu W, Yang J, Tang Z, Wu H, Lin Y, Zhang M, Zhang Q, Shi M, Liu Y, Zhou Y, Lan K, Chen Y. Transcriptomic characteristics of bronchoalveolar lavage fluid and peripheral blood mononuclear cells in COVID-19 patients. Emerging Microbes Infections 2020;9:761&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7170362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32228226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu ZS, Shu T, Kang L, Wu D, Zhou X, Liao BW, Sun XL, Zhou X, Wang YY. Temporal profiling of plasma cytokines, chemokines and growth factors from mild, severe and fatal COVID-19 patients. Signal Transduction Targeted Ther 2020;5:100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7303571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32561706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan R, Zhang Y, Li Y, Xia L, Guo Y, Zhou Q. Structural basis for the recognition of SARS-CoV-2 by full-length human ACE2. Science 2020;367:1444&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7164635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32132184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang AC, Kern F, Losada PM, Maat CA, Schmartz G, Fehlmann T, Schaum N, Lee DP, Calcuttawala K, Vest RT, Gate D, Berdnik D, McNerney MW, Channappa D, Cobos I, Ludwig N, Schulz-Schaeffer WJ, Keller A, Wyss-Coray T. Broad transcriptional dysregulation of brain and choroid plexus cell types with COVID-19. bioRxiv 2020. doi: 10.1101/2020.10.22.349415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.10.22.349415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousuf MS, Samtleben S, Lamothe SM, Friedman TN, Catuneanu A, Thorburn K, Desai M, Tenorio G, Schenk GJ, Ballanyi K, Kurata HT, Simmen T, Kerr BJ. Endoplasmic reticulum stress in the dorsal root ganglia regulates large-conductance potassium channels and contributes to pain in a model of multiple sclerosis. FASEB J 2020. doi: 10.1096/fj.202001163R [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202001163R</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32677089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Charmchi Z, Seidman RJ, Anziska Y, Velayudhan V, Perk J. COVID-19&#x2013;associated myositis with severe proximal and bulbar weakness. Muscle Nerve 2020;62:E57&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32535934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JY, Wang XM, Xing X, Xu Z, Zhang C, Song JW, Fan X, Xia P, Fu JL, Wang SY, Xu RN, Dai XP, Shi L, Huang L, Jiang TJ, Shi M, Zhang Y, Zumla A, Maeurer M, Bai F, Wang FS. Single-cell landscape of immunological responses in patients with COVID-19. Nat Immunol 2020;21:1107&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Bastard P, Liu Z, Le Pen J, Moncada-Velez M, Chen J, Ogishi M, Sabli IKD, Hodeib S, Korol C, Rosain J, Bilguvar K, Ye J, Bolze A, Bigio B, Yang R, Arias AA, Zhou Q, Zhang Y, Onodi F, Korniotis S, Karpf L, Philippot Q, Chbihi M, Bonnet-Madin L, Dorgham K, Smith N, Schneider WM, Razooky BS, Hoffmann HH, Michailidis E, Moens L, Han JE, Lorenzo L, Bizien L, Meade P, Neehus AL, Ugurbil AC, Corneau A, Kerner G, Zhang P, Rapaport F, Seeleuthner Y, Manry J, Masson C, Schmitt Y, Schluter A, Le Voyer T, Khan T, Li J, Fellay J, Roussel L, Shahrooei M, Alosaimi MF, Mansouri D, Al-Saud H, Al-Mulla F, Almourfi F, Al-Muhsen SZ, Alsohime F, Al Turki S, Hasanato R, van de Beek D, Biondi A, Bettini LR, D'Angio M, Bonfanti P, Imberti L, Sottini A, Paghera S, Quiros-Roldan E, Rossi C, Oler AJ, Tompkins MF, Alba C, Vandernoot I, Goffard JC, Smits G, Migeotte I, Haerynck F, Soler-Palacin P, Martin-Nalda A, Colobran R, Morange PE, Keles S, Colkesen F, Ozcelik T, Yasar KK, Senoglu S, Karabela SN, Rodriguez-Gallego C, Novelli G, Hraiech S, Tandjaoui-Lambiotte Y, Duval X, Laouenan C, Clinicians C-S, Clinicians C, Imagine CG, French CCSG, Co VCC, Amsterdam UMCCB, Effort CHG, Group N-UTCI, Snow AL, Dalgard CL, Milner JD, Vinh DC, Mogensen TH, Marr N, Spaan AN, Boisson B, Boisson-Dupuis S, Bustamante J, Puel A, Ciancanelli MJ, Meyts I, Maniatis T, Soumelis V, Amara A, Nussenzweig M, Garcia-Sastre A, Krammer F, Pujol A, Duffy D, Lifton RP, Zhang SY, Gorochov G, Beziat V, Jouanguy E, Sancho-Shimizu V, Rice CM, Abel L, Notarangelo LD, Cobat A, Su HC, Casanova JL. Inborn errors of type I IFN immunity in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science 2020;370:eabd4570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Han T, Chen J, Hou C, Hua L, He S, Guo Y, Zhang S, Wang Y, Yuan J, Zhao C, Zhang J, Jia Q, Zuo X, Li J, Wang L, Cao Q, Jia E. Clinical and autoimmune characteristics of severe and critical cases of COVID-19. Clin Transl Sci 2020. doi: 10.1111/cts.12805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cts.12805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32315487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Yang P, Zhao Y, Zhuang Z, Wang Z, Song R, Zhang J, Liu C, Gao Q, Xu Q, Wei X, Sun HX, Ye B, Wu Y, Zhang N, Lei G, Yu L, Yan J, Diao G, Meng F, Bai C, Mao P, Yu Y, Wang M, Yuan Y, Deng Q, Li Z, Huang Y, Hu G, Liu Y, Wang X, Xu Z, Liu P, Bi Y, Shi Y, Zhang S, Chen Z, Wang J, Xu X, Wu G, Wang FS, Gao GF, Liu L, Liu WJ. Single-cell sequencing of peripheral mononuclear cells reveals distinct immune response landscapes of COVID-19 and influenza patients. Immunity 2020;53:685&#x2013;96 e683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7368915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32783921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zylka MJ, Rice FL, Anderson DJ. Topographically distinct epidermal nociceptive circuits revealed by axonal tracers targeted to Mrgprd. Neuron 2005;45:17&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15629699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>