<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34845462</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>medRxiv : the preprint server for health sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>medRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Higher Limbic and Basal Ganglia volumes in surviving COVID-negative patients and the relations to fatigue.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2021.11.23.21266761</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1101/2021.11.23.21266761</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Among systemic abnormalities caused by the novel coronavirus, little is known about the critical attack on the central nervous system (CNS). Few studies have shown cerebrovascular pathologies that indicate CNS involvement in acute patients. However, replication studies are necessary to verify if these effects persist in COVID-19 survivors more conclusively. Furthermore, recent studies indicate fatigue is highly prevalent among 'long-COVID' patients. How morphometry in each group relate to work-related fatigue need to be investigated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">COVID survivors were MRI scanned two weeks after hospital discharge. We hypothesized, these survivors will demonstrate altered gray matter volume (GMV) and experience higher fatigue levels when compared to healthy controls, leading to stronger correlation of GMV with fatigue. Voxel-based morphometry was performed on T1-weighted MRI images between 46 survivors and 30 controls. Unpaired two-sample t-test and multiple linear regression were performed to observe group differences and correlation of fatigue with GMV.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The COVID group experienced significantly higher fatigue levels and GMV of this group was significantly higher within the <i>Limbic System</i> and <i>Basal Ganglia</i> when compared to healthy controls. Moreover, while a significant positive correlation was observed across the whole group between GMV and self-reported fatigue, COVID subjects showed stronger effects within the <i>Posterior Cingulate, Precuneus</i> and <i>Superior Parietal Lobule</i> .</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Brain regions with GMV alterations in our analysis align with both single case acute patient reports and current group level neuroimaging findings. We also newly report a stronger positive correlation of GMV with fatigue among COVID survivors within brain regions associated with fatigue, indicating a link between structural abnormality and brain function in this cohort.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hafiz</LastName><ForeName>Rakibul</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, New Jersey Institute of Technology (NJIT), 323 Dr Martin Luther King Jr Blvd, Newark, NJ 07102, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gandhi</LastName><ForeName>Tapan Kumar</ForeName><Initials>TK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Block II, IIT Delhi Main Rd, IIT Campus, Hauz Khas, New Delhi, Delhi 110016, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mishra</LastName><ForeName>Sapna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Block II, IIT Delhi Main Rd, IIT Campus, Hauz Khas, New Delhi, Delhi 110016, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prasad</LastName><ForeName>Alok</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Irene Hospital &amp; Senior Consultant Medicine, Metro Heart and Super-specialty Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahajan</LastName><ForeName>Vidur</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Advanced Research in Imaging, Neuroscience &amp; Genomics, Mahajan Imaging, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, New Jersey Institute of Technology (NJIT), 323 Dr Martin Luther King Jr Blvd, Newark, NJ 07102, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Natelson</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin H</ForeName><Initials>BH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Director, Pain &amp; Fatigue Study Center, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, The Mount Sinai Hospital, 5 East 98th Street, 7th Floor, New York, NY 10029.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biswal</LastName><ForeName>Bharat B</ForeName><Initials>BB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, New Jersey Institute of Technology (NJIT), 323 Dr Martin Luther King Jr Blvd, Newark, NJ 07102, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AT009829</GrantID><Acronym>AT</Acronym><Agency>NCCIH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>medRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101767986</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateIn"><RefSource>Neuroimage Rep. 2022 Jun;2(2):100095. doi: 10.1016/j.ynirp.2022.100095</RefSource><PMID Version="1">35496469</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34845462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8629206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.11.23.21266761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2021.11.23.21266761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>(WHO) WHO. WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard 2022 [February/12/2022]. Available from: WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kremer S, Lersy F, Anheim M, Merdji H, Schenck M, Oesterl&#xe9; H, Bolognini F, Messie J, Khalil A, Gaudemer A, Carr&#xe9; S, Alleg M, Lecocq C, Schmitt E, Anxionnat R, Zhu F, Jager L, Nesser P, Mba YT, Hmeydia G, Benzakoun J, Oppenheim C, Ferr&#xe9; JC, Maamar A, Carsin-Nicol B, Comby PO, Ricolfi F, Thouant P, Boutet C, Fabre X, Forestier G, de Beaurepaire I, Bornet G, Desal H, Boulouis G, Berge J, Kaz&#xe9;mi A, Pyatigorskaya N, Lecler A, Saleme S, Edjlali-Goujon M, Kerleroux B, Constans JM, Zorn PE, Mathieu M, Baloglu S, Ardellier FD, Willaume T, Brisset JC, Caillard S, Collange O, Mertes PM, Schneider F, Fafi-Kremer S, Ohana M, Meziani F, Meyer N, Helms J, Cotton F. Neurologic and neuroimaging findings in patients with COVID-19: A retrospective multicenter study. Neurology. 2020;95(13):e1868&#x2013;e82. Epub 2020/07/19. doi: 10.1212/wnl.0000000000010112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.0000000000010112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32680942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller E, Brandi G, Winklhofer S, Imbach LL, Kirschenbaum D, Frontzek K, Steiger P, Dietler S, Haeberlin M, Willms J, Porta F, Waeckerlin A, Huber M, Abela IA, Lutterotti A, Stippich C, Globas C, Varga Z, Jelcic I. Large and Small Cerebral Vessel Involvement in Severe COVID-19: Detailed Clinical Workup of a Case Series. Stroke. 2020;51(12):3719&#x2013;22. Epub 2020/10/16. doi: 10.1161/strokeaha.120.031224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/strokeaha.120.031224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7678671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33054673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson P, Alshafai L, Krings T. Neuroimaging Findings in Patients with COVID-19. American Journal of Neuroradiology. 2020;41(8):1380&#x2013;3. doi: 10.3174/ajnr.A6630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3174/ajnr.A6630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7658900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32527843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radmanesh A, Derman A, Lui YW, Raz E, Loh JP, Hagiwara M, Borja MJ, Zan E, Fatterpekar GM. COVID-19-associated Diffuse Leukoencephalopathy and Microhemorrhages. Radiology. 2020;297(1):E223&#x2013;E7. Epub 2020/05/21. doi: 10.1148/radiol.2020202040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2020202040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7507998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandemirli SG, Dogan L, Sarikaya ZT, Kara S, Akinci C, Kaya D, Kaya Y, Yildirim D, Tuzuner F, Yildirim MS, Ozluk E, Gucyetmez B, Karaarslan E, Koyluoglu I, Demirel Kaya HS, Mammadov O, Kisa Ozdemir I, Afsar N, Citci Yalcinkaya B, Rasimoglu S, Guduk DE, Kedir Jima A, Ilksoz A, Ersoz V, Yonca Eren M, Celtik N, Arslan S, Korkmazer B, Dincer SS, Gulek E, Dikmen I, Yazici M, Unsal S, Ljama T, Demirel I, Ayyildiz A, Kesimci I, Bolsoy Deveci S, Tutuncu M, Kizilkilic O, Telci L, Zengin R, Dincer A, Akinci IO, Kocer N. Brain MRI Findings in Patients in the Intensive Care Unit with COVID-19 Infection. Radiology. 2020;297(1):E232&#x2013;e5. Epub 2020/05/10. doi: 10.1148/radiol.2020201697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2020201697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7507997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32384020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson RW, Brown RL, Benjamin L, Nortley R, Wiethoff S, Bharucha T, Jayaseelan DL, Kumar G, Raftopoulos RE, Zambreanu L, Vivekanandam V, Khoo A, Geraldes R, Chinthapalli K, Boyd E, Tuzlali H, Price G, Christofi G, Morrow J, McNamara P, McLoughlin B, Lim ST, Mehta PR, Levee V, Keddie S, Yong W, Trip SA, Foulkes AJM, Hotton G, Miller TD, Everitt AD, Carswell C, Davies NWS, Yoong M, Attwell D, Sreedharan J, Silber E, Schott JM, Chandratheva A, Perry RJ, Simister R, Checkley A, Longley N, Farmer SF, Carletti F, Houlihan C, Thom M, Lunn MP, Spillane J, Howard R, Vincent A, Werring DJ, Hoskote C, J&#xe4;ger HR, Manji H, Zandi MS. The emerging spectrum of COVID-19 neurology: clinical, radiological and laboratory findings. Brain. 2020;143(10):3104&#x2013;20. Epub 2020/07/09. doi: 10.1093/brain/awaa240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awaa240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32637987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan K, Premi E, Pilotto A, Cristillo V, Benussi A, Libri I, Giunta M, Bockholt HJ, Liu J, Campora R, Pezzini A, Gasparotti R, Magoni M, Padovani A, Calhoun VD. Alterations of frontal-temporal gray matter volume associate with clinical measures of older adults with COVID-19. Neurobiol Stress. 2021;14:100326. Epub 20210413. doi: 10.1016/j.ynstr.2021.100326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ynstr.2021.100326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8041745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33869679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin Y, Wu J, Chen T, Li J, Zhang G, Wu D, Zhou Y, Zheng N, Cai A, Ning Q, Manyande A, Xu F, Wang J, Zhu W. Long-term microstructure and cerebral blood flow changes in patients recovered from COVID-19 without neurological manifestations. J Clin Invest. 2021;131(8). doi: 10.1172/jci147329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci147329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8262559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33630760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F, Arthofer C, Wang C, Lange F, Andersson JLR, Griffanti L, Duff E, Jbabdi S, Taschler B, Winkler A, Nichols TE, Collins R, Matthews PM, Allen N, Miller KL, Smith SM. Brain imaging before and after COVID-19 in UK Biobank. medRxiv. 2021. Epub 20210620. doi: 10.1101/2021.06.11.21258690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.06.11.21258690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li X, Geng D, Mei N, Wu P-Y, Huang C-C, Jia T, Zhao Y, Wang D, Xiao A, Yin B. Cerebral Micro-Structural Changes in COVID-19 Patients &#x2013; An MRI-based 3-month Follow-up Study. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu Y, Zhang Y, Li Y, Zhao Q, Bi Y, Lu X, Kong Y, Wang L, Lu Z, Hu L. Post-traumatic stress symptoms in COVID-19 survivors: a self-report and brain imaging follow-up study. Molecular Psychiatry. 2021. doi: 10.1038/s41380-021-01223-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-021-01223-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8290134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34285348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logue JK, Franko NM, McCulloch DJ, McDonald D, Magedson A, Wolf CR, Chu HY. Sequelae in Adults at 6 Months After COVID-19 Infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(2):e210830. Epub 2021/02/20. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.0830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.0830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33606031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabacof L, Tosto-Mancuso J, Wood J, Cortes M, Kontorovich A, McCarthy D, Rizk D, Mohammadi N, Breyman E, Nasr L, Kellner C, Putrino D. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome negatively impacts health and wellbeing despite less severe acute infection. medRxiv. 2020:2020.11.04.20226126. doi: 10.1101/2020.11.04.20226126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.11.04.20226126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Kelly JD, Lu S, Goldberg SA, Davidson MC, Mathur S, Durstenfeld MS, Spinelli MA, Hoh R, Tai V, Fehrman EA, Torres L, Hernandez Y, Williams MC, Arreguin MI, Bautista JA, Ngo LH, Deswal M, Munter SE, Martinez EO, Anglin KA, Romero MD, Tavs J, Rugart PR, Chen JY, Sans HM, Murray VW, Ellis PK, Donohue KC, Massachi JA, Weiss JO, Mehdi I, Pineda-Ramirez J, Tang AF, Wegner M, Assenzio M, Yuan Y, Krone M, Rutishauser RL, Rodriguez-Barraquer I, Greenhouse B, Sauceda JA, Gandhi M, Hsue P, Henrich TJ, Deeks SG, Martin JN. Rapid implementation of a cohort for the study of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection/COVID-19. medRxiv. 2021:2021.03.11.21252311. doi: 10.1101/2021.03.11.21252311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.03.11.21252311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashburner J, Friston KJ. Voxel-Based Morphometry&#x2014;The Methods. NeuroImage. 2000;11(6):805&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1006/nimg.2000.0582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/nimg.2000.0582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10860804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashburner J. A fast diffeomorphic image registration algorithm. NeuroImage. 2007;38(1):95&#x2013;113. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2007.07.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2007.07.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17761438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashburner J, Friston KJ. Computing average shaped tissue probability templates. NeuroImage. 2009;45(2):333&#x2013;41. Epub 2009/01/17. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2008.12.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2008.12.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19146961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yassa MA, Stark CE. A quantitative evaluation of cross-participant registration techniques for MRI studies of the medial temporal lobe. NeuroImage. 2009;44(2):319&#x2013;27. Epub 2008/10/22. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2008.09.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2008.09.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18929669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;ders E, Steinmetz H, J&#xe4;ncke L. Brain size and grey matter volume in the healthy human brain. Neuroreport. 2002;13(17), https://journals.lww.com/neuroreport/Fulltext/2002/12030/Brain_size_and_grey_matter_volume_in_the_healthy.40.aspx.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12488829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RStudio. RStudio Team (2021). RStudio: Integrated Development for R. http://www.rstudio.com/.
RStudio, Inc. Boston, MA: RStudio; 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen M, Poggiali D, Whitaker K, Marshall TR, Van Langen J, Kievit RA. Raincloud plots: a multi-platform tool for robust data visualization. Wellcome Open Research. 2021;4:63. doi: 10.12688/wellcomeopenres.15191.2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/wellcomeopenres.15191.2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6480976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31069261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Q, Peng W, Zhang J, Weng X, Zhang Y, Liu T, Zang Y-F, Wang Z. Short-term apparent brain tissue changes are contributed by cerebral blood flow alterations. PloS one. 2017;12(8):e0182182. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0182182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0182182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5562307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28820894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho SS, Aminian K, Li C, Lang AE, Houle S, Strafella AP. Fatigue in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: The contribution of cerebral metabolic changes. Human brain mapping. 2017;38(1):283&#x2013;92. Epub 2016/08/29. doi: 10.1002/hbm.23360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.23360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6867035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27571419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boissoneault J, Letzen J, Lai S, Robinson ME, Staud R. Static and dynamic functional connectivity in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome: use of arterial spin labelling fMRI. Clinical physiology and functional imaging. 2018;38(1):128&#x2013;37. Epub 2016/09/28. doi: 10.1111/cpf.12393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5373941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27678090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gay CW, Robinson ME, Lai S, O&#x2019;Shea A, Craggs JG, Price DD, Staud R. Abnormal Resting-State Functional Connectivity in Patients with Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: Results of Seed and Data-Driven Analyses. Brain connectivity. 2016;6(1):48&#x2013;56. Epub 2015/11/10. doi: 10.1089/brain.2015.0366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/brain.2015.0366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4744887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26449441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese M, Rinaldi F, Grossi P, Mattisi I, Bernardi V, Favaretto A, Perini P, Gallo P. Basal ganglia and frontal/parietal cortical atrophy is associated with fatigue in relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler. 2010;16(10):1220&#x2013;8. Epub 20100729. doi: 10.1177/1352458510376405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458510376405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20670981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellicano C, Gallo A, Li X, Ikonomidou VN, Evangelou IE, Ohayon JM, Stern SK, Ehrmantraut M, Cantor F, McFarland HF, Bagnato F. Relationship of Cortical Atrophy to Fatigue in Patients With Multiple Sclerosis. Archives of Neurology. 2010;67(4):447&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1001/archneurol.2010.48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneurol.2010.48</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20385911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wylie GR, Genova H, Dobryakova E, DeLuca J, Chiaravalloti N, Falvo M, Cook D. Fatigue in Gulf War Illness is associated with tonically high activation in the executive control network. NeuroImage Clinical. 2019;21:101641. Epub 20181211. doi: 10.1016/j.nicl.2018.101641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2018.101641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6411905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30558870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhuri A, Behan PO. Fatigue and basal ganglia. J Neurol Sci. 2000;179(S 1&#x2013;2):34&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1016/s0022-510x(00)00411-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0022-510x(00)00411-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11054483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobryakova E, Genova HM, DeLuca J, Wylie GR. The Dopamine Imbalance Hypothesis of Fatigue in Multiple Sclerosis and Other Neurological Disorders. Frontiers in Neurology. 2015;6(52). doi: 10.3389/fneur.2015.00052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2015.00052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4357260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25814977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wylie GR, Dobryakova E, DeLuca J, Chiaravalloti N, Essad K, Genova H. Cognitive fatigue in individuals with traumatic brain injury is associated with caudate activation. Scientific reports. 2017;7(1):8973. Epub 20170821. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-08846-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-08846-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5567054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28827779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobryakova E, Hulst HE, Spirou A, Chiaravalloti ND, Genova HM, Wylie GR, DeLuca J. Fronto-striatal network activation leads to less fatigue in multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler. 2018;24(9):1174&#x2013;82. Epub 20170619. doi: 10.1177/1352458517717087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458517717087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28627957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobryakova E, Genova H, Schneider V, Chiaravalloti ND, Spirou A, Wylie GR, DeLuca J. Reward presentation reduces on-task fatigue in traumatic brain injury. Cortex. 2020;126:16&#x2013;25. Epub 20200124. doi: 10.1016/j.cortex.2020.01.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cortex.2020.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32062140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bornh&#xf6;vd K, Quante M, Glauche V, Bromm B, Weiller C, B&#xfc;chel C. Painful stimuli evoke different stimulus-response functions in the amygdala, prefrontal, insula and somatosensory cortex: a single-trial fMRI study. Brain. 2002;125(Pt 6):1326&#x2013;36. Epub 2002/05/23. doi: 10.1093/brain/awf137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awf137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12023321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inagaki TK, Muscatell KA, Irwin MR, Cole SW, Eisenberger NI. Inflammation selectively enhances amygdala activity to socially threatening images. NeuroImage. 2012;59(4):3222&#x2013;6. Epub 2011/11/04. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2011.10.090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2011.10.090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3348143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22079507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sergeeva M, Rech J, Schett G, Hess A. Response to peripheral immune stimulation within the brain: magnetic resonance imaging perspective of treatment success. Arthritis Research &amp; Therapy. 2015;17(1):268. doi: 10.1186/s13075-015-0783-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-015-0783-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4610054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26477946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Schouwenburg MR, den Ouden HE, Cools R. Selective attentional enhancement and inhibition of fronto-posterior connectivity by the basal ganglia during attention switching. Cerebral cortex (New York, NY : 1991). 2015;25(6):1527&#x2013;34. Epub 2013/12/18. doi: 10.1093/cercor/bht345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bht345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24343891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpazza C, Nichols TE, Seramondi D, Maumet C, Sartori G, Mechelli A. When the Single Matters more than the Group (II): Addressing the Problem of High False Positive Rates in Single Case Voxel Based Morphometry Using Non-parametric Statistics. Frontiers in neuroscience. 2016;10:6&#x2013;. doi: 10.3389/fnins.2016.00006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2016.00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4724722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26834533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulko E, Oleksk ML, Gomes W, Ali S, Mehta H, Overby P, Al-Mufti F, Rozenshtein A. MRI Brain Findings in 126 Patients with COVID-19: Initial Observations from a Descriptive Literature Review. American Journal of Neuroradiology. 2020. doi: 10.3174/ajnr.A6805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3174/ajnr.A6805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7963260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32883670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>