<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38056494</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1439-1309</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Die Rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rehabilitation (Stuttg)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Assessment of Long COVID in Medical Rehabilitation].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>331</StartPage><EndPage>338</EndPage><MedlinePgn>331-338</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/a-2186-5422</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of the study was to provide an insight into the care situation of long COVID patients in inpatient medical rehabilitation facilities in Germany.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">For this purpose, a standardized online survey was conducted among 1,080 inpatient medical rehabilitation facilities in Germany.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 338 cases were available for the analysis. Of these, 173 (51%) reported treating long COVID. The cumulative total number of rehabilitants with long COVID treated in the facilities up to the time of the survey was 11,948. The results showed that rehabilitation facilities were mostly prepared for the care of patients with Long COVID. Lack of capacity was reported especially by those rehabilitation facilities that treated rehabilitants with long COVID in pneumology departments. Furthermore, capacity bottlenecks were related to the total number of patients with long COVID in the rehabilitation facility ("proportion of rehabilitants with long COVID to all rehabilitants in the department"). Heterogeneity was found in the treatment concept for long COVID and the allocation of patients to a specific department.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results of the long COVID inventory underline the importance of medical rehabilitation in the treatment of the long-term health and participation-related consequences of COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sch&#xfc;ring</LastName><ForeName>Stefan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fachbereich Teilhabeverfahrensbericht, Systembeobachtung und Forschung, Bundesarbeitsgemeinschaft f&#xfc;r Rehabilitation e. V. (BAR), Frankfurt am Main.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Widera</LastName><ForeName>Teresia</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fachbereich Teilhabeverfahrensbericht, Systembeobachtung und Forschung, Bundesarbeitsgemeinschaft f&#xfc;r Rehabilitation e. V. (BAR), Frankfurt am Main.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>ger</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><VernacularTitle>Bestandsaufnahme zu Long COVID in der medizinischen Rehabilitation.</VernacularTitle><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Rehabilitation (Stuttg)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0401273</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0034-3536</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005858" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Germany</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012047" MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation Centers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger"><AbstractText Label="ZIELSTELLUNG" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Ziel der explorativen Studie war es, einen Einblick in die Versorgungssituation von Long COVID-Patienten in den station&#xe4;ren medizinischen Reha-Einrichtungen in Deutschland zu gewinnen.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODIK" NlmCategory="METHODS">Daf&#xfc;r wurde eine standardisierte Online-Befragung unter den 1.080 station&#xe4;ren medizinischen Reha-Einrichtungen in Deutschland, die im Reha-Einrichtungsverzeichnis der Bundesarbeitsgemeinschaft f&#xfc;r Rehabilitation e. V. (BAR) gelistet sind, durchgef&#xfc;hrt.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ERGEBNISSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Insgesamt konnten die Antworten von 338 Reha-Einrichtungen f&#xfc;r die Auswertungen herangezogen werden. Davon gaben 173 (51%) an, Long COVID zu behandeln. Die kumulierte Gesamtzahl der bis zum Zeitpunkt der Befragung behandelten Long-COVID-Rehabilitanden in den Einrichtungen betrug 11.948. Die Ergebnisse zeigen, dass die Reha-Einrichtungen &#xfc;berwiegend auf die Versorgung von Patienten mit Long COVID vorbereitet sind. Fehlende Kapazit&#xe4;ten wurden insbesondere von jenen Reha-Einrichtungen berichtet, die Rehabilitanden mit Long COVID in pneumologischen Fachabteilungen behandeln. Au&#xdf;erdem hingen kapazitative Engp&#xe4;sse mit der Gesamtanzahl von Long-COVID-Patienten in der Reha-Einrichtung zusammen (Anteil von Long-COVID-Rehabilitanden an allen Rehabilitanden in der jeweiligen Fachabteilung). Heterogenit&#xe4;t zeigte sich im Bereich des Behandlungskonzeptes f&#xfc;r Long COVID und der Zuordnung der Patienten zu einer Fachabteilung.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SCHLUSSFOLGERUNG" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Die Ergebnisse der Long-COVID-Bestandserhebung unterstreichen die Bedeutung der medizinischen Rehabilitation in der Behandlung der gesundheitlichen und teilhabebezogenen Langzeitfolgen von COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><CoiStatement>Die Autorinnen/Autoren geben an, dass kein Interessenkonflikt besteht.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38056494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2186-5422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>