<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35169790</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2693-5015</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Research square</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Res Sq</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of COVID-19 symptoms on social aspects of life among female long haulers: A qualitative study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">rs.3.rs-1285284</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.21203/rs.3.rs-1285284/v1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Persistent COVID-19 symptoms (long COVID) may bring numerous challenges to long haulers' social lives. Women may have to endure more profound impacts given their social roles and existing structural inequality. This study aims to explore the impacts of long COVID on various aspects of social life among female long haulers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We conducted 15 semi-structured interviews with female long haulers in the United States purposely recruited from Facebook groups, Slack group, and organization websites. The interviews were audio recorded after appropriate consent and transcribed verbatim. Inductive approach was applied in thematic analysis, which consists of six stages: becoming familiar with data, developing initial codes, extracting themes, refining themes, labeling themes, and reporting. The MAXQDA software was used in data analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Participants reported persistent symptoms that negatively affected their social lives in many ways. The main impacts included physical limitation, financial hardship, social relationship, conflict of social roles, and social stigma. Negative effects of long COVID hindered female long haulers' recovery process. Social isolation, COVID-19 associated stigma, and conflicts of social roles cause tremendous stress. Employers' support and social media usage may play positive role in their coping with impacts of long COVID on their social life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Existing policies and intervention programs need to be adapted to address the challenges and barriers that long haulers face in returning to normal social life, especially for females. Tailored social life-related recommendations and social support are needed for female long haulers.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aghaei</LastName><ForeName>Atefeh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ran</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Slone</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tam</LastName><ForeName>Cheuk-Chi</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Chih-Hsiang</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoming</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qiao</LastName><ForeName>Shan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AI127203</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Res Sq</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101768035</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2693-5015</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">USA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">log haulers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quantitative study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social aspects of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">women</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35169790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8845510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.3.rs-1285284/v1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">rs.3.rs-1285284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard
2022. Available from: https://covid19.who.int/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leviner S. Recognizing the Clinical Sequelae of COVID-19 in Adults: COVID-19 Long-Haulers. Journal for nurse practitioners. 2021;17(8):946&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8103144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33976591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladds E, Rushforth A, Wieringa S, Taylor S, Rayner C, Husain L, et al. Persistent symptoms after Covid-19: qualitative study of 114 &#x201c;long Covid&#x201d; patients and draft quality principles for services. BMC health services research. 2020;20(1):1144&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7750006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33342437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callard F, Perego E. How and why patients made Long Covid. Social science &amp; medicine (1982). 2021;268:113426&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7539940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33199035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancet. Facing up to long COVID. The Lancet (British edition). 2020;396(10266):1861&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33308453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeting the challenge of long COVID. Nature medicine. 2020;26(12):1803&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33288947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, Geddes JR, Husain M, Harrison PJ. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: A 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS medicine. 2021;18(9):e1003773&#x2013;e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh J, Singh J. COVID-19 and Its Impact on Society. Electronic Research Journal of Social Sciences and Humanities. 2020;2(I).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HHS. DOJ issue guidance on &#x2018;Long COVID&#x2019; and disability rights under the ADA. Medicine and health, Rhode Island. 2021;104(6):86&#x2013;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peckham H, de Gruijter NM, Raine C, Radziszewska A, Ciurtin C, Wedderburn LR, et al. Male sex identified by global COVID-19 meta-analysis as a risk factor for death and ITU admission. Nature communications. 2020;11(1):6317&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7726563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33298944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson S, Hirsch JS, Narasimhan M, Crawford JM, McGinn T, Davidson KW, et al. Presenting Characteristics, Comorbidities, and Outcomes Among 5700 Patients Hospitalized With COVID-19 in the New York City Area. JAMA : the journal of the American Medical Association. 2020;323(20):2052&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7177629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32320003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connor J, Madhavan S, Mokashi M, Amanuel H, Johnson NR, Pace LE, et al. Health risks and outcomes that disproportionately affect women during the Covid-19 pandemic: A review. Social science &amp; medicine (1982). 2020;266:113364&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7487147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32950924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tajfel H, Turner J. An integrative theory of intergroup conflict: The Social Psychology of Inter-Group Relations; 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Dalton AN, Lee J. The &#x201c;Self&#x201d; under COVID-19: Social role disruptions, self-authenticity and present-focused coping. PloS one. 2021;16(9):e0256939&#x2013;e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8415594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34478454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung G, Lanier P, Wong PYJ. Mediating Effects of Parental Stress on Harsh Parenting and Parent-Child Relationship during Coronavirus (COVID-19) Pandemic in Singapore. Journal of family violence. 2020:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7467635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32895601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Labour Organization. The COVID-19 response: getting gender equality right for a better future for women at work. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson LM, Simard JF, Oluyomi A, Nava V, Rosas LG, Bondy M, et al. US Public Concerns About the COVID-19 Pandemic From Results of a Survey Given via Social Media. JAMA internal medicine. 2020;180(7):1020&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7139509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32259192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ettman CK, Abdalla SM, Cohen GH, Sampson L, Vivier PM, Galea S. Low assets and financial stressors associated with higher depression during COVID-19 in a nationally representative sample of US adults. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7722349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33277339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Financial Health Network. Income, age, race, and gender are key factors as new data shows 1 in 3 Americans earning less during COVID-19 Financial Health Network
2020.  [Available from: https://finhealthnetwork.org/research/income-age-race-and-gender-are-key-factors-as-new-data-shows-1-in-3-americans-earning-less-during-covid-19/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alon T, Doepke M, Tertilt M. This Time It&#x2019;s Different: The Role of Women&#x2019;s Employment in a Pandemic Recession. Cambridge, MA: National Bureau of Economic Research; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranji U, Frederiksen B, Salganicoff A, Long M. Women, Work, and Family During COVID-19: Findings from the KFF Women&#x2019;s Health Survey: Kaiser Family Foundation; 2021.  [Women&#x2019;s Health Policy: [Available from: https://www.kff.org/womens-health-policy/issue-brief/women-work-and-family-during-covid-19-findings-from-the-kff-womens-health-survey/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations. Policy brief: The impact of COVID-19 on Women. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoom Video Communications Inc. https://zoom.us/
2021.  [Available from: https://zoom.us/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otter.ai. https://otter.ai/
2021.  [</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyatzis RE. Transforming qualitative information : thematic analysis and code development. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fereday J, Muir-Cochrane E. Demonstrating Rigor Using Thematic Analysis: A Hybrid Approach of Inductive and Deductive Coding and Theme Development. International journal of qualitative methods. 2006;5(1):80&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest G, Bunce A, Johnson L. How Many Interviews Are Enough?: An Experiment with Data Saturation and Variability. Field methods. 2006;18(1):59&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qualitative research in psychology. 2006;3(2):77&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAXQDA. https://www.maxqda.com.
2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnard P. A method of analysing interview transcripts in qualitative research. Nurse education today. 1991;11(6):461&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1775125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polit DF, Hungler BP. Nursing research: principles and methods. 7th ed. Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbin JM, Strauss A. Basics of Qualitative Research: Techniques and Procedures for Developing Grounded Theory. Los Angeles: SAGE Publications Inc; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln YS, Guba EG. Naturalistic inquiry. Beverly Hills, Calif: Sage Publications; 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padgett D. Qualitative methods in social work research. 2nd ed. Los Angeles, Calif: Sage Publications; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krippendorff K. Content analysis : an introduction to its methodology. Beverly Hills: Sage Publications; 1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor C, Joffe H. Intercoder Reliability in Qualitative Research: Debates and Practical Guidelines. International journal of qualitative methods. 2020;19:160940691989922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelley J, Hudson J, Mackintosh KA, Saynor ZL, Duckers J, Lewis KE, et al. &#x2018;I Live a Kind of Shadow Life&#x2019;: Individual Experiences of COVID-19 Recovery and the Impact on Physical Activity Levels. International journal of environmental research and public health. 2021;18(21):11417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8583577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34769934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew M, Kerai G, Ainslie D. Coronavirus and the social impacts of &#x2018;long COVID&#x2019; on people&#x2019;s lives in Great Britain: 7 April to 13 June 2021. Newport, Wales: Office for National Statistics; 2021. p. 1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphreys H, Kilby L, Kudiersky N, Copeland R. Long COVID and the role of physical activity: a qualitative study. BMJ open. 2021;11(3):e047632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7948149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swami V, Todd J, Robinson C, Furnham A. Self-compassion mediates the relationship between COVID-19-related stress and body image disturbance: Evidence from the United Kingdom under lockdown. Personality and individual differences. 2021;183:111130&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8675061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34931100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burki T. The indirect impact of COVID-19 on women. The Lancet infectious diseases. 2020;20(8):904&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin J-M, Bai P, He W, Wu F, Liu X-F, Han D-M, et al. Gender Differences in Patients With COVID-19: Focus on Severity and Mortality. Frontiers in public health. 2020;8:152&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7201103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32411652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Labour Organization. COVID-19 and the world of work: Impact and policy responses. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Boca D, Oggero N, Profeta P, Rossi M. Women&#x2019;s and men&#x2019;s work, housework and childcare, before and during COVID-19. Review of economics of the household. 2020;18(4):1001&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7474798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32922242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utami WK, Godjali MR. The Role of Women in Empowerment and Improvement of Community Literation through Waste Management. Journal of Governance. 2020;5(2):164&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safrizal HBA, Eliyana A, Febriyanti KL. The Effect of Double Role Conflict (Work Family Conflict) on Female Worker&#x2019;s Performance with Work Stress as the Intervening Variable. Systematic Reviews in Pharmacy. 2020;11(10):10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantamneni N. The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on marginalized populations in the United States: A research agenda. Journal of vocational behavior. 2020;119:103439&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7205696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32390658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nohe C, Meier LL, Sonntag K, Michel A. The Chicken or the Egg? A Meta-Analysis of Panel Studies of the Relationship Between Work-Family Conflict and Strain. Journal of applied psychology. 2015;100(2):522&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25285385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenham C, Smith J, Davies SE, Feng H, Gr&#xe9;pin KA, Harman S, et al. Women are most affected by pandemics - lessons from past outbreaks. Nature (London). 2020;583(7815):194&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32641809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong DT, Belkin LY. You Don&#x2019;t Care for me, So What&#x2019;s the Point for me to Care for Your Business? Negative Implications of Felt Neglect by the Employer for Employee Work Meaning and Citizenship Behaviors Amid the COVID-19 Pandemic. Journal of business ethics. 2021:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8476982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34602685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey S, Haines VY III. Employer Treatment of Employees during a Community Crisis: The Role of Procedural and Distributive Justice. Journal of business and psychology. 2005;20(1):53&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaushik M, Guleria N. The Impact of Pandemic COVID &#x2212;19 in Workplace. European Journal of Business and Management. 2020;12:9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frye NK, Breaugh JA. Family-Friendly Policies, Supervisor Support, Work-Family Conflict, Family-Work Conflict, and Satisfaction: A Test of a Conceptual Model. Journal of business and psychology. 2004;19(2):197&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karatepe OM, Kilic H. Relationships of supervisor support and conflicts in the work&#x2013;family interface with the selected job outcomes of frontline employees. Tourism management (1982). 2007;28(1):238&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schieman S, Badawy PJ, Milkie M A., Bierman A. Work-Life Conflict During the COVID-19 Pandemic. Socius : sociological research for a dynamic world. 2021;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demerouti E, Geurts SAE, Kompier M. Positive and negative work-home interaction: prevalence and correlates. Equal opportunities international. 2004;23(1/2):6&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill EJ. Work-Family Facilitation and Conflict, Working Fathers and Mothers, Work-Family Stressors and Support. Journal of family issues. 2005;26(6):793&#x2013;819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algeri D, Saladino V, Auriemma V. The Psychological and Social Impact of Covid-19: New Perspectives of Well-Being. Frontiers in psychology. 2020;11:577684&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7561673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33132986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harasemiw O, Newall N, Mackenzie CS, Shooshtari S, Menec V. Is the association between social network types, depressive symptoms and life satisfaction mediated by the perceived availability of social support? A cross-sectional analysis using the Canadian Longitudinal Study on Aging. Aging &amp; mental health. 2019;23(10):1413&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30406668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng L, Miao M, Gan Y. Perceived Control Buffers the Effects of the COVID-19 Pandemic on General Health and Life Satisfaction: The Mediating Role of Psychological Distance. Applied psychology : health and well-being. 2020;12(4):1095&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32955170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clair R, Gordon M, Kroon M, Reilly C. The effects of social isolation on well-being and life satisfaction during pandemic. Humanities &amp; social sciences communications. 2021;8(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umberson D, Montez JK. Social Relationships and Health: A Flashpoint for Health Policy. Journal of health and social behavior. 2010;51(1_suppl):S54&#x2013;S66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3150158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20943583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegelman JN. Reflections of a COVID-19 Long Hauler. JAMA : the journal of the American Medical Association. 2020;324(20):2031&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel A, Gupta L. Social Media in the Times of COVID-19. Journal of clinical rheumatology. 2020;26(6):13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7437428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32852927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venegas-Vera AV, Colbert GB, Lerma EV. Positive and negative impact of social media in the COVID-19 era. Reviews in cardiovascular medicine. 2020;21(4):561&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33388000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goggin G, Ellis K. Disability, communication, and life itself in the COVID-19 pandemic. Health sociology review. 2020;29(2):168&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33411654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennington N. Communication outside of the home through social media during COVID-19. Computers in human behavior reports. 2021;4:100118&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8452466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34568638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imran N, Afzal H, Aamer I, Hashmi AM, Shabbir B, Asif A, et al. Scarlett Letter: A study based on experience of stigma by COVID-19 patients in quarantine. Pakistan journal of medical sciences. 2020;36(7):1471&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7674879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33235559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohiniva A-L, Dub T, Hagberg L, Nohynek H. Learning about COVID-19-related stigma, quarantine and isolation experiences in Finland. PloS one. 2021;16(4):e0247962&#x2013;e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8046198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33852581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baral N, Adhikari G, Karki S, Champine A, Sud P. Does Social Stigma and Neglect Post-COVID-19 Matter? A Case Report on Brief Psychotic Disorder Post-COVID-19 and Self-Quarantine. Cur&#x113;us (Palo Alto, CA). 2021;13(1):e12973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7913998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33654634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed F, Mihan R, Mousavi SZ, Reniers RL, Bateni FS, Alikhani R, et al. A Narrative Review of Stigma Related to Infectious Disease Outbreaks: What Can Be Learned in the Face of the Covid-19 Pandemic? Frontiers in psychiatry. 2020;11:565919&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7738431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33343414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grover S, Sahoo S, Mishra E, Gill KS, Mehra A, Nehra R, et al. Fatigue, perceived stigma, self-reported cognitive deficits and psychological morbidity in patients recovered from COVID-19 infection. Asian journal of psychiatry. 2021;64:102815&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8379818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34455354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruns DP, Kraguljac NV, Bruns TR. COVID-19: Facts, Cultural Considerations, and Risk of Stigmatization. Journal of transcultural nursing. 2020;31(4):326&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7324134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32316872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry P, Donini-Lenhoff F. Stigmatization complicates infectious disease management. AMA Journal of Ethics. 2010;12(3):5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23140873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korstjens I, Moser A. Series: Practical guidance to qualitative research. Part 4: Trustworthiness and publishing. The European journal of general practice. 2018;24(1):120&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8816392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29202616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>