<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37525488</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2151-4658</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>76</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Arthritis care &amp; research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Applying Lessons From Rheumatology to Better Understand Long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>49</StartPage><EndPage>56</EndPage><MedlinePgn>49-56</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/acr.25210</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long COVID can sometimes be attributed to organ damage and well-characterized pathophysiology, but more often there is no evidence of organ damage or abnormal biomarkers. This is most evident in patients with mild to moderate initial SARS-CoV-2 infection who were not hospitalized. Their persistent symptoms are strikingly similar to those of fibromyalgia and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome, including fatigue, post-exertional malaise, myalgias/arthralgias, and sleep and cognitive disturbances in 50% to 100% of cases. Analogous pathophysiologic pathways in fibromyalgia (FM), myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS), and long COVID include host-microbial interactions in the absence of direct tissue invasion and absence of systemic autoimmunity, with&#xa0;evidence for immune dysregulation as well as autonomic, peripheral, and central nervous system dysfunction. Current treatment of long COVID has been based on multidisciplinary management recommended for FM and ME/CFS and has been formalized and made widely available by funding for nationwide long COVID clinics. Long COVID and its treatment should be distinguished by the presence or absence of organ damage. The acknowledged role of patient engagement in research and open dialogue regarding work and disability noted in long COVID may have meaningful impact on patients with FM and ME/CFS. Hopefully, advances in basic long COVID research will aid in understanding FM and ME/CFS, and rheumatologists should thus be involved in such research and patient care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 American College of Rheumatology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldenberg</LastName><ForeName>Don L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3737-0243</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tufts University School of Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts, and Oregon Health Sciences University, Portland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518086</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2151-464X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015673" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fatigue Syndrome, Chronic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005356" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fibromyalgia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012219" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rheumatology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37525488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.25210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Callard F, Perego E. How and why patients made long Covid. Soc Sci Med 2021;268:113426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S, Williams MA. Confronting our next national health disaster - Long-Haul Covid. N Engl J Med 2021;385:577-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence, Royal College of General Practitioners, Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. NICE Guideline, No. 188. April 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchwald D, Goldenberg DL, Sullivan JL, et al. The &#x201c;chronic, active Epstein-Barr virus infection&#x201d; syndrome and primary fibromyalgia. Arthritis Rheum 1987;30:1132-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenberg DL. Diagnosing fibromyalgia as a disease, an illness, a state, or a trait? Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2019;71:334-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sneller MC, Liang CJ, Marques AR, et al. A longitudinal study of COVID-19 sequelae and immunity: Baseline findings. Ann Intern Med 2022;175:969-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaes AW, Go&#xeb;rtz YM, Van Herck M, et al. Recovery from COVID-19: a sprint or marathon? 6-month follow-up data from online long COVID-19 support group members. ERJ Open Res 2021;7:00141-2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese C, Kirchner E, Calabrese LH. Long COVID and rheumatology: clinical, diagnostic and therapeutic implications. Best Pract Clin Rheumatol 2022;36:101794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldhaber NH, Kohn JN, Ogan WS, et al. Deep dive into the long haul: analysis of symptom clusters and risk factors for post acute sequelae of COVID-19 to inform clinical care. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022;19:16841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvache-Mateo A, L&#xf3;pez-L&#xf3;pez L, Mart&#xed;n-N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez J, et al. Pain and clinical presentation: a cross-sectional study of patients with new-onset chronic pain in long-COVID-19 syndrome. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2023;20:4049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ursini F, Ciaffi J, Mancarella L, et al. Fibromyalgia: a new facet of the post-COVID-19 syndrome spectrum? Results from a web-based survey. RMD Open 2021;7:e001735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savin E, Rosenn G, Tsur AM, et al. The possible onset of fibromyalgia following acute COVID-19 infection. PLoS One 2023;18:e0281593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barhorst EE, Boruch AE, Cook DB, et al. Pain-related post-exertional malaise in myalgic encephalomyelitis / chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) and fibromyalgia: a systematic review and three-level meta-analysis. Pain Med 2022;23:1144-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantovani E, Mariotto S, Gabbiani D, et al. Chronic fatigue syndrome: an emerging sequela in COVID-19 survivors? J Neurovirol 2021;27:631-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason LA, Dorri JA. ME/CFS and post-exertional malaise among patients with long COVID. Neurol Int 2022;15:1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonila H, Quach TC, Tiwari A, et al. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome is common in post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC): results from a post-COVID-19 multidisciplinary clinic. Front Neurol 2023;14:1090747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skarpsno ES, Lund Nilson TI, Sand T, et al. The joint effect of insomnia symptoms and lifestyle factors on risk of self-reported fibromyalgia in women: longitudinal data from the HUNT study. BMJ Open 2019;9:e028684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merikanto I, Dauvilliers Y, Chung F, et al. Sleep symptoms are essential features of long-COVID - comparing healthy controls with COVID-19 cases of different severity in the international COVID sleep study (ICOSS-II). J Sleep Res 2023;32:e13754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul E, Fancourt D. Health behaviours the month prior to COVID-19 infection and the development of self-reported long COVID and specific long COVID symptoms: a longitudinal analysis of 1581 UK adults. BMC Public Health 2022;22:1716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schilling C, Nieters C, Schredl M, et al. Pre-existing sleep problems as a predictor of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. J Sleep Res 2023:e13949. doi:https://doi.org/10.1111/jsr.13949. E-pub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meresh ES, Artin H, Joyce C, et al. Obstructive sleep apnea co-morbidity in patients with fibromyalgia. Open Access Rheumatol 2019;11:103-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandel HL, Colleen G, Abedian S, et al. Risk of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection associated with pre-coronavirus disease obstructive sleep apnea diagnoses: an electronic health record-based analysis from the RECOVER initiative. Sleep 2023;46:zsad126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu YL, Huang CJ, Fang SC, et al. Cognitive impairment in fibromyalgia: a meta-analysis of case-control studies. Psychosom Med 2018;80:432-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kratz AL, Whibley D, Kim S, et al. Fibrofog in daily life: an examination of ambulatory subjective and objective cognitive function in fibromyalgia. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2020;72:1669-77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cockshell SJ, Mathias JL. Cognitive functioning in chronic fatigue syndrome: a meta-analysis. Psychol Med 2010;40:1253-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings G, Monaghan A, Xue F, et al. Comprehensive clinical characterization of brain fog in adults reporting long COVID symptoms. J Clin Med 2022;11:3440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavaco S, Sousa G, Gon&#xe7;alves A, et al. Predictors of cognitive dysfunction one-year post COVID-19. Neuropsychology 2023;37:557-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleykamp BA, Ferguson MC, McNicol E, et al. The prevalence of psychiatric and chronic pain comorbidities in fibromyalgia: an ACTTION systematic review. Semin Arthritis Rheum 2021;51:166-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandler CX, Cvejic E, Valencis BM, et al. Predictors of chronic fatigue syndrome and mood disturbance after acute infection. Front Neurol 2022;13:35442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismael F, Bizario JC, Battagin T, et al. Post-infection depressive, anxiety and post-traumatic stress symptoms: a prospective cohort study in patients with mild COVID-19. Prog Neuro-Psychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry 2021;111:110341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milde C, Glombiewski JA, Wilhelm M, et al. Psychological factors predict higher odds and impairment of post-COVID symptoms: a prospective study. Psychosom Med 2023;85:479-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Casta&#xf1;eda A, Lu P, Geraghty AC, et al. Mild respiratory COVID can cause multi-lineage neural cell and myelin dysregulation. Cell 2022;185:2452-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz-Pablos M, Paiva B, Montero-Mateo R, et al. Epstein-Barr virus and the origin of myalgic encephalomyelitis or chronic fatigue syndrome. Front Immunol 2021;12:656797.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenberg DL. Fibromyalgia, chronic fatigue syndrome, and myofascial pain syndrome [review]. Curr Opin Rheumatol 1997;9:135-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell 2022;185:881-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deveau TM, Munter SE, et al. Chronic viral coinfections differentially affect the likelihood of developing long COVID. J Clin Invest 2023;133:e163669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minerbi A, Fitzcharles MA. Gut microbiome: pertinence in fibromyalgia [review]. Clin Exp Rheumatol 2020;38 Suppl 123:S99-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupo GF, Rocchetti G, Lucini L, et al. Potential role of microbiome in chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME). Sci Rep 2021;11:7043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Mak J, Su Q, et al. Gut microbiota dynamics in a prospective cohort of patients with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Gut 2022;71:544-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Thomas IL, Munter SE, et al. Lack of antinuclear antibodies in convalescent coronavirus disease 2019 patients with persistent symptoms. Clin Infect Dis 2023;74:2083-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J, Wood J, Jaycox J, et al. Distinguishing features of long COVID identified through immune profiling. medRxiv doi:https://doi.org/10.1101/2022.08.09.22278592v1. 2022. E-pub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allan-Blitz LT, Akbari O, Kojima N, et al. Unique immune and inflammatory cytokine.profiles may define long COVID syndrome. Clin Exp Med doi:https://doi.org/10.1007/s10238-023-01065-6. 2023. E-pub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Mitchell A, CY Wang, et al. Low prevalence of interferon &#x3b1; autoantibodies in people experiencing symptoms of post-Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) conditions, or long COVID. J Infect Dis 2023;227:246-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muri J, Cecchinato V, Cavalli A, et al. Autoantibodies against chemokines post-SARS-CoV-2 infection correlate with disease course. Nat Immunol 2023;24:604-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Hernandez A, de la Coba P, Reyes Del Paso GA. Central sensitization pain and autonomic deficiencies in fibromyalgia. Clin Exp Rheumatol 2022;40:1202-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Campen CL, Rowe PC, Visser FC. Cerebral blood flow remains reduced after tilt table testing in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients. Clin Neurophysiol Pract 2021;6:245-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak P, Giannetti MP, Weller E, et al. Network autonomic analysis of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 and postural tachycardia syndrome. Neurol Sci 2022;43:6627-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen NW, Stiles LE, Shaik R, et al. Characterization of autonomic symptom burden in long COVID: a global survey of 2,314 adults. Front Neurol 2022;13:1012668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ser MH, &#xc7;al&#x131;ku&#x15f;u FZ, Tanriverdin U, et al. Autonomic and neuropathic complaints of long-COVID objectified: an investigation from electrophysiological perspective. Neurol Sci 2022;43:6167-77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beiner E, Lucas V, Reichert J, et al. Stress biomarkers in individuals with fibromyalgia syndrome: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Pain 2023;164:1416-27</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulos AS, Cleare AJ. Hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis dysfunction in chronic fatigue syndrome [review]. Nat Rev Endocrinol 2011;8:22-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff AL, Lipkin WI. Insights from myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome may help unravel the pathogenesis of postacute COVID-19 syndrome. Trends Mol Med 2021;27:895-906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yavropoulou MP, Tsokos GC, Chrousos GP, et al. Protracted stress-induced hypocortisolemia may account for the clinical and immune manifestations of long COVID. Clin Immunol 2022;245:109133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sluka KA, Clauw DJ. Neurobiology of fibromyalgia and chronic widespread pain [review]. Neuroscience 2016;338:114-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maksoud R, du Preez S, Eaton-Fitch N, et al. A systematic review of neurological impairments in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome using neuroimaging techniques. PloS One 2020;15:e02322475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F, et al. SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature 2022;604:697-707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen M, N&#xe4;gele FL, Mayer C, et al. Brain imaging and neuropsychological assessment of individuals recovered from mild to moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Proc Natl Acad Sci 2023;120:e2217232120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goehringer F, Bruyere A, Doyen M, et al. Brain 18F-FDG PET imaging in outpatients with post-COVID-19 conditions: findings and associations with clinical characteristics. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging 2023;50:1084-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franke C, Boesl F, Goereci Y, et al. Association of cerebrospinal fluid brain-binding autoantibodies with cognitive impairment in post-COVID-19 syndrome. Brain Behav Immun 2023;109:139-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atta AA, Ibrahim WW, Mohamed AF, et al. Microglia polarization in nociplastic pain: mechanisms and perspectives. Inflammopharmacology 2023;31:1053-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krock E, Morado-Urbina CE, Menezes J, et al. Fibromyalgia patients with elevated levels of anti-satellite glia cell immunoglobulin G antibodies present with more severe symptoms. Pain 2023;164:1828-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauw DJ, Calabrese L. Rheumatology and long COVID: lessons from the study of fibromyalgia. Ann Rheum Dis doi:https://doi.org/10.1136/ard-2023-224250. 2023. E-pub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monje M, Iwasaki A. The neurobiology of long COVID. Neuron 2022;110:3484-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohrs R, Ladyzhets B. The NIH poured $ 1 billion into long Covid research - with little to show for it. STAT 2023. URL: https://www.statnews.com/2023/04/20/long-covid-nih-billion/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendelman O, Amital H, Bar-On Y, et al. Time to diagnosis of fibromyalgia and factors associated with delayed diagnosis in primary care. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol 2018;32:489-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim EJ, Son CG. Review of case definitions for myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) [review]. J Transl Med 2020;18:289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley SE, Karlson EW, et al. Development of a definition of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA 2023;329:1934-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minhas D, Murphy A, Clauw DJ. Fibromyalgia and centralized pain in the rheumatoid arthritis patient. Curr Opin Rheumatol 2023;35:170-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan CM, Schrepf A, Ichesco E, et al. Association of inflammation with pronociceptive brain connections in rheumatoid arthritis patients with concomitant fibromyalgia. Arthritis Rheumatol 2020;72:41-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorfman D, Berger Z. Appropriate workplace accommodations for patients with long Covid-advice for physicians. N Engl J Med. 2023;388:2115-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. National Center for Health Statistics. URL: https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>