<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36916685</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-6984</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Season>Sep-Oct</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of language &amp; communication disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Lang Commun Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A retrospective study of patients presenting with speech and language therapy needs within multidisciplinary Long COVID services: A service evaluation describing and comparing two cohorts across two NHS Trusts.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1424</StartPage><EndPage>1439</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1424-1439</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1460-6984.12868</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Post-COVID Syndrome (also known as Long COVID) refers to the multi-system condition affecting individuals following COVID-19 infection. This can include speech and language therapy (SLT) needs, including voice, swallowing, communication and upper airway difficulties. There is limited published literature in this clinical area of practice, particularly for those receiving input from community SLT services.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIMS">To describe and compare demand, typical SLT presentation and service delivery across two National Health Service (NHS) Long COVID multidisciplinary services. Independent retrospective service evaluation was completed for each service. Descriptive statistics were produced and compared across services. This service evaluation followed The Strengthening the Reporting of Observation Studies in Epidemiology guidelines for cohort studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OUTCOMES &amp; RESULTS">The findings indicated similarities across the two services in SLT service need and demand, clinical presentations and intervention approaches provided within Long COVID services. There were specific differences in the service provision and delivery of intervention in cognitive communication and upper airways subspecialities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS &amp; IMPLICATIONS">This study highlights the clinical complexities of SLT needs in individuals with Long COVID and the importance for an appropriately skilled and supported workforce within effective multidisciplinary teams. We call for consensus on SLT practices and a consistent and standardized approach to evaluation for SLT needs in Long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="WHAT THIS PAPER ADDS">What is already known on this subject SLT needs, including voice, swallowing, communication and upper airway difficulties, are present in individuals presenting with Long COVID, both in those who were or were not hospitalized. SLTs are seeing such individuals in a variety of settings, including community services and Long COVID multidisciplinary teams. There is minimal evidence of the clinical presentations and interventions provided to individuals with SLT needs compared across Long COVID services. What this study adds to existing knowledge This study compares two NHS Long COVID services providing a SLT service pathway. It highlights the similarities and differences in service demand and capacity, patient presentation, and SLT intervention to make suggestions for future practice consideration and priority evaluation. Expert consensus among SLT clinicians is a priority to ensure clinicians are delivering consistent and equitable care for patients, while new evidence and data emerge. A consistent and standardized approach to data collection and outcome measures is essential to ensure future research captures the impact and value of SLT input with individuals with Long COVID. What are the clinical implications of this work? The complexities and multifactorial SLT needs of individual with Long COVID call for appropriate SLT staffing provision, skill and training to fulfil the needs of this population. Speech and language therapists should be integrated with multidisciplinary Long COVID services to provide holistic care for patients and to support the professionals working with individuals with post-COVID voice, swallowing, communication and upper airway symptoms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. International Journal of Language &amp; Communication Disorders published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Royal College of Speech and Language Therapists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chalmers</LastName><ForeName>Sophie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5919-1740</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Long COVID Service, Long Term Conditions, Integrated Community Services Division, Bolton NHS Foundation Trust, Bolton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Allied Health Research Unit, School of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Central Lancashire, Preston, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harrall</LastName><ForeName>Kate</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8579-5855</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech and Language Therapy Dept, Integrated Pathways Division, East Suffolk and North Essex NHS Foundation Trust, Colchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development Unit, Strategy, Research and Innovation Division, East Suffold and North Essex NHS Foundation Trust, Colchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Sze Yin</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech and Language Therapy Dept, Integrated Pathways Division, East Suffolk and North Essex NHS Foundation Trust, Colchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kablan</LastName><ForeName>Widad</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paediatric Speech and Language Therapy, Family Care Division, Bolton NHS Foundation Trust, Bolton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clunie</LastName><ForeName>Gemma</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1796-731X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech and Language Therapy, Surgery and Cancer, Imperial College London Healthcare NHS Trust &amp; Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Lang Commun Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9803709</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1368-2822</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007808" MajorTopicYN="Y">Language Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013222" MajorTopicYN="N">State Medicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013060" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013070" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-COVID Syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multidisciplinary working</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">service evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">swallowing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">voice</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36916685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1460-6984.12868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Allen, J.E., Clunie, G.M. &amp; Winiker, K. (2021) Ultrasound: an emerging modality for the dysphagia assessment toolkit? Current Opinion in Otolaryngology &amp; Head and Neck Surgery, 29(3), 213-218. Epub 2021/03/21. https://doi.org/10.1097/moo.0000000000000708 PubMed PMID: 33741822; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC7611059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archer, S.K., Iezzi, C.M. &amp; Gilpin, L. (2021) Swallowing and voice outcomes in patients hospitalized with COVID-19: an Observational Cohort Study. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, 102(6), 1084-1090. Epub 2021/02/03. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmr.2021.01.063. PubMed PMID: 33529610; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC7846878.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belafsky, P.C., Postma, G.N. &amp; Koufman, J.A. (2002) Validity and Reliability of the Reflux Symptom Index (RSI). Journal of Voice, 16(2), 274-277. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0892-1997(02)00097-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley, D.P., Vojtech, J.M. &amp; Stepp, C.E. (2021) Relative fundamental frequency in individuals with globus syndrome and muscle tension dysphagia. Journal of Voice, : official journal of the Voice Foundation, S0892-1997(21), 00347-7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvoice.2021.10.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceruti, S., Glotta, A., Galli, A., Biggiogero, M., Bona, G., Mauri, R., et&#xa0;al. (2021) Dysphagic disorder in a cohort of COVID-19 patients: evaluation and evolution. Annals of Medicine and Surgery, 69, 102837. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amsu.2021.102837</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadd, K., Chalmers, S., Harrall, K., Moyse, K. &amp; Clunie, G. (2022) An evaluation of speech and language therapy services for people with long COVID in the UK: a call for integrated care. Journal of Integrated Care, in press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christman Buckingham, S.S., Sneed, K.E. (2018) Cognitive-communication disorder. In: Kreutzer, J.S., DeLuca, J. &amp; Caplan, B. (Eds). Encyclopedia of clinical neuropsychology. Cham: Springer International Publishing, pp. 868-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson, K., O'Rourke, A.K. &amp; Fortunato, J.E. &amp; Jadcherla, S. (2020) The emerging importance of high-resolution manometry in the evaluation and treatment of deglutition in infants, children, and adults: new opportunities for speech-language pathologists. American Journal of Speech-Language Pathology, 29(2S), 945-955. https://doi.org/10.1044/2019_AJSLP-19-00067</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, H.E., Assaf, G.S., McCorkell, L., Wei, H., Low, R.J., Re'em, Y., et&#xa0;al. (2021) Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine, 38, 101019. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson, C., Capewell, R., Ellis, S., Matthews, S., Adamson, S., Wood, M., et&#xa0;al. (2020) Dysphagia presentation and management following coronavirus disease 2019: an acute care tertiary centre experience. The Journal of Laryngology &amp; Otology, 134(11), 981-986. Epub 2020/11/10. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0022215120002443</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas, J.M, O'Flaherty, C.A. &amp; Snow, P.C. (2000) Measuring perception of communicative ability: the development and evaluation of the La Trobe Communication&#xa0;Questionnaire. Aphasiology, 14, 251-268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frajkova, Z., Tedla, M., Tedlova, E., Suchankova, M. &amp; Geneid, A. (2020) Postintubation dysphagia during COVID-19 outbreak-Contemporary review. Dysphagia, 35(4), 549-557. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00455-020-10139-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham, E.L., Clark, J.R., Orban, Z.S., Lim, P.H., Szymanski, A.L., Taylor, C., et&#xa0;al. (2021) Persistent neurologic symptoms and cognitive dysfunction in non-hospitalized Covid-19 &#x2018;long haulers&#x2019;. Annals of Clinical and Translational Neurology, 8(5), 1073-1085. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.51350</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamdan, A.L., Khalifee, E., Jaffal, H., Ghanem, A. &amp; El Hage, A. (2019) Prevalence of dysphagia in patients with muscle tension dysphonia. The Journal of Laryngology &amp; Otology, 133(5), 390-393. Epub 2019/04/05. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0022215119000513</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Education England (HEE) (2022) The Allied Health Professions (AHPs) Strategy for England: 2022-2027 AHPs Deliver. Report No. (1), June 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hull, J.H., Backer, V., Gibson, P.G. &amp; Fowler, S.J. (2016) Laryngeal Dysfunction: assessment and Management for the Clinician. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, 194(9), 1062-1072. Epub 2016/11/01. https://doi.org/10.1164/rccm.201606-1249CI PubMed PMID: 27575803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hull, J.H., Backer, V., Gibson, P.G. &amp; Fowler, S.J. (2016) Laryngeal dysfunction: assessment and management for the clinician. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, 194(9), 1062-1072. https://dx.doi.org/10.1164/rccm.201606-1249CI</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail, Z., Elbayoumi, H., Fischer, C.E., Hogan, D.B., Millikin, C.P., Schweizer, T., et&#xa0;al. (2017) Prevalence of depression in patients with mild cognitive impairment: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatry, 74(1), 58-67. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2016.3162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings, G., Monaghan, A., Xue, F., Mockler, D. &amp; Romero-Ortu&#xf1;o, R. (2021) A systematic review of persistent symptoms and residual abnormal functioning following acute COVID-19: ongoing symptomatic phase vs. post-COVID-19 syndrome. Journal of Clinical Medicine, 10(24), 5913. Epub 2021/12/25. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10245913. PubMed PMID: 34945213; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC8708187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruser, J.M. &amp; Prescott, H.C. (2017) Dysphagia after acute respiratory distress syndrome. Another lasting legacy of critical illness. Annals of the American Thoracic Society, 14(3), 307-308. https://doi.org/10.1513/AnnalsATS.201612-1040ED. PubMed PMID: 28248578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechien, J.R., Chiesa-Estomba, C.M., Cabaraux, P., Mat, Q., Huet, K., Harmegnies, B., et&#xa0;al. (2020) Features of mild-to-moderate COVID-19 patients with dysphonia. Journal of Voice, 36(2), 249-255. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvoice.2020.05.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDonald, S. (2015) Cognitive Communication Checklist for Acquired Brain Injury (CCCABI): An SLP Screening and Referral Tool.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malcomess, K. (2020) The Care Aims Intended Outcomes Framework 2020. Available from: https://careaims.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Care-Aims-Intended-Outcome-Framework-Summary-updated-2020.pdf [Accessed 21st October 2022]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchese, M.R., Ausili, C.C., Mari, G., Proietti, I., Carf&#xec;, A., Tosato, M., et&#xa0;al. (2022) Oropharyngeal dysphagia after hospitalization for COVID-19 disease: our screening results. Dysphagia, 37(2), 447-453. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00455-021-10325-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHorney, C.A., Robbins, J., Lomax, K., Rosenbek, J.C., Chignell, K., Kramer, A.E., et&#xa0;al. (2002) The SWAL-QOL and SWAL-CARE outcomes tool for oropharyngeal dysphagia in adults: III. Documentation of reliability and validity. Dysphagia, 17(2), 97-114. Epub 2002/04/17. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00455-001-0109-1 PubMed PMID: 11956835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles, A., McRae, J., Clunie, G., Gillivan-Murphy, P., Inamoto, Y., Kalf, H., et&#xa0;al. (2022) An International Commentary on dysphagia and dysphonia during the COVID-19 pandemic. Dysphagia, 37(6), 1349-1374. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00455-021-10396-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misono, S., Dietrich, M. &amp; Piccirillo, J.F. (2020) The puzzle of medically unexplained symptoms-A holistic view of the patient with laryngeal symptoms. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg, 146(6), 550-551. Epub 2020/05/01. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaoto.2020.0559 PubMed PMID: 32352490; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC7483320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musella, A., Gentile, A., Rizzo, F.R., De Vito, F., Fresegna, D., Bullitta, S., et&#xa0;al. (2018) Interplay between age and neuroinflammation in multiple sclerosis: effects on motor and cognitive functions. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience, 10, 238. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2018.00238</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) (2022) COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. Report No. 1, 1 March 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neevel, A.J., Smith, J.D., Morrison, R.J., Hogikyan, N.D., Kupfer, R.A. &amp; Stein, A.P. (2021) Postacute COVID-19 laryngeal injury and dysfunction. OTO Open, 5(3), 2473974&#xd7;211041040. https://doi.org/10.1177/2473974x211041040. PubMed PMID: 34458661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England. (2022).The NHS plan for improving long COVID services. [online] Available: https://www.england.nhs.uk/publication/the-nhs-plan-for-improving-long-covid-services/ [Accessed 8 March 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England. (2022). National commissioning guidance for post COVID services. [online] Available: https://england.nhs.uk/publication/natioanl-commissioning-guidance-for-post-covid-services/ [Accessed 8 March 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Occomore-Kent, L.C., Hatch, E. &amp; Cruice, M. (2021) Scoping opinion: speech and language therapists' views on extending their role to the urgent ear, nose and throat pathway. International Journal of Language &amp; Communication Disorders, 56(5), 975-988. Epub 2021/07/27. https://doi.org/10.1111/1460-6984.12650 PubMed PMID: 34309979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics (ONS) (2022) Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK: 7 July 2022. Available from: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/7july2022 [Updated 7th July 2022; Accessed 7 July 2022]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payten, C.L., Eakin, J., Smith, T., Stewart, V., Madill, C.J. &amp; Weir, K.A. (2020) Outcomes of a multidisciplinary Ear, Nose and Throat Allied Health Primary Contact outpatient assessment service. Clinical Otolaryngology, 45(6), 904-913. Epub 2020/08/12. https://doi.org/10.1111/coa.13631 PubMed PMID: 32780943; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC7821116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regan, J., Walshe, M., Lavan, S., Horan, E., Gillivan, M.P., Healy, A., et&#xa0;al. (2021) Post-extubation dysphagia and dysphonia amongst adults with COVID-19 in the Republic of Ireland: a prospective multi-site observational cohort study. Clinical Otolaryngology, 46(6), 1290-1299. https://doi.org/10.1111/coa.13832. PubMed PMID: 34197688; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC8444742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouhani, M.J., Clunie, G., Thong, G., Lovell, L., Roe, J., Ashcroft, M., et&#xa0;al. (2021) A prospective study of voice, swallow, and airway outcomes following tracheostomy for COVID-19. The Laryngoscope, 131(6), E1918-E1925. https://doi.org/10.1002/lary.29346</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royal College of Speech and Language Therapists (RCSLT) (2022) Understanding the need for and provision of speech and language therapy services for individuals with post-COVID syndrome in the UK. [online] Available: https://www.rcslt.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Post-COVID-syndrome-report-RCSLT-January-2022.pdf [Accessed 8 March 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royal College of Speech and Language Therapists (RCSLT) (2021b) Speech and language therapist-led endoscopic procedures: considerations for all patients during the COVID-19 pandemic. [online] Available: [Accessed 8 March 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royal College of Speech and Language Therapists (RCSLT) (2021c) Position paper: the role of the speech and language therapy in upper airway disorders within adult respiratory services. London: RCSLT. [online] Available: https://www.rcslt.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/RCSLT-upper-airways-position-paper-October-2021.pdf [Accessed 8 March 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royal College of Speech and Language Therapists (RCSLT) (2021a) Long COVID and speech and language therapy: Understanding the mid- to long-term speech and language therapy needs and the impact on services. [online] Available: https://www.rcslt.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/RCSLT-Long-Covid-Survey-Report-May-2021.pdf [Accessed 8 March 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seabrook, M., Schwarz, M., Ward, E.C. &amp; Whitfield, B. (2019) Implementation of an extended scope of practice speech-language pathology allied health practitioner service: an evaluation of service impacts and outcomes. Int J Speech Lang Pathol, 21(1), 65-74. Epub 2017/09/28. https://doi.org/10.1080/17549507.2017.1380702. PubMed PMID: 28952361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>See&#xdf;le, J., Waterboer, T., Hippchen, T., Simon, J., Kirchner, M. &amp; Lim, A., et&#xa0;al. (2021) Persistent symptoms in adult patients 1 year after coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a Prospective Cohort Study. Clinical Infectious Diseases, 74(7), 1191-1198. https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciab611</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silbergleit, A.K., Schultz, L., Jacobson, B.H., Beardsley, T. &amp; Johnson, A.F. (2012) The Dysphagia handicap index: development and validation. Dysphagia, 27(1), 46-52. Epub 2011/03/23. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00455-011-9336-2 PubMed PMID: 21424584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson, F. (2006) Mount wilga high level language test (revised). 20th Anniversary Revised Edition.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian, A., Nirantharakumar, K., Hughes, S., Myles, P., Williams, T., Gokhale, K.M., et&#xa0;al. (2022) Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nature Medicine, 28, 1706-1714. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-01909-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, R.R. &amp; Kielhofner, G.W. (2005) Work-related impairment and employment-focused rehabilitation options for individuals with chronic fatigue syndrome: a review. Journal of Mental Health, 14(3), 253-267. https://doi.org/10.1080/09638230500136571</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasanthan, R., Sorooshian, P., Sri Shanmuganathan, V. &amp; Al-Hashim, M. (2021) Laryngotracheal stenosis following intubation and tracheostomy for COVID-19 pneumonia: a case report. Journal of Surgical Case Reports, 2021(1), rjaa569. https://doi.org/10.1093/jscr/rjaa569</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vertigan, A.E., Bone, S.L. &amp; Gibson, P.G. (2014) Development and validation of the Newcastle laryngeal hypersensitivity questionnaire. Cough, 10(1), 1. https://doi.org/10.1186/1745-9974-10-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm, E., Altman, D.G., Egger, M., Pocock, S.J., G&#xf8;tzsche, P.C. &amp; Vandenbroucke, J.P. (2008) The Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology, 61(4), 344-349. Epub 2008/03/04. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.11.008. PubMed PMID: 18313558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation (WHO) (2021) Coronavirus disease (COVID-19): Post COVID-19 condition 2021. Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/questions-and-answers/item/coronavirus-disease-(covid-19)-post-covid-19-condition?gclid=EAIaIQobChMI9Y-JzaGb-QIVhpftCh1lRQf2EAAYASAAEgIXpvD_BwE [Accessed 19th December 2021].</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>