<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37334978</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence and risk factors of long COVID 6-12 months after infection with the Omicron variant among nonhospitalized patients in Hong Kong.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e28862</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e28862</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.28862</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long COVID has been reported among patients with COVID-19, but little is known about the prevalence and risk factors associated with long COVID 6-12 months after infection with the Omicron variant. This is a large-scale retrospective study. A total of 6242 out of 12&#x2009;950 nonhospitalized subjects of all ages with SARS-CoV-2 infection (confirmed by polymerase chain reaction/rapid antigen test) during the Omicron dominant outbreak (December 31, 2021-May 6, 2022) in Hong Kong were included. Prevalence of long COVID, frequencies of symptoms, and risk factors were analyzed. Three thousand four hundred and thirty (55.0%) subjects reported at least one long COVID symptom. The most reported symptom was fatigue (1241, 36.2%). Female gender, middle age, obesity, comorbidities, vaccination after infection, having more symptoms, and presenting fatigue/chest tightness/headache/diarrhea in the acute stage of illness were identified as associated risk factors for long COVID. Patients who had received three or more doses of vaccine were not associated with a lower risk of long COVID (adjusted odds ratio 1.105, 95% confidence interval 0.985-1.239, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.088). Among patients with at least three doses of vaccine, there was no significant difference in the risk of long COVID between the CoronaVac vaccine and BNT162b2 vaccine (p&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). Omicron infection can lead to long COVID in a significant proportion of nonhospitalized patients 6-12 months after infection. Further investigation is needed to uncover the mechanisms underlying the development of long COVID and determine the impact of various risk factors such as vaccines.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Jingyuan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vincent V.C. Woo Chinese Medicine Clinical Research Institute, School of Chinese Medicine, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Chinese Herbal Medicine Drug Development, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jialing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vincent V.C. Woo Chinese Medicine Clinical Research Institute, School of Chinese Medicine, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Chinese Herbal Medicine Drug Development, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Hiu To</ForeName><Initials>HT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vincent V.C. Woo Chinese Medicine Clinical Research Institute, School of Chinese Medicine, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Hoi Ki</ForeName><Initials>HK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vincent V.C. Woo Chinese Medicine Clinical Research Institute, School of Chinese Medicine, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lyu</LastName><ForeName>Aiping</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vincent V.C. Woo Chinese Medicine Clinical Research Institute, School of Chinese Medicine, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chinese Medicine, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheung</LastName><ForeName>Chun Hoi</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vincent V.C. Woo Chinese Medicine Clinical Research Institute, School of Chinese Medicine, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chinese Medicine, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bian</LastName><ForeName>Zhaoxiang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6206-1958</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vincent V.C. Woo Chinese Medicine Clinical Research Institute, School of Chinese Medicine, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Chinese Herbal Medicine Drug Development, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chinese Medicine, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000722216">sinovac COVID-19 vaccine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000090982">BNT162 Vaccine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000711908">SARS-CoV-2 variants</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Med Virol. 2023 Nov;95(11):e29235. doi: 10.1002/jmv.29235</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37970745</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006723" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Hong Kong</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000090982" MajorTopicYN="N">BNT162 Vaccine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Omicron</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">symptom</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37334978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>WHO. 2023. WHO coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard. Accessed February 28, 2023. https://covid19.who.int/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):626-631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Mahoney LL, Routen A, Gillies C, et al. The prevalence and long-term health effects of long covid among hospitalized and non-hospitalized populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;55:101762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. 2021. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Accessed February 13, 2023. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, et al. Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat Med. 2022;28(8):1706-1714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, et al. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6(9):e005427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter RS, Nieters A, Kr&#xe4;usslich H-G, et al. Post-acute sequelae of covid-19 six to 12 months after infection: population based study. BMJ. 2022;379:e071050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanares-Zapatero D, Chalon P, Kohn L, et al. Pathophysiology and mechanism of long COVID: a comprehensive review. Ann Med. 2022;54(1):1473-1487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. 2023. Tracking SARS-CoV-2 variants. Accessed February 14, 2023. https://www.who.int/activities/tracking-SARS-CoV-2-variants</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. Archive of statistics on 5th wave of COVID-19. Self-reported long COVID after infection with the Omicron variant in the UK. 2023. Accessed February 1, 2023. https://www.coronavirus.gov.hk/pdf/5th_wave_statistics/5th_wave_statistics_20230129.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie R, Edwards KM, Adam DC, et al. Resurgence of Omicron BA.2 in SARS-CoV-2 infection-naive Hong Kong. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):2422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menni C, Valdes AM, Polidori L, et al. Symptom prevalence, duration, and risk of hospital admission in individuals infected with SARS-CoV-2 during periods of omicron and delta variant dominance: a prospective observational study from the ZOE COVID study. Lancet. 2022;399(10335):1618-1624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet. 2022;399(10343):2263-2264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo J, Zhang J, Tang HT, et al. Weekly symptom profiles of non-hospitalized individuals infected with SARS-CoV-2 during the omicron outbreak in Hong Kong: a retrospective observational study from a telemedicine centre. J Med Virol. 2022;95:e28447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arjun MC, Singh AK, Roy P, et al. Long COVID following Omicron wave in Eastern India-a retrospective cohort study. J Med Virol. 2023;95(1):e28214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlis RH, Santillana M, Ognyanova K, et al. Prevalence and correlates of long COVID symptoms among US adults. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(10):e2238804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jassat W, Mudara C, Vika C, et al. A cohort study of post-COVID-19 condition across the Beta, Delta, and Omicron waves in South Africa: 6-month follow-up of hospitalized and nonhospitalized participants. Int J Infect Dis. 2023;128:102-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. Hong Kong vaccination dashboard. 2023. Accessed February 24, 2023. https://www.covidvaccine.gov.hk/en/dashboard/eHealth</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accorsi EK, Britton A, Fleming-Dutra KE, et al. Association between 3 doses of mRNA COVID-19 vaccine and symptomatic infection caused by the SARS-CoV-2 omicron and delta variants. JAMA. 2022;327(7):639-651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan P. NICE guideline on long COVID. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9(2):129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. Body mass index (BMI) distribution (classification of weight status for Chinese adults in Hong Kong). 2010. Accessed February 17, 2023. https://www.chp.gov.hk/en/statistics/data/10/280/427.html2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. Hong Kong COVID-19 vaccination programme: about the vaccines. 2023. Accessed May 9, 2023. https://www.covidvaccine.gov.hk/en/vaccine2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP. The Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Lancet. 2007;370(9596):1453-1457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong MC, Huang J, Wong NY, et al. Epidemiology, symptomatology, and risk factors for long COVID symptoms: multi-centre study. JMIR Public Health Surveill. 2023;9:e42315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du M, Ma Y, Deng J, Liu M, Liu J. Comparison of long COVID-19 caused by different SARS-CoV-2 strains: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(23):16010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. 2022. Self-reported long COVID after infection with the Omicron variant in the UK. Accessed May 11, 2023. https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/selfreportedlongcovidafterinfectionwiththeomicronvariant/6may2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuodi P, Gorelik Y, Zayyad H, et al. Association between BNT162b2 vaccination and reported incidence of post-COVID-19 symptoms: cross-sectional study 2020-21, Israel. NPJ Vaccines. 2022;7(1):101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azzolini E, Levi R, Sarti R, et al. Association between BNT162b2 vaccination and long COVID after infections not requiring hospitalization in health care workers. JAMA. 2022;328(7):676-678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchida T, Hirose M, Inoue Y, Kunishima H, Otsubo T, Matsuda T. Relationship between changes in symptoms and antibody titers after a single vaccination in patients with long COVID. J Med Virol. 2022;94(7):3416-3420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarte KI, Catahay JA, Velasco JV, et al. Impact of COVID-19 vaccination on the risk of developing long-COVID and on existing long-COVID symptoms: a systematic review. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;53:101624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe A, Iwagami M, Yasuhara J, Takagi H, Kuno T. Protective effect of COVID-19 vaccination against long COVID syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Vaccine. 2023;41(11):1783-1790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strain WD, Sherwood O, Banerjee A, Van der Togt V, Hishmeh L, Rossman J. The impact of COVID vaccination on symptoms of long COVID: an international survey of people with lived experience of long COVID. Vaccines. 2022;10(5):652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Ayuzo del Valle NC, et al. Long-COVID in children and adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):9950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roessler M, Tesch F, Batram M, et al. Post COVID-19 in children, adolescents, and adults: results of a matched cohort study including more than 150,000 individuals with COVID-19. medRxiv. Preprint posted online 2021. doi:10.1101/2021.10.21.21265133</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). 2022. Accessed October 20, 2022. https://www.chp.gov.hk/en/healthtopics/content/24/102466.html</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>