<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35134812</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1421-9662</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>145</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta haematologica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Haematol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Challenges and Management of Long COVID in Individuals with Hematological Illnesses.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>275</StartPage><EndPage>281</EndPage><MedlinePgn>275-281</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000522437</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>COVID-19 has impacted hundreds of millions of people globally, a relatively large proportion of whom continue to suffer from ongoing, sometime debilitating symptoms. This phenomenon, termed "long COVID," is difficult to diagnose and manage because of a paucity of objective findings and despite the abundance of descriptive data published so far. In this review, we aimed to describe the common manifestations of long COVID, diagnostic and management challenges, and address specific aspects in hematologic patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 S. Karger AG, Basel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yelin</LastName><ForeName>Dana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>COVID Recovery Clinic, Rabin Medical Center, Beilinson Hospital, Petah Tikva, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Margalit</LastName><ForeName>Ili</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>COVID Recovery Clinic, Rabin Medical Center, Beilinson Hospital, Petah Tikva, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Unit, Rabin Medical Center, Beilinson Hospital, Petah Tikva, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Haematol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0141053</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0001-5792</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Persistent symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35134812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9059010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000522437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">000522437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO  WHO Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) dashboard (live) [Internet]  [cited 2021 Feb 27]. Available from:  https://covid19.who.int/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  . A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. 2021. Oct,  Available from:  https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-20211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, Cheng V, Dagens A, Hastie C, et al. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Heal. 2021;6((9)):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27((4)):626&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin D, Margalit I, Yahav D, Runold M, Bruchfeld J. Long COVID-19: it's not over until? Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27((4)):506&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33316400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickie I, Davenport T, Wakefield D, Vollmer-Conna U, Cameron B, Vernon SD, et al. Post-infective and chronic fatigue syndromes precipitated by viral and non-viral pathogens: prospective cohort study. Br Med J. 2006;333((7568)):575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1569956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16950834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam MHB, Wing YK, Yu MWM, Leung CM, Ma RCW, Kong APS, et al. Mental morbidities and chronic fatigue in severe acute respiratory syndrome survivors long-term follow-up. Arch Intern Med. 2009;169((22)):2142&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20008700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scoppettuolo P, Borrelli S, Naeije G. Neurological involvement in SARS-CoV-2 infection: a clinical systematic review. Brain Behav Immun Heal. 2020;5:100094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33521692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanghvi SK, Schwarzman LS, Nazir NT. Cardiac MRI and myocardial injury in COVID-19: diagnosis, risk stratification and prognosis. Diagnostics. 2021;11((1)):130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7830889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelle MC, Tassone B, Ricchio M, Mazzitelli M, Davoli C, Procopio G, et al. Late-onset myocardial infarction and autoimmune haemolytic anaemia in a COVID-19 patient without respiratory symptoms, concomitant with a paradoxical increase in inflammatory markers: a case report. J Med Case Rep. 2020;14((1)):246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7746982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33339534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharjee S, Banerjee M. Immune thrombocytopenia secondary to COVID-19: a systematic review. SN Compr Clin Med. 2020;14((11)):2048&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7501509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32984764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marazuela M, Giustina A, Puig-Domingo M. Endocrine and metabolic aspects of the COVID-19 pandemic. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2020;21((4)):495&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7343578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32643004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehme M, Braillard O, Chappuis F, Courvoisier DS, Guessous I. Prevalence of symptoms more than seven months after diagnosis of symptomatic COVID-19 in an outpatient setting. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174((9)):1252&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34224254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. Articles 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;10270((9)):220&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Penfold RS, Merino J, Sudre CH, Molteni E, Berry S, et al. Risk factors and disease profile of post-vaccination SARS-CoV-2 infection in UK users of the COVID symptom study app: a prospective, community-based, nested, case-control study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22((1)):43&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34480857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Wang F, Shen Y, Zhang X, Cen Y, Wang B, et al. Symptoms and health outcomes among survivors of COVID-19 infection 1 year after discharge from hospitals in Wuhan, China. JAMA Netw Open. 2021 Sep;4((9)):e2127403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34586367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F, Tomasoni D, Falcinella C, Barbanotti D, Castoldi R, Mul&#xe8; G, et al. Female gender is associated with &#x201c;long COVID&#x201d; syndrome: a prospective cohort study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;S1198&#x2013;743X((21)):00629&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boscolo-Rizzo P, Guida F, Polesel J, Marcuzzo AV, Capriotti V, D'Alessandro A, et al. Sequelae in adults at 12 months after mild-to-moderate coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Int Forum Allergy Rhinol. 2021;11((12)):1685&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9291310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34109765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardo MDM, Foppiani A, Peretti GM, Mangiavini L, Battezzati A, Bertoli S, et al. Long term COVID-19 complications in inpatients and outpatients: a One-Year Follow Up Cohort Study. SSRN Electron J. 2021;8:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8344801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34386546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, Billig Rose E, Shapiro NI, Files DC, et al. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network: United States, March&#x2013;June 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69:993&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, Bobkova P, Spiridonova E, Shikhaleva A, Gamirova A, Blyuss O, et al. Incidence and risk factors for persistent symptoms in adults previously hospitalized for COVID-19. Clin Exp Allergy. 2021;51((9)):1107&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34351016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terpos E, Ntanasis-Stathopoulos I, Elalamy I, Kastritis E, Sergentanis TN, Politou M, et al. Hematological findings and complications of COVID-19. Am J Hematol. 2020;95((7)):834&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32282949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuter DJ. Exacerbation of immune thrombocytopenia following COVID-19 vaccination. Br J Haematol. 2021 Nov;195((3)):365&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34075578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano C, Espa&#xf1;ol I, Cascales A, Moraleda JM, Kalita P, Laishram D, et al. Secondary hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis in post-COVID-19 patients: a report of two cases. SN Compr Clin Med. 2021;13((12)):2389&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E, Vlok M, Venter C, Bezuidenhout JA, Laubscher GJ, Steenkamp J, et al. Persistent clotting protein pathology in long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) is accompanied by increased levels of antiplasmin. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2021;20((1)):1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8381139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34425843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuin M, Rigatelli G, Zuliani G, Roncon L. The risk of thrombosis after acute-COVID-19 infection. QJM An Int J Med. 2021 Sep;114((9)):619&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7989150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33720351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havervall S, Rosell A, Phillipson M, Mangsbo SM, Nilsson P, Hober S, et al. Symptoms and functional impairment assessed 8 months after mild COVID-19 among health care workers. Jama. 2021;11:11&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8027932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33825846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peghin M, Palese A, Venturini M, De Martino M, Gerussi V, Graziano E, et al. Post-COVID-19 symptoms 6 months after acute infection among hospitalized and non-hospitalized patients. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021 Jun;S1198&#x2013;743X((21)):00281&#x2013;0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8180450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34111579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, Bobkova P, Spiridonova E, Shikhaleva A, Gamirova A, Blyuss O, et al. Risk factors for long-term consequences of COVID-19 in hospitalised adults in Moscow using the ISARIC Global follow-up protocol: StopCOVID cohort study. medRxiv. 2021;2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, Wang Q, Ren L, Wang Y, et al. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398((10302)):747&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid: mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty H, Townsend L, Morrin H, Ahmad A, Comerford C, Karampini E, et al. Persistent endotheliopathy in the pathogenesis of long COVID syndrome. J Thromb Haemost. 2021 Oct;19((10)):2546&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8420256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34375505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuken PA, Stallmach A, Pletz MW, Brandt C, Andreas N, Hahnfeld S, et al. Severe clinical relapse in an immunocompromised host with persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection. Leukemia. 2021;35((3)):920&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7893131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33608636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helleberg M, Niemann CU, Moestrup KS, Kirk O, Lebech A-M, Lane C, et al. Persistent COVID-19 in an immunocompromised patient temporarily responsive to two courses of remdesivir therapy. J Infect Dis. 2020 Sep;222((7)):1103&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32702095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truong TT, Ryutov A, Pandey U, Yee R, Goldberg L, Bhojwani D, et al. Persistent SARS-CoV-2 infection and increasing viral variants in children and young adults with impaired humoral immunity. medRxiv Prepr Serv Heal Sci. 2021 Mar;2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33915337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahav D, Yelin D, Eckerle I, Eberhardt CS, Wang J, Cao B, et al. Definitions for coronavirus disease 2019 reinfection, relapse and PCR re-positivity. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2020;27:315&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7718119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33285276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Zhang W, Yang Y, Zhang J, Li Y, Chen Y. Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: a randomized controlled study. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2020;39:101166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gloeckl R, Leitl D, Jarosch I, Schneeberger T, Nell C, Stenzel N, et al. Benefits of pulmonary rehabilitation in COVID-19: a prospective observational cohort study. ERJ Open Res. 2021;7((2)):00108&#x2013;2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7957293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34095290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin VA, Allan L, Bethel A, Cowley A, Cross JL, Day J, et al. Rehabilitation to enable recovery from COVID-19: a rapid systematic review. Physiotherapy. 2021 Jun;111:4&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7902208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33637294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings G, Monaghan A, Xue F, Mockler D, Romero-Ortu&#xf1;o R. A systematic review of persistent symptoms and residual abnormal functioning following acute COVID-19: ongoing symptomatic phase vs. post-COVID-19 syndrome. medRxiv. 2021;10((24)):5913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8708187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34945213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassar MP, Tunnicliffe EM, Petousi N, Lewandowski AJ, Xie C, Mahmod M, et al. Symptom persistence despite improvement in cardiopulmonary health: insights from longitudinal CMR, CPET and lung function testing post-COVID-19. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;41:101159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8527025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34693230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halle M, Bloch W, Niess AM, Predel H, Reinsberger C, Scharhag J, et al. Exercise and sports after COVID 19: guidance from a clinical perspective. Transl Sport Med. 2021;4((3)):310&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34230908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma&#x142;ek &#x141;A, Marczak M, Mi&#x142;osz-Wieczorek B, Konopka M, Braksator W, Drygas W, et al. Cardiac involvement in consecutive elite athletes recovered from Covid-19: a magnetic resonance study. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2021;53((6)):1723&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33474768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker JH, Lin JJ, Doernberg M, Stone K, Navis A, Festa JR, et al. Assessment of cognitive function in patients after COVID-19 infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4((10)):8&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8536953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34677597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watters K, Marks TS, Edwards DF, Skidmore ER, Giles GM. A framework for addressing clients' functional cognitive deficits after COVID-19. Am J Occup Ther. 2021 Jul&#x2013;Aug;75((Suppl 1)):7511347010p1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34405800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, O&#x2bc;Byrne L, MacKeith S, Philpott C, Hopkins C, Burton MJ. Interventions for the prevention of persistent post-COVID-19 olfactory dysfunction. Cochrane database Syst Rev. 2021;7:CD013877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8406518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34291812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addison AB, Wong B, Ahmed T, Macchi A, Konstantinidis I, Huart C, et al. Clinical Olfactory Working Group consensus statement on the treatment of postinfectious olfactory dysfunction. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2021;147((5)):1704&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelalim AA, Mohamady AA, Elsayed RA, Elawady MA, Ghallab AF. Corticosteroid nasal spray for recovery of smell sensation in COVID-19 patients: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Otolaryngol. 2021 Mar&#x2013;Apr;42((2)):102884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33429174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>