<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36452019</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2233-8276</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Asia Pacific allergy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Asia Pac Allergy</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Severe chronic cough relating to post-COVID-19 interstitial lung disease: a case report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e42</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e42</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e42</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5415/apallergy.2022.12.e42</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cough is a common symptom occurring in patients with acute coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) infection as well as during the post-COVID-19 period. The post-COVID-19 cough can improve over time and the incidence of sustained post-COVID-19 chronic cough is low. Approaching post-COVID-19 cough is challenging to clinicians including pulmonologists and allergists due to a diverse set of etiologies and the lack of published guidance on effective treatments. A 60-year-old male ex-smoker presented to the outpatient long COVID-19 clinic because of a prolonged cough for 4 months after a severe COVID-19 infection. His cough was so violent that he had suffered a spontaneous pneumothorax on 2 occasions. In addition, he also complained of exertional breathlessness. Due to concerns over ongoing systemic inflammation from COVID-19 or thromboembolism, a serum C-reactive protein and d-dimer where checked and were normal. Chest computed tomography (CT) images revealed diffuse ground glass opacities combined with scattered emphysema in the bilateral upper lobes and several small bullae located close to the pleura. His diagnosis was post-COVID-19 interstitial lung disease (ILD) and he was treated with methylprednisolone 32 mg/day. After 2 weeks of treatment, he showed improvement with near cessation of cough and a significant decline in dyspnea. The follow-up chest CT also showed improvement in the ground glass opacities. Severe chronic cough could be a manifestation of post-COVID-19 ILD. This case demonstrates the use of systemic corticosteroid to improve both post-COVID-19 ILD and its associated chronic cough.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022. Asia Pacific Association of Allergy, Asthma and Clinical Immunology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen-Ho</LastName><ForeName>Lam</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7171-2257</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Center HCMC, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen-Nhu</LastName><ForeName>Vinh</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8358-902X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Center HCMC, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran-Thi</LastName><ForeName>Thuy-Tuong</ForeName><Initials>TT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9890-5753</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Center HCMC, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solomon</LastName><ForeName>Joshua J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5488-4874</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Medicine, National Jewish Health, Denver, CO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Asia Pac Allergy</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101561954</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2233-8276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic cough</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Corticosteroid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary sequelae</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest: The authors have no financial conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36452019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9669464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5415/apallergy.2022.12.e42</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, Cook JR, Nordvig AS, Shalev D, Sehrawat TS, Ahluwalia N, Bikdeli B, Dietz D, Der-Nigoghossian C, Liyanage-Don N, Rosner GF, Bernstein EJ, Mohan S, Beckley AA, Seres DS, Choueiri TK, Uriel N, Ausiello JC, Accili D, Freedberg DE, Baldwin M, Schwartz A, Brodie D, Garcia CK, Elkind MSV, Connors JM, Bilezikian JP, Landry DW, Wan EY. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, Pujol JC, Klaser K, Antonelli M, Canas LS, Molteni E, Modat M, Jorge Cardoso M, May A, Ganesh S, Davies R, Nguyen LH, Drew DA, Astley CM, Joshi AD, Merino J, Tsereteli N, Fall T, Gomez MF, Duncan EL, Menni C, Williams FMK, Franks PW, Chan AT, Wolf J, Ourselin S, Spector T, Steves CJ. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27:626&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocconcelli E, Bernardinello N, Giraudo C, Castelli G, Giorgino A, Leoni D, Petrarulo S, Ferrari A, Saetta M, Cattelan A, Spagnolo P, Balestro E. Characteristics and prognostic factors of pulmonary fibrosis after COVID-19 pneumonia. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022;8:823600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8841677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35174188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, Ng RH, Wang K, Choi J, Li S, Hong S, Zhang R, Xie J, Kornilov SA, Scherler K, Pavlovitch-Bedzyk AJ, Dong S, Lausted C, Lee I, Fallen S, Dai CL, Baloni P, Smith B, Duvvuri VR, Anderson KG, Li J, Yang F, Duncombe CJ, McCulloch DJ, Rostomily C, Troisch P, Zhou J, Mackay S, DeGottardi Q, May DH, Taniguchi R, Gittelman RM, Klinger M, Snyder TM, Roper R, Wojciechowska G, Murray K, Edmark R, Evans S, Jones L, Zhou Y, Rowen L, Liu R, Chour W, Algren HA, Berrington WR, Wallick JA, Cochran RA, Micikas ME, Wrin T, Petropoulos CJ, Cole HR, Fischer TD, Wei W, Hoon DSB, Price ND, Subramanian N, Hill JA, Hadlock J, Magis AT, Ribas A, Lanier LL, Boyd SD, Bluestone JA, Chu H, Hood L, Gottardo R, Greenberg PD, Davis MM, Goldman JD, Heath JR ISB-Swedish COVID-19 Biobanking Unit. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185:881&#x2013;895. e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, Brown JS, Denneny EK, Hare SS, Heightman M, Hillman TE, Jacob J, Jarvis HC, Lipman MCI, Naidu SB, Nair A, Porter JC, Tomlinson GS, Hurst JR ARC Study Group. &#x2018;Long-COVID&#x2019;: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Kessel SAM, Olde Hartman TC, Lucassen PLBJ, van Jaarsveld CHM. Post-acute and long-COVID-19 symptoms in patients with mild diseases: a systematic review. Fam Pract. 2022;39:159&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8414057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34268556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Guijarro C, Plaza-Canteli S, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Barrera V, Torres-Macho J. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 cough one year after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a multicenter study. Lung. 2021;199:249&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8124095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33993321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song WJ, Hui CKM, Hull JH, Birring SS, McGarvey L, Mazzone SB, Chung KF. Confronting COVID-19-associated cough and the post-COVID syndrome: role of viral neurotropism, neuroinflammation, and neuroimmune responses. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:533&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8041436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33857435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortona E, Malorni W. Long COVID: to investigate immunological mechanisms and sex/gender related aspects as fundamental steps for tailored therapy. Eur Respir J. 2022;59:2102245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8462012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34531277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sis&#xf3;-Almirall A, Brito-Zer&#xf3;n P, Conangla Ferr&#xed;n L, Kostov B, Moragas Moreno A, Mestres J, Sellar&#xe8;s J, Galindo G, Morera R, Basora J, Trilla A, Ramos-Casals M On Behalf Of The CAMFiC Long Covid-Study Group. Long COVID-19: proposed primary care clinical guidelines for diagnosis and disease management. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:4350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33923972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borakati A, Perera A, Johnson J, Sood T. Diagnostic accuracy of X-ray versus CT in COVID-19: a propensity-matched database study. BMJ Open. 2020;10:e042946</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7650091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33158840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clofent D, Polverino E, Felipe A, Granados G, Arjona-Peris M, Andreu J, S&#xe1;nchez-Mart&#xed;nez AL, Varona D, Cabanzo L, Escudero JM, &#xc1;lvarez A, Loor K, Mu&#xf1;oz X, Culebras M. Lung ultrasound as a first-line test in the evaluation of post-COVID-19 pulmonary sequelae. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022;8:815732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8794580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35096906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouadi PW, Idriss SA, Bousquet J, Laidlaw TM, Azar CR, Al-Ahmad MS, Ya&#xf1;ez A, Al-Nesf MAY, Nsouli TM, Bahna SL, Abou-Jaoude E, Zaitoun FH, Hadi UM, Hellings PW, Scadding GK, Smith PK, Morais-Almeida M, G&#xf3;mez RM, Gonzalez Diaz SN, Klimek L, Juvelekian GS, Riachy MA, Canonica GW, Peden D, Wong GWK, Sublett J, Bernstein JA, Wang L, Tanno LK, Chikhladze M, Levin M, Chang YS, Martin BL, Caraballo L, Custovic A, Ortega-Martell JA, Jensen-Jarolim E, Ebisawa M, Fiocchi A, Ansotegui IJ. WAO-ARIA consensus on chronic cough - Part II: phenotypes and mechanisms of abnormal cough presentation - Updates in COVID-19 . World Allergy Organ J. 2021;14:100618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8666560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34963794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayakumar B, Tonkin J, Devaraj A, Philip KEJ, Orton CM, Desai SR, Shah PL. CT lung abnormalities after COVID-19 at 3 months and 1 year after hospital discharge. Radiology. 2022;303:444&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34609195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon JJ, Heyman B, Ko JP, Condos R, Lynch DA. CT of post-acute lung complications of COVID-19. Radiology. 2021;301:E383&#x2013;E395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8369881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34374591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myall KJ, Mukherjee B, Castanheira AM, Lam JL, Benedetti G, Mak SM, Preston R, Thillai M, Dewar A, Molyneaux PL, West AG. Persistent post-COVID-19 interstitial lung disease. An observational study of corticosteroid treatment. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2021;18:799&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8086530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhooria S, Chaudhary S, Sehgal IS, Agarwal R, Arora S, Garg M, Prabhakar N, Puri GD, Bhalla A, Suri V, Yaddanapudi LN, Muthu V, Prasad KT, Aggarwal AN. High-dose versus low-dose prednisolone in symptomatic patients with post-COVID-19 diffuse parenchymal lung abnormalities: an open-label, randomised trial (the COLDSTER trial) Eur Respir J. 2022;59:2102930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8850687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34887325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funke-Chambour M, Bridevaux PO, Clarenbach CF, Soccal PM, Nicod LP, von Garnier C Swiss COVID Lung Study Group and the Swiss Society of Pulmonology. Swiss recommendations for the follow-up and treatment of pulmonary long COVID. Respiration. 2021;100:826&#x2013;841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8339046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34091456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarc&#xf3;n-Rodr&#xed;guez J, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Velilla M, Ure&#xf1;a-Vacas A, Mart&#xed;n-Pinacho JJ, Rigual-Bobillo JA, Jauregu&#xed;zar-Oriol A, Gorospe-Saras&#xfa;a L. Radiological management and follow-up of post-COVID-19 patients. Radiologia. 2021;63:258&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7914006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35370314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>