<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34249236</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1949-8470</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of radiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Radiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Thoracic imaging outcomes in COVID-19 survivors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>149</StartPage><EndPage>156</EndPage><MedlinePgn>149-156</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4329/wjr.v13.i6.149</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic presents a significant global public health challenge. One in five individuals with COVID-19 presents with symptoms that last for weeks after hospital discharge, a condition termed "long COVID". Thus, efficient follow-up of patients is needed to assess the resolution of lung pathologies and systemic involvement. Thoracic imaging is multimodal and involves using different forms of waves to produce images of the organs within the thorax. In general, it includes chest X-ray, computed tomography, lung ultrasound and magnetic resonance imaging techniques. Such modalities have been useful in the diagnosis and prognosis of COVID-19. These tools have also allowed for the follow-up and assessment of long COVID. This review provides insights on the effectiveness of thoracic imaging techniques in the follow-up of COVID-19 survivors who had long COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2021. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alqahtani</LastName><ForeName>Jaber S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Care, Prince Sultan Military College of Health Sciences, Dammam 3431, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alghamdi</LastName><ForeName>Saeed M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Applied Medical Sciences, Umm Al-Qura University, Makkah 21990, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aldhahir</LastName><ForeName>Abdulelah M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Respiratory Care Department, Faculty of Applied Medical Sciences, Jazan University, Jazan 4514, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Althobiani</LastName><ForeName>Malik</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Division of Medicine, University College London, London NW3 2PF, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raya</LastName><ForeName>Reynie Purnama</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science, Universitas 'Aisyiyah Bandung, Bandung 40264, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oyelade</LastName><ForeName>Tope</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Liver and Digestive Health, Division of Medicine, University College London, London NW3 2PF, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Radiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101538184</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1949-8470</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chest X-ray</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Computed tomography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lung ultrasound</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Survivors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thoracic imaging</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors have nothing to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34249236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8245750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4329/wjr.v13.i6.149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alqahtani JS, Oyelade T, Aldhahir AM, Alghamdi SM, Almehmadi M, Alqahtani AS, Quaderi S, Mandal S, Hurst JR. Prevalence, Severity and Mortality associated with COPD and Smoking in patients with COVID-19: A Rapid Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0233147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7213702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32392262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi S, Qin M, Shen B, Cai Y, Liu T, Yang F, Gong W, Liu X, Liang J, Zhao Q, Huang H, Yang B, Huang C. Association of Cardiac Injury With Mortality in Hospitalized Patients With COVID-19 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:802&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32211816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson S, Hirsch JS, Narasimhan M, Crawford JM, McGinn T, Davidson KW the Northwell COVID-19 Research Consortium. Barnaby DP, Becker LB, Chelico JD, Cohen SL, Cookingham J, Coppa K, Diefenbach MA, Dominello AJ, Duer-Hefele J, Falzon L, Gitlin J, Hajizadeh N, Harvin TG, Hirschwerk DA, Kim EJ, Kozel ZM, Marrast LM, Mogavero JN, Osorio GA, Qiu M, Zanos TP. Presenting Characteristics, Comorbidities, and Outcomes Among 5700 Patients Hospitalized With COVID-19 in the New York City Area. JAMA. 2020;323:2052&#x2013;2059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7177629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32320003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhazzani W, M&#xf8;ller MH, Arabi YM, Loeb M, Gong MN, Fan E, Oczkowski S, Levy MM, Derde L, Dzierba A, Du B, Aboodi M, Wunsch H, Cecconi M, Koh Y, Chertow DS, Maitland K, Alshamsi F, Belley-Cote E, Greco M, Laundy M, Morgan JS, Kesecioglu J, McGeer A, Mermel L, Mammen MJ, Alexander PE, Arrington A, Centofanti JE, Citerio G, Baw B, Memish ZA, Hammond N, Hayden FG, Evans L, Rhodes A. Surviving Sepsis Campaign: guidelines on the management of critically ill adults with Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Intensive Care Med. 2020;46:854&#x2013;887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7101866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32222812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alqahtani JS, Mendes RG, Aldhahir A, Rowley D, AlAhmari MD, Ntoumenopoulos G, Alghamdi SM, Sreedharan JK, Aldabayan YS, Oyelade T, Alrajeh A, Olivieri C, AlQuaimi M, Sullivan J, Almeshari MA, Esquinas A. Global Current Practices of Ventilatory Support Management in COVID-19 Patients: An International Survey. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2020;13:1635&#x2013;1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7680685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Heightman M, O'Brien S. UK guidelines for managing long-term effects of COVID-19. Lancet. 2021;397:1706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8102038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33965081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Hu B, Hu C, Zhu F, Liu X, Zhang J, Wang B, Xiang H, Cheng Z, Xiong Y, Zhao Y, Li Y, Wang X, Peng Z. Clinical Characteristics of 138 Hospitalized Patients With 2019 Novel Coronavirus-Infected Pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA. 2020;323:1061&#x2013;1069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi N. Long covid: How to define it and how to manage it. BMJ. 2020;370:m3489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32895219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A'Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020;370:m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, Brown JS, Denneny EK, Hare SS, Heightman M, Hillman TE, Jacob J, Jarvis HC, Lipman MCI, Naidu SB, Nair A, Porter JC, Tomlinson GS, Hurst JR ARC Study Group. 'Long-COVID': a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntmann VO, Carerj ML, Wieters I, Fahim M, Arendt C, Hoffmann J, Shchendrygina A, Escher F, Vasa-Nicotera M, Zeiher AM, Vehreschild M, Nagel E. Outcomes of Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance Imaging in Patients Recently Recovered From Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:1265&#x2013;1273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorna R, MacDermott N, Rayner C, O'Hara M, Evans S, Agyen L, Nutland W, Rogers N, Hastie C. Long COVID guidelines need to reflect lived experience. Lancet. 2021;397:455&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33357467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mossa-Basha M, Meltzer CC, Kim DC, Tuite MJ, Kolli KP, Tan BS. Radiology Department Preparedness for COVID-19: Radiology Scientific Expert Review Panel. Radiology. 2020;296:E106&#x2013;E112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7233387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32175814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soldati G, Smargiassi A, Inchingolo R, Buonsenso D, Perrone T, Briganti DF, Perlini S, Torri E, Mariani A, Mossolani EE, Tursi F, Mento F, Demi L. Is There a Role for Lung Ultrasound During the COVID-19 Pandemic? J Ultrasound Med. 2020;39:1459&#x2013;1462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32198775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong HYF, Lam HYS, Fong AH, Leung ST, Chin TW, Lo CSY, Lui MM, Lee JCY, Chiu KW, Chung TW, Lee EYP, Wan EYF, Hung IFN, Lam TPW, Kuo MD, Ng MY. Frequency and Distribution of Chest Radiographic Findings in Patients Positive for COVID-19. Radiology. 2020;296:E72&#x2013;E78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7233401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32216717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai T, Yang Z, Hou H, Zhan C, Chen C, Lv W, Tao Q, Sun Z, Xia L. Correlation of Chest CT and RT-PCR Testing for Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) in China: A Report of 1014 Cases. Radiology. 2020;296:E32&#x2013;E40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7233399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32101510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin GD, Ryerson CJ, Haramati LB, Sverzellati N, Kanne JP, Raoof S, Schluger NW, Volpi A, Yim JJ, Martin IBK, Anderson DJ, Kong C, Altes T, Bush A, Desai SR, Goldin J, Goo JM, Humbert M, Inoue Y, Kauczor HU, Luo F, Mazzone PJ, Prokop M, Remy-Jardin M, Richeldi L, Schaefer-Prokop CM, Tomiyama N, Wells AU, Leung AN. The Role of Chest Imaging in Patient Management During the COVID-19 Pandemic: A Multinational Consensus Statement From the Fleischner Society. Chest. 2020;158:106&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7138384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orsi MA, Oliva AG, Cellina M. Radiology Department Preparedness for COVID-19: Facing an Unexpected Outbreak of the Disease. Radiology. 2020;295:E8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7233380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32228364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pezzotti W. Chest X-ray interpretation: not just black and white. Nursing. 2014;44:40&#x2013;7; quiz 47-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24281317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Chen C, Hu Y, Lv W, Ai T, Xia L. Chest CT imaging features and severity scores as biomarkers for prognostic prediction in patients with COVID-19. Ann Transl Med. 2020;8:1449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7723645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33313194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleverley J, Piper J, Jones MM. The role of chest radiography in confirming covid-19 pneumonia. BMJ. 2020;370:m2426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32675083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao X, Wang Y, He Z, Yun Y, Hu M, Ma Z, Huang L, Cai Q, Xu L, Hao Y, Liu L. Three-month pulmonary function and radiological outcomes in COVID-19 survivors: a longitudinal patient cohort study. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2020:ofaa540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34667824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobi A, Chung M, Bernheim A, Eber C. Portable chest X-ray in coronavirus disease-19 (COVID-19): A pictorial review. Clin Imaging. 2020;64:35&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7141645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32302927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren MA, Zhao Z, Koyama T, Bastarache JA, Shaver CM, Semler MW, Rice TW, Matthay MA, Calfee CS, Ware LB. Severity scoring of lung oedema on the chest radiograph is associated with clinical outcomes in ARDS. Thorax. 2018;73:840&#x2013;846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6410734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29903755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun D, Li X, Guo D, Wu L, Chen T, Fang Z, Chen L, Zeng W, Yang R. CT Quantitative Analysis and Its Relationship with Clinical Features for Assessing the Severity of Patients with COVID-19. Korean J Radiol. 2020;21:859&#x2013;868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7289692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32524786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Cruz RF, Waller MD, Perrin F, Periselneris J, Norton S, Smith LJ, Patrick T, Walder D, Heitmann A, Lee K, Madula R, McNulty W, Macedo P, Lyall R, Warwick G, Galloway JB, Birring SS, Patel A, Patel I, Jolley CJ. Chest radiography is a poor predictor of respiratory symptoms and functional impairment in survivors of severe COVID-19 pneumonia. ERJ Open Res. 2021;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7585700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33575312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y, Zhang H, Xie J, Lin M, Ying L, Pang P, Ji W. Sensitivity of Chest CT for COVID-19: Comparison to RT-PCR. Radiology. 2020;296:E115&#x2013;E117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7233365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32073353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Hong H, Yoon SH. Diagnostic Performance of CT and Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction for Coronavirus Disease 2019: A Meta-Analysis. Radiology. 2020;296:E145&#x2013;E155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7233409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32301646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie X, Zhong Z, Zhao W, Zheng C, Wang F, Liu J. Chest CT for Typical Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Pneumonia: Relationship to Negative RT-PCR Testing. Radiology. 2020;296:E41&#x2013;E45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7233363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32049601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Zhong Z, Xie X, Yu Q, Liu J. Relation Between Chest CT Findings and Clinical Conditions of Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) Pneumonia: A Multicenter Study. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2020;214:1072&#x2013;1077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32125873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalaber C, Lapotre T, Morcet-Delattre T, Ribet F, Jouneau S, Lederlin M. Chest CT in COVID-19 pneumonia: A review of current knowledge. Diagn Interv Imaging. 2020;101:431&#x2013;437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7287482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32571748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fred HL. Drawbacks and limitations of computed tomography: views from a medical educator. Tex Heart Inst J. 2004;31:345&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC548232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15745283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao YM, Shang YM, Song WB, Li QQ, Xie H, Xu QF, Jia JL, Li LM, Mao HL, Zhou XM, Luo H, Gao YF, Xu AG. Follow-up study of the pulmonary function and related physiological characteristics of COVID-19 survivors three months after recovery. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Dong C, Hu Y, Li C, Ren Q, Zhang X, Shi H, Zhou M. Temporal Changes of CT Findings in 90 Patients with COVID-19 Pneumonia: A Longitudinal Study. Radiology. 2020;296:E55&#x2013;E64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7233482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32191587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabatabaei SMH, Rajebi H, Moghaddas F, Ghasemiadl M, Talari H. Chest CT in COVID-19 pneumonia: what are the findings in mid-term follow-up? Emerg Radiol. 2020;27:711&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7649573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33165674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Zhang L, Zhang D, Yuan H, Wu C, Zhang Y, He L, Wang R, Wang J, Xie M. Bedside ultrasound in assessment of 510 severe and critical patients with COVID-19 pneumonia in Wuhan, China. AUDT. 2020;4:60&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soldati G, Smargiassi A, Inchingolo R, Buonsenso D, Perrone T, Briganti DF, Perlini S, Torri E, Mariani A, Mossolani EE, Tursi F, Mento F, Demi L. Proposal for International Standardization of the Use of Lung Ultrasound for Patients With COVID-19: A Simple, Quantitative, Reproducible Method. J Ultrasound Med. 2020;39:1413&#x2013;1419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32227492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alqahtani JS, Oyelade T, Sreedharan J, Aldhahir AM, Alghamdi SM, Alrajeh AM, Alqahtani AS, Alsulayyim A, Aldabayan YS, Alobaidi NY, AlAhmari MD. Diagnostic and clinical values of non-cardiac ultrasound in COPD: A systematic review. BMJ Open Respir Res. 2020;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7520906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32978244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng QY, Wang XT, Zhang LN Chinese Critical Care Ultrasound Study Group (CCUSG) Findings of lung ultrasonography of novel corona virus pneumonia during the 2019-2020 epidemic. Intensive Care Med. 2020;46:849&#x2013;850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7080149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32166346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denault AY, Delisle S, Canty D, Royse A, Royse C, Serra XC, Gebhard CE, Couture &#xc9;J, Girard M, Cavayas YA, Peschanski N, Langevin S, Ouellet P. A proposed lung ultrasound and phenotypic algorithm for the care of COVID-19 patients with acute respiratory failure. Can J Anaesth. 2020;67:1393&#x2013;1404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7241588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32440906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil-Rodrigo A, Llorens P, Mart&#xed;nez-Buend&#xed;a C, Luque-Hern&#xe1;ndez MJ, Espinosa B, Ramos-Rinc&#xf3;n JM. Diagnostic yield of point-of-care ultrasound imaging of the lung in patients with COVID-19. Emergencias. 2020;32:340&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33006834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojatti M, Regli IB, Zanforlin A, Ferretti E, Falk M, Strapazzon G, Gamper M, Zanon P, Bock M, Rauch S. Lung Ultrasound and Respiratory Pathophysiology in Mechanically Ventilated COVID-19 Patients-an Observational Trial. SN Compr Clin Med. 2020:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7516234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32995708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung-Chen Y, Mart&#xed; de Gracia M, Parra-Gordo ML, D&#xed;ez-Tasc&#xf3;n A, Agudo-Fern&#xe1;ndez S, Ossaba-V&#xe9;lez S. Usefulness of Lung Ultrasound Follow-up in Patients Who Have Recovered From Coronavirus Disease 2019. J Ultrasound Med. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33159704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Xue H, Wang M, He N, Lv Z, Cui L. Lung Ultrasound Findings in Patients With Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2021;216:80&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32755198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung-Chen Y. Lung ultrasound in the monitoring of COVID-19 infection. Clin Med (Lond) 2020;20:e62&#x2013;e65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkes RC, Holland GN, Moore WS, Worthington BS. Nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) tomography of the brain: a preliminary clinical assessment with demonstration of pathology. J Comput Assist Tomogr. 1980;4:577&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6967878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith FW, Hutchison JM, Mallard JR, Johnson G, Redpath TW, Selbie RD, Reid A, Smith CC. Oesophageal carcinoma demonstrated by whole-body nuclear magnetic resonance imaging. Br Med J (Clin Res Ed) 1981;282:510&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1504319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6780102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grover VP, Tognarelli JM, Crossey MM, Cox IJ, Taylor-Robinson SD, McPhail MJ. Magnetic Resonance Imaging: Principles and Techniques: Lessons for Clinicians. J Clin Exp Hepatol. 2015;5:246&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4632105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26628842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Zhao P, Tang D, Zhu T, Han R, Zhan C, Liu W, Zeng H, Tao Q, Xia L. Cardiac Involvement in Patients Recovered From COVID-2019 Identified Using Magnetic Resonance Imaging. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2020;13:2330&#x2013;2339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7214335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32763118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>