<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39056479</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1520-6629</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of community psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Community Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Experienced discrimination and internalized stigma among people infected with SARS-CoV-2 and surviving COVID-19: Association with anxiety, depression, and insomnia symptoms.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>910</StartPage><EndPage>928</EndPage><MedlinePgn>910-928</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcop.23136</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>People surviving COVID-19 may experience social stigma related to their condition even after clinical recovery. This study aimed to: (1) investigate COVID-19-related experienced discrimination and internalized stigma, and (2) explore their association with symptoms of anxiety, depression, and insomnia. We conducted an online survey of people who survived COVID-19. Perception of stigma was assessed using the COVID-19 Experienced Discrimination Scale and the COVID-19 Internalized Stigma Scale. Depression, anxiety, and insomnia were assessed using, respectively, the Patient Health Questionnaire-9, the General Anxiety Disorder Scale-7, and the Insomnia Severity Index. Multivariable logistic regression analyses for each psychopathological domain were performed. A total of 579 participants participated in this study. Overall, 25% reported some degree of experienced discrimination, and 23% reported some degree of internalized stigma. Adjusted odds ratio&#xa0;showed that scoring higher on internalized stigma related significantly to higher symptoms of depression (2.14; 95% confidence interval [CI], 1.35-3.39), anxiety (2.30; 95%&#xa0;CI, 1.48-3.59), and insomnia (2.54; 95%&#xa0;CI, 1.64-3.95), whereas experienced discrimination was associated to anxiety (1.55; 95%&#xa0;CI, 1.06-2.28) and insomnia (1.82; 95% CI, 1.24-2.69). Experiences of social stigmatization are frequent among people surviving COVID-19 and seem to be associated with levels of psychological disturbances. Further research is required to elucidate the direction of these relationships to implement effective treatment strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Journal of Community Psychology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lasalvia</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9963-6081</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Psychiatry, Department of Neurosciences, Biomedicine and Movement Sciences, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UOC Psichiatria, Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Integrata (AOUI) di Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bodini</LastName><ForeName>Luca</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Psychiatry, Department of Neurosciences, Biomedicine and Movement Sciences, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pace</LastName><ForeName>Davide</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Psychiatry, Department of Neurosciences, Biomedicine and Movement Sciences, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colombi</LastName><ForeName>Morena</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Associazione Italiana Long Covid (AILC), Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caruson</LastName><ForeName>Mattia Marco</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mama Health Technologies GmbH, Potsdam, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Bortel</LastName><ForeName>Tine</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Life Sciences,&#xa0;Leicester School of Allied Health Sciences, De Montfort University, Leicester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Cambridge Public Health Interdisciplinary Research Centre, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bonetto</LastName><ForeName>Chiara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Psychiatry, Department of Neurosciences, Biomedicine and Movement Sciences, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Community Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0367033</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0090-4392</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057545" MajorTopicYN="Y">Social Stigma</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007319" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="Y">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anxiety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063508" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Discrimination</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID&#x2010;19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">discrimination</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insomnia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">internalized stigma</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39056479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcop.23136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Adjaottor, E. S., Addo, F. M., Ahorsu, F. A., Chen, H. P., &amp; Ahorsu, D. K. (2022). Predictors of COVID&#x2010;19 stress and COVID&#x2010;19 vaccination acceptance among adolescents in Ghana. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19, 7871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amerio, A., Lugo, A., Stival, C., Fanucchi, T., Gorini, G., Pacifici, R., Odone, A., Serafini, G., &amp; Gallus, S. (2021). COVID&#x2010;19 lockdown impact on mental health in a large representative sample of Italian adults. Journal of Affective Disorders, 292, 398&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagcchi, S. (2020). Stigma during the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic. The Lancet Infectious Diseases, 20, 782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldassarre, A., Giorgi, G., Alessio, F., Lulli, L., Arcangeli, G., &amp; Mucci, N. (2020). Stigma and discrimination (SAD) at the time of the SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 pandemic. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 17, 6341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastien, C. (2001). Validation of the Insomnia Severity Index as an outcome measure for insomnia research. Sleep Medicine, 2, 297&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodini, L., Bonetto, C., Colombi, M., Barbieri, N., Van Bortel, T., &amp; Lasalvia, A. (2024). Is self&#x2010;compassion associated with lower psychological distress in people with long COVID? Results from a cross&#x2010;sectional survey. Cogent. Psychology, 11, 2351151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonetto, C., Pace, D., Bodini, L., Colombi, M., Van Bortel, T., &amp; Lasalvia, A. (2022). Development and psychometric validation of new questionnaires assessing experienced discrimination and internalised stigma among people with Covid&#x2010;19. Epidemiology and Psychiatric Sciences, 31, e37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Bortel, T., Basnayake, A., Wurie, F., Jambai, M., Koroma, A. S., Muana, A. T., Hann, K., Eaton, J., Martin, S., &amp; Nellums, L. B. (2016). Psychosocial effects of an Ebola outbreak at individual, community and international levels. Bulletin of the World Health Organization, 94, 210&#x2013;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brohan, E., Clement, S., Rose, D., Sartorius, N., Slade, M., &amp; Thornicroft, G. (2013). Development and psychometric evaluation of the Discrimination and Stigma Scale (DISC). Psychiatry Research, 208, 33&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks, S. K., Webster, R. K., Smith, L. E., Woodland, L., Wessely, S., Greenberg, N., Rubin, G. J., Brooks, S. K., Webster, R. K., Smith, L. E., Woodland, L., Wessely, S., Greenberg, N., &amp; Rubin, G. J. (2020). The psychological impact of quarantine and how to reduce it: Rapid review of the evidence. The Lancet, 395, 912&#x2013;920.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruns, D. P., Kraguljac, N. V., &amp; Bruns, T. R. (2020). COVID&#x2010;19: Facts, cultural considerations, and risk of stigmatization. Journal of Transcultural Nursing, 31, 326&#x2013;332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campo&#x2010;Arias, A., Pedrozo&#x2010;Pupo, J. C., &amp; Caballero&#x2010;Dom&#xed;nguez, C. C. (2022). Relation of perceived discrimination with depression, insomnia and post&#x2010;traumatic stress in COVID&#x2010;19 survivors. Psychiatry Research, 307, 114337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xe9;nat, J. M., Noorishad, P. G., Kokou&#x2010;Kpolou, C. K., Dalexis, R. D., Hajizadeh, S., Guerrier, M., Clorm&#xe9;us, L. A., Bukaka, J., Birangui, J. P., Adansikou, K., Ndengeyingoma, A., Sezibera, V., Derivois, D., &amp; Rousseau, C. (2021). Prevalence and correlates of depression during the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic and the major role of stigmatization in low&#x2010; and middle&#x2010;income countries: A multinational cross&#x2010;sectional study. Psychiatry Research, 297, 113714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, K. K. S., &amp; Fung, W. T. W. (2019). The impact of experienced discrimination and self&#x2010;stigma on sleep and health&#x2010;related quality of life among individuals with mental disorders in Hong Kong. Quality of Life Research, 28, 2171&#x2013;2182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, K. K. S., &amp; Fung, W. T. W. (2021). Differential impact of experienced and anticipated discrimination on sleep and health among sexual minorities. Archives of Sexual Behavior, 50, 3053&#x2013;3063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, K. K. S., &amp; Tsui, J. K. C. (2023). Longitudinal impact of experienced discrimination on mental health among people with mental disorders. Psychiatry Research, 322, 115099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H., Chen, Y., Zhang, Y., Wang, Z., Shi, D., Liu, J., Yang, X., Xu, L., Cai, Y., &amp; Hu, F. (2022). Social stigma and depression among asymptomatic COVID&#x2010;19 carriers in shanghai, China: The mediating role of entrapment and decadence. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19, 13006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clucas, C., Sibley, E., Harding, R., Liu, L., Catalan, J., &amp; Sherr, L. (2011). A systematic review of interventions for anxiety in people with HIV. Psychology, Health &amp; Medicine, 16, 528&#x2013;547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrigan, P., Markowitz, F. E., Watson, A., Rowan, D., &amp; Kubiak, M. A. (2003). An attribution model of public discrimination towards persons with mental illness. Journal of Health and Social Behavior, 44, 162&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrigan, P. W., Nieweglowski, K., &amp; Sayer, J. (2019). Self&#x2010;stigma and the mediating impact of the &#x201c;why try&#x201d; effect on depression. Journal of Community Psychology, 47, 698&#x2013;705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrigan, P. W., &amp; Rao, D. (2012). On the self&#x2010;stigma of mental illness: Stages, disclosure, and strategies for change. The Canadian Journal of Psychiatry, 57, 464&#x2013;469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrigan, P. W., &amp; Watson, A. C. (2002). The paradox of self&#x2010;stigma and mental illness. Clinical Psychology: Science and Practice, 9, 35&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Daalen, K. R., Cobain, M., Franco, O. H., &amp; Chowdhury, R. (2021). Stigma: the social virus spreading faster than COVID&#x2010;19. Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health, 75, 313&#x2013;314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dar, S. A., Khurshid, S. Q., Wani, Z. A., Khanam, A., Haq, I., Shah, N. N., &amp; Mustafa, H. (2020). Stigma in coronavirus disease&#x2010;19 survivors in Kashmir, India: A cross&#x2010;sectional exploratory study. PLoS One, 15, e0240152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, J., Zhou, F., Hou, W., Silver, Z., Wong, C. Y., Chang, O., Huang, E., &amp; Zuo, Q. K. (2021). The prevalence of depression, anxiety, and sleep disturbances in COVID&#x2010;19 patients: A meta&#x2010;analysis. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 1486, 90&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drapalski, A. L., Lucksted, A., Perrin, P. B., Aakre, J. M., Brown, C. H., DeForge, B. R., &amp; Boyd, J. E. (2013). A model of internalized stigma and its effects on people with mental illness. Psychiatric Services, 64, 264&#x2013;269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Economou, M. (2021). Social distance in COVID&#x2010;19: Drawing the line between protective behavior and stigma manifestation. Psychiatriki, 32, 183&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Economou, M., Peppou, L. E., Souliotis, K., Lazaratou, H., Kontoangelos, K., Nikolaidi, S., Palli, A., &amp; Stefanis, C. N. (2019). Attitudes to depression and psychiatric medication amid the enduring financial crisis in Attica: Comparison between 2009 and 2014. International Journal of Social Psychiatry, 65, 479&#x2013;487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, W., Qian, Y., &amp; Jin, Y. (2021). Stigma, perceived discrimination, and mental health during China's COVID&#x2010;19 outbreak: A mixed&#x2010;methods investigation. Journal of Health and Social Behavior, 62, 562&#x2013;581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiorillo, A., Sampogna, G., Giallonardo, V., Del Vecchio, V., Luciano, M., Albert, U., Carmassi, C., Carr&#xe0;, G., Cirulli, F., Dell'Osso, B., Nanni, M. G., Pompili, M., Sani, G., Tortorella, A., &amp; Volpe, U. (2020). Effects of the lockdown on the mental health of the general population during the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic in Italy: Results from the COMET collaborative network. European Psychiatry, 63, e87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, F., Sun, W., Zhang, L., Lu, H., &amp; Chen, W.&#x2010;T. (2022). Depressive symptoms mediate COVID&#x2010;associated stigma and quality of life: Stigma instrument validation and path analysis. Journal of Affective Disorders, 297, 269&#x2013;275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komariah, M., Amirah, S., Faisal, E. G., Prayogo, S. A., Maulana, S., Platini, H., Suryani, S., Yosep, I., &amp; Arifin, H. (2022). Efficacy of Internet&#x2010;Based cognitive behavioral therapy for depression and anxiety among global population during the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of a randomized controlled trial study. Healthcare, 10, 1224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke, K., Spitzer, R. L., &amp; Williams, J. B. W. (2001). The PHQ&#x2010;9: Validity of a brief depression severity measure. Journal of General Internal Medicine, 16, 606&#x2013;613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasalvia, A. (2020). Epidemic emergencies and social stigma. Which lessons should we learn from SARS and Ebola epidemics for the current CoViD&#x2010;19 pandemics?. Rivista di Psichiatria, 55, 250&#x2013;253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasalvia, A., Zoppei, S., Van Bortel, T., Bonetto, C., Cristofalo, D., Wahlbeck, K., Bacle, S. V., Van Audenhove, C., van Weeghel, J., Reneses, B., Germanavicius, A., Economou, M., Lanfredi, M., Ando, S., Sartorius, N., Lopez&#x2010;Ibor, J. J., &amp; Thornicroft, G., ASPEN/INDIGO Study Group. (2013). Global pattern of experienced and anticipated discrimination reported by people with major depressive disorder: A cross&#x2010;sectional survey. The Lancet, 381, 55&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Liang, W., Yuan, B., &amp; Zeng, G. (2020). Internalized stigmatization, social support, and individual mental health problems in the public health crisis. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 17, 4507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Link, B. G., &amp; Phelan, J. C. (2001). Conceptualizing stigma. Annual Review of Sociology, 27, 363&#x2013;385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H., Chen, S., Liu, M., Nie, H., &amp; Lu, H. (2020). Comorbid chronic diseases are strongly correlated with disease severity among COVID&#x2010;19 patients: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Aging and Disease, 11, 668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoudi, H., Saffari, M., Movahedi, M., Sanaeinasab, H., Rashidi&#x2010;Jahan, H., Pourgholami, M., Poorebrahim, A., Barshan, J., Ghiami, M., Khoshmanesh, S., Potenza, M. N., Lin, C. Y., &amp; Pakpour, A. H. (2021). A mediating role for mental health in associations between COVID&#x2010;19&#x2010;related self&#x2010;stigma, PTSD, quality of life, and insomnia among patients recovered from COVID&#x2010;19. Brain and Behavior, 11, e02138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza, C., Ricci, E., Biondi, S., Colasanti, M., Ferracuti, S., Napoli, C., &amp; Roma, P. (2020). A nationwide survey of psychological distress among Italian people during the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic: Immediate psychological responses and associated factors. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 17, 3165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokhtari, R., &amp; Golitaleb, M. (2021). Stigma; A major challenge amid the Covid&#x2010;19 pandemic. International Journal of Preventive Medicine, 12, 58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overholt, L., Wohl, D. A., Fischer, W. A., Westreich, D., Tozay, S., Reeves, E., Pewu, K., Adjasso, D., Hoover, D., Merenbloom, C., Johnson, H., Williams, G., Conneh, T., Diggs, J., Buller, A., McMillian, D., Hawks, D., Dube, K., &amp; Brown, J. (2018). Stigma and Ebola survivorship in Liberia: results from a longitudinal cohort study. PLoS One, 13, e0206595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson, A., Olliaro, P. L., &amp; Rojek, A. (2023). Addressing stigma in infectious disease outbreaks: A crucial step in pandemic preparedness. Frontiers in Public Health, 11, 1303679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pescosolido, B. A., &amp; Martin, J. K. (2015). The stigma complex. Annual Review of Sociology, 41, 87&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ransing, R., Ramalho, R., de Filippis, R., Ojeahere, M. I. I, Karaliuniene, R., Orsolini, L., Pinto da Costa, M., Ullah, I., Grandinetti, P., Gashi Byty&#xe7;i, D., Grigo, O., Mhamunkar, A., El Hayek, S., Essam, L., Larnaout, A., Shalbafan, M., Nofal, M., Soler&#x2010;Vidal, J., Pereira&#x2010;Sanchez, V., &amp; Adiukwu, F. (2020). Infectious disease outbreak related stigma and discrimination during the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic: Drivers, facilitators, manifestations, and outcomes across the world. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 89, 555&#x2013;558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritsher, J. B., &amp; Phelan, J. C. (2004). Internalized stigma predicts erosion of morale among psychiatric outpatients. Psychiatry Research, 129, 257&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi, R., Socci, V., Talevi, D., Mensi, S., Niolu, C., Pacitti, F., Di Marco, A., Rossi, A., Siracusano, A., &amp; Di Lorenzo, G. (2020). COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic and lockdown measures impact on mental health among the general population in Italy. Frontiers in Psychiatry, 11, 790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacco, M. A., Scalise, C., Zibetti, A., Aquila, V., Abenavoli, L., Ricci, P., &amp; Aquila, I. (2022). The impact of the covid&#x2010;19 pandemic on the risk of social stigma. European Psychiatry, 65(Suppl. 1), S869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saffari, M., Chang, K. C., Chen, J. S., Chang, C. W., Chen, I. H., Huang, S. W., Liu, C., Lin, C. Y., &amp; Potenza, M. N. (2022). Temporal associations between depressive features and self&#x2010;stigma in people with substance use disorders related to heroin, amphetamine, and alcohol use: A cross&#x2010;lagged analysis. BMC Psychiatry, 22, 815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shpigelman, C. N., &amp; HaGani, N. (2019). The impact of disability type and visibility on self&#x2010;concept and body image: Implications for mental health nursing. Journal of Psychiatric and Mental Health Nursing, 26, 77&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soh, H. L., Ho, R. C., Ho, C. S., &amp; Tam, W. W. (2020). Efficacy of digital cognitive behavioural therapy for insomnia: A meta&#x2010;analysis of randomised controlled trials. Sleep Medicine, 75, 315&#x2013;325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer, R. L., Kroenke, K., Williams, J. B. W., &amp; L&#xf6;we, B. (2006). A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: The GAD&#x2010;7. Archives of Internal Medicine, 166, 1092&#x2013;1097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornicroft, G., Brohan, E., Rose, D., Sartorius, N., &amp; Leese, M., INDIGO Study Group. (2009). Global pattern of experienced and anticipated discrimination against people with schizophrenia: A cross&#x2010;sectional survey. The Lancet, 373, 408&#x2013;415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornicroft, G., Rose, D., Kassam, A., &amp; Sartorius, N. (2007). Stigma: Ignorance, prejudice or discrimination? British Journal of Psychiatry, 190, 192&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton, L., Batterham, P. J., Fassnacht, D. B., Kay&#x2010;Lambkin, F., Calear, A. L., &amp; Hunt, S. (2016). Recruiting for health, medical or psychosocial research using Facebook: Systematic review. Internet Interventions, 4, 72&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toulabi, T., Pour, F. J., Veiskramian, A., &amp; Heydari, H. (2021). Exploring COVID&#x2010;19 patients&#x2019; experiences of psychological distress during the disease course: A qualitative study. BMC Psychiatry, 21, 625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner&#x2010;Musa, J., Ajayi, O., &amp; Kemp, L. (2020). Examining social determinants of health, stigma, and COVID&#x2010;19 disparities. Healthcare, 8, 168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiner, B. (1995). Judgments of responsibility: A foundation for a theory of social conduct. Guilford Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong, J., Lipsitz, O., Nasri, F., Lui, L. M. W., Gill, H., Phan, L., Chen&#x2010;Li, D., Iacobucci, M., Ho, R., Majeed, A., &amp; McIntyre, R. S. (2020). Impact of COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic on mental health in the general population: A systematic review. Journal of Affective Disorders, 277, 55&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>