<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35131989</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-6971</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in pulmonary medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Pulm Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A clinical review of long-COVID with a focus on the respiratory system.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>174</StartPage><EndPage>179</EndPage><MedlinePgn>174-179</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCP.0000000000000863</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Persistence of symptoms after acute coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), often described as long- COVID, is common and debilitating. In this article, we review the epidemiology, clinical features, and research priorities for long-COVID focusing on the respiratory system.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Breathlessness, cough and chest pain were the most commonly reported respiratory symptoms associated with long-COVID. In hospitalised patients, abnormalities on lung function testing or chest imaging were observed less commonly at 12&#x200a;months compared to six months since discharge. Clinical assessment of patients with persisting symptoms after acute COVID-19 requires a comprehensive evaluation to exclude other possible causes for symptoms. With no robust current evidence for interventions to treat long-COVID respiratory symptoms, symptomatic treatment, supported self-management and pulmonary rehabilitation should be considered to help individuals with respiratory symptoms associated with long-COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Long-COVID is a debilitating syndrome that often includes persisting respiratory symptoms and to a lesser degree, abnormalities in lung physiology or imaging. Respiratory features of long-COVID may reduce over time, yet resolution is not seen in all cases. Future research is needed to understand the natural history of long-COVID, identify factors associated with spontaneous improvement/persistence, investigate mechanisms for persisting symptoms, and test interventions to prevent and treat long-COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daines</LastName><ForeName>Luke</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Usher Institute, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Bang</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Usher Institute, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pfeffer</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barts Health NHS Trust and Queen Mary University of London, London.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hurst</LastName><ForeName>John R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCL Respiratory, University College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheikh</LastName><ForeName>Aziz</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Usher Institute, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>COV/LTE/20/15</GrantID><Acronym>CSO_</Acronym><Agency>Chief Scientist Office</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Pulm Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9503765</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1070-5287</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003371" MajorTopicYN="N">Cough</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012137" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory System</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>
<b>Conflicts of interest</b>
. AS is a member of the Scottish Government Chief Medical Officer&#x2019;s COVID-19 Advisory Group and its Standing Committee on Pandemics. He is a member of the UK Government&#x2019;s Risk Stratification Subgroup and Astra-Zeneca&#x2019;s Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic Taskforce. All roles are unremunerated. JRH reports grants, personal fees and non-financial support from pharmaceutical companies that make medicines to treat respiratory disease, outside the submitted work. PEP reports grants from NIHR, outside the submitted work. All authors are part of the PHOSP-COVID airways working group.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35131989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">EMS140974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7612723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCP.0000000000000863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00063198-202205000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Coronavirus (COVID-19) Dashboard.  [Accessed December 2021].  Available from:  https://covid19.who.int/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for national statistics. Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK : 2 December 2021.  [Accessed December 2021].  Available from:  https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/2december2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Health and Care Excellence. COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19.  [Accessed December 2021].  Available from:  https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization clinical case definition working group on post COVID-19 condition. A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. 2021. Oct,  [Accessed December 2021].  Available from:  https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitaker M, Elliott J, Chadeau-Hyam M, et al. Persistent symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection in a random community sample of 508,707 people. [Accessed December 2021];medRxiv. 2021 doi: 10.1101/2021.06.28.21259452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.06.28.21259452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nature medicine. 2021 Apr;27(4):626&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, McAuley H, Harrison EM, et al. Physical, cognitive, and mental health impacts of COVID-19 after hospitalisation (PHOSP-COVID): a UK multicentre, prospective cohort study. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine. 9(11):1275&#x2013;1287. [*A multi-centre cohort study of reporting the 6 month follow up of individuals who were discharged from hospital following treatment for acute COVID-19. Includes a comprehensive evaluation of mental, physical and clinical test results. Reported that 29% of individuals felt fully recovered, and 93% had at least one symptom at follow up.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34627560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, et al. Symptoms, complications, and management of long COVID: a review. Journal of the Royal Society of Medicine. 2021;114(9):428&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigfrid L, Drake TM, Pauley E, et al. Long Covid in adults discharged from UK hospitals after Covid-19: A prospective, multicentre cohort study using the ISARIC WHO Clinical Characterisation Protocol. Lancet Reg Health Eur. 2021;8:100186. doi: 10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8343377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34386785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittaker HR, Gulea C, Koteci A, et al. GP consultation rates for sequelae after acute covid-19 in patients managed in the community or hospital in the UK: population based study. BMJ. 2021;375</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, Leavy OC, Richardson M, et al. Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of Long-COVID and association with one-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. medRxiv. :2021.12.13.21267471. doi: https://doi.org/10.1101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9034855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35472304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Florencio LL, Cuadrado ML, Plaza-Manzano G, Navarro-Santana M. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Intern Med. 2021;92:55&#x2013;70. [*This systematic review and meta-analysis provides data on the prevalence of symptoms after acute COVID-19 which is presented so that comparisons can be made between hospitalised vs non-hospitalised patients at three different time points.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34167876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, et al. &#x2018;Long-COVID&#x2019;: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76(4):396&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, et al. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. The Lancet. 2021;398(10302):747&#x2013;58. [*One of the first cohort studies to report follow up data for hospitalised patients with COVID-19 at 12 months. Reported that 49% had at least one persisting at the 12 month follow up assessment but 88% of those who were employed prior to acute COVID-19, had returned to work.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraser E. Long term respiratory complications of covid-19. BMJ. 2020;370:m3001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32747332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngai JC, Ko FW, Ng SS, et al. The long-term impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome on pulmonary function, exercise capacity and health status. Respirology. 2010;15(3):543&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7192220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20337995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Li J, Liu H, et al. Long-term bone and lung consequences associated with hospital-acquired severe acute respiratory syndrome: a 15-year follow-up from a prospective cohort study. Bone research. 2020;8(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7018717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32128276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai SR, Wells AU, Rubens MB, Evans TW, Hansell DM. Acute respiratory distress syndrome: CT abnormalities at long-term follow-up. Radiology. 1999;210(1):29&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9885583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiumello D, Coppola S, Froio S, Gotti M. What&#x2019;s next after ARDS: long-term outcomes. Respiratory care. 2016;61(5):689&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27121623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowdy DW, Eid MP, Dennison CR, et al. Quality of life after acute respiratory distress syndrome: a meta-analysis. Intensive Care Med. 2006;32(8):1115&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16783553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briand J, Behal H, Chenivesse C, W&#xe9;meau-Stervinou L, Wallaert B. The 1-minute sit-to-stand test to detect exercise-induced oxygen desaturation in patients with interstitial lung disease. Therapeutic advances in respiratory disease. 2018:1753466618793028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6088463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30091679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heightman M, Prashar J, Hillman TE, et al. Post-COVID-19 assessment in a specialist clinical service: a 12-month, single-centre, prospective study in 1325 individuals. BMJ open respiratory research. 2021;8(1):e001041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8587466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34764200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozalevli S, Ozden A, Itil O, Akkoclu A. Comparison of the Sit-to-Stand Test with 6 min walk test in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Respir Med. 2007 Feb;101(2):286&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16806873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Thoracic Society. BTS guidance on respiratory follow up of patients with radiologically confirmed COVID-19 pneumonia.  [Accessed 6 December 2021].  Available from:  https://www.brit-thoracic.org.uk/covid-19/covid-19-information-for-the-respiratory-community/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhawan RT, Gopalan D, Howard L. Beyond the clot: perfusion imaging of the pulmonary vasculature after COVID-19. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine. 2021;9(1):107&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33217366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health Research: Funding and awards. Supported remote rehabilitation post Covid-19: development, deployment and evaluation of a digitally-enabled rehabilitation programme.  [Accessed December 2021].  Available from:  https://fundingawards.nihr.ac.uk/award/NIHR132243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sing S, Bolton C, Nolan C, et al.  Delivering rehabilitation to patients surviving COVID-19 using an adapted pulmonary rehabilitation approach &#x2013; BTS guidance.  [Accessed 6 December 2021].  Available from:  https://www.brit-thoracic.org.uk/covid-19/covid-19-information-for-the-respiratory-community/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeloye D, Elneima O, Daines L, et al. The long-term sequelae of COVID-19: an international consensus on research priorities for patients with pre-existing and new-onset airways disease. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine. 2021;9(12):1467&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8372501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34416191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beasley R, Kearns N, Hills T. Charting a course for the management of long COVID. The Lancet Respiratory Medicine. 2021;9(12):1358&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8372495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34416190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson G, Long Covid Forum Group Research priorities for Long Covid: refined through an international multi-stakeholder forum. BMC Med. 2021;19:84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8009733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor RR, Trivedi B, Patel N, et al. Post-COVID symptoms reported at asynchronous virtual review and stratified follow-up after COVID-19 pneumonia. Clin Med (Lond) 2021;21(4):e384&#x2013;91. doi: 10.7861/clinmed.2021-0037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7861/clinmed.2021-0037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8313189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34103378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathur R, Rentsch CT, Morton CE, et al. Ethnic differences in SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19-related hospitalisation, intensive care unit admission, and death in 17 million adults in England: an observational cohort study using the OpenSAFELY platform. The Lancet. 2021;397(10286):1711&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8087292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33939953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>