<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37255048</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-698X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19 and the gastrointestinal tract in children.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>585</StartPage><EndPage>589</EndPage><MedlinePgn>585-589</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MOP.0000000000001263</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">This is an overview of the effects of COVID-19 in the gastrointestinal tract in children, and current evidence of the impact of COVID-19 in pediatric patients with chronic gastrointestinal conditions, including inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), chronic liver disease, and disorders of the gut-brain interaction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Children with COVID-19 have a milder course and more favorable outcomes than adults, even in those with immunosuppression due to IBD or liver transplantation. Children with chronic gastrointestinal conditions do not have worse clinical outcomes than healthy children and infection itself has not been linked to an increased incidence of conditions such as IBD and celiac disease, but results regarding post-infectious irritable bowel syndrome are mixed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Research specific to pediatrics is needed, particularly in post-infectious disorders of the gut-brain interaction (PI-DGBIs) and long COVID-19. Data extrapolated from adult trials may not apply to children, as their clinical course is different. PI-DGBIs and long COVID-19 require special attention, as they represent a major morbidity burden in children.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riera-Canales</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Miami, Leonard M. Miller School of Medicine, Division of Pediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Nutrition, Miami, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Llanos-Chea</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Texas Southwestern, Division of Pediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Nutrition, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9000850</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1040-8703</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015212" MajorTopicYN="Y">Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043183" MajorTopicYN="Y">Irritable Bowel Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D041981" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal Tract</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37255048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MOP.0000000000001263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00008480-990000000-00101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>CDC COVID Data Tracker. https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#datatracker-home 2023. [Accessed 2 April 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Laughlin KN, Thompson M, Hota B, et al. Study protocol for the Innovative Support for Patients with SARS-COV-2 Infections Registry (INSPIRE): a longitudinal study of the medium and long-term sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. PLoS One 2022; 17:e0264260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venegas-Borsellino C, Sankararaman S, Roche K, et al. Impact of COVID-19 on the intestinal microbiome. Curr Nutr Rep 2021; 10:300&#x2013;306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galanopoulos M, Gkeros F, Doukatas A, et al. COVID-19 pandemic: pathophysiology and manifestations from the gastrointestinal tract. World J Gastroenterol 2020; 26:4579&#x2013;4588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assa A, Benninga MA, Borrelli O, et al. Gastrointestinal perspective of Coronavirus disease 2019 in children: an updated review. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr 2021; 73:299&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donati Zeppa S, Agostini D, Piccoli G, et al. Gut microbiota status in COVID-19: an unrecognized player? Front Cell Infect Microbiol 2020; 10:576551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo T, Zhang F, Lui GCY, et al. Alterations in gut microbiota of patients with COVID-19 during time of hospitalization. Gastroenterology 2020; 159:944&#x2013;955. e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effenberger M, Grabherr F, Mayr L, et al. Faecal calprotectin indicates intestinal inflammation in COVID-19. Gut 2020; 69:1543&#x2013;1544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puoti MG, Rybak A, Kiparissi F, et al. SARS-CoV-2 and the gastrointestinal tract in children. Front Pediatr 2021; 9:617980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayed IA, Bhalala U, Strom L, et al. Gastrointestinal manifestations in hospitalized children with acute SARS-CoV-2 infection and multisystem inflammatory condition: an analysis of the VIRUS COVID-19 Registry. Pediatr Infect Dis J 2022; 41:751&#x2013;758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pegoraro F, Trapani S, Indolfi G. Gastrointestinal, hepatic and pancreatic manifestations of COVID-19 in children. Clin Res Hepatol Gastroenterol 2022; 46:101818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antala S, Diamond T, Kociolek LK, et al. Severe hepatitis in pediatric Coronavirus disease 2019. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr 2022; 74:631&#x2013;635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoste L, Van Paemel R, Haerynck F. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children related to COVID-19: a systematic review. Eur J Pediatr 2021; 180:2019&#x2013;2034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahn B, Eze OP, Edelman MC, et al. Features of intestinal disease associated with COVID-related multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr 2021; 72:384&#x2013;387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez Jimenez D, Velasco Rodr&#xed;guez-Belv&#xed;s M, Ferrer Gonzalez P, et al. COVID-19 gastrointestinal manifestations are independent predictors of PICU admission in hospitalized pediatric patients. Pediatr Infect Dis J 2020; 39:e459&#x2013;e462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolia R, Dhanesh Goel A, Badkur M, Jain V. Gastrointestinal manifestations of pediatric coronavirus disease and their relationship with a severe clinical course: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Trop Pediatr 2021; 67:fmab051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Pittet LF, Curtis N. How common is long COVID in children and adolescents? Pediatr Infect Dis J 2021; 40:e482&#x2013;e487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner EJ, Pigneur B, Focht G, et al. Benign evolution of SARS-Cov2 infections in children with inflammatory bowel disease: results from two international databases. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 2021; 19:394&#x2013;396. e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ungaro RC, Brenner EJ, Gearry RB, et al. Effect of IBD medications on COVID-19 outcomes: results from an international registry. Gut 2021; 70:725&#x2013;732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi K, Godoy Brewer G, Thu Nguyen M, et al. COVID-19 and outcomes in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: systematic review and meta-analysis. Inflamm Bowel Dis 2022; 28:1265&#x2013;1279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner EJ, Ungaro RC, Gearry RB, et al. Corticosteroids, but not TNF antagonists, are associated with adverse COVID-19 outcomes in patients with inflammatory bowel diseases: results from an International Registry. Gastroenterology 2020; 159:481&#x2013;491. e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batsiou A, Mantzios P, Piovani D, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection and outcomes in children with inflammatory bowel diseases: a systematic review. J Clin Med 2022; 11:7238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner D, Huang Y, Mart&#xed;n-de-Carpi J, et al. Corona virus disease 2019 and paediatric inflammatory bowel diseases: global experience and provisional guidance (March 2020) from the Paediatric IBD Porto Group of European Society of Paediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology, and Nutrition. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr 2020; 70:727&#x2013;733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen R, Mahlab-Guri K, Atali M, Elbirt D. Viruses and celiac disease: what do we know? Clin Exp Med 2023; 1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1007/s10238-023-01070-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10238-023-01070-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottesman BL, Yu J, Tanaka C, et al. Incidence of new-onset type 1 diabetes among US children during the COVID-19 global pandemic. JAMA Pediatr 2022; 176:414&#x2013;415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasbarrini G, Dionisi T, Corazza GR, et al. COVID-19 in celiac disease: a multicentric retrospective cohort study. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci 2021; 25:4400&#x2013;4404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Tian A, Yang D, Zhang M, et al. Celiac disease and the susceptibility of COVID-19 and the risk of severe COVID-19: a Mendelian randomization study. Clin Transl Gastroenterol 2022; 13:e00480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crocco M, Calvi A, Canzoneri F, et al. The influence of SARS-CoV-2 pandemic on the diagnosis of celiac disease and clinical practice in pediatric gastroenterology. Nutrients 2023; 15:559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uche-Anya E, Husby S, Kaplan GG, et al. An international reporting registry of patients with celiac disease and COVID-19: initial results From SECURE-CELIAC. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 2021; 19:2435&#x2013;2437. e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marjot T, Moon AM, Cook JA, et al. Outcomes following SARS-CoV-2 infection in patients with chronic liver disease: an international registry study. J Hepatol 2021; 74:567&#x2013;577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Giorgio A, Hartleif S, Warner S, Kelly D. COVID-19 in children with liver disease. Front Pediatr 2021; 9:616381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boettler T, Newsome PN, Mondelli MU, et al. Care of patients with liver disease during the COVID-19 pandemic: EASL-ESCMID position paper. JHEP Rep 2020; 2:100113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Antiga L. Coronaviruses and immunosuppressed patients: the facts during the third epidemic. Liver Transpl 2020; 26:832&#x2013;834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavriilidis P, Pai M. The impact of COVID-19 global pandemic on morbidity and mortality of liver transplant recipients children and adults: a systematic review of case series. J Clin Med Res 2020; 12:404&#x2013;408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Guo C, Tang L, et al. Prolonged presence of SARS-CoV-2 viral RNA in faecal samples. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol 2020; 5:434&#x2013;435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung KS, Hung IFN, Chan PPY, et al. Gastrointestinal manifestations of SARS-CoV-2 infection and virus load in fecal samples from a Hong Kong cohort: systematic review and meta-analysis. Gastroenterology 2020; 159:81&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghoshal UC, Ghoshal U, Rahman MM, et al. Post-infection functional gastrointestinal disorders following coronavirus disease-19: a case-control study. J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2022; 37:489&#x2013;498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marasco G, Cremon C, Barbaro MR, et al. Post COVID-19 irritable bowel syndrome. Gut 2022; gutjnl-2022-328483. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2022-328483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2022-328483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klem F, Wadhwa A, Prokop LJ, et al. Prevalence, risk factors, and outcomes of irritable bowel syndrome after infectious enteritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Gastroenterology 2017; 152:1042&#x2013;1054. e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farello G, Di Lucia A, Fioravanti B, et al. Analysis of the impact of COVID-19 pandemic on functional gastrointestinal disorders among paediatric population. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci 2021; 25:5836&#x2013;5842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpato E, Kolacek S, Jojkic-Pavkov D, et al. Prevalence of functional gastrointestinal disorders in children and adolescents in the Mediterranean region of Europe. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 2018; 16:870&#x2013;876.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>