<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38593220</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1749-6632</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>1535</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann N Y Acad Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID and post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 pathogenesis and treatment: A Keystone Symposia report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>31</StartPage><EndPage>41</EndPage><MedlinePgn>31-41</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nyas.15132</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In 2023, the Keystone Symposia held the first international scientific conference convening research leaders investigating the pathology of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) or Long COVID, a growing and urgent public health priority. In this report, we present insights from the talks and workshops presented during this meeting and highlight key themes regarding what researchers have discovered regarding the underlying biology of PASC and directions toward future treatment. Several themes have emerged in the biology, with inflammation and other immune alterations being the most common focus, potentially related to viral persistence, latent virus reactivation, and/or tissue damage and dysfunction, especially of the endothelium, nervous system, and mitochondria. In order to develop safe and effective treatments for people with PASC, critical next steps should focus on the replication of major findings regarding potential mechanisms, disentangling pathogenic mechanisms from downstream effects, development of cellular and animal models, mechanism-focused randomized, placebo-controlled trials, and closer collaboration between people with lived experience, scientists, and other stakeholders. Ultimately, by learning from other post-infectious syndromes, the knowledge gained may help not only those with PASC/Long COVID, but also those with other post-infectious syndromes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of The New York Academy of Sciences.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Durstenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Matthew S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of California, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiman</LastName><ForeName>Shannon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Keystone Symposia, Silverthorne, Colorado, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holtzman</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Washington University School of Medicine in St. Louis, St. Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blish</LastName><ForeName>Catherine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stanford Immunology Program and Department of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pretorius</LastName><ForeName>Resia</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiological Sciences, Faculty of Science, Stellenbosch University, Stellenbosch, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Cell and Systems Biology, Institute of Systems, Molecular and Integrative Biology, Faculty of Health and Life Sciences, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deeks</LastName><ForeName>Steven G</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of California, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K12 HL143961</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann N Y Acad Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7506858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0077-8923</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000093485" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Drug Treatment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">conference report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post&#x2010;acute sequelae of COVID&#x2010;19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post&#x2010;viral conditions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>COMPETING INTERESTS. M.S.D., none; S.W., Keystone Symposia employee; M.H., Founder, Nupeak Therapeutics Inc.; C.B., DeepCell, Inc., Catamaran Bio, Immunebridge; R.P., none; S.G.D., Pfizer, Enantha.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38593220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2029842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11500513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nyas.15132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Horwitz LI, Thaweethai T, Brosnahan SB, Cicek MS, Fitzgerald ML, Goldman JD, Hess R, Hodder SL, Jacoby VL, Jordan MR, Krishnan JA, Laiyemo AO, Metz TD, Nichols L, Patzer RE, Sekar A, Singer NG, Stiles LE, Taylor BS, &#x2026; Foulkes AS (2023). Researching COVID to Enhance Recovery (RECOVER) adult study protocol: Rationale, objectives, and design. PLoS ONE, 18, e0286297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10289397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37352211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley SE, Karlson EW, Levitan EB, Levy B, Mccomsey GA, Mccorkell L, Nadkarni GN, Parthasarathy S, Singh U, Walker TA, Selvaggi CA, Shinnick DJ, Schulte CCM, Atchley-Challenner R, Horwitz LI, Foulkes AS, Aberg JA, Adolphi NL, &#x2026; Zisis S (2023). Development of a definition of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA, 329, 1934&#x2013;1946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10214179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeler SP, Wu K, Zhang Y, Mao D, Li M, Iberg CA, Austin SR, Glaser SA, Yantis J, Podgorny S, Brody SL, Chartock JR, Han Z, Byers DE, Romero AG, &amp; Holtzman MJ (2023). A potent MAPK13-14 inhibitor prevents airway inflammation and mucus production. American Journal of Physiology. Lung Cellular and Molecular Physiology, 325, L726&#x2013;L740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11068410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37847710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J, Wood J, Jaycox JR, Dhodapkar RM, Lu P, Gehlhausen JR,Tabachnikova A,Greene K,Tabacof L, Malik AA, Silva Monteiro V, Silva J, Kamath K, Zhang M, Dhal A, Ott IM, Valle G, Pe&#xf1;a-Hern&#xe1;ndez M, Mao T, &#x2026; &amp; Iwasaki A (2023). Distinguishing features of long COVID identified through immune profiling. Nature, 623,139&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10620090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37748514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Swank ZN, Goldberg SA, Lu S, Dalhuisen T, Borberg E, Senussi Y, Luna MA, Song CC, Clark A, Zamora A, Lew M, Viswanathan B, Huang B, Anglin K, Hoh R, Hsue PY, Durstenfeld MS, Spinelli MA, &#x2026; Martin JN (2023). Plasma-based antigen persistence in the post-acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Medrxiv, 10.1101/2023.10.24.23297114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.10.24.23297114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38604216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Ryder D, Flavell R, Wang Y, Levi J, LaFranchi BH, Deveau TM, Buck AM, Munter SE, Asare KA, Aslam M, Koch W, Szabo G, Hoh R, Deswal M, Rodriguez A, Buitrago M, Tai V, Shrestha U, &#x2026; Henrich TJ (2023). Multimodal molecular imaging reveals tissue-based T cell activation and viral RNA persistence for up to 2 years following COVID-19. Medrxiv, 10.1101/2023.07.27.23293177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.07.27.23293177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swank Z, Senussi Y, Manickas-Hill Z, Yu XUG, Li JZ, Alter G, &amp; Walt DR (2023). Persistent circulating severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 spike is associated with post-acute coronavirus disease 2019 sequelae. Clinical Infectious Diseases, 76, e487&#x2013;e490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10169416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36052466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Col&#xf3;n GJ, Ratnasiri K, Chen H, Jiang S, Zanley E, Rustagi A, Verma R, Chen H, Andrews JR, Mertz KD, Tzankov A, Azagury D, Boyd J, Nolan GP, Sch&#xfc;rch CM, Matter MS, Blish CA, &amp; Mclaughlin TL (2022). SARS-CoV-2 infection drives an inflammatory response in human adipose tissue through infection of adipocytes and macrophages. Science Translational Medicine, 14, eabm9151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9529056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36137009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheibenbogen C, Bellmann-Strobl JT, Heindrich C, Wittke K, Stein E, Franke C, Pr&#xfc;ss H, Pre&#xdf;ler H, Machule M-L, Audebert H, Finke C, Zimmermann HG, Sawitzki B, Meisel C, Toelle M, Krueger A, Aschenbrenner AC, Schultze JL, Beyer MD, &#x2026; Burock S (2023). Fighting post-COVID and ME/CFS&#x2014;Developmentof curative therapies. Frontiers in Medicine (Lausanne), 10,1194754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10309204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37396922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB, Howe A, Munier CML, Patel SK, Juno JA, Burrell LM, Kent SJ, Dore GJ, Kelleher AD, &amp; Matthews GV (2022). Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nature Immunology, 23, 210&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruger A, Vlok M, Turner S, Venter C, Laubscher GJ, Kell DB, &amp; Pretorius E (2022). Proteomics of fibrin amyloid microclots in long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) shows many entrapped pro-inflammatory molecules that may also contribute to a failed fibrinolytic system. Cardiovascular Diabetology, 21,190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9491257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36131342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M-H, Perl DP, Nair G, Li W, Maric D, Murray H, Dodd SJ, Koretsky AP, Watts JA, Cheung V, Masliah E, Horkayne-Szakaly I, Jones R, Stram MN, Moncur J, Hefti M, Folkerth RD, &amp; Nath A (2021). Microvascular injury in the brains of patients with Covid-19. New England Journal of Medicine, 384,481&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7787217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33378608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin K, Peluso MJ, Luo X, Thomas R, Shin M-G, Neidleman J, Andrew A, Young KC, Ma T, Hoh R, Anglin K, Huang B, Argueta U, Lopez M, Valdivieso D, Asare K, Deveau T-M, Munter SE, Ibrahim R, &#x2026; Roan NR (2024). Long COVID manifests with T cell dysregulation, inflammation and an uncoordinated adaptive immune response to SARS-CoV-2. Nature Immunology, 25, 218&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10834368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38212464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Aumatell A, Bovo MV, Carreras-Abad C, Cuso-Perez S, Dom&#xe8;nech Marsal &#xc8;, Coll-Fern&#xe1;ndez R, Goicoechea Calvo A, Giralt-L&#xf3;pez M, Ense&#xf1;at Cantallops A, Moron-Lopez S, Martinez-Picado J, Sol Ventura P, Rodrigo C, &amp; M&#xe9;ndez Hern&#xe1;ndez M (2022). Social, academic, and health status impact of long COVID on children and young people: An observational, descriptive, and longitudinal cohort study. Children (Basel), 9, 1677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9689050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36360405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durstenfeld MS, Peluso MJ, Kaveti P, Hill C, Li D, Sander E, Swaminathan S, Arechiga VM, Lu S, Goldberg SA, Hoh R, Chenna A, Yee BC, Winslow JW, Petropoulos CJ, Kelly JD, Glidden DV, Henrich TJ, Martin JN, &#x2026; Hsue PY (2023). Reduced exercise capacity, chronotropic incompetence, and early systemic inflammation in cardiopulmonary phenotype long coronavirus disease 2019. Journal of Infectious Diseases, 228, 542&#x2013;554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10686699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37166076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mataraarachchi N, Peluso M, Long CS, Grandis DJ, Deeks S, Hsue PY, &amp; Durstenfeld M (2023). Evaluation of post-covid autonomic dysfunction with tilt table testing. Journal of the American College of Cardiology, 81,53&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, Mccorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re&#x2019;em Y, Redfield S, Austin JP, &amp; Akrami A (2021). Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 Months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine, 38,101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Mccorkell L, Vogel JM, &amp; Topol EJ (2023). Long COVID: Major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nature Reviews Microbiology, 21, 133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Re&#x2019;em Y, Stelson EA, Davis HE, Mccorkell L, Wei H, Assaf G, &amp; Akrami A (2023). Factors associated with psychiatric outcomes and coping in Long COVID. Nature Mental Health, 1, 361&#x2013;372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollack B, Von Saltza E, Mccorkell L, Santos L, Hultman A, Cohen AK, &amp; Soares L (2023). Female reproductive health impacts of Long COVID and associated illnesses including ME/CFS, POTS, and connective tissue disorders: A literature review. Frontiers in Rehabilitation Sciences, 4, 1122673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10208411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37234076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Lodge T, Kingdon C, Strong JWL, Maclennan J, Lacerda E, Kujawski S, Zalewski P, Huang WE, &amp; Morten KJ (2023). Developing a blood cell-based diagnostic test for myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome using peripheral blood mononuclear cells. Advanced Science (Weinheim), 10, e2302146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10602530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37653608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanz TV, Brewer RC, Ho PP, Moon J-S, Jude KM, Fernandez D, Fernandes RA, Gomez AM, Nadj G-S, Bartley CM, Schubert RD, Hawes IA, Vazquez SE, Iyer M, Zuchero JB, Teegen B, Dunn JE, Lock CB, Kipp LB, &#x2026; Robinson WH (2022). Clonally expanded B cells in multiple sclerosis bind EBV EBNA1 and GlialCAM. Nature, 603, 321&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9382663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35073561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques A (2022). Persistent symptoms after treatment of Lyme disease. Infectious Disease Clinics of North America, 36,621&#x2013;638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9494579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36116839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appelman B, Charlton BT, Goulding RP, Kerkhoff TJ, Breedveld EA, Noort W, Offringa C, Bloemers FW, Van Weeghel M, Schomakers BV, Coelho P, Posthuma JJ, Aronica E, Joost Wiersinga W, Van Vugt M, &amp; W&#xfc;st RCI (2024). Muscle abnormalities worsen after post-exertional malaise in long COVID. Nature Communications, 15, 17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10766651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38177128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasso EM, Muraki K, Eaton-Fitch N, Smith P, Lesslar OLY, Deed G, &amp; Marshall-Gradisnik S (2022). Transient receptor potential melastatin 3 dysfunction in post COVID-19 condition and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients. Molecular Medicine, 28, 98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35986236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinnon KH, Leist SR, Okuda K, Dang H, Fritch EJ, Gully KL, De La Cruz G, Evangelista MD, Asakura T, Gilmore RC, Hawkins P, Nakano S, West A, Sch&#xe4;fer A, Gralinski LE, Everman JL, Sajuthi SP, Zweigart MR, Dong S, &#x2026; Baric RS (2022). SARS-CoV-2 infection produces chronic pulmonary epithelial and immune cell dysfunction with fibrosis in mice. Science Translational Medicine, 14, eabo5070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9273046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35857635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph P, Singh I, Oliveira R, Capone CA, Mullen MP, Cook DB, Stovall MC, Squires J, Madsen K, Waxman AB, &amp; Systrom DM (2023). Exercise pathophysiology in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome and postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2: More in common than not? Chest, 164, 717&#x2013;726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10088277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37054777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, &amp; Deeks SG (2022). Early clues regarding the pathogenesis of long-COVID. Trends in Immunology, 43, 268&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8901423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35272932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwasaki A, &amp; Putrino D (2023). Why we need a deeper understanding of the pathophysiology of long COVID. Lancet Infectious Diseases, 23, 393&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9928485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36967698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>