<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37363273</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2673-253X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in digital health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Digit Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of opinion dynamics on the public health damage inflicted by COVID-19 in the presence of societal heterogeneities.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1146178</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1146178</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1146178</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fdgth.2023.1146178</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Certain behavioral practices, such as wearing masks, practicing social distancing, and accepting vaccines, play a crucial role in impeding the spread of COVID-19 and reducing the severity of symptoms. Opinions regarding whether to observe such behavioral practices evolve over time through interactions via networks that overlap with but are not identical to the physical interaction networks over which the disease progresses. This necessitates the joint study of the dynamics of COVID-19 and opinion evolution.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We develop a mathematical model that can be easily adapted to a wide range of behavioral practices and captures in a computationally tractable manner the joint evolution of the disease and relevant opinions in populations of large sizes. Populations of large sizes are typically heterogeneous in that they comprise individuals of different age groups, genders, races, and underlying health conditions. Such groups have different propensities to imbibe severe forms of the disease, different physical contact, and social interaction patterns and rates. These lead to different disease and opinion dynamics in them. Our model is designed to effectively capture such diversities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Computations using our model reveal that opinion dynamics have a strong impact on fatality and hospitalization counts and the number of man-days lost due to symptoms both in the regular form of the disease and the extended forms, more commonly known as long COVID. We show that opinion dynamics in certain groups have a disproportionate impact on the overall public health attributes because they have high physical interaction rates, even when they have the lowest propensity to imbibe severe forms of the disease. This identifies a social vulnerability that malactors can utilize to inflict heavy public health damages through opinion campaigns targeting specific segments. Once such vulnerabilities are identified, which we accomplish, adequate precautions may be designed to enhance resilience to such targeted attacks and better protect public health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">By recognizing and understanding the vulnerabilities, appropriate precautions can be developed to enhance resilience against targeted attacks and safeguard public health. Our study underscores the importance of considering opinion evolution alongside disease dynamics, providing insights into the interplay between behavioral practices, opinions, and disease outcomes. We believe that our model is a valuable tool for understanding the joint dynamics of COVID-19 and opinions. We hope that our findings will help to inform public health policy and facilitate evidence-based decision-making for public health interventions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Ali and Sarkar.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Rex N</ForeName><Initials>RN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Systems Engineering, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarkar</LastName><ForeName>Saswati</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Systems Engineering, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Digit Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101771889</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2673-253X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 dynamics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behavioral practice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cooperativity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disease and opinion dynamics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long Covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opinion dynamics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opinion spread rate</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37363273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10285391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2023.1146178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control, Prevention (CDC). First travel-related case of 2019 novel coronavirus detected in United States. 2020 January. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2020/p0121-novel-coronavirus-travel-case.html (Accessed November 1, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeller M, Gangavarapu K, Anderson C, Smither AR, Vanchiere JA, Rose R, et al. Emergence of an early SARS-CoV-2 epidemic in the United States. Cell. (2021) 184(19):4939&#x2013;52. 10.1016/j.cell.2021.07.030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2021.07.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8313480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34508652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). WHO Director-General&#x2019;s opening remarks at the media briefing on COVID-19-11 March 2020. Available from: https://www.who.int/director-general/speeches/detail/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-the-media-briefing-on-covid-19&#x2014;11-march-2020 (Accessed November 1, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control, Prevention (CDC). CDC Covid data tracker. Available from: https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/datatracker-home (Accessed November 1, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abaluck J, Kwong LH, Styczynski A, Haque A, Kabir MA, Bates-Jefferys E, et al. Impact of community masking on COVID-19: a cluster-randomized trial in Bangladesh. Science. (2022) 375(6577):eabi9069. 10.1126/science.abi9069</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abi9069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9036942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34855513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilder-Smith A. What is the vaccine effect on reducing transmission in the context of the SARS-CoV-2 delta variant? Lancet Infect Dis. (2022) 22(2):152&#x2013;3. 10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00690-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00690-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8554481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34756187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Summary of guidance for minimizing the impact of COVID-19 on individual persons, communities, and health care systems&#x2014;United States, August 2022. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/71/wr/mm7133e1.htm (Accessed November 1, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson MG, Stenehjem E, Grannis S, Ball SW, Naleway AL, Ong TC, et al. Effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccines in ambulatory and inpatient care settings. N Engl J Med. (2021) 385(15):1355&#x2013;71. 10.1056/NEJMoa2110362</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2110362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8451184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34496194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calafiore GC, Fracastoro G. Age structure in SIRD models for the covid-19 pandemic&#x2014;a case study on italy data and effects on mortality. PLoS One. (2022) 17(2):e0264324. 10.1371/journal.pone.0264324</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0264324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8870534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35202438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). COVID-19 risks and vaccine information for older adults. 2021 August. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/aging/covid19/covid19-older-adults.html (Accessed November 1, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. COVID-19 pandemic planning scenarios. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/planning-scenarios.html (Accessed December 10, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandler RF. COVID19 and the commonwealth: vulnerable populations in Pennsylvania: health risks &amp; factors. Pennsylvania Population Network, Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA. Issue 05 | Apr 2020 https://pop.psu.edu/sites/pri/files/COVIDSmoking&amp;Obesity.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). People with certain medical conditions. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/need-extra-precautions/people-with-medical-conditions.html (Accessed January 2, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeSimone DC. Why are people of color more at risk of being affected by COVID-19? October 2022. Available from: https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/coronavirus/expert-answers/coronavirus-infection-by-race/faq-20488802 (Accessed November 1, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin J-M, Bai P, He W, Wu F, Liu X-F, Han D-M, et al. Gender differences in patients with COVID-19: focus on severity and mortality. Front Public Health. (2020) 8:152. 10.3389/fpubh.2020.00152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2020.00152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7201103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32411652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcum CS. Age differences in daily social activities. Res Aging. (2013) 35(5):612&#x2013;40. 10.1177/0164027512453468</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0164027512453468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4151480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25190898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaidyanathan R. Why don&#x2019;t black, white Americans live together?
British Broadcasting Corporation;  (2016). https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-35255835</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunsmuir L. Many Americans have no friends of another race: poll. New York: Reuters;  (2013). https://www.reuters.com/article/ususa-poll-race/many-americans-have-no-friends-of-another-race-poll-idUSBRE97704320130808</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen D-Y, Kenney D, Chin C-V, Tavares AH, Khan N, Conway HL, et al. Role of spike in the pathogenic, antigenic behavior of SARS-CoV-2 BA.1 Omicron. bioRxiv (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV. A clinical case definition of post-covid-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. (2022) 22(4):e102&#x2013;7. 10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control, Prevention (CDC). Long COVID or post-COVID conditions. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html (Accessed November 7, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Defining adult overweight &amp; obesity. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/obesity/basics/adult-defining.html (Accessed February 6, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Demographic Statistical Atlas of the United States&#x2014;Statistical Atlas. Available from: https://statisticalatlas.com/state/Pennsylvania/Age-and-Sex (Accessed: July 20, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali RN, Rubin H, Sarkar S. Countering the potential re-emergence of a deadly infectious disease&#x2014;information warfare, identifying strategic threats, launching countermeasures. PLoS One. (2021) 16(8):e0256014. 10.1371/journal.pone.0256014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0256014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8378755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34415941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolloni A, Poletto C, Ramasco JJ, Jensen P, Colizza V. Metapopulation epidemic models with heterogeneous mixing, travel behaviour. Theor Biol Medical Model. (2014) 11(1):3. 10.1186/1742-4682-11-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1742-4682-11-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3909360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24418011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colizza V, Vespignani A. Epidemic modeling in metapopulation systems with heterogeneous coupling pattern: theory, simulations. J Theor Biol. (2008) 251(3):450&#x2013;67. 10.1016/j.jtbi.2007.11.028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtbi.2007.11.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18222487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogilvy Kermack W, McKendrick AG. A contribution to the mathematical theory of epidemics. Proc R Soc Lond A. (1927) 115(772):700&#x2013;21. 10.1098/rspa.1927.0118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rspa.1927.0118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshghi S, Preciado VM, Sarkar S, Venkatesh SS, Zhao Q, D&#x2019;Souza R, et al. Spread, then target, and advertise in waves: optimal budget allocation across advertising channels. IEEE Trans Netw Sci Eng. (2018) 7(2):750&#x2013;63. 10.1109/TNSE.2018.2873281</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSE.2018.2873281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Sarkar S, Venkatesh SS, Smirti Ryerson M, Starobinski D. An epidemiological diffusion framework for vehicular messaging in general transportation networks. Trans Res B Methodol. (2020) 131:160&#x2013;90. 10.1016/j.trb.2019.11.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trb.2019.11.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiss IZ, Miller JS, Simon P. Mathematics of epidemics on networks: from exact to approximate models. Springer;  (2017). https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0%2C39&amp;q=Mathematics+of+Epidemics+on+Networks%3AFrom+Exact+to+Approximate+Models&amp;btnG=</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Beusekom M. Two or 3 vaccine doses may cut risk of long COVID. Center for Infectious Disease Research &amp; Policy. Available from: https://www.cidrap.umn.edu/two-or-3-vaccine-doses-may-cut-risk-long-covid (Accessed January 7, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azzolini E, Levi R, Sarti R, Pozzi C, Mollura M, Mantovani A, et al. Association between BNT162b2 vaccination and long COVID after infections not requiring hospitalization in health care workers. JAMA. (2022) 328(7):676&#x2013;8. 10.1001/jama.2022.11691</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.11691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9250078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35796131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghadas SM, Vilches TN, Zhang K, Wells CR, Shoukat A, Singer BH, et al. The impact of vaccination on coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) outbreaks in the United States. Clin Infect Dis. (2021) 73(12):2257&#x2013;64. 10.1093/cid/ciab079</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33515252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). COVID-19&#x2014;frequently asked questions about COVID-19 vaccination. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/faq.html (Accessed January 10, 2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>