<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38900060</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>One- and Two-year Multidisciplinary Follow-Up of MIS-C at a Tertiary Hospital: A Retrospective Cohort Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>980</StartPage><EndPage>986</EndPage><MedlinePgn>980-986</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000004430</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Although 6-month follow-up of patients with multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) was reassuring, there is scant data on long-term sequelae, including whether changing variants affect clinical severity and outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Children (&lt;18 years of age) admitted to Great Ormond Street Hospital between April 4, 2020, and January 2023, meeting diagnostic criteria for MIS-C were included. Admission and follow-up data were categorized by the predominant SARS-CoV-2 circulating variant in the United Kingdom.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">One hundred and sixty children [median age, 10.1 (interquartile range, 7.9-12.6) years] were included. There was no difference in the time of symptom onset to diagnosis between waves ( P =0.23) or hospitalization days across all waves ( P =0.32). Inflammatory markers were normal for up to 2 years in all patients except one. Eleven patients (6.9%) remain in follow-up: cardiology (n=5), gastroenterology (n=5) and nephrology (n=1). The main self-reported symptoms at 2 years were abdominal pain (n=5) and myalgia (n=2). Fatigue was present in approximately a quarter of patients at admission; this reduced to 14 (9%), (2%) and 1 (2%) at 6-month, 1-year and 2-year follow-ups, respectively. Chronic fatigue or long-COVID symptomatology was rare (n=1) even with high rates of concurrent Epstein-Barr virus positivity (49/134). All patients had sustained neurological recovery with no new neurological pathology observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients with MIS-C have a sustained recovery, which is reassuring for positive long-term outcomes. Across waves, time from symptom onset to diagnosis and treatment, symptomatology and length of stay were similar. Sustained recovery is reassuring for clinicians and parents alike. Differentiating long-COVID symptomatology from that of MIS-C is important in formulating an individualized treatment plan.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Sarah May</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From theDepartment of Paediatric Infectious Diseases, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Penner</LastName><ForeName>Justin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7911-3272</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From theDepartment of Paediatric Infectious Diseases, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Issitt</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Great Ormond Street Hospital and Great Ormond Street Institute of Child Health and NIHR GOSH Biomedical Research Centre, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Cardiovascular Science, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kmentt</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From theDepartment of Paediatric Infectious Diseases, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grant</LastName><ForeName>Karlie</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From theDepartment of Paediatric Infectious Diseases, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandey</LastName><ForeName>Ashwin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From theDepartment of Paediatric Infectious Diseases, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Champsas</LastName><ForeName>Dimitrios</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric Neurology, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdel-Mannan</LastName><ForeName>Omar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric Neurology, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queen Square MS Centre, UCL Queen Square Institute of Neurology, Faculty of Brain Sciences, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maillard</LastName><ForeName>Sue</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation Services, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McKenzie</LastName><ForeName>Kim</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation Services, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Golding</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychology and Mental Health Services at Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kucera</LastName><ForeName>Filip</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric Cardiology, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hacohen</LastName><ForeName>Yael</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric Neurology, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queen Square MS Centre, UCL Queen Square Institute of Neurology, Faculty of Brain Sciences, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moshal</LastName><ForeName>Karyn</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From theDepartment of Paediatric Infectious Diseases, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCL Great Ormond Street Institute of Child Health, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C000705967">pediatric multisystem inflammatory disease, COVID-19 related</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062606" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tertiary Care Centers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018746" MajorTopicYN="Y">Systemic Inflammatory Response Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006113" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United Kingdom</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006760" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitalization</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38900060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000004430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-202410000-00012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dufort EM, Koumans EH, Chow EJ, et al.; New York State and Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Multisystem Inflammatory Syndrome in Children Investigation Team. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children in New York State. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:347&#x2013;358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorg AL, Hufnagel M, Doenhardt M, et al. Risk for severe outcomes of COVID-19 and PIMS-TS in children with SARS-CoV-2 infection in Germany. Eur J Pediatr. 2022;181:3635&#x2013;3643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dionne A, Son MBF, Randolph AG. An update on multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children related to SARS-CoV-2. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2022;41:e6&#x2013;e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoste L, Van Paemel R, Haerynck F. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children related to COVID-19: a systematic review. Eur J Pediatr. 2021;180:2019&#x2013;2034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter MJ, Fish M, Jennings A, et al. Peripheral immunophenotypes in children with multisystem inflammatory syndrome associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med. 2020;26:1701&#x2013;1707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penner J, Abdel-Mannan O, Grant K, et al.; GOSH PIMS-TS MDT Group. 6-month multidisciplinary follow-up and outcomes of patients with paediatric inflammatory multisystem syndrome (PIMS-TS) at a UK tertiary paediatric hospital: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2021;5:473&#x2013;482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Mannan O, Eyre M, Lobel U, et al. Neurologic and radiographic findings associated with COVID-19 infection in children. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:1440&#x2013;1445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittaker E, Bamford A, Kenny J, et al.; PIMS-TS Study Group and EUCLIDS and PERFORM Consortia. Clinical characteristics of 58 children with a pediatric inflammatory multisystem syndrome temporally associated with SARS-CoV-2. JAMA. 2020;324:259&#x2013;269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L, Tang K, Irfan O, et al. Epidemiology, clinical features, and outcomes of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) and adolescents-a live systematic review and meta-analysis. Curr Pediatr Rep. 2022;10:19&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies P, du Pre P, Lillie J, et al. One-year outcomes of critical care patients post-COVID-19 multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children. JAMA Pediatr. 2021;175:1281&#x2013;1283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otten MH, Buysse CMP, Buddingh EP, et al. Neurocognitive, psychosocial, and quality of life outcomes after multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children admitted to the PICU. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2023;24:289&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousaf AR, Cortese MM, Taylor AW, et al.; MIS-C Investigation Authorship Group. Reported cases of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children aged 12-20 years in the USA who received a COVID-19 vaccine, December, 2020, through August, 2021: a surveillance investigation. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2022;6:303&#x2013;312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zambrano LD, Newhams MM, Olson SM, et al.; Overcoming COVID-19 Investigators. BNT162b2 mRNA vaccination against coronavirus disease 2019 is associated with a decreased likelihood of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children aged 5-18 Years-United States, July 2021-April 2022. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76:e90&#x2013;e100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nygaard U, Holm M, Hartling UB, et al. Incidence and clinical phenotype of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children after infection with the SARS-CoV-2 delta variant by vaccination status: a Danish nationwide prospective cohort study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2022;6:459&#x2013;465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller AD, Yousaf AR, Bornstein E, et al. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children during severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) delta and omicron variant circulation-United States, July 2021-January 2022. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;75(Suppl 2):S303&#x2013;S307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez L, Burgner D, Glover C, et al.; Australian Vasculitis Working Group and Paediatric Active Enhanced Disease Surveillance (PAEDS) network. Lower risk of Multi-system inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) with the omicron variant. Lancet Reg Health West Pac. 2022;27:100604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen JM, Carter MJ, Cheung CR, et al.; Evelina Paediatric Inflammatory Multisystem Syndrome Temporally related to SARS-CoV-2 (PIMS-TS) Study Group. Lower risk of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children with the delta and omicron variants of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76:e518&#x2013;e521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therneau TM, Grambsch PM. Modeling Survival Data: Extending the Cox Model. Springer New York; 2013:7&#x2013;283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates D, M&#xe4;chler M, Bolker B, et al. Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4. J Stat Softw. 2015;67:1&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farooqi KM, Chan A, Weller RJ, et al.; Columbia University Interdisciplinary MIS-C Follow-up Program and the CUIMC Pediatric/Adult Congenital Heart Research Collaborative. Longitudinal outcomes for multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children. Pediatrics. 2021;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrindle BW, Rowley AH, Newburger JW, et al.; American Heart Association Rheumatic Fever, Endocarditis, and Kawasaki Disease Committee of the Council on Cardiovascular Disease in the Young; Council on Cardiovascular and Stroke Nursing; Council on Cardiovascular Surgery and Anesthesia; and Council on Epidemiology and Prevention. Diagnosis, treatment, and long-term management of Kawasaki disease: a scientific statement for health professionals from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2017;135:e927&#x2013;e999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty A, Johnson JN, Spagnoli J, et al. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children associated with COVID-19 using an institution based algorithm. Pediatr Cardiol. 2023;44:367&#x2013;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapoor R, Chandra T, Singh CP, et al. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) related to SARS-CoV-2 and 1-year follow-up. Indian J Pediatr. 2022;90:1008&#x2013;1012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fremed MA, Farooqi KM. Longitudinal outcomes and monitoring of patients with multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children. Front Pediatr. 2022;10:820229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahn R, Berg S, Berntson L, et al. Population-based study of multisystem inflammatory syndrome associated with COVID-19 found that 36% of children had persistent symptoms. Acta Paediatr. 2022;111:354&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Ayuzo Del Valle NC, et al. Long-COVID in children and adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Sci Rep. 2022;12:9950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng YB, Zeng N, Yuan K, et al. Prevalence and risk factor for long COVID in children and adolescents: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Public Health. 2023;16:660&#x2013;672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messiah SE, Xie L, Mathew MS, et al. Comparison of long-term complications of COVID-19 illness among a diverse sample of children by MIS-C status. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:13382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz BZ, Shiraishi Y, Mears CJ, et al. Chronic fatigue syndrome after infectious mononucleosis in adolescents. Pediatrics. 2009;124:189&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olivotto S, Basso E, Lavatelli R, et al. Acute encephalitis in pediatric multisystem inflammatory syndrome associated with COVID-19. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2021;34:84&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddux AB, Young CC, Kucukak S, et al.; Overcoming COVID-19 Investigators. Risk factors for health impairments in children after hospitalization for acute COVID-19 or MIS-C. Front Pediatr. 2023;11:1260372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theberath M, Bauer D, Chen W, et al. Effects of COVID-19 pandemic on mental health of children and adolescents: a systematic review of survey studies. SAGE Open Med. 2022;10:20503121221086712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rollins CK, Calderon J, Wypij D, et al.; Overcoming COVID-19 Investigators. Neurological and psychological sequelae associated with multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6:e2324369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarselli V, Calderoni D, Terrinoni A, et al. A neuropsychiatric assessment of children with previous SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Clin Med. 2023;12:3917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman A, Ovin F, Moshal K, et al. Responding to the psychological needs of children following admission to paediatric Intensive Care for paediatric inflammatory multisystem syndrome: a narrative therapy based photography workshop. Clin Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2023;28:997&#x2013;1011.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>