<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35383586</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3686</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2022 May-Jun 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of therapeutics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Scoping Review of Pharmacological Management of Postacute Sequelae of Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 Infection in 2021.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e305</StartPage><EndPage>e321</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e305-e321</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MJT.0000000000001486</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Postacute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection (PASC), or long-COVID, are signs and symptoms that persist after the acute phase of Coronavirus disease 2019 infection has passed. PASC is newly recognized, and research is ongoing to answer questions about pathology, symptoms, diagnosis, and optimal treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AREAS OF UNCERTAINTY" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Use of pharmacologic treatment for symptoms of PASC is currently evolving. This scoping review aims to assess medical literature for any evidence supporting or refuting use of any medications to specifically treat PASC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="METHODS">PubMed, EMBASE, Web of Science, and gray literature sources were searched for any study of medication use for PASC. Studies were included if they described medication use in patients with PASC. There were no exclusion criteria based on study type or if results were reported. Studies were divided into completed works and ongoing research.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fifty-two records were included in final analysis from an initial 3524 records found, including 2 randomized controlled trials, 7 prospective, open-label or observational studies, 14 case reports or case series, 1 survey, 1 correspondence, 1 retrospective analysis, and 26 studies in progress. Seven of the 26 completed works investigate ivabradine or beta-blockers, whereas 7 investigate local or systemic corticosteroids. Three investigate multi-ingredient nutritional supplements. The other 9 completed works as well as the 26 studies in progress investigate a wide variety of other treatments including drugs in development, drugs used for other conditions, herbals, supplements, and vitamins.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">There is limited, but evolving, literature on medication treatment for PASC. Providers who opt to use pharmacologic therapy for PASC need to be vigilant in their knowledge of these evolving data.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carson</LastName><ForeName>Erin</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy Practice, College of Pharmacy, University of Illinois at Chicago, Rockford, IL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hemenway</LastName><ForeName>Alice N</ForeName><Initials>AN</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9441347</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1075-2765</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000093485" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19 Drug Treatment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35383586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MJT.0000000000001486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00045391-990000000-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Rapid Guideline: Managing the Long-Term Effects of COVID-19. London, England: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (UK); 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID. Let patients help define long-lasting COVID symptoms. Nature. 2020;586:170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, et al. Defining post-COVID symptoms (Post-Acute COVID, long COVID, persistent post-COVID): an integrative classification. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:2621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Living with Covid19. National Institute for Health Research; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long-haul COVID-19: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis. 2021;53:737&#x2013;754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT, et al. Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up; results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax. 2021;76:399&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirulli ET, et al. Long-term COVID-19 symptoms in a large unselected population. medRxiv. 2020. doi: 10.07.20208702</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.07.20208702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li X, Geng D, et al. Cerebral micro-structural changes in COVID-19 patients - an MRI-based 3-month follow-up study. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, et al. Long-COVID: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID-19. Thorax. 2021;76:396&#x2013;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazato Y, Morioka S, Tsuzuki S, et al. Prolonged and late-onset symptoms of coronavirus disease 2019. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2020;7:ofaa507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen MS, et al. Long COVID in the Faroe Islands - a longitudinal study among nonhospitalized patients. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e4058&#x2013;e4063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah AS, et al. A prospective study of 12-week respiratory outcomes in COVID-19-related hospitalisations. Thorax. 2021;76:402&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sollini M, et al. Vasculitis changes in COVID-19 survivors with persistent symptoms: an [(18)F]FDG-PET/CT study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48:1460&#x2013;1466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, et al. Persistent symptoms 1.5-6 months after COVID-19 in non-hospitalised subjects: a population-based cohort study. Thorax. 2021;76:405&#x2013;407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, et al. Attributes and predictors of Long-COVID: analysis of COVID cases and their symptoms collected by the Covid Symptoms Study App. medRxiv. 2020. doi: 10.19.20214494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19.20214494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, et al. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0240784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Borst B, Peters JB, Brink M, et al. Comprehensive health assessment three months after recovery from acute COVID-19. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e1089&#x2013;e1098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong AW, Shah AS, Johnston JC, et al. Patient-reported outcome measures after COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2020;56:200&#x2013;276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao YM, Shang YM, Song WB, et al. Follow-up study of the pulmonary function and related physiological characteristics of COVID-19 survivors three months after recovery. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A'Court C, et al. Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020;370:m3026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594:259&#x2013;264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Wamil M, Kapur S, et al. Multi-organ impairment in low-risk individuals with long COVID. Health Policy. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludvigsson JF. Case report and systematic review suggest that children may experience similar long&#x2010;term effects to adults after clinical COVID&#x2010;19. Acta Paediatr. 2021;110:914&#x2013;921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oronsky B, Larson C, Hammond TC, et al. A review of persistent post-covid syndrome(Ppcs). Clinic Rev Allerg Immunol. 2021;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afrin LB, Weinstock LB, Molderings GJ. Covid-19 hyperinflammation and post-Covid-19 illness may be rooted in mast cell activation syndrome. Int J Infect Dis. 2020;100:327&#x2013;332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The American Autonomic Society, Raj SR, Arnold AC, Barboi A, et al. Long-COVID postural tachycardia syndrome: an American Autonomic Society statement. Clin Auton Res. 2021;31:365&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers JP, Chesney E, Oliver D, et al. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: a systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;7:611&#x2013;627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dressing A, Bormann T, Blazhenets G, et al. Neuropsychological profiles and cerebral glucose metabolism in neurocognitive long COVID-syndrome. J Nucl Med. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low RN, Low RJ, Akrami A. A Cytokine-Based Model for the Pathophysiology of Long COVID Symptoms: Open Science Framework; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troyer EA, Kohn JN, Hong S. Are we facing a crashing wave of neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19? Neuropsychiatric symptoms and potential immunologic mechanisms. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:34&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs JJL. Persistent SARS-2 infections contribute to long COVID-19. Med Hypotheses. 2021;149:110538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramer WM, Rethlefsen ML, Kleijnen J, et al. Optimal database combinations for literature searches in systematic reviews: a prospective exploratory study. Syst Rev. 2017;6:245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadhav KP, Jariwala PV. Ivabradine versus carvedilol in the management of palpitation with sinus tachycardia among recovered COVID-19 patients. J Cardiol Cardiovasc Med. 2020;5:176&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanjwal K, Jamal S, Kichloo A, et al. New-onset postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome following coronavirus disease 2019 infection. J Innov Card Rhythm Manage. 2020;11:4302&#x2013;4304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miglis MG, Prieto T, Shaik R, et al. A case report of postural tachycardia syndrome after COVID-19. Clin Auton Res. 2020;30:449&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podzolkov VI, Bragina AE, Tarzimanova AI, et al. Post-covid syndrome and tachycardia: theoretical base and treatment experience. Rational Pharmacotherapy Cardiol. 2021;17:256&#x2013;262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Sullivan JS, Lyne A, Vaughan CJ. COVID-19-induced postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome treated with ivabradine. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14:e243585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson M, St&#xe5;hlberg M, Runold M, et al. Long-haul post&#x2013;covid-19 symptoms presenting as a variant of postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. JACC Case Rep. 2021;3:573&#x2013;580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S, Whitelaw S. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (Pots) and other autonomic disorders after COVID-19 infection: a case series of 20 patients. Immunol Res. 2021;69:205&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaira LA, Hopkins C, Petrocelli M, et al. Efficacy of corticosteroid therapy in the treatment of long- lasting olfactory disorders in COVID-19 patients. Rhin. 2021;59:21&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelalim AA, Mohamady AA, Elsayed RA, et al. Corticosteroid nasal spray for recovery of smell sensation in COVID-19 patients: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Otolaryngol Head Neck Med Surg. 2021;42:102884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touisserkani SK, Ayatollahi A. Oral corticosteroid relieves post-covid-19 anosmia in a 35-year-old patient. Case Rep Otolaryngol. 2020;2020:5892047&#x2013;5892052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myall KJ, Mukherjee B, Castanheira AM, et al. Persistent post&#x2013;covid-19 interstitial lung disease. An observational study of corticosteroid treatment. Ann Amer Thorac Soc. 2021;18:799&#x2013;806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utero-Rico A, Ruiz-Ruigomez M, Laguna-Goya R, et al. A short corticosteroid course reduces symptoms and immunological alterations underlying long-COVID. Biomedicines. 2021;9:1540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayat P, Burza A, Habeeb C. Hypocortisolism in a patient with covid-19: a case report and discussion on management. Chest. 2021;160:A715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathi A, Jadhav SB, Shah N. A randomized controlled trial of the efficacy of systemic enzymes and probiotics in the resolution of post-covid fatigue. Medicines (Basel). 2021;8:47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossato MS, Brilli E, Ferri N, et al. Observational study on the benefit of a nutritional supplement, supporting immune function and energy metabolism, on chronic fatigue associated with the SARS-CoV-2 post-infection progress. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2021;46:510&#x2013;518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belcaro G, Cornelli U, Cesarone MR, et al. Preventative effects of Pycnogenol &#xae; on cardiovascular risk factors (including endothelial function) and microcirculation in subjects recovering from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Minerva Med. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel N, Goyal N, Nagaraja R, et al. Systemic corticosteroids for management of &#x2018;long-COVID&#x2019;: an evaluation after 3 months of treatment. Monaldi Arch Chest Dis. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hohberger B, Harrer T, Mardin C, et al. Case report: neutralization of autoantibodies targeting G-protein-coupled receptors improves capillary impairment and fatigue symptoms after COVID-19 infection. Front Med. 2021;8:754&#x2013;667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitrani MI, Bellio MA, Meglin A, et al. Treatment of a COVID-19 long hauler with an amniotic fluid-derived extracellular vesicle biologic. Respir Med Case Rep. 2021;34:101502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P, Tahmasebi N, Gant V, et al. Long COVID following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: characteristic T cell alterations and response to antihistamines. J Investig Med. 2022;70:61&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold D, Milne A, Samms E, et al. Are vaccines safe in patients with long COVID? A prospective observational study. Medrxiv. 2021. Available at: https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.03.11.21253225v3.full.pdf. Accessed December 20, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acanfora D, Acanfora C, Ciccone MM, et al. The cross-talk between thrombosis and inflammatory storm in acute and long-COVID-19: therapeutic targets and clinical cases. Viruses. 2021;13:1904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinoso-Arija R, Lopez-Ramirez C, Jiminez-Ruis JA, et al. Effectiveness of aprepitant in post-acute COVID19 syndrome. Clin Case Rep. 2021;9:eo4646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jania C. The treatment of long COVID with Chinese Medicine: a case report. J Chin Med. 2021;127:17&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleh A, Jung R, Tonner S, et al. Post-coronavirus disease 2019 polyneuropathy with significant response to immunoglobulin therapy: a case report. J Med Case Reports. 2021;15:547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, Bunker CB, Ciurtin C, et al. Chilblain-like acral+ lesions in long COVID-19: management and implications for understanding microangiopathy. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordi Gol i Gurina Foundation. Efficacy of montelukast in mild-moderate respiratory symptoms in patients with long-COVID-19: (E-SPERANZA). Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04695704. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLM identifier: NCT04695704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Northwell Health. Pi-Co-Li (pulmonary COVID-19 study). Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04782700. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLM identifier: NCT04782700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackensack Meridian Health. Post-acute sequelae of Cornoavirus-19 (COVID-19) with dyspnea on exertion and associated tachycardia treatment study (PEACE). Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05096884. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT05096884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The George Institute. Statin Treatment for COVID-19 to optimize neurological recovery (STRONGER). Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04904536. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04904536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brain and Cognition Discovery Foundation. Vortioxetine for post-COVID-19 syndrome. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05047952. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT05047952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IMMUNOe Research Centers. Study to evaluate the benefit of Ruconest in improving neurological symptoms in post COVID-19 infection. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLM identifier: NCT04705831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PureTech. LYT-100 in post-acute COVID-19 respiratory disease. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04652518. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLM identifier: NCT04652518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AgelessRX. Pilot study into the use of metformin and LDN for patients with COVID-19. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04604678. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04604678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AgelessRX. Pilot study into LDN and NAD+ for treatment of patients with post-COVID-19 syndrome. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04604704. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLM identifier: NCT04604704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cytodyn Inc. COVID-19 long-haulers study. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04678830. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLM identifier: NCT04678830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ampio pharmaceuticals inc. A study to evaluate ampion in patients with prolonged respiratory symptoms due to COVID-19 (long COVID). Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04880161. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04880161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cellular sciences inc. Effects of sodium pyruvate nasal spray in COVID-19 long haulers. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871815. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04871815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaleido Biosciences. An Observational Clinical Study to Evaluate COVID-19 Symptoms in &#x201c;Long Hauler&#x201d; Patients Who ParticiAU16 pated in K031-120 or K032-120. Available at: https://clinicaltrials. gov/ct2/show/NCT04814914. NLB identifier: NCT04814914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resolve Therapeutics. Phase 2 study of RSLV-132 in subjects with long COVID. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04944121. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04944121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SolAeroMed inc. Safety, tolerability, and efficacy of S-1226 in post-COVID-19 subjects with persistent respiratory symptoms. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04949386. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04949386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Direct biologics LLC. ExoFloTM infusion for post-acute COVID-19 and chronic post-COVID-19 syndrome. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05116761. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT05116761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorrento Therapeutics inc. Study of allogeneic adipose-derived mesenchymal stem cells to treat post-COVID-19 &#x201c;long haul&#x201d; pulmonary compromise (BR). Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04992247. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04992247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anewsha Therapeutics Inc. CBDRA60 to prevent or reduce symptoms of COVID-19 and prevention of Post-acute sequelae of SARS-COV-2 infection PASC. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04777981. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04777981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endourage LLC. Study to evaluate benefits and safety of Endourage Formula C oral drops in people with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome &#x201c;BAC-PAC&#x201d;. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04828668. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04828668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug Science UK. Feasibility of cannabidiol for the treatment of long COVID. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04997395. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04997395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aarhus University Hospital. Coenzyme Q10 as treatment for long term COVID-19 (QVID). Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04960215. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackensack Meridian Health. Feasibility pilot clinical trial of omega-3 supplement vs placebo for post-COVID-19 recovery among health care workers. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05121766. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT05121766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stichting O&amp;O Franciscus Gasthius &amp; Vleitland. Lactoferrin in the treatment of long COVID. Available at: https://www.trialregister.nl/trial/9742. Accessed December 3, 2021. Netherlands trial register identifier: NL9742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massachusetts General Hospital. Clinical trial of niagen to examine recovery in people with persistent cognitive and physical symptoms after COVID-19 illness (long-COVID). Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04809974. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04809974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>All Natural Medicine Clinic, LLC. Recovering damaged cells for sequelae caused by COVID-19, SARS-CoV-2. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04846010. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04846010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swedish Herbal Institute AB. Efficacy of adaptogens in patients with long COVID-19. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04795557. Accessed December 3, 2021. NLB identifier: NCT04795557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheldon RS, Grubb BP, Olshansky B, et al. 2015 heart rhythm society expert consensus statement on the diagnosis and treatment of postural tachycardia syndrome, inappropriate sinus tachycardia, and vasovagal syncope. Heart Rhythm. 2015;12:e41&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taub PR, Zadourian A, Lo HC, et al. Randomized trial of ivabradine in patients with hyperadrenergic postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;77:861&#x2013;871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee on the Diagnostic Criteria for Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome, Board on the Health of Select Populations, Institute of Medicine. Beyond Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: Redefining an Illness. Washington, DC: National Academies Press (US); 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poole-Wright K, Gaughran F, Evans R, et al. Fatigue Outcomes Following Coronavirus or Influenza Virus Infection: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Infectious Diseases (except HIV/AIDS); 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das KM, Lee EY, Singh R, et al. Follow-up chest radiographic findings in patients with MERS-CoV after recovery. Indian J Radiol Imaging. 2017;27:342&#x2013;349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam MH, Wing YK, Yu MW, et al. Mental morbidities and chronic fatigue in severe acute respiratory syndrome survivors: long-term follow-up. Arch Intern Med. 2009;169:2142&#x2013;2147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngai JC, Ko FW, Ng SS, et al. The long-term impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome on pulmonary function, exercise capacity and health status. Respirology. 2010;15:543&#x2013;550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siso-Almirall A, Brito-Zeron P, Conangla Ferrin L, et al. Long covid-19: proposed primary care clinical guidelines for diagnosis and disease management. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:4350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng A, Shi E, Herman E, et al. Clinical guidelines: long COVID-19. OHSU. Available at: https://www.ohsu.edu/sites/default/files/2021-04/Long-COVID-19-Clinical-Guidelines-English-April-21-2021.pdf. Accessed December 3, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marik P. An overview of the MATH+, I-MASK+, and I-RECOVER protocols: a guide to the management of COVID-19. FLCCC alliance. Available at: https://covid19criticalcare.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/FLCCC-Protocols-%E2%80%93-A-Guide-to-the-Management-of-COVID-19.pdf. Accessed December 3, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera JE, Niehaus WN, Whiteson J, et al. Multidisciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of fatigue in postacute sequelae of SARS-COV-2 infection (PASC) patients. PMR. 2021;13:1027&#x2013;1043.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>