<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37889567</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-0237</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of thoracic imaging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Thorac Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Functional Impairment in Small Airways Associated With the Breathlessness Symptoms in Long-Coronavirus Disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>79</StartPage><EndPage>85</EndPage><MedlinePgn>79-85</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/RTI.0000000000000748</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to determine the association between functional impairment in small airways and symptoms of dyspnea in patients with Long-coronavirus disease (COVID), using imaging and computational modeling analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Thirty-four patients with Long-COVID underwent thoracic computed tomography and hyperpolarized Xenon-129 magnetic resonance imaging (HP Xe MRI) scans. Twenty-two answered dyspnea-12 questionnaires. We used a computed tomography-based full-scale airway network (FAN) flow model to simulate pulmonary ventilation. The ventilation distribution projected on a coronal plane and the percentage lobar ventilation modeled in the FAN model were compared with the HP Xe MRI data. To assess the ventilation heterogeneity in small airways, we calculated the fractal dimensions of the impaired ventilation regions in the HP Xe MRI and FAN models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The ventilation distribution projected on a coronal plane showed an excellent resemblance between HP Xe MRI scans and FAN models (structure similarity index: 0.87 &#xb1; 0.04). In both the image and the model, the existence of large clustered ventilation defects was not identifiable regardless of dyspnea severity. The percentage lobar ventilation of the HP Xe MRI and FAN model showed a strong correlation (&#x3c1; = 0.63, P &lt; 0.001). The difference in the fractal dimension of impaired ventilation zones between the low and high dyspnea-12 score groups was significant (HP Xe MRI: 1.97 [1.89 to 2.04] and 2.08 [2.06 to 2.14], P = 0.005; FAN: 2.60 [2.59 to 2.64] and 2.64 [2.63 to 2.65], P = 0.056).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study has identified a potential association of small airway functional impairment with breathlessness in Long-COVID, using fractal analysis of HP Xe MRI scans and FAN models.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Minsuok</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical, Electrical, and Manufacturing Engineering, Loughborough University, Loughborough.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hwang</LastName><ForeName>Jeongeun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Engineering Science, Institute of Biomedical Engineering, Oxford e-Research Centre.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical IT Engineering, Soonchunhyang University, Chungcheonnam-do.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grist</LastName><ForeName>James T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Anatomy, and Genetics.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oxford Centre for Clinical MR Research, John Radcliffe Hospital, Oxford University Hospitals NHS Trust, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abueid</LastName><ForeName>Gabriele</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoon</LastName><ForeName>Soon Ho</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grau</LastName><ForeName>Vicente</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Department of Internal Medicine, Korea University College of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fraser</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oxford Interstitial Lung Disease Service, The Churchill Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gleeson</LastName><ForeName>Fergus V</ForeName><Initials>FV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, University of Oxford.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Thorac Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8606160</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0883-5993</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014979">Xenon Isotopes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014979" MajorTopicYN="Y">Xenon Isotopes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012119" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004417" MajorTopicYN="N">Dyspnea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>J.H. has received the National Research Foundation of Korea grant funded by the Korean government (#NRF-2019R1I1A1A01063383). The remaining authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37889567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RTI.0000000000000748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005382-202403000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xie J, Covassin N, Fan ZY, et al. Association between hypoxemia and mortality in patients with COVID-19. Mayo Clin Proc. 2020;95:1138&#x2013;1147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callard F, Perego E. How and why patients made long COVID. Soc Sci Med. 2021;268:113426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Rio C, Collins LF, Malani P. Long-term health consequences of COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:1723&#x2013;1724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farr E, Wolfe AR, Deshmukh S, et al. Diaphragm dysfunction in sever COVID-19 as determined by neuromuscular ultrasound. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2022;8:1745&#x2013;1749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, et al. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 2021;18:e1003773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, et al. Long-COVID mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buttery S, Philip KEJ, Williams P, et al. Patient symptoms and experience following COVID-19: results from a UK-wide survey. BMJ Open Respir Res. 2021;8:e001075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carfi A, Bernabei R, Landi F, et al. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkinson NS, Jenkins G, Hart N. COVID-19 and what comes after? Thorax. 2021;76:324&#x2013;325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93:1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doganay O, Chen M, Matin T, et al. Magnetic resonance imaging of the time course of hyperpolarized (129)Xe gas exchange in the human lungs and heart. Eur Radiol. 2019;29:2283&#x2013;2292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahir BA, Van Holsbeke C, Ireland RH, et al. Comparison of CT-based lobar ventilation with He-3 MR imaging ventilation measurements. Radiology. 2016;278:585&#x2013;592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grist JT, Chen M, Collier GJ, et al. Abnormalities in dyspneic patients 3 months after COVID-19 pneumonia: preliminary results. Radiology. 2021;301:1353&#x2013;E1360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grist JT, Collier GJ, Walters H, et al. Lung abnormalities depicted with hyperpolarized xenon MRI in patients with long COVID. Radiology. 2022;305:220069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inui S, Yoon SH, Doganay O, et al. Impaired pulmonary ventilation beyond pneumonia in COVID-19: a preliminary observation. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0263158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiebler ML, Parraga G. Visualization of the small airways:what it is and why it matters. Radiology. 2019;293:674&#x2013;675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorke J, Swigris J, Russell AM, et al. Dyspnea-12 is a valid and reliable measure of breathlessness in patients with interstitial lung disease. Chest. 2011;139:159&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordas R, Lefevre C, Veeckmans B, et al. Development and analysis of patient-based complete conducting airways models. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0144105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M, Doganay O, Matin TN, et al. CT-based airway flow model to assess ventilation in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a pilot study. Radiology. 2019;293:666&#x2013;673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grassberger P. On the fractal dimension of the henon attractor. Phys Lett A; 1983;97:224&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ott E. Chaos in Dynamical Systems, 2nd ed. Cambridge University Press. 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bridges JP, Vladar EK, Huang H, et al. Respiratory epithelial cell responses to SARS-CoV-2 in COVID-19. Thorax. 2022;77:203&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdebenito S, Bessis S, Annane D, et al. COVID-19 lung pathogenesis in SARS-CoV-2 autopsy cases. Front Immunol. 2021;12:735922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenblatt EE, Butler JP, Venegas JG, et al. Pendelluft in the bronchial tree. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2014;117:979&#x2013;988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler T, Venegas JG. Self-organized patterns of airway narrowing. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2011;110:1482&#x2013;1486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwee TC, Kwee RM. Chest CT in COVID-19: what the radiologist needs to know. Radiographics. 2020;40:1848&#x2013;1865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon JJ, Heyman B, Ko JP, et al. CT of post-acute lung complications of COVID-19. Radiology. 2021;301:E383&#x2013;E395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang R, Zhu J, Zhou J, et al. Inspiratory and expiratory chest high-resolution CT: small-airway disease evaluation in patients with COVID-19. Curr Med Imaging. 2021;17:1299&#x2013;1307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooner HK, McIntosh MJ, Matheson AM, et al. ventilation defects in ever-hospitalized and never-hospitalized people with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. BMJ Open Respir Res. 2022;9:e001235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho JL, Villacreses R, Nagpal P, et al. Quantitative chest CT assessment of small airways disease in post-acute SARS-CoV-2 infection. Radiology. 2022;304:185&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>