<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38421118</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1573</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Phytotherapy research : PTR</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phytother Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID-19 gastrointestinal related disorders and traditional Chinese medicine: A network target-based approach.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2323</StartPage><EndPage>2346</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2323-2346</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ptr.8163</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The significant number of individuals impacted by the pandemic makes prolonged symptoms after COVID-19 a matter of considerable concern. These are numerous and affect multiple organ systems. According to the World Health Organization (WHO), prolonged gastrointestinal issues are a crucial part of post-COVID-19 syndrome. The resulting disruption of homeostasis underscores the need for a therapeutic approach based on compounds that can simultaneously affect more than one target/node. The present review aimed to check for nutraceuticals possessing multiple molecular mechanisms helpful in relieving Long COVID-19-specific gastrointestinal symptoms. Specific plants used in Keywords Chinese Medicine (TCM) expected to be included in the WHO Global Medical Compendium were selected based on the following criteria: (1) they are widely used in the Western world as natural remedies and complementary medicine adjuvants; (2) their import and trade are regulated by specific laws that ensure quality and safety (3) have the potential to be beneficial in alleviating intestinal issues associated with Long COVID-19. Searches were performed in PubMed, Elsevier, Google Scholar, Scopus, Science Direct, and ResearchGate up to 2023. Cinnamomum cassia, Glycyrrhiza uralensis, Magnolia officinalis, Poria cocos, Salvia miltiorrhiza, Scutellaria baicalensis, and Zingiber officinalis were identified as the most promising for their potential impact on inflammation and oxidative stress. Based on the molecular mechanisms of the phytocomplexes and isolated compounds of the considered plants, their clinical use may lead to benefits in gastrointestinal diseases associated with Long COVID-19, thanks to a multiorgan and multitarget approach.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mattioli</LastName><ForeName>Laura Beatrice</ForeName><Initials>LB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9932-6104</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy and Biotechnology, Food Chemistry and Nutraceutical Lab, Alma Mater Studiorum-University of Bologna, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frosini</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Life Sciences, University of Siena, Siena, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Corazza</LastName><ForeName>Ivan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Surgical Sciences (DIMEC), Alma Mater Studiorum-University of Bologna, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fiorino</LastName><ForeName>Sirio</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine Unit, Azienda USL, Budrio Hospital, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zippi</LastName><ForeName>Maddalena</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Gastroenterology &amp; Digestive Endoscopy, Sandro Pertini Hospital, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Micucci</LastName><ForeName>Matteo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomolecular Sciences, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Urbino "Carlo Bo", Urbino, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Budriesi</LastName><ForeName>Roberta</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8454-9740</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy and Biotechnology, Food Chemistry and Nutraceutical Lab, Alma Mater Studiorum-University of Bologna, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Phytother Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904486</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0951-418X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004365">Drugs, Chinese Herbal</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008516" MajorTopicYN="Y">Medicine, Chinese Traditional</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005767" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrointestinal Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004365" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drugs, Chinese Herbal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000093485" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Drug Treatment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastrointestinal tract</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID&#x2010;19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multitarget approach</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phytotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post&#x2010;acute COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">traditional Chinese medicine</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38421118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.8163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Agrawal, A., Sharma, A., Mathur, M., Sharma, A., Modi, G., &amp; Patel, T. (2023). Perspective toward complementary &amp; alternative medicines in the prevention of COVID&#x2010;19 infection. Indian Journal of Community Medicine: Official Publication of Indian Association of Preventive &amp; Social Medicine, 48(3), 401&#x2013;406. https://doi.org/10.4103/ijcm.ijcm_282_22</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, S. R., Rabbee, M. F., Roy, A., Chowdhury, R., Banik, A., Kubra, K., Hassan Chowdhury, M. M., &amp; Baek, K.&#x2010;H. (2021). Therapeutic promises of medicinal plants in Bangladesh and their bioactive compounds against ulcers and inflammatory diseases. Plants, 10(7), 7. https://doi.org/10.3390/plants10071348</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajayi, B. O., Adedara, I. A., &amp; Farombi, E. O. (2015). Pharmacological activity of 6&#x2010;gingerol in dextran sulphate sodium&#x2010;induced ulcerative colitis in BALB/c mice. Phytotherapy Research, 29(4), 566&#x2013;572. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.5286</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajayi, B. O., Adedara, I. A., &amp; Farombi, E. O. (2018). Protective mechanisms of 6&#x2010;gingerol in dextran sulfate sodium&#x2010;induced chronic ulcerative colitis in mice. Human &amp; Experimental Toxicology, 37(10), 1054&#x2013;1068. https://doi.org/10.1177/0960327117751235</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews, P. L. R., Cai, W., Rudd, J. A., &amp; Sanger, G. J. (2021). COVID&#x2010;19, nausea, and vomiting. Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, 36(3), 646&#x2013;656. https://doi.org/10.1111/jgh.15261</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arru, L., Mussi, F., Forti, L., &amp; Buschini, A. (2021). Biological effect of different spinach extracts in comparison with the individual components of the phytocomplex. Food, 10(2), 382. https://doi.org/10.3390/foods10020382</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment. (2009). Characterization of tanshinones with quinone reductase induction activity from radix Salvia miltiorrhiza by liquid chromatography/tandem mass spectrometry. https://hero.epa.gov/hero/index.cfm/reference/details/reference_id/8319370</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atta, A. H., &amp; Mouneir, S. M. (2005). Evaluation of some medicinal plant extracts for antidiarrhoeal activity. Phytotherapy Research, 19(6), 481&#x2013;485. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.1639</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attilio, D. (2022). The Chinese herbal formula Qing Jin Yi Qi Wan improves long COVID&#x2010;19 symptoms. Acupuncture Times. https://www.acupuncturetimes.com/the-chinese-herbal-formula-qing-jin-yi-qi-wan-improves-long-covid-19-symptoms/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett, R. N., &amp; Wallsgrove, R. M. (1994). Secondary metabolites in plant defence mechanisms. The New Phytologist, 127(4), 633. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-8137.1994.tb02968.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, Y., Zeng, M., &amp; Chen, Y.&#x2010;Z. (2021). The pharmacological mechanism of Huashi Baidu formula for the treatment of COVID&#x2010;19 by combined network pharmacology and molecular docking. Annals of Palliative Medicine, 10(4), 3895. https://doi.org/10.21037/apm-20-1759</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, W. (2020). What Do we know So far about gastrointestinal and liver injuries induced by SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 virus? Gastroenterology Research, 13(6), 225&#x2013;226. https://doi.org/10.14740/gr1350</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho, A., Alqusairi, R., Adams, A., Paul, M., Kothari, N., Peters, S., &amp; DeBenedet, A. T. (2020). SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 gastrointestinal infection causing hemorrhagic colitis: Implications for detection and transmission of COVID&#x2010;19 disease. The American Journal of Gastroenterology, 115(6), 942&#x2013;946. https://doi.org/10.14309/ajg.0000000000000667</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, K., Lo, A. C., Yeung, J. H., &amp; Woo, K. S. (1995). The effects of Danshen (Salvia miltiorrhiza) on warfarin pharmacodynamics and pharmacokinetics of warfarin enantiomers in rats. The Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmacology, 47(5), 402&#x2013;406. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.2042-7158.1995.tb05819.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, S. S.&#x2010;K., Zhao, M., Lao, L., Fong, H. H., &amp; Che, C.&#x2010;T. (2008). Magnolol and honokiol account for the anti&#x2010;spasmodic effect of Magnolia officinalis in isolated guinea pig ileum. Planta Medica, 74(4), 381&#x2013;384. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-2008-1034320</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaput, N., Lepage, P., Coutzac, C., Soularue, E., Le Roux, K., Monot, C., Boselli, L., Routier, E., Cassard, L., Collins, M., Vaysse, T., Marthey, L., Eggermont, A., Asvatourian, V., Lanoy, E., Mateus, C., Robert, C., &amp; Carbonnel, F. (2017). Baseline gut microbiota predicts clinical response and colitis in metastatic melanoma patients treated with ipilimumab. Annals of Oncology: Official Journal of the European Society for Medical Oncology, 28(6), 1368&#x2013;1379. https://doi.org/10.1093/annonc/mdx108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhari, V., Buttar, H. S., Bagwe&#x2010;Parab, S., Tuli, H. S., Vora, A., &amp; Kaur, G. (2021). Therapeutic and industrial applications of curdlan with overview on its recent patents. Frontiers in Nutrition, 8, 646988. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2021.646988</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang, H.&#x2010;C., Yang, S.&#x2010;T., Lee, K.&#x2010;C., Huang, P.&#x2010;Y., Hsu, M., &amp; Chang, H.&#x2010;H. (2012). From theory to clinic: Key components of qi deficiency in traditional Chinese medicine. Alternative Therapies in Health and Medicine, 18(6), 28&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, Y. Y., Kim, M. H., Hong, J., Kim, S.&#x2010;H., &amp; Yang, W. M. (2013). Dried ginger (Zingiber officinalis) inhibits inflammation in a lipopolysaccharide&#x2010;induced mouse model. Evidence&#x2010;Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine, 2013, 914563. https://doi.org/10.1155/2013/914563</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chunlian, W., Heyong, W., Jia, X., Jie, H., Xi, C., &amp; Gentao, L. (2014). Magnolol inhibits tumor necrosis factor&#x2010;&#x3b1;&#x2010;induced ICAM&#x2010;1 expression via suppressing NF&#x2010;&#x3ba;B and MAPK signaling pathways in human lung epithelial cells. Inflammation, 37(6), 1957&#x2013;1967. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10753-014-9928-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark, I. A. (2022). Chronic cerebral aspects of long COVID, post&#x2010;stroke syndromes and similar states share their pathogenesis and perispinal etanercept treatment logic. Pharmacology Research &amp; Perspectives, 10(2), e00926. https://doi.org/10.1002/prp2.926</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cyranoski, D. (2018). Why Chinese medicine is heading for clinics around the world. Nature, 561(7724), 7724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, Y.&#x2010;J., Wan, S.&#x2010;Y., Gong, S.&#x2010;S., Liu, J.&#x2010;C., Li, F., &amp; Kou, J.&#x2010;P. (2020). Recent advances of traditional Chinese medicine on the prevention and treatment of COVID&#x2010;19. Chinese Journal of Natural Medicines, 18(12), 889. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1875-5364(20)60031-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani, M., Dirksen, A., Taraborrelli, P., Torocastro, M., Panagopoulos, D., Sutton, R., &amp; Lim, P. B. (2021). Autonomic dysfunction in &#x201c;long COVID&#x201d;: Rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clinical Medicine, 21(1), e63&#x2013;e67. https://doi.org/10.7861/clinmed.2020-0896</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty, S. E., Guo, Y., Heath, K., Dasmari&#xf1;as, M. C., Jubilo, K. G., Samranvedhya, J., Lipsitch, M., &amp; Cohen, K. (2021). Risk of clinical sequelae after the acute phase of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection: Retrospective cohort study. BMJ (Clinical Research Ed.), 373, n1098. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n1098</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, H. E., Assaf, G. S., McCorkell, L., Wei, H., Low, R. J., Re'em, Y., Redfield, S., Austin, J. P., &amp; Akrami, A. (2021). Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine, 38, 101019. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, H. E., McCorkell, L., Vogel, J. M., &amp; Topol, E. J. (2023). Long COVID: Major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nature Reviews Microbiology, 21(3), 133&#x2013;146. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebrahim Nakhli, R., Shanker, A., Sarosiek, I., Boschman, J., Espino, K., Sigaroodi, S., Al Bayati, I., Elhanafi, S., Sadeghi, A., Sarosiek, J., Zuckerman, M. J., Rezaie, A., McCallum, R. W., Schmulson, M. J., Bashashati, A., &amp; Bashashati, M. (2022). Gastrointestinal symptoms and the severity of COVID&#x2010;19: Disorders of gut&#x2013;brain interaction are an outcome. Neurogastroenterology and Motility, 34(9), e14368. https://doi.org/10.1111/nmo.14368</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmunzer, B. J., Spitzer, R. L., Foster, L. D., Merchant, A. A., Howard, E. F., Patel, V. A., West, M. K., Qayed, E., Nustas, R., Zakaria, A., Piper, M. S., Taylor, J. R., Jaza, L., Forbes, N., Chau, M., Lara, L. F., Papachristou, G. I., Volk, M. L., Hilson, L. G., &#x2026; North American Alliance for the Study of Digestive Manifestations of COVID&#x2010;19. (2021). Digestive manifestations in patients hospitalized with coronavirus disease 2019. Clinical Gastroenterology and Hepatology: The Official Clinical Practice Journal of the American Gastroenterological Association, 19(7), 1355&#x2013;1365.e4. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cgh.2020.09.041</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elshazli, R. M., Kline, A., Elgaml, A., Aboutaleb, M. H., Salim, M. M., Omar, M., Munshi, R., Mankowski, N., Hussein, M. H., Attia, A. S., Toraih, E. A., Settin, A., Killackey, M., Fawzy, M. S., &amp; Kandil, E. (2021). Gastroenterology manifestations and COVID&#x2010;19 outcomes: A meta&#x2010;analysis of 25,252 cohorts among the first and second waves. Journal of Medical Virology, 93, 2740&#x2013;2768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erb, M., &amp; Kliebenstein, D. J. (2020). Plant secondary metabolites as defenses, regulators, and primary metabolites: The blurred functional trichotomy. Plant Physiology, 184(1), 39&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.1104/pp.20.00433</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ettorre, A., Frosali, S., Andreassi, M., &amp; Di Stefano, A. (2010). Lycopene phytocomplex, but not pure lycopene, is able to trigger apoptosis and improve the efficacy of photodynamic therapy in HL60 human leukemia cells. Experimental Biology and Medicine, 235, 1114&#x2013;1125. https://doi.org/10.1258/ebm.2010.009386</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xe4;ndriks, L. (2010). The angiotensin II type 2 receptor and the gastrointestinal tract. Journal of the Renin&#x2010;Angiotensin&#x2010;Aldosterone System, 11(1), 43&#x2013;48. https://doi.org/10.1177/1470320309347788</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fehr, A. R., &amp; Perlman, S. (2015). Coronaviruses: An overview of their replication and pathogenesis. Methods in Molecular Biology, 1282, 1&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4939-2438-7_1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, J., Guo, C., Zhu, Y., Pang, L., Yang, Z., Zou, Y., &amp; Zheng, X. (2014). Baicalin down regulates the expression of TLR4 and NFkB&#x2010;p65 in colon tissue in mice with colitis induced by dextran sulfate sodium. International Journal of Clinical and Experimental Medicine, 7(11), 4063&#x2013;4072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, X., Duan, X.&#x2010;J., Zhang, B., Sarina, Su, X.&#x2010;F., Ma, S.&#x2010;Y., Li, Y., &amp; Guo, Y.&#x2010;B. (2020). Analysis of programs and guidelines on traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) for COVID&#x2010;19 to provide suggestions for future development of TCM clinical practice guidelines. Chinese Journal of Experimental Traditional Medical Formulae, (9), 20&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontana, R., Mattioli, L. B., Biotti, G., Budriesi, R., Gotti, R., Micucci, M., Corazza, I., Marconi, P., Frosini, M., Manfredini, S., Buzzi, R., &amp; Vertuani, S. (2023). Magnolia officinalis L. bark extract and respiratory diseases: From traditional Chinese medicine to western medicine via network target. Phytotherapy Research, 37(7), 2915&#x2013;2938. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.7786</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg, M., Angus, P. W., Burrell, L. M., Herath, C., Gibson, P. R., &amp; Lubel, J. S. (2012). Review article: The pathophysiological roles of the renin&#x2010;angiotensin system in the gastrointestinal tract. Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics, 35(4), 428. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2036.2011.04971.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannos, P., &amp; Prokopidis, K. (2022). Gut dysbiosis and long COVID&#x2010;19: Feeling gutted. Journal of Medical Virology, 94(7), 2917&#x2013;2918. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.27684</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golla, R., Vuyyuru, S. K., Kante, B., Kedia, S., &amp; Ahuja, V. (2022). Disorders of gut&#x2010;brain interaction in post&#x2010;acute COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome. Postgraduate Medical Journal, 99, 834&#x2013;843. https://doi.org/10.1136/pmj-2022-141749</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gui, Y., Sun, L., Liu, R., &amp; Luo, J. (2021). Pachymic acid inhibits inflammation and cell apoptosis in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)&#x2010;induced rat model with pneumonia by regulating NF&#x2010;&#x3ba;B and MAPK pathways. Allergologia et Immunopathologia, 49(5), 87&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.15586/aei.v49i5.468</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y., Xie, J.&#x2010;P., Deng, K., Li, X., Yuan, Y., Xuan, Q., Xie, J., He, X.&#x2010;M., Wang, Q., Li, J.&#x2010;J., &amp; Luo, H.&#x2010;R. (2019). Prophylactic effects of bifidobacterium adolescentis on anxiety and depression&#x2010;like phenotypes after chronic stress: A role of the gut microbiota&#x2010;inflammation axis. Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience, 13, 126. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnbeh.2019.00126</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin, S. J., McIvor, C., Whyatt, G., Adams, A., Harvey, O., McLean, L., Walshaw, C., Kemp, S., Corrado, J., Singh, R., Collins, T., O'Connor, R. J., &amp; Sivan, M. (2021). Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID&#x2010;19 infection: A cross&#x2010;sectional evaluation. Journal of Medical Virology, 93(2), 1013&#x2013;1022. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.26368</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmer, D., Gilbert, M., Borman, R., &amp; Clark, K. L. (2002). Quantitative mRNA expression profiling of ACE 2, a novel homologue of angiotensin converting enzyme. FEBS Letters, 532(1&#x2013;2), 107&#x2013;110. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0014-5793(02)03640-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan, A., Zhang, M., Shang, Z.&#x2010;P., Yi, Y., Kuang, Y., Yu, R., Fan, J.&#x2010;J., Huang, Y.&#x2010;X., Nijat, D., Qiao, X., &amp; Ye, M. (2022). Bioactive prenylated phenolic compounds from the aerial parts of Glycyrrhiza uralensis. Phytochemistry, 201, 113284. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.phytochem.2022.113284</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto, T., Perlot, T., Rehman, A., Trichereau, J., Ishiguro, H., Paolino, M., Sigl, V., Hanada, T., Hanada, R., Lipinski, S., Wild, B., Camargo, S. M. R., Singer, D., Richter, A., Kuba, K., Fukamizu, A., Schreiber, S., Clevers, H., Verrey, F., &#x2026; Penninger, J. M. (2012). ACE2 links amino acid malnutrition to microbial ecology and intestinal inflammation. Nature, 487(7408), 477&#x2013;481. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature11228</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan, S. M., &amp; Hassan, A. H. (2018). The possibility of using shogaol for treatment of ulcerative colitis. Iranian Journal of Basic Medical Sciences, 21(9), 943&#x2013;949. https://doi.org/10.22038/IJBMS.2018.28616.6932</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, J., Chen, L., Heber, D., Shi, W., &amp; Lu, Q.&#x2010;Y. (2006). Antibacterial compounds from Glycyrrhiza uralensis. Journal of Natural Products, 69(1), 121&#x2013;124. https://doi.org/10.1021/np058069d</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, K. (2015). Traditional Chinese and Thai medicine in a comparative perspective. Complementary Therapies in Medicine, 23(6), 821&#x2013;826. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ctim.2015.10.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, R., Ma, T.&#x2010;T., Gong, M.&#x2010;X., Xie, K.&#x2010;L., Wang, Z.&#x2010;M., &amp; Li, J. (2023). The correlation between pharmacological activity and contents of eight constituents of Glycyrrhiza uralensis Fisch. Heliyon, 9(3), e14570. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e14570</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henke, M. T., Kenny, D. J., Cassilly, C. D., Vlamakis, H., Xavier, R. J., &amp; Clardy, J. (2019). Ruminococcus gnavus, a member of the human gut microbiome associated with Crohn's disease, produces an inflammatory polysaccharide. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 116(26), 12672&#x2013;12677. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1904099116</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann, M., Kleine&#x2010;Weber, H., Schroeder, S., Kr&#xfc;ger, N., Herrler, T., Erichsen, S., Schiergens, T. S., Herrler, G., Wu, N.&#x2010;H., Nitsche, A., M&#xfc;ller, M. A., Drosten, C., &amp; P&#xf6;hlmann, S. (2020). SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and is blocked by a clinically proven protease inhibitor. Cell, 181(2), 271&#x2013;280.e8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong, J.&#x2010;W., Yang, G.&#x2010;E., Kim, Y. B., Eom, S. H., Lew, J.&#x2010;H., &amp; Kang, H. (2012). Anti&#x2010;inflammatory activity of cinnamon water extract in vivo and in vitro LPS&#x2010;induced models. BMC Complementary and Alternative Medicine, 12, 237. https://doi.org/10.1186/1472-6882-12-237</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins, A. L. (2008). Network pharmacology: The next paradigm in drug discovery. Nature Chemical Biology, 4(11), 682. https://doi.org/10.1038/nchembio.118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Q., Yu, T., Li, J., Yu, Q., Zhu, L., &amp; Gu, Y. (2019). End&#x2010;to&#x2010;end syndrome differentiation of Yin deficiency and Yang deficiency in traditional Chinese medicine. Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine, 174, 9&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmpb.2018.10.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Y., Qiao, J., Zhang, X., &amp; Ge, C. (2011). Antimicrobial effect of Magnolia officinalis extract against Staphylococcus aureus. Journal of the Science of Food and Agriculture, 91(6), 1050&#x2013;1056. https://doi.org/10.1002/jsfa.4280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, X., Qin, J., &amp; Lu, S. (2014). Magnesium isoglycyrrhizinate protects hepatic L02 cells from ischemia/reperfusion induced injury. International Journal of Clinical and Experimental Pathology, 7(8), 4755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikarashi, N., Kon, R., &amp; Sugiyama, K. (2016). Aquaporins in the colon as a new therapeutic target in diarrhea and constipation. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 17(7), 1172. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms17071172</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Integratori alimentari | EFSA. (2022). https://www.efsa.europa.eu/it/topics/topic/food-supplements</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafarzadeh, A., Jafarzadeh, S., &amp; Nemati, M. (2021). Therapeutic potential of ginger against COVID&#x2010;19: Is there enough evidence? Journal of Traditional Chinese Medical Sciences, 8(4), 267&#x2013;279. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtcms.2021.10.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, M., Zhao, S., Yang, S., Lin, X., He, X., Wei, X., Song, Q., Li, R., Fu, C., Zhang, J., &amp; Zhang, Z. (2020). An &#x201c;essential herbal medicine&#x201d;&#x2014;Licorice: A review of phytochemicals and its effects in combination preparations. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 249, 112439. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jep.2019.112439</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, X., Lian, J.&#x2010;S., Hu, J.&#x2010;H., Gao, J., Zheng, L., Zhang, Y.&#x2010;M., Hao, S.&#x2010;R., Jia, H.&#x2010;Y., Cai, H., Zhang, X.&#x2010;L., Yu, G.&#x2010;D., Xu, K.&#x2010;J., Wang, X.&#x2010;Y., Gu, J.&#x2010;Q., Zhang, S.&#x2010;Y., Ye, C.&#x2010;Y., Jin, C.&#x2010;L., Lu, Y.&#x2010;F., Yu, X., &#x2026; Yang, Y. (2020). Epidemiological, clinical and virological characteristics of 74 cases of coronavirus&#x2010;infected disease 2019 (COVID&#x2010;19) with gastrointestinal symptoms. Gut, 69(6), 1002&#x2013;1009. https://doi.org/10.1136/gutjnl-2020-320926</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung, H. W., Yoon, C.&#x2010;H., Park, K. M., Han, H. S., &amp; Park, Y.&#x2010;K. (2009). Hexane fraction of Zingiberis Rhizoma Crudus extract inhibits the production of nitric oxide and proinflammatory cytokines in LPS&#x2010;stimulated BV2 microglial cells via the NF&#x2010;kappaB pathway. Food and Chemical Toxicology: An International Journal Published for the British Industrial Biological Research Association, 47(6), 1190&#x2013;1197. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fct.2009.02.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kageyama, Y., Nishizaki, Y., Aida, K., Yayama, K., Ebisui, T., Akiyama, T., &amp; Nakamura, T. (2022). Lactobacillus plantarum induces innate cytokine responses that potentially provide a protective benefit against COVID&#x2010;19: A single&#x2010;arm, double&#x2010;blind, prospective trial combined with an in vitro cytokine response assay. Experimental and Therapeutic Medicine, 23(1), 20. https://doi.org/10.3892/etm.2021.10942</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, D. M., Khing, T. M., Thein, W., Choi, W. S., Shin, C. Y., &amp; Sohn, U. D. (2020). Signaling pathways underlying changes in the contractility of the stomach fundus smooth muscle in diabetic rats. Archives of Pharmacal Research, 43(6), 666&#x2013;675. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12272-020-01244-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, E. H., Shim, B., Kang, S., Jeong, G., Lee, J., Yu, Y.&#x2010;B., &amp; Chun, M. (2009). Anti&#x2010;inflammatory effects of Scutellaria baicalensis extract via suppression of immune modulators and MAP kinase signaling molecules. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 126(2), 320&#x2013;331. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jep.2009.08.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H. J., Han, T., Kim, Y. T., So, I., &amp; Kim, B. J. (2017). Magnolia officinalis bark extract induces depolarization of pacemaker potentials through M2 and M3 muscarinic receptors in cultured murine small intestine interstitial cells of cajal. Cellular Physiology and Biochemistry, 43(5), 1790&#x2013;1802. https://doi.org/10.1159/000484065</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H. J., La, J.&#x2010;H., Kim, H. M., Yang, I.&#x2010;S., &amp; Sung, T. S. (2019). Anti&#x2010;diarrheal effect of Scutellaria baicalensis is associated with suppression of smooth muscle in the rat colon. Experimental and Therapeutic Medicine, 17(6), 4748&#x2013;4756. https://doi.org/10.3892/etm.2019.7469</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J.&#x2010;Y., Park, S. J., Yun, K.&#x2010;J., Cho, Y.&#x2010;W., Park, H.&#x2010;J., &amp; Lee, K.&#x2010;T. (2008). Isoliquiritigenin isolated from the roots of Glycyrrhiza uralensis inhibits LPS&#x2010;induced iNOS and COX&#x2010;2 expression via the attenuation of NF&#x2010;kappaB in RAW 264.7 macrophages. European Journal of Pharmacology, 584(1), 175&#x2013;184. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejphar.2008.01.032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S. Y., Kim, J., Jeong, S.&#x2010;I., Jahng, K. Y., &amp; Yu, K.&#x2010;Y. (2015). Antimicrobial effects and resistant regulation of magnolol and honokiol on methicillin&#x2010;resistant Staphylococcus aureus. BioMed Research International, 2015, 283630. https://doi.org/10.1155/2015/283630</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, T.&#x2010;G., Lee, Y.&#x2010;H., Lee, N.&#x2010;H., Bhattarai, G., Lee, I.&#x2010;K., Yun, B.&#x2010;S., &amp; Yi, H.&#x2010;K. (2013). The antioxidant property of pachymic acid improves bone disturbance against AH plus&#x2010;induced inflammation in MC&#x2010;3T3 E1 cells. Journal of Endodontics, 39(4), 461&#x2013;466. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joen.2012.11.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko, H. M., Lee, S.&#x2010;H., Jee, W., Jung, J. H., Kim, K.&#x2010;I., Jung, H.&#x2010;J., &amp; Jang, H.&#x2010;J. (2021). Gancaonin N from Glycyrrhiza uralensis attenuates the inflammatory response by downregulating the NF&#x2010;&#x3ba;B/MAPK pathway on an acute pneumonia in vitro model. Pharmaceutics, 13(7), 1028. https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics13071028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreda, S. M., Gynn, M. C., Fenstermacher, D. A., Boucher, R. C., &amp; Gabriel, S. E. (2001). Expression and localization of epithelial aquaporins in the adult human lung. American Journal of Respiratory Cell and Molecular Biology, 24(3), 224&#x2013;234. https://doi.org/10.1165/ajrcmb.24.3.4367</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuang, Y., Li, B., Fan, J., Qiao, X., &amp; Ye, M. (2018). Antitussive and expectorant activities of licorice and its major compounds. Bioorganic &amp; Medicinal Chemistry, 26(1), 278&#x2013;284. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bmc.2017.11.046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo, W.&#x2010;L., Chung, C.&#x2010;Y., Hwang, T.&#x2010;L., &amp; Chen, J.&#x2010;J. (2013). Biphenyl&#x2010;type neolignans from Magnolia officinalis and their anti&#x2010;inflammatory activities. Phytochemistry, 85, 153&#x2013;160. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.phytochem.2012.08.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon, K.&#x2010;B., Kim, E.&#x2010;K., Jeong, E.&#x2010;S., Lee, Y.&#x2010;H., Lee, Y.&#x2010;R., Park, J.&#x2010;W., Ryu, D.&#x2010;G., &amp; Park, B.&#x2010;H. (2006). Cortex cinnamomi extract prevents streptozotocin&#x2010; and cytokine&#x2010;induced beta&#x2010;cell damage by inhibiting NF&#x2010;kappaB. World Journal of Gastroenterology, 12(27), 4331&#x2013;4337. https://doi.org/10.3748/wjg.v12.i27.4331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam, F. F. Y., Yeung, J. H. K., Cheung, J. H. Y., &amp; Or, P. M. Y. (2006). Pharmacological evidence for calcium channel inhibition by danshen (Salvia miltiorrhiza) on rat isolated femoral artery. Journal of Cardiovascular Pharmacology, 47(1), 139&#x2013;145. https://doi.org/10.1097/01.fjc.0000197540.12685.ce</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, H.&#x2010;S., Kim, B.&#x2010;S., &amp; Kim, M.&#x2010;K. (2002). Suppression effect of Cinnamomum cassia bark&#x2010;derived component on nitric oxide synthase. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry, 50(26), 7700&#x2013;7703. https://doi.org/10.1021/jf020751f</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J. H., Kwak, H. J., Shin, D., Seo, H. J., Park, S. J., Hong, B.&#x2010;H., Shin, M.&#x2010;S., Kim, S. H., &amp; Kang, K. S. (2022). Mitigation of gastric damage using Cinnamomum cassia extract: Network pharmacological analysis of active compounds and protection effects in rats. Plants, 11(6), 716. https://doi.org/10.3390/plants11060716</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S., Gim, H., Shim, J. H., Jung Kim, H., Lee, J. R., Kim, S. C., Kwon, Y. K., Ha, K.&#x2010;T., So, I., &amp; Kim, B. J. (2015). The traditional herbal medicine, Ge&#x2010;Gen&#x2010;Tang, inhibits pacemaker potentials by nitric oxide/cGMP dependent ATP&#x2010;sensitive K+ channels in cultured interstitial cells of Cajal from mouse small intestine. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 170, 201&#x2013;209. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jep.2015.05.025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S. R., Lee, S., Moon, E., Park, H.&#x2010;J., Park, H. B., &amp; Kim, K. H. (2017). Bioactivity&#x2010;guided isolation of anti&#x2010;inflammatory triterpenoids from the sclerotia of Poria cocos using LPS&#x2010;stimulated Raw264.7 cells. Bioorganic Chemistry, 70, 94&#x2013;99. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bioorg.2016.11.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, Y.&#x2010;H., Lee, N.&#x2010;H., Bhattarai, G., Kim, G.&#x2010;E., Lee, I.&#x2010;K., Yun, B.&#x2010;S., Hwang, P.&#x2010;H., &amp; Yi, H.&#x2010;K. (2013). Anti&#x2010;inflammatory effect of pachymic acid promotes odontoblastic differentiation via HO&#x2010;1 in dental pulp cells. Oral Diseases, 19(2), 193&#x2013;199. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1601-0825.2012.01970.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung, J. M., Yang, C. X., Tam, A., Shaipanich, T., Hackett, T.&#x2010;L., Singhera, G. K., Dorscheid, D. R., &amp; Sin, D. D. (2020). ACE&#x2010;2 expression in the small airway epithelia of smokers and COPD patients: Implications for COVID&#x2010;19. The European Respiratory Journal, 55(5), 2000688. https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.00688-2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, F.&#x2010;S., &amp; Weng, J.&#x2010;K. (2017). Demystifying traditional herbal medicine with modern approach. Nature Plants, 3, 17109. https://doi.org/10.1038/nplants.2017.109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Xu, M., Fan, Q., Xie, X., Zhang, Y., Mu, D., Zhao, P., Zhang, B., Cao, F., Wang, Y., Jin, F., &amp; Li, Z. (2011). Tanshinone IIA ameliorates seawater exposure&#x2010;induced lung injury by inhibiting aquaporins (AQP) 1 and AQP5 expression in lung. Respiratory Physiology &amp; Neurobiology, 176(1), 39&#x2013;49. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.resp.2011.01.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Q., Cui, Y., Xu, B., Wang, Y., Lv, F., Li, Z., Li, H., Chen, X., Peng, X., Chen, Y., Wu, E., Qu, D., Jian, Y., &amp; Si, H. (2021). Main active components of Jiawei Gegen Qinlian decoction protects against ulcerative colitis under different dietary environments in a gut microbiota&#x2010;dependent manner. Pharmacological Research, 170, 105694. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.phrs.2021.105694</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S. (2016). Exploring traditional chinese medicine by a novel therapeutic concept of network target. Chinese Journal of Integrative Medicine, 22(9), 647&#x2013;652. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11655-016-2499-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S., Hu, Y., &amp; Su, S.&#x2010;B. (2020). Network pharmacology and traditional medicine. Frontiers Media SA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S., &amp; Zhang, B. (2013). Traditional Chinese medicine network pharmacology: Theory, methodology and application. Chinese Journal of Natural Medicines, 11(2), 110&#x2013;120. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1875-5364(13)60037-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., Ao, M., Zhang, C., Fan, S., Chen, Z., &amp; Yu, L. (2021). Zingiberis Rhizoma Recens: A review of its traditional uses, Phytochemistry, pharmacology, and toxicology. Evidence&#x2010;Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine, 2021, 6668990. https://doi.org/10.1155/2021/6668990</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., Ma, L., &amp; Zhang, L. (2019). Molecular basis for Poria cocos mushroom polysaccharide used as an antitumor drug in China. Progress in Molecular Biology and Translational Science, 163, 263&#x2013;296. https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.pmbts.2019.02.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, X., Li, H., &amp; Li, S. (2014). A novel network pharmacology approach to analyse traditional herbal formulae: The Liu&#x2010;Wei&#x2010;Di&#x2010;Huang pill as a case study. Molecular BioSystems, 10(5), 1014&#x2013;1022. https://doi.org/10.1039/c3mb70507b</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao, H., Ye, J., Gao, L., &amp; Liu, Y. (2021). The main bioactive compounds of Scutellaria baicalensis Georgi. for alleviation of inflammatory cytokines: A comprehensive review. Biomedicine &amp; Pharmacotherapy = Biomedecine &amp; Pharmacotherapie, 133, 110917. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2020.110917</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao, J.&#x2010;C., Deng, J.&#x2010;S., Chiu, C.&#x2010;S., Hou, W.&#x2010;C., Huang, S.&#x2010;S., Shie, P.&#x2010;H., &amp; Huang, G.&#x2010;J. (2012). Anti&#x2010;inflammatory activities of Cinnamomum cassia constituents in vitro and in vivo. Evidence&#x2010;Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine, 2012, 429320. https://doi.org/10.1155/2012/429320</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling, H., Jia, X., Zhang, Y., Gapter, L. A., Lim, Y., Agarwal, R., &amp; Ng, K. (2010). Pachymic acid inhibits cell growth and modulates arachidonic acid metabolism in nonsmall cell lung cancer A549 cells. Molecular Carcinogenesis, 49(3), 271&#x2013;282. https://doi.org/10.1002/mc.20597</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, F., Smith, A. D., Solano&#x2010;Aguilar, G., Wang, T. T. Y., Pham, Q., Beshah, E., Tang, Q., Urban, J. F., Xue, C., &amp; Li, R. W. (2020). Mechanistic insights into the attenuation of intestinal inflammation and modulation of the gut microbiome by krill oil using in vitro and in vivo models. Microbiome, 8(1), 83. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40168-020-00843-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H., Ye, F., Sun, Q., Liang, H., Li, C., Li, S., Lu, R., Huang, B., Tan, W., &amp; Lai, L. (2021). Scutellaria baicalensis extract and baicalein inhibit replication of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 and its 3C&#x2010;like protease in vitro. Journal of Enzyme Inhibition and Medicinal Chemistry, 36(1), 497&#x2013;503. https://doi.org/10.1080/14756366.2021.1873977</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, P., Yang, H., Long, F., Hao, H.&#x2010;P., Xu, X., Liu, Y., Shi, X.&#x2010;W., Zhang, D.&#x2010;D., Zheng, H.&#x2010;C., Wen, Q.&#x2010;Y., Li, W.&#x2010;W., Ji, H., Jiang, X.&#x2010;J., Zhang, B.&#x2010;L., Qi, L.&#x2010;W., &amp; Li, P. (2014). Bioactive equivalence of combinatorial components identified in screening of an herbal medicine. Pharmaceutical Research, 31(7), 1800. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11095-013-1283-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Q., Mak, J. W. Y., Su, Q., Yeoh, Y. K., Lui, G. C.&#x2010;Y., Ng, S. S. S., Zhang, F., Li, A. Y. L., Lu, W., Hui, D. S.&#x2010;C., Chan, P. K., Chan, F. K. L., &amp; Ng, S. C. (2022). Gut microbiota dynamics in a prospective cohort of patients with post&#x2010;acute COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome. Gut, 71(3), 544&#x2013;552. https://doi.org/10.1136/gutjnl-2021-325989</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X., Yu, X., Xu, X., Zhang, X., &amp; Zhang, X. (2018). The protective effects of Poria cocos&#x2010;derived polysaccharide CMP33 against IBD in mice and its molecular mechanism. Food &amp; Function, 9(11), 5936&#x2013;5949. https://doi.org/10.1039/c8fo01604f</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z.&#x2010;H., &amp; Sun, X.&#x2010;B. (2012). Network pharmacology: New opportunity for the modernization of traditional Chinese medicine. Yao Xue Xue Bao = Acta Pharmaceutica Sinica, 47(6), 696&#x2013;703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez&#x2010;Leon, S., Wegman&#x2010;Ostrosky, T., Perelman, C., Sepulveda, R., Rebolledo, P. A., Cuapio, A., &amp; Villapol, S. (2021). More than 50 Long&#x2010;term effects of COVID&#x2010;19: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. medRxiv: The Preprint Server for Health Sciences, 11(1), 16144. https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.01.27.21250617</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, Y., Joerger, R., &amp; Wu, C. (2011). Study of the chemical composition and antimicrobial activities of ethanolic extracts from roots of Scutellaria baicalensis Georgi. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry, 59(20), 10934&#x2013;10942. https://doi.org/10.1021/jf202741x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luan, X., Zhang, L.&#x2010;J., Li, X.&#x2010;Q., Rahman, K., Zhang, H., Chen, H.&#x2010;Z., &amp; Zhang, W.&#x2010;D. (2020). Compound&#x2010;based Chinese medicine formula: From discovery to compatibility mechanism. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 254, 112687. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jep.2020.112687</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, H., Wu, H., Yu, X., Zhang, X., Lu, Y., Fan, J., Tang, L., &amp; Wang, Z. (2019). A review of the phytochemistry and pharmacological activities of Magnoliae officinalis cortex. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 236, 412&#x2013;442. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jep.2019.02.041</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, L., Wu, F., Shao, Q., Chen, G., Xu, L., &amp; Lu, F. (2021). Baicalin alleviates oxidative stress and inflammation in diabetic nephropathy via Nrf2 and MAPK signaling pathway. Drug Design, Development and Therapy, 15, 3207&#x2013;3221. https://doi.org/10.2147/DDDT.S319260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal, S., Barnett, J., Brill, S. E., Brown, J. S., Denneny, E. K., Hare, S. S., Heightman, M., Hillman, T. E., Jacob, J., Jarvis, H. C., Lipman, M. C. I., Naidu, S. B., Nair, A., Porter, J. C., Tomlinson, G. S., Hurst, J. R., &amp; ARC Study Group. (2021). &#x201c;Long&#x2010;COVID&#x201d;: A cross&#x2010;sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for COVID&#x2010;19. Thorax, 76(4), 398. https://doi.org/10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-215818</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao, Q.&#x2010;Q., Xu, X.&#x2010;Y., Cao, S.&#x2010;Y., Gan, R.&#x2010;Y., Corke, H., Beta, T., &amp; Li, H.&#x2010;B. (2019). Bioactive compounds and bioactivities of ginger (Zingiber officinale Roscoe). Food, 8(6), 185. https://doi.org/10.3390/foods8060185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendelson, M., Nel, J., Blumberg, L., Madhi, S. A., Dryden, M., Stevens, W., &amp; Venter, F. W. D. (2020). Long&#x2010;COVID: An evolving problem with an extensive impact. South African Medical Journal = Suid&#x2010;Afrikaanse Tydskrif Vir Geneeskunde, 111(1), 10&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.7196/SAMJ.2020.v111i11.15433</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merra, G., Capacci, A., Cenname, G., Esposito, E., Dri, M., Di Renzo, L., &amp; Marchetti, M. (2022). The &#x201c;microbiome&#x201d;: A protagonist in COVID&#x2010;19 era. Microorganisms, 10(2), 296. https://doi.org/10.3390/microorganisms10020296</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micucci, M., Gotti, R., Corazza, I., Tocci, G., Chiarini, A., De Giorgio, M., Camarda, L., Frosini, M., Marzetti, C., Cevenini, M., &amp; Budriesi, R. (2017). Newer insights into the antidiarrheal effects of Acacia catechu Willd. Extract in guinea pig. Journal of Medicinal Food, 20(6), 592&#x2013;600. https://doi.org/10.1089/jmf.2016.0154</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milosavljevic, M. N., Kostic, M., Milovanovic, J., Zaric, R. Z., Stojadinovic, M., Jankovic, S. M., &amp; Stefanovic, S. M. (2022). Antimicrobial treatment of Erysipelatoclostridium ramosum invasive infections: A systematic review. Revista Do Instituto de Medicina Tropical de S&#xe3;o Paulo, 63, e30. https://doi.org/10.1590/S1678-9946202163030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montalvo, M., Nallapaneni, P., Hassan, S., Nurko, S., Pittock, S. J., &amp; Khlevner, J. (2022). Autoimmune gastrointestinal dysmotility following SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection successfully treated with intravenous immunoglobulin. Neurogastroenterology and Motility: The Official Journal of the European Gastrointestinal Motility Society, 34(7), e14314. https://doi.org/10.1111/nmo.14314</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad, J. S., Zaidi, S. F., Shaharyar, S., Refaat, A., Usmanghani, K., Saiki, I., &amp; Sugiyama, T. (2015). Anti&#x2010;inflammatory effect of cinnamaldehyde in Helicobacter pylori induced gastric inflammation. Biological &amp; Pharmaceutical Bulletin, 38(1), 109&#x2013;115. https://doi.org/10.1248/bpb.b14-00609</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman, D. J., &amp; Cragg, G. M. (2020). Natural products as sources of new drugs over the nearly four decades from 01/1981 to 09/2019. Journal of Natural Products, 83(3), 770&#x2013;803. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jnatprod.9b01285</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, K. K. (1966). Blockade of adrenergic and cholinergic transmissions by emetine. British Journal of Pharmacology and Chemotherapy, 28(2), 228&#x2013;237. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1476-5381.1966.tb01889.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie, A., Chao, Y., Zhang, X., Jia, W., Zhou, Z., &amp; Zhu, C. (2020). Phytochemistry and pharmacological activities of Wolfiporia cocos (F.A. Wolf) Ryvarden &amp; Gilb. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 11, 505249. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2020.505249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu, L., Hou, Y., Jiang, M., &amp; Bai, G. (2021). The rich pharmacological activities of Magnolia officinalis and secondary effects based on significant intestinal contributions. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 281, 114524. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jep.2021.114524</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobel, Y. R., Phipps, M., Zucker, J., Lebwohl, B., Wang, T. C., Sobieszczyk, M. E., &amp; Freedberg, D. E. (2020). Gastrointestinal symptoms and coronavirus disease 2019: A case&#x2010;control study from the United States. Gastroenterology, 159(1), 373&#x2013;375.e2. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2020.04.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nogales, C., Mamdouh, Z. M., List, M., Kiel, C., Casas, A. I., &amp; Schmidt, H. H. H. W. (2022). Network pharmacology: Curing causal mechanisms instead of treating symptoms. Trends in Pharmacological Sciences, 43(2), 136&#x2013;150. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tips.2021.11.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. (2021). Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID&#x2010;19) infection in the UK &#x2010; Office for National Statistics. https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/datasets/alldatarelatingtoprevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oravecz, M., &amp; M&#xe9;sz&#xe1;ros, J. (2012). Traditional Chinese medicine: Theoretical background and its use in China. Orvosi Hetilap, 153(19), 723&#x2013;731. https://doi.org/10.1556/oh.2012.29365</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, L., Mu, M., Yang, P., Sun, Y., Wang, R., Yan, J., Li, P., Hu, B., Wang, J., Hu, C., Jin, Y., Niu, X., Ping, R., Du, Y., Li, T., Xu, G., Hu, Q., &amp; Tu, L. (2020). Clinical characteristics of COVID&#x2010;19 patients with digestive symptoms in Hubei, China: A descriptive, cross&#x2010;sectional, multicenter study. The American Journal of Gastroenterology, 115(5), 766&#x2013;773. https://doi.org/10.14309/ajg.0000000000000620</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang, W., Yang, F., Zhao, Y., Dai, E., Feng, J., Huang, Y., Guo, Y., Zhou, S., Huang, M., Zheng, W., Ma, J., Li, H., Li, Q., Hou, L., Zhang, S., Wang, H., Liu, Q., Zhang, B., &amp; Zhang, J. (2022). Qingjin Yiqi granules for post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 condition: A randomized clinical trial. Journal of Evidence&#x2010;Based Medicine, 15(1), 30&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.1111/jebm.12465</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe1;ramo&#x2010;Zunzunegui, J., Ortega&#x2010;Fern&#xe1;ndez, I., Calvo&#x2010;Espino, P., Diego&#x2010;Hern&#xe1;ndez, C., Ariza&#x2010;Ibarra, I., Otazu&#x2010;Canals, L., Dan&#xe9;s&#x2010;Grases, J. E., &amp; Menchero&#x2010;S&#xe1;nchez, A. (2020). Severe Clostridium difficile colitis as potential late complication associated with COVID&#x2010;19. Annals of the Royal College of Surgeons of England, 102(7), e176&#x2013;e179. https://doi.org/10.1308/rcsann.2020.0166</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, J.&#x2010;Y., Kim, J. H., Kim, Y. M., Jeong, H. J., Kim, D. W., Park, K. H., Kwon, H.&#x2010;J., Park, S.&#x2010;J., Lee, W. S., &amp; Ryu, Y. B. (2012). Tanshinones as selective and slow&#x2010;binding inhibitors for SARS&#x2010;CoV cysteine proteases. Bioorganic &amp; Medicinal Chemistry, 20(19), 5928&#x2013;5935. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bmc.2012.07.038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, S.&#x2010;Y., Kim, Y. D., Kim, M. S., Kim, K.&#x2010;T., &amp; Kim, J. Y. (2023). Cinnamon (Cinnamomum cassia) water extract improves diarrhea symptoms by changing the gut environment: A randomized controlled trial. Food &amp; Function, 14(3), 1520&#x2013;1529. https://doi.org/10.1039/d2fo01835g</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel, A., Ali, R., Hussain, M., Slim, J., &amp; DaCosta, T. (2022). Severe gastroparesis flare: Is COVID&#x2010;19 the inciting factor? Journal of Medical Cases, 13(2), 85&#x2013;88. https://doi.org/10.14740/jmc3883</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelagalli, A., Squillacioti, C., Mirabella, N., &amp; Meli, R. (2016). Aquaporins in health and disease: An overview focusing on the gut of different species. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 17(8), 1213. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms17081213</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, B., He, R., Yang, B., Lu, Y., Gao, J., &amp; Li, J. (2010). Comparative study of effect of Magnolia officinalis and M. officinalis var. Biloba on gastrointestinal motility dysfunction. Zhongguo Zhong Yao Za Zhi = Zhongguo Zhongyao Zazhi = China Journal of Chinese Materia Medica, 35(19), 2624&#x2013;2627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perisetti, A., Goyal, H., Gajendran, M., Boregowda, U., Mann, R., &amp; Sharma, N. (2020). Prevalence, mechanisms, and implications of gastrointestinal symptoms in COVID&#x2010;19. Frontiers in Medicine, 7, 588711. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2020.588711</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petitjean, S. J. L., Lecocq, M., Lelong, C., Denis, R., Defr&#xe8;re, S., Mariage, P.&#x2010;A., Alsteens, D., &amp; Pilette, C. (2022). Salvia miltiorrhiza Bunge as a potential natural compound against COVID&#x2010;19. Cell, 11(8), 1311. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells11081311</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, G.&#x2010;Q., Yang, N.&#x2010;B., Ding, F., Ma, A. H. Y., Wang, Z.&#x2010;Y., Shen, Y.&#x2010;F., Shi, C.&#x2010;W., Lian, X., Chu, J.&#x2010;G., Chen, L., Wang, Z.&#x2010;Y., Ren, D.&#x2010;W., Li, G.&#x2010;X., Chen, X.&#x2010;Q., Shen, H.&#x2010;J., &amp; Chen, X.&#x2010;M. (2020). Epidemiologic and clinical characteristics of 91 hospitalized patients with COVID&#x2010;19 in Zhejiang, China: A retrospective, multi&#x2010;centre case series. QJM: Monthly Journal of the Association of Physicians, 113(7), 474&#x2013;481. https://doi.org/10.1093/qjmed/hcaa089</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Queiroz, M. A. F., das Neves, P. F. M., Lima, S. S., Lopes, J. d. C., Torres, M. K. d. S., Vallinoto, I. M. V. C., Bichara, C. D. A., Dos Santos, E. F., de Brito, M. T. F. M., da Silva, A. L. S., Leite, M. d. M., da Costa, F. P., Viana, M. d. N. d. S. d. A., Rodrigues, F. B. B., de Sarges, K. M. L., Cantanhede, M. H. D., da Silva, R., Bichara, C. N. C., van den Berg, A. V. S., &#x2026; Vallinoto, A. C. R. (2022). Cytokine profiles associated with acute COVID&#x2010;19 and Long COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome. Frontiers in Cellular and Infection Microbiology, 12, 922422. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcimb.2022.922422</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rangnekar, H., Patankar, S., Suryawanshi, K., &amp; Soni, P. (2020). Safety and efficacy of herbal extracts to restore respiratory health and improve innate immunity in COVID&#x2010;19 positive patients with mild to moderate severity: A structured summary of a study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials, 21(1), 943. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13063-020-04906-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xed;os, J.&#x2010;L. (2011). Chemical constituents and pharmacological properties of Poria cocos. Planta Medica, 77(7), 681&#x2013;691. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0030-1270823</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson, N. (2011). Integrative medicine&#x2014;Traditional Chinese medicine, a model? Chinese Journal of Integrative Medicine, 17(1), 21&#x2013;25. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11655-011-0602-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusch, C. M., Molleston, J. M., Glasser, M. F., Don, S., &amp; Kulkarni, S. S. (2022). Postviral gastroparesis associated with SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection in a pediatric patient. JPGN Reports, 3(2), e195. https://doi.org/10.1097/PG9.0000000000000195</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahn, B., Eze, O. P., Edelman, M. C., Chougar, C. E., Thomas, R. M., Schleien, C. L., &amp; Weinstein, T. (2021). Features of intestinal disease associated with COVID&#x2010;related multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children. Journal of Pediatric Gastroenterology and Nutrition, 72(3), 384&#x2013;387. https://doi.org/10.1097/MPG.0000000000002953</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santini, A., Tenore, G. C., &amp; Novellino, E. (2017). Nutraceuticals: A paradigm of proactive medicine. European Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences: Official Journal of the European Federation for Pharmaceutical Sciences, 96, 53&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejps.2016.09.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulthei&#xdf;, C., Willscher, E., Paschold, L., Gottschick, C., Klee, B., Henkes, S.&#x2010;S., Bosurgi, L., Dutzmann, J., Sedding, D., Frese, T., Girndt, M., H&#xf6;ll, J. I., Gekle, M., Mikolajczyk, R., &amp; Binder, M. (2022). The IL&#x2010;1&#x3b2;, IL&#x2010;6, and TNF cytokine triad is associated with post&#x2010;acute sequelae of COVID&#x2010;19. Cell Reports Medicine, 3(6), 100663. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100663</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebai, H., Rtibi, K., Selmi, S., Jridi, M., Balti, R., &amp; Marzouki, L. (2019). Modulating and opposite actions of two aqueous extracts prepared from Cinnamomum cassia L. bark and Quercus ilex L. on the gastrointestinal tract in rats. RSC Advances, 9(38), 21695&#x2013;21706. https://doi.org/10.1039/C9RA02429H</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seigler, D. S. (1999). Sesquiterpenes. In D. S. Seigler (Ed.), Plant secondary metabolism (pp. 367&#x2013;397). Springer US. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4615-4913-0_21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Settanni, C. R., Ianiro, G., Ponziani, F. R., Bibb&#xf2;, S., Segal, J. P., Cammarota, G., &amp; Gasbarrini, A. (2021). COVID&#x2010;19 as a trigger of irritable bowel syndrome: A review of potential mechanisms. World Journal of Gastroenterology, 27(43), 7433. https://doi.org/10.3748/wjg.v27.i43.7433</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang, Q., Xu, H., &amp; Huang, L. (2012). Tanshinone IIA: A promising natural cardioprotective agent. Evidence&#x2010;Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine, 2012, 716459. https://doi.org/10.1155/2012/716459</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A., Ahmad Farouk, I., &amp; Lal, S. K. (2021). COVID&#x2010;19: A review on the novel coronavirus disease evolution, transmission, detection, control and prevention. Viruses, 13(2), 202. https://doi.org/10.3390/v13020202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng, Y., Wu, T., Dai, Y., Ji, K., Zhong, Y., &amp; Xue, Y. (2020). The effect of 6&#x2010;gingerol on inflammatory response and Th17/Treg balance in DSS&#x2010;induced ulcerative colitis mice. Annals of Translational Medicine, 8(7), 442. https://doi.org/10.21037/atm.2020.03.141</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng, Y., Wu, T., Dai, Y., Xu, L., Zhong, Y., Xue, Y., &amp; Tian, Y. (2020). 6&#x2010;gingerol alleviates inflammatory injury in DSS&#x2010;induced ulcerative colitis mice by regulating NF&#x2010;&#x3ba;B signaling. Annals of Palliative Medicine, 9(4), 1944&#x2013;1952. https://doi.org/10.21037/apm-20-903</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, R. S., Singh, A., Kaur, H., Batra, G., Sarma, P., Kaur, H., Bhattacharyya, A., Sharma, A. R., Kumar, S., Upadhyay, S., Tiwari, V., Avti, P., Prakash, A., &amp; Medhi, B. (2021). Promising traditional Indian medicinal plants for the management of novel coronavirus disease: A systematic review. Phytotherapy Research, 35(8), 4456&#x2013;4484. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.7150</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syu, W.&#x2010;J., Shen, C.&#x2010;C., Lu, J.&#x2010;J., Lee, G.&#x2010;H., &amp; Sun, C.&#x2010;M. (2004). Antimicrobial and cytotoxic activities of neolignans from Magnolia officinalis. Chemistry &amp; Biodiversity, 1(3), 530&#x2013;537. https://doi.org/10.1002/cbdv.200490046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, Z., Zhang, Q., Zhao, R., Huang, T., Tian, Y., &amp; Lin, Y. (2023). A comparative study on the effects of different sources of carboxymethyl Poria polysaccharides on the repair of DSS&#x2010;induced colitis in mice. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 24(10), 9034. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms24109034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanikawa, T., Hayashi, T., Suzuki, R., Kitamura, M., &amp; Inoue, Y. (2022). Inhibitory effect of honokiol on furin&#x2010;like activity and SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection. Journal of Traditional and Complementary Medicine, 12(1), 69&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtcme.2021.09.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao, Q., Du, J., Li, X., Zeng, J., Tan, B., Xu, J., Lin, W., &amp; Chen, X.&#x2010;L. (2020). Network pharmacology and molecular docking analysis on molecular targets and mechanisms of Huashi Baidu formula in the treatment of COVID&#x2010;19. Drug Development and Industrial Pharmacy, 46, 1345&#x2013;1353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoharides, T. C., Cholevas, C., Polyzoidis, K., &amp; Politis, A. (2021). Long&#x2010;COVID syndrome&#x2010;associated brain fog and chemofog: Luteolin to the rescue. BioFactors, 47(2), 232&#x2013;241. https://doi.org/10.1002/biof.1726</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, D. C., Chablani, D., Parekh, S., Pichammal, R. C., Shanmugasundaram, K., &amp; Pitchumani, P. K. (2022). Dysgeusia: A review in the context of COVID&#x2010;19. Journal of the American Dental Association, 153(3), 251&#x2013;264. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.adaj.2021.08.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, T., Wu, Y.&#x2010;Q., Ni, W.&#x2010;J., Shen, A.&#x2010;Z., &amp; Liu, S. (2020). The potential insights of traditional Chinese medicine on treatment of COVID&#x2010;19. Chinese Medicine, 15, 51. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13020-020-00326-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosato, M., Ciciarello, F., Zazzara, M. B., Pais, C., Savera, G., Picca, A., Galluzzo, V., Coelho&#x2010;J&#xfa;nior, H. J., Calvani, R., Marzetti, E., &amp; Landi, F. (2022). Nutraceuticals and dietary supplements for older adults with long COVID. Clinics in Geriatric Medicine, 38(3), 565&#x2013;591. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cger.2022.04.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traboulsi, H., Cloutier, A., Boyapelly, K., Bonin, M.&#x2010;A., Marsault, &#xc9;., Cantin, A. M., &amp; Richter, M. V. (2015). The flavonoid isoliquiritigenin reduces lung inflammation and mouse morbidity during influenza virus infection. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, 59(10), 6317&#x2013;6327. https://doi.org/10.1128/AAC.01098-15</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valipour, M. (2022). Different aspects of emetine's capabilities as a highly potent SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 inhibitor against COVID&#x2010;19. ACS Pharmacology &amp; Translational Science, 5(6), 387&#x2013;399. https://doi.org/10.1021/acsptsci.2c00045</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valipour, M. (2023). Therapeutic prospects of naturally occurring p38 MAPK inhibitors tanshinone IIA and pinocembrin for the treatment of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2&#x2010;induced CNS complications. Phytotherapy Research, 37(9), 3724&#x2013;3743. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.7902</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valipour, M., Hosseini, A., Di Sotto, A., &amp; Irannejad, H. (2023). Dual action anti&#x2010;inflammatory/antiviral isoquinoline alkaloids as potent naturally occurring anti&#x2010;SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 agents: A combined pharmacological and medicinal chemistry perspective. Phytotherapy Research, 37(5), 2168&#x2013;2186. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.7833</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valipour, M., Irannejad, H., &amp; Emami, S. (2022). Papaverine, a promising therapeutic agent for the treatment of COVID&#x2010;19 patients with underlying cardiovascular diseases (CVDs). Drug Development Research, 83(6), 1246&#x2013;1250. https://doi.org/10.1002/ddr.21961</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valipour, M., Irannejad, H., &amp; Keyvani, H. (2023). An overview on anti&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 drug achievements and challenges ahead. ACS Pharmacology &amp; Translational Science, 6(9), 1248&#x2013;1265. https://doi.org/10.1021/acsptsci.3c00121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valipour, M., Zarghi, A., Ebrahimzadeh, M. A., &amp; Irannejad, H. (2021). Therapeutic potential of chelerythrine as a multi&#x2010;purpose adjuvant for the treatment of COVID&#x2010;19. Cell Cycle, 20(22), 2321&#x2013;2336. https://doi.org/10.1080/15384101.2021.1982509</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villapol, S. (2020). Gastrointestinal symptoms associated with COVID&#x2010;19: Impact on the gut microbiome. Translational Research: The Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, 226, 57&#x2013;69. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trsl.2020.08.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vodnar, D.&#x2010;C., Mitrea, L., Teleky, B.&#x2010;E., Szabo, K., C&#x103;linoiu, L.&#x2010;F., Neme&#x15f;, S.&#x2010;A., &amp; Mart&#x103;u, G.&#x2010;A. (2020). Coronavirus disease (COVID&#x2010;19) caused by (SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2) infections: A real challenge for human gut microbiota. Frontiers in Cellular and Infection Microbiology, 10, 575559. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcimb.2020.575559</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollbracht, C., &amp; Kraft, K. (2022). Oxidative stress and hyper&#x2010;inflammation as major drivers of severe COVID&#x2010;19 and long COVID: Implications for the benefit of high&#x2010;dose intravenous vitamin C. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 13, 899198. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2022.899198</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, G.&#x2010;D., Wang, X.&#x2010;Y., Hu, H.&#x2010;Z., Fang, X.&#x2010;C., Liu, S., Gao, N., Xia, Y., &amp; Wood, J. D. (2005). Angiotensin receptors and actions in guinea pig enteric nervous system. American Journal of Physiology. Gastrointestinal and Liver Physiology, 289(3), G614&#x2013;G626. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpgi.00119.2005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H., Jin, X.&#x2010;Y., Pang, B., Liu, C.&#x2010;X., Zheng, W.&#x2010;K., Yang, F.&#x2010;W., Pang, W.&#x2010;T., &amp; Zhang, J.&#x2010;H. (2020). Analysis on clinical study protocols of traditional Chinese medicine for coronavirus disease 2019. Zhongguo Zhong Yao Za Zhi = Zhongguo Zhongyao Zazhi = China Journal of Chinese Materia Medica, 45(6), 1232&#x2013;1241. https://doi.org/10.19540/j.cnki.cjcmm.20200220.501</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, K.&#x2010;X., Gao, Y., Gong, W.&#x2010;X., Ye, X.&#x2010;F., Fan, L.&#x2010;Y., Wang, C., Gao, X.&#x2010;F., Gao, L., Du, G.&#x2010;H., Qin, X.&#x2010;M., Lu, A.&#x2010;P., &amp; Guan, D.&#x2010;G. (2020). A novel strategy for decoding and validating the combination principles of Huanglian Jiedu decoction from multi&#x2010;scale perspective. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 11, 567088. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2020.567088</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, M., Dong, Y., Wu, J., Li, H., Zhang, Y., Fan, S., &amp; Li, D. (2020). Baicalein ameliorates ionizing radiation&#x2010;induced injuries by rebalancing gut microbiota and inhibiting apoptosis. Life Sciences, 261, 118463. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lfs.2020.118463</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., Luo, R., She, B., Chen, Y., &amp; Guo, J. (2014). Traditional Chinese medicine (Shun&#x2010;Qi&#x2010;Tong&#x2010;Xie Granule) for irritable bowel syndrome: Study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials, 15(1), 273. https://doi.org/10.1186/1745-6215-15-273</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z.&#x2010;L., Wang, S., Kuang, Y., Hu, Z.&#x2010;M., Qiao, X., &amp; Ye, M. (2018). A comprehensive review on phytochemistry, pharmacology, and flavonoid biosynthesis of Scutellaria baicalensis. Pharmaceutical Biology, 56(1), 465&#x2013;484. https://doi.org/10.1080/13880209.2018.1492620</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weidinger, C., Hegazy, A. N., Glauben, R., &amp; Siegmund, B. (2021). COVID&#x2010;19&#x2010;from mucosal immunology to IBD patients. Mucosal Immunology, 14(3), 566&#x2013;573. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41385-021-00384-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. (2021). A clinical case definition of post COVID&#x2010;19 condition by a Delphi consensus. https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-2019-nCoV-Post_COVID-19_condition-Clinical_case_definition-2021.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wondrak, G. T., Villeneuve, N. F., Lamore, S. D., Bause, A. S., Jiang, T., &amp; Zhang, D. D. (2010). The cinnamon&#x2010;derived dietary factor cinnamic aldehyde activates the Nrf2&#x2010;dependent antioxidant response in human epithelial colon cells. Molecules, 15(5), 3338&#x2013;3355. https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules15053338</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, C.&#x2010;Y., Yu, X.&#x2010;P., Ma, A. H. Y., Wang, L.&#x2010;P., Yang, N.&#x2010;B., Li, G.&#x2010;X., Shi, J.&#x2010;J., &amp; Qian, G.&#x2010;Q. (2020). Coronavirus disease 19 with gastrointestinal symptoms as initial manifestations: A case report. The Journal of International Medical Research, 48(9), 300060520952256. https://doi.org/10.1177/0300060520952256</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, M. J., Shin, D. H., Kim, M. Y., Park, C. G., Kim, Y. D., Lee, J., Park, I. K., Choi, S., So, I., Park, J. S., &amp; Jun, J. Y. (2015). Functional effects of &#x3b2;3&#x2010;adrenoceptor on pacemaker activity in interstitial cells of Cajal from the mouse colon. European Journal of Pharmacology, 754, 32&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejphar.2015.02.031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, S.&#x2010;E., Hashimoto&#x2010;Hill, S., Woo, V., Eshleman, E. M., Whitt, J., Engleman, L., Karns, R., Denson, L. A., Haslam, D. B., &amp; Alenghat, T. (2020). Microbiota&#x2010;derived metabolite promotes HDAC3 activity in the gut. Nature, 586(7827), 108&#x2013;112. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2604-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, T.&#x2010;Y., Khor, T. O., Saw, C. L. L., Loh, S. C., Chen, A. I., Lim, S. S., Park, J. H. Y., Cai, L., &amp; Kong, A.&#x2010;N. T. (2011). Anti&#x2010;inflammatory/anti&#x2010;oxidative stress activities and differential regulation of Nrf2&#x2010;mediated genes by non&#x2010;polar fractions of tea Chrysanthemum zawadskii and licorice Glycyrrhiza uralensis. The AAPS Journal, 13(1), 1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1208/s12248-010-9239-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Z., Chen, X., Ni, W., Zhou, D., Chai, S., Ye, W., Zhang, Z., Guo, Y., Ren, L., &amp; Zeng, Y. (2021). The inhibition of Mpro, the primary protease of COVID&#x2010;19, by Poria cocos and its active compounds: A network pharmacology and molecular docking study. RSC Advances, 11(20), 11821&#x2013;11843. https://doi.org/10.1039/d0ra07035a</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, Z. W., Zhang, W., Ma, L., &amp; Qiu, Z. W. (2014). Therapeutic effect of magnesium isoglycyrrhizinate in rats on lung injury induced by paraquat poisoning. European Review for Medical and Pharmacological Sciences, 18(3), 311&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, K., Cai, H., Shen, Y., Ni, Q., Chen, Y., Hu, S., Li, J., Wang, H., Yu, L., Huang, H., Qiu, Y., Wei, G., Fang, Q., Zhou, J., Sheng, J., Liang, T., &amp; Li, L. (2020). Management of COVID&#x2010;19: The Zhejiang experience. Zhejiang Da Xue Xue Bao. Yi Xue Ban = Journal of Zhejiang University. Medical Sciences, 49(2), 147&#x2013;157. https://doi.org/10.3785/j.issn.1008-9292.2020.02.02</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav, E., Yadav, N., Hus, A., &amp; Yadav, J. S. (2020). Aquaporins in lung health and disease: Emerging roles, regulation, and clinical implications. Respiratory Medicine, 174, 106193. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rmed.2020.106193</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, R., Yuan, B.&#x2010;C., Ma, Y.&#x2010;S., Zhou, S., &amp; Liu, Y. (2017). The anti&#x2010;inflammatory activity of licorice, a widely used Chinese herb. Pharmaceutical Biology, 55(1), 5&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1080/13880209.2016.1225775</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, S.&#x2010;Y., Lin, Z.&#x2010;X., Xian, Y.&#x2010;F., Zhang, H.&#x2010;M., &amp; Xu, H.&#x2010;X. (2023). Traditional uses, chemical compounds, pharmacological activities and clinical studies on the traditional Chinese prescription Yi&#x2010;Gan San. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 302 (Pt A), 115859. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jep.2022.115859</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi, Y., Li, J., Lai, X., Zhang, M., Kuang, Y., Bao, Y.&#x2010;O., Yu, R., Hong, W., Muturi, E., Xue, H., Wei, H., Li, T., Zhuang, H., Qiao, X., Xiang, K., Yang, H., &amp; Ye, M. (2022). Natural triterpenoids from licorice potently inhibit SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection. Journal of Advanced Research, 36, 201&#x2013;210. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jare.2021.11.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue, S.&#x2010;J., Qin, Y.&#x2010;F., Kang, A., Tao, H.&#x2010;J., Zhou, G.&#x2010;S., Chen, Y.&#x2010;Y., Jiang, J.&#x2010;Q., Tang, Y.&#x2010;P., &amp; Duan, J.&#x2010;A. (2021). Total flavonoids of Glycyrrhiza uralensis alleviates irinotecan&#x2010;induced colitis via modification of gut microbiota and fecal metabolism. Frontiers in Immunology, 12, 628358. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.628358</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C., Fan, L., Fan, S., Wang, J., Luo, T., Tang, Y., Chen, Z., &amp; Yu, L. (2019). Cinnamomum cassia Presl: A review of its traditional uses, phytochemistry, pharmacology and toxicology. Molecules, 24(19), 3473. https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules24193473</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, D.&#x2010;H., Zhang, X., Peng, B., Deng, S.&#x2010;Q., Wang, Y.&#x2010;F., Yang, L., Zhang, K.&#x2010;Z., Ling, C.&#x2010;Q., &amp; Wu, K.&#x2010;L. (2020). Network pharmacology suggests biochemical rationale for treating COVID&#x2010;19 symptoms with a traditional Chinese medicine. Communications Biology, 3(1), 466. https://doi.org/10.1038/s42003-020-01190-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H.&#x2010;S., &amp; Wang, S.&#x2010;Q. (2006). Salvianolic acid B from Salvia miltiorrhiza inhibits tumor necrosis factor&#x2010;alpha (TNF&#x2010;alpha)&#x2010;induced MMP&#x2010;2 upregulation in human aortic smooth muscle cells via suppression of NAD(P)H oxidase&#x2010;derived reactive oxygen species. Journal of Molecular and Cellular Cardiology, 41(1), 138&#x2013;148. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yjmcc.2006.03.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M., Xu, C., Liu, D., Han, M. K., Wang, L., &amp; Merlin, D. (2018). Oral delivery of nanoparticles loaded with ginger active compound, 6&#x2010;Shogaol, attenuates ulcerative colitis and promotes wound healing in a murine model of ulcerative colitis. Journal of Crohn's &amp; Colitis, 12(2), 217&#x2013;229. https://doi.org/10.1093/ecco-jcc/jjx115</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M., Zang, K.&#x2010;H., Luo, J.&#x2010;L., Leung, F.&#x2010;P., Huang, Y., Lin, C.&#x2010;Y., Yang, Z.&#x2010;J., Lu, A.&#x2010;P., Tang, X.&#x2010;D., Xu, H.&#x2010;X., Sung, J. J., &amp; Bian, Z.&#x2010;X. (2013). Magnolol inhibits colonic motility through down&#x2010;regulation of voltage&#x2010;sensitive L&#x2010;type Ca2+ channels of colonic smooth muscle cells in rats. Phytomedicine: International Journal of Phytotherapy and Phytopharmacology, 20(14), 1272&#x2013;1279. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.phymed.2013.07.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Q., Chen, X.&#x2010;Y., &amp; Martin, C. (2016). Scutellaria baicalensis, the golden herb from the garden of Chinese medicinal plants. Science Bulletin, 61(18), 1391&#x2013;1398. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11434-016-1136-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y., Du, X., Duan, Y., Pan, X., Sun, Y., You, T., Han, L., Jin, Z., Shang, W., Yu, J., Guo, H., Liu, Q., Wu, Y., Peng, C., Wang, J., Zhu, C., Yang, X., Yang, K., Lei, Y., &#x2026; Yang, H. (2021). High&#x2010;throughput screening identifies established drugs as SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 PLpro inhibitors. Protein &amp; Cell, 12(11), 877&#x2013;888. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13238-021-00836-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, P., Xu, J., Yang, D., Shen, Y., Wang, L., Feng, Y., Du, C., Song, Y., Wu, C., Hu, X., &amp; Sun, Y. (2020). COVID&#x2010;19&#x2010;associated gastrointestinal and liver injury: Clinical features and potential mechanisms. Signal Transduction and Targeted Therapy, 5, 256. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41392-020-00373-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, X., Surh, Y.&#x2010;J., Do, S.&#x2010;G., Shin, E., Shim, K.&#x2010;S., Lee, C.&#x2010;K., &amp; Na, H.&#x2010;K. (2019). Baicalein inhibits dextran sulfate sodium&#x2010;induced mouse colitis. Journal of Cancer Prevention, 24(2), 129&#x2013;138. https://doi.org/10.15430/JCP.2019.24.2.129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, L.&#x2010;P., Wang, J., Xie, R.&#x2010;H., Pakhale, S., Krewski, D., Cameron, D. W., &amp; Wen, S. W. (2021). The effects of traditional Chinese medicine as an auxiliary treatment for COVID&#x2010;19: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Journal of Alternative and Complementary Medicine, 27(3), 225&#x2013;237. https://doi.org/10.1089/acm.2020.0310</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Y., Li, W., Xu, L., &amp; Chen, L. (2011). In Salvia miltiorrhiza, phenolic acids possess protective properties against amyloid &#x3b2;&#x2010;induced cytotoxicity, and tanshinones act as acetylcholinesterase inhibitors. Environmental Toxicology and Pharmacology, 31(3), 443&#x2013;452. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.etap.2011.02.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Z., Chen, B., Chen, S., Lin, M., Chen, Y., Jin, S., Chen, W., &amp; Zhang, Y. (2020). Applications of network pharmacology in traditional Chinese medicine research. Evidence&#x2010;Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine, 2020, e1646905. https://doi.org/10.1155/2020/1646905</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Z.&#x2010;Y., Zhao, W.&#x2010;R., Zhang, J., Chen, X.&#x2010;L., &amp; Tang, J.&#x2010;Y. (2019). Sodium tanshinone IIA sulfonate: A review of pharmacological activity and pharmacokinetics. Biomedicine &amp; Pharmacotherapy = Biomedecine &amp; Pharmacotherapie, 118, 109362. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2019.109362</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, G., Ma, S., Li, X., Zhang, P., Tang, L., Cao, L., Liu, A., Sugita, T., &amp; Tomoda, T. (2018). The effect of ethanol extract of Glycyrrhiza uralensis on the voltage&#x2010;gated sodium channel subtype 1.4. Journal of Pharmacological Sciences, 136(2), 57&#x2013;65. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphs.2017.11.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo, G.&#x2010;Y., Zhang, X.&#x2010;J., Han, J., Li, Y.&#x2010;Q., &amp; Wang, G.&#x2010;C. (2015). In vitro synergism of magnolol and honokiol in combination with antibacterial agents against clinical isolates of methicillin&#x2010;resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA). BMC Complementary and Alternative Medicine, 15, 425. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12906-015-0938-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo, T., Zhang, F., Lui, G. C. Y., Yeoh, Y. K., Li, A. Y. L., Zhan, H., Wan, Y., Chung, A. C. K., Cheung, C. P., Chen, N., Lai, C. K. C., Chen, Z., Tso, E. Y. K., Fung, K. S. C., Chan, V., Ling, L., Joynt, G., Hui, D. S. C., Chan, F. K. L., &#x2026; Ng, S. C. (2020). Alterations in gut microbiota of patients with COVID&#x2010;19 during time of hospitalization. Gastroenterology, 159(3), 944&#x2013;955.e8. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2020.05.048</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>