<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38327880</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-3546</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Brain, behavior, &amp; immunity - health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Brain Behav Immun Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identification of CD8 T-cell dysfunction associated with symptoms in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) and Long COVID and treatment with a nebulized antioxidant/anti-pathogen agent in a retrospective case series.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100720</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100720</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100720</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bbih.2023.100720</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patients with post-acute sequelae of Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection (PASC, i.e., Long COVID) have a symptom complex highly analogous to many features of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS), suggesting they may share some aspects of pathogenesis in these similar disorders. ME/CFS is a complex disease affecting numerous organ systems and biological processes and is often preceded by an infection-like episode. It is postulated that the chronic manifestations of illness may result from an altered host response to infection or inability to resolve inflammation, as is being reported in Long COVID. The immunopathogenesis of both disorders is still poorly understood. Here, we show data that suggest Long COVID and ME/CFS may be due to an aberrant response to an immunological trigger-like infection, resulting in a dysregulated immune system with CD8 T-cell dysfunction reminiscent of some aspects of T-cell clonal exhaustion, a phenomenon associated with oxidative stress. As there is an urgent need for diagnostic tools and treatment strategies for these two related disabling disorders, here, in a retrospective case series, we have also identified a potential nebulized antioxidant/anti-pathogen treatment that has evidence of a good safety profile. This nebulized agent is comprised of five ingredients previously reported individually to relieve oxidative stress, attenuate NF-&#x3ba;B signaling, and/or to act directly to inhibit pathogens, including viruses. Administration of this treatment by nebulizer results in rapid access of small doses of well-studied antioxidants and agents with anti-pathogen potential to the lungs; components of this nebulized agent are also likely to be distributed systemically, with potential to enter the central nervous system.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">and Findings: We conducted an analysis of CD8 T-cell function and severity of symptoms by self-report questionnaires in ME/CFS, Long COVID and healthy controls. We developed a CD8 T-cell functional assay, assessing CD8 T-cell dysfunction by intracellular cytokine staining (ICS) in a group of ME/CFS (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;12) and Long COVID patients (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;8), comparing to healthy controls (HC) with similar age and sex (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;10). Magnet-enriched fresh CD8 T-cells in both patient groups had a significantly diminished capacity to produce both cytokines, IFN&#x3b3; or TNF&#x3b1;, after PMA stimulation when compared to HC. The symptom severity questionnaire showed similar symptom profiles for the two disorders. Fortuitously, through a retrospective case series, we were able to examine the ICS and questionnaire data of 4 ME/CFS and 4 Long COVID patients in conjunction with their treatment (3-15 months). In parallel with the treatment pursued electively by participants in this retrospective case series, there was an increase in CD8 T-cell IFN&#x3b3; and TNF&#x3b1; production and a decrease in overall self-reported symptom severity score by 54%. No serious treatment-associated side effects or laboratory anomalies were noted in these patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Here, in this small study, we present two observations that appear potentially fundamental to the pathogenesis and treatment of Long COVID and ME/CFS. The first is that both disorders appear to be characterized by dysfunctional CD8 T-cells with severe deficiencies in their abilities to produce IFN&#x3b3; and TNF&#x3b1;. The second is that in a small retrospective Long COVID and ME/CFS case series, this immune dysfunction and patient health improved in parallel with treatment with an immunomodulatory, antioxidant pharmacological treatment with anticipated anti-pathogen activity. This work provides evidence of the potential utility of a biomarker, CD8 T-cell dysfunction, and suggests the potential for benefit from a new nebulized antioxidant/anti-pathogen treatment. These immune biomarker data may help build capacity for improved diagnosis and tracking of treatment outcomes during clinical trials for both Long COVID and ME/CFS while providing clues to new treatment avenues that suggest potential efficacy for both conditions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gil</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Massachusetts Chan Medical School, Department of Pathology, Worcester, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoag</LastName><ForeName>George E</ForeName><Initials>GE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inspiritol, Inc., Fairfield, CT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salerno</LastName><ForeName>John P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inspiritol, Inc., Fairfield, CT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Salerno Center for Complementary Medicine, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hornig</LastName><ForeName>Mady</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Columbia University Mailman School of Public Health, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klimas</LastName><ForeName>Nancy</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nova Southeastern University, Fort Lauderdale, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Selin</LastName><ForeName>Liisa K</ForeName><Initials>LK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Massachusetts Chan Medical School, Department of Pathology, Worcester, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Brain Behav Immun Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101759062</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-3546</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antioxidant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CD8 T-cell dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immune dysregulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inspiritol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nebulized</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">T cell exhaustion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38327880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10847863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbih.2023.100720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-3546(23)00134-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ablashi D.V., Eastman H.B., Owen C.B., Roman M.M., Friedman J., Zabriskie J.B., et al. Frequent HHV-6 reactivation in multiple sclerosis (MS) and chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS) patients. J. Clin. Virol. 2000;16(3):179&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10738137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z., Xie Y., Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594(7862):259&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hakeim H.K., Al-Rubaye H.T., Al-Hadrawi D.S., Almulla A.F., Maes M. Long-COVID post-viral chronic fatigue and affective symptoms are associated with oxidative damage, lowered antioxidant defenses and inflammation: a proof of concept and mechanism study. Mol. Psychiatr. 2023;28(2):564&#x2013;578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9589528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36280755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ANZMES Preliminary survey findings, n.d. Nov 15, 2021. https://anzmesorgnz/anzmes-preliminary-survey-findings/. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong C.W., McGregor N.R., Butt H.L., Gooley P.R. Metabolism in chronic fatigue syndrome. Adv. Clin. Chem. 2014;66:121&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25344988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslan N., Watkin L.B., Gil A., Mishra R., Clark F.G., Welsh R.M., et al. Severity of acute infectious mononucleosis correlates with cross-reactive CD8 T-cell receptor repertoires. mBio. 2017;8 doi: 10.1128/mBio.01841-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/mBio.01841-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5717389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29208744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astani A., Reichling J., Schnitzler P. Screening for antiviral activities of isolated compounds from essential oils. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2011;2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20008902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attiq A., Yao L.J., Afzal S., Khan M.A. The triumvirate of NF-kappaB, inflammation and cytokine storm in COVID-19. Int. Immunopharm. 2021;101(Pt B)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8516728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34688149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baraniuk J.N., El-Amin S., Corey R., Rayhan R., Timbol C. Carnosine treatment for gulf war illness: a randomized controlled trial. Global J. Health Sci. 2013;5(3):69&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4209301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23618477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber D.L., Wherry E.J., Masopust D., Zhu B., Allison J.P., Sharpe A.H., et al. Restoring function in exhausted CD8 T cells during chronic viral infection. Nature. 2006;439(7077):682&#x2013;687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16382236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedree H., Sunnquist M., Jason L.A. The DePaul symptom questionnaire-2: a validation study. Fatigue. 2019;7(3):166&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7367506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32685281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bested A.C., Marshall L.M. Review of Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: an evidence-based approach to diagnosis and management by clinicians. Rev. Environ. Health. 2015;30(4):223&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26613325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyond myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: redefining an illness. Mil. Med. 2015;180(7):721&#x2013;723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26126237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C., Hudson V.M., Hilton S.C., Wilde C. A pilot study of the effect of inhaled buffered reduced glutathione on the clinical status of patients with cystic fibrosis. Chest. 2005;127(1):308&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15653998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blank C.U., Haining W.N., Held W., Hogan P.G., Kallies A., Lugli E., et al. Defining 'T cell exhaustion'. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2019;19(11):665&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7286441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31570879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bridgeman M.M., Marsden M., MacNee W., Flenley D.C., Ryle A.P. Cysteine and glutathione concentrations in plasma and bronchoalveolar lavage fluid after treatment with N-acetylcysteine. Thorax. 1991;46(1):39&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1020912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1871695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broderick G., Fuite J., Kreitz A., Vernon S.D., Klimas N., Fletcher M.A. A formal analysis of cytokine networks in chronic fatigue syndrome. Brain Behav. Immun. 2010;24(7):1209&#x2013;1217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2939140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20447453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchwald D., Cheney P.R., Peterson D.L., Henry B., Wormsley S.B., Geiger A., et al. A chronic illness characterized by fatigue, neurologic and immunologic disorders, and active human herpesvirus type 6 infection. Ann. Intern. Med. 1992;116(2):103&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1309285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buhl R., Vogelmeier C., Critenden M., Hubbard R.C., Hoyt R.F., Jr., Wilson E.M., et al. Augmentation of glutathione in the fluid lining the epithelium of the lower respiratory tract by directly administering glutathione aerosol. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 1990;87(11):4063&#x2013;4067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC54047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2349219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese C., Tosco A., Abete P., Carnovale V., Basile C., Magliocca A., et al. Randomized, single blind, controlled trial of inhaled glutathione vs placebo in patients with cystic fibrosis. J. Cyst. Fibros. 2015;14(2):203&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25458463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantin A.M., Paquette B., Richter M., Larivee P. Albumin-mediated regulation of cellular glutathione and nuclear factor kappa B activation. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 2000;162(4 Pt 1):1539&#x2013;1546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11029374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavar Zeljkovic S., Schadich E., Dzubak P., Hajduch M., Tarkowski P. Antiviral activity of selected lamiaceae essential oils and their monoterpenes against SARS-Cov-2. Front. Pharmacol. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9108200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35586050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia J.K., Chia A.Y. Chronic fatigue syndrome is associated with chronic enterovirus infection of the stomach. J. Clin. Pathol. 2008;61(1):43&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choutka J., Jansari V., Hornig M., Iwasaki A. Unexplained post-acute infection syndromes. Nat. Med. 2022;28(5):911&#x2013;923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35585196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clute S.C., Watkin L.B., Cornberg M., Naumov Y.N., Sullivan J.L., Luzuriaga K., et al. Cross-reactive influenza virus-specific CD8+ T cells contribute to lymphoproliferation in Epstein-Barr virus-associated infectious mononucleosis. J. Clin. Invest. 2005;115(12):3602&#x2013;3612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1288832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16308574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornberg M., Kenney L.L., Chen A.T., Waggoner S.N., Kim S.K., Dienes H.P., et al. Clonal exhaustion as a mechanism to protect against severe immunopathology and death from an overwhelming CD8 T cell response. Front. Immunol. 2013;4:475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3869045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24391647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahham S.S., Tabana Y.M., Iqbal M.A., Ahamed M.B., Ezzat M.O., Majid A.S., et al. The anticancer, antioxidant and antimicrobial properties of the sesquiterpene beta-caryophyllene from the essential oil of aquilaria crassna. Molecules. 2015;20(7):11808&#x2013;11829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6331975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26132906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies D.A., Adlimoghaddam A., Albensi B.C. The effect of COVID-19 on NF-kappaB and neurological manifestations of disease. Mol. Neurobiol. 2021;58(8):4178&#x2013;4187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8169418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34075562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H.E., Assaf G.S., McCorkell L., Wei H., Low R.J., Re'em Y., et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H.E., McCorkell L., Vogel J.M., Topol E.J. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2023:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dekhuijzen P.N. Antioxidant properties of N-acetylcysteine: their relevance in relation to chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Eur. Respir. J. 2004;23(4):629&#x2013;636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15083766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A., Wamil M., Alberts J., Oben J., Cuthbertson D.J., Wootton D., et al. Multiorgan impairment in low-risk individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome: a prospective, community-based study. BMJ Open. 2021;11(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher M.A., Zeng X.R., Barnes Z., Levis S., Klimas N.G. Plasma cytokines in women with chronic fatigue syndrome. J. Transl. Med. 2009;7:96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2779802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19909538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fluge O., Mella O., Bruland O., Risa K., Dyrstad S.E., Alme K., et al. Metabolic profiling indicates impaired pyruvate dehydrogenase function in myalgic encephalopathy/chronic fatigue syndrome. JCI Insight. 2016;1(21)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5161229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28018972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francomano FC A., Barbarossa A., Fazio A., La Torre C., Ceramella J., Mallamaci R., Saturnino C., Iacopetta D., Sinicropi M.S. &#x3b2;-Caryophyllene: a sesquiterpene with countless biological properties. Appl. Sci. 2019;9:5420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K., Straus S.E., Hickie I., Sharpe M.C., Dobbins J.G., Komaroff A. The chronic fatigue syndrome: a comprehensive approach to its definition and study. International Chronic Fatigue Syndrome Study Group. Ann. Intern. Med. 1994;121(12):953&#x2013;959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7978722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao F., Mallajoysula V., Arunachalam P.S., van der Ploeg K., Manohar M., Roltgen K., et al. Spheromers reveal robust T cell responses to the Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine and attenuated peripheral CD8(+) T cell responses post SARS-CoV-2 infection. Immunity. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10017386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36996809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Martinez F.J., Moreno-Artero E., Jahnke S. SARS-CoV-2 and EBV coinfection. Med. Clin. 2020;155(7):319&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32953993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geiler J., Michaelis M., Sithisarn P., Cinatl J., Jr. Comparison of pro-inflammatory cytokine expression and cellular signal transduction in human macrophages infected with different influenza A viruses. Med. Microbiol. Immunol. 2011;200(1):53&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20865277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold J.E., Okyay R.A., Licht W.E., Hurley D.J. Investigation of long COVID prevalence and its relationship to epstein-barr virus reactivation. Pathogens. 2021;10(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8233978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34204243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golomb B.A., Allison M., Koperski S., Koslik H.J., Devaraj S., Ritchie J.B. Coenzyme Q10 benefits symptoms in Gulf War veterans: results of a randomized double-blind study. Neural Comput. 2014;26(11):2594&#x2013;2651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25149705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould N.S., Min E., Gauthier S., Chu H.W., Martin R., Day B.J. Aging adversely affects the cigarette smoke-induced glutathione adaptive response in the lung. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 2010;182(9):1114&#x2013;1122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3001254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20622027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould N.S., Min E., Gauthier S., Martin R.J., Day B.J. Lung glutathione adaptive responses to cigarette smoke exposure. Respir. Res. 2011;12(1):133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3215650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21982222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould N.S., Min E., Huang J., Chu H.W., Good J., Martin R.J., et al. Glutathione depletion accelerates cigarette smoke-induced inflammation and airspace enlargement. Toxicol. Sci. 2015;147(2):466&#x2013;474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4707200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26149495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray-Rodriguez S., Jensen M.P., Otero-Jimenez M., Hanley B., Swann O.C., Ward P.A., et al. Multisystem screening reveals SARS-CoV-2 in neurons of the myenteric plexus and in megakaryocytes. J. Pathol. 2022;257(2):198&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9325073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35107828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greiner J.F., Muller J., Zeuner M.T., Hauser S., Seidel T., Klenke C., et al. 1,8-Cineol inhibits nuclear translocation of NF-kappaB p65 and NF-kappaB-dependent transcriptional activity. Biochim. Biophys. Acta. 2013;1833(12):2866&#x2013;2878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23872422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara S.I., Ishii Y., Kitamura S. Aerosolized administration of N-acetylcysteine attenuates lung fibrosis induced by bleomycin in mice. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 2000;162(1):225&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10903246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardcastle S.L., Brenu E.W., Johnston S., Nguyen T., Huth T., Ramos S., et al. Serum immune proteins in moderate and severe chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis patients. Int. J. Med. Sci. 2015;12(10):764&#x2013;772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4615236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26516304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson T.A. Valacyclovir treatment of chronic fatigue in adolescents. Adv. Mind Body Med. 2014;28(1):4&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24445302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill E., Mehta H., Sharma S., Mane K., Xie C., Cathey E., et al. medRxiv; 2022. Risk Factors Associated with Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 in an EHR Cohort: A National COVID Cohort Collaborative (N3C) Analysis as Part of the NIH RECOVER Program.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgin K.S., Donovan E.K., Kekes-Szabo S., Lin J.C., Feick J., Massey R.L., et al. A placebo-controlled, pseudo-randomized, crossover trial of botanical agents for gulf war illness: resveratrol (polygonum cuspidatum), luteolin, and fisetin (rhus succedanea) Int. J. Environ. Res. Publ. Health. 2021;18(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33802381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holroyd K.J., Buhl R., Borok Z., Roum J.H., Bokser A.D., Grimes G.J., et al. Correction of glutathione deficiency in the lower respiratory tract of HIV seropositive individuals by glutathione aerosol treatment. Thorax. 1993;48(10):985&#x2013;989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC464806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8256245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homma S., Azuma A., Taniguchi H., Ogura T., Mochiduki Y., Sugiyama Y., et al. Efficacy of inhaled N-acetylcysteine monotherapy in patients with early stage idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Respirology. 2012;17(3):467&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22257422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornig M., Montoya J.G., Klimas N.G., Levine S., Felsenstein D., Bateman L., et al. Distinct plasma immune signatures in ME/CFS are present early in the course of illness. Sci. Adv. 2015;1(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26079000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang IP R. Lymphopenia in severe coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-10): systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Intensive Care. 2020;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32483488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jager W., Nasel B., Nasel C., Binder R., Stimpfl T., Vycudilik W., et al. Pharmacokinetic studies of the fragrance compound 1,8-cineol in humans during inhalation. Chem. Senses. 1996;21(4):477&#x2013;480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8866111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimenez-Guardeno J.M., Ortega-Prieto A.M., Menendez Moreno B., Maguire T.J.A., Richardson A., Diaz-Hernandez J.I., et al. Drug repurposing based on a quantum-inspired method versus classical fingerprinting uncovers potential antivirals against SARS-CoV-2. PLoS Comput. Biol. 2022;18(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9333455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35849631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson C.  Health Rising; 2022. The ME/CFS Coronavirus Vaccine Side Effects Poll Update + the New Severely Ill Vaccine Side-Effects Poll.https://www.healthrising.org/blog/2021/03/17/coronavirus-vaccine-poll-chronic-fatigue-fibromyalgia-severely-ill/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson C.  Health Rising; 2023. &#x201c;Long Vax&#x201d; (Coronavirus Vaccine-Induced Injury) Starting to Make Inroads in the Medical Community.https://www.healthrising.org/blog/2023/08/01/long-vax-coronavirus-vaccine-injury-inroads-medical-community/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juergens U.R., Dethlefsen U., Steinkamp G., Gillissen A., Repges R., Vetter H. Anti-inflammatory activity of 1.8-cineol (eucalyptol) in bronchial asthma: a double-blind placebo-controlled trial. Respir. Med. 2003;97(3):250&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12645832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juergens U.R., Engelen T., Racke K., Stober M., Gillissen A., Vetter H. Inhibitory activity of 1,8-cineol (eucalyptol) on cytokine production in cultured human lymphocytes and monocytes. Pulm. Pharmacol. Ther. 2004;17(5):281&#x2013;287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15477123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juergens L.J., Tuleta I., Stoeber M., Racke&#xb4; K., Juergens U.R. Regulation of monocyte redox balance by 1,8-cineole (eucalyptol) controls oxidative stress and pro-inflammatory responses in vitro: a new option to increase the antioxidant effects of combined respiratory therapy with budesonide and formoterol? Synergy. 2018;7:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juergens L.J., Worth H., Juergens U.R. New perspectives for mucolytic, anti-inflammatory and adjunctive therapy with 1,8-cineole in COPD and asthma: review on the new therapeutic approach. Adv. Ther. 2020;37(5):1737&#x2013;1753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7467491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32200535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasimir F., Toomey D., Liu Z., Kaiping A.C., Ariza M.E., Prusty B.K. Tissue specific signature of HHV6 infection in ME/CFS. Front. Mol. Biosci. 2022;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9795011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedor C., Freitag H., Meyer-Arndt L., Wittke K., Hanitsch L.G., Zoller T., et al. A prospective observational study of post-COVID-19 chronic fatigue syndrome following the first pandemic wave in Germany and biomarkers associated with symptom severity. Nat. Commun. 2022;13(1):5104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9426365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36042189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy-Feitosa E., Okuro R.T., Pinho Ribeiro V., Lanzetti M., Barroso M.V., Zin W.A., et al. Eucalyptol attenuates cigarette smoke-induced acute lung inflammation and oxidative stress in the mouse. Pulm. Pharmacol. Ther. 2016;41:11&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27599597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S.Y., Solomon D.H. Tumor necrosis factor blockade and the risk of viral infection. Nat. Rev. Rheumatol. 2010;6(3):165&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3155180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20142812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K.Y., Seo H.J., Min S.S., Park M., Seol G.H. The effect of 1,8-cineole inhalation on preoperative anxiety: a randomized clinical trial. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2014;2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4083598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25028591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K.Y., Lee H.S., Seol G.H. Eucalyptol suppresses matrix metalloproteinase-9 expression through an extracellular signal-regulated kinase-dependent nuclear factor-kappa B pathway to exert anti-inflammatory effects in an acute lung inflammation model. J. Pharm. Pharmacol. 2015;67(8):1066&#x2013;1074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25773735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim E.H., Lee B.W., Ryu B., Cho H.M., Kim S.M., Jang S.G., et al. Inhibition of a broad range of SARS-CoV-2 variants by antiviral phytochemicals in hACE2 mice. Antivir. Res. 2022;204</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9239703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35777669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J., Wood J., Jaycox J., Lu P., Dhodapkar R.M., Gehlhausen J.R., et al. Distinguishing features of Long COVID identified through immune profiling. medRxiv. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10620090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37748514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A., Kumar P., Dungdung A., Kumar Gupta A., Anurag A., Kumar A. Pattern of liver function and clinical profile in COVID-19: a cross-sectional study of 91 patients. Diabetes Metabol. Syndr. 2020;14(6):1951&#x2013;1954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33039937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Balc'h P., Pinceaux K., Pronier C., Seguin P., Tadie J.M., Reizine F. Herpes simplex virus and cytomegalovirus reactivations among severe COVID-19 patients. Crit. Care. 2020;24(1):530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7453668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32859241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehner G.F., Klein S.J., Zoller H., Peer A., Bellmann R., Joannidis M. Correlation of interleukin-6 with Epstein-Barr virus levels in COVID-19. Crit. Care. 2020;24(1):657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7682685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33228750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Lai Y., Wang Y., Liu N., Zhang F., Xu P. 1, 8-cineol protect against influenza-virus-induced pneumonia in mice. Inflammation. 2016;39(4):1582&#x2013;1593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27351430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Wei X., Chen C., Zhang Z., Liu D., Hei Z., et al. N-Acetylcysteine inhalation improves pulmonary function in patients received liver transplantation. Biosci. Rep. 2018;38(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6165840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30217943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima P.R., de Melo T.S., Carvalho K.M., de Oliveira I.B., Arruda B.R., de Castro Brito G.A., et al. 1,8-cineole (eucalyptol) ameliorates cerulein-induced acute pancreatitis via modulation of cytokines, oxidative stress and NF-kappaB activity in mice. Life Sci. 2013;92(24&#x2013;26):1195&#x2013;1201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23702424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou H., Kaplowitz N. Glutathione depletion down-regulates tumor necrosis factor alpha-induced NF-kappaB activity via IkappaB kinase-dependent and -independent mechanisms. J. Biol. Chem. 2007;282(40):29470&#x2013;29481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17690092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado K.D.C., Islam M.T., Ali E.S., Rouf R., Uddin S.J., Dev S., et al. A systematic review on the neuroprotective perspectives of beta-caryophyllene. Phytother Res. 2018;32(12):2376&#x2013;2388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30281175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M., Kubera M., Uytterhoeven M., Vrydags N., Bosmans E. Increased plasma peroxides as a marker of oxidative stress in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) Med. Sci. Mon. Int. Med. J. Exp. Clin. Res. 2011;17(4):SC11&#x2013;S15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3539515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21455120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M., Twisk F.N., Kubera M., Ringel K. Evidence for inflammation and activation of cell-mediated immunity in Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS): increased interleukin-1, tumor necrosis factor-alpha, PMN-elastase, lysozyme and neopterin. J. Affect. Disord. 2012;136(3):933&#x2013;939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21975140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M., Twisk F.N., Johnson C. Myalgic Encephalomyelitis (ME), Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (CFS), and Chronic Fatigue (CF) are distinguished accurately: results of supervised learning techniques applied on clinical and inflammatory data. Psychiatr. Res. 2012;200(2&#x2013;3):754&#x2013;760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22521895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M., Kubera M., Stoyanova K., Leunis J.C. The reification of the clinical diagnosis of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) as an immune and oxidative stress disorder: construction of a data-driven nomothethic network and exposure of ME/CFS subgroups. Curr. Top. Med. Chem. 2021;21(16):1488&#x2013;1499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34315375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandarano A.H., Maya J., Giloteaux L., Peterson D.L., Maynard M., Gottschalk C.G., et al. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients exhibit altered T cell metabolism and cytokine associations. J. Clin. Invest. 2020;130(3):1491&#x2013;1505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7269566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31830003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLane L.M., Abdel-Hakeem M.S., Wherry E.J. CD8 T cell exhaustion during chronic viral infection and cancer. Annu. Rev. Immunol. 2019;37:457&#x2013;495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30676822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellman I., Hubbard-Lucey V.M., Tontonoz M.J., Kalos M.D., Chen D.S., Allison J.P., et al. De-risking immunotherapy: report of a consensus workshop of the cancer immunotherapy consortium of the cancer research Institute. Cancer Immunol. Res. 2016;4(4):279&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27036972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris G., Walder K., Puri B.K., Berk M., Maes M. The deleterious effects of oxidative and nitrosative stress on palmitoylation, membrane lipid rafts and lipid-based cellular signalling: new drug targets in neuroimmune disorders. Mol. Neurobiol. 2016;53(7):4638&#x2013;4658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26310971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naviaux R.K., Naviaux J.C., Li K., Bright A.T., Alaynick W.A., Wang L., et al. Metabolic features of chronic fatigue syndrome. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2016;113(37):E5472&#x2013;E5480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5027464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27573827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naviaux R.K., Naviaux J.C., Li K., Bright A.T., Alaynick W.A., Wang L., et al. Reply to Vogt et al.: metabolomics and chronic fatigue syndrome. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2016;113(46):E7142&#x2013;E7143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5135342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27810963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nencioni L., Iuvara A., Aquilano K., Ciriolo M.R., Cozzolino F., Rotilio G., et al. Influenza A virus replication is dependent on an antioxidant pathway that involves GSH and Bcl-2. FASEB J. 2003;17(6):758&#x2013;760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12594179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Neal A.J., Hanson M.R. The enterovirus theory of disease etiology in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a critical review. Front. Med. 2021;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8253308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34222292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oka S., Kamata H., Kamata K., Yagisawa H., Hirata H. N-acetylcysteine suppresses TNF-induced NF-kappaB activation through inhibition of IkappaB kinases. FEBS Lett. 2000;472(2&#x2013;3):196&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10788610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pajaro-Castro N.F.M.C., Ocazionez R., Stashenko E., Olivero-Verbel J. Potential interaction of components from essential oils with dengue virus proteins. Bol. Latinoam. Caribe Plantas Med. Aromat. 2015;14:141&#x2013;155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pall M.L. Elevated nitric oxide/peroxynitrite theory of multiple chemical sensitivity: central role of N-methyl-D-aspartate receptors in the sensitivity mechanism. Environ. Health Perspect. 2003;111(12):1461&#x2013;1464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1241647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12948884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panahi Y., Ghanei M., Rahimi M., Samim A., Vahedian-Azimi A., Atkin S.L., et al. Evaluation the efficacy and safety of N-acetylcysteine inhalation spray in controlling the symptoms of patients with COVID-19: an open-label randomized controlled clinical trial. J. Med. Virol. 2023;95(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9878233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36495185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauken K.E., Dougan M., Rose N.R., Lichtman A.H., Sharpe A.H. Adverse events following cancer immunotherapy: obstacles and opportunities. Trends Immunol. 2019;40(6):511&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6527345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31053497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul B.D., Lemle M.D., Komaroff A.L., Snyder S.H. Redox imbalance links COVID-19 and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2021;118(34)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8403932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34400495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulin F.V., Zagatto A.M., Chiappa G.R., Muller P.T. Addition of vitamin B12 to exercise training improves cycle ergometer endurance in advanced COPD patients: a randomized and controlled study. Respir. Med. 2017;122:23&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27993287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso M.J., Ryder D., Flavell R., Wang Y., Levi J., LaFranchi B.H., et al. medRxiv; 2023. Multimodal Molecular Imaging Reveals Tissue-Based T Cell Activation and Viral RNA Persistence for up to 2 Years Following COVID-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pender M.P., Csurhes P.A., Burrows J.M., Burrows S.R. Defective T-cell control of Epstein-Barr virus infection in multiple sclerosis. Clin Transl Immunology. 2017;6(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5292561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28197337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pender M.P., Csurhes P.A., Smith C., Douglas N.L., Neller M.A., Matthews K.K., et al. Epstein-Barr virus-specific T cell therapy for progressive multiple sclerosis. JCI Insight. 2018;3(22)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6302936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30429369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pendergrast T., Brown A., Sunnquist M., Jantke R., Newton J.L., Strand E.B., et al. Housebound versus nonhousebound patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis and chronic fatigue syndrome. Chron. Illness. 2016;12(4):292&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5464362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27127189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C., Darley D.R., Wilson D.B., Howe A., Munier C.M.L., Patel S.K., et al. Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat. Immunol. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal A.D., VanElzakker M.B. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): an overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front. Microbiol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prousky J. The treatment of pulmonary diseases and respiratory-related conditions with inhaled (nebulized or aerosolized) glutathione. Evid. base Compl. Alternative Med. 2007;5(1):27&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2249747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18317545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhoden C.R., Lawrence J., Godleski J.J., Gonzalez-Flecha B. N-acetylcysteine prevents lung inflammation after short-term inhalation exposure to concentrated ambient particles. Toxicol. Sci. 2004;79(2):296&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roederer M., Staal F.J., Raju P.A., Ela S.W., Herzenberg L.A., Herzenberg L.A. Cytokine-stimulated human immunodeficiency virus replication is inhibited by N-acetyl-L-cysteine. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 1990;87(12):4884&#x2013;4888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC54223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2112750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell L., Broderick G., Taylor R., Fernandes H., Harvey J., Barnes Z., et al. Illness progression in chronic fatigue syndrome: a shifting immune baseline. BMC Immunol. 2016;17:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4785654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26965484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusznak C., Mills P.R., Devalia J.L., Sapsford R.J., Davies R.J., Lozewicz S. Effect of cigarette smoke on the permeability and IL-1beta and sICAM-1 release from cultured human bronchial epithelial cells of never-smokers, smokers, and patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am. J. Respir. Cell Mol. Biol. 2000;23(4):530&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santella C., Bitton A., Filliter C., Bessissow T., Vutcovici M., Lakatos P.L., et al. Anti-TNF therapy and the risk of herpes zoster among patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Inflamm. Bowel Dis. 2022;28(2):176&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33999136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selin L.K., Wlodarczyk M.F., Kraft A.R., Nie S., Kenney L.L., Puzone R., et al. Heterologous immunity: immunopathology, autoimmunity and protection during viral infections. Autoimmunity. 2011;44(4):328&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3633594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21250837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith F.J., Monto R.W., Rebuck J.W. B12 inhalation therapy in pernicious anemia. Trans. Am. Clin. Climatol. Assoc. 1952;64:27&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2248818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13136209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon B.J., Loong H.H., Summers Y., Thomas Z.M., French P., Lin B.K., et al. Correlation between treatment effects on response rate and progression-free survival and overall survival in trials of targeted therapies in molecularly enriched populations. ESMO Open. 2022;7(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9058889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35183043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straface E., Matarrese P., Gambardella L., Forte S., Carlone S., Libianchi E., et al. N-Acetylcysteine counteracts erythrocyte alterations occurring in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 2000;279(2):552&#x2013;556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11118324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudhoff H., Klenke C., Greiner J.F., Muller J., Brotzmann V., Ebmeyer J., et al. 1,8-Cineol reduces mucus-production in a novel human ex vivo model of late rhinosinusitis. PLoS One. 2015;10(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4514714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26207629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takatsuka H., Wakae T., Mori A., Okada M., Fujimori Y., Takemoto Y., et al. Endothelial damage caused by cytomegalovirus and human herpesvirus-6. Bone Marrow Transplant. 2003;31(6):475&#x2013;479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12665843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takemoto Y., Kishi C., Sugiura Y., Yoshioka Y., Matsumura S., Moriyama T., et al. Distribution of inhaled volatile beta-caryophyllene and dynamic changes of liver metabolites in mice. Sci. Rep. 2021;11(1):1728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7813867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33462287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M., Dercon Q., Luciano S., Geddes J.R., Husain M., Harrison P.J. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 2021;18(9)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unger E.R., Lin J.S., Tian H., Natelson B.H., Lange G., Vu D., et al. Multi-site clinical assessment of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (MCAM): design and implementation of a prospective/retrospective rolling cohort study. Am. J. Epidemiol. 2017;185(8):617&#x2013;626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5565838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28338983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdez A.R., Hancock E.E., Adebayo S., Kiernicki D.J., Proskauer D., Attewell J.R., et al. Estimating prevalence, demographics, and costs of ME/CFS using large scale medical claims data and machine learning. Front Pediatr. 2019;6:412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6331450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30671425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Doren W.W., Iqbal U.H., Helmer D.A., Litke D.R., Simon J.E., Wu Q., et al. Changes in polyphenol serum levels and cognitive performance after dietary supplementation with Concord grape juice in veterans with Gulf War Illness. Life Sci. 2022;292</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9267469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34237311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma D., Church T.M., Swaminathan S. Epstein-Barr virus co-opts TFIIH component XPB to specifically activate essential viral lytic promoters. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2020;117(23):13044&#x2013;13055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7293708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32434920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter R., Hartmann K., Fleisch F., Reinhart W.H., Kuhn M. Reactivation of herpesvirus infections after vaccinations? Lancet. 1999;353(9155):810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10459967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Chen X., Pan J., Zhang X., Zhang L. Epstein-barr virus and human cytomegalovirus infection in intestinal mucosa of Chinese patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Front. Microbiol. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9195000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35711779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watt T., Oberfoell S., Balise R., Lunn M.R., Kar A.K., Merrihew L., et al. Response to valganciclovir in chronic fatigue syndrome patients with human herpesvirus 6 and Epstein-Barr virus IgG antibody titers. J. Med. Virol. 2012;84(12):1967&#x2013;1974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23080504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsh R.M., Selin L.K. No one is naive: the significance of heterologous T-cell immunity. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2002;2(6):417&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12093008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenzel J., Lampe J., Muller-Fielitz H., Schuster R., Zille M., Muller K., et al. The SARS-CoV-2 main protease M(pro) causes microvascular brain pathology by cleaving NEMO in brain endothelial cells. Nat. Neurosci. 2021;24(11):1522&#x2013;1533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8553622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34675436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams T.L.J. A comparison of nebulized vitamin B12 versus oral vitamin B12 supplementation (Ph.D. Dissertation.) Theses and Dissertations.Ph.D. Dissertation. 2013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood E., Hall K.H., Tate W. Role of mitochondria, oxidative stress and the response to antioxidants in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a possible approach to SARS-CoV-2 'long-haulers'. Chronic Dis Transl Med. 2021;7(1):14&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7680046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33251031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J. Tackle the free radicals damage in COVID-19. Nitric Oxide. 2020;102:39&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32562746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J.W.W., Zhong X.X., Feng Y., Wei X., Liu X.G. EXPRESS: methylcobalamin ameliorates neuropathic pain induced by vincristine in rats: effect on loss of peripheral nerve fibers and imbalance of cytokines in the spinal dorsal horn. Mol. Pain. 2016;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4956006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27306413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav N., Chandra H. Suppression of inflammatory and infection responses in lung macrophages by eucalyptus oil and its constituent 1,8-cineole: role of pattern recognition receptors TREM-1 and NLRP3, the MAP kinase regulator MKP-1, and NFkappaB. PLoS One. 2017;12(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5687727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29141025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada K., Toyota K., Tsunoda Y., Matahira Y., Matsumura S., Yoshioka Y., et al. Effects of inhaled beta-caryophyllene on vascular stiffness in smokers: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Exp. Ther. Med. 2023;25(1):57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9780513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36588810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamano E., Sugimoto M., Hirayama A., Kume S., Yamato M., Jin G., et al. Index markers of chronic fatigue syndrome with dysfunction of TCA and urea cycles. Sci. Rep. 2016;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5057083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27725700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z., Wu N., Fu Y., Yang G., Wang W., Zu Y., et al. Anti-infectious bronchitis virus (IBV) activity of 1,8-cineole: effect on nucleocapsid (N) protein. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2010;28(3):323&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20919748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Zhao S., Cao Z. Impact of Epstein-Barr virus infection in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Front. Immunol. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9651941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36389673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>