<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37936547</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2222</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical and experimental allergy : journal of the British Society for Allergy and Clinical Immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Exp Allergy</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Allergic diseases as risk factors for Long-COVID symptoms: Systematic review of prospective cohort studies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1162</StartPage><EndPage>1176</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1162-1176</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/cea.14391</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The role of allergy as a risk factor for Long-COVID (LC) is unclear and has not been thoroughly examined yet. We aimed to systematically review and appraise the epidemiological evidence on allergic diseases as risk factors for LC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN">This is an initial systematic review. Two reviewers independently performed the study selection and data extraction using Covidence. Risk of bias (RoB) and certainty of evidence (GRADE) were assessed. Random effects meta-analyses were used to pool unadjusted ORs within homogeneous data subsets.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES">We retrieved articles published between January 1st, 2020 and January 19th, 2023 from MEDLINE via PubMed, Scopus, the WHO-COVID-19 database and the LOVE platform (Epistemonikos Foundation). In addition, citations and reference lists were searched.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA">We included prospective cohort studies recruiting individuals of all ages with confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection that were followed up for at least 12&#x2009;months for LC symptoms where information on pre-existing allergic diseases was available. We excluded all study designs that were not prospective cohort studies and all publication types that were not original articles.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We identified 13 studies (9967 participants, range 39-1950 per study), all assessed as high RoB, due to population selection and methods used to ascertain the exposures and the outcome. Four studies did not provide sufficient data to calculate Odds Ratios. The evidence supported a possible relationship between LC and allergy, but was very uncertain. For example, pre-existing asthma measured in hospital-based populations (6 studies, 4019 participants) may be associated with increased risk of LC (Odds Ratio 1.94, 95% CI 1.08, 3.50) and findings were similar for pre-existing rhinitis (3 studies, 1141 participants; Odds Ratio 1.96, 95% CI 1.61, 2.39), both very low certainty evidence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Pre-existing asthma or rhinitis may increase the risk of LC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Clinical &amp; Experimental Allergy published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolff</LastName><ForeName>Doreen</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8359-7815</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Social Medicine and Health Systems Research, University of Magdeburg, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drewitz</LastName><ForeName>Karl Philipp</ForeName><Initials>KP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0808-1987</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Social Medicine and Health Systems Research, University of Magdeburg, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ulrich</LastName><ForeName>Angela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-0833-1676</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Social Medicine and Health Systems Research, University of Magdeburg, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siegels</LastName><ForeName>Doreen</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4049-9120</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Evidence-Based Healthcare, University Hospital and Medical Faculty Carl Gustav Carus, Technical University Dresden, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deckert</LastName><ForeName>Stefanie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4889-3632</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Evidence-Based Healthcare, University Hospital and Medical Faculty Carl Gustav Carus, Technical University Dresden, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sprenger</LastName><ForeName>Antonia Anabella</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1180-7702</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Social Medicine and Health Systems Research, University of Magdeburg, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuper</LastName><ForeName>Paula Ricarda</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7481-976X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Social Medicine and Health Systems Research, University of Magdeburg, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schmitt</LastName><ForeName>Jochen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0264-0960</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Evidence-Based Healthcare, University Hospital and Medical Faculty Carl Gustav Carus, Technical University Dresden, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Munblit</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9652-6856</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Care for Long Term Conditions Division, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Apfelbacher</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3805-8219</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Social Medicine and Health Systems Research, University of Magdeburg, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine and Primary Care, Lee Kong Chian School of Medicine, Nanyang Technological University Singapore, Singapore City, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Bundesministerium f&#xfc;r Bildung und Forschung</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Exp Allergy</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8906443</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0954-7894</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Neurosciences (Riyadh). 2024 Jan;29(1):68.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">38195129</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012220" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rhinitis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001249" MajorTopicYN="Y">Asthma</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">allergy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">asthma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37936547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cea.14391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Callard F, Perego E. How and why patients made long Covid. Soc Sci Med. 2021;268:113426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emergency use ICD codes for COVID-19. Disease outbreak. 2021 https://www.who.int/standards/classifications/classification-of-diseases/emergency-use-icd-codes-for-covid-19-disease-outbreak. [Accessed April 20, 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koczulla AR, Ankermann T, Behrends U, et al. S1-Leitlinie Post-COVID/Long-COVID. AWMF; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampasian V, Elghazaly H, Chattopadhyay R, et al. Risk factors associated with post-COVID-19 condition: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Intern Med. 2023;183:e230750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Overview|COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19|Guidance|NICE. NICE. 2021. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188. [Accessed April 20, 2023.]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, O'Hara ME, Akrami A, Perego E, Olliaro P, Needham DM. Long COVID: aiming for a consensus. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10(7):632-634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chhiba KD, Patel GB, Vu THT, et al. Prevalence and characterization of asthma in hospitalized and nonhospitalized patients with COVID-19. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2020;146(2):307-314.e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chippa V, Aleem A, Anjum F. Post Acute Coronavirus (COVID-19) Syndrome. StatPearls Publishing; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond). 2021;53(10):737-754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boscolo-Rizzo P, Guida F, Polesel J, et al. Sequelae in adults at 12 months after mild-to-moderate coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Int Forum Allergy Rhinol. 2021;11(12):1685-1688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bliddal S, Banasik K, Pedersen OB, et al. Acute and persistent symptoms in non-hospitalized PCR-confirmed COVID-19 patients. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):13153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KG-I, Brokstad KA, et al. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med. 2021;27(9):1607-1613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):16144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanichkachorn G, Newcomb R, Cowl CT, et al. Post-COVID-19 syndrome (long haul syndrome): description of a multidisciplinary Clinic at Mayo Clinic and Characteristics of the initial patient cohort. Mayo Clin Proc. 2021;96(7):1782-1791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozak R, Armstrong SM, Salvant E, et al. Recognition of long-covid-19 patients in a Canadian tertiary hospital setting: a retrospective analysis of their clinical and laboratory characteristics. Pathogens. 2021;10(10):1246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballering AV, van Zon SKR, Olde Hartman TC, Rosmalen JGM. Persistence of somatic symptoms after COVID-19 in The Netherlands: an observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022;400(10350):452-461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestre-Mu&#xf1;iz MM, Arias &#xc1;, Mata-V&#xe1;zquez E, et al. Long-term outcomes of patients with coronavirus disease 2019 at one year after hospital discharge. J Clin Med. 2021;10(13):2945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220-232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Schneider C, Laurent E, Lemaignen A, et al. Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27(2):258-263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doykov I, H&#xe4;llqvist J, Gilmour KC, Grandjean L, Mills K, Heywood WE. The long tail of Covid-19&#x2032; - the detection of a prolonged inflammatory response after a SARS-CoV-2 infection in asymptomatic and mildly affected patients. F1000Res. 2020;9:1349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A, Cuthbertson DJ, Wootton D, et al. Multi-organ impairment and long COVID: a 1-year prospective, longitudinal cohort study. J R Soc Med. 2023;116(3):97-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarte KI, de Oliveira MHS, Peligro PJ, et al. Age, sex and previous comorbidities as risk factors not associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection for long COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Med. 2022;11(24):7314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philip KEJ, Buttery S, Williams P, et al. Impact of COVID-19 on people with asthma: a mixed methods analysis from a UK wide survey. BMJ Open Respir Res. 2022;9(1):e001056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Library of Medicine PubMed User Guide: COVID-19 article filters. National Library of Medicine. 2023. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/help/#covid19-article-filters. [Accessed April 20, 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PubMed. covid-19 - Search Results - PubMed. PubMed 2021. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=covid-19. [Accessed July 1, 2021].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero Starke K, Kofahl M, Freiberg A, et al. Are daycare Workers at a Higher Risk of parvovirus B19 infection? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16(8):1392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann H, Bro&#x17c;ek J, Guyatt G, Oxman AD. GRADE handbook: Handbook for grading the quality of evidence and the strength of recommendations using the GRADE approach. Updated October 2021. Sch&#xfc;nemann H, Bro&#x17c;ek J, Guyatt G, Oxman AD 2013. https://guidelinedevelopment.org/handbook. [Accessed June 11, 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GRADEpro GDT. GRADEpro Guideline Development Tool. McMaster University and Evidence Prime; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santesso N, Glenton C, Dahm P, et al. GRADE guidelines 26: informative statements to communicate the findings of systematic reviews of interventions. J Clin Epidemiol. 2020;119:126-135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantel N, Haenszel W. Statistical aspects of the analysis of data from retrospective studies of disease. J Natl Cancer Inst. 1959;22(4):719-748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robins J, Greenland S, Breslow NE. A general estimator for the variance of the Mantel-Haenszel odds ratio. Am J Epidemiol. 1986;124(5):719-723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paule RC, Mandel J. Consensus values and weighting factors. J Res Natl Bur Stand. 1982;87(5):377-385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knapp G, Hartung J. Improved tests for a random effects meta-regression with a single covariate. Stat Med. 2003;22(17):2693-2710.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG. Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2002;21(11):1539-1558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Davey Smith G, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ. 1997;315(7109):629-634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical. R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balduzzi S, R&#xfc;cker G, Schwarzer G. How to perform a meta-analysis with R: a practical tutorial. Evid Based Ment Health. 2019;22(4):153-160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Guijarro C, Plaza-Canteli S, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Barrera V, Torres-Macho J. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 cough one year after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a multicenter study. Lung. 2021;199(3):249-253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Zuil M, Ben&#xed;tez ID, et al. One year overview and follow-up in a post-COVID consultation of critically ill patients. Front Med. 2022;9:897990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catal&#xe1;n IP, Mart&#xed; CR, La Sota DP, et al. Corticosteroids for COVID-19 symptoms and quality of life at 1 year from admission. J Med Virol. 2022;94(1):205-210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia C, Zurbuchen Y, Taeschler P, et al. Immunoglobulin signature predicts risk of post-acute Covid-19 syndrome. Nat Commun. 2021:446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marando M, Fusi-Schmidhauser T, Tamburello A, et al. 1-year radiological, functional and quality-of-life outcomes in patients with SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia - a prospective observational study. NPJ Prim Care Respir Med. 2022;32(1):8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Yang C, An X, et al. Follow-up study on COVID-19 survivors one year after discharge from hospital. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;112:173-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rank A, Tzortzini A, Kling E, et al. One year after mild COVID-19: the majority of patients maintain specific immunity, but one in four still suffer from long-term symptoms. J Clin Med. 2021;10(15):3305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fumagalli C, Zocchi C, Tassetti L, et al. Factors associated with persistence of symptoms 1 year after COVID-19: a longitudinal, prospective phone-based interview follow-up cohort study. Eur J Intern Med. 2022;97:36-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer A, Zhang L, Elb&#xe9;ji A, et al. Long COVID symptomatology after 12 months and its impact on quality of life according to initial coronavirus disease 2019 disease severity. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2022;9(8):ofac397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pazukhina E, Andreeva M, Spiridonova E, et al. Prevalence and risk factors of post-COVID-19 condition in adults and children at 6 and 12 months after hospital discharge: a prospective, cohort study in Moscow (StopCOVID). BMC Med. 2022;20(1):244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almutairi DM, Almalki AH, Mirza AA, et al. Patterns of self-reported recovery from chemosensory dysfunction following SARS-CoV-2 infection: insights after 1 year of the pandemic. Acta Otolaryngol. 2022;142(3-4):333-339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs ET, Catalfamo CJ, Colombo PM, et al. Pre-existing conditions associated with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. J Autoimmun. 2023;135:102991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng J, Yu X, Bao H, et al. Chronic diseases as a predictor for severity and mortality of COVID-19: a systematic review with cumulative meta-analysis. Front Med. 2021;8:588013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO COVID-19 Research Database. World Health Organization. https://search.bvsalud.org/global-literature-on-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/. [Accessed April 20, 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooke BS, Schwartz TA, Pawlik TM. MOOSE reporting guidelines for meta-analyses of observational studies. JAMA Surg. 2021;156(8):787-788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappelmann N, Dantzer R, Khandaker GM. Interleukin-6 as potential mediator of long-term neuropsychiatric symptoms of COVID-19. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2021;131:105295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulthei&#xdf; C, Willscher E, Paschold L, et al. Liquid biomarkers of macrophage dysregulation and circulating spike protein illustrate the biological heterogeneity in patients with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. J Med Virol. 2023;95(1):e28364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin J-X, Agbana YL, Sun Z-S, et al. Increased interleukin-6 is associated with long COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Infect Dis Poverty. 2023;12(1):43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>University Health Network. CANCOV-Study. University Health Network; 2023. https://cancov.net/about-us/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connecting European Cohorts to Increase Common and Effective Response to SARS-CoV-2 Pandemic. ORCHESTRA. https://orchestra-cohort.eu/. [Accessed April 20, 2023.]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn A, Krist L, Lieb W, et al. Long-term health sequelae and quality of life at least 6 months after infection with SARS-CoV-2: design and rationale of the COVIDOM-study as part of the NAPKON population-based cohort platform (POP). Infection. 2021;49(6):1277-1287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurth F, Roennefarth M, Thibeault C, et al. Studying the pathophysiology of coronavirus disease 2019: a protocol for the Berlin prospective COVID-19 patient cohort (Pa-COVID-19). Infection. 2020;48(4):619-626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wild JM, Porter JC, Molyneaux PL, et al. Understanding the burden of interstitial lung disease post-COVID-19: the UK interstitial lung disease-long COVID study (UKILD-long COVID). BMJ open Respir Res. 2021;8(1):e001049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, Nicholson T, Akrami A, et al. A core outcome set for post-COVID-19 condition in adults for use in clinical practice and research: an international Delphi consensus study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10(7):715-724.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>