<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36643174</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1877-0509</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>216</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Procedia computer science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Procedia Comput Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Developing an online information portal for enhancing society awareness of RPTRA (A case study RPTRA MAYA ASRI 13).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>144</StartPage><EndPage>150</EndPage><MedlinePgn>144-150</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.procs.2022.12.121</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The long COVID-19 pandemic has limited the activities of Ruang Publik Terpadu Ramah Anak (RPTRA) such as environment cleaning, repair of RPTRA infrastructure, learning and others, as well as the lack of public awareness about the existence and importance of RPTRA to the public and foreign tourists encouraging the RPTRA to make changes in the dissemination of information about the activities carried out in the RPTRA through the use of technology to survive and grow even during the Covid-19 Pandemic. The methodology used in this research is Group Discussion Forum with the administrators of the RPTRA Maya ASRI 13 to learn about the needs and expectations of the RPTRA administrators regarding the web portal to be built. Then, the implementation of the conceptual model, development, and evaluation of the effectiveness of the RPTRA information web portal was carried out. The contribution in this research is to implement a conceptual model on the information portal built on the platform of the Website with the PHP framework, which is then evaluated on the results of the pre-test and post-test about RPTRA the Wilcoxon-Signed Rank Test to test the effectiveness of the information web portal for general users. The results obtained from these tests indicate that the RPTRA Information Web Portal can help the public learn more about the existence of RPTRA Maya Asri 13.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arifin</LastName><ForeName>Yulyani</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computer Science Departement, BINUS Graduate Program - Doctor of Computer Science, Bina Nusantara University, Jakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gunawan</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth Paskahlia</ForeName><Initials>EP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computer Science Department, School of Computer Science, Bina Nusantara University, Jakarta 11480, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohyver</LastName><ForeName>Margaretha</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Statistics Department, School of Computer Science, Bina Nusantara University, Jakarta 11480, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Procedia Comput Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101537771</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PHP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RPTRA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">The Covid-19 Pandemic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Web Portal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Web Technology</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36643174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9829422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procs.2022.12.121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1877-0509(22)02199-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Honey-Ros&#xe9;s J, Anguelovski I, Chireh VK, Daher C, Konijnendijk van den Bosch C, Litt JS, et al. The impact of covid-19 on public space: An early review of the emerging questions &#x2013; design, perceptions and inequities. Cities &amp; Health. 2020;5 doi: 10.1080/23748834.2020.1780074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23748834.2020.1780074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rustanto AE, Akhmad J. RPTRA activities program in services to the community during the COVID-19 pandemic. Advances in Social Science, Education and Humanities Research 2021. doi:10.2991/assehr.k.210430.014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldschmidt K. The COVID-19 pandemic: Technology use to support the wellbeing of children. Journal of Pediatric Nursing. 2020;53:88&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7161478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32317129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanna RC, Cicinelli MV, Gilbert SS, Honavar SG, Murthy GSV. Covid-19 pandemic: Lessons learned and future directions. Indian Journal of Ophthalmology. 2020;68:703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7350475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32317432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sein MK. The serendipitous impact of covid-19 pandemic: A rare opportunity for research and Practice. International Journal of Information Management. 2020;55</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7261442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32836630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurabadi A, Suhariadi F, Bafadal I, Gunawan I, Soepriyanto Y, Burham AS, et al. 2021 7th International Conference on Education and Technology (ICET) 2021. Measuring the effectiveness of using the principal's induction program website.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/icet53279.2021.9575068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arifin Y, Gunawan EP, Ohyver M. Development web application for enhancing information and activity in Rptra maya asri 13. ICCD. 2021;3:409&#x2013;412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benmoussa K, Laaziri M, Khoulji S, Larbi KM, Yamami AE. A new model for the selection of web development frameworks: Application to PHP frameworks. International Journal of Electrical and Computer Engineering (IJECE) 2019;9:695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakoso S, Dewi J. IOP Conference Series: Earth and Environmental Science. Vol. 126. 2018. Child-friendly integrated public spaces (RPTRA): Uses and sense of attachment.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakhmawati NA, Harits S, Hermansyah D, Furqon MA. A survey of web technologies used in Indonesia local governments. Sisfo. 2018;07 doi: 10.24089/j.sisfo.2018.05.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24089/j.sisfo.2018.05.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil HJ, Surwade YP. Web technologies from web 2.0 to web 4.0. International Journal for Science and Advance Research in Technology. 2018;4:810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi S, Liebchen G, Cetinkaya D. HCI International 2022 - Late Breaking Papers Design, User Experience and Interaction. 2022. A survey on the usability and user experience of the open community web portals; pp. 409&#x2013;423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilcoxon F. Individual comparisons by ranking methods. Springer Series in Statistics. 1992:196&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massey FJ. The Kolmogorov-Smirnov test for goodness of fit. Journal of the American Statistical Association. 1951;46:68&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bignami DF, Dragoni A, Menduni G. Assessing and improving flood and landslide community social awareness and engagement via a web platform: The case of italy. International Journal of Disaster Risk Science. 2018;9:530&#x2013;540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kompen RT, Edirisingha P, Canaleta X, Alsina M, Monguet JM. Personal learning Environments based on Web 2.0 services in higher education. Telematics and Informatics. 2019;38:194&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wamuyu PK. Leveraging web 2.0 technologies to foster collective civic environmental initiatives among low-income urban communities. Computers in Human Behavior. 2018;85:1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xed;fano S, Isaias P, Miranda P. Advances in Business Information Systems and Analytics. 2021. Successful implementation of web 2.0 in non-profit organisations; pp. 353&#x2013;369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliha F. Usability Evaluation of Web Portals in Fostering Social Learning. International Journal of Education and Development using Information and Communication Technology. 2021;17:141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warke B, Gromala D, Gupta A, Shaw C, Li L. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 2022. Wild intercepts: A novel approach to usability testing of a &#x2018;citizen science&#x2019; portal, developed for understanding the &#x2018;burdens of pain&#x2019; among citizens; pp. 174&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>