<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37396704</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2220-3249</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Etiopathogenic theories about long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>204</StartPage><EndPage>208</EndPage><MedlinePgn>204-208</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5501/wjv.v12.i3.204</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The main etiopathogenic theories of long coronavirus disease (COVID) are listed and a conjunction of them is carried out with the objective of deciphering the pathophysiology of the entity, finally the main lines of treatment existing in real life are discussed (Paxlovid, use of antibiotics in dysbiosis, triple anticoagulant therapy, temelimab).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2023. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Del Carpio-Orantes</LastName><ForeName>Luis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Virology, Research, Study Group for the Diagnosis and Treatment of COVID-19 in Veracruz, Veracruz 91900, Veracruz, Mexico. neurona23@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101608353</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2220-3249</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyloid microthrombosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dysbiosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Paxlovid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Triple therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Viral persistence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weakened immune system</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The author declares no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37396704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10311581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5501/wjv.v12.i3.204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Department of Health and Human Services, Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health. 2022. National Research Action Plan on Long COVID, 200 Independence Ave SW, Washington, DC 20201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tejerina F, Catalan P, Rodriguez-Grande C, Adan J, Rodriguez-Gonzalez C, Mu&#xf1;oz P, Aldamiz T, Diez C, Perez L, Fanciulli C, Garcia de Viedma D Gregorio Mara&#xf1;on Microbiology ID COVID 19 Study Group. Post-COVID-19 syndrome. SARS-CoV-2 RNA detection in plasma, stool, and urine in patients with persistent symptoms after COVID-19. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22:211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8892394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35240997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swank Z, Senussi Y, Manickas-Hill Z, Yu XG, Li JZ, Alter G, Walt DR. Persistent Circulating Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 Spike Is Associated With Post-acute Coronavirus Disease 2019 Sequelae. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76:e487&#x2013;e490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10169416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36052466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willyard C. Could tiny blood clots cause long COVID's puzzling symptoms? Nature. 2022;608:662&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36002482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charfeddine S, Ibn Hadj Amor H, Jdidi J, Torjmen S, Kraiem S, Hammami R, Bahloul A, Kallel N, Moussa N, Touil I, Ghrab A, Elghoul J, Meddeb Z, Thabet Y, Kammoun S, Bouslama K, Milouchi S, Abdessalem S, Abid L. Long COVID 19 Syndrome: Is It Related to Microcirculation and Endothelial Dysfunction? Insights From TUN-EndCOV Study. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2021;8:745758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34917659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kell DB, Laubscher GJ, Pretorius E. A central role for amyloid fibrin microclots in long COVID/PASC: origins and therapeutic implications. Biochem J. 2022;479:537&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8883497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35195253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E, Vlok M, Venter C, Bezuidenhout JA, Laubscher GJ, Steenkamp J, Kell DB. Persistent clotting protein pathology in Long COVID/Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) is accompanied by increased levels of antiplasmin. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2021;20:172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8381139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34425843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nystr&#xf6;m S, Hammarstr&#xf6;m P. Amyloidogenesis of SARS-CoV-2 Spike Protein. J Am Chem Soc. 2022;144:8945&#x2013;8950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9136918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35579205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulou M, Bakola E, Papapostolou A, Stefanou MI, Gaga M, Zouvelou V, Michopoulos I, Tsivgoulis G. Autonomic dysfunction in long-COVID syndrome: a neurophysiological and neurosonology study. J Neurol. 2022;269:4611&#x2013;4612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9086662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35536408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese C, Kirchner E, Calabrese LH. Long COVID and rheumatology: Clinical, diagnostic, and therapeutic implications. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2022:101794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9641578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36369208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merad M, Blish CA, Sallusto F, Iwasaki A. The immunology and immunopathology of COVID-19. Science. 2022;375:1122&#x2013;1127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35271343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur JM, Forrest JC, Boehme KW, Kennedy JL, Owens S, Herzog C, Liu J, Harville TO. Development of ACE2 autoantibodies after SARS-CoV-2 infection. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0257016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8415618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34478478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or Post-acute Sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): An Overview of Biological Factors That May Contribute to Persistent Symptoms. Front Microbiol. 2021;12:698169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rha MS, Shin EC. Activation or exhaustion of CD8(+) T cells in patients with COVID-19. Cell Mol Immunol. 2021;18:2325&#x2013;2333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8374113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34413488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algaadi SA. Herpes zoster and COVID-19 infection: a coincidence or a causal relationship? Infection. 2022;50:289&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8607065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34807403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold JE, Okyay RA, Licht WE, Hurley DJ. Investigation of Long COVID Prevalence and Its Relationship to Epstein-Barr Virus Reactivation. Pathogens. 2021;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8233978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34204243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deveau TM, Munter SE, Ryder D, Buck A, Beck-Engeser G, Chan F, Lu S, Goldberg SA, Hoh R, Tai V, Torres L, Iyer NS, Deswal M, Ngo LH, Buitrago M, Rodriguez A, Chen JY, Yee BC, Chenna A, Winslow JW, Petropoulos CJ, Deitchman AN, Hellmuth J, Spinelli MA, Durstenfeld MS, Hsue PY, Kelly JD, Martin JN, Deeks SG, Hunt PW, Henrich TJ. Impact of Pre-Existing Chronic Viral Infection and Reactivation on the Development of Long COVID. medRxiv. 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Zhang L, Wang Y, Dai T, Qin Z, Zhou F. Alterations in microbiota of patients with COVID-19: potential mechanisms and therapeutic interventions. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2022;7:143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9052735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35487886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haran JP, Bradley E, Zeamer AL, Cincotta L, Salive MC, Dutta P, Mutaawe S, Anya O, Meza-Segura M, Moormann AM, Ward DV, McCormick BA, Bucci V. Inflammation-type dysbiosis of the oral microbiome associates with the duration of COVID-19 symptoms and long COVID. JCI Insight. 2021;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8564890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34403368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA, Akbari A, Emami A, Lotfi M, Rostamihosseinkhani M, Nemati H, Barzegar Z, Kabiri M, Zeraatpisheh Z, Farjoud-Kouhanjani M, Jafari A, Sasannia S, Ashrafi S, Nazeri M, Nasiri S, Shahisavandi M. Long COVID syndrome-associated brain fog. J Med Virol. 2022;94:979&#x2013;984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieto Rodr&#xed;guez M&#xc1;, March Cerd&#xe1; JC, Mart&#xed;n Barato A, Escudero Carretero M, L&#xf3;pez Doblas M, Luque Mart&#xed;n N. [Consequences of the COVID-19 lockdown in patients with chronic diseases in Andalusia] Gac Sanit. 2022;36:139&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7680018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33342601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveendran AV, Misra A. Post COVID-19 Syndrome ("Long COVID") and Diabetes: Challenges in Diagnosis and Management. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15:102235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8317446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34384972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burekovic A, Halilovic D, Sahbaz A. Hypothyroidism and Subclinical Hypothyroidism as a Consequence of COVID-19 Infection. Med Arch. 2022;76:12&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8976890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35422565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Bluemke DA, L&#xfc;scher TF, Neubauer S. Long COVID: post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 with a cardiovascular focus. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:1157&#x2013;1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8903393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35176758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj L, Kannapadi NV, Briggs J, Seal SM, Battaglini D, Fanning J, Suen J, Robba C, Fraser J, Cho SM. Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: A meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci. 2022;434:120162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8798975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> The Yale Paxlovid for Long COVID (PAX LC) Trial. https://medicine.yale.edu/cii/research/paxlc-study/ </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E, Venter C, Laubscher GJ, Kotze MJ, Oladejo SO, Watson LR, Rajaratnam K, Watson BW, Kell DB. Prevalence of symptoms, comorbidities, fibrin amyloid microclots and platelet pathology in individuals with Long COVID/Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) Cardiovasc Diabetol . 2022;21:148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9356426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35933347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JM, Kell DB, Pretorius E. Cardiovascular and haematological pathology in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS): A role for viruses. Blood Rev. 2023:101075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10027292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36963989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladyzhets B.  Chronic fatigue syndrome is a puzzle. Your gut microbiome may have the key. Nationalgeographic magazine. Published march 9, 2023. Available from: https://www.nationalgeographic.com/magazine/article/chronic-fatigue-syndrome-gut-microbiome-may-have-the-key .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X, Sakamoto S, Ishii C, Smith MD, Ito K, Obayashi M, Unger L, Hasegawa Y, Kurokawa S, Kishimoto T, Li H, Hatano S, Wang TH, Yoshikai Y, Kano SI, Fukuda S, Sanada K, Calabresi PA, Kamiya A. Dectin-1 signaling on colonic &#x3b3;&#x3b4; T cells promotes psychosocial stress responses. Nat Immunol. 2023;24:625&#x2013;636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10704545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36941398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arany&#xf3; J, Bazan V, Llad&#xf3;s G, Dominguez MJ, Bisbal F, Massanella M, Sarrias A, Adeli&#xf1;o R, Riverola A, Paredes R, Clotet B, Bay&#xe9;s-Gen&#xed;s A, Mateu L, Villuendas R. Inappropriate sinus tachycardia in post-COVID-19 syndrome. Sci Rep. 2022;12:298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8741896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34996973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouliou DS, Dardiotis E. Temelimab for MS and SARS-CoV-2: Could it be a double-edged blessing? Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2022;64:103938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9169463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35717898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>