<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">39189651</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>96</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Inflammation-, immunothrombosis,- and autoimmune-feedback loops may lead to persistent neutrophil self-stimulation in long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e29887</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e29887</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.29887</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Understanding the pathophysiology of long COVID is one of the most intriguing challenges confronting contemporary medicine. Despite observations recently made in the relevant molecular, cellular, and physiological domains, it is still difficult to say whether the post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 directly correspond to the consequences of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection. This work hypothesizes that neutrophils and neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) production are at the interconnection of three positive feedback loops which are initiated in the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection, and which involve inflammation, immunothrombosis, and autoimmunity. This phenomenon could be favored by the fact that SARS-CoV-2 may directly bind and penetrate neutrophils. The ensuing strong neutrophil stimulation leads to a progressive amplification of an exacerbated and uncontrolled NETs production, potentially persisting for months beyond the acute phase of infection. This continuous self-stimulation of neutrophils leads, in turn, to systemic inflammation, micro-thromboses, and the production of autoantibodies, whose significant consequences include the persistence of endothelial and multiorgan damage, and vascular complications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Journal of Medical Virology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thierry</LastName><ForeName>Alain R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4632-5404</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCM, Institute of Research on Cancerology of Montpellier, INSERM U1194, University of Montpellier, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Montpellier Cancer Institute (ICM), Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salmon</LastName><ForeName>Dominique</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Institut Fournier, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>SIRIC Montpellier Cancer</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Soci&#xe9;t&#xe9; Fran&#xe7;aise des Acides Nucl&#xe9;iques Circulants</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>INSERM</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="Y">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000090882" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thromboinflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015551" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmunity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D025461" MajorTopicYN="Y">Feedback, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009504" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neutrophils</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065206" MajorTopicYN="N">Extracellular Traps</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003141" MajorTopicYN="N">Communicable Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NETosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neutrophil extracellular traps</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">platelets</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thrombosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viral persistence</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39189651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.29887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2010;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis. 2021;53(10):737&#x2010;754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post&#x2010;acute COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome. Nature Med. 2021;27(4):601&#x2010;615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza INO, Barros&#x2010;Arag&#xe3;o FGQ, Frost PS, Figueiredo CP, Clarke JR. Late neurological consequences of zika virus infection: risk factors and pharmaceutical approaches. Pharmaceuticals. 2019;12(2):60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;ttiker P, Stefano GB, Weissenberger S, et al. HIV, HSV, SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 and ebola share long&#x2010;term neuropsychiatric sequelae. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2022;18:2229&#x2010;2237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grist JJ, Marro B, Lane TE. Neutrophils and viral&#x2010;induced neurologic disease. Clin Immunol. 2018;189:52&#x2010;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gousseff M, Penot P, Gallay L, et al. Clinical recurrences of COVID&#x2010;19 symptoms after recovery: viral relapse, reinfection or inflammatory rebound? J Infect. 2020;81(5):816&#x2010;846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salmon&#x2010;Ceron D, Slama D, De Broucker T, et al. Clinical, virological and imaging profile in patients with prolonged forms of COVID&#x2010;19: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. J Infect. 2021;82(2):e1&#x2010;e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz BM, Acevedo OA, Kalergis AM, Bueno SM. Role of extracellular trap release during bacterial and viral infection. Front Microbiol. 2022;13:798853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camp JV, Jonsson CB. A role for neutrophils in viral respiratory disease. Front Immunol. 2017;8:550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkmann V. Neutrophil extracellular traps in the second decade. J Innate Immun. 2018;10(5&#x2010;6):414&#x2010;421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiel L, Mayeur&#x2010;Rousse C, Helms J, Meziani F, Mauvieux L. First visualization of circulating neutrophil extracellular traps using cell fluorescence during human septic shock&#x2010;induced disseminated intravascular coagulation. Thromb Res. 2019;183:153&#x2010;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aloul KM, Nielsen JE, Defensor EB, et al. Upregulating human cathelicidin antimicrobial peptide LL&#x2010;37 expression may prevent severe COVID&#x2010;19 inflammatory responses and reduce microthrombosis. Front Immunol. 2022;13:880961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radic M, Muller S. LL&#x2010;37, a multi&#x2010;faceted amphipathic peptide involved in NETosis. Cells. 2022;11(15):2463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papayannopoulos V. Neutrophil extracellular traps in immunity and disease. Nat Rev Immunol. 2018;18(2):134&#x2010;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousefi S, Stojkov D, Germic N, et al. Untangling &#x201c;NETosis&#x201d; from NETs. Eur J Immunol. 2019;49(2):221&#x2010;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Y, Yalavarthi S, Shi H, et al. Neutrophil extracellular traps in COVID&#x2010;19. JCI Insight. 2020;5(11):e138999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng H, Havervall S, Rosell A, et al. Circulating markers of neutrophil extracellular traps are of prognostic value in patients with COVID&#x2010;19. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2021;41(2):988&#x2010;994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thierry AR, Roch B. Neutrophil extracellular traps and by&#x2010;products play a key role in COVID&#x2010;19: pathogenesis, risk factors, and therapy. J Clin Med. 2020;9(9):2942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thierry AR, Roch B. SARS&#x2010;CoV2 may evade innate immune response, causing uncontrolled neutrophil extracellular traps formation and multi&#x2010;organ failure. Clin Sci. 2020;134(12):1295&#x2010;1300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes BJ, Adrover JM, Baxter&#x2010;Stoltzfus A, et al. Targeting potential drivers of COVID&#x2010;19: neutrophil extracellular traps. J Exp Med. 2020;217(6):e20200652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middleton EA, He XY, Denorme F, et al. Neutrophil extracellular traps contribute to immunothrombosis in COVID&#x2010;19 acute respiratory distress syndrome. Blood. 2020;136(10):1169&#x2010;1179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorch SK, Kubes P. An emerging role for neutrophil extracellular traps in noninfectious disease. Nature Med. 2017;23(3):279&#x2010;287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan MJ, Radic M. Neutrophil extracellular traps: double&#x2010;edged swords of innate immunity. J&#xa0;Immunol. 2012;189(6):2689&#x2010;2695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonaventura A, Vecchi&#xe9; A, Dagna L, et al. Endothelial dysfunction and immunothrombosis as key pathogenic mechanisms in COVID&#x2010;19. Nat Rev Immunol. 2021;21(5):319&#x2010;329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nickel KF, Renn&#xe9; T. Crosstalk of the plasma contact system with bacteria. Thromb Res. 2012;130:S78&#x2010;S83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connors JM, Ridker PM. Thromboinflammation and antithrombotics in COVID&#x2010;19: accumulating evidence and current status. JAMA. 2022;327(13):1234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs TA, Kremer Hovinga JA, Schatzberg D, Wagner DD, L&#xe4;mmle B. Circulating DNA and myeloperoxidase indicate disease activity in patients with thrombotic microangiopathies. Blood. 2012;120(6):1157&#x2010;1164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farooqui AA, Farooqui T, Sun GY, Lin TN, Teh DBL, Ong WY. COVID&#x2010;19, blood lipid changes, and thrombosis. Biomedicines. 2023;11(4):1181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Bruggen S, Martinod K. The coming of age of neutrophil extracellular traps in thrombosis: where are we now and where are we headed? Immunol Rev. 2023;314(1):376&#x2010;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pastorek M, D&#xfa;brava M, Celec P. On the origin of neutrophil extracellular traps in COVID&#x2010;19. Front Immunol. 2022;13:821007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherlinger M, Richez C, Tsokos GC, Boilard E, Blanco P. The role of platelets in immune&#x2010;mediated inflammatory diseases. Nat Rev Immunol. 2023;23(6):409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean LS, Devendra G, Jiyarom B, et al. Phenotypic alteration of low&#x2010;density granulocytes in people with pulmonary post&#x2010;acute sequelae of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1076724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wichmann D, Sperhake JP, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, et al. Autopsy findings and venous thromboembolism in patients with COVID&#x2010;19: a prospective cohort study. Ann Intern Med. 2020:173(4):268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazeldine J, Lord JM. Neutrophils and COVID&#x2010;19: active participants and rational therapeutic targets. Front Immunol. 2021;12:680134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Chen X, Liu X. NETosis and neutrophil extracellular traps in COVID&#x2010;19: immunothrombosis and beyond. Front Immunol. 2022;13:838011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nappi F, Bellomo F, Avtaar Singh SS. Insights into the role of neutrophils and neutrophil extracellular traps in causing cardiovascular complications in patients with COVID&#x2010;19: a systematic review. J Clin Med. 2022;11(9):2460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Y, Zuo M, Yalavarthi S, et al. Neutrophil extracellular traps and thrombosis in COVID&#x2010;19. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2021;51(2):446&#x2010;453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Montfoort ML, Stephan F, Lauw MN, et al. Circulating nucleosomes and neutrophil activation as risk factors for deep vein thrombosis. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2013;33(1):147&#x2010;151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varj&#xfa; I, Longstaff C, Szab&#xf3; L, et al. DNA, histones and neutrophil extracellular traps exert anti&#x2010;fibrinolytic effects in a plasma environment. Thromb Haemost. 2015;113(06):1289&#x2010;1298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeiler S, Stark K, Massberg S, Engelmann B. Propagation of thrombosis by neutrophils and extracellular nucleosome networks. Haematologica. 2017;102(2):206&#x2010;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonaventura A, Vecchi&#xe9; A, Abbate A, Montecucco F. Neutrophil extracellular traps and cardiovascular diseases: an update. Cells. 2020;9(1):231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang N, Li D, Wang X, Sun Z. Abnormal coagulation parameters are associated with poor prognosis in patients with novel coronavirus pneumonia. J Thromb Haemostasis. 2020;18(4):844&#x2010;847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolai L, Kaiser R, Stark K. Thromboinflammation in long COVID&#x2010;the elusive key to postinfection sequelae? J Thromb Haemostasis. 2023;21(8):2020&#x2010;2031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Lu H, Zhang W. Clinical observation and management of COVID&#x2010;19 patients. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2020;9(1):687&#x2010;690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belouzard S, Madu I, Whittaker GR. Elastase&#x2010;mediated activation of the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus spike protein at discrete sites within the S2 domain. J Biol Chem. 2010;285(30):22758&#x2010;22763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiroki CH, Toller&#x2010;Kawahisa JE, Fumagalli MJ, et al. Neutrophil extracellular traps effectively control acute chikungunya virus infection. Front Immunol. 2020;10:3108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saitoh T, Komano J, Saitoh Y, et al. Neutrophil extracellular traps mediate a host defense response to human immunodeficiency virus&#x2010;1. Cell Host Microbe. 2012;12(1):109&#x2010;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veras FP, Pontelli MC, Silva CM, et al. SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2&#x2013;triggered neutrophil extracellular traps mediate COVID&#x2010;19 pathology. J Exp Med. 2020;217(12):e20201129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebourgeois S, David A, Chenane HR, et al. Differential activation of human neutrophils by SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 variants of concern. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1010140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisareva E, Roch B, Sanchez C, et al. Comparison of the structures and topologies of plasma extracted circulating nuclear and mitochondrial cell&#x2010;free DNA. Front Genet. 2023;14:1104732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry BM, de Oliveira MHS, Cheruiyot I, et al. Cell&#x2010;free DNA, neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), and endothelial injury in coronavirus disease 2019&#x2013;(COVID&#x2010;19&#x2013;) associated acute kidney injury. In: Filippin Monteiro FB, ed. Mediators of Inflammation. Vol 2022, 2022:1&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Amir Dache Z, Thierry AR. Mitochondria&#x2010;derived cell&#x2010;to&#x2010;cell communication. Cell Rep. 2023;42(7):112728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burtscher J, Cappellano G, Omori A, Koshiba T, Millet GP. Mitochondria: in the cross fire of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 and immunity. iScience. 2020;23(10):101631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirose T, Hamaguchi S, Matsumoto N, et al. Presence of neutrophil extracellular traps and citrullinated histone H3 in the bloodstream of critically ill patients. PLoS One. 2014;9(11):e111755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashar HK, Mueller NC, Rudd JM, et al. The role of extracellular histones in influenza virus pathogenesis. Am J Pathol. 2018;188(1):135&#x2010;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambardella S, Limanaqi F, Ferese R, et al. ccf&#x2010;mtDNA as a potential link between the brain and immune system in neuro&#x2010;immunological disorders. Front Immunol. 2019;10:1064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paunel&#x2010;G&#xf6;rg&#xfc;l&#xfc; A, Wacker M, El Aita M, et al. cfDNA correlates with endothelial damage after cardiac surgery with prolonged cardiopulmonary bypass and amplifies NETosis in an intracellular TLR9&#x2010;independent manner. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):17421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unudurthi SD, Luthra P, Bose RJC, McCarthy JR, Kontaridis MI. Cardiac inflammation in COVID&#x2010;19: lessons from heart failure. Life Sci. 2020;260:118482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh SE, Parikh NS. Recent advances in the impact of infection and inflammation on stroke risk and outcomes. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2022;22(3):161&#x2010;170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thierry AR. Anti&#x2010;protease treatments targeting plasmin(ogen) and neutrophil elastase may be beneficial in fighting COVID&#x2010;19. Physiol Rev. 2020;100(4):1597&#x2010;1598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell RA, Boucher RC, Stutts MJ. Neutrophil elastase activates near&#x2010;silent epithelial Na+ channels and increases airway epithelial Na+ transport. Am&#xa0;J&#xa0;Physiol&#x2010;Lung Cell&#xa0;Mol&#xa0;Physiol. 2005;288(5):L813&#x2010;L819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Amir Dache Z, Otandault A, Tanos R, et al. Blood contains circulating cell&#x2010;free respiratory competent mitochondria. FASEB J. 2020;34(3):3616&#x2010;3630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousefi S, Mihalache C, Kozlowski E, Schmid I, Simon HU. Viable neutrophils release mitochondrial DNA to form neutrophil extracellular traps. Cell Death Differ. 2009;16(11):1438&#x2010;1444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene C, Connolly R, Brennan D, et al. Blood&#x2010;brain barrier disruption in long COVID&#x2010;associated cognitive impairment. Nature Neurosci. 202327(3):421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanin A, Amah G, Chakroun S, et al. Parasympathetic autonomic dysfunction is more often evidenced than sympathetic autonomic dysfunction in fluctuating and polymorphic symptoms of &#x201c;long&#x2010;COVID&#x201d; patients. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):8251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melki I, Allaeys I, Tessandier N, et al. Platelets release mitochondrial antigens in systemic lupus erythematosus. Sci Transl Med. 2021;13(581):eaav5928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fousert E, Toes R, Desai J. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) take the central stage in driving autoimmune responses. Cells. 2020;9(4):915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x141;ukasik ZM, Makowski M, Makowska JS. From blood coagulation to innate and adaptive immunity: the role of platelets in the physiology and pathology of autoimmune disorders. Rheumatol Int. 2018;38(6):959&#x2010;974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riley JS, Tait SW. Mitochondrial DNA in inflammation and immunity. EMBO Rep. 2020;21(4):e49799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koenig A, Buskiewicz&#x2010;Koenig IA. Redox activation of mitochondrial DAMPs and the metabolic consequences for development of autoimmunity. Antioxid Redox Signaling. 2022;36(7&#x2010;9):441&#x2010;461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KH, Kronbichler A, Park DDY, et al. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) in autoimmune diseases: a comprehensive review. Autoimmun Rev. 2017;16(11):1160&#x2010;1173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres&#x2010;Ruiz J, Absal&#xf3;n&#x2010;Aguilar A, Nu&#xf1;ez&#x2010;Aguirre M, et al. Neutrophil extracellular traps contribute to COVID&#x2010;19 hyperinflammation and humoral autoimmunity. Cells. 2021;10(10):2545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radic M, Marion TN. Neutrophil extracellular chromatin traps connect innate immune response to autoimmunity. Semin Immunopathol. 2013;35(4):465&#x2010;480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisareva E, Badiou S, Mihalovi&#x10d;ov&#xe1; L, et al. Persistence of neutrophil extracellular traps and anticardiolipin auto&#x2010;antibodies in post&#x2010;acute phase COVID&#x2010;19 patients. J Med Virol. 2023;95(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Y, Estes SK, Ali RA, et al. Prothrombotic autoantibodies in serum from patients hospitalized with COVID&#x2010;19. Sci Transl Med. 2020;12(570):eabd3876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Xiao M, Zhang S, et al. Coagulopathy and antiphospholipid antibodies in patients with Covid&#x2010;19. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(17):e38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harzallah I, Debliquis A, Dr&#xe9;nou B. Lupus anticoagulant is frequent in patients with Covid&#x2010;19. J Thromb Haemostasis. 2020;18(8):2064&#x2010;2065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi H, Zuo Y, Navaz S, et al. Endothelial cell&#x2010;activating antibodies in COVID&#x2010;19.&#xa0;Infectious diseases (except HIV/AIDS). 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Y, Yalavarthi S, Navaz S, et al. Autoantibodies stabilize neutrophil extracellular traps in COVID&#x2010;19. Infectious diseases (except HIV/AIDS). 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin X, Wang Y, Xu J, et al. Plasma cell&#x2010;free DNA promise monitoring and tissue injury assessment of COVID&#x2010;19. Mol Genet Genomics. 2023;298(4):823&#x2010;836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papayannopoulos V, Metzler KD, Hakkim A, Zychlinsky A. Neutrophil elastase and myeloperoxidase regulate the formation of neutrophil extracellular traps. J Cell Biol. 2010;191(3):677&#x2010;691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>George PM, Reed A, Desai SR, et al. A persistent neutrophil&#x2010;associated immune signature characterizes post&#x2013;COVID&#x2010;19 pulmonary sequelae. Sci Transl Med. 2022;14(671):eabo5795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taghadosi M, Safarzadeh E, Asgarzadeh A, et al. Partners in crime: autoantibodies complicit in COVID&#x2010;19 pathogenesis. Rev Med Virol. 2023;33(2):e2412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post&#x2010;acute COVID&#x2010;19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185(5):881&#x2010;895.e20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz DB, Helms J, Aquino LR, et al. DNA&#x2010;bound elastase of neutrophil extracellular traps degrades plasminogen, reduces plasmin formation, and decreases fibrinolysis: proof of concept in septic shock plasma. FASEB J. 2019;33(12):14270&#x2010;14280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruger A, Vlok M, Turner S, et al. Proteomics of fibrin amyloid microclots in long COVID/post&#x2010;acute sequelae of COVID&#x2010;19 (PASC) shows many entrapped pro&#x2010;inflammatory molecules that may also contribute to a failed fibrinolytic system. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner S, Naidoo CA, Usher TJ, et al. Increased levels of inflammatory and endothelial biomarkers in blood of long COVID patients point to thrombotic endothelialitis. Semin Thromb Hemost. 2023:50(2):288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kell DB, Laubscher GJ, Pretorius E. A central role for amyloid fibrin microclots in long COVID/PASC: origins and therapeutic implications. Biochem J. 2022;479(4):537&#x2010;559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E, Thierry A, Sanchez C, et al. Circulating microclots are structurally associated with neutrophil extracellular traps and their amounts are strongly elevated in long COVID patients. 2024. doi:10.21203/rs.3.rs-4666650/v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young RM, Staudt LM. Targeting pathological B cell receptor signalling in lymphoid malignancies. Nat Rev Drug Discovery. 2013;12(3):229&#x2010;243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas M, Rodr&#xed;guez Y, Acosta&#x2010;Ampudia Y, et al. Autoimmunity is a hallmark of post&#x2010;COVID syndrome. J Transl Med. 2022;20(1):129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch MH, Timmermans SAMEG, Nagy M, et al. Neutrophils and contact activation of coagulation as potential drivers of COVID&#x2010;19. Circulation. 2020;142(18):1787&#x2010;1790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Z, Abrams ST, Alhamdi Y, et al. Circulating histones are major mediators of multiple organ dysfunction syndrome in acute critical illnesses. Crit Care Med. 2019;47(8):e677&#x2010;e684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodruff MC, Bonham KS, Anam FA, et al. Chronic inflammation, neutrophil activity, and autoreactivity splits long COVID. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):4201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodruff MC, Ramonell RP, Haddad NS, et al. Dysregulated naive B cells and de novo autoreactivity in severe COVID&#x2010;19. Nature. 2022;611(7934):139&#x2010;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xf6;nrich G, Raftery MJ. Neutrophil extracellular traps go viral. Front Immunol. 2016;7:366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefran&#xe7;ais E, Mallavia B, Zhuo H, Calfee CS, Looney MR. Maladaptive role of neutrophil extracellular traps in pathogen&#x2010;induced lung injury. JCI Insight. 2018;3(3):e98178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T, Hittle M, Goodman SN. Assessment of the frequency and variety of persistent symptoms among patients with COVID&#x2010;19: a systematic review. JAMA Network Open. 2021;4(5):e2111417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed H, Patel K, Greenwood D, et al. Long&#x2010;term clinical outcomes in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus outbreaks after hospitalisation or ICU admission: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Rehabil Med. 2020;52(5):jrm00063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batawi S, Tarazan N, Al&#x2010;Raddadi R, et al. Quality of life reported by survivors after hospitalization for Middle East respiratory syndrome (MERS). Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2019;17(1):101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eddleston AL. Hepatitis C infection and autoimmunity. J Hepatol. 1996;24(2 suppl):55&#x2010;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beydon M, Rodriguez C, Karras A, et al. Bartonella and Coxiella infections presenting as systemic vasculitis: case series and review of literature. Rheumatology. 2022;61(6):2609&#x2010;2618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicher K, Wicher V. Autoimmunity in syphilis. Immunol Ser. 1990;52:101&#x2010;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Almeida AJ, Campos&#x2010;de&#x2010;Magalh&#xe3;es M, Antonietti CL, et al. Autoimmune thrombocytopenia related to chronic hepatitis C virus infection. Hematology. 2009;14(1):49&#x2010;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oseghale O, Vlahos R, O'Leary JJ, et al. Influenza virus infection during pregnancy as a trigger of acute and chronic complications. Viruses. 2022;14(12):2729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swank Z, Senussi Y, Manickas&#x2010;Hill Z, et al. Persistent circulating severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 spike is associated with post&#x2010;acute coronavirus disease 2019 sequelae. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76(3):e487&#x2010;e490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Melo GD, Lazarini F, Levallois S, et al. COVID&#x2010;19&#x2013;related anosmia is associated with viral persistence and inflammation in human olfactory epithelium and brain infection in hamsters. Sci Transl Med. 2021;13(596):eabf8396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou Q, Fang J, Zhang Z, et al. TcpC inhibits neutrophil extracellular trap formation by enhancing ubiquitination mediated degradation of peptidylarginine deiminase 4. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):3481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutua V, Gershwin LJ. A review of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) in disease: potential anti&#x2010;NETs therapeutics. Clin&#xa0;Rev&#xa0;Aller Immunol. 2021;61(2):194&#x2010;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Hong W, Wan M, Zheng L. Molecular mechanisms and therapeutic target of NETosis in diseases. MedComm (2020). 2022;3(3): e162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desilles JP, Gregoire C, Le Cossec C, et al. Efficacy and safety of aerosolized intra&#x2010;tracheal dornase alfa administration in patients with SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2&#x2010;induced acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS): a structured summary of a study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials. 2020;21(1):548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batiha GES, Al&#x2010;kuraishy HM, Al&#x2010;Gareeb AI, Welson NN. Pathophysiology of post&#x2010;COVID syndromes: a new perspective. Virol J. 2022;19(1):158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thierry AR. Host/genetic factors associated with COVID&#x2010;19 call for precision medicine. Precision Clin&#xa0;Med. 2020;3(3):228&#x2010;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balnis J, Madrid A, Hogan KJ, et al. Persistent blood DNA methylation changes one year after SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection. Clin Epigenetics. 2022;14(1):94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iosef C, Knauer MJ, Nicholson M, et al. Plasma proteome of Long&#x2010;COVID patients indicates HIF&#x2010;mediated vasculo&#x2010;proliferative disease with impact on brain and heart function. J Transl Med. 2023;21(1):377.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>