<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39283441</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0065-2598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>1457</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advances in experimental medicine and biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Exp Med Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Obesity, Physical Activity, and COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>431</StartPage><EndPage>446</EndPage><MedlinePgn>431-446</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/978-3-031-61939-7_24</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Estimates suggest that over 80% of people with COVID-19 may experience mild to no symptoms. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) reported that around 7-8% of positive COVID-19 cases were hospitalized in the first year of the pandemic. A substantial body of evidence points to obesity, sedentary behavior, and low physical activity levels as risk factors for susceptibility to the virus and the severity of symptoms. Obese individuals are 46% more likely to contract the virus than those of normal weight, and those who are physically active have an 11% reduced risk of contracting the virus. Medical experts have also identified obesity, sedentary behavior, and physical inactivity as risk factors for severe COVID-19 symptoms and long COVID. Evidence from bariatric surgery suggests that weight loss decreases the susceptibility and severity of COVID-19. The mechanisms linking obesity, sedentary behavior, and physical activity to COVID-19 are somewhat similar. Obesity, sedentary behavior, and low physical activity are all linked to inflammation, immune dysfunction, and comorbidities such as diabetes and cardiovascular disease that increase COVID-19 risk. Additionally, achieving the recommended 150&#xa0;min of moderate-intensity exercise seems to be the desired dose for protection from COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s), under exclusive license to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeigler</LastName><ForeName>Zachary</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Grand Canyon University, 19013 W Solano Dr. Litchfield Park, Phoenix, AZ, 85340, USA. Zachary.zeigler@gcu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Acevedo</LastName><ForeName>Anthony</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Grand Canyon University, 19013 W Solano Dr. Litchfield Park, Phoenix, AZ, 85340, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Exp Med Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0121103</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0065-2598</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057185" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sedentary Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015897" MajorTopicYN="N">Comorbidity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sedentary behavior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Upper body obesity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39283441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-031-61939-7_24</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adams GR et al (2011) Exercise and leukocyte interchange among central circulation, lung, spleen, and muscle. Brain Behav Immun 25(4):658&#x2013;66. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aminian A, Fathalizadeh A, Tu C, Scott Butsch W, Pantalone KM, Griebeler ML, Kashyap SR, Rosenthal RJ, Burguera B, Nissen SE (2021) Association of prior metabolic and bariatric surgery with severity of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in patients with obesity. Surg Obes Relat Dis 17(1):208&#x2013;214. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popkin BM, Du S, Green WD, Beck MA, Algaith T, Herbst CH, Alsukait RF, Alluhidan M, Alazemi N, Shekar M (2020) Individuals with obesity and COVID&#x2010;19: a global perspective on the epidemiology and biological relationships. Obes Rev 21(11):e13128. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belan&#x10d;i&#x107; A, Kresovi&#x107; A, Valentino R (2020) Potential pathophysiological mechanisms leading to increased COVID-19 susceptibility and severity in obesity. Obes Med 19:100259. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biscarini S, Colaneri M, Ludovisi S, Seminari E, Teresa CP, Valsecchi P, Gallazzi I, Giusti E, Camm&#xe0; C, Zuccaro V (2020) The obesity paradox: analysis from the SMAtteo COvid-19 REgistry (SMACORE) cohort. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis 30(11):1920&#x2013;1925. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buitrago-Garcia D, Egli-Gany D, Michel JC, Hossmann S, Imeri H, Ipekci AM, Salanti G, Low N (2020) Occurrence and transmission potential of asymptomatic and presymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infections: a living systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS Med 17(9):e1003346. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Francesco L (2020) Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. Jama 324(6):603&#x2013;605. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carole HS, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, Pujol JC, Klaser K, Antonelli M, Canas LS (2021) Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med 27(4):626&#x2013;631. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caussy C, Wallet F, Laville M, Emmanuel D (2020) Obesity is associated with severe forms of COVID-19. Obesity 28(7):1175. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and, Prevention (2021) COVID-19 hospitalization and death by age (2021). 2023. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinti F, Saverio C (2022) The endocrine adipose organ: a system playing a central role in COVID-19. Cells 11(13):2109. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham GB (2021) Physical activity and its relationship with COVID-19 cases and deaths: Analysis of U.S. counties. J Sport Health Sci 10(5):570&#x2013;76. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzatvar Y et al (2022) Physical activity and risk of infection, severity and mortality of COVID-19: a systematic review and non-linear dose&#x2013;response meta-analysis of data from 1 853 610 adults. Br J Sports Med 56(20):1188&#x2013;1193. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Lidiane LF, Cuadrado ML, Plaza-Manzano G, Navarro-Santana M (2021) Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Int Med 92:55&#x2013;70. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xf6;ldi M, Farkas N, Kiss S, Dembrovszky F, Szak&#xe1;cs Z, Balask&#xf3; M, Er&#x151;ss B, Hegyi P, Andrea S (2021) Visceral adiposity elevates the risk of critical condition in COVID&#x2010;19: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Obesity 29(3):521&#x2013;528. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao F, Zheng KI, Wang X-B, Sun Q-F, Pan K-H, Wang T-Y, Chen Y-P, Targher G, Byrne CD, George J (2020) Obesity is a risk factor for greater COVID-19 severity. Diab Care 43(7):e72&#x2013;e74. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg S, Kim L, Whitaker M, O'Halloran A, Cummings C, Holstein R, Prill M, Chai SJ, Kirley PD, Alden NB (2020) Hospitalization rates and characteristics of patients hospitalized with laboratory-confirmed coronavirus disease 2019&#x2014;COVID-NET, 14 States, March 1&#x2013;30, 2020. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 69(15):458. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P et al (2022) Long COVID following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: characteristic T cell alterations and response to antihistamines. J Invest Med 70(1):61&#x2013;67. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamer M, Catharine RG, Kivim&#xe4;ki M, David Batty G (2020) Overweight, obesity, and risk of hospitalization for COVID-19: a community-based cohort study of adults in the United Kingdom. Proc Nat Acad Sci 117(35):21011&#x2013;21013. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hekmatikar A, Hossein A et al (2022) Functional and psychological changes after exercise training in post-COVID-19 patients discharged from the hospital: a PRISMA-compliant systematic review. Int J Environ Res Publ Heal 19(4):2290. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hindsberger B, Lindegaard B, Andersen LR, Israelsen SB, Pedersen L, Szecsi PB, Benfield T (2023) Circulating adiponectin levels are inversely associated with mortality and respiratory failure in patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Int J Endocrinol 2023 (2023). Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>David J-P, Carbonell-Baeza A, Lavie CJ (2020) Physical exercise as therapy to fight against the mental and physical consequences of COVID-19 quarantine: Special focus in older people. Prog Cardiovasc Dis 63(3):386. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim NH, Kim KJ, Choi J, Sin Gon K (2022) Metabolically unhealthy individuals, either with obesity or not, have a higher risk of critical coronavirus disease 2019 outcomes than metabolically healthy individuals without obesity. Metabolism 128:154894. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klang E, Kassim G, Soffer S, Freeman R, Matthew AL, Reich DL (2020) Severe obesity as an independent risk factor for COVID&#x2010;19 mortality in hospitalized patients younger than 50. Obesity 28(9):1595&#x2013;99. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larrabee RC (1902) Leucocytosis after violent exercise. J Med Res 7(1):76. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Cao Z, Yang H, Zhang Y, Xu F, Wang Y (2021) Metabolic healthy obesity, vitamin D status, and risk of COVID-19. Aging Dis 12(1):61. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobelo F et al (2020) Routine assessment and promotion of physical activity in healthcare settings: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation 137(18):e495&#x2013;e522. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malavazos AE, Secchi F, Basilico S, Capitanio G, Boveri S, Milani V, Dubini C, Schiaffino S, Morricone L, Foschini C (2021) Abdominal obesity phenotype is associated with COVID-19 chest X-ray severity score better than BMI-based obesity. Eat Weight Disord &#x2013;Stud Anorexia Bulimia Obes (2021):1&#x2013;15. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muzyka I, Revenko O, Kovalchuk I, Savytska M, Bekesevych A, Oksana Z (2023) What is the role of brown adipose tissue in metabolic health: lessons learned and future perspectives in the long COVID? Inflammopharmacology 1&#x2013;9. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, Cook JR, Nordvig AS, Shalev D, Sehrawat TS (2021) Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med 27(4):601&#x2013;615. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieman DC (2020) Coronavirus disease-2019: A tocsin to our aging, unfit, corpulent, and immunodeficient society. J Sport Health Sci 9(4):293&#x2013;301. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Shea D, Hogan AE (2019) Dysregulation of natural killer cells in obesity. Cancers 11(4):573. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C et al (2022) Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Immunol 23(2):210&#x2013;216. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poly TN, Islam MM, Yang HC, Lin MC, Jian W-S, Hsu M-H, Yu-Chuan Jack L (2021) Obesity and mortality among patients diagnosed with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Frontiers Med 8:620044. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawshani A et al (2021) Severe COVID-19 in people with type 1 and type 2 diabetes in Sweden: a nationwide retrospective cohort study. Lancet Reg Health-Eur 4:100105. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallis R et al (2021) Physical inactivity is associated with a higher risk for severe COVID-19 outcomes: a study in 48 440 adult patients. Brit J Sports Med 55(19):1099&#x2013;1105. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sattar N, McInnes IB, McMurray JJV (2020) Obesity is a risk factor for severe COVID-19 infection: multiple potential mechanisms. Circulation 142(1):4&#x2013;6. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siahaan YMT, Hartoyo V, Hariyanto TI, Andree K (2022) Coronavirus disease 2019 (Covid-19) outcomes in patients with sarcopenia: a meta-analysis and meta-regression. Clin Nutrition ESPEN 48 (2022):158&#x2013;66. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefan N, Andreas LB, Schulze MB, Ludwig DS (2020) Obesity and impaired metabolic health in patients with COVID-19. Nat Rev Endocrinol 16(7):341&#x2013;342. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trayhurn P, Wood IS (2004) Adipokines: inflammation and the pleiotropic role of white adipose tissue. Br J Nutr 92(3):347&#x2013;355. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vulturar D-M, Crivii C-B, Or&#x103;san OH, Palade E, Buzoianu A-D, Zehan IG, Doina Adina T (2022) Obesity impact on SARS-CoV-2 infection: pros and cons "Obesity Paradox"&#x2014;a systematic review. J Clin Med 11(13):3844. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health, Organization (2020) World Health Organization coronavirus disease (COVID-19) dashboard. World Health Organization&#xa0;(2020). Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright J, Astill SL, Sivan M (2022a) The relationship between physical activity and long COVID: a Cross-Sectional Study. Int J Environ Res Pub Heal 19(9):5093. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright J, Astill SL, Sivan M (2022b) The relationship between physical activity and long covid: a cross-sectional study. Int J Environ Res Publ Heal 19(9):5093. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Ma ZY, Lei YC (2021)A meta-analysis of the association between obesity and COVID-19. Epidemiol Infect 149 (2021). Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zachary Z, Brianna F, Brianna L, Garrett P, Jade W, Alyssa D, Mikayla K (2020) Self-quarantine and weight gain related risk factors during the COVID-19 pandemic. Obes Res Clin Pract 14(3):210&#x2013;216. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zachary Z (2021) COVID-19 self-quarantine and weight gain risk factors in adults. Curr Obes Rep 10:423&#x2013;433. Print</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeigler Z, Lawrence J, Jamison A, Pete S (2021) Physical activity behaviors and COVID-19 symptoms. OBM Integr Complement Med 6(3):1&#x2013;16. Print</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>