<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38827682</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2249-4863</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of family medicine and primary care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Family Med Prim Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Young hearts at risk: Unveiling novel factors in myocardial infarction susceptibility and prevention.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1200</StartPage><EndPage>1205</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1200-1205</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_1639_23</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The increasing incidence of acute myocardial infarction (AMI) among the young population represents a significant and emerging health concern, contributing substantially to both mortality and morbidity. Unlike myocardial infarctions occurring in older individuals, traditional risk factors such as diabetes and hypertension exhibit a weaker association in the younger demographic. Consequently, there is a pressing need for a deeper understanding of novel risk factors that contribute to AMI in young patients. In this review, we explore distinct risk factor profiles associated with young-onset AMI in comparison to older patients. Special attention is given to novel risk factors, examining their susceptibility factors and exploring preventive measures. The comprehensive risk profile of extremely young South Asians who develop early coronary arterial disease is not yet fully understood. There are many novel evolving risk factors associated with young AMI which need intervention to reduce morbidity and mortality. It has been seen that established inflammatory markers like lipoprotein (a), dyslipidaemia, long COVID, and new emerging risk factors like air pollution (micro- and nanoplastics), periodontitis, acute stress, energy drinks, misuse of recreational drugs may increase risk and influence treatment, and outcomes of AMI in this young population. Screening of emerging novel risk markers and their optimization is important in preventing young patients with AMI. The role of conventional risk factors should not be overlooked and should be treated aggressively. Sex and geographic-specific base approaches are required to reduce risk factors and prevent AMI in young. More prospective studies are needed to evaluate the increasing incidence of young AMI and its associated novel risk factors.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2024 Journal of Family Medicine and Primary Care.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ranjan</LastName><ForeName>Ashis</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, AIIMS Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agarwal</LastName><ForeName>Rajat</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic Surgery, AIIMS Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mudgal</LastName><ForeName>Shiv Kumar</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, AIIMS Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhattacharya</LastName><ForeName>Sudip</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community and Family Medicine, AIIMS Deoghar, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Barun</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, AIIMS Rishikesh, Uttarakhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Family Med Prim Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610082</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2249-4863</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute myocardial infarction in young</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">conventional risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">novel risk markers</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38827682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11141995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_1639_23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JFMPC-13-1200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Biery DW, Singh A, Divakaran S, DeFilippis EM, Wu WY, et al. Risk factors and outcomes of very young adults who experience myocardial infarction: The partners YOUNG-MI registry. Am J Med. 2020;133:605&#x2013;12.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7210047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31715169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora S, Stouffer GA, Kucharska-Newton AM, Qamar A, Vaduganathan M, Pandey A, et al. Twenty year trends and sex differences in young adults hospitalized with acute myocardial infarction. Circulation. 2019;139:1047&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6380926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30586725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dugani SB, Ayala Melendez AP, Reka R, Hydoub YM, McCafferty SN, Murad MH, et al. Risk factors associated with premature myocardial infarction: A systematic review protocol. BMJ Open. 2019;9:e023647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6377544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30755446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afshar M, Rong J, Zhan Y, Chen HY, Engert JC, Sniderman AD, et al. Risks of incident cardiovascular disease associated with concomitant elevations in Lipoprotein(a) and low-density lipoprotein cholesterol-The Framingham heart study. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020;9:e014711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7726982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32892691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enas EA, Varkey B, Dharmarajan TS, Pare G, Bahl VK. Lipoprotein(a): An underrecognized genetic risk factor for malignant coronary artery disease in young Indians. Indian Heart J. 2019;71:184&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6796644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31543191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah N, Kelly AM, Cox N, Wong C, Soon K. Myocardial infarction in the &#x201c;young&#x201d;: Risk factors, presentation, management and prognosis. Heart Lung Circ. 2016;25:955&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27265644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta MD, Gupta P, Mp G, Roy A, Qamar A. Risk factors for myocardial infarction in very young South Asians. Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes. 2020;27:87&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32073427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad AS, Ashraf T, Mir A, Alishan S, Farooq F, Ammar A, et al. Comparative assessment of clinical profile and outcomes after primary percutaneous coronary intervention in young patients with single vs multivessel disease. World J Cardiol. 2020;12:136&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32431784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh B, Singh A, Goyal A, Chhabra S, Tandon R, Aslam N, et al. the prevalence, clinical spectrum and the long term outcome of ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction in young-A prospective observational study. Cardiovasc Revascularization Med Mol Interv. 2019;20:387&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30068493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Divakaran S, Singh A, Biery D, Yang J, DeFilippis EM, Collins BL, et al. Diabetes is associated with worse long-term outcomes in young adults after myocardial infarction: The partners YOUNG-MI registry. Diabetes Care. 2020;43:1843&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7372040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31548242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yandrapalli S, Nabors C, Goyal A, Aronow WS, Frishman WH. Modifiable risk factors in young adults with first myocardial infarction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;73:573&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30732711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#x103;tescu C, Anghel L, Benchea LC, Tudurachi BS, Leonte A, Z&#x103;voi A, et al. A systematic review on the risk modulators of myocardial infarction in the &#x201c;young&#x201d;&#x2014;Implications of Lipoprotein (a) Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24:5927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10051886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36983001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfaddagh A, Khraishah H, Rashed W, Sharma G, Blumenthal RS, Zubaid M. Clinical characteristics and outcomes of young adults with first myocardial infarction: Results from Gulf COAST. Int J Cardiol Heart Vasc. 2020;31:100680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7710649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33304990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Par&#xe9; G, &#xc7;aku A, McQueen M, Anand SS, Enas E, Clarke R, et al. Lipoprotein(a) levels and the risk of myocardial infarction among 7 ethnic groups. Circulation. 2019;139:1472&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30667276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bittner VA, Szarek M, Aylward PE, Bhatt DL, Diaz R, Edelberg JM, et al. Effect of Alirocumab on Lipoprotein(a) and cardiovascular risk after acute coronary syndrome. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;75:133&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31948641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsimikas S, Karwatowska-Prokopczuk E, Gouni-Berthold I, Tardif JC, Baum SJ, Steinhagen-Thiessen E, et al. Lipoprotein(a) reduction in persons with cardiovascular disease. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:244&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31893580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donoghue ML, Rosenson RS, Gencer B, L&#xf3;pez JAG, Lepor NE, Baum SJ, et al. Small interfering RNA to reduce Lipoprotein(a) in cardiovascular disease. N Engl J Med. 2022;387:1855&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36342163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byon MJ, Kim SY, Kim JS, Kim HN, Kim JB. Association of periodontitis with atherosclerotic cardiovascular diseases: A nationwide population-based retrospective matched cohort study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:7261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7578974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33020434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudry FA, Hamshere SM, Rathod KS, Akhtar MM, Archbold RA, Guttmann OP, et al. High thrombus burden in patients with COVID-19 presenting with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76:1168&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32679155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siripanthong B, Asatryan B, Hanff TC, Chatha SR, Khanji MY, Ricci F, et al. The pathogenesis and long-term consequences of COVID-19 cardiac injury. JACC Basic Transl Sci. 2022;7:294&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8828362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35165665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boogaard H, Walker K, Cohen AJ. Air pollution: The emergence of a major global health risk factor. Int Health. 2019;11:417&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31613318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X, Wang C, Duan X, Liang B, Genbo Xu E, Huang Z. Micro- and nanoplastics: A new cardiovascular risk factor? Environ Int. 2023;171:107662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36473237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhakal B, Shiwakoti S, Park EY, Kang KW, Schini-Kerth VB, Park SH, et al. SGLT2 inhibition ameliorates nano plastics-induced premature endothelial senescence and dysfunction. Sci Rep. 2023;13:6256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10110533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37069192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendzerska T, Gershon AS, Hawker G, Leung RS, Tomlinson G. Obstructive sleep apnea and risk of cardiovascular events and all-cause mortality: A decade-long historical cohort study. PLoS Med. 2014;11:e1001599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3913558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24503600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Rio F, Alonso-Fern&#xe1;ndez A, Armada E, Mediano O, Lores V, Rojo B, et al. CPAP effect on recurrent episodes in patients with sleep apnea and myocardial infarction. Int J Cardiol. 2013;168:1328&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23302113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajeganova S, Hafstr&#xf6;m I, Frosteg&#xe5;rd J. Patients with SLE have higher risk of cardiovascular events and mortality in comparison with controls with the same levels of traditional risk factors and intima-media measures, which is related to accumulated disease damage and antiphospholipid syndrome: A case-control study over 10 years. Lupus Sci Med. 2021;8:e000454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7871345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33547230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi G, Cervellin G, Sanchis-Gomar F. Energy drinks and myocardial ischemia: A review of case reports. Cardiovasc Toxicol. 2016;16:207&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26320007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman MJ, Zamorano JL, Parhofer KG. Reducing residual cardiovascular risk in Europe: Therapeutic implications of European medicines agency approval of icosapent ethyl/eicosapentaenoic acid. Pharmacol Ther. 2022;237:108172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35304222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tersalvi G, Biasco L, Radovanovic D, Rickli H, Roffi M, Eberli F, et al. Heavy drinking habits are associated with worse in-hospital outcomes in patients with acute coronary syndrome: An insight from the AMIS plus registry. Cardiology. 2020;145:757&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32818933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kajanoja J, Scheinin NM, Karukivi M, Karlsson L, Karlsson H. Alcohol and tobacco use in men: The role of alexithymia and externally oriented thinking style. Am J Drug Alcohol Abuse. 2019;45:199&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30427739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bielas H, Meister-Langraf RE, Schmid JP, Barth J, Znoj H, Schnyder U, et al. Acute stress disorder and C-reactive protein in patients with acute myocardial infarction. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2018;25:298&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29243511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jortveit J, Pripp AH, Lang&#xf8;rgen J, Halvorsen S. Incidence, risk factors and outcome of young patients with myocardial infarction. Heart Br Card Soc. 2020;106:1420&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32111640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>