<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38561784</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2524-4655</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>One health outlook</Title><ISOAbbreviation>One Health Outlook</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Scientific highlights of the 9th ESWI Influenza Conference.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s42522-024-00099-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The European Scientific Working Group on Influenza (ESWI) held the 9th ESWI Influenza Conference in Valencia from 17-20 September 2023. Here we provide a summary of twelve key presentations, covering major topics on influenza virus, respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) and SARS coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) including: infection processes beyond acute respiratory disease, long COVID, vaccines against influenza and RSV, the implications of the potential extinction of influenza B virus Yamagata lineage, and the threats posed by zoonotic highly pathogenic avian influenza viruses.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reperant</LastName><ForeName>Leslie</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pikado BV, Utrechtse Heuvelrug, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Russell</LastName><ForeName>Colin A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology and Infection Prevention, Amsterdam University Medical Center, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Osterhaus</LastName><ForeName>Albert</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Infection Medicine and Zoonosis Research and the University of Veterinary Medicine Hannover, Hannover, Germany. Albert.Osterhaus@tiho-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>One Health Outlook</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101769253</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2524-4655</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Ab Osterhaus is the Editor-in-Chief of <i>One Health Outlook.</i>
</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38561784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10986029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42522-024-00099-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s42522-024-00099-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ag&#xfc;ero M, Monne I, S&#xe1;nchez A, Zecchin B, Fusaro A, Ruano MJ, del Valle Arrojo M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Antonio R, Souto AM, Tordable P, Ca&#xf1;&#xe1;s J, Bonfante F, Giussani E, Terregino C, Orejas JJ. Authors&#x2019; response: Highly pathogenic influenza A(H5N1) viruses in farmed mink outbreak contain a disrupted second sialic acid binding site in neuraminidase, similar to human influenza A viruses. Eurosurveillance. 2023;28(7):1. doi: 10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2023.28.7.2300109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2023.28.7.2300109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9936594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36795502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews SF, Cominsky LY, Shimberg GD, Gillespie RA, Gorman J, Raab JE, Brand J, Creanga A, Gajjala SR, Narpala S, Cheung CSF, Harris DR, Zhou T, Gordon I, Holman LS, Mendoza F, Houser KV, Chen GL, Mascola JR, &#x2026; McDermott A. B. An influenza H1 hemagglutinin stem-only immunogen elicits a broadly cross-reactive B cell response in humans. Sci Transl Med 2023;15(692). 10.1126/SCITRANSLMED.ADE4976</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37075126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker C, Collet K, Gbesemete D, Piggin M, Watson D, Prister&#xe0; P, Lawerence W, Smith E, Bahrami-Hessari M, Johnson H, Baker K, Qavi A, McGrath C, Chiu C, Read RC, Ward H. Public attitudes to a human challenge study with SARS-CoV-2: A mixed-methods study. Wellcome Open Res 2022;7. 10.12688/WELLCOMEOPENRES.17516.1/DOI</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8921687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35321005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanken MO, Rovers MM, Molenaar JM, Winkler-Seinstra PL, Meijer A, Kimpen JLL, Bont L. Respiratory syncytial virus and recurrent wheeze in healthy preterm infants. N Engl J Med. 2013;368(19):1791&#x2013;1799. doi: 10.1056/NEJMOA1211917/SUPPL_FILE/NEJMOA1211917_DISCLOSURES.PDF.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMOA1211917/SUPPL_FILE/NEJMOA1211917_DISCLOSURES.PDF</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23656644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caliendo V, Lewis NS, Pohlmann A, Baillie SR, Banyard A C, Beer M, Brown IH, Fouchier RAM, Hansen RDE, Lameris TK, Lang AS, Laurendeau S, Lung O, Robertson G, van der Jeugd H, Alkie TN, Thorup K., van Toor ML, Waldenstr&#xf6;m J, &#x2026; Berhane Y. Transatlantic spread of highly pathogenic avian influenza H5N1 by wild birds from Europe to North America in 2021. Scientific Rep 2022;12:(1):1&#x2013;18. 10.1038/s41598-022-13447-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9276711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35821511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chestakova IV, van der Linden A, Bellido Martin B, Caliendo V, Vuong O, Thewessen S, Hartung T, Bestebroer T, Dekker J, Jonge Poerink B, Gr&#xf6;ne A, Koopmans M, Fouchier R, van den Brand JMA, Sikkema RS. High number of HPAI H5 virus infections and antibodies in wild carnivores in the Netherlands, 2020&#x2013;2022. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2023;12(2). 10.1080/22221751.2023.2270068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10732216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37842795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, Leavy OC, Richardson M, Elneima O, McAuley HJC, Shikotra A, Singapuri A, Sereno M, Saunders RM, Harris VC, Houchen-Wolloff L, Aul R, Beirne P, Bolton CE, Brown JS, Choudhury G, Diar-Bakerly N, Easom N, Echevarria C, &#x2026; Zongo O. Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet Respir Med 2022;10(8):761&#x2013;775. 10.1016/S2213-2600(22)00127-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9034855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35472304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;nther A, Krone O, Svansson V, Pohlmann A, King J, Hallgrimsson GT, Skarph&#xe9;&#xf0;insson KH, Sigur&#xf0;ard&#xf3;ttir H, J&#xf3;nsson SR, Beer M, Brugger B, Harder T. Iceland as stepping stone for spread of highly pathogenic avian influenza virus between Europe and North America. Emerg Infect Dis. 2022;28(12):2383&#x2013;2388. doi: 10.3201/EID2812.221086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/EID2812.221086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9707596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36261139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guthmiller JJ, Han J, Li L, Freyn AW, Liu STH, Stovicek O, Stamper CT, Dugan HL, Tepora ME, Utset HA, Bitar DJ, Hamel NJ, Changrob S, Zheng NY, Huang M, Krammer F, Nachbagauer R, Palese P, Ward AB, Wilson PC. First exposure to the pandemic H1N1 virus induced broadly neutralizing antibodies targeting hemagglutinin head epitopes. Sci Transl Med. 2021;13(596):4535. doi: 10.1126/SCITRANSLMED.ABG4535/SUPPL_FILE/ABG4535_SM.V1.PDF.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/SCITRANSLMED.ABG4535/SUPPL_FILE/ABG4535_SM.V1.PDF</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10173203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34078743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guthmiller JJ, Han J, Utset HA, Li L, Lan LYL, Henry C, Stamper CT, McMahon M, O&#x2019;Dell G, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Quintero ML, Freyn AW, Amanat F, Stovicek O, Gentles L, Richey ST, de la Pe&#xf1;a AT, Rosado V, Dugan HL, Zheng NY, &#x2026; Wilson PC. Broadly neutralizing antibodies target a haemagglutinin anchor epitope. Nature 2021;602(7896):314&#x2013;320. 10.1038/s41586-021-04356-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8828479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34942633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habel JR, Chua BY, Kedzierski L, Selva KJ, Damelang T, Haycroft ER, Nguyen THO, Koay HF, Nicholson S, McQuilten HA, Jia X, Allen LF, Hensen L, Zhang W, van de Sandt CE, Neil JA, Pragastis K, Lau JSY, Jumarang J, &#x2026; Kedzierska K. Immune profiling of SARS-CoV-2 infection during pregnancy reveals NK cell and &#x3b3;&#x3b4; T cell perturbations. JCI Insight 2023;8(7). 10.1172/JCI.INSIGHT.167157</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10132165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37036008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habel JR, Nguyen THO, van de Sandt CE, Juno JA, Chaurasia P, Wragg K, Koutsakos M, Hensen L, Jia X, Chua B, Zhang W, Tan HX, Flanagan KL, Doolan DL, Torresi J, Chen W, Wakim LM, Cheng AC, Doherty PC, &#x2026; Kedzierska K. Suboptimal SARS-CoV-2&#x2212;specific CD8+ T cell response associated with the prominent HLA-A*02:01 phenotype. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA, 2020;117(39):24384&#x2013;24391. 10.1073/PNAS.2015486117/SUPPL_FILE/PNAS.2015486117.SD01.XLSX</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7533701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32913053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habibi MS, Jozwik A, Makris S, Dunning J, Paras A, DeVincenzo JP, De Haan CAM, Wrammert J, Openshaw PJM, Chiu C. Impaired antibody-mediated protection and defective iga b-cell memory in experimental infection of adults with respiratory syncytial virus. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2015;191(9):1040&#x2013;1049. doi: 10.1164/RCCM.201412-2256OC/SUPPL_FILE/DISCLOSURES.PDF.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/RCCM.201412-2256OC/SUPPL_FILE/DISCLOSURES.PDF</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4435460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25730467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jozwik A, Habibi MS, Paras A, Zhu J, Guvenel A, Dhariwal J, Almond M, Wong EHC, Sykes A, Maybeno M, Del Rosario J, Trujillo-Torralbo MB, Mallia P, Sidney J, Peters B, Kon OM, Sette A, Johnston SL, Openshaw PJ, Chiu C. RSV-specific airway resident memory CD8+ T cells and differential disease severity after experimental human infection. Nat Commun 2015;6. 10.1038/NCOMMS10224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4703893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26687547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killingley B, Mann AJ, Kalinova M, Boyers A, Goonawardane N, Zhou J, Lindsell K, Hare SS, Brown J, Frise R, Smith E, Hopkins C, Noulin N, L&#xf6;ndt B, Wilkinson T, Harden S, McShane H, Baillet M, Gilbert A, &#x2026; Chiu C. Safety, tolerability and viral kinetics during SARS-CoV-2 human challenge in young adults. Nat Med 2022;28(5):1031&#x2013;1041. 10.1038/S41591-022-01780-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35361992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knisely JM, Buyon LE, Mandt R, Farkas R, Balasingam S, Bok K, Buchholz UJ, D&#x2019;Souza MP, Gordon JL, King DFL, Le TT, Leitner WW, Seder RA, Togias A, Tollefsen S, Vaughn DW, Wolfe DN, Taylor KL, Fauci AS. Mucosal vaccines for SARS-CoV-2: scientific gaps and opportunities-workshop report. NPJ Vaccines 2023;8(1). 10.1038/S41541-023-00654-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10091310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37045860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutsakos M, Rowntree LC, Hensen L, Chua BY, van de Sandt CE, Habel JR, Zhang W, Jia X, Kedzierski L, Ashhurst TM, Putri GH, Marsh-Wakefield F, Read MN, Edwards DN, Clemens EB, Wong CY, Mordant FL, Juno JA, Amanat F, &#x2026; Kedzierska K. Integrated immune dynamics define correlates of COVID-19 severity and antibody responses. Cell Rep Med 2021;2(3):100208. 10.1016/J.XCRM.2021.100208</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7862905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33564749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liew F, Efstathiou C, Openshaw PJM. Long COVID: clues about causes. Eur Respir J 2023;61(5). 10.1183/13993003.00409-2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10040855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36958743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lingwood D, McTamney PM, Yassine HM, Whittle JRR, Guo X, Boyington JC, Wei CJ, Nabel GJ. Structural and genetic basis for development of broadly neutralizing influenza antibodies. Nature. 2012;489(7417):566&#x2013;570. doi: 10.1038/nature11371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature11371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22932267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Sikkema RS, Velkers FC, Nieuwenhuijse DF, Fischer EAJ, Meijer PA, Bouwmeester-Vincken N, Rietveld A, Wegdam-Blans MCA, Tolsma P, Koppelman M, Smit LAM, Hakze-van der Honing RW, van der Poel WHM, van der Spek AN, Spierenburg MAH, Molenaar RJ, Rond J de, Augustijn M, &#x2026; Koopmans MPG. Adaptation, spread and transmission of SARS-CoV-2 in farmed minks and associated humans in the Netherlands. Nat Commun 2021;12(1):1&#x2013;12. 10.1038/s41467-021-27096-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8611045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34815406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mochizuki H, Kusuda S, Okada K, Yoshihara S, Furuya H, Sim&#xf5;es EAF, Asanuma H, Yoshida H, Katayose M, Imamura T, Suzumura H, Honma Y, Maruyama K, Ohki Y, Ozasa K, Nariai A, Uchiyama A, Uryu H, Hosono S, &#x2026; Ibara S. Palivizumab prophylaxis in preterm infants and subsequent recurrent wheezing: Six-year follow-up study. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2017;196(1):29&#x2013;38. 10.1164/RCCM.201609-1812OC/SUPPL_FILE/DISCLOSURES.PDF</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28152315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudd PA, Minervina AA, Pogorelyy MV, Turner JS, Kim W, Kalaidina E, Petersen J, Schmitz AJ, Lei T, Haile A, Kirk AM, Mettelman RC, Crawford JC, Nguyen THO, Rowntree LC, Rosati E, Richards KA, Sant AJ, Klebert MK, &#x2026; Ellebedy AH. SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccination elicits a robust and persistent T follicular helper cell response in humans. Cell 2022;185(4):603&#x2013;613.e15. 10.1016/J.CELL.2021.12.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8695127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35026152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munnink BBO, Sikkema RS, Nieuwenhuijse DF, Molenaar RJ, Munger E, Molenkamp R, Van Der Spek A, Tolsma P, Rietveld A, Brouwer M, Bouwmeester-Vincken N, Harders F, Der Honing RH Van, Wegdam-Blans MCA, Bouwstra RJ, GeurtsvanKessel C, Van Der Eijk AA, Velkers FC, Smit LAM, &#x2026; Koopmans MPG. Transmission of SARS-CoV-2 on mink farms between humans and mink and back to humans. Science (New York, N.Y.) 2021;371(6525):172&#x2013;177. 10.1126/SCIENCE.ABE5901</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nachbagauer R, Feser J, Naficy A, Bernstein DI, Guptill J, Walter EB, Berlanda-Scorza F, Stadlbauer D, Wilson PC, Aydillo T, Behzadi MA, Bhavsar D, Bliss C, Capuano C, Carre&#xf1;o JM, Chromikova V, Claeys C, Coughlan L, Freyn AW, &#x2026; Krammer F. A chimeric hemagglutinin-based universal influenza virus vaccine approach induces broad and long-lasting immunity in a randomized, placebo-controlled phase I trial. Nat Med 2020;27(1):106&#x2013;114. 10.1038/s41591-020-1118-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33288923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neeland MR, Bannister S, Clifford V, Dohle K, Mulholland K, Sutton P, Curtis N, Steer AC, Burgner DP, Crawford NW, Tosif S, Saffery R. Innate cell profiles during the acute and convalescent phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection in children. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-21414-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-21414-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7889848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33597531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen THO, Kedzierska K. Lung-resident memory CD81 T cells in human influenza: How innate are they? Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2021;204(7):753&#x2013;755. doi: 10.1164/RCCM.202106-1508ED/SUPPL_FILE/DISCLOSURES.PDF.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/RCCM.202106-1508ED/SUPPL_FILE/DISCLOSURES.PDF</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8528524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34352192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen THO, Rowntree LC, Allen LF, Chua BY, Kedzierski L, Lim C, Lasica M, Tennakoon GS, Saunders NR, Crane M, Chee L, Seymour JF, Anderson MA, Whitechurch A, Clemens EB, Zhang W, Chang SY, Habel JR, Jia X, &#x2026; Kedzierska K. Robust SARS-CoV-2 T&#xa0;cell responses with common TCR&#x3b1;&#x3b2; motifs toward COVID-19 vaccines in patients with hematological malignancy impacting B cells. Cell Rep Med 2023;4(4):101017. 10.1016/J.XCRM.2023.101017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10040362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37030296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen THO, Rowntree LC, Petersen J, Chua BY, Hensen L, Kedzierski L, van de Sandt CE, Chaurasia P, Tan HX, Habel JR, Zhang W, Allen LF, Earnest L, Mak KY, Juno JA, Wragg K, Mordant FL, Amanat F, Krammer F, &#x2026; Kedzierska K. CD8+ T&#xa0;cells specific for an immunodominant SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid epitope display high naive precursor frequency and TCR promiscuity. Immunity 2021;54(5):1066. 10.1016/J.IMMUNI.2021.04.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8049468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33951417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Openshaw PJM, Chiu C, Culley FJ, Johansson C. Protective and harmful immunity to RSV infection. 2017;35:501&#x2013;532. 10.1146/ANNUREV-IMMUNOL-051116-052206</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28226227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pappas L, Foglierini M, Piccoli L, Kallewaard NL, Turrini F, Silacci C, Fernandez-Rodriguez B, Agatic G, Giacchetto-Sasselli I, Pellicciotta G, Sallusto F, Zhu Q, Vicenzi E, Corti D, Lanzavecchia A. Rapid development of broadly influenza neutralizing antibodies through redundant mutations. Nature. 2014;516(7531):418&#x2013;422. doi: 10.1038/NATURE13764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/NATURE13764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25296253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Y, Mentzer AJ, Liu G, Yao X, Yin Z, Dong D, Dejnirattisai W, Rostron T, Supasa P, Liu C, L&#xf3;pez-Camacho C, Slon-Campos J, Zhao Y, Stuart DI, Paesen GC, Grimes JM, Antson AA, Bayfield OW, Hawkins DEDP, &#x2026; Knight JC. Broad and strong memory CD4+ and CD8+ T cells induced by SARS-CoV-2 in UK convalescent individuals following COVID-19. Nature Immunol 2020;21(11):1336&#x2013;1345. 10.1038/s41590-020-0782-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32887977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piggin M, Smith E, Mankone P, Ndegwa L, Gbesemete D, Prister&#xe0; P, Bahrami-Hessari M, Johnson H, Catchpole AP, Openshaw PJM, Chiu C, Read RC, Ward H, Barker C. The role of public involvement in the design of the first SARS-CoV-2 human challenge study during an evolving pandemic. Epidemics. 2022;41:100626. doi: 10.1016/J.EPIDEM.2022.100626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.EPIDEM.2022.100626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9434955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36088739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rijks JM, Leopold MF, K&#xfc;hn S, in&#x2019;t Veld R, Schenk F, Brenninkmeijer A, Lilipaly SJ, Ballmann MZ, Kelder L, de Jong JW, Courtens W, Slaterus R, Kleyheeg E, Vreman S, Kik MJL, Gr&#xf6;ne A., Fouchier RAM, Engelsma M, de Jong MCM, &#x2026; Beerens N. Mass mortality caused by highly pathogenic influenza A(H5N1) virus in sandwich terns, the Netherlands. Emerging Infect Dis 2022;28(12):2538&#x2013;254210.3201/EID2812.221292</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9707584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36418000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roestenberg M, Hoogerwerf MA, Ferreira DM, Mordm&#xfc;ller B, Yazdanbakhsh M. Experimental infection of human volunteers. Lancet Infect Dis. 2018;18(10):e312&#x2013;e322. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(18)30177-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(18)30177-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29891332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowntree LC, Nguyen THO, Kedzierski L, Neeland MR, Petersen J, Crawford JC, Allen LF, Clemens EB, Chua B, McQuilten HA, Minervina AA, Pogorelyy MV, Chaurasia P, Tan HX, Wheatley AK, Jia X, Amanat F, Krammer F, Allen EK, &#x2026; Kedzierska K. SARS-CoV-2-specific T cell memory with common TCR&#x3b1;&#x3b2; motifs is established in unvaccinated children who seroconvert after infection. Immunity 2022a;55(7):1299&#x2013;1315.e4. 10.1016/J.IMMUNI.2022.06.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9174177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35750048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowntree LC, Nguyen THO, Kedzierski L, Neeland MR, Petersen J, Crawford JC, Allen LF, Clemens EB, Chua B, McQuilten HA, Minervina AA, Pogorelyy MV, Chaurasia P, Tan HX, Wheatley AK, Jia X, Amanat F, Krammer F, Allen EK, &#x2026; Kedzierska K. SARS-CoV-2-specific T&#xa0;cell memory with common TCR&#x3b1;&#x3b2; motifs is established in unvaccinated children who seroconvert after infection. Immunity 2022b;55(7)1299&#x2013;1315.e4. 10.1016/J.IMMUNI.2022.06.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9174177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35750048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowntree LC, Petersen J, Juno JA, Chaurasia P, Wragg K, Koutsakos M, Hensen L, Wheatley AK, Kent SJ, Rossjohn J, Kedzierska K, Nguyen THO. SARS-CoV-2-specific CD8+ T-cell responses and TCR signatures in the context of a prominent HLA-A*24:02 allomorph. Immunol Cell Biol. 2021;99(9):990&#x2013;1000. doi: 10.1111/IMCB.12482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/IMCB.12482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34086357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selva KJ, van de Sandt CE, Lemke MM, Lee CY, Shoffner SK, Chua BY, Davis SK, Nguyen THO, Rowntree LC, Hensen L, Koutsakos M, Wong CY, Mordant F, Jackson DC, Flanagan KL, Crowe J, Tosif S, Neeland MR, Sutton P, &#x2026; Chung AW. Systems serology detects functionally distinct coronavirus antibody features in children and elderly. Nat Commun 2021;12(1):1&#x2013;14. 10.1038/s41467-021-22236-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8016934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33795692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigurs N, Aljassim F, Kjellman B, Robinson PD, Sigurbergsson F, Bjarnason R, Gustafsson PM. Asthma and allergy patterns over 18 years after severe RSV bronchiolitis in the first year of life. Thorax. 2010;65(12):1045&#x2013;1052. doi: 10.1136/THX.2009.121582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/THX.2009.121582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20581410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sui J, Hwang WC, Perez S, Wei G, Aird D, Chen LM, Santelli E, Stec B, Cadwell G, Ali M, Wan H, Murakami A, Yammanuru A, Han T, Cox NJ, Bankston LA, Donis RO, Liddington RC, Marasco WA. Structural and functional bases for broad-spectrum neutralization of avian and human influenza A viruses. Nat Struct Mol Biol. 2009;16(3):265&#x2013;273. doi: 10.1038/NSMB.1566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/NSMB.1566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2692245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19234466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thevarajan I, Nguyen THO, Koutsakos M, Druce J, Caly L, van de Sandt CE, Jia X, Nicholson S, Catton M, Cowie B, Tong SYC, Lewin SR, Kedzierska K. Breadth of concomitant immune responses prior to patient recovery: a case report of non-severe COVID-19. Nature Medicine. 2020;26(4):453&#x2013;455. doi: 10.1038/s41591-020-0819-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-020-0819-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32284614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Sandt CE, Clemens EB, Grant EJ, Rowntree LC, Sant S, Halim H, Crowe J, Cheng AC, Kotsimbos TC, Richards M, Miller A, Tong SYC, Rossjohn J, Nguyen THO, Gras S, Chen W, Kedzierska K. Challenging immunodominance of influenza-specific CD8+ T cell responses restricted by the risk-associated HLA-A*68:01 allomorph. Nat Commun. 2019;10(1):1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1038/s41467-019-13346-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-019-13346-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6898063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31811120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van De Sandt CE, Hillaire MLB, Geelhoed-Mieras MM, Osterhaus ADME, Fouchier RAM, Rimmelzwaan GF. Human influenza A virus-specific CD8+ T-cell response is long-lived. J Infect Dis. 2015;212(1):81&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1093/INFDIS/JIV018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/INFDIS/JIV018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4542594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25583167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Sandt CE, Kreijtz JHCM, de Mutsert G, Geelhoed-Mieras MM, Hillaire MLB, Vogelzang-van Trierum SE, Osterhaus ADME, Fouchier RAM, Rimmelzwaan GF. Human cytotoxic T lymphocytes directed to seasonal influenza A viruses cross-react with the newly emerging H7N9 virus. J Virol. 2014;88(3):1684&#x2013;1693. doi: 10.1128/JVI.02843-13/ASSET/811751C6-BC07-4871-808D-DD7F667CB1ED/ASSETS/GRAPHIC/ZJV9990986040003.JPEG.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.02843-13/ASSET/811751C6-BC07-4871-808D-DD7F667CB1ED/ASSETS/GRAPHIC/ZJV9990986040003.JPEG</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3911609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24257602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Sandt CE, Nguyen THO, Gherardin NA, et al. Newborn and child-like molecular signatures in older adults stem from TCR shifts across human lifespan. Nat Immunol. 2023;24:1890&#x2013;907. 10.1038/s41590-023-01633-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10602853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37749325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verhagen JH, Fouchier RAM, Lewis N. Highly pathogenic avian influenza viruses at the wild-domestic bird interface in Europe: future directions for research and surveillance. Viruses. 2021;13(2):212. doi: 10.3390/V13020212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/V13020212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7912471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33573231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Wan Y, Qiu C, Qui&#xf1;ones-Parra S, Zhu Z, Loh L, Tian D, Ren Y, Hu Y, Zhang X, Thomas PG, Inouye M, Doherty PC, Kedzierska K, Xu J. Recovery from severe H7N9 disease is associated with diverse response mechanisms dominated by CD8+ T cells. Nat Commun. 2015;6(1):1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1038/ncomms7833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms7833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4479016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25967273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheatley AK, Kent SJ. Strength in diversity: widening B cell recruitment for broader vaccine protection. Immunity. 2023;56(10):2182&#x2013;2184. doi: 10.1016/J.IMMUNI.2023.09.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.IMMUNI.2023.09.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37820580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang E, Nguyen THO, Allen LF, Kedzierski L, Rowntree LC, Chang SY, Zhang W, Habel JR, Foo IJ, Menon T, Mitchell J, Leong RW, Bond K, Williamson DA, Kedzierka K, Christensen B. Robust SARS-CoV-2 antibody and T cell immunity following three COVID-19 vaccine doses in inflammatory bowel disease patients receiving anti-TNF or alternative treatments. Gut. 2023 doi: 10.1136/GUTJNL-2022-329136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/GUTJNL-2022-329136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36878683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Kedzierski L, Chua BY, Mayo M, Lonzi C, Rigas V, Middleton BF, McQuilten HA, Rowntree LC, Allen LF, Purcell RA, Tan HX, Petersen J, Chaurasia P, Mordant F, Pogorelyy MV, Minervina AA, Crawford JC, Perkins GB, &#x2026; Kedzierska K. Robust and prototypical immune responses toward COVID-19 vaccine in First Nations peoples are impacted by comorbidities. Nat Immunol 2023;24(6):966&#x2013;978. 10.1038/s41590-023-01508-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10232372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37248417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Singanayagam A, Goonawardane N, Moshe M, Sweeney FP, Sukhova K, Killingley B, Kalinova M, Mann AJ, Catchpole AP, Barer MR, Ferguson NM, Chiu C, Barclay WS. Viral emissions into the air and environment after SARS-CoV-2 human challenge: a phase 1, open label, first-in-human study. Lancet Microbe. 2023;4(8):e579&#x2013;e590. doi: 10.1016/S2666-5247(23)00101-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2666-5247(23)00101-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10256269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37307844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X, Gebo KA, Abraham AG, Habtehyimer F, Patel EU, Laeyendecker O, Gniadek TJ, Fernandez RE, Baker OR, Ram M, Cachay ER, Currier JS, Fukuta Y, Gerber JM, Heath SL, Meisenberg B, Huaman MA, Levine AC, Shenoy A, &#x2026; Tobian AAR. Dynamics of inflammatory responses after SARS-CoV-2 infection by vaccination status in the USA: a prospective cohort study. Lancet Microbe, 2023;4(9):e692&#x2013;e703. 10.1016/S2666-5247(23)00171-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10475695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37659419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>