<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37094584</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4023</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>82</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cardiovascular pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cardiovasc Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Postural Orthostatic Tachycardia Syndrome After COVID-19: A Systematic Review of Therapeutic Interventions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23</StartPage><EndPage>31</EndPage><MedlinePgn>23-31</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/FJC.0000000000001432</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) is a clinical syndrome of inappropriate increase in heart rate on standing that has been recently also associated with Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) as part of the postacute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) or long-COVID. We herein aimed to systematically review reported cases of POTS after COVID-19 and determine the characteristics of the subjects, the diagnostic approach used, and the treatment strategies. We searched the literature according to the following criteria: (1) diagnosis of POTS according to standard definition; (2) timely association with a probable or definite diagnosis of COVID-19; and (3) a description of the individual subject(s). We identified 21 reports meeting criteria between March 2020 and September 2022, including 68 subjects (51 females and 17 males, 3:1 ratio) with a mean age of 34 &#xb1; 12 years, with reports deriving from the United States, Norway, Sweden, Israel, Ireland, United Kingdom, Singapore, and Japan. Most cases had mild COVID-19 symptoms. The most common POTS symptoms were palpitations, chest pain, lightheadedness, and debilitating fatigue. The diagnosis was established by means of head-up tilt table or active stand test. Nonpharmacologic treatments (fluids, sodium intake, and compression stockings) were virtually always used, but largely ineffective. Subjects received different treatments, the most common being beta-adrenergic blockers (ie, propranolol), mineral corticosteroids (ie, fludrocortisone), midodrine, and ivabradine. Symptoms tended to improve over time, but most patients remained symptomatic for several months. In conclusion, POTS after COVID-19 is a clinical condition affecting young individuals, and disproportionately young women, occurring as part of PASC-long-COVID, often debilitating, which can be easily diagnosed with a thorough clinical assessment and measuring changes in orthostatic heart rate and blood pressure. POTS after COVID-19 seems to be poorly responsive to nonpharmacological treatments but with symptoms improving with pharmacological interventions. Given the limited data available, additional research is urgently needed with respect to its epidemiology, pathophysiology, and treatments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abbate</LastName><ForeName>Gerardina</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robert M. Berne Cardiovascular Research Center, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, VA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Iulio</LastName><ForeName>Beatrice</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robert M. Berne Cardiovascular Research Center, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, VA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>Georgia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pauley Heart Center, Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Priday</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robert M. Berne Cardiovascular Research Center, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, VA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biondi-Zoccai</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medico-Surgical Sciences and Biotechnologies, Sapienza University of Rome, Latina, Italy; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mediterranea Cardiocentro, Napoli, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Markley</LastName><ForeName>Roshanak</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pauley Heart Center, Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abbate</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robert M. Berne Cardiovascular Research Center, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, VA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cardiovasc Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7902492</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0160-2446</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000319">Adrenergic beta-Antagonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>6YE7PBM15H</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008879">Midodrine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054972" MajorTopicYN="Y">Postural Orthostatic Tachycardia Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000319" MajorTopicYN="N">Adrenergic beta-Antagonists</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008879" MajorTopicYN="Y">Midodrine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37094584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/FJC.0000000000001432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005344-202307000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Low PA, Opfer-Gehrking TL, Textor SC, et al. Postural tachycardia syndrome (POTS). Neurology. 1995;45:S19&#x2013;S25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR. Postural tachycardia syndrome (POTS). Circulation. 2013;127:2336&#x2013;2342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B Cannom D, Fedorowski A, et al. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS): a critical assessment. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2020;63:263&#x2013;270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miglis MG, Prieto T, Shaik R, et al. A case report of postural tachycardia syndrome after COVID-19. Clin Auton Res. 2020;30:449&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanjwal K, Jamal S, Kichloo A, et al. New-onset postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome following coronavirus disease 2019 infection. J Innov Card Rhythm Manag. 2020;11:4302&#x2013;4304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umapathi T, Poh MQW, Fan BE, et al. Acute hyperhidrosis and postural tachycardia in a COVID-19 patient. Clin Auton Res. 2020;30:571&#x2013;573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR, Arnold AC, Barboi A, et al. Long-COVID postural tachycardia syndrome: an American Autonomic Society statement. Clin Auton Res. 2021;31:365&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang DH, Roy DJ, Gu BJ, et al. Postacute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection: a state-of-the-art review. JACC Basic Transl Sci. 2021;6:796&#x2013;811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S, Whitelaw S. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) and other autonomic disorders after COVID-19 infection: a case series of 20 patients. Immunol Res. 2021; 69:205&#x2013;211. Erratum in: Immunol Res. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson M, St&#xe5;hlberg M, Runold M, et al. Long-haul post-COVID-19 symptoms presenting as a variant of postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome: the Swedish experience. JACC Case Rep. 2021;3:573&#x2013;580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shouman K, Vanichkachorn G, Cheshire WP, et al. Autonomic dysfunction following COVID-19 infection: an early experience. Clin Auton Res. 2021;31:385&#x2013;394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman BP, Khoury JA, Blair JE, Grill MF. COVID-19 dysautonomia. Front Neurol. 2021; 12:624968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani M, Dirksen A, Taraborrelli P, et al. Autonomic dysfunction in 'long COVID': rationale, physiology and management strategies. Clin Med (Lond). 2021;21:e63&#x2013;e67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Sullivan JS, Lyne A, Vaughan CJ. COVID-19-induced postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome treated with ivabradine. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14:e243585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varanasi S, Sathyamoorthy M, Chamakura S, Shah SA. Management of long-COVID postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome with enhanced external counterpulsation. Cureus 2021; 13:e18398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajendran N, Rameli PM, Collins G. Quadruple-negative RT-PCR assay for COVID-19, but clinically and radiologically COVID pneumonia with POTS: case report and case-based review. SAGE Open Med Case Rep. 2021; 9:;2050313X2110666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schofield JR. Persistent antiphospholipid antibodies, mast cell activation syndrome, postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome and post-COVID syndrome: 1 Year on. Eur J Case Rep Intern Med. 2021; 8:002378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishibashi Y, Yoneyama K, Tsuchida T, et al. Post-COVID-19 postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. Intern Med. 2021;60:2345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gall NP, James S, Kavi L. Observational case series of postural tachycardia syndrome (PoTS) in post-COVID-19 patients. Br J Cardiol. 2022; 29:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco J, Titano R. Severe Post-COVID-19 dysautonomia: a case report. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22:214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miglis MG, Seliger J, Shaik R, et al. A case series of cutaneous phosphorylated &#x3b1;-synuclein in Long-COVID POTS. Clin Auton Res. 2022;32:209&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drogalis-Kim D, Kramer C, Duran S. Ongoing dizziness following acute COVID-19 infection: a single center pediatric case series. Pediatrics. 2022;150:e2022056860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agnihotri SP, Luis CVS, Kazamel M. Autonomic neuropathy as post-acute sequela of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a case report. J Neurovirol. 2022;28:158&#x2013;161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldokla AM, Ali ST. Autonomic function testing in long-COVID syndrome patients with orthostatic intolerance. Auton Neurosci. 2022;241:102997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitsou V, Blomberg B, Lunde T, Saeed S. Intermittent left bundle branch block with septal flash and postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome in a young woman with long COVID-19. BMJ Case Rep. 2022;15:e249608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokorelis C, Malone L, Byrne K, et al. Onset of postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) following COVID-19 infection: a pediatric case report. Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2023;62:92&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://covid19.who.int &#x2013; last. Accessed on 28 February 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28:583&#x2013;590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barda N, Dagan N, Ben-Shlomo Y, et al. Safety of the BNT162b2 mRNA covid-19 vaccine in a nationwide setting. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:1078&#x2013;1090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan AC, Ebinger JE, Wei J, et al. Apparent risks of postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome diagnoses after COVID-19 vaccination and SARS-Cov-2 infection. Nat Cardiovasc Res. 2022;1:1187&#x2013;1194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021; 38: 101019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hira R, Baker JR, Siddiqui T, et al. Objective hemodynamic cardiovascular autonomic abnormalities in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Can J Cardiol. 2022:S0828&#x2013;282X()01091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedorowski A, Sutton R. Autonomic dysfunction and postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome in post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2023; 20:281&#x2013;282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandman-Goddard G, Peeva E, Shoenfeld Y. Gender and autoimmunity. Autoimmun Rev. 2007;6:366&#x2013;372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piro M, Della Bona R, Abbate A, et al. Sex-related differences in myocardial remodeling. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2010;55:1057&#x2013;1065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plash WB, Diedrich A, Biaggioni I, et al. Diagnosing postural tachycardia syndrome: comparison of tilt testing compared with standing haemodynamics. Clin Sci (Lond). 2013;124:109&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR, Black BK, Biaggioni I, et al. Propranolol decreases tachycardia and improves symptoms in the postural tachycardia syndrome: less is more. Circulation. 2009;120:725&#x2013;734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold AC, Okamoto LE, Diedrich A, et al. Low-dose propranolol and exercise capacity in postural tachycardia syndrome: a randomized study. Neurology. 2013;80:1927&#x2013;1933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon J, Kim DY, Lee WJ, et al. Efficacy of propranolol, bisoprolol, and pyridostigmine for postural tachycardia syndrome: a randomized clinical trial. Neurotherapeutics. 2018;15:785&#x2013;795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Q, Vangundy TB, Shibata S, et al. Exercise training versus propranolol in the treatment of the postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. Hypertension. 2011;58:167&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taub PR, Zadourian A, Lo HC, et al. Randomized trial of ivabradine in patients with hyperadrenergic postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;77:861&#x2013;871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas J, Santos R, Azevedo E, et al. Clinical improvement in patients with orthostatic intolerance after treatment with bisoprolol and fludrocortisone. Clin Auton Res. 2000;10:293&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross AJ, Ocon AJ, Medow MS, Stewart JM. A double-blind placebo-controlled cross-over study of the vascular effects of midodrine in neuropathic compared with hyperadrenergic postural tachycardia syndrome. Clin Sci (Lond). 2014; 126:289&#x2013;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeldtke RD, Bryner KD, Hoeldtke ME, Hobbs G. Treatment of postural tachycardia syndrome: a comparison of octreotide and midodrine. Clin Auton Res. 2006;16:390&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>