<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38774167</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the Heart Failure Connection in Long COVID Patients: A Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e58694</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e58694</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e58694</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.58694</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In this narrative review, we explore the relationship between long COVID patients and their risk of developing heart failure (HF). Patients with long COVID face a heightened risk of HF, a critical cardiovascular complication linked to the prolonged effects of COVID-19. Clinical manifestations of long COVID-associated HF present diagnostic challenges, complicating patient management. Multidisciplinary care is essential to address these complexities effectively. We found that long COVID can result in various cardiovascular issues including HF. The current view is long COVID leads to HF by activating systemic inflammation by causing endothelial dysfunction, which leads to activation of the complement pathways, tissue factor pathways, and Von Willebrand factor; activation of all these factors leads to venous and arterial thrombosis, which could lead to clogging of blood vessel of the heart leading to cardiovascular complications. The association between long COVID and HF can be challenging despite being recognized as comorbidity because biomarkers are not dependable in determining whether a patient had HF before or after contracting COVID-19. Emerging therapeutic modalities offer hope for improving outcomes, but further research is needed to refine management strategies and mitigate long-term cardiovascular consequences of COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Olumuyide et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olumuyide</LastName><ForeName>Emmanuel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Advocate Illinois Masonic Medical Center, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agwuegbo</LastName><ForeName>Chibuike C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Southwest Healthcare, Temecula, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Eman N</ForeName><Initials>EN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Alfaisal University College of Medicine, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">2019-ncov</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular/cardio and vascular/blood vessel disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long covid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sars-cov-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wuhan coronavirus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38774167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11108637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.58694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The year in cardiovascular medicine 2021: heart failure and cardiomyopathies. Bauersachs J, de Boer RA, Lindenfeld J, Bozkurt B. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:367&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9383181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34974611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronavirus diseases (COVID-19) current status and future perspectives: a narrative review. Di Gennaro F, Pizzol D, Marotta C, Antunes M, Racalbuto V, Veronese N, Smith L. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:2690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32295188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: an overview. Raveendran AV, Jayadevan R, Sashidharan S. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15:869&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severe COVID-19 infection and cardiovascular disease - a long-term relationship or short myocardial affair? Motwani M. J Hypertens. 2022;40:1268&#x2013;1269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35762470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>New heart failure diagnoses among patients hospitalized for COVID-19. Alvarez-Garcia J, Jaladanki S, Rivas-Lasarte M, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;77:2260&#x2013;2262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8074874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33926664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A recovered case of COVID-19 myocarditis and ARDS treated with corticosteroids, tocilizumab, and experimental AT-001. Coyle J, Igbinomwanhia E, Sanchez-Nadales A, Danciu S, Chu C, Shah N. JACC Case Rep. 2020;2:1331&#x2013;1336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7196388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32368755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Increased risk of new&#x2010;onset cardiovascular disease after COVID&#x2010;19: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of 14 cohorts. Sun M, Yuan M, Lai H, et al. Rev Med Virol. 2024;34:2518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impaired right ventricular longitudinal strain without pulmonary hypertension in patients who have recovered from COVID-19. Nuzzi V, Castrichini M, Collini V, et al. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging. 2021;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33827250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Nat Med. 2022;28:583&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35132265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-recovery COVID-19 and incident heart failure in the National COVID Cohort Collaborative (N3C) study. Salah HM, Fudim M, O'Neil ST, Manna A, Chute CG, Caughey MC. Nat Commun. 2022;13:4117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9284961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35840623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term cardiovascular outcomes in COVID-19 survivors among non-vaccinated population: Aaretrospective cohort study from the TriNetX US collaborative networks. Wang W, Wang CY, Wang SI, Wei JC. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;53:101619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9366236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35971425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk of incident heart failure after COVID-19 recovery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Zuin M, Rigatelli G, Roncon L, Pasquetto G, Bilato C. Heart Fail Rev. 2023;28:859&#x2013;864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9792307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36572763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The long-term effects of the Covid-19 infection on cardiac symptoms. Golchin Vafa R, Heydarzadeh R, Rahmani M, et al. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2023;23:286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10243271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37280530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiac inflammation in COVID-19: lessons from heart failure. Unudurthi SD, Luthra P, Bose RJ, McCarthy JR, Kontaridis MI. Life Sci. 2020;260:118482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7505073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32971105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronavirus spike proteins in viral entry and pathogenesis. Gallagher TM, Buchmeier MJ. Virology. 2001;279:371&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7133764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11162792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and is blocked by a clinically proven protease inhibitor. Hoffmann M, Kleine-Weber H, Schroeder S, et al. Cell. 2020;181:271&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronavirus spike protein and tropism changes. Hulswit RJ, de Haan CA, Bosch BJ. Adv Virus Res. 2016;96:29&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7112277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27712627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physiological and molecular triggers for SARS-CoV membrane fusion and entry into host cells. Millet JK, Whittaker GR. Virology. 2018;517:3&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7112017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29275820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Structure of the SARS-CoV-2 spike receptor-binding domain bound to the ACE2 receptor. Lan J, Ge J, Yu J, et al. Nature. 2020;581:215&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32225176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Structural basis of receptor recognition by SARS-CoV-2. Shang J, Ye G, Shi K, et al. Nature. 2020;581:221&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7328981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32225175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Structural and functional basis of SARS-CoV-2 entry by using human ACE2. Wang Q, Zhang Y, Wu L, et al. Cell. 2020;181:894&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7144619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postmortem examination of COVID-19 patients reveals diffuse alveolar damage with severe capillary congestion and variegated findings in lungs and other organs suggesting vascular dysfunction. Menter T, Haslbauer JD, Nienhold R, et al. Histopathol. 2020;77:198&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7496150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32364264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endothelial cell infection and endotheliitis in COVID-19. Varga Z, Flammer AJ, Steiger P, et al. Lancet. 2020;395:1417&#x2013;1418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 in cardiac tissue of a child with COVID-19-related multisystem inflammatory syndrome. Dolhnikoff M, Ferreira Ferranti J, de Almeida Monteiro RA, et al. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2020;4:790&#x2013;794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7440866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32828177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 and heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. Freaney PM, Shah SJ, Khan SS. J Am Med Assoc. 2020;324:1499&#x2013;1500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33001179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term cardiovascular effects of COVID-19: emerging data relevant to the cardiovascular clinician. Tobler DL, Pruzansky AJ, Naderi S, Ambrosy AP, Slade JJ. Curr Atheroscler Rep. 2022;24:563&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9065238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35507278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Presenting characteristics, comorbidities, and outcomes among 5700 patients hospitalized with COVID-19 in the New York City area. Richardson S, Hirsch JS, Narasimhan M, et al. J Am Med Assoc. 2020;323:2052&#x2013;2059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7177629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32320003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical predictors of mortality due to COVID-19 based on an analysis of data of 150 patients from Wuhan, China. Ruan Q, Yang K, Wang W, Jiang L, Song J. Intensive Care Med. 2020;46:846&#x2013;848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7080116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32125452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impaired norepinephrine regulation of monocyte inflammatory cytokine balance in heart failure. Ng TM, Toews ML. World J Cardiol. 2016;8:584&#x2013;589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5088364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27847559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interleukin 6 and haemostasis. Kerr R, Stirling D, Ludlam CA. Br J Haematol. 2001;115:3&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11722403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interleukin-1 and the inflammasome as therapeutic targets in cardiovascular disease. Abbate A, Toldo S, Marchetti C, Kron J, Van Tassell BW, Dinarello CA. Circ Res. 2020;126:1260&#x2013;1280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8760628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32324502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Electrical remodeling in ischemia and infarction. Pinto J. Cardiovasc Res. 1999;42:284&#x2013;297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10533567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiovascular considerations for patients, health care workers, and health systems during the COVID-19 pandemic. Driggin E, Madhavan MV, Bikdeli B, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;75:2352&#x2013;2371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7198856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32201335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heart failure in COVID-19 patients: prevalence, incidence and prognostic implications. Rey JR, Caro-Cod&#xf3;n J, Rosillo SO, et al. Eur J Heart Fail. 2020;22:2205&#x2013;2215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32833283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID and the cardiovascular system-elucidating causes and cellular mechanisms in order to develop targeted diagnostic and therapeutic strategies: a joint Scientific Statement of the ESC Working Groups on Cellular Biology of the Heart and Myocardial and Pericardial Diseases. Gy&#xf6;ngy&#xf6;si M, Alcaide P, Asselbergs FW, et al. Cardiovasc Res. 2023;119:336&#x2013;356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9384470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35875883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>"LONG COVID": an insight. Ahmad MS, Shaik RA, Ahmad RK, et al. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2021;25:5561&#x2013;5577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34533807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multi-disciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of cardiovascular complications in patients with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) Whiteson JH, Azola A, Barry JT, et al. PM R. 2022;14:855&#x2013;878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9347705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35657351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, et al. J R Soc Med. 2021;114:428&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiac manifestations of post-acute COVID-19 infection. Mohammad KO, Lin A, Rodriguez JB. Curr Cardiol Rep. 2022;24:1775&#x2013;1783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9628458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36322364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Admission NT-proBNP and outcomes in patients without history of heart failure hospitalized with COVID-19. Yoo J, Grewal P, Hotelling J, et al. ESC Heart Fail. 2021;8:4278&#x2013;4287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8426942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34346182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spectrum of cardiac manifestations in COVID-19: a systematic echocardiographic study. Szekely Y, Lichter Y, Taieb P, et al. Circulation. 2020;142:342&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7382541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prognostic value of right ventricular longitudinal strain in patients with COVID-19. Li Y, Li H, Zhu S, et al. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2020;13:2287&#x2013;2299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32654963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Right ventricular dilation in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 infection. Argulian E, Sud K, Vogel B, et al. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2020;13:2459&#x2013;2461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32426088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prognostic utility of right ventricular remodeling over conventional risk stratification in patients with COVID-19. Kim J, Volodarskiy A, Sultana R, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76:1965&#x2013;1977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7572068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33092732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echocardiographic abnormalities and predictors of mortality in hospitalized COVID-19 patients: the ECHOVID-19 study. Lassen MC, Skaarup KG, Lind JN, et al. ESC Heart Fail. 2020;7:4189&#x2013;4197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33089972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recovery of cardiac function following COVID-19&#xa0;-&#xa0;ECHOVID-19: a prospective longitudinal cohort study. Lassen MC, Skaarup KG, Lind JN, et al. Eur J Heart Fail. 2021;23:1903&#x2013;1912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8652600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34514713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes of cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in patients recently recovered from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Puntmann VO, Carerj ML, Wieters I, et al. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:1265&#x2013;1273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiac involvement in patients recovered from COVID-2019 identified using magnetic resonance imaging. Huang L, Zhao P, Tang D, et al. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2020;13:2330&#x2013;2339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7214335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32763118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathogenic mechanisms of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) Sherif ZA, Gomez CR, Connors TJ, Henrich TJ, Reeves WB. Elife. 2023;12:86002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10032659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36947108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The pathogenesis and long-term consequences of COVID-19 cardiac injury. Siripanthong B, Asatryan B, Hanff TC, et al. JACC Basic Transl Sci. 2022;7:294&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8828362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35165665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combined cardiac fluorodeoxyglucose-positron emission tomography/magnetic resonance imaging assessment of myocardial injury in patients who recently recovered from COVID-19. Hanneman K, Houbois C, Schoffel A, et al. JAMA Cardiol. 2022;7:298&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8756363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35019953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tocilizumab in patients admitted to hospital with COVID-19 (RECOVERY): a randomised, controlled, open-label, platform trial. RECOVERY Collaborative Group. Lancet. 2021;397:1637&#x2013;1645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8084355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33933206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Rapid Guideline: Managing COVID-19. National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE)  [
Mar;
2024 
]. 2022. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK571450/ http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK571450/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34181371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endotoxin-induced cardiomyopathy and systemic inflammation in mice is prevented by aldose reductase inhibition. Ramana KV, Willis MS, White MD, et al. Circulation. 2006;114:1838&#x2013;1846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17030682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Successful treatment of acute heart failure in COVID-19-induced cytokine storm with tocilizumab: a case report. Chitturi KR, Thacker S, Al-Saadi MA, Kassi M. Eur Heart J Case Rep. 2020;4:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33089052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID-19 myocarditis and various heart failure presentations: a case series. Rohun J, Dorniak K, Faran A, Kocha&#x144;ska A, Zacharek D, Dani&#x142;owicz-Szymanowicz L. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis. 2022;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9785067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36547424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathological interplay and clinical complications between COVID-19 and cardiovascular diseases: an overview in 2023. Zhou S, Zhang A, Liao H, Liu Z, Yang F. Cardiology. 2024;149:60&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11251668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37586358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disparities by social determinants of health: links between Long COVID and cardiovascular disease. Banerjee A. Can J Cardiol. 2024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38428523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>