<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37389095</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2233-8276</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Asia Pacific allergy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Asia Pac Allergy</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Immunological dysfunction and mast cell activation syndrome in long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>50</StartPage><EndPage>53</EndPage><MedlinePgn>50-53</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5415/apallergy.0000000000000022</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>At least 65 million people around the world suffer from long COVID-19, with the majority of cases occurring in the productive age (36-50 years old). Individuals with long COVID-19 are confounded with multiple organ system dysfunctions, long-term organ injury sequelae, and a decreased quality of life. There is an overlapping of risk factors between long COVID-19 and other postviral infection syndromes, so advances in research could also benefit other groups of patients. Long COVID-19 is the consequence of multiple immune system dysregulation, such as T-cell depletion, innate immune cell hyperactivity, lack of naive T and B cells, and elevated signature of pro-inflammatory cytokines, together with persistent severe acute respiratory syndrome-coronavirus 2 reservoir and other consequences of acute infection. There is an activated condition of mast cells in long COVID-19, with abnormal granulation and excessive inflammatory cytokine release. A study by Weinstock et al. indicates that patients with long COVID-19 suffer the same clinical syndrome as patients with mast cell activation syndrome (MCAS). Diagnosis and treatment of MCAS in patients with long COVID-19 will provide further symptomatic relief, and manage mast cell-mediated hyperinflammation states, which could be useful in the long-term control and recovery of such patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023. Asia Pacific Association of Allergy, Asthma and Clinical Immunology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sumantri</LastName><ForeName>Stevent</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5866-6484</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Allergy and Clinical Immunology Division, Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Pelita Harapan, Banten, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rengganis</LastName><ForeName>Iris</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8748-8544</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Allergy and Clinical Immunology Division, Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Indonesia, Jakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Asia Pac Allergy</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101561954</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2233-8276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MCAS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mast cells</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no financial conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37389095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10166245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5415/apallergy.0000000000000022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Data Explorer - Our World in Data.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umesh A, Pranay K, Pandey RC, Gupta MK. Evidence mapping and review of long-COVID and its underlying pathophysiological mechanism. Infection 2022;50:1053&#x2013;1066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9055372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35489015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanares-Zapatero D, Chalon P, Kohn L, Dauvrin M, Detollenaere J, Maertens de Noordhout C, Primus-de Jong C, Cleemput I, Van den Heede K. Pathophysiology and mechanism of long COVID: a comprehensive review. Ann Medicine 2022;54:1473&#x2013;1487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35594336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonsaksen T, Leung J, Price D, Ruffolo M, Lamph G, Kabelenga I, Thygesen H, Geirdal A&#xd8;. Self-reported long COVID in the general population: sociodemographic and health correlates in a cross-national sample. Life 2022;12:901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9228837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35743932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi B, Sudry T, Flaks-Manov N, Yehezkelli Y, Kalkstein N, Akiva P, Ekka-Zohar A, Ben David SS, Lerner U, Bivas-Benita M, Greenfeld S. Long covid outcomes at one year after mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: nationwide cohort study. BMJ 2023;380:e072529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9832503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36631153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlis RH, Santillana M, Ognyanova K, Safarpour A, Trujillo KL, Simonson MD, Green J, Quintana A, Druckman J, Baum MA, Lazer D. Prevalence and correlates of long COVID symptoms among US adults. JAMA Netw Open 2022;5:e2238804E2238804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9614581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36301542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Mahoney LL, Routen A, Gillies C, Ekezie W, Welford A, Zhang A, Karamchandani U, Simms-Williams N, Cassambai S, Ardavani A, Wilkinson T J, Hawthorne G, Curtis F, Kingsnorth AP, Almaqhawi A, Ward T, Ayoubkhani D, Banerjee A, Calvert M, Shafran R, Stephenson T, Sterne J, Ward H, Evans RA, Zaccardi F, Wright S, Khunti K. The prevalence and long-term health effects of long Covid among hospitalised and non-hospitalised populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine 2023;55:101762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9714474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36474804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fainardi V, Meoli A, Chiopris G, Motta M, Skenderaj K, Grandinetti R, Bergomi A, Antodaro F, Zona S, Esposito S. Long COVID in children and adolescents. Life 2022;12:285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8876679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35207572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M. Pathological sequelae of long-haul COVID. Nat Immunol 2022;23:194&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mumtaz A, Sheikh AAE, Khan AM, Khalid SN, Khan J, Nasrullah A, Sagheer S, Sheikh AB. COVID-19 vaccine and long COVID: a scoping review. Life 2022;12:1066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9324565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35888154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Wang Y, Sun Q, Knopf J, Herrmann M, Lin L, Jiang J, Shao C, Li P, He X, Hua F, Niu Z, Ma C, Zhu Y, Ippolito G, Piacentini M, Estaquier J, Melino S, Weiss FD, Andreano E, Latz E, Schultze JL, Rappuoli R, Mantovani A, Mak TW, Melino G, Shi Y. Immune response in COVID-19: what is next? Cell Death Differ 2022;29:1107&#x2013;1122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9110941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35581387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nile SH, Nile A, Qiu J, Li L, Jia X, Kai G. COVID-19: pathogenesis, cytokine storm and therapeutic potential of interferons. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev 2020;53:66&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7204669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32418715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Geng M, Peng Y, Meng L, Lu S. Molecular immune pathogenesis and diagnosis of COVID-19. J Pharm Anal 2020;10:102&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7104082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32282863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batiha GES, Al-kuraishy HM, Al-Gareeb AI, Welson NN. Pathophysiology of post-COVID syndromes: a new perspective. Virol J 2022;19:158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9548310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36210445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monje M, Iwasaki A. The neurobiology of long COVID. Neuron 2022;110:3484&#x2013;3496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9537254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36288726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akin C, Valent P, Metcalfe DD. Mast cell activation syndrome: proposed diagnostic criteria. J Allergy Clin Immunol 2010;126:1099&#x2013;1104.e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3753019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21035176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akin C. Mast cell activation syndromes. J Allergy Clin Immunol 2017;140:349&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28780942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castells M, Butterfield J. Mast cell activation syndrome and mastocytosis: initial treatment options and long-term management. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract 2019;7:1097&#x2013;1106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30961835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szukiewicz D, Wojdasiewicz P, Watroba M, Szewczyk G. mast cell activation syndrome in COVID-19 and female reproductive function: theoretical background vs. accumulating clinical evidence. J Immunol Res 2022;2022:9534163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9242765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35785029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstock LB, Brook JB, Walters AS, Goris A, Afrin LB., Molderings GJ. Mast cell activation symptoms are prevalent in long-COVID. Int J Infect Dis 2021;112:217&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34563706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortona E, Malorni W. Long COVID: to investigate immunological mechanisms and sex/gender related aspects as fundamental steps for a tailored therapy. Eur Respir J 2022;59:2102245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8462012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34531277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton MJ. Nonclonal mast cell activation syndrome: a growing body of evidence. Immunol Allergy Clin North Am 2018;38:469&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6049091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30007464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings SV, Finnerty CC, Hobart JS, Mart&#xed;n-Mart&#xed;nez M, Sinclair KA, Slee VM, Agopian J, Akin C, &#xc1;lvarez-Twose I, Bonadonna P, Bowman AS, Brockow K, Bumbea H, de Haro C, Fok JS, Hartmann K, Hegmann N, Hermine O, Kalisiak M, Katelaris CH, Kurz J, Marcis P, Mayne D, Mendoza D, Moussy A, Mudretzkyj G, Vaia NN, Niedoszytko M, Elberink HO, Orfao A, Radia DH, Rosenmeier S, Ribada E, Schinhofen W, Schwaab J, Siebenhaar F, Triggiani M, Tripodo G, Velazquez R, Wielink Y, Wimazal F, Yigit T, Zubrinich C, Valent P. Mast cell diseases in practice and research: issues and perspectives raised by patients and their recommendations to the scientific community and beyond. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract 2022;10:2039&#x2013;2051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35777651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>