<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37215236</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2645-4904</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Archives of academic emergency medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arch Acad Emerg Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Late Complications of COVID-19; An Umbrella Review on Current Systematic Reviews.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e28</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e28</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e28</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.22037/aaem.v11i1.1907</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Several clinical manifestations have been discovered for COVID-19 since the emergence of SARS-CoV-2, which can be classified into early, medium, and long-term complications. However, late complications can be present after recovery from acute COVID-19 illness. The present study aims to comprehensively review the available evidence of late complications related to COVID-19.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A search was conducted, using keywords, through electronic databases, which included Scopus, Web of Science, PubMed, and Embase up to August 29, 2022. Study selection was performed according to a strict inclusion and exclusion criteria. The Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) checklist was followed, and studies were appraised using the National Institute of Health (NIH) quality assessment and risk of bias tool.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In total, 50 studies were included, and nine distinct COVID-19 late complication categories were identified. A review of these studies revealed that neurologic and psychiatric (n=41), respiratory (n=27), musculoskeletal and rheumatologic (n=22), cardiovascular (n=9), and hepatic and gastrointestinal (n=6) complications were the most prevalent complications of long COVID-19.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Almost all human body systems are affected by late complications of COVID-19 with different severity and prevalence. Fatigue and some other neuropsychiatric symptoms are the most common late complications among long COVID-19 patients. Respiratory symptoms including dyspnea (during exercise), cough, and chest tightness were the next most prevalent long-term complications of COVID-19. Since these complications are persistent and late, being aware of the signs and symptoms is essential for the healthcare providers and patients.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>SeyedAlinaghi</LastName><ForeName>SeyedAhmad</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Iranian Research Center for HIV/AIDS, Iranian Institute for Reduction of High Risk Behaviors, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bagheri</LastName><ForeName>AmirBehzad</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Consortium on Advanced Motion Performance, Division of Vascular Surgery and Endovascular Therapy, Michael E. DeBakey Department of Surgery, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Razi</LastName><ForeName>Armin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of medicine, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mojdeganlou</LastName><ForeName>Paniz</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mojdeganlou</LastName><ForeName>Hengameh</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, The Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Afsahi</LastName><ForeName>Amir Masoud</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, School of Medicine, University of California, San Diego (UCSD), California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Afzalian</LastName><ForeName>Arian</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of medicine, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paranjkhoo</LastName><ForeName>Parinaz</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Turpanjian College of Health Sciences, American University of Armenia, Yerevan 0019, Armenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahidi</LastName><ForeName>Ramin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Bushehr University of Medical Sciences, Bushehr, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzapour</LastName><ForeName>Pegah</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Iranian Research Center for HIV/AIDS, Iranian Institute for Reduction of High Risk Behaviors, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pashaei</LastName><ForeName>Zahra</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Iranian Research Center for HIV/AIDS, Iranian Institute for Reduction of High Risk Behaviors, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Habibi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Amin</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Development Center, Qom University of Medical Sciences, Qom, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahbazi</LastName><ForeName>Parmida</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedic Department, Orthopedic Surgery Research Center (OSRC), Sina Hospital, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nooralioghli Parikhani</LastName><ForeName>Sahar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of medicine, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farizani Gohari</LastName><ForeName>Narjes Sadat</ForeName><Initials>NS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Shahid Sadoughi University of Medical Sciences, Yazd, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Popoola</LastName><ForeName>Yusuf</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Information Management Unit, Department of Computer Science, Adeleke University, Ede, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehraeen</LastName><ForeName>Esmaeil</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Information Technology, Khalkhal University of Medical Sciences, Khalkhal, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hackett</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activity, Lifestyle, Ageing and Wellbeing Faculty Research Group, School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Arch Acad Emerg Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101740147</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2645-4904</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Outcome Assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest regarding the publication of this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37215236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10197916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22037/aaem.v11i1.1907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mehraeen E, Oliaei S, SeyedAlinaghi S, Karimi A, Mirzapour P, Afsahi AM, et al. COVID-19 in pediatrics: a systematic review of current knowledge and practice. Infect Disord Drug Targets (Formerly Current Drug Targets-Infectious Disorders). 2022;22(5):47&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34587889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SeyedAlinaghi S, Karimi A, Barzegary A, Pashaei Z, Afsahi AM, Alilou S, Janfaza N, Shojaei A, Afroughi F, Mohammadi P, Soleimani Y, Nazarian N, Amiri A, Tantuoyir MM, Oliaei S, Mehraeen E, Dadras O. Mucormycosis infection in patients with COVID-19: A systematic review. Health Sci Rep. 2022 Feb;5(2):e529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8885749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35252593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M, Kleine-Weber H, Schroeder S, Kr&#xfc;ger N, Herrler T, Erichsen S, et al. SARS-CoV-2 Cell Entry Depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and Is Blocked by a Clinically Proven Protease Inhibitor. Cell. 2020;181(2):271&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Fang X, Cai Z, Wu X, Gao X, Min J, et al. Comorbid Chronic Diseases and Acute Organ Injuries Are Strongly Correlated with Disease Severity and Mortality among COVID-19 Patients: A Systemic Review and Meta-Analysis. Research (Wash D C). 2020;2020:2402961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32377638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alimohamadi Y, Sepandi M, Taghdir M, Hosamirudsari H. Determine the most common clinical symptoms in COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Prev Med Hyg. 2020;61(3):E304&#x2013;e12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7595075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33150219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Cassar MP, Tunnicliffe EM, Filippini N, Griffanti L, Alfaro-Almagro F, et al. Medium-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on multiple vital organs, exercise capacity, cognition, quality of life and mental health, post-hospital discharge. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;31:100683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33490928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):16144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, Billig Rose E, Shapiro NI, Files DC, et al. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network&#x2014;United States, March&#x2013;June 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69(30):993&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, Hishmeh L. Managing the long term effects of covid-19: summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ. 2021 Jan;:372:n136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai AD, Lavelle M, Boursiquot BC, Wan EY. Long-term complications of COVID-19. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol.&#xa0;. 2022;322(1):C1&#x2013;C11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8721906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34817268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh Y, Gupta G, Kazmi I, Al&#x2010;Abbasi FA, Negi P, Chellappan DK, et al. SARS CoV&#x2010;2 aggravates cellular metabolism mediated complications in COVID&#x2010;19 infection. Dermatol Ther . &#xa0;2020;33(6):e13871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32558055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coperchini F, Chiovato L, Croce L, Magri F, Rotondi M. The cytokine storm in COVID-19: An overview of the involvement of the chemokine/chemokine-receptor system. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2020;53:25&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32446778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj L, Kannapadi NV, Briggs J, Seal SM, Battaglini D, Fanning J, et al. Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: A meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci.&#xa0;. 2022;434:120162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8798975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinzon RT, Wijaya VO, Jody AA, Nunsio PN, Buana RB. Persistent neurological manifestations in long COVID-19 syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Infect Public Health. 2022 Aug;15(8):856&#x2013;869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9221935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35785594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long Q, Li J, Hu X, Bai Y, Zheng Y, Gao Z. Follow-Ups on Persistent Symptoms and Pulmonary Function Among Post-Acute COVID-19 Patients: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Front Med (Lausanne). 2021 Sep;8:702635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8448290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34540862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderlind WM, Rabinovitz BB, Miao IY, Oberlin LE, Bueno-Castellano C, Fridman C, et al. A systematic review of neuropsychological and psychiatric sequalae of COVID-19: implications for treatment. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2021;34(4):420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8183238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34016818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schou TM, Joca S, Wegener G, Bay-Richter C. Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19&#x2013;A systematic review. Brain Behav Immun. 2021;97:328&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8363196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora T, Grey I, &#xd6;stlundh L, Lam KBH, Omar OM, Arnone D. The prevalence of psychological consequences of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. J Health Psychol. 2022;27(4):805&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33118376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badenoch JB, Rengasamy ER, Watson C, Jansen K, Chakraborty S, Sundaram RD, et al. Persistent neuropsychiatric symptoms after COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Commun. 2022;4(1):fcab297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8833580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35169700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourmistrova NW, Solomon T, Braude P, Strawbridge R, Carter B. Long-term effects of COVID-19 on mental health: A systematic review. J Affect Disord. 2022;299:118&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8758130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34798148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khraisat B, Toubasi A, AlZoubi L, Al-Sayegh T, Mansour A. Meta-analysis of prevalence: the psychological sequelae among COVID-19 survivors. Int J Psychiatry Clin Pract. 2022 Sep;26(3):234&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34709105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed H, Patel K, Greenwood DC, Halpin S, Lewthwaite P, Salawu A, et al. Long-term clinical outcomes in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus outbreaks after hospitalisation or ICU admission: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Rehabil Med. 2020;52(5):jrm00063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32449782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkodaymi MS, Omrani OA, Fawzy NA, Shaar BA, Almamlouk R, Riaz M, et al. Prevalence of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome symptoms at different follow-up periods: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28(5):657&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8812092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Ling S, Lui LMW, Lee Y, Gill H, Teopiz KM, et al. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun. 2022;101:93&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global Prevalence of Post-Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Condition or Long COVID: A Meta-Analysis and Systematic Review. J Infect Dis. 2022 Nov;226(9):1593&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Florencio LL, Cuadrado ML, Plaza-Manzano G, et al. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Intern Med. 2021;92:55&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34167876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, Cheng V, Dagens A, Hastie C, O'Hara M, Suett J, Dahmash D, Bugaeva P, Rigby I, Munblit D, Harriss E, Burls A, Foote C, Scott J, Carson G, Olliaro P, Sigfrid L, Stavropoulou C. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Health. 2021 Sep;6(9):e005427&#x2013;2021-005427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen NN, Hoang VT, Dao TL, Dudouet P, Eldin C, Gautret P. Clinical patterns of somatic symptoms in patients suffering from post-acute long COVID: a systematic review. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2022;41(4):515&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8830952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salamanna F, Veronesi F, Martini L, Landini MP, Fini M. Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: The Persistent Symptoms at the Post-viral Stage of the Disease A Systematic Review of the Current Data. Front Med (Lausanne). 2021;8:653516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8129035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34017846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T, Yan MZ, Li X, Lau EHY. Sequelae of COVID-19 among previously hospitalized patients up to 1&#xa0;year after discharge: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Infection. 2022;50(5):1067&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9244338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35750943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng N, Zhao YM, Yan W, Li C, Lu QD, Liu L, Ni SY, Mei H, Yuan K, Shi L, Li P, Fan TT, Yuan JL, Vitiello MV, Kosten T, Kondratiuk AL, Sun HQ, Tang XD, Liu MY, Lalvani A, Shi J, Bao YP, Lu L. A systematic review and meta-analysis of long term physical and mental sequelae of COVID-19 pandemic: call for research priority and action. Mol Psychiatry. 2023 Jan;28(1):423&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9168643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35668159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almas T, Malik J, Alsubai AK, Jawad Zaidi SM, Iqbal R, Khan K, Ali M, Ishaq U, Alsufyani M, Hadeed S, Alsufyani R, Ahmed R, Thakur T, Huang H, Antony M, Antony I, Bhullar A, Kotait F, Al-Ani L. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and its prolonged effects: An updated systematic review. Ann Med Surg (Lond). 2022 Aug;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9197790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35721785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad MS, Shaik RA, Ahmad RK, Yusuf M, Khan M, Almutairi AB, et al. &#x201c;LONG COVID&#x201d;: An insight. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2021;25(17):5561&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34533807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healey Q, Sheikh A, Daines L, Vasileiou E. Symptoms and signs of long COVID: A rapid review and meta-analysis. J Glob Health. 2022 May;12:05014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9125197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35596571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>d'Ettorre G, Gentilini Cacciola E, Santinelli L, De Girolamo G, Spagnolello O, Russo A, et al. Covid&#x2010;19 sequelae in working age patients: A systematic review. J Med Virol. 2022;94(3):858&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34655247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE, Ba DM, Parsons N, Poudel GR, et al. Short-term and long-term rates of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a systematic review. JAMA network open. 2021;4(10):e2128568&#x2013;e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34643720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q, Zheng B, Daines L, Sheikh A. Long-Term sequelae of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis of one-year follow-up studies on post-COVID symptoms. Pathogens. 2022;11(2):269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8875269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35215212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwu CJ, Iwu CD, Wiysonge CS. The occurrence of long COVID: a rapid review. Pan Afr Med J. 2021 Jan;38:65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8028365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33889231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal FM, Lam K, Sounderajah V, Clarke JM, Ashrafian H, Darzi A. Characteristics and predictors of acute and chronic post-COVID syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;36:100899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8141371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34036253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SeyedAlinaghi S, Afsahi AM, MohsseniPour M, Behnezhad F, Salehi MA, Barzegary A, Mirzapour P, Mehraeen E, Dadras O. Late Complications of COVID-19; a Systematic Review of Current Evidence. Arch Acad Emerg Med. 2021 Jan;9(1):e14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7927752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33681819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings G, Monaghan A, Xue F, Mockler D, Romero-Ortu&#xf1;o R. A systematic review of persistent symptoms and residual abnormal functioning following acute COVID-19: ongoing symptomatic phase vs. post-COVID-19 syndrome. J Clin Med.&#xa0;. 2021;10(24):5913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8708187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34945213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y, Deng J, Liu Q, Du M, Liu M, Liu J. Long-Term Consequences of COVID-19 at 6 Months and Above: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(11):6865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9180091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35682448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik P, Patel K, Pinto C, Jaiswal R, Tirupathi R, Pillai S, et al. Post&#x2010;acute COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome (PCS) and health&#x2010;related quality of life (HRQoL)&#x2014;A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Med Virol. 2022;94(1):253&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34463956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera Martimbianco AL, Pacheco RL, Bagattini &#xc2;M, Riera R. Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID&#x2010;19: A systematic review. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75(10):e14357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8236920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33977626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Ramirez DC, Normand K, Zhaoyun Y, Torres-Castro R. Long-term impact of COVID-19: a systematic review of the literature and meta-analysis. Biomedicines. 2021;9(8):900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34440104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandler CX, Wyller VBB, Moss-Morris R, Buchwald D, Crawley E, Hautvast J, Katz BZ, Knoop H, Little P, Taylor R, Wensaas KA, Lloyd AR. Long COVID and Post-infective Fatigue Syndrome: A Review. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021 Sep;8(10):ofab440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8496765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34631916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renaud-Charest O, Lui LM, Eskander S, Ceban F, Ho R, Di Vincenzo JD, et al. Onset and frequency of depression in post-COVID-19 syndrome: A systematic review. J Psychiatr Res. 2021;144:129&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34619491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z&#xfc;rcher SJ, Banzer C, Adamus C, Lehmann AI, Richter D, Kerksieck P. Post-viral mental health sequelae in infected persons associated with COVID-19 and previous epidemics and pandemics: Systematic review and meta-analysis of prevalence estimates. J Infect Public Health. 2022 May;15(5):599&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9020842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35490117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehraeen E, Dadras O, Afsahi AM, Karimi A, Pour MM, Mirzapour P, et al. Vaccines for COVID-19: A Systematic Review of Feasibility and Effectiveness. Infect Disord Drug Targets. 2022;22(2):e230921196758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34554905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed JO, Ahmad SA, Hassan MN, Kakamad FH, Salih RQ, Abdulla BA, Rahim Fattah FH, Mohammed SH, Ali RK, Salih AM. Post COVID-19 neurological complications; a meta-analysis. Ann Med Surg (Lond). 2022 Apr;76:103440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8891214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35261766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez&#x2010;de&#x2010;las&#x2010;Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro&#x2010;Santana M, G&#xf3;mez&#x2010;Mayordomo V, Cuadrado ML, Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Azor&#xed;n D, Arendt&#x2010;Nielsen L, et al. Headache as an acute and post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 symptom in COVID&#x2010;19 survivors: A meta&#x2010;analysis of the current literature. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28(11):3820&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34327787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>So M, Kabata H, Fukunaga K, Takagi H, Kuno T. Radiological and functional lung sequelae of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Pulm Med. 2021 Mar;21(1):97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7983097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33752639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patria YN, Sabirin RM. COVID-19 potentially causes long-term deterioration of lung function: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Med. J. Indones. 2021;30(4):279&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gracia-Ramos AE, Martin-Nares E, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Molina G. New Onset of Autoimmune Diseases Following COVID-19 Diagnosis. Cells. 2021 Dec;10(12):3592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8700122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34944099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alosaimi B, AlFayyad I, Alshuaibi S, Almutairi G, Alshaebi N, Alayyaf A, et al. Cardiovascular complications and outcomes among athletes with COVID-19 disease: a systematic review. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2022;14(1):74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9020555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35443680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramadan MS, Bertolino L, Zampino R, Durante-Mangoni E. Cardiac sequelae after coronavirus disease 2019 recovery: a systematic review. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27(9):1250&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8220864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34171458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Tariq R, Jena A, Vesely EK, Singh S, Khanna S, et al. Gastrointestinal manifestations of long COVID: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Therap Adv Gastroenterol. 2022;15:17562848221118403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9393939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36004306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Ayuzo Del Valle NC, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, et al. Long-COVID in children and adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):9950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9226045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35739136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behnood SA, Shafran R, Bennett SD, Zhang AXD, O'Mahoney LL, Stephenson TJ, et al. Persistent symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection amongst children and young people: A meta-analysis of controlled and uncontrolled studies. J Infect.&#xa0;. 2022;84(2):158&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8604800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34813820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca P, Di Stadio A, Colacurcio V, Marra P, Scarpa A, Ricciardiello F, et al. Long COVID, audiovestibular symptoms and persistent chemosensory dysfunction: a systematic review of the current evidence. Acta Otorhinolaryngol Ital. 2022;42(Suppl 1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9137376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35763279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali SS, Mumtaz A, Qamar MA, Tebha SS, Parhin A, Butt M, Essar MY. New-onset Parkinsonism as a Covid-19 infection sequela: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Med Surg (Lond). 2022 Aug;80:104281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9359766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35971509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willi S, L&#xfc;thold R, Hunt A, H&#xe4;nggi NV, Sejdiu D, Scaff C, et al. COVID-19 sequelae in adults aged less than 50 years: A systematic review. Travel Med Infect Dis. 2021;40:101995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7898978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33631340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>