<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37650258</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1862-8354</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Proteomics. Clinical applications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Proteomics Clin Appl</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Detection of recombinant Spike protein in the blood of individuals vaccinated against SARS-CoV-2: Possible molecular mechanisms.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2300048</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2300048</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/prca.202300048</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The SARS-CoV-2 pandemic prompted the development and use of next-generation vaccines. Among these, mRNA-based vaccines consist of injectable solutions of mRNA encoding for a recombinant Spike, which is distinguishable from the wild-type protein due to specific amino acid variations introduced to maintain the protein in a prefused state. This work presents a proteomic approach to reveal the presence of recombinant Spike protein in vaccinated subjects regardless of antibody titer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="EXPERIMENTAL DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Mass spectrometry examination of biological samples was used to detect the presence of specific fragments of recombinant Spike protein in subjects who received mRNA-based vaccines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The specific PP-Spike fragment was found in 50% of the biological samples analyzed, and its presence was independent of the SARS-CoV-2 IgG antibody titer. The minimum and maximum time at which PP-Spike was detected after vaccination was 69 and 187 days, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND CLINICAL RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The presented method allows to evaluate the half-life of the Spike protein molecule "PP" and to consider the risks or benefits in continuing to administer additional booster doses of the SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccine. This approach is of valuable support to complement antibody level monitoring and represents the first proteomic detection of recombinant Spike in vaccinated subjects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Proteomics - Clinical Applications published by Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brogna</LastName><ForeName>Carlo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research, Craniomed Group Facility Srl, Bresso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cristoni</LastName><ForeName>Simone</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ISB-Ion Source &amp; Biotechnologies Srl, Bresso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marino</LastName><ForeName>Giuliano</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Marsanconsulting Srl. Public Health Company, Napoli, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Montano</LastName><ForeName>Luigi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Andrology Unit and Service of LifeStyle Medicine in Uro-Andrology, Local Health Authority (ASL) Salerno, Salerno, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Viduto</LastName><ForeName>Valentina</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Long COVID-19 Foundation, Brookfield Court, Garforth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fabrowski</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Royal Sussex County Hospital, University Hospitals Sussex, Brighton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lettieri</LastName><ForeName>Gennaro</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, University of Naples Federico II, Napoli, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piscopo</LastName><ForeName>Marina</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0560-6952</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, University of Naples Federico II, Napoli, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Proteomics Clin Appl</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101298608</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1862-8346</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000086663">COVID-19 Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000657845">spike protein, SARS-CoV-2</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D064370">Spike Glycoprotein, Coronavirus</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012333">RNA, Messenger</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086663" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19 Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040901" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteomics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064370" MajorTopicYN="N">Spike Glycoprotein, Coronavirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012333" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Messenger</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014611" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccination</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spike protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mass spectrometry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccine mRNA</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37650258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/prca.202300048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Brogna, B., Brogna, C., Petrillo, M., Conte, A. M., Benincasa, G., Montano, L., &amp; Piscopo, M. (2021). SARS-CoV-2 detection in fecal sample from a patient with typical findings of COVID-19 pneumonia on CT but negative to multiple SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR tests on oropharyngeal and nasopharyngeal swab samples. Medicina, 57(3), 3. https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina57030290</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna, C., Brogna, B., Bisaccia, D. R., Giuliano, M., Montano, L., Cristoni, S., Petrillo, M., &amp; Piscopo, M. (2022). SARS-CoV-2: Reinfection after 18 months of a previous case with multiple negative nasopharyngeal swab tests and positive fecal molecular test. Medicina, 58(5), 5. https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina58050642</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna, C., Brogna, B., Bisaccia, D. R., Lauritano, F., Marino, G., Montano, L., Cristoni, S., Prisco, M., &amp; Piscopo, M. (2022). Could SARS-CoV-2 have bacteriophage behavior or induce the activity of other bacteriophages? Vaccines, 10(5), 5. https://doi.org/10.3390/vaccines10050708</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna, C., Costanzo, V., Brogna, B., Bisaccia, D. R., Brogna, G., Giuliano, M., Montano, L., Viduto, V., Cristoni, S., Fabrowski, M., &amp; Piscopo, M. (2023). Analysis of bacteriophage behavior of a human RNA virus, SARS-CoV-2, through the integrated approach of immunofluorescence microscopy, proteomics and D-amino acid quantification. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 24(4), 4. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms24043929</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogna, C., Cristoni, S., Brogna, B., Bisaccia, D. R., Marino, G., Viduto, V., Montano, L., &amp; Piscopo, M. (2023). Toxin-like peptides from the bacterial cultures derived from gut microbiome infected by SARS-CoV-2-new data for a possible role in the long COVID pattern. Biomedicines, 11(1), 1. https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines11010087</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, W., Gan, H., Ma, Y., Xu, L., Cheng, Z. J., Li, B., Zhang, X., Jiang, W., Sun, J., Sun, B., &amp; Hao, C. (2022). The molecular mechanism of SARS-CoV-2 evading host antiviral innate immunity. Virology Journal, 19(1), 49. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12985-022-01783-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gusev, E., Sarapultsev, A., Solomatina, L., &amp; Chereshnev, V. (2022). SARS-CoV-2-specific immune response and the pathogenesis of COVID-19. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 23(3), 1716. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms23031716</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel, R., Kaki, M., Potluri, V. S., Kahar, P., &amp; Khanna, D. (2022). A comprehensive review of SARS-CoV-2 vaccines: Pfizer, Moderna &amp; Johnson &amp; Johnson. Human Vaccines &amp; Immunotherapeutics, 18(1), 2002083. https://doi.org/10.1080/21645515.2021.2002083</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#x103;ndulescu, O., Apostolescu, C. G., Preo&#x21b;escu, L. L., Streinu-Cercel, A., &amp; S&#x103;ndulescu, M. (2023). Therapeutic developments for SARS-CoV-2 infection-molecular mechanisms of action of antivirals and strategies for mitigating resistance in emerging variants in clinical practice. Frontiers in Microbiology, 14, 1132501. https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fmicb.2023.1132501</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasidharan, S., Sarkar, N., &amp; Saudagar, P. (2023). Discovery of compounds inhibiting SARS-COV-2 multi-targets. Journal of Biomolecular Structure and Dynamics, 41(6), 2602-2617. https://doi.org/10.1080/07391102.2021.2025149</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva Andrade, B., Siqueira, S., de Assis Soares, W. R., de Souza Rangel, F., Santos, N. O., dos Santos Freitas, A., Ribeiro da Silveira, P., Tiwari, S., Alzahrani, K. J., G&#xf3;es-Neto, A., Azevedo, V., Ghosh, P., &amp; Barh, D. (2021). Long-COVID and post-COVID health complications: An up-to-date review on clinical conditions and their possible molecular mechanisms. Viruses, 13(4), 4. https://doi.org/10.3390/v13040700</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Letko, M., Marzi, A., &amp; Munster, V. (2020). Functional assessment of cell entry and receptor usage for SARS-CoV-2 and other lineage B betacoronaviruses. Nature Microbiology, 5(4), 562-569. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41564-020-0688-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, L., &amp; Gao, G. F. (2021). Viral targets for vaccines against COVID-19. Nature Reviews Immunology, 21(2), 2. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41577-020-00480-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andries, O., Mc Cafferty, S., De Smedt, S. C., Weiss, R., Sanders, N. N., &amp; Kitada, T. (2015). N(1)-methylpseudouridine-incorporated mRNA outperforms pseudouridine-incorporated mRNA by providing enhanced protein expression and reduced immunogenicity in mammalian cell lines and mice. Journal of Controlled Release: Official Journal of the Controlled Release Society, 217, 337-344. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jconrel.2015.08.051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nance, K. D., &amp; Meier, J. L. (2021). Modifications in an emergency: The role of N1-methylpseudouridine in COVID-19 vaccines. ACS Central Sciences, 7(5), 748-756. https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.1c00197</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbett, K. S., Edwards, D. K., Leist, S. R., Abiona, O. M., Boyoglu-Barnum, S., Gillespie, R. A., Himansu, S., Sch&#xe4;fer, A., Ziwawo, C. T., DiPiazza, A. T., Dinnon, K. H., Elbashir, S. M., Shaw, C. A., Woods, A., Fritch, E. J., Martinez, D. R., Bock, K. W., Minai, M., Nagata, B. M., &amp; Graham, B. S. (2020). SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccine design enabled by prototype pathogen preparedness. Nature, 586(7830), 567-571. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2622-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wrapp, D., Wang, N., Corbett, K. S., Goldsmith, J. A., Hsieh, C.-L., Abiona, O., Graham, B. S., &amp; McLellan, J. S. (2020). Cryo-EM structure of the 2019-nCoV spike in the prefusion conformation. Science, 367(6483), 1260-1263. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.abb2507</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen, J. V., Ong, S.-E., &amp; Mann, M. (2004). Trypsin cleaves exclusively C-terminal to arginine and lysine residues. Molecular &amp; Cellular Proteomics: MCP, 3(6), 608-614. https://doi.org/10.1074/mcp.T400003-MCP200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cristoni, S., &amp; Bernardi, L. R. (2004). Bioinformatics in mass spectrometry data analysis for proteomics studies. Expert Review of Proteomics, 1(4), 469-483. https://doi.org/10.1586/14789450.1.4.469</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cristoni, S., Bernardi, L. R., Biunno, I., Tubaro, M., &amp; Guidugli, F. (2003). Surface-activated no-discharge atmospheric pressure chemical ionization. Rapid Communications in Mass Spectrometry, 17(17), 1973-1981. https://doi.org/10.1002/rcm.1141</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundgren, D. H., Hwang, S.-I., Wu, L., &amp; Han, D. K. (2010). Role of spectral counting in quantitative proteomics. Expert Review of Proteomics, 7(1), 39-53. https://doi.org/10.1586/epr.09.69</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okada, P., Buathong, R., Phuygun, S., Thanadachakul, T., Parnmen, S., Wongboot, W., Waicharoen, S., Wacharapluesadee, S., Uttayamakul, S., Vachiraphan, A., Chittaganpitch, M., Mekha, N., Janejai, N., Iamsirithaworn, S., Lee, R. T., &amp; Maurer-Stroh, S. (2020). Early transmission patterns of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in travellers from Wuhan to Thailand, January 2020. Eurosurveillance, 25(8), 2000097. https://doi.org/10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2020.25.8.2000097</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cognetti, J. S., &amp; Miller, B. L. (2021). Monitoring serum spike protein with disposable photonic biosensors following SARS-CoV-2 vaccination. Sensors, 21(17), 17. https://doi.org/10.3390/s21175857</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castruita, J. A. S., Schneider, U. V., Mollerup, S., Leineweber, T. D., Weis, N., Bukh, J., Pedersen, M. S., &amp; Westh, H. (2023). SARS-CoV-2 spike mRNA vaccine sequences circulate in blood up to 28 days after COVID-19 vaccination. Apmis, 131(3), 128-132. https://doi.org/10.1111/apm.13294</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsafarova, B., Hodzhev, Y., Yordanov, G., Tolchkov, V., Kalfin, R., &amp; Panaiotov, S. (2023). Morphology of blood microbiota in healthy individuals assessed by light and electron microscopy. Frontiers in Cellular and Infection Microbiology, 12, 1091341. https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fcimb.2022.1091341</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yishai Aviram, L., Magen, M., Chapman, S., Neufeld Cohen, A., Lazar, S., &amp; Dagan, S. (2018). Dry Blood Spot sample collection for post-exposure monitoring of chemical warfare agents-in vivo determination of phosphonic acids using LC-MS/MS. Journal of Chromatography B: Analytical Technologies in the Biomedical and Life Sciences, 1093-1094, 60-65. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchromb.2018.06.035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medical Advisory Secretariat. (2003). Neonatal screening of inborn errors of metabolism using tandem mass spectrometry: An evidence-based analysis. Ontario Health Technology Assessment Series, 3(3), 1-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Girolamo, F., Alessandroni, J., Somma, P., &amp; Guadagni, F. (2010). Pre-analytical operating procedures for serum low molecular weight protein profiling. Journal of Proteomics, 73(3), 667-677. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jprot.2009.09.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, N. L., Clark, T., Raman, R., &amp; Sasisekharan, R. (2021). Insights on the mutational landscape of the SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variant. Cell Reports Medicine, 3(2), 100527. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.1005279</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cristoni, S., Dusi, G., Brambilla, P., Albini, A., Conti, M., Brambilla, M., Bruno, A., Di Gaudio, F., Ferlin, L., Tazzari, V., Mengozzi, S., Barera, S., Sialer, C., Trenti, T., Cantu, M., Rossi Bernardi, L., &amp; Noonan, D. M. (2017). SANIST: Optimization of a technology for compound identification based on the European Union directive with applications in forensic, pharmaceutical and food analyses. Journal of Mass Spectrometry: JMS, 52(1), 16-21. https://doi.org/10.1002/jms.3895</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>