<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38776716</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0372</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>87</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Yin and yang of interferons: lessons from the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102423</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102423</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.coi.2024.102423</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0952-7915(24)00013-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The host immune response against severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 includes the induction of a group of natural antiviral cytokines called interferons (IFNs). Although originally recognized for their ability to potently counteract infections, the mechanistic functions of IFNs in patients with varying severities of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) have highlighted a more complex scenario. Cellular and molecular analyses have revealed that timing, location, and subtypes of IFNs produced during severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection play a major role in determining disease progression and severity. In this review, we summarize what the COVID-19 pandemic has taught us about the protective and detrimental roles of IFNs during the inflammatory response elicited against a new respiratory virus across different ages and its longitudinal consequences in driving the development of long COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Svensson Akusj&#xe4;rvi</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Division of Immunology, Boston Children's Hospital, Boston, MA, USA; Division of Immunology and Allergy, Department of Medicine Solna, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zanoni</LastName><ForeName>Ivan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Division of Immunology, Boston Children's Hospital, Boston, MA, USA; Division of Gastroenterology, Boston Children's Hospital, Boston, MA, USA. Electronic address: ivan.zanoni@childrens.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 DK115217</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8900118</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0952-7915</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9008-11-1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007372">Interferons</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007372" MajorTopicYN="Y">Interferons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016709" MajorTopicYN="N">Yin-Yang</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38776716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1996929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11162909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coi.2024.102423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0952-7915(24)00013-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lazear HM, Schoggins JW, Diamond MS: Shared and Distinct Functions of Type I and Type III Interferons. Immunity 2019, 50:907&#x2013;923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6839410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30995506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee AK, Blanco MR, Bruce EA, Honson DD, Chen LM, Chow A, Bhat P, Ollikainen N, Quinodoz SA, Loney C, et al.: SARS-CoV-2 Disrupts Splicing, Translation, and Protein Trafficking to Suppress Host Defenses. Cell 2020, 183:1325&#x2013;1339.e1321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33080218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu JC, Laurent-Rolle M, Pawlak JB, Wilen CB, Cresswell P: Translational shutdown and evasion of the innate immune response by SARS-CoV-2 NSP14 protein. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2021, 118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8214666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34045361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkel Y, Gluck A, Nachshon A, Winkler R, Fisher T, Rozman B, Mizrahi O, Lubelsky Y, Zuckerman B, Slobodin B, et al.: SARS-CoV-2 uses a multipronged strategy to impede host protein synthesis. Nature 2021, 594:240&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33979833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kehrer T, Cupic A, Ye C, Yildiz S, Bouhaddou M, Crossland NA, Barrall EA, Cohen P, Tseng A, &#xc7;a&#x11f;atay T, et al.: Impact of SARS-CoV-2 ORF6 and its variant polymorphisms on host responses and viral pathogenesis. Cell Host Microbe 2023, 31:1668&#x2013;1684e.1612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10750313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37738983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minkoff JM, tenOever B: Innate immune evasion strategies of SARS-CoV-2. Nature Reviews Microbiology 2023, 21:178&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9838430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36631691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanoni I: Interfering with SARS-CoV-2: are interferons friends or foes in COVID-19? Curr Opin Virol 2021, 50:119&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8367741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco-Melo D, Nilsson-Payant BE, Liu WC, Uhl S, Hoagland D, M&#xf8;ller R, Jordan TX, Oishi K, Panis M, Sachs D, et al.: Imbalanced Host Response to SARS-CoV-2 Drives Development of COVID-19. Cell 2020, 181:1036&#x2013;1045.e1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7227586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32416070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galani IE, Rovina N, Lampropoulou V, Triantafyllia V, Manioudaki M, Pavlos E, Koukaki E, Fragkou PC, Panou V, Rapti V, et al.: Untuned antiviral immunity in COVID-19 revealed by temporal type I/III interferon patterns and flu comparison. Nat Immunol 2021, 22:32&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33277638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong L-YR, Perlman S: Immune dysregulation and immunopathology induced by SARS-CoV-2 and related coronaviruses &#x2014; are we our own worst enemy? Nature Reviews Immunology 2022, 22:47&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8617551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34837062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park A, Iwasaki A: Type I and Type III Interferons - Induction, Signaling, Evasion, and Application to Combat COVID-19. Cell Host Microbe 2020, 27:870&#x2013;878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32464097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucas C, Wong P, Klein J, Castro TBR, Silva J, Sundaram M, Ellingson MK, Mao T, Oh JE, Israelow B, et al.: Longitudinal analyses reveal immunological misfiring in severe COVID-19. Nature 2020, 584:463&#x2013;469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7477538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32717743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadjadj J, Yatim N, Barnabei L, Corneau A, Boussier J, Smith N, P&#xe9;r&#xe9; H, Charbit B, Bondet V, Chenevier-Gobeaux C, et al.: Impaired type I interferon activity and inflammatory responses in severe COVID-19 patients. Science 2020, 369:718&#x2013;724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7402632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israelow B, Song E, Mao T, Lu P, Meir A, Liu F, Alfajaro MM, Wei J, Dong H, Homer RJ, et al.: Mouse model of SARS-CoV-2 reveals inflammatory role of type I interferon signaling. J Exp Med 2020, 217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7401025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32750141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sefik E, Israelow B, Mirza H, Zhao J, Qu R, Kaffe E, Song E, Halene S, Meffre E, Kluger Y, et al.: A humanized mouse model of chronic COVID-19. Nature Biotechnology 2022, 40:906&#x2013;920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9203605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34921308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sefik E, Qu R, Junqueira C, Kaffe E, Mirza H, Zhao J, Brewer JR, Han A, Steach HR, Israelow B, et al.: Inflammasome activation in infected macrophages drives COVID-19 pathology. Nature 2022, 606:585&#x2013;593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9288243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35483404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson SJ, Bedard O, McNally KL, Shaia C, Clancy CS, Lewis M, Broeckel RM, Chiramel AI, Shannon JG, Sturdevant GL, et al.: Genetically diverse mouse models of SARS-CoV-2 infection reproduce clinical variation in type I interferon and cytokine responses in COVID-19. Nature Communications 2023, 14:4481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10368652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37491352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castaneda DC, Jangra S, Yurieva M, Martinek J, Callender M, Coxe M, Choi A, Garc&#xed;a-Bernalt Diego J, Lin J, Wu TC, et al.: Spatiotemporally organized immunomodulatory response to SARS-CoV-2 virus in primary human broncho-alveolar epithelia. iScience 2023, 26:107374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10374611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37520727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adam L, Stanifer M, Springer F, Mathony J, Brune M, Di Ponzio C, Eils R, Boulant S, Niopek D, Kallenberger SM: Transcriptomics-inferred dynamics of SARS-CoV-2 interactions with host epithelial cells. Science Signaling 2023, 16:eabl8266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37751479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagstaffe HR, Thwaites RS, Reynaldi A, Sidhu JK, McKendry R, Ascough S, Papargyris L, Collins AM, Xu J, Lemm N-M, et al.: Mucosal and systemic immune correlates of viral control after SARS-CoV-2 infection challenge in seronegative adults. Science Immunology 2024, 9:eadj9285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38335268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziegler CGK, Miao VN, Owings AH, Navia AW, Tang Y, Bromley JD, Lotfy P, Sloan M, Laird H, Williams HB, et al.: Impaired local intrinsic immunity to SARS-CoV-2 infection in severe COVID-19. Cell 2021, 184:4713&#x2013;4733.e4722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8299217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34352228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sposito B, Broggi A, Pandolfi L, Crotta S, Clementi N, Ferrarese R, Sisti S, Criscuolo E, Spreafico R, Long JM, et al.: The interferon landscape along the respiratory tract impacts the severity of COVID-19. Cell 2021, 184:4953&#x2013;4968.e4916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8373821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34492226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastard P, Rosen LB, Zhang Q, Michailidis E, Hoffmann HH, Zhang Y, Dorgham K, Philippot Q, Rosain J, B&#xe9;ziat V, et al.: Autoantibodies against type I IFNs in patients with lifethreatening COVID-19. Science 2020, 370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asano T, Boisson B, Onodi F, Matuozzo D, Moncada-Velez M, Maglorius Renkilaraj MRL, Zhang P, Meertens L, Bolze A, Materna M, et al.: X-linked recessive TLR7 deficiency in ~1% of men under 60 years old with life-threatening COVID-19. Sci Immunol 2021, 6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8532080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34413140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastard P, Gervais A, Le Voyer T, Rosain J, Philippot Q, Manry J, Michailidis E, Hoffmann HH, Eto S, Garcia-Prat M, et al.: Autoantibodies neutralizing type I IFNs are present in ~4% of uninfected individuals over 70 years old and account for ~20% of COVID-19 deaths. Sci Immunol 2021, 6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8521484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34413139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang EY, Mao T, Klein J, Dai Y, Huck JD, Jaycox JR, Liu F, Zhou T, Israelow B, Wong P, et al.: Diverse functional autoantibodies in patients with COVID-19. Nature 2021, 595:283&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34010947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arrestier R, Bastard P, Belmondo T, Voiriot G, Urbina T, Luyt CE, Gervais A, Bizien L, Segaux L, Ben Ahmed M, et al.: Auto-antibodies against type I IFNs in &gt; 10% of critically ill COVID-19 patients: a prospective multicentre study. Ann Intensive Care 2022, 12:121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9803887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36586050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastard P, Vazquez S, Liu J, Laurie MT, Wang CY, Gervais A, Le Voyer T, Bizien L, Zamecnik C, Philippot Q, et al.: Vaccine breakthrough hypoxemic COVID-19 pneumonia in patients with auto-Abs neutralizing type I IFNs. Sci Immunol 2022:eabp8966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9210448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35857576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucciol G, Moens L, Ogishi M, Rinchai D, Matuozzo D, Momenilandi M, Kerrouche N, Cale CM, Treffeisen ER, Al Salamah M, et al.: Human inherited complete STAT2 deficiency underlies inflammatory viral diseases. The Journal of Clinical Investigation 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10266780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36976641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matuozzo D, Talouarn E, Marchal A, Zhang P, Manry J, Seeleuthner Y, Zhang Y, Bolze A, Chaldebas M, Milisavljevic B, et al.: Rare predicted loss-of-function variants of type I IFN immunity genes are associated with life-threatening COVID-19. Genome Med 2023, 15:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10074346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37020259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combes AJ, Courau T, Kuhn NF, Hu KH, Ray A, Chen WS, Chew NW, Cleary SJ, Kushnoor D, Reeder GC, et al.: Global absence and targeting of protective immune states in severe COVID-19. Nature 2021, 591:124&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8567458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33494096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowery SA, Sariol A, Perlman S: Innate immune and inflammatory responses to SARS-CoV-2: Implications for COVID-19. Cell Host Microbe 2021, 29:1052&#x2013;1062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8126603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34022154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Bastard P, Liu Z, Le Pen J, Moncada-Velez M, Chen J, Ogishi M, Sabli IKD, Hodeib S, Korol C, et al.: Inborn errors of type I IFN immunity in patients with life-threatening COVID-19. Science 2020, 370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solanich X, Vargas-Parra G, van der Made CI, Simons A, Schuurs-Hoeijmakers J, Antol&#xed; A, Del Valle J, Rocamora-Blanch G, Seti&#xe9;n F, Esteller M, et al.: Genetic Screening for TLR7 Variants in Young and Previously Healthy Men With Severe COVID-19. Front Immunol 2021, 12:719115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8343010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34367187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a A, P&#xe9;rez de Diego R, Flores C, Rinchai D, Sol&#xe9;-Viol&#xe1;n J, Dey&#xe0;-Mart&#xed;nez &#xc0;, Garc&#xed;a-Solis B, Lorenzo-Salazar JM, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Brito E, Lanz A-L, et al.: Humans with inherited MyD88 and IRAK-4 deficiencies are predisposed to hypoxemic COVID-19 pneumonia. Journal of Experimental Medicine 2023, 220:e20220170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9998661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36880831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scully EP, Haverfield J, Ursin RL, Tannenbaum C, Klein SL: Considering how biological sex impacts immune responses and COVID-19 outcomes. Nat Rev Immunol 2020, 20:442&#x2013;447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7288618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32528136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodin P: Immune determinants of COVID-19 disease presentation and severity. Nature Medicine 2021, 27:28&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33442016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pairo-Castineira E, Clohisey S, Klaric L, Bretherick AD, Rawlik K, Pasko D, Walker S, Parkinson N, Fourman MH, Russell CD, et al.: Genetic mechanisms of critical illness in COVID-19. Nature 2021, 591:92&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33307546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edahiro R, Shirai Y, Takeshima Y, Sakakibara S, Yamaguchi Y, Murakami T, Morita T, Kato Y, Liu Y-C, Motooka D, et al.: Single-cell analyses and host genetics highlight the role of innate immune cells in COVID-19 severity. Nature Genetics 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10181941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37095364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solanich X, Rigo-Bonnin R, Gumucio VD, Bastard P, Rosain J, Philippot Q, Perez-Fernandez XL, Fuset-Cabanes MP, Gordillo-Benitez M, Suarez-Cuartin G, et al.: Pre-existing Autoantibodies Neutralizing High Concentrations of Type I Interferons in Almost 10% of COVID-19 Patients Admitted to Intensive Care in Barcelona. J Clin Immunol 2021, 41:1733&#x2013;1744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8475877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34570326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastard P, Gervais A, Taniguchi M, Saare L, S&#xe4;rekannu K, Le Voyer T, Philippot Q, Rosain J, Bizien L, Asano T, et al.: Higher COVID-19 pneumonia risk associated with anti-IFN-&#x3b1; than with anti-IFN-&#x3c9; auto-Abs in children. Journal of Experimental Medicine 2024, 221:e20231353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10771097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38175961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casanova JL, Anderson MS: Unlocking life-threatening COVID-19 through two types of inborn errors of type I IFNs. J Clin Invest 2023, 133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9888384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36719370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su HC, Jing H, Zhang Y, Casanova J-L: Interfering with Interferons: A Critical Mechanism for Critical COVID-19 Pneumonia. Annual Review of Immunology 2023, 41:561&#x2013;585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37126418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson EJ, Walker AJ, Bhaskaran K, Bacon S, Bates C, Morton CE, Curtis HJ, Mehrkar A, Evans D, Inglesby P, et al.: Factors associated with COVID-19-related death using OpenSAFELY. Nature 2020, 584:430&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32640463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McPadden J, Warner F, Young HP, Hurley NC, Pulk RA, Singh A, Durant TJS, Gong G, Desai N, Haimovich A, et al.: Clinical characteristics and outcomes for 7,995 patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection. PLoS One 2021, 16:e0243291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8011821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33788846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manry J, Bastard P, Gervais A, Le Voyer T, Rosain J, Philippot Q, Michailidis E, Hoffmann HH, Eto S, Garcia-Prat M, et al.: The risk of COVID-19 death is much greater and age dependent with type I IFN autoantibodies. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2022, 119:e2200413119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9173764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35576468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodansky A, Vazquez SE, Chou J, Novak T, Al-Musa A, Young C, Newhams M, Kucukak S, Zambrano LD, Mitchell A, et al.: NFKB2 haploinsufficiency identified via screening for IFN-&#x3b1;2 autoantibodies in children and adolescents hospitalized with SARS-CoV-2-related complications. J Allergy Clin Immunol 2023, 151:926&#x2013;930.e922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9733962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36509151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Voyer T, Parent AV, Liu X, Cederholm A, Gervais A, Rosain J, Nguyen T, Perez Lorenzo M, Rackaityte E, Rinchai D, et al.: Autoantibodies against type I IFNs in humans with alternative NF-&#x3ba;B pathway deficiency. Nature 2023, 623:803&#x2013;813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10665196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37938781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong SD, Lee H, Chang JY, Lee SY, Choi JE, Yang E, Jeong HW, Choi J-P, Han MS, Shin E-C: Increased type III interferons and NK cell functions in SARS-CoV-2-infected children. Signal Transduction and Targeted Therapy 2023, 8:54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9896443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36737427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tovo PA, Garazzino S, Dapr&#xe0; V, Pruccoli G, Calvi C, Mignone F, Alliaudi C, Denina M, Scolfaro C, Zoppo M, et al.: COVID-19 in Children: Expressions of Type I/II/III Interferons, TRIM28, SETDB1, and Endogenous Retroviruses in Mild and Severe Cases. Int J Mol Sci 2021, 22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8303145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34299101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sposito F, Pennington SH, David CAW, Duggan J, Northey S, Biagini GA, Liptrott NJ, Charras A, McNamara PS, Hedrich CM: Age-differential CD13 and interferon expression in airway epithelia affect SARS-CoV-2 infection - Effects of vitamin D. Mucosal Immunology 2023, 16:776&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37574128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magalh&#xe3;es VG, Lukassen S, Drechsler M, Loske J, Burkart SS, W&#xfc;st S, Jacobsen EM, R&#xf6;hmel J, Mall MA, Debatin KM, et al.: Immune-epithelial cell cross-talk enhances antiviral responsiveness to SARS-CoV-2 in children. EMBO reports 2023, 24:e57912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10702842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37818799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wimmers F, Burrell AR, Feng Y, Zheng H, Arunachalam PS, Hu M, Spranger S, Nyhoff LE, Joshi D, Trisal M, et al.: Multi-omics analysis of mucosal and systemic immunity to SARS-CoV-2 after birth. Cell 2023, 186:4632&#x2013;4651.e4623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10724861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37776858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucas M, Schachterle W, Oberle K, Aichele P, Diefenbach A: Dendritic Cells Prime Natural Killer Cells by trans-Presenting Interleukin 15. Immunity 2007, 26:503&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2084390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17398124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanoni I, Spreafico R, Bodio C, Di Gioia M, Cigni C, Broggi A, Gorletta T, Caccia M, Chirico G, Sironi L, et al.: IL-15 cis presentation is required for optimal NK cell activation in lipopolysaccharide-mediated inflammatory conditions. Cell Rep 2013, 4:1235&#x2013;1249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24055061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin H, Kim S, Jo A, Won J, Gil CH, Yoon SY, Cha H, Kim HJ: Intranasal inoculation of IFN-&#x3bb; resolves SARS-CoV-2 lung infection via the rapid reduction of viral burden and improvement of tissue damage. Front Immunol 2022, 13:1009424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9744928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36524125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santer DM, Li D, Ghosheh Y, Zahoor MA, Prajapati D, Hansen BE, Tyrrell DLJ, Feld JJ, Gehring AJ: Interferon-&#x3bb; treatment accelerates SARS-CoV-2 clearance despite age-related delays in the induction of T cell immunity. Nat Commun 2022, 13:6992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9667439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36385011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoagland DA, M&#xf8;ller R, Uhl SA, Oishi K, Frere J, Golynker I, Horiuchi S, Panis M, Blanco-Melo D, Sachs D, et al.: Leveraging the antiviral type I interferon system as a first line of defense against SARS-CoV-2 pathogenicity. Immunity 2021, 54:557&#x2013;570.e555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7846242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong Z, Karl CE, Halfmann PJ, Kawaoka Y, Winkler ES, Keeler SP, Holtzman MJ, Yu J, Diamond MS: Nasally delivered interferon-&#x3bb; protects mice against infection by SARS-CoV-2 variants including Omicron. Cell Rep 2022, 39:110799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9021357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35523172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao T, Israelow B, Lucas C, Vogels CBF, Gomez-Calvo ML, Fedorova O, Breban MI, Menasche BL, Dong H, Linehan M, et al.: A stem-loop RNA RIG-I agonist protects against acute and chronic SARS-CoV-2 infection in mice. J Exp Med 2022, 219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8590200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34757384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beer J, Crotta S, Breithaupt A, Ohnemus A, Becker J, Sachs B, Kern L, Llorian M, Ebert N, Labroussaa F, et al.: Impaired immune response drives age-dependent severity of COVID-19. J Exp Med 2022, 219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9499827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36129445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatton CF, Botting RA, Due&#xf1;as ME, Haq IJ, Verdon B, Thompson BJ, Spegarova JS, Gothe F, Stephenson E, Gardner AI, et al.: Delayed induction of type I and III interferons mediates nasal epithelial cell permissiveness to SARS-CoV-2. Nature Communications 2021, 12:7092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8651658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34876592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuhenn J, Meister TL, Todt D, Bracht T, Schork K, Billaud JN, Elsner C, Heinen N, Karakoese Z, Haid S, et al.: Differential interferon-&#x3b1; subtype induced immune signatures are associated with suppression of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2022, 119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8872780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35131898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vezzani B, Neri M, D&#x2019;Errico S, Papi A, Contoli M, Giorgi C: SARS-CoV-2 Infection Prompts IL-1&#x3b2;-Mediated Inflammation and Reduces IFN-&#x3bb; Expression in Human Lung Tissue. Pathogens 2022, 11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9698775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36422642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karki R, Sharma BR, Tuladhar S, Williams EP, Zalduondo L, Samir P, Zheng M, Sundaram B, Banoth B, Malireddi RKS, et al.: Synergism of TNF-&#x3b1; and IFN-&#x3b3; Triggers Inflammatory Cell Death, Tissue Damage, and Mortality in SARS-CoV-2 Infection and Cytokine Shock Syndromes. Cell 2021, 184:149&#x2013;168.e117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7674074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33278357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Butler-Laporte G, Nakanishi T, Morrison DR, Afilalo J, Afilalo M, Laurent L, Pietzner M, Kerrison N, Zhao K, et al.: A Neanderthal OAS1 isoform protects individuals of European ancestry against COVID-19 susceptibility and severity. Nat Med 2021, 27:659&#x2013;667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33633408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danziger O, Patel RS, DeGrace EJ, Rosen MR, Rosenberg BR: Inducible CRISPR activation screen for interferon-stimulated genes identifies OAS1 as a SARS-CoV-2 restriction factor. PLOS Pathogens 2022, 18:e1010464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9041830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35421191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickenhagen A, Sugrue E, Lytras S, Kuchi S, Noerenberg M, Turnbull ML, Loney C, Herder V, Allan J, Jarmson I, et al.: A prenylated dsRNA sensor protects against severe COVID-19. Science 2021, 374:eabj3624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7612834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34581622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banday AR, Stanifer ML, Florez-Vargas O, Onabajo OO, Papenberg BW, Zahoor MA, Mirabello L, Ring TJ, Lee CH, Albert PS, et al.: Genetic regulation of OAS1 nonsense-mediated decay underlies association with COVID-19 hospitalization in patients of European and African ancestries. Nat Genet 2022, 54:1103&#x2013;1116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9355882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35835913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhat SA, Shibata T, Leong M, Plummer J, Vail E, Khan Z: Comparative Upper Respiratory Tract Transcriptomic Profiling Reveals a Potential Role of Early Activation of Interferon Pathway in Severe COVID-19. Viruses 2022, 14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9608318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36298737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broggi A, Ghosh S, Sposito B, Spreafico R, Balzarini F, Lo Cascio A, Clementi N, De Santis M, Mancini N, Granucci F, Zanoni I: Type III interferons disrupt the lung epithelial barrier upon viral recognition. Science 2020, 369:706&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7292499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32527925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Major J, Crotta S, Llorian M, McCabe TM, Gad HH, Priestnall SL, Hartmann R, Wack A: Type I and III interferons disrupt lung epithelial repair during recovery from viral infection. Science 2020, 369:712&#x2013;717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7292500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32527928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Liu J, Zhang D, Xu Z, Ji J, Wen C: Cytokine Storm in COVID-19: The Current Evidence and Treatment Strategies. Front Immunol 2020, 11:1708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7365923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32754163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent P, Yang C, Rendeiro AF, Nilsson-Payant BE, Carrau L, Chandar V, Bram Y, tenOever BR, Elemento O, Ivashkiv LB, et al.: Sensing of SARS-CoV-2 by pDCs and their subsequent production of IFN-I contribute to macrophage-induced cytokine storm during COVID-19. Science Immunology 2022, 7:eadd4906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9853436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36083891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sluis RM, Cham LB, Gris-Oliver A, Gammelgaard KR, Pedersen JG, Idorn M, Ahmadov U, Hernandez SS, C&#xe9;malovic E, Godsk SH, et al.: TLR2 and TLR7 mediate distinct immunopathological and antiviral plasmacytoid dendritic cell responses to SARS-CoV-2 infection. The EMBO Journal 2022, 41:e109622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9108609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35178710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith N, Poss&#xe9;m&#xe9; C, Bondet V, Sugrue J, Townsend L, Charbit B, Rouilly V, Saint-Andr&#xe9; V, Dott T, Pozo AR, et al.: Defective activation and regulation of type I interferon immunity is associated with increasing COVID-19 severity. Nature Communications 2022, 13:7254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9700809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36434007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onodi F, Bonnet-Madin L, Meertens L, Karpf L, Poirot J, Zhang S-Y, Picard C, Puel A, Jouanguy E, Zhang Q, et al.: SARS-CoV-2 induces human plasmacytoid predendritic cell diversification via UNC93B and IRAK4 SARS-CoV-2 and plasmacytoid predendritic cells. Journal of Experimental Medicine 2021, 218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7849819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33533916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viox EG, Hoang TN, Upadhyay AA, Nchioua R, Hirschenberger M, Strongin Z, Tharp GK, Pino M, Nguyen K, Harper JL, et al.: Modulation of type I interferon responses potently inhibits SARS-CoV-2 replication and inflammation in rhesus macaques. Science Immunology 2023, 8:eadg0033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10936760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37506197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein JA-O, Wood J, Jaycox JR, Dhodapkar RA-O, Lu PA-OX, Gehlhausen JR, Tabachnikova A, Greene K, Tabacof L, Malik AA, et al.: Distinguishing features of long COVID identified through immune profiling. Nature 2023, 623:139&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10620090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37748514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altmann DM, Whettlock EM, Liu S, Arachchillage DJ, Boyton RJ: The immunology of long COVID. Nature Reviews Immunology 2023, 23:618&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37433988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AA-O, VanElzakker MB, Aleman S, Bach K, Boribong BA-O, Buggert MA-O, Cherry SAO, Chertow DA-O, Davies HA-OX, Dupont CA-O, et al.: SARS-CoV-2 reservoir in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC). Nature Immunology 2023, 24:1616&#x2013;1627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37667052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ: Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nature Reviews Microbiology 2023, 21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F, Tomasoni D, Falcinella C, Barbanotti D, Castoldi R, Mule G, Augello M, Mondatore D, Allegrini M, Cona A, et al.: Female gender is associated with long COVID syndrome: a prospective cohort study. Clin Microbiol Infect 2022, 28:611 e619&#x2013;611 e616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB, Howe A, Munier CML, Patel SK, Juno JA, Burrell LM, Kent SJ, Dore GJ, et al.: Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nature Immunology 2022, 23:210&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talla A, Vasaikar SV, Szeto GL, Lemos MP, Czartoski JL, MacMillan H, Moodie Z, Cohen KW, Fleming LB, Thomson Z, et al.: Persistent serum protein signatures define an inflammatory subcategory of long COVID. Nat Commun 2023, 14:3417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10252177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37296110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishna BA, Lim EY, Metaxaki M, Jackson S, Mactavous L, BioResource N, Lyons PA, Doffinger R, Bradley JR, Smith KGC, et al.: Spontaneous, persistent, T cell&#x2013;dependent IFN-&#x3b3; release in patients who progress to Long Covid. Science Advances 2024, 10:eadi9379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10881041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38381822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, Ng RH, Wang K, Choi J, Li S, Hong S, Zhang R, Xie J, et al.: Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell 2022, 185:881&#x2013;895 e820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiech M, Chroscicki P, Swatler J, Stepnik D, De Biasi S, Hampel M, Brewinska-Olchowik M, Maliszewska A, Sklinda K, Durlik M, et al.: Remodeling of T Cell Dynamics During Long COVID Is Dependent on Severity of SARS-CoV-2 Infection. Front Immunol 2022, 13:886431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9226563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35757700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozonoff AA-O, Jayavelu ND, Liu S, Melamed E, Milliren CE, Qi J, Geng LN, McComsey GA, Cairns CA-O, Baden LR, et al.: Features of acute COVID-19 associated with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 phenotypes: results from the IMPACC study. Nature Communications 2024, 15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10764789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38172101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia X, Cao S, Lee AS, Manohar M, Sindher SB, Ahuja N, Artandi M, Blish CA, Blomkalns AL, Chang I, et al.: Anti-nucleocapsid antibody levels and pulmonary comorbid conditions are linked to post-COVID-19 syndrome. JCI Insight 2022, 7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9310538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35801588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia C, Zurbuchen Y, Taeschler P, Ballouz T, Menges D, Hasler S, Adamo S, Raeber ME, Bachli E, Rudiger A, et al.: Immunoglobulin signature predicts risk of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Commun 2022, 13:446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8789854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35078982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson RC, Simons NW, Wilkins L, Cheng E, Del Valle DM, Hoffman GE, Cervia C, Fennessy B, Mouskas K, Francoeur NJ, et al.: Molecular states during acute COVID-19 reveal distinct etiologies of long-term sequelae. Nat Med 2023, 29:236&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9873574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36482101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodruff MC, Bonham KS, Anam FA, Walker TA, Faliti CE, Ishii Y, Kaminski CY, Ruunstrom MC, Cooper KR, Truong AD, et al.: Chronic inflammation, neutrophil activity, and autoreactivity splits long COVID. Nature Communications 2023, 14:4201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10349085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37452024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galbraith MD, Kinning KT, Sullivan KD, Araya P, Smith KP, Granrath RE, Shaw JR, Baxter R, Jordan KR, Russell S, et al.: Specialized interferon action in COVID-19. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2022, 119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8931386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35217532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felgenhauer U, Schoen A, Gad HH, Hartmann R, Schaubmar AR, Failing K, Drosten C, Weber F: Inhibition of SARS-CoV-2 by type I and type III interferons. J Biol Chem 2020, 295:13958&#x2013;13964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7549028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32587093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinnon KH, Leist SR, Sch&#xe4;fer A, Edwards CE, Martinez DR, Montgomery SA, West A, Yount BL, Hou YJ, Adams LE, et al.: A mouse-adapted model of SARS-CoV-2 to test COVID-19 countermeasures. Nature 2020, 586:560&#x2013;566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8034761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32854108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese LH, Lenfant T, Calabrese C: Interferon therapy for COVID-19 and emerging infections: Prospects and concerns. Cleveland Clinic Journal of Medicine 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33219050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sodeifian F, Nikfarjam M, Kian N, Mohamed K, Rezaei N: The role of type I interferon in the treatment of COVID-19. J Med Virol 2022, 94:63&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34468995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monk PD, Marsden RJ, Tear VJ, Brookes J, Batten TN, Mankowski M, Gabbay FJ, Davies DE, Holgate ST, Ho LP, et al.: Safety and efficacy of inhaled nebulised interferon beta-1a (SNG001) for treatment of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 2 trial. Lancet Respir Med 2021, 9:196&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33189161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monk PD, Brookes JL, Tear VJ, Batten TN, Mankowski M, Adzic-Vukicevic T, Crooks MG, Dosanjh DPS, Kraft M, Brightling CE, et al.: Nebulised interferon-&#x3b2;1a (SNG001) in hospitalised COVID-19: SPRINTER phase III study. ERJ Open Res 2023, 9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9790107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36994453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Z, Wang T, Chen L, Chen X, Li L, Qin X, Li H, Luo J: The Effect of Recombinant Human Interferon Alpha Nasal Drops to Prevent COVID-19 Pneumonia for Medical Staff in an Epidemic Area. Curr Top Med Chem 2021, 21:920&#x2013;927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33970846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchynskyi M, Kamyshna I, Lyubomirskaya K, Moshynets O, Kobyliak N, Oksenych V, Kamyshnyi A: Efficacy of interferon alpha for the treatment of hospitalized patients with COVID-19: A meta-analysis. Front Immunol 2023, 14:1069894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9909279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36776844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosi C, Ferrarese R, De Lorenzo R, Mancini N, Bosi E: Lack of efficacy of Interferon &#x3b2;&#x2212;1a in COVID-19 patients with mild to moderate pneumonia. European Journal of Internal Medicine 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9715494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36517370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casado JL, Vizcarra P, Del Rey JM, Soriano MC, Rodriguez-Dominguez M, Manzano L, Acero J, Palomar-Fernandez C, Vallejo A, On Behalf Of The Covid-Irycis T: Lost in Translation: Evaluation of Subcutaneous Interferon-&#x3b2; Treatment for SARS-CoV-2 Infection in Real Life. J Clin Med 2022, 11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9739717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36498527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro-Rodriguez JA, Fish EN, Montgomery ST, Kollmann TR, Iturriaga C, Shannon C, Karpievitch Y, Ho J, Chen V, Balshaw R, et al.: Interferon &#x3b2;&#x2212;1a ring prophylaxis to reduce household transmission of SARS-CoV-2: a cluster randomised clinical trial. EClinicalMedicine 2023, 62:102082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10393621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37538539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung IF, Lung KC, Tso EY, Liu R, Chung TW, Chu MY, Ng YY, Lo J, Chan J, Tam AR, et al.: Triple combination of interferon beta-1b, lopinavir-ritonavir, and ribavirin in the treatment of patients admitted to hospital with COVID-19: an open-label, randomised, phase 2 trial. Lancet 2020, 395:1695&#x2013;1704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32401715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davoudi-Monfared E, Rahmani H, Khalili H, Hajiabdolbaghi M, Salehi M, Abbasian L, Kazemzadeh H, Yekaninejad MS: A Randomized Clinical Trial of the Efficacy and Safety of Interferon &#x3b2;&#x2212;1a in Treatment of Severe COVID-19. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2020, 64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7449227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmani H, Davoudi-Monfared E, Nourian A, Khalili H, Hajizadeh N, Jalalabadi NZ, Fazeli MR, Ghazaeian M, Yekaninejad MS: Interferon &#x3b2;&#x2212;1b in treatment of severe COVID-19: A randomized clinical trial. Int Immunopharmacol 2020, 88:106903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32862111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consortium WHOST, Pan H, Peto R, Henao-Restrepo AM, Preziosi MP, Sathiyamoorthy V, Abdool Karim Q, Alejandria MM, Hernandez Garcia C, Kieny MP, et al.: Repurposed Antiviral Drugs for Covid-19 - Interim WHO Solidarity Trial Results. N Engl J Med 2021, 384:497&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33264556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ader F, Peiffer-Smadja N, Poissy J, Bouscambert-Duchamp M, Belhadi D, Diallo A, Delmas C, Saillard J, Dechanet A, Mercier N, et al.: An open-label randomized controlled trial of the effect of lopinavir/ritonavir, lopinavir/ritonavir plus IFN-&#x3b2;&#x2212;1a and hydroxychloroquine in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Clin Microbiol Infect 2021, 27:1826&#x2013;1837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8149166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34048876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalil AC, Mehta AK, Patterson TF, Erdmann N, Gomez CA, Jain MK, Wolfe CR, Ruiz-Palacios GM, Kline S, Regalado Pineda J, et al.: Efficacy of interferon beta-1a plus remdesivir compared with remdesivir alone in hospitalised adults with COVID-19: a double-bind, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Respir Med 2021, 9:1365&#x2013;1376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8523116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang N, Zhan Y, Zhu L, Hou Z, Liu F, Song P, Qiu F, Wang X, Zou X, Wan D, et al.: Retrospective Multicenter Cohort Study Shows Early Interferon Therapy Is Associated with Favorable Clinical Responses in COVID-19 Patients. Cell Host Microbe 2020, 28:455&#x2013;464 e452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7368656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32707096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prokunina-Olsson L, Alphonse N, Dickenson RE, Durbin JE, Glenn JS, Hartmann R, Kotenko SV, Lazear HM, O&#x2019;Brien TR, Odendall C, et al.: COVID-19 and emerging viral infections: The case for interferon lambda. Journal of Experimental Medicine 2020, 217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7155807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32289152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagannathan P, Andrews JR, Bonilla H, Hedlin H, Jacobson KB, Balasubramanian V, Purington N, Kamble S, de Vries CR, Quintero O, et al.: Peginterferon Lambda-1a for treatment of outpatients with uncomplicated COVID-19: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Nature Communications 2021, 12:1967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8009873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feld JJ, Kandel C, Biondi MJ, Kozak RA, Zahoor MA, Lemieux C, Borgia SM, Boggild AK, Powis J, McCready J, et al.: Peginterferon lambda for the treatment of outpatients with COVID-19: a phase 2, placebo-controlled randomised trial. Lancet Respir Med 2021, 9:498&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7906707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33556319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reis G, Moreira Silva EAS, Medeiros Silva DC, Thabane L, Campos VHS, Ferreira TS, Santos CVQ, Nogueira AMR, Almeida A, Savassi LCM, et al.: Early Treatment with Pegylated Interferon Lambda for Covid-19. N Engl J Med 2023, 388:518&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9933926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36780676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>