<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34408531</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1179-7266</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pragmatic and observational research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pragmat Obs Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Risk Predictors and Symptom Features of Long COVID Within a Broad Primary Care Patient Population Including Both Tested and Untested Patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>93</StartPage><EndPage>104</EndPage><MedlinePgn>93-104</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/POR.S316186</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Symptoms may persist after the initial phases of COVID-19 infection, a phenomenon termed long COVID. Current knowledge on long COVID has been mostly derived from test-confirmed and hospitalized COVID-19 patients. Data are required on the burden and predictors of long COVID in a broader patient group, which includes both tested and untested COVID-19 patients in primary care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is an observational study using data from Platform C19, a quality improvement program-derived research database linking primary care electronic health record data (EHR) with patient-reported questionnaire information. Participating general practices invited consenting patients aged 18-85 to complete an online questionnaire since 7th August 2020. COVID-19 self-diagnosis, clinician-diagnosis, testing, and the presence and duration of symptoms were assessed via the questionnaire. Patients were considered present with long COVID if they reported symptoms lasting &#x2265;4 weeks. EHR and questionnaire data up till 22nd January 2021 were extracted for analysis. Multivariable regression analyses were conducted comparing demographics, clinical characteristics, and presence of symptoms between patients with long COVID and patients with shorter symptom duration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Long COVID was present in 310/3151 (9.8%) patients with self-diagnosed, clinician-diagnosed, or test-confirmed COVID-19. Only 106/310 (34.2%) long COVID patients had test-confirmed COVID-19. Risk predictors of long COVID were age &#x2265;40 years (adjusted Odds Ratio [AdjOR]=1.49 [1.05-2.17]), female sex (adjOR=1.37 [1.02-1.85]), frailty (adjOR=2.39 [1.29-4.27]), visit to A&amp;E (adjOR=4.28 [2.31-7.78]), and hospital admission for COVID-19 symptoms (adjOR=3.22 [1.77-5.79]). Aches and pain (adjOR=1.70 [1.21-2.39]), appetite loss (adjOR=3.15 [1.78-5.92]), confusion and disorientation (adjOR=2.17 [1.57-2.99]), diarrhea (adjOR=1.4 [1.03-1.89]), and persistent dry cough (adjOR=2.77 [1.94-3.98]) were symptom features statistically more common in long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study reports the factors and symptom features predicting long COVID in a broad primary care population, including both test-confirmed and the previously missed group of COVID-19 patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Jones et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Rupert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5463-2981</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optimum Patient Care, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, University of Plymouth, Plymouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davis</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optimum Patient Care, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stanley</LastName><ForeName>Brooklyn</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optimum Patient Care, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Julious</LastName><ForeName>Steven</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Sheffield, South Yorkshire, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ryan</LastName><ForeName>Dermot</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4115-7376</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Usher Institute, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jackson</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guy's &amp; St Thomas' NHS Trust, School of Immunology &amp; Microbial Sciences, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halpin</LastName><ForeName>David M G</ForeName><Initials>DMG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2009-4406</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Exeter Medical School, College of Medicine and Health, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hickman</LastName><ForeName>Katherine</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bradford and Leeds Clinical Commissioning Group, Leeds, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinnock</LastName><ForeName>Hilary</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5976-8386</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Asthma UK Centre for Applied Research, Usher Institute, The University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quint</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer K</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0149-4869</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Heart &amp; Lung Institute, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khunti</LastName><ForeName>Kamlesh</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2343-7099</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diabetes Research Centre, University of Leicester, Leicester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heaney</LastName><ForeName>Liam G</ForeName><Initials>LG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wellcome-Wolfson Centre for Experimental Medicine, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast, Northern Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliver</LastName><ForeName>Phillip</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9665-0635</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Sheffield, South Yorkshire, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siddiqui</LastName><ForeName>Salman</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Lung Health, Leicester National Institute for Health Research Biomedical Research Centre, University of Leicester, Leicester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pavord</LastName><ForeName>Ian</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4288-5973</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Respiratory Medicine Unit and Oxford Respiratory NIHR BRC, Nuffield Department of Medicine, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>David H M</ForeName><Initials>DHM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Box Surgery, Wiltshire, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hyland</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, University of Plymouth, Plymouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Plymouth Marjon University, Plymouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ritchie</LastName><ForeName>Lewis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Academic Primary Care, Division of Applied Health Sciences, University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Young</LastName><ForeName>Pam</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wellbeing Software, Mansfield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Megaw</LastName><ForeName>Tony</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wellbeing Software, Mansfield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davis</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interface Clinical Services, Leeds, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walker</LastName><ForeName>Samantha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Asthma UK &amp; British Lung Foundation, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holgate</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical and Experimental Sciences, University of Southampton, Southampton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beecroft</LastName><ForeName>Sue</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>OPEN Health, Buckinghamshire, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kemppinen</LastName><ForeName>Anu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optimum Patient Care, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Appiagyei</LastName><ForeName>Francis</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optimum Patient Care, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Emma-Jane</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optimum Patient Care, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Preston</LastName><ForeName>Megan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9601-4690</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optimum Patient Care, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hardjojo</LastName><ForeName>Antony</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2823-7996</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optimum Patient Care, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carter</LastName><ForeName>Victoria</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optimum Patient Care, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Melle</LastName><ForeName>Marije</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optimum Patient Care, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Price</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9728-9992</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optimum Patient Care, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Academic Primary Care, Division of Applied Health Sciences, University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>G0800766</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Pragmat Obs Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101688693</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1179-7266</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frailty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">observational study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">questionnaire</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Rupert Jones reports grants, personal fees, and non-financial support from AstraZeneca and OPRI, personal fees and non-financial support from Boehringer Ingelheim, grants, personal fees, and non-financial support from GSK, grants and non-financial support from Novartis, non-financial support from Nutricia, and personal fees from Pfizer outside the submitted work. Andrew Davis was an employee of Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute at the time this study was conducted. Brooklyn Stanley and Anu Kemppinen are employees of Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute, which conducted this study and conducted paid research in respiratory disease on behalf of the following other organizations in the past 5 years: Aerocrine, AKL Research and Development Ltd, Almirall, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, GlaxoSmithKline, Mylan, Mundipharma, Napp, Novartis, Orion, Takeda, Teva, Zentiva (a Sanofi company). Dermot Ryan has (in the last 3 years) lectured on behalf of, received sponsorship from, or acted as a paid advisor to Mylan, AZ, Chiesi, Novartis, GSK, Boehringer Ingelheim and Regeneron. David J Jackson has received advisory board and speaker fees from AstraZeneca, GSK, BI, Teva, Napp, Chiesi, Novartis and research grant funding from AstraZeneca. David MG Halpin has received sponsorship to attend international meetings, and honoraria for lecturing, attending advisory boards and preparing educational materials from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, GSK, Novartis and Pfizer. Jennifer K Quint reports grants from MRC, grants from The Health Foundation, grants and personal fees from AZ, grants from Bayer, grants and personal fees from Chiesi, grants and personal fees from GSK, grants and personal fees from BI, outside the submitted work. Kamlesh Khunti has been a consultant and speaker for Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Sanofi-Aventis, Lilly, and Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme; has received grants in support of investigator-initiated trials from Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Sanofi-Aventis, Lilly, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Pfizer, and Boehringer Ingelheim; has served on advisory boards for Novo Nordisk, SanofiAventis, Lilly, and Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme; and is supported by the UK National Institute for Health Research (NIHR) Applied Research Collaboration East Midlands and the NIHR Leicester Biomedical Research Centre. Liam G Heaney is an Academic Lead for the UK MRC Consortium for Stratified Medicine in Severe Asthma &#x2013; Industrial Pharma partners Amgen, AstraZeneca, MedImmune, Janssen, Novartis, Roche/Genentech, GlaxoSmithKline, and Boehringer Ingelheim; prior project grant funding from MedImmune, Novartis UK, Roche/Genentech, and GlaxoSmithKline; has taken part in Advisory Boards/Lectures supported by Novartis, Roche/Evelo Biosciences, Genentech, GlaxoSmithKline, Teva, Theravance and Vectura; has travel funding support to international respiratory meetings (AstraZeneca, Chiesi, Novartis, Boehringer Ingelheim, Teva, and GlaxoSmithKline) and has taken part in asthma clinical trials (GlaxoSmithKline, Schering Plough, Synairgen, Novartis, and Roche/Genentech) for which his institution was remunerated. Salman Siddiqui reports advisory board/advisory services and speaker fees from AstraZeneca, GlaxoSmithKline, Chiesi, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, Mundipharma, ERT medical, Owlstone Medical and received grants from UKRI PHOSP-COVID consortium. Ian Pavord reports grants from NIHR and personal fees from Aerocrine, Almirall, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, Circassia, Genentech, GlaxoSmithKline, Knopp, Novartis, Regeneron, Sanofi and Teva, outside the submitted work, and is a member of the GOLD Science Committee. Michael Hyland has received personal fees from Novartis and GSK. Stephen T Holgate is a co-founder of Synairgen Research, owns shares in the company, and has received personal fees as a Non-Executive Director and Consultant of Synairgen Research outside of the submitted work. Francis Appiagyei, Emma-Jane Roberts, Megan Preston, Marije van Melle and Victoria Carter are employees of Optimum Patient Care who funded this study. David Price has board membership with AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, Mylan, Novartis, Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, Sanofi Genzyme, Thermofisher; consultancy agreements with Airway Vista Secretariat, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, EPG Communication Holdings Ltd, FIECON Ltd, Fieldwork International, GlaxoSmithKline, Mylan, Mundipharma, Novartis, OM Pharma SA, PeerVoice, Phadia AB, Spirosure Inc, Strategic North Limited, Synapse Research Management Partners S.L., Talos Health Solutions, Theravance and WebMD Global LLC; grants and unrestricted funding for investigator-initiated studies (conducted through Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute Pte Ltd) from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, Mylan, Novartis, Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, Respiratory Effectiveness Group, Sanofi Genzyme, Theravance and UK National Health Service; payment for lectures/speaking engagements from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, Cipla, GlaxoSmithKline, Kyorin, Mylan, Mundipharma, Novartis, Regeneron Pharmaceuticals and Sanofi Genzyme; payment for travel/accommodation/meeting expenses from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Mundipharma, Mylan, Novartis, Thermofisher; stock/stock options from AKL Research and Development Ltd, which produces phytopharmaceuticals; owns 74% of the social enterprise Optimum Patient Care Ltd (Australia and UK) and 92.61% of Observational and Pragmatic Research Institute Pte Ltd (Singapore); 5% shareholding in Timestamp, which develops adherence monitoring technology; is peer reviewer for grant committees of the UK Efficacy and Mechanism Evaluation programme, and Health Technology Assessment; and was an expert witness for GlaxoSmithKline. Michael Hyland reports personal fees from GSK, outside the submitted work. Pam Young and Tony Megaw are employees of Wellbeing Software.&#xa0; The remaining authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34408531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8366779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/POR.S316186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">316186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan P. NICE guideline on long COVID. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9(2):129. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00031-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00031-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National institute for health and care excellence: clinical guidelines. In: COVID-19 Rapid Guideline: Managing the Long-Term Effects of COVID-19. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (UK);2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perego E, Callard F, Stras L, Melville-J&#xf3;hannesson B, Pope R, Alwan N. Why the patient-made term &#x2018;long covid&#x2019; is needed [version 1; peer review: 1 approved with reservations, 1 not approved]. Wellcome Open Res. 2020;5(224).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A&#x2019;Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020;370:m3026. doi:10.1136/bmj.m3026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m3026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. MedRxiv. 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes DL, Holdsworth L, Jawad N, Gunasekera P, Morice AH, Crooks MG. Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: what is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung. 2021;192:113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, et al. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One. 2020;15(11):e0240784. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0240784</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0240784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Gemelli against C-P-ACSG. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603&#x2013;605. doi:10.1001/jama.2020.12603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.12603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesh R, Ghosh AK, Nyman MA, et al. PROMIS scales for assessment of persistent post-COVID Symptoms: a cross sectional study. J Prim Care Community Health. 2021;12:21501327211030413. doi:10.1177/21501327211030413</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21501327211030413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8267017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34231395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, et al. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network -United States, March-June 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69(30):993&#x2013;998. doi:10.15585/mmwr.mm6930e1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm6930e1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93(2):1013&#x2013;1022. doi:10.1002/jmv.26368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestre-Mu&#xf1;iz MM, Arias &#xc1;, Mata-V&#xe1;zquez E, et al. Long-term outcomes of patients with coronavirus disease 2019 at one year after hospital discharge. J Clin Med. 2021;10(13):2945. doi:10.3390/jcm10132945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm10132945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8269002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34209085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The prevalence of long COVID symptoms and COVID-19 complications [Website]. Office for national statistics. Available from: https://www.ons.gov.uk/news/statementsandletters/theprevalenceoflongcovidsymptomsandcovid19complications. Accessed February2, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson KB, Rao M, Bonilla H, et al. Patients with uncomplicated COVID-19 have long-term persistent symptoms and functional impairment similar to patients with severe COVID-19: a cautionary tale during a global pandemic. Clin Infect Dis. 2021. doi:10.1093/cid/ciab103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33624010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):626&#x2013;631. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;hning D, Rocchetti I, Maruotti A, Holling H. Estimating the undetected infections in the Covid-19 outbreak by harnessing capture&#x2013;recapture methods. Int J Infect Dis. 2020;97:197&#x2013;201. doi:10.1016/j.ijid.2020.06.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2020.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7286831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32534143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocchetti I, B&#xf6;hning D, Holling H, Maruotti A. Estimating the size of undetected cases of the COVID-19 outbreak in Europe: an upper bound estimator. J Epidemiol Methods. 2020;9:s1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold D, Hamilton F, Milne A, et al. Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with COVID-19 and implications for follow-up; results from a prospective UK cohort. Thorax. 2021;76(4):399. doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216086</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simani L, Ramezani M, Darazam IA, et al. Prevalence and correlates of chronic fatigue syndrome and post-traumatic stress disorder after the outbreak of the COVID-19. J Neurovirol. 2021;27(1):154&#x2013;159. doi:10.1007/s13365-021-00949-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13365-021-00949-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7852482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33528827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra V, Flanders SA, O&#x2019;Malley M, Malani AN, Prescott HC. Sixty-day outcomes among patients hospitalized with COVID-19. Ann Intern Med. 2020;174:576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7707210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet (London, England). 2021;397(10270):220&#x2013;232. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, McAuley H, Harrison EM, et al. Physical, cognitive and mental health impacts of COVID-19 following hospitalisation &#x2013; a multi-centre prospective cohort study. MedRxiv. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34627560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goertz YMJ, Van Herck M, Delbressine JM, et al. Persistent symptoms 3 months after a SARS-CoV-2 infection: the post-COVID-19 syndrome? ERJ Open Res. 2020;6(4):00542&#x2013;2020. doi:10.1183/23120541.00542-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00542-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National data opt-out [website]. NHS digital; 2021. Available from: https://digital.nhs.uk/services/national-data-opt-out/compliance-with-the-national-data-opt-out/check-for-national-data-opt-outs-service. Accessed July16, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peckham H, de Gruijter NM, Raine C, et al. Male sex identified by global COVID-19 meta-analysis as a risk factor for death and ITU admission. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):6317. doi:10.1038/s41467-020-19741-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-19741-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7726563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33298944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladwig KH, Marten-Mittag B, Formanek B, Dammann G. Gender differences of symptom reporting and medical health care utilization in the German population. Eur J Epidemiol. 2000;16(6):511&#x2013;518. doi:10.1023/A:1007629920752</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1007629920752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11049093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewitt J, Carter B, Vilches-Moraga A, et al. The effect of frailty on survival in patients with COVID-19 (COPE): a multicentre, European, observational cohort study. Lancet Public Health. 2020;5(8):e444&#x2013;e451. doi:10.1016/S2468-2667(20)30146-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-2667(20)30146-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7326416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32619408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 rapid guideline: critical care in adults. National institute for clinical excellence; 2021. Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng159/resources/covid19-rapid-guideline-critical-care-in-adults-pdf-66141848681413. Accessed July16, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra N, Chowdhury M, Singh AK, et al. Clinical predictors of long COVID-19 and phenotypes of mild COVID-19 at a tertiary care centre in India. Drug Discov Ther. 2021;15(3):156&#x2013;161. doi:10.5582/ddt.2021.01014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5582/ddt.2021.01014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34234065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyland ME, Bacon AM, Lanario JW, Davies AF. Symptom frequency and development of a generic functional disorder symptom scale suitable for use in studies of patients with irritable bowel syndrome, fibromyalgia syndrome or chronic fatigue syndrome. Chronic Dis Transl Med. 2019;5(2):129&#x2013;138. doi:10.1016/j.cdtm.2019.05.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cdtm.2019.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6656911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31367702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>