<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37452676</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2702-3648</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>123</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of osteopathic medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Osteopath Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19 scent dog research highlights and synthesis during the pandemic of December 2019-April 2023.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>509</StartPage><EndPage>521</EndPage><MedlinePgn>509-521</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/jom-2023-0104</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CONTEXT">This review was undertaken to provide information concerning the advancement of research in the area of COVID-19 screening and testing during the worldwide pandemic from December 2019 through April 2023. In this review, we have examined the safety, effectiveness, and practicality of utilizing trained scent dogs in clinical and public situations for COVID-19 screening. Specifically, results of 29 trained scent dog screening peer-reviewed studies were compared with results of real-time reverse-transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) and rapid antigen (RAG) COVID-19 testing methods.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">The review aims to systematically evaluate the strengths and weaknesses of utilizing trained scent dogs in COVID-19 screening.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">At the time of submission of our earlier review paper in August 2021, we found only four peer-reviewed COVID-19 scent dog papers: three clinical research studies and one preprint perspective paper. In March and April 2023, the first author conducted new literature searches of the MEDLINE/PubMed, Google Scholar, and Cochrane Library websites. Again, the keyword phrases utilized for the searches included "COVID detection dogs," "COVID scent dogs," and "COVID sniffer dogs." The Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) 2020 Checklist was followed to ensure that our review adhered to evidence-based guidelines for reporting. Utilizing the results of the reviewed papers, we compiled statistics to intercompare and summarize basic information concerning the scent dogs and their training, the populations of the study participants, the types of sampling methods, the comparative tests utilized, and the effectiveness of the scent dog screening.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 8,043 references were identified through our literature search. After removal of duplicates, there were 7,843 references that were screened. Of these, 100 were considered for full-text eligibility, 43 were included for qualitative synthesis, and 29 were utilized for quantitative analysis. The most relevant peer-reviewed COVID-19 scent dog references were identified and categorized. Utilizing all of the scent dog results provided for this review, we found that 92.3&#x202f;% of the studies reached sensitivities exceeding 80 and 32.0&#x202f;% of the studies exceeding specificities of 97&#x202f;%. However, 84.0&#x202f;% of the studies reported specificities above 90&#x202f;%. Highlights demonstrating the effectiveness of the scent dogs include: (1) samples of breath, saliva, trachea-bronchial secretions and urine as well as face masks and articles of clothing can be utilized; (2) trained COVID-19 scent dogs can detect presymptomatic and asymptomatic patients; (3) scent dogs can detect new SARS-CoV-2 variants and Long COVID-19; and (4) scent dogs can differentiate SARS-CoV-2 infections from infections with other novel respiratory viruses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The effectiveness of the trained scent dog method is comparable to or in some cases superior to the real-time RT-PCR test and the RAG test. Trained scent dogs can be effectively utilized to provide quick (seconds to minutes), nonintrusive, and accurate results in public settings and thus reduce the spread of the COVID-19 virus or other viruses. Finally, scent dog research as described in this paper can serve to increase the medical community's and public's knowledge and acceptance of medical scent dogs as major contributors to global efforts to fight diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 the author(s), published by De Gruyter, Berlin/Boston.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dickey</LastName><ForeName>Tommy</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7360-6041</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Distinguished Professor Emeritus, Geography Department, University of California Santa Barbara, Santa Barbara, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Junqueira</LastName><ForeName>Heather</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>BioScent, Inc., Myakka City, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Osteopath Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101776472</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2702-3648</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000711908">SARS-CoV-2 variants</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004285" MajorTopicYN="N">Dogs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086742" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Testing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009812" MajorTopicYN="N">Odorants</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pandemic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scent dogs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sniffer dogs</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37452676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/jom-2023-0104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jom-2023-0104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) Website . Coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard [Updated April 26, 2023]. https://covid19.who.int/ [Accessed 1 May 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickey, T, Junqueira, H. Toward the use of medical scent dogs for COVID-19 screening. J Osteopath Med 2021;121:141&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1515/jom-2020-0222 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/jom-2020-0222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crozier, A, Rajan, S, McKee, M. Put to the test: use of rapid testing technologies for covid-19. BMJ 2021;372:n208. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n208 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosell, F. Secrets of the snout . Chicago: University of Chicago Press; 2014:265 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodavage, M. Doctor dogs . New York: Dutton publishing; 2019:353 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokoci&#x144;ska-Kusiak, A, Woszczy&#x142;o, M, Zybala, M, Maciocha, J, Bar&#x142;owska, K, Dzi&#x119;cio&#x142;, M. Canine olfaction: physiology, behavior, and possibilities for practical applications. Animals 2021;11:2463. https://doi.org/10.3390/ani11082463 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani11082463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker, DB, Walker, JC, Cavnar, PJ, Taylor, JL, Pickel, DH, Hall, SB, et al.. Naturalistic quantification of canine olfactory sensitivity. Appl Anim Behav Sci 2006;97:241&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applanim.2005.07.009 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applanim.2005.07.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijland, LA, Bomers, MK, Smulders, YM. Smelling the diagnosis: a review on the use of scent in diagnosing disease. Neth J Med 2013;71:300&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angle, C, Waggoner, LP, Ferrando, A, Haney, P, Passer, T. Canine detection of the volatilome: a review of implications for pathogen and disease detection. Front Vet Sci 2016;3:4&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2016.00047 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fvets.2016.00047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Junqueira, H, Quinn, T, Biringer, R, Hussein, M, Smiriglio, C, Barrueto, et al.. Accuracy of canine scent detection of non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer in blood serum. J Am Osteopath Assoc 2019;119:413&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.7556/jaoa.2019.077 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7556/jaoa.2019.077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Aniello, B, Pinelli, C, Varcamonti, MRM, Lombardi, P, Scandurra, A. COVID sniffer dogs: technical and ethical concerns. Front Vet Sci 2021;8:669712. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2021.669712 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fvets.2021.669712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan, MN, Best, EM, Gadberry, JD, Sharpes, CE, Evans, KL, Chue, CC, et al.. The use and potential of biomedical detection dogs during a disease outbreak. Front Med 2022;9:848090. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2022.848090 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.848090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otto, CM, Sell, TK, Veenema, TG, Hosangadi, D, Vahey, RA, Connell, ND, et al.. The promise of disease detection dogs in pandemic response: lessons learned from COVID-19. Disaster Med Public Health Prep 2021;17:e20. https://doi.org/10.1017/dmp.2021.183 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/dmp.2021.183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakr, R, Ghsoub, C, Rbeiz, C, Lattouf, V, Riachy, R, Haddad, et al.. COVID-19 detection by dogs: from physiology to field application-a review article. Postgrad Med 2022;98:212&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1136/postgradmedj-2020-139410 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/postgradmedj-2020-139410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meller, S, Al Khatri, MSA, Alhammadi, HK, &#xc1;lvarez, G, Alvergnat, G, Alves, LC, et al.. Expert considerations and consensus for using dogs to detect human SARS-CoV-2-infections. Front Med 2022;9:1015620. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2022.1015620 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.1015620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angeletti, S, Travaglino, F, Spoto, S, Pascarella, MC, Mansi, G, De Cesaris, M, et al.. COVID-19 sniffer dog experimental training: which protocol and which implications for reliable identification? J Med Virol 2021;93:5924&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.27147 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.27147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaber, AL, Hazel, S, Matthews, B, Withers, A, Alvergnat, G, Grandjean, D, et al.. Evaluation of canine detection of COVID-19 infected individuals under controlled settings. Transbound Emerg Dis 2022;69:e1951&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1111/tbed.14529 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tbed.14529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demirbas, YS, Kismali, G, Saral, B, Sareyyupoglu, B, Habiloglu, AD, Ozturk, H, et al.. Development of a safety protocol for training and using SARS-CoV-2 detection dogs: a pilot study. J Vet Behav 2023;60:79&#x2013;88. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jveb.2023.01.002 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jveb.2023.01.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devillier, P, Gallet, C, Salvator, H, Lecoq-Julien, C, Naline, E, Roisse, D, et al.. Biomedical detection dogs for identification of SARS-CoV-2 infections from axillary sweat and breath samples. J Breath Res 2022;16. https://doi.org/10.1088/1752-7163/ac5d8c .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1752-7163/ac5d8c</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskandari, E, Ahmadi Marzaleh, M, Roudgari, H, Hamidi Farahani, R, Nezami-Asl, A, Laripour, R, et al.. Sniffer dogs as a screening/diagnostic tool for COVID-19: a proof of concept study. BMC Infect Dis 2021;21:243. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12879-021-05939-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-021-05939-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Essler, JL, Kane, SA, Nolan, P, Akaho, EH, Berna, AZ, DeAngelo, A, et al.. Discrimination of SARS-CoV-2 infected patient samples by detection dogs: a proof of concept study. PLoS One 2021;16:e0250158. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0250158 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0250158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandjean, D, Sarkis, R, Lecoq-Julien, C, Benard, A, Roger, V, Levesque, E, et al.. Can the detection dog alert on COVID-19 positive persons by sniffing axillary sweat samples? A proof-of-concept study. PLoS One 2020;15:e0243122. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0243122 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0243122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandjean, D, Elie, C, Gallet, C, Julien, C, Roger, V, Desquilbet, L, et al.. Diagnostic accuracy of non-invasive detection of SARS-CoV-2 infection by canine olfaction. PLoS One 2022a;17:e0268382. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0268382 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0268382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandjean, D, Gallet, C, Julien, C, Sarkis, R, Muzzin, Q, Roger, V, et al.. Identifying SARS-COV-2 infected patients through canine olfactive detection on axillary sweat samples; study of observed sensitivities and specificities within a group of trained dogs. PLoS One 2022b;17:e0262631. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0262631 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0262631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest, C, Dewhirst, SY, Lindsay, SW, Allen, DJ, Aziz, S, Baerenbold, O, et al.. Using trained dogs and organic semi-conducting sensors to identify asymptomatic and mild SARS-CoV-2 infections: an observational study. J Trav Med 2022;29:taac043. https://doi.org/10.1093/jtm/taac043 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jtm/taac043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hag-Ali, M, AlShamsi, AS, Boeijen, L, Mahmmod, Y, Manzoor, R, Rutten, H, et al.. The detection dogs test is more sensitive than real-time PCR in screening for SARS-CoV-2. Commun Biol 2021;4:686. https://doi.org/10.1038/s42003-021-02232-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42003-021-02232-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jendrny, P, Schulz, C, Twele, F, Meller, S, von K&#xf6;ckritz-Blickwede, M, Osterhaus, ADME, et al.. Scent dog identification of samples from COVID-19 patients-a pilot study. Inf Disp 2020;20:536. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12879-020-05281-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-020-05281-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jendrny, P, Twele, F, Meller, S, Schulz, C, von K&#xf6;ckritz-Blickwede, M, Osterhaus, ADME, et al.. Scent dog identification of SARS-CoV-2 infections in different body fluids. BMC Infect Dis 2021;21:707. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12879-021-06411-1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-021-06411-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Maia, RCC, Alves, LC, da Silva, JES, Czyba, FR, Pereira, JA, Soistier, V, et al.. Canine olfactory detection of SARS-CoV-2 infected patients: a One Health approach. Front Public Health 2021;9:647903. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2021.647903 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2021.647903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurer, M, Seto, T, Guest, C, Somal, A, Julian, C. Detection of SARS-CoV-2 by canine olfaction: a pilot study. Open Forum Infect Dis 2022;9:ofac226. https://doi.org/10.1093/ofid/ofac226 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ofid/ofac226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendel, J, Frank, K, Edlin, L, Hall, K, Webb, D, Mills, J, et al.. Preliminary accuracy of COVID-19 odor by canines and HS-SPME-GC-MS using exhaled breath samples. Forensic Sci Int: Syn 2021;3. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fsisyn.2021.100155 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fsisyn.2021.100155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutesa, L, Misbah, G, Remera, E, Ebbers, H, Schalke, E, Tuyisenge, P, et al.. Use of trained scent dogs for detection of COVID-19 and evidence of cost-saving. Front Med 2022;9:1006315. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2022.1006315 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.1006315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozgur-Buyukatalay, E, Demirbas, YS, Bozdayi, G, Kismali, G, Ilhan, MN. Is diagnostic performance of SARS-CoV-2 detection dogs reduced -due to virus variation- over the time. Appl Anim Behav Sci 2023;258:105825. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applanim.2022.105825 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applanim.2022.105825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkis, R, Lichaa, A, Mjaess, G, Saliba, M, Selman, C, Lecoq-Julien, C, et al.. New method of screening for COVID-19 disease using sniffer dogs and scents from axillary sweat samples. J Public Health 2022;44:e36&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1093/pubmed/fdab215 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/pubmed/fdab215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ten Hagen, NA, Twele, F, Meller, S, Jendrny, P, Schulz, C, von K&#xf6;ckritz-Blickwede, M, et al.. Discrimination of SARS-CoV-2 infections from other viral respiratory infections by scent dog detection dogs. Front Med 2021;8:749588. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2021.749588 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.749588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twele, F, Ten Hagen, NA, Meller, S, Schulz, C, Osterhaus, A, Jendrny, P, et al.. Detection of post-COVID-19 patients using medical scent detection dogs &#x2013; a pilot study. Front Med 2022;9:877259. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2022.877259 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.877259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokool, VA, Crespo-Cajigas, J, Mallikarjun, A, Collins, A, Kane, SA, Plymouth, V, et al.. The use of biological sensors and instrumental analysis to discriminate COVID-19 odor signatures. Biosensors 2022;12:1003. https://doi.org/10.3390/bios12111003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bios12111003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles, M, Eckbo, E, Zurberg, T, Woznow, T, Aksu, L, Navas, LG, et al.. In search of COVID-19: the ability of biodetection canines to detect COVID-19 odours from clinical samples. JAMMI 2022;7:343&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.3138/jammi-2022-017 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3138/jammi-2022-017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantele, A, Paajanen, J, Turunen, S, Pakkanen, SH, Patjas, A, Itkonen, L, et al.. Scent dogs in detection of COVID-19: triple-blinded randomized trial and operational real-life screening in airport setting. BMJ Glob Health 2022;7:e008024. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgh-2021-008024 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2021-008024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancilla-Tapia, JM, Lozano-Esparza, V, Ordu&#xf1;a, A, Osuna-Ch&#xe1;vez, RF, Robles-Zepeda, RE, Maldonado-Cabrera, B, et al.. Dogs detecting COVID-19 from sweat and saliva of positive people: a field experience in Mexico. Front Med 2022;9:837053. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2022.837053 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.837053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirrone, F, Piotti, P, Galli, M, Gasparri, R, La Spina, A, Spaggiari, L, et al.. Sniffer dogs performance is stable over time in detecting COVID-19 positive samples and agrees with rapid antigen test in the field. Sci Rep 2023;13:3679. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-30897-1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-30897-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ten Hagen, NA, Twele, F, Meller, S, Wijnen, L, Schulz, C, Schoneberg, C, et al.. Canine real-time detection of SARS-CoV-2 infections in the context of a mass screening event. BMJ Glob Health 2022;7:e010276. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgh-2022-010276 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2022-010276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vesga, O, Agudelo, M, Valencia-Jaramillo, AF, Mira-Montoya, A, Ossa-Ospina, F, Ocampo, E, et al.. Highly sensitive scent-detection of COVID-19 patients in vivo by trained dogs. PLoS One 2021;16:e0257474. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0257474 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0257474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaser, CA, Le Marchand, CE, Rizzo, K, Bornstein, L, Messenger, S, Edwards, CA, et al.. Lessons learned from a COVID-19 dog screening pilot in California K-12 schools. JAMA Pediatr 2023:177:644&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapediatrics.2023.0489 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2023.0489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sit, THC, Brackman, CJ, Ip, SM, Tam, KWS, Law, PYT, To, EMW, et al.. Infection of dogs with SARS-CoV-2. Nature 2020;586:776&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2334-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-020-2334-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroy, EM, Goulih, MA, Brugere-Picpux, J. The risk of SARS-CoV-2 transmission to pets and other wild and domestic animals strongly mandates a one-health strategy to control the COVID-19 pandemic. One Health 2020;10:100133. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.onehit.2020.100133 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.onehit.2020.100133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medkour, H, Catheland, S, Boucraut-Baralon, C, Laidoudi, Y, Sereme, Y, Pingret, JL, et al.. First evidence of human-to-dog transmission of SARS-CoV-2 B.1.160 variant in France. Transbound Emerg Dis 2022;69:e823&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1111/tbed.14359 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tbed.14359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza Barbosa, AB, Kmetiuk, LB, de Carvalho, OV, Brand&#xe3;o, APD, Doline, FR, Lopes, SRRS, et al.. Infection of SARS-CoV-2 in domestic dogs associated with owner viral load. Res Vet Sci 2022;153:61&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rvsc.2022.10.006 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rvsc.2022.10.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritz, M, Rosolen, B, Krafft, E, Becquart, P, Elguero, E, Vratskikh, O, et al.. High prevalence of SARS-CoV-2 antibodies in pets. One Health 2021;11:100192. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.onehlt.2020.100192 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.onehlt.2020.100192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberto-Orlando, S, Calderon, JL, Leon-Sosa, A, Pati&#xf1;o, L, Zambrano-Alvarado, MN, Pasquel-Villa, LD, et al.. ARS-CoV-2 transmission from infected owner to household dogs and cats is associated with food sharing. Int J Infect Dis 2022;122:295&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2022.05.049 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2022.05.049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamer, SA, Ghai, RR, Zecca, IB, Auckland, LD, Roundy, CM, Davila, E, et al.. SARS-CoV-2 B.1.1.7 variant of concern detected in a pet dog and cat after exposure to a person with COVID-19, USA. Transbound Emerg Dis 2022;69:1656&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1111/tbed.14122 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tbed.14122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, DH, Helal, ZH, Kim, J, Hunt, A, Barbieri, A, Tocco, N, et al.. Severe acute respiratory syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) in a dog in Connecticut in February 2021. Viruses 2021;13:2141. https://doi.org/10.3390/v13112141 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v13112141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barroso-Ar&#xe9;valo, S, Rivera, B, Dom&#xed;nguez, L, S&#xe1;nchez-Vizca&#xed;no, JM. First detection of SARS-CoV-2 B.1.1.7 variant of concern in an asymptomatic dog in Spain. Viruses 2021;13:1379. https://doi.org/10.3390/v13071379 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v13071379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Bastit, L, Rodon, J, Pradenas, E, Marfil, S, Trinit&#xe9;, B, Parera, M, et al.. First detection of SARS-CoV-2 Delta (B.1.617.2) variant of concern in a dog with clinical signs in Spain. Viruses 2021;13:2526. https://doi.org/10.3390/v13122526 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v13122526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuhlmeier, E, Chan, T, Ag&#xfc;&#xed;, CV, Willi, B, Wolfensberger, A, Beisel, C, et al.. Detection and molecular characterization of the SARS-CoV-2 Delta variant and the specific immune response in companion animals in Switzerland. Viruses 2023;15:245. https://doi.org/10.3390/v15010245 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v15010245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon, GT, Kim, HR, Kim, JM, Baek, JS, Shin, YK, Kwon, OK, et al.. Tailored multiplex real-time RT-PCR with species-specific internal positive controls for detecting SARS-CoV-2 in canine and feline clinical samples. Animals 2023;13:602. https://doi.org/10.3390/ani13040602 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani13040602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panei, CJ, Bravi, ME, Mor&#xe9;, G, De Felice, L, Unzaga, JM, et al.. Serological evidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection in pets naturally exposed during the COVID-19 outbreak in Argentina. Vet Immunol Immunopathol 2022;254:110519. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vetimm.2022.110519 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vetimm.2022.110519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, R, Wolff, C, Prada, JM, Mughini-Gras, L. When COVID-19 sits on people&#x2019;s laps: a systematic review of SARS-CoV-2 infection prevalence in household dogs and cats. One Health 2023;16:100497. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.onehlt.2023.100497 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.onehlt.2023.100497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Montes, S, Ballados-Gonz&#xe1;lez, GG, Gamboa-Prieto, J, Cruz-Romero, A, Romero-Salas, D, P&#xe9;rez-Br&#xed;gido, CD, et al.. No molecular evidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection in companion animals from Veracruz, Mexico. Transbound Emerg Dis 2022;69:2398&#x2013;403. https://doi.org/10.1111/tbed.14153 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tbed.14153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suharsono, H, Mukti, AG, Suryana, K, Tenaya, IWM, Pradana, DK, Daly, G, et al.. Preliminary study of coronavirus disease 2019 on pets in pandemic in Denpasar, Bali, Indonesia. Vet World 2021;14:2979&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.14202/vetworld.2021.2979-2983 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14202/vetworld.2021.2979-2983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temmam, S, Barbarino, A, Maso, D, Behillil, S, Enouf, V, Huon, C, et al.. Absence of SARS-CoV-2 infection in cats and dogs in close contact with a cluster of COVID-19 patients in a veterinary campus. Health 2020;10:100164. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.onehlt.2020.100164 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.onehlt.2020.100164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhtardanesh, B, Jajarmi, M, Shojaee, M, Salajegheh, Tazerji, S, Khalili Mahani, M, et al.. Molecular screening of SARS-CoV-2 in dogs and cats from households with infected owners diagnosed with COVID-19 during Delta and Omicron variant waves in Iran. Vet Med Sci 2023;9:82&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1002/vms3.1036 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/vms3.1036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dr&#xf3;&#x17c;d&#x17c;, M, Krzy&#x17c;ek, P, Dudek, B, Makuch, S, Janczura, A, Paluch, E. Current state of knowledge about the role of pets in zoonotic transmission of SARS-CoV-2. Viruses 2021;13:1149. https://doi.org/10.3390/v13061149 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v13061149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krafft, E, Denolly, S, Boson, B, Angelloz-Pessey, S, Levaltier, S, Nesi, N, et al.. Report of one-year prospective surveillance of SARS-CoV-2 in dogs and cats in France with various exposure risks: confirmation of a low prevalence of shedding, detection and complete sequencing of an alpha variant in a cat. Viruses 2021;13:1759. https://doi.org/10.3390/v13091759 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v13091759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas, J, Hughes, GM, Keough, KC, Painter, CA, Persky, NS, Corbo, M, et al.. Broad host range of SARS-CoV-2 predicted by comparative and structural analysis of ACE2 in vertebrates. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2020;117:22311&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2010146117 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2010146117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiersinga, WJ, Rhodes, A, Cheng, AC, Peacock, SJ, Prescott, HC. Pathophysiology, transmission, diagnosis, and treatment of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a review. JAMA 2020;324:782&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.12839 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.12839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghoshal, U, Vasanth, S, Tejan, N. A guide to laboratory diagnosis of Corona Virus Disease-19 for the gastroenterologists. Indian J Gastroenterol 2020;39:236&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12664-020-01082-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12664-020-01082-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boger, B, Fasci, MM, Vilhena, RO, Cobre, AF, Tonin, FS, Pontarolo, R. Systematic review with meta-analysis of the accuracy of diagnostic tests for COVID-19. Am J Infect Control 2021;49:21&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajic.2020.07.011 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajic.2020.07.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinnes, J, Deeks, JJ, Berhane, S, Taylor, M, Adriano, A, Davenport, C, et al.. Rapid, point-of- care antigen and molecular-based tests for diagnosis of SARS-VoC-2 infection. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2021;3:CD013705. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD013705 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul-Ehrlich-Institut. Mindestkriterien f&#xfc;r SARS-CoV-2 Antigentests im Sinne von &#xa7;1 Abs. 1 Satz 1 TestVO: antigenschnelltests . 2022. https://www.pei.de/SharedDocs/Downloads/DE/newsroom/dossiers/mindestkriterien-sars-cov-2-antigentests.pdf?__blob=publicationFile&amp;v=9 [Accessed April, 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larremore, DB, Wilder, DB, Lester, E, Shehata, S, Burke, JM, Hay, JA, et al.. Test sensitivity is secondary to frequency and turn-around times for COVID-19 screening. Sci Adv 2021;7. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.abd5393 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest, C, Harris, R, Sfanos, KS, Shrestha, E, Partin, AW, Trock, B, et al.. Feasibility of integrating canine olfaction with chemical and microbial profiling of urine to detect lethal prostate cancer. PLoS One 2021;16:e0245530. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0245530 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0245530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karakaya, D, Ulucan, O, Turkan, M. Electronic nose and its applications: a survey. Int J Autom Comput 2020;17:179&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snitz, K, Andelman-Gur, M, Pinchover, L, Weissgross, R, Weissbrod, A, Mishor, E, et al.. Proof of concept for real- time detection of SARS CoV-2 infection with an electronic nose. PLoS One 2021;16:e0252121. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0252121 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0252121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ates, HC, Nguyen, PQ, Gonzalez-Macia, L, Morales-Narv&#xe1;ez, E, G&#xfc;der, F, Collins, JJ, et al.. End-to-end design of wearable sensors. Nat Rev Mater 2022;7:887&#x2013;907. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41578-022-00460-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41578-022-00460-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>