<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39037494</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1866-3370</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>67</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current topics in behavioral neurosciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Top Behav Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical Activity and Fatigue Symptoms: Neurotypical Adults and People with Chronic Multisymptom Illnesses.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>281</StartPage><EndPage>308</EndPage><MedlinePgn>281-308</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/7854_2024_502</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>For neurotypical adults, a single bout of low-to-moderate intensity physical activity usually transiently improves feelings of energy. Similar bouts of exercise have the opposite effect of increased feelings of fatigue when performed by samples with chronic multisymptom illnesses (CMIs) such as Long-COVID, Gulf War Illness (GWI), or Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS). The short-term adoption of regular moderate intensity physical activity (typical experiments are 1 to 6&#xa0;months) among neurotypical adults results in small-to-moderate improvements in self-reported feelings of fatigue, energy, and vitality. Small improvements in these feelings, or no change at all, occur for CMIs, but limited data precludes strong conclusions. The mechanisms of exercise effects on fatigue, whether acute or chronic, are poorly understood but likely involve multiple neural circuits and associated transmitters. For CMIs, the mechanisms of acute worsening of fatigue with exercise may be driven by the yet unknown pathophysiological mechanisms of the disease (perhaps involving brain, immune and autonomic system dysfunction, and their interactions). Likewise, fatigue improvements may depend on whether chronic physical activity is a disease-modifying treatment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s), under exclusive license to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boruch</LastName><ForeName>Alex</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Service, William S. Middleton Memorial Veterans Hospital, Madison, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Branchaw</LastName><ForeName>Grace</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Service, William S. Middleton Memorial Veterans Hospital, Madison, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Connor</LastName><ForeName>Patrick J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Georgia, Athens, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cook</LastName><ForeName>Dane B</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Service, William S. Middleton Memorial Veterans Hospital, Madison, WI, USA. dane.cook@wisc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, USA. dane.cook@wisc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Top Behav Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101535383</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1866-3370</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015673" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fatigue Syndrome, Chronic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018923" MajorTopicYN="N">Persian Gulf Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002908" MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-exertional malaise</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39037494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/7854_2024_502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aaronson NK, Ahmedzai S, Bergman B, Bullinger M, Cull A, Duez NJ et al (1993) The European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer QLQ-C30: a quality-of-life instrument for use in international clinical trials in oncology. JNCI J Natl Cancer Inst 85(5):365&#x2013;376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8433390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Maqbali M, Al Sinani M, Al Naamani Z, Al Badi K, MaI T (2021) Prevalence of fatigue in patients with cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Pain Symptom Manag 61(1):167&#x2013;89.e14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander T, Watson MA, Klein-Adams JC, Ndirangu DS, Serrador JM, Falvo MJ et al (2023) Deployed veterans exhibit distinct respiratory patterns and greater dyspnea during maximal cardiopulmonary exercise: a case-control study. PLoS One 18(5):e0286015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37224153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10208524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghamdi I, Ariti C, Williams A, Wood E, Hewitt J (2021) Prevalence of fatigue after stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur Stroke J 6(4):319&#x2013;332</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35342803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8948505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arent SM, Alderman BL, Short EJ, Landers DM (2007) The impact of the testing environment on affective changes following acute resistance exercise. J Appl Sport Psychol 19(3):364&#x2013;378</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aritake S, Kaneita Y, Ohtsu T, Uchiyama M, Mishima K, Akashiba T et al (2015) Prevalence of fatigue symptoms and correlations in the general adult population. Sleep Biol Rhythms 13(2):146&#x2013;154</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baraniuk JN, Kern G, Narayan V, Cheema A (2021) Exercise modifies glutamate and other metabolic biomarkers in cerebrospinal fluid from Gulf War illness and Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. PLoS One 16(1):e0244116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33440400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7806361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barhorst EE, Boruch AE, Cook DB, Lindheimer JB (2021) Pain-related post-exertional malaise in Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) and fibromyalgia: a systematic review and three-level meta-analysis. Pain Med 23:1144</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartholomew JB, Morrison D, Ciccolo JT (2005) Effects of acute exercise on mood and well-being in patients with major depressive disorder. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37(12):2032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16331126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basso JC, Suzuki WA (2017) The effects of acute exercise on mood, cognition, neurophysiology, and neurochemical pathways: a review. Brain Plasticity 2:127&#x2013;152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29765853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5928534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu N, Yang X, Luben RN, Whibley D, Macfarlane GJ, Wareham NJ et al (2016) Fatigue is associated with excess mortality in the general population: results from the EPIC-Norfolk study. BMC Med 14(1):122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27543008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4992307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazelmans E, Bleijenberg G, Voeten MJ, van der Meer JW, Folgering H (2005) Impact of a maximal exercise test on symptoms and activity in chronic fatigue syndrome. J Psychosom Res 59(4):201&#x2013;208</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16223622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boecker H, Drzezga A (2016) A perspective on the future role of brain pet imaging in exercise science. NeuroImage 131:73&#x2013;80</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26477649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boolani A, Manierre M (2019) An exploratory multivariate study examining correlates of trait mental and physical fatigue and energy. Fatigue Biomed, Health Behav 7(1):29&#x2013;40</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boolani A, O&#x2019;Connor PJ, Reid J, Ma S, Mondal S (2019) Predictors of feelings of energy differ from predictors of fatigue. Fatigue Biomed, Health Behav 7(1):12&#x2013;28</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boruch AE, Lindheimer JB, Klein-Adams JC, Stegner AJ, Wylie GR, Ninneman JV et al (2021) Predicting post-exertional malaise in Gulf War illness based on acute exercise responses. Life Sci 280:119701</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34119538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10214407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boruch AE, Lindheimer JB, Ninneman JV, Wylie GR, Alexander T, Klein-Adams JC et al (2023) Exercise-induced changes in gene expression do not mediate post exertional malaise in Gulf War illness. Brain Behav Immun Health 29:100612</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36950022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10027470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botsford C, Brellenthin AG, Cisler JM, Hillard CJ, Koltyn KF, Crombie KM (2023) Circulating endocannabinoids and psychological outcomes in women with PTSD. J Anxiety Disord 93:102656</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36469982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouquet J, Li T, Gardy JL, Kang X, Stevens S, Stevens J et al (2019) Whole blood human transcriptome and virome analysis of ME/CFS patients experiencing post-exertional malaise following cardiopulmonary exercise testing. PLoS One 14(3):e0212193</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30897114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6428308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brellenthin AG, Crombie KM, Hillard CJ, Koltyn KF (2017) Endocannabinoid and mood responses to exercise in adults with varying activity levels. Med Sci Sports Exerc 49(8):1688&#x2013;1696</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28319590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown A, Jason LA (2020) Meta-analysis investigating post-exertional malaise between patients and controls. J Health Psychol 25(13&#x2013;14):2053&#x2013;2071</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29974812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carruthers BM, Jain AK, De Meirleir KL, Peterson DL, Klimas NG, Lerner AM et al (2003) Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: clinical working case definition, diagnostic and treatment protocols. J Chronic Fatigue Syndr 11(1):7&#x2013;115</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casson S, Jones MD, Cassar J, Kwai N, Lloyd AR, Barry BK et al (2022) The effectiveness of activity pacing interventions for people with chronic fatigue syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Disabil Rehabil 1-15:3788</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castell BD, Kazantzis N, Moss-Morris RE (2011) Cognitive behavioral therapy and graded exercise for chronic fatigue syndrome: a meta-analysis. Clin Psychol Sci Pract 18(4):311</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella D, Lai J-S, Jensen SE, Christodoulou C, Junghaenel DU, Reeve BB et al (2016) PROMIS fatigue item bank had clinical validity across diverse chronic conditions. J Clin Epidemiol 73:128&#x2013;134</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26939927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4902759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B (2022) Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis 226(9):1593&#x2013;1607</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho HJ, Hotopf M, Wessely S (2005) The placebo response in the treatment of chronic fatigue syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychosom Med 67(2):301&#x2013;313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15784798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu L, Valencia IJ, Garvert DW, Montoya JG (2018) Deconstructing post-exertional malaise in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a patient-centered, cross-sectional survey. PLoS One 13(6):e0197811</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29856774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5983853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clapp LL, Richardson MT, Smith JF, Wang M, Clapp AJ, Pieroni RE (1999) Acute effects of thirty minutes of light-intensity, intermittent exercise on patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. Phys Ther 79(8):749&#x2013;756</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10440661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clayton EW (2015) Beyond myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: an IOM report on redefining an illness. JAMA 313(11):1101&#x2013;1102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25668027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee on the Diagnostic Criteria for Myalgic Encephalomyelitis, Chronic Fatigue S, Board on the Health of Select P, Institute of M (2015) The national academies collection: reports funded by National Institutes of Health. Beyond myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: redefining an illness. National Academies Press (US). Copyright 2015 by the National Academy of Sciences. All rights reserved, Washington</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook DB, O'Connor PJ, Eubanks SA, Smith JC, Lee M (1997) Naturally occurring muscle pain during exercise: assessment and experimental evidence. Med Sci Sports Exerc 29(8):999&#x2013;1012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9268956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook DB, Light AR, Light KC, Broderick G, Shields MR, Dougherty RJ et al (2017) Neural consequences of post-exertion malaise in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Brain Behav Immun 62:87</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28216087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook DB, Van Riper S, Dougherty RJ, Lindheimer JB, Falvo MJ, Chen Y et al (2022) Cardiopulmonary, metabolic, and perceptual responses during exercise in Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS): a multi-site clinical assessment of ME/CFS (MCAM) sub-study. PLoS One 17(3):e0265315</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35290404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8923458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper SL, Whitaker MM, Lydon GW (2022) Acute effects of continuous exercise, interval exercise, and sedentary colouring on anxiety, mood, and physical activity enjoyment. Int J Sport Exerc Psychol 1&#x2013;18:951</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costello SE, O&#x2019;Neill BV, Howatson G, van Someren K, Haskell-Ramsay CF (2022) Detrimental effects on executive function and mood following consecutive days of repeated high-intensity sprint interval exercise in trained male sports players. J Sports Sci 40(7):783&#x2013;796</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34955079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courneya KS, Jones LW, Peddle CJ, Sellar CM, Reiman T, Joy AA et al (2008) Effects of aerobic exercise training in anemic cancer patients receiving Darbepoetin alfa: a randomized controlled trial. Oncologist 13(9):1012&#x2013;1020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18779540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crombie KM, Brellenthin AG, Hillard CJ, Koltyn KF (2018) Endocannabinoid and opioid system interactions in exercise-induced Hypoalgesia. Pain Med 19(1):118&#x2013;123</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28387833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curran SL, Andrykowski MA, Studts JL (1995) Short form of the profile of mood states (POMS-SF): psychometric information. Psychol Assess 7(1):80&#x2013;83</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutler DM (2022) The economic cost of long COVID: an update. Published online July 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Silva A, Fox DE, Nasser Y, Vallance JK, Quinn RR, Ronksley PE et al (2022) Prevalence and risk factors for fatigue in adults with inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 20(5):995&#x2013;1009.e7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34216824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re'em Y et al (2021) Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. eClinicalMedicine 38:202108. Available at SSRN 3820561.2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dishman RK, O'Connor PJ (2009) Lessons in exercise neurobiology: the case of endorphins. Ment Health Phys Act 2(1):4&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dishman RK, Thom NJ, Puetz TW, O'Connor PJ, Clementz BA (2010) Effects of cycling exercise on vigor, fatigue, and electroencephalographic activity among young adults who report persistent fatigue. Psychophysiology 47(6):1066&#x2013;1074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20409016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donta ST, Clauw DJ, Engel CC Jr, Guarino P, Peduzzi P, Williams DA et al (2003) Cognitive behavioral therapy and aerobic exercise for Gulf War veterans' illnesses: a randomized controlled trial. JAMA 289(11):1396&#x2013;1404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12636462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dursa EK, Barth SK, Porter BW, Schneiderman AI (2019) Health status of female and male Gulf War and gulf era veterans: a population-based study. Womens Health Issues 29:S39&#x2013;S46</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31253241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durstenfeld MS, Sun K, Tahir P, Peluso MJ, Deeks SG, Aras MA et al (2022) Use of cardiopulmonary exercise testing to evaluate long COVID-19 symptoms in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open 5(10):e2236057-e</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eignor DR (2013) The standards for educational and psychological testing. APA handbook of testing and assessment in psychology, Test theory and testing and assessment in industrial and organizational psychology. APA handbooks in psychology&#xae;, vol 1. American Psychological Association, Washington, pp 245&#x2013;250</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Est&#xe9;vez-L&#xf3;pez F, Mudie K, Wang-Steverding X, Bakken IJ, Ivanovs A, Castro-Marrero J et al (2020) Systematic review of the epidemiological burden of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome across Europe: current evidence and EUROMENE research recommendations for epidemiology. J Clin Med 9(5):1557</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32455633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7290765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fappiano CM, Baraniuk JN (2020) Gulf War illness symptom severity and onset: a cross-sectional survey. Mil Med 185(7&#x2013;8):e1120&#x2013;e11e7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32009157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focht BC (2009) Brief walks in outdoor and laboratory environments: effects on affective responses, enjoyment, and intentions to walk for exercise. Res Q Exerc Sport 80(3):611&#x2013;620</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19791648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedberg F, Tintle N, Clark J, Bromet E (2015) Prolonged fatigue in Ukraine and the United States: prevalence and risk factors. Fatigue Biomed, Health Behav 3(1):33&#x2013;46</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedberg F, Adamowicz JL, Bruckenthal P, Milazzo M, Ramjan S, Zhang X et al (2023) Sex differences in post-exercise fatigue and function in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Sci Rep 13(1):5442</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37012343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10070276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritz K, O&#x2019;Connor PJ (2016) Acute exercise improves mood and motivation in young men with ADHD symptoms. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48(6):1153&#x2013;1160</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26741120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K, Straus SE, Hickie I, Sharpe MC, Dobbins JG, Komaroff A (1994) The chronic fatigue syndrome: a comprehensive approach to its definition and study. International chronic fatigue syndrome study group. Ann Intern Med 121(12):953&#x2013;959</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7978722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K, Nisenbaum R, Stewart G, Thompson WW, Robin L, Washko RM et al (1998) Chronic multisymptom illness affecting air force veterans of the Gulf War. JAMA 280(11):981&#x2013;988</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9749480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulcher KY, White PD (1997) Randomised controlled trial of graded exercise in patients with the chronic fatigue syndrome. BMJ 314(7095):1647</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9180065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2126868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Germain A, Barupal DK, Levine SM, Hanson MR (2020) Comprehensive circulatory metabolomics in ME/CFS reveals disrupted metabolism of acyl lipids and steroids. Meta 10(1):34</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Germain A, Giloteaux L, Moore GE, Levine SM, Chia JK, Keller BA et al (2022) Plasma metabolomics reveals disrupted response and recovery following maximal exercise in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. JCI Insight 7(9):e157621</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35358096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9090259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go&#xeb;rtz YMJ, Braamse AMJ, Spruit MA, Janssen DJA, Ebadi Z, Van Herck M et al (2021) Fatigue in patients with chronic disease: results from the population-based lifelines cohort study. Sci Rep 11(1):20977</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34697347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8546086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goudsmit EM, Nijs J, Jason LA, Wallman KE (2012) Pacing as a strategy to improve energy management in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a consensus document. Disabil Rehabil 34(13):1140&#x2013;1147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22181560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene DR, Greene CL, Petruzzello SJ (2023) Crank it up: Utilizing exercise to combat acute fatigue and pain in individuals with probable posttraumatic stress disorder. Sport Exerc Perform Psychol 12(4):229&#x2013;240</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heboyan V, Krengel MH, Sullivan K, Iobst S, Klimas N, Wilson C et al (2019) Sex differences in Gulf War illness: a reanalysis of data from the CDC air force study using CDC and modified Kansas case definitions. J Occup Environ Med 61(7):610&#x2013;616</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31090678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herring MP, O'Connor PJ (2009) The effect of acute resistance exercise on feelings of energy and fatigue. J Sports Sci 27(7):701&#x2013;709</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19424902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtzman CS, Bhatia S, Cotler J, Jason LA (2019) Assessment of post-exertional malaise (PEM) in patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME) and chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS): a patient-driven survey. Diagnostics 9(1):26</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30832336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6468435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphreys H, Kilby L, Kudiersky N, Copeland R (2021) Long COVID and the role of physical activity: a qualitative study. BMJ Open 11(3):e047632</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam MF, Cotler J, Jason LA (2020) Post-viral fatigue and COVID-19: lessons from past epidemics. Fatigue Biomed, Health Behav 8(2):61&#x2013;69</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason LA, Mirin AA (2021) Updating the National Academy of medicine ME/CFS prevalence and economic impact figures to account for population growth and inflation. Fatigue Biomed, Health Behav 9(1):9&#x2013;13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n A, Franco-L&#xf3;pez F, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, S&#xe1;nchez-Agar JA, S&#xe1;nchez-Alcaraz Mart&#xed;nez BJ et al (2022) Rehabilitation for post-COVID-19 condition through a supervised exercise intervention: a randomized controlled trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports 32(12):1791&#x2013;1801</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36111386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph P, Arevalo C, Oliveira RKF, Faria-Urbina M, Felsenstein D, Oaklander AL et al (2021) Insights from invasive cardiopulmonary exercise testing of patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Chest 160(2):642&#x2013;651</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8727854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph P, Singh I, Oliveira R, Capone CA, Mullen MP, Cook DB et al (2023) Exercise pathophysiology in Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome and post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2: more in common than not? Chest 164:717</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37054777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10088277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan F, Kennedy G, Spence VA, Newton DJ, Belch JJF (2004) Peripheral cholinergic function in humans with chronic fatigue syndrome, Gulf War syndrome and with illness following organophosphate exposure. Clin Sci 106(2):183&#x2013;189</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kline CE, Hillman CH, Bloodgood Sheppard B, Tennant B, Conroy DE, Macko RF et al (2021) Physical activity and sleep: an updated umbrella review of the 2018 physical activity guidelines advisory committee report. Sleep Med Rev 58:101489</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33934046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8338757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krupp LB, LaRocca NG, Muir-Nash J, Steinberg AD (1989) The fatigue severity scale: application to patients with multiple sclerosis and systemic lupus erythematosus. Arch Neurol 46(10):1121&#x2013;1123</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2803071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaCaille RA, Masters KS, Heath EM (2004) Effects of cognitive strategy and exercise setting on running performance, perceived exertion, affect, and satisfaction. Psychol Sport Exerc 5(4):461&#x2013;476</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakhan SE, Kirchgessner A (2010) Gut inflammation in chronic fatigue syndrome. Nutr Metab 7:1&#x2013;10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larun L, Brurberg KG, Odgaard-Jensen J, Price JR (2019) Exercise therapy for chronic fatigue syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 10:CD003200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31577366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legrand FD, Race M, Herring MP (2018) Acute effects of outdoor and indoor exercise on feelings of energy and fatigue in people with depressive symptoms. J Environ Psychol 56:91&#x2013;96</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Light AR, White AT, Hughen RW, Light KC (2009) Moderate exercise increases expression for sensory, adrenergic, and immune genes in chronic fatigue syndrome patients but not in normal subjects. J Pain 10(10):1099&#x2013;1112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19647494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2757484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Light AR, Bateman L, Jo D, Hughen RW, Vanhaitsma TA, White AT et al (2012) Gene expression alterations at baseline and following moderate exercise in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome and fibromyalgia syndrome. J Intern Med 271(1):64&#x2013;81</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21615807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim E-J, Ahn Y-C, Jang E-S, Lee S-W, Lee S-H, Son C-G (2020a) Systematic review and meta-analysis of the prevalence of chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME). J Transl Med 18(1):100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32093722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7038594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim E-J, Kang E-B, Jang E-S, Son C-G (2020b) The prospects of the two-day cardiopulmonary exercise test (CPET) in ME/CFS patients: a meta-analysis. J Clin Med 9(12):4040</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33327624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7765094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindheimer JB, O&#x2019;Connor PJ, Dishman RK (2015) Quantifying the placebo effect in psychological outcomes of exercise training: a meta-analysis of randomized trials. Sports Med 45(5):693&#x2013;711</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25762083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindheimer JB, O'Connor PJ, McCully KK, Dishman RK (2017a) The effect of light-intensity cycling on mood and working memory in response to a randomized, placebo-controlled design. Psychosom Med 79(2):243</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27551990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindheimer JB, Meyer JD, Stegner AJ, Dougherty RJ, Van Riper SM, Shields M et al (2017b) Symptom variability following acute exercise in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a perspective on measuring post-exertion malaise. Fatigue Biomed, Health Behav 5(2):69&#x2013;88</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindheimer JB, Cook DB, Klein-Adams JC, Qian W, Hill HZ, Lange G et al (2019) Veterans with Gulf War illness exhibit distinct respiratory patterns during maximal cardiopulmonary exercise. PLoS One 14(11):e0224833</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31714907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6850551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindheimer JB, Stegner AJ, Wylie GR, Klein-Adams JC, Almassi NE, Ninneman JV et al (2020) Post-exertional malaise in veterans with Gulf War illness. Int J Psychophysiol 147:202&#x2013;212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31786249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loy BD, O'Connor PJ (2016) The effect of histamine on changes in mental energy and fatigue after a single bout of exercise. Physiol Behav 153:7&#x2013;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26482543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loy BD, O'Connor PJ, Dishman RK (2013) The effect of a single bout of exercise on energy and fatigue states: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Fatigue Biomed, Health Behav 1(4):223&#x2013;242</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loy BD, O&#x2019;Connor PJ, Dishman RK (2016) Effect of acute exercise on fatigue in people with ME/CFS/SEID: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48(10):2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27187093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5026555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loy BD, Cameron MH, O'Connor PJ (2018) Perceived fatigue and energy are independent unipolar states: supporting evidence. Med Hypotheses 113:46&#x2013;51</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29523293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5846196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma RC, Li XJ, Liu R, Xu XX (2023) Effects of physical exercise interventions for individuals with gynecologic cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Oncol Nurs Forum 50(4):531&#x2013;543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37677754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancini DM, Brunjes DL, Lala A, Trivieri MG, Contreras JP, Natelson BH (2021) Use of cardiopulmonary stress testing for patients with unexplained dyspnea post&#x2013;coronavirus disease. Heart Failure 9(12):927&#x2013;937</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34857177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques MM, De Gucht V, Gouveia MJ, Leal I, Maes S (2015) Differential effects of behavioral interventions with a graded physical activity component in patients suffering from chronic fatigue (syndrome): an updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Psychol Rev 40:123&#x2013;137</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26112761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDowell CP, Campbell MJ, Herring MP (2016) Sex-related differences in mood responses to acute aerobic exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48(9):1798&#x2013;1802</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27128666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNair DM, Lorr M, Droppleman LF (1981) Profile of mood states questionnaire. EDITS, San Diego</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros Torres D, Jorge Koifman R, da Silva SS (2022) Impact on fatigue of different types of physical exercise during adjuvant chemotherapy and radiotherapy in breast cancer: systematic review and meta-analysis. Support Care Cancer 30(6):4651&#x2013;4662</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35064331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R, Piacentini MF, Meirleir KD (2001) Brain microdialysis in exercise research. Sports Med 31(14):965&#x2013;983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11735681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer JD, Light AR, Shukla SK, Clevidence D, Yale S, Stegner AJ et al (2013) Post-exertion malaise in chronic fatigue syndrome: symptoms and gene expression. Fatigue Biomed, Health Behav 1(4):190&#x2013;209</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer JD, Crombie KM, Cook DB, Hillard CJ, Koltyn KF (2019) Serum endocannabinoid and mood changes after exercise in major depressive disorder. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51(9):1909&#x2013;1917</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30973483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6727944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moneghetti KJ, Skhiri M, Contrepois K, Kobayashi Y, Maecker H, Davis M et al (2018) Value of circulating cytokine profiling during submaximal exercise testing in Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Sci Rep 8(1):2779</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29426834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5807550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monroe DC, Gist NH, Freese EC, O'Connor PJ, McCully KK, Dishman RK (2016) Effects of sprint interval cycling on fatigue, energy, and cerebral oxygenation. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48(4):615&#x2013;624</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26559448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore GE, Keller BA, Stevens J, Mao X, Stevens SR, Chia JK et al (2023) Recovery from exercise in persons with Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). Medicina 59(3):571</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36984572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10059925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustian KM, Alfano CM, Heckler C, Kleckner AS, Kleckner IR, Leach CR et al (2017) Comparison of pharmaceutical, psychological, and exercise treatments for cancer-related fatigue: a meta-analysis. JAMA Oncol 3(7):961&#x2013;968</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28253393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5557289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehme M, Chappuis F, Kaiser L, Assal F, Guessous I (2023) The prevalence, severity, and impact of post-COVID persistent fatigue, post-exertional malaise, and chronic fatigue syndrome. J Gen Intern Med 38(3):835&#x2013;839</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36357723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijs J, De Meirleir K, Duquet W (2004) Kinesiophobia in chronic fatigue syndrome: assessment and associations with disability. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 85(10):1586&#x2013;1592</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15468015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien PM, O&#x2019;Conner PJ (2000) Effect of bright light on cycling performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 32(2):439&#x2013;447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10694129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor PJ (2004) Evaluation of four highly cited energy and fatigue mood measures. J Psychosom Res 57(5):435&#x2013;441</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15581646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor PJ, Puetz TW (2005) Chronic physical activity and feelings of energy and fatigue. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37(2):299&#x2013;305</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15692327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor PJ, Herring MP, Caravalho A (2010) Mental health benefits of strength training in adults. Am J Lifestyle Med 4(5):377&#x2013;396</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliva Ramirez A, Keenan A, Kalau O, Worthington E, Cohen L, Singh S (2021) Prevalence and burden of multiple sclerosis-related fatigue: a systematic literature review. BMC Neurol 21(1):468</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34856949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8638268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paneroni M, Vitacca M, Venturelli M, Simonelli C, Bertacchini L, Scalvini S et al (2020) The impact of exercise training on fatigue in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pulmonology 26(5):304&#x2013;313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32184070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson PK, Sirr SA, Grammith FC, Schenck CH, Pheley AM, Hu S et al (1994) Effects of mild exercise on cytokines and cerebral blood flow in chronic fatigue syndrome patients. Clin Diagn Lab Immunol 1(2):222&#x2013;226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7496949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">368231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petruzzello SJ, Hall EE, Ekkekakis P (2001) Regional brain activation as a biological marker of affective responsivity to acute exercise: influence of fitness. Psychophysiology 38(1):99&#x2013;106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11321625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilutti LA, Greenlee TA, Motl RW, Nickrent MS, Petruzzello SJ (2013) Effects of exercise training on fatigue in multiple sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Psychosom Med 75(6):575</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23788693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell P, Bentall RP, Nye FJ, Edwards RHT (2001) Randomised controlled trial of patient education to encourage graded exercise in chronic fatigue syndrome. BMJ 322(7283):387</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11179154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">26565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proffitt M (2023) Oxford English dictionary. OED.com . Oxford University Press</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proost M, Habay J, De Wachter J, De Pauw K, Rattray B, Meeusen R et al (2022) How to tackle mental fatigue: a systematic review of potential countermeasures and their underlying mechanisms. Sports Med 52(9):2129&#x2013;2158</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35543922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puetz TW (2006) Physical activity and feelings of energy and fatigue. Sports Med 36(9):767&#x2013;780</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puetz TW, O'Connor PJ, Dishman RK (2006) Effects of chronic exercise on feelings of energy and fatigue: a quantitative synthesis. Psychol Bull 132(6):866&#x2013;876</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17073524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu D, Zhang Z, Yu X, Zhao J, Qiu F, Huang J (2016) Psychotropic drugs for the management of cancer-related fatigue: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Cancer Care 25(6):970&#x2013;979</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raichlen DA, Foster AD, Gerdeman GL, Seillier A, Giuffrida A (2012) Wired to run: exercise-induced endocannabinoid signaling in humans and cursorial mammals with implications for the 'runner's high. J Exp Biol 215(Pt 8):1331&#x2013;1336</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22442371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rayhan RU, Baraniuk JN (2021) Submaximal exercise provokes increased activation of the anterior default mode network during the resting state as a biomarker of postexertional malaise in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Front Neurosci 15:748426</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34975370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8714840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razazian N, Kazeminia M, Moayedi H, Daneshkhah A, Shohaimi S, Mohammadi M et al (2020) The impact of physical exercise on the fatigue symptoms in patients with multiple sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Neurol 20(1):93</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32169035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7068865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves WC, Jones JF, Maloney E, Heim C, Hoaglin DC, Boneva RS et al (2007) Prevalence of chronic fatigue syndrome in metropolitan, urban, and rural Georgia. Popul Health Metrics 5(1):5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regier DA, Kuhl EA, Kupfer DJ (2013) The DSM-5: classification and criteria changes. World Psychiatry 12(2):92&#x2013;98</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23737408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3683251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riedl A, Schmidtmann M, Stengel A, Goebel M, Wisser A-S, Klapp BF et al (2008) Somatic comorbidities of irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic analysis. J Psychosom Res 64(6):573&#x2013;582</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18501257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rongen-van Dartel SAA, Repping-Wuts H, Flendrie M, Bleijenberg G, Metsios GS, van den Hout WB et al (2015) Effect of aerobic exercise training on fatigue in rheumatoid arthritis: a meta-analysis. Arthritis Care Res 67(8):1054&#x2013;1062</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salamone JD, Correa M (2024) The neurobiology of activational aspects of motivation: exertion of effort, effort-based decision making, and the role of dopamine. Annu Rev Psychol 75(1):null</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shine K, Bloom FE, Cook KF, Cory-Slechta DA, Friedberg F, Grossblatt N (2014) Chronic multisymptom illness in Gulf War veterans: case definitions reexamined. National Academies Press, Washington</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shukla SK, Cook D, Meyer J, Vernon SD, Le T, Clevidence D et al (2015) Changes in gut and plasma microbiome following exercise challenge in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). PLoS One 10(12):e0145453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26683192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4684203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh I, Joseph P, Heerdt PM, Cullinan M, Lutchmansingh DD, Gulati M et al (2022) Persistent exertional intolerance after COVID-19: insights from invasive cardiopulmonary exercise testing. Chest 161(1):54&#x2013;63</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34389297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smylie AL, Broderick G, Fernandes H, Razdan S, Barnes Z, Collado F et al (2013) A comparison of sex-specific immune signatures in Gulf War illness and chronic fatigue syndrome. BMC Immunol 14:29</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23800166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3698072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stahl SM (2002) The psychopharmacology of energy and fatigue. J Clin Psychiatry 63(1):7&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11838630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, Ghanima W, Olsen MK, Gilboe HM, Einvik G (2021) Prevalence and determinants of fatigue after COVID-19 in non-hospitalized subjects: a population-based study. Int J Environ Res Public Health 18(4):2030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33669714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7921928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele L (2000) Prevalence and patterns of Gulf War illness in Kansas veterans: association of symptoms with characteristics of person, place, and time of military service. Am J Epidemiol 152(10):992&#x2013;1002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11092441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stegner AJ, Almassi NE, Dougherty RJ, Ellingson LD, Gretzon NP, Lindheimer JB et al (2021) Safety and efficacy of short-term structured resistance exercise in Gulf War veterans with chronic unexplained muscle pain: a randomized controlled trial. Life Sci 282:119810</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34256041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10214409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stussman B, Williams A, Snow J, Gavin A, Scott R, Nath A et al (2020) Characterization of post&#x2013;exertional malaise in patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Front Neurol 11:1025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33071931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7530890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan K, Krengel M, Heboyan V, Schildroth S, Wilson CC, Iobst S et al (2020) Prevalence and patterns of symptoms among female veterans of the 1991 Gulf War era: 25 years later. J Women's Health 29(6):819&#x2013;826</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szabo A (2013) Acute psychological benefits of exercise: reconsideration of the placebo effect. J Ment Health 22(5):449&#x2013;455</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23324013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley SE, Karlson EW, Levitan EB, Levy B, McComsey GA et al (2023) Development of a definition of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA 329(22):1934&#x2013;1946</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10214179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomlinson D, Diorio C, Beyene J, Sung L (2014) Effect of exercise on cancer-related fatigue: a meta-analysis. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 93(8):675</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24743466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>United States Department of Veterans Affairs (2008) Research advisory committee on Gulf War veterans I. Gulf War illness and the health of Gulf War veterans: scientific findings and recommendations. US Government Printing Office</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Ness JM, Stevens SR, Bateman L, Stiles TL, Snell CR (2010) Postexertional malaise in women with chronic fatigue syndrome. J Women's Health (Larchmt) 19(2):239&#x2013;244</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Oosterwijck J, Nijs J, Meeus M, Lefever I, Huybrechts L, Lambrecht L et al (2010) Pain inhibition and postexertional malaise in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: an experimental study. J Intern Med 268(3):265&#x2013;278</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20412374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vulpen JK, Sweegers MG, Peeters PHM, Courneya KS, Newton RU, Aaronson NK et al (2020) Moderators of exercise effects on cancer-related fatigue: a meta-analysis of individual patient data. Med Sci Sports Exerc 52(2):303&#x2013;314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31524827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6962544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Yin J, Miller AH, Xiao C (2017) A systematic review of the association between fatigue and genetic polymorphisms. Brain Behav Immun 62:230&#x2013;244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28089639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5947855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward-Ritacco C, Poudevigne MS, O'Connor PJ (2016) Muscle strengthening exercises during pregnancy are associated with increased energy and reduced fatigue. J Psychosom Obstet Gynaecol 37(2):68&#x2013;72</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26984583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4978349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward-Ritacco CL, Wilson AR, O&#x2019;Connor PJ (2021) An apple extract beverage combined with caffeine can improve alertness, mental fatigue, and information processing speed. J Cogn Enhanc 5(3):267&#x2013;279</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware JEJ (2000) SF-36 health survey update. Spine 25(24):3130&#x2013;3139</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11124729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washington SD, Rayhan RU, Garner R, Provenzano D, Zajur K, Addiego FM et al (2020) Exercise alters brain activation in Gulf War illness and Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Brain Commun 2(2):fcaa070</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32954325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7425336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstein AA, Deuster PA, Francis JL, Beadling C, Kop WJ (2010) The role of depression in short-term mood and fatigue responses to acute exercise. Int J Behav Med 17(1):51&#x2013;57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19333764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wender CLA, Manninen M, O'Connor PJ (2022) The effect of chronic exercise on energy and fatigue states: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized trials. Front Psychol 13:907637</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35726269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9206544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White AT, Light AR, Hughen RW, Bateman L, Martins TB, Hill HR et al (2010) Severity of symptom flare after moderate exercise is linked to cytokine activity in chronic fatigue syndrome. Psychophysiology 47(4):615&#x2013;624</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20230500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4378647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White PD, Goldsmith KA, Johnson AL, Potts L, Walwyn R, DeCesare JC et al (2011) Comparison of adaptive pacing therapy, cognitive behaviour therapy, graded exercise therapy, and specialist medical care for chronic fatigue syndrome (PACE): a randomised trial. Lancet 377(9768):823&#x2013;836</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21334061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3065633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo M, Kim S, Kim J, Petruzzello SJ, Hatfield BD (2009) Examining the exercise-affect dose&#x2013;response relationship: does duration influence frontal EEG asymmetry? Int J Psychophysiol 72(2):166&#x2013;172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19110012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao P, Ding S, Duan Y, Li L, Zhou Y, Luo X et al (2022) Effect of light therapy on cancer-related fatigue: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Pain Symptom Manag 63(2):e188&#x2013;e202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon JH, Park NH, Kang YE, Ahn YC, Lee EJ, Son CG (2023) The demographic features of fatigue in the general population worldwide: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Public Health 11:1192121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37575103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10416797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T (1984) Effect of exercise duration during incremental exercise on the determination of anaerobic threshold and the onset of blood lactate accumulation. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 53(3):196&#x2013;199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6542852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou S, Kumar U (2018) Cannabinoid receptors and the endocannabinoid system: signaling and function in the central nervous system. Int J Mol Sci 19(3):833</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29533978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5877694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>