<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38284464</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2702</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of long-term COVID-19 on aetiological factors related to nocturia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1161</StartPage><EndPage>1168</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1161-1168</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocn.17037</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study was conducted to examine the possible aetiology of nocturia in patients with long-term COVID-19.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Physical and neuropsychiatric symptoms, an increase in overactive bladder symptoms, especially from urinary system complaints, has been reported in patients with COVID-19, 10-14&#x2009;weeks after the illness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">A descriptive design.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study consisted of 70 patients who had experienced COVID-19, had nocturia, and were followed in the State Hospital between April and July 2022. Data were collected using a patient information form, the 'TANGO' nocturia screening tool, and the Visual Analog Scale. This study was created in accordance with the STROBE Statement Checklist.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">When the nocturia effects of long-term COVID-19 were examined it was determined that the urinary tract was the 'priority' aetiological condition. It was observed that there was a significant difference between the aetiological factor groups in terms of the mean age of the patients and the number of nocturia (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05). According to post-hoc analysis, the mean age of patients with a dominant cardio-metabolic factor was found to be significantly younger (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05). In addition, when comparing the number of nocturia according to the aetiological factors of the patients, it was observed that the number of nocturia was significantly frequent in the patients with a dominant sleep factor (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">It was found that the urinary tract aetiological factor was dominant in patients with long-term COVID-19 and nocturia, patients with a dominant cardiovascular aetiological factor were younger, and that the number of nocturia was higher in patients with a dominant sleep factor.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RELEVANCE TO CLINICAL PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Identification of the early signs and symptoms and underlying causes of nocturia in individuals with post-COVID-19 syndrome will enable nurses and health professionals to guide the early identification of different underlying problems, as well as the implementation of approaches to treat and eliminate nocturia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENT OR PUBLIC CONTRIBUTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The patients contributed to the study by agreeing to participate in the evaluation of nocturia complaints after COVID-19 infection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;ulha</LastName><ForeName>Yeliz</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5460-5844</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fundamentals of Nursing Department, Florence Nightingale Faculty of Nursing, Istanbul University-Cerrahpa&#x15f;a, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>B&#xfc;y&#xfc;ky&#x131;lmaz</LastName><ForeName>Funda</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fundamentals of Nursing Department, Florence Nightingale Faculty of Nursing, Istanbul University-Cerrahpa&#x15f;a, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;ulha</LastName><ForeName>Mehmet G&#xf6;khan</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Prof. Dr. Cemal Tasc&#x131;oglu City Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9207302</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0962-1067</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053158" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nocturia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053201" MajorTopicYN="Y">Urinary Bladder, Overactive</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001743" MajorTopicYN="N">Urinary Bladder</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TANGO</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lower urinary tract symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nocturia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38284464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.17037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Bower, W. F., Rose, G. E., Ervin, C. F., Goldin, J., Whishaw, D. M., &amp; Khan, F. (2017). TANGO-A screening tool to identify comorbidities on the causal pathway of nocturia. BJU International, 119(6), 933-941. https://doi.org/10.1111/bju.13774</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can, O., Erkoc, M., &#xd6;zer, M., Karakanli, M., &amp; Otunctemur, A. (2021). Increased lower urinary tract symptoms in female COVID-19 patients: A clinical trial. Journal of Reconstructive Urology, 11, 123-127. https://doi.org/10.5336/urology.2021-85030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can, O., Erko&#xe7;, M., Ozer, M., Karakanli, M. U., &amp; Otunctemur, A. (2021). The effect of COVID-19 on lower urinary tract symptoms in elderly men. International Journal of Clinical Practice, 75(6), e14110. https://doi.org/10.1111/ijcp.14110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carod-Artal, F. J. (2021). Post-COVID-19 syndrome: Epidemiology, diagnostic criteria and pathogenic mechanisms involved. Revista de Neurologia, 72(11), 384-396. https://doi.org/10.33588/rn.7211.2021230</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, E. P. H., Wan, E. Y. F., Kwok, J. Y. Y., Chin, W. Y., &amp; Lam, C. L. K. (2019). The mediating role of sleep quality in the association between nocturia and health-related quality of life. Health and Quality of Life Outcomes, 17(1), 181. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12955-019-1251-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creta, M., Sagnelli, C., Celentano, G., Napolitano, L., La Rocca, R., Capece, M., Califano, G., Calogero, A., Sica, A., Mangiapia, F., Ciccozzi, M., Fusco, F., Mirone, V., Sagnelli, E., &amp; Longo, N. (2021). SARS-CoV-2 infection affects the lower urinary tract and male genital system: A systematic review. Journal of Medical Virology, 93(5), 3133-3142. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.26883</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook, H., Raza, S., Nowell, J., Young, M., &amp; Edison, P. (2021). Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ, 374, n1648. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n1648</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culha, M. G., Culha, Y., Buyukyilmaz, F., Turan, N., &amp; Bower, W. (2021). "TANGO" nocturia scanning tool: Turkish validity and reliability study. Lower urinary tract symptoms, 13(1), 88-92. https://doi.org/10.1111/luts.12336</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Costa, A., Ishida, M., Akrour, R., Mary-Heck, G., Grilo, N., Schurch, B., &amp; Lang, P. O. (2017). Nocturia in aged patient: In practice. Revue M&#xe9;dicale Suisse, 13(582), 1946-1951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhar, N., Dhar, S., Timar, R., Lucas, S., Lamb, L. E., &amp; Chancellor, M. B. (2020). De novo urinary symptoms associated with COVID-19: COVID-19-associated cystitis. Journal of Clinical Medical Research, 12(10), 681-682. https://doi.org/10.14740/jocmr4294</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutoglu, E., Soysal, P., Smith, L., Arik, F., Kalan, U., Kazancioglu, R. T., &amp; Isik, A. T. (2019). Nocturia and its clinical implications in older women. Archives of Gerontology and Geriatrics, 85, 103917. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.archger.2019.103917</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham, J. N., Jr., Desroches, B. R., &amp; Weiss, J. P. (2014). Nocturia causes vary with each decade. Current Opinion in Urology, 24(4), 358-362. https://doi.org/10.1097/mou.0000000000000061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graugaard-Jensen, C., Rittig, S., &amp; Djurhuus, J. C. (2006). Nocturia and circadian blood pressure profile in healthy elderly male volunteers. The Journal of Urology, 176(3), 1034-1039. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.juro.2006.04.046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirayama, A., Torimoto, K., Yamada, A., Tanaka, N., Fujimoto, K., Yoshida, K., &amp; Hirao, Y. (2011). Relationship between nocturnal urine volume, leg edema, and urinary antidiuretic hormone in older men. Urology, 77(6), 1426-1431. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.urology.2010.12.030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C., Huang, L., Wang, Y., Li, X., Ren, L., Gu, X., Kang, L., Guo, L., Liu, M., Zhou, X., Luo, J., Huang, Z., Tu, S., Zhao, Y., Chen, L., Xu, D., Li, Y., Li, C., Peng, L., &#x2026; Cao, B. (2021). 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: A cohort study. Lancet, 397(10270), 220-232. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(20)32656-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb, L. E., Dhar, N., Timar, R., Wills, M., Dhar, S., &amp; Chancellor, M. B. (2020). COVID-19 inflammation results in urine cytokine elevation and causes COVID-19 associated cystitis (CAC). Medical Hypotheses, 145, 110375. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mehy.2020.110375</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb, L. E., Timar, R., Wills, M., Dhar, S., Lucas, S. M., Komnenov, D., Chancellor, M. B., &amp; Dhar, N. (2022). Long COVID and COVID-19-associated cystitis (CAC). International Urology and Nephrology, 54(1), 17-21. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11255-021-03030-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monaghan, C. K., Larkin, J. W., Chaudhuri, S., Han, H., Jiao, Y., Bermudez, K. M., Weinhandl, E. D., Dahne-Steuber, I. A., Belmonte, K., Neri, L., Kotanko, P., Kooman, J. P., Hymes, J. L., Kossmann, R. J., Usvyat, L. A., &amp; Maddux, F. W. (2021). Machine learning for prediction of patients on hemodialysis with an undetected SARS-CoV-2 infection. Kidney360, 2(3), 456-468. https://doi.org/10.34067/kid.0003802020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mumm, J. N., Osterman, A., Ruzicka, M., Stihl, C., Vilsmaier, T., Munker, D., Khatamzas, E., Giessen-Jung, C., Stief, C., Staehler, M., &amp; Rodler, S. (2020). Urinary frequency as a possibly overlooked symptom in COVID-19 patients: Does SARS-CoV-2 cause viral cystitis? European Urology, 78(4), 624-628. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eururo.2020.05.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parums, D. V. (2021). Editorial: Long COVID, or post-COVID syndrome, and the global impact on health care. Medical Science Monitor, 27, e933446. https://doi.org/10.12659/msm.933446</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesonen, J. S., Vernooij, R. W. M., Cartwright, R., Aoki, Y., Agarwal, A., Mangera, A., Markland, A. D., Tsui, J. F., Santti, H., Griebling, T. L., Pryalukhin, A. E., Riikonen, J., T&#xe4;htinen, R. M., Vaughan, C. P., Johnson, T. M., 2nd, Heels-Ansdell, D., Guyatt, G. H., &amp; Tikkinen, K. A. O. (2020). The impact of nocturia on falls and fractures: A systematic review and meta-analysis. The Journal of Urology, 203(4), 674-683. https://doi.org/10.1097/ju.0000000000000459</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes, P. B. G., Butcher, K., Cotterill, N., Drake, M. J., Gimson, A., Gogola, L., Henderson, E. J., Huntley, A. L., Rees, J., Strong, E., Wong, C., Skyrme-Jones, A., &amp; Dawson, S. (2022). Implications of cardiovascular disease for assessment and treatment of nocturia in primary care: Systematic review and nominal group technique consensus. European Urology Focus, 8(1), 26-32. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.euf.2021.12.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sighinolfi, M. C., Rocco, B., &amp; Mussini, C. (2020). COVID-19: Importance of the awareness of the clinical syndrome by urologists. European Urology, 78(1), e40-e41. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eururo.2020.03.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes, D. L., Holdsworth, L., Jawad, N., Gunasekera, P., Morice, A. H., &amp; Crooks, M. G. (2021). Post-COVID-19 symptom burden: What is long-COVID and how should we manage it? Lung, 199(2), 113-119. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00408-021-00423-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobler, D. L., Pruzansky, A. J., Naderi, S., Ambrosy, A. P., &amp; Slade, J. J. (2022). Long-term cardiovascular effects of COVID-19: Emerging data relevant to the cardiovascular clinician. Current Atherosclerosis Reports, 24(7), 563-570. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11883-022-01032-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm, E., Altman, D. G., Egger, M., Pocock, S. J., G&#xf8;tzsche, P. C., &amp; Vandenbroucke, J. P. (2008). The strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement: Guidelines for reporting observational studies. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology, 61(4), 344-349. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.11.008</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>