<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34620202</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1745-6673</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of occupational medicine and toxicology (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Occup Med Toxicol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impact of Post-COVID-Syndrome on functioning - results from a community survey in patients after mild and moderate SARS-CoV-2-infections in Germany.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>45</StartPage><MedlinePgn>45</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">45</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12995-021-00337-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In COVID-19 survivors a relatively high number of long-term symptoms have been observed. Besides impact on quality of life, these symptoms (now called Post-COVID-Syndrome) may have an impact on functioning and may also hinder to participation in social life in affected people. However, little is known about developing such syndrome a for patients with mild and moderate COVID-19 who did not need hospitalization or intensive care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional study in 1027 patients with mild or moderate COVID-19 was performed in two communities in Bavaria, Germany. The Rehabilitation-Needs-Survey (RehabNeS) including the Short Form 36 Health Survey (SF-36) on health-related quality of life, was used. Descriptive statistics were calculated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In all, 97.5% of patients reported one symptom in the infection stage, such as fatigue, respiratory problems, limitations of the senses of taste and smell, fear and anxiety and other symptoms. In this time period, 84.1% of the participants experienced activity limitations and participation restrictions such as carrying out daily routines, handling stress, getting household tasks done, caring for/supporting others, and relaxing and leisure concerns. In all, 61.9% of participants reported persisting symptoms more than 3&#x2009;months after infection. These were fatigue, sleep disturbances, respiratory problems, pain, fear and anxiety, and restrictions in movement; 49% of the participants reported activity limitations and participation restrictions. Predominately, these were handling stress, carrying out daily routines, looking after one's health, relaxing and leisure activities and doing house work. The impacts on quality of life and vocational performance were rather low.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results show that long-term symptoms after mild and moderate COVID-19 are common and lead to limitations of activities and participation. However, it seems that in most cases they are not severe and do not lead to frequent or serious issues with quality of life or work ability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lemh&#xf6;fer</LastName><ForeName>Christina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Jena University Hospital, Jena, Germany. Christina.lemhoefer@med.uni-jena.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sturm</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Hannover Medical School, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loudovici-Krug</LastName><ForeName>Dana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Jena University Hospital, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Best</LastName><ForeName>Norman</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Jena University Hospital, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gutenbrunner</LastName><ForeName>Christoph</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Hannover Medical School, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Occup Med Toxicol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101245790</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-6673</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger"><AbstractText Label="ZUSAMMENFASSUNG" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">HINTERGRUND: Bei COVID-19-&#xdc;berlebenden kann eine relativ hohe Anzahl von Langzeitsymptomen beobachtet werden. Neben der Beeintr&#xe4;chtigung der Lebensqualit&#xe4;t k&#xf6;nnen diese Symptome (jetzt als Post-COVID oder Long-COVID bezeichnet) auch Auswirkungen auf die Funktionsf&#xe4;higkeit haben und die Betroffenen an der Teilnahme am sozialen Leben hindern. Es ist jedoch wenig bekannt, ob und in welchem Ausma&#xdf; Patienten und Patientinnen mit leichtem und mittelschwererem Verlauf, die keine intensivmedizinische oder normalstation&#xe4;re Behandlung ben&#xf6;tigten, ein solches Syndrom mit entsprechenden Defiziten entwickeln.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODE" NlmCategory="METHODS">In einer Querschnittsstudie wurden 1027 Patienten und Patientinnen mit leichtem oder mittelschwerem COVID-19 Verlauf in zwei Landkreisen in Bayern, fragebogenbasiert befragt. Hierzu wurde der Rehabilitation-Need-Survey (RehabNeS), der den Short Form 36 Gesundheitsfragebogen (SF-36) zur gesundheitsbezogenen Lebensqualit&#xe4;t beinhaltet, angewendet. Es erfolgte eine deskriptive Auswertung.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ERGEBNISSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">97,5% der Patienten und Patientinnen berichteten &#xfc;ber mindestens ein bestehendes Symptom in der Infektionsphase, wie M&#xfc;digkeit, Atemprobleme, Einschr&#xe4;nkungen des Geschmacks- und Geruchssinns sowie Angst und Unruhe. In dieser Phase erlebten 84,1% der Befragten Aktivit&#xe4;tseinschr&#xe4;nkungen und Einschr&#xe4;nkungen der Teilhabe, z. B. in der Durchf&#xfc;hrung der t&#xe4;glichen Routine, der Bew&#xe4;ltigung von Stress, der Erledigung von Aufgaben im Haushalt, die Pflege/Unterst&#xfc;tzung anderer sowie bei der F&#xe4;higkeit sich zu entspannen. 61,9% der Teilnehmer und Teilnehmerinnen berichteten &#xfc;ber anhaltende Symptome nach mehr als 3 Monaten nach der Infektion. Dies waren u.a. M&#xfc;digkeit, Schlafst&#xf6;rungen, Atemprobleme, Schmerzen, &#xc4;ngste und Bef&#xfc;rchtungen sowie Bewegungseinschr&#xe4;nkungen. 49% der Befragten berichteten &#xfc;ber Aktivit&#xe4;ts- und Teilnahmeeinschr&#xe4;nkungen. &#xdc;berwiegend waren dies der Umgang mit Stress, die Durchf&#xfc;hrung der t&#xe4;glichen Routine, die Pflege der Gesundheit, die F&#xe4;higkeit zur Entspannung und Freizeitaktivit&#xe4;ten sowie die Verrichtung von Hausarbeiten. Die Auswirkungen auf die Lebensqualit&#xe4;t und die berufliche Leistungsf&#xe4;higkeit waren eher gering.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SCHLUSSFOLGERUNG" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Die Ergebnisse zeigen, dass Langzeitsymptome nach leichten und mittelschweren COVID-19 h&#xe4;ufig sind und zu Einschr&#xe4;nkungen von Aktivit&#xe4;ten und Teilhabe f&#xfc;hren. Es scheint jedoch, dass sie in den meisten F&#xe4;llen nicht sehr schwerwiegend sind und nicht zu h&#xe4;ufigen oder schwerwiegenden Problemen in der Lebensqualit&#xe4;t oder der beruflichen Leistungsf&#xe4;higkeit f&#xfc;hren.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Impact on functioning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mild and moderate COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34620202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8495185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12995-021-00337-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12995-021-00337-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Di Maria E, Latini A, Borgiani P, Novelli G. Genetic variants of the human host influencing the coronavirus-associated phenotypes (SARS, MERS and COVID-19): rapid systematic review and field synopsis. Hum Genomics. 2020;14(1):30. doi: 10.1186/s40246-020-00280-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40246-020-00280-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7484929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32917282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie L, Liu Y, Xiao Y, Tian Q, Fan B, Zhao H, Chen W. Follow-up study on pulmonary function and lung radiographic changes in rehabilitating severe acute respiratory syndrome patients after discharge. Chest. 2005;127(6):2119&#x2013;2124. doi: 10.1378/chest.127.6.2119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.127.6.2119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X, Liang M, Ding M, Liu W, Ma H, Zhou X, Ren H. Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO) in critically ill patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pneumonia and acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) Med Sci Monit. 2020;26:e925364. doi: 10.12659/MSM.925364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.925364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7430351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z, McGoogan JM. Characteristics of and important lessons from the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) outbreak in China: summary of a report of 72 314 cases from the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention. JAMA. 2020;323(13):1239&#x2013;1242. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.2648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.2648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32091533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buitrago-Garcia D, Egli-Gany D, Counotte MJ, Hossmann S, Imeri H, Ipekci AM, Salanti G, Low N. Occurrence and transmission potential of asymptomatic and presymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infections: a living systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS Med. 2020;17(9):e1003346. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1003346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1003346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32960881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong E, Du H, Gardner L. An interactive web-based dashboard to track COVID-19 in real time. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20(5):533&#x2013;534. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30120-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30120-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32087114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathi M, Vakili K, Sayehmiri F, Mohamadkhani A, Hajiesmaeili M, Rezaei-Tavirani M, Eilami O. The prognostic value of comorbidity for the severity of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis study. PLoS One. 2021;16(2):e0246190. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0246190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0246190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7886178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33592019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudatsir M, Fajar JK, Wulandari L, Soegiarto G, Ilmawan M, Purnamasari Y, et al. Predictors of COVID-19 severity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. F1000Res. 2020;9:1107. doi: 10.12688/f1000research.26186.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/f1000research.26186.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7607482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33163160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, Kang L, Guo L, Liu M, Zhou X, Luo J, Huang Z, Tu S, Zhao Y, Chen L, Xu D, Li Y, Li C, Peng L, Li Y, Xie W, Cui D, Shang L, Fan G, Xu J, Wang G, Wang Y, Zhong J, Wang C, Wang J, Zhang D, Cao B. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220&#x2013;232. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, et al. Attributes and predictors of long-COVID: analysis of COVID cases and their symptoms collected by the Covid symptoms study app. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, Dunne J, Mooney A, Gaffney F, O'Connor L, Leavy D, O'Brien K, Dowds J, Sugrue JA, Hopkins D, Martin-Loeches I, Ni Cheallaigh C, Nadarajan P, McLaughlin AM, Bourke NM, Bergin C, O'Farrelly C, Bannan C, Conlon N. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One. 2020;15(11):e0240784. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0240784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0240784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung TYM, Chan AYL, Chan EW, Chan VKY, Chui CSL, Cowling BJ, Gao L, Ge MQ, Hung IFN, Ip MSM, Ip P, Lau KK, Lau CS, Lau LKW, Leung WK, Li X, Luo H, Man KKC, Ng VWS, Siu CW, Wan EYF, Wing YK, Wong CSM, Wong KHT, Wong ICK. Short- and potential long-term adverse health outcomes of COVID-19: a rapid review. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2020;9(1):2190&#x2013;2199. doi: 10.1080/22221751.2020.1825914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/22221751.2020.1825914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7586446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32940572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker-Davies RM, O'Sullivan O, Senaratne KPP, Baker P, Cranley M, Dharm-Datta S, Ellis H, Goodall D, Gough M, Lewis S, Norman J, Papadopoulou T, Roscoe D, Sherwood D, Turner P, Walker T, Mistlin A, Phillip R, Nicol AM, Bennett AN, Bahadur S. The Stanford hall consensus statement for post-COVID-19 rehabilitation. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(16):949&#x2013;959. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2020-102596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-102596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7418628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32475821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liebl ME, Gutenbrunner C, Glaesener JJ, Schwarzkopf S, Best N, Lichti G, Kraft E, Krischak G, Rei&#xdf;hauer A. Fr&#xfc;he Rehabilitation bei COVID-19 &#x2013; Best Practice Empfehlungen f&#xfc;r die fr&#xfc;he Rehabilitation von Patient/innen mit COVID-19. Phys Rehab Kur Med. 2020;30(03):129&#x2013;134. doi: 10.1055/a-1162-4919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1162-4919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutenbrunner C, Stokes EK, Dreinh&#xf6;fer K, Monsbakken J, Clarke S, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, et al. Why Rehabilitation must have priority during and after the COVID-19-pandemic: A position statement of the Global Rehabilitation Alliance. J Rehabil Med. 2020;52(7):jrm00081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32719884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson R, Robinson L. Rehabilitation after critical illness in people with COVID-19 infection. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2020;99(6):470&#x2013;474. doi: 10.1097/PHM.0000000000001443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000001443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7253039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32282359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemh&#xf6;fer C, Gutenbrunner C, Best N, Loudovici-Krug D, Schiller J, B&#xf6;kel A, et al. Assessment of rehabilitation needs in patients during and after COVID-19 &#x2013; development of the COVID-19-rehabilitation needs survey (C19-RehabNeS) J Rehabil Med. 2021;53(4):jrm00183. doi: 10.2340/16501977-2818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/16501977-2818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8814869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33764478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morfeld M, Bullinger M, Kirchberger I. Fragebogen zum Gesundheitszustand: SF-36; deutsche Version des Short form-36 health survey.&#xa0;G&#xf6;ttingen: Hogrefe; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi S, Reddy S, Gholamrezanezhad A. Long-term pulmonary consequences of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): what we know and what to expect. J Thorac Imaging. 2020;35(4):W87&#x2013;W89. doi: 10.1097/RTI.0000000000000534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RTI.0000000000000534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32404798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasgupta A, Kalhan A, Kalra S. Long term complications and rehabilitation of COVID-19 patients. J Pak Med Assoc. 2020;70(Suppl 3-5):S131&#x2013;S135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32515393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenzen-Schulte M. Long COVID: Der lange Schatten von COVID-19. Dtsch Arztebl International. 2020;117(49):A&#x2013;2416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson KB, Rao M, Bonilla H, Subramanian A, Hack I, Madrigal M, Singh U, Jagannathan P, Grant P. Patients with uncomplicated COVID-19 have long-term persistent symptoms and functional impairment similar to patients with severe COVID-19: a cautionary tale during a global pandemic. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73(3):e826&#x2013;e829. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciab103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33624010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Kream RM, Stefano GB. Long-term respiratory and neurological sequelae of COVID-19. Med Sci Monit. 2020;26:e928996. doi: 10.12659/MSM.928996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.928996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7643287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33177481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosain R, Miller K. Symptoms and symptom management in long-term cancer survivors. Cancer J. 2013;19(5):405&#x2013;409. doi: 10.1097/01.PPO.0000434391.11187.c3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.PPO.0000434391.11187.c3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24051613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A, Singh RS, Sarma P, Batra G, Joshi R, Kaur H, Sharma AR, Prakash A, Medhi B. A comprehensive review of animal models for coronaviruses: SARS-CoV-2, SARS-CoV, and MERS-CoV. Virol Sin. 2020;35(3):290&#x2013;304. doi: 10.1007/s12250-020-00252-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12250-020-00252-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7324485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32607866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belli S, Balbi B, Prince I, Cattaneo D, Masocco F, Zaccaria S, Bertalli L, Cattini F, Lomazzo A, Dal Negro F, Giardini M, Franssen FME, Janssen DJA, Spruit MA. Low physical functioning and impaired performance of activities of daily life in COVID-19 patients who survived hospitalisation. Eur Respir J. 2020;56(4):56. doi: 10.1183/13993003.02096-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02096-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7411272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32764112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwek S-K, Chew W-M, Ong K-C, Ng AW-K, Lee LS-U, Kaw G, Leow MKS. Quality of life and psychological status in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome at 3 months postdischarge. J Psychosom Res. 2006;60(5):513&#x2013;519. doi: 10.1016/j.jpsychores.2005.08.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2005.08.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16650592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowdy DW, Eid MP, Dennison CR, Mendez-Tellez PA, Herridge MS, Guallar E, Pronovost PJ, Needham DM. Quality of life after acute respiratory distress syndrome: a meta-analysis. Intensive Care Med. 2006;32(8):1115&#x2013;1124. doi: 10.1007/s00134-006-0217-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-006-0217-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16783553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo MS, Malsy J, P&#xf6;ttgen J, Seddiq Zai S, Ufer F, Hadjilaou A, et al. Frequent neurocognitive deficits after recovery from mild COVID-19. Brain Commun. 2020;2(2):fcaa205. doi: 10.1093/braincomms/fcaa205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/braincomms/fcaa205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33376990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re'em Y, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L'hoest H, Acar L, Osterkamp N, Marschall U. bifg- Analyse zu Arbeitsf&#xe4;higkieten wegen COVID-19 und Post-COVID Symptomen; 2021 [cited 2021 Jun 30]. Available from: URL: http://docs.dpaq.de/17738-20210616_bifg_epaper_post-covid_bf.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirulli ET, Schiabor Barrett KM, Riffle S, Bolze A, Neveux I, Dabe S, et al. Long-term COVID-19 symptoms in a large unselected population. 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>