<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38527781</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2093-2340</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Infection &amp; chemotherapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Infect Chemother</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Updated Clinical Practice Guidelines for the Diagnosis and Management of Long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>122</StartPage><EndPage>157</EndPage><MedlinePgn>122-157</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3947/ic.2024.0024</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>"Long COVID" is a term used to describe a condition when the symptoms and signs associated with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) persist for more than three months among patients infected with COVID-19; this condition has been reported globally and poses a serious public health issue. Long COVID can manifest in various forms, highlighting the need for appropriate evaluation and management by experts from various fields. However, due to the lack of clear clinical definitions, knowledge of pathophysiology, diagnostic methods, and treatment protocols, it is necessary to develop the best standard clinical guidelines based on the scientific evidence reported to date. We developed this clinical guideline for diagnosing and treating long COVID by analyzing the latest research data collected from the start of the COVID-19 pandemic until June 2023, along with the consensus of expert opinions. This guideline provides recommendations for diagnosis and treatment that can be applied in clinical practice, based on a total of 32 key questions related to patients with long COVID. The evaluation of patients with long COVID should be comprehensive, including medical history, physical examination, blood tests, imaging studies, and functional tests. To reduce the risk of developing long COVID, vaccination and antiviral treatment during the acute phase are recommended. This guideline will be revised when there is a reasonable need for updates based on the availability of new knowledge on the diagnosis and treatment of long COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 by The Korean Society of Infectious Diseases, Korean Society for Antimicrobial Therapy, and The Korean Society for AIDS.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seo</LastName><ForeName>Jun-Won</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2806-1863</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, College of Medicine, Chosun University, Gwangju, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Seong Eun</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0162-6155</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Chonnam National University Medical School, Gwangju, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Yoonjung</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7454-4014</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, School of Medicine, Kyungpook National University, Kyungpook National University Hospital, Daegu, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Eun Jung</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2352-5267</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health, Welfare, Family and Gender Equality Team, National Assembly Research Service, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Tark</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8829-4183</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Soonchunhyang University Bucheon Hospital, Bucheon, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Taehwa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3722-0261</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonology, Allergy and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Pusan National University Yangsan Hospital, Yangsan, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>So Hee</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9005-3207</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, National Medical Center, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Eunjung</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7724-8288</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Soonchunhyang University Seoul Hospital, Soonchunhyang University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jacob</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7041-065X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Kangnam Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seo</LastName><ForeName>Yu Bin</ForeName><Initials>YB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5183-1996</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Kangnam Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeong</LastName><ForeName>Young-Hoon</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0403-3726</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CAU Thrombosis and Biomarker Center, Chung-Ang University Gwangmyeong Hospital, Gwangmyeong, and Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Chung-Ang University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jung</LastName><ForeName>Young Hee</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8945-2200</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Myongji Hospital, Hanyang University College of Medicine, Goyang, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Yu Jung</ForeName><Initials>YJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-1933-5843</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Korea University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Joon Young</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0148-7194</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Korea University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea. infection@korea.ac.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>HD22C2045</GrantID><Agency>Korea Health Industry Development Institute</Agency><Country>Republic of Korea</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Infect Chemother</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101531537</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1598-8112</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Persistent symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-COVID condition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>JYS is editorial board of Infect Chemother; however, he did not involve in the peer reviewer selection, evaluation, and decision process of this article. Otherwise, no potential conflicts of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38527781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10990882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3947/ic.2024.0024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">56.e11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. London: NICE; 2020. Dec 18,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin D, Moschopoulos CD, Margalit I, Gkrania-Klotsas E, Landi F, Stahl JP, Yahav D. ESCMID rapid guidelines for assessment and management of long COVID. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28:955&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8849856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35182760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health (NIH) Long COVID.  [Accessed 28 September 2023].  Available at:  https://covid19.nih.gov/covid-19-topics/long-covid#what-is-long-covid?-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Kim SE, Kim T, Yun KW, Lee SH, Lee E, Seo JW, Jung YH, Chong YP. Preliminary guidelines for the clinical evaluation and management of long COVID. Infect Chemother. 2022;54:566&#x2013;597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9533168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36196612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis. 2022;226:1593&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet. 2022;399:2263&#x2013;2264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35717982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Zhang L, Zhang Y, Chen G, Wang D, Chen X, Wang Z, Wang J, Che X, Horita N, Seki N. Prevalence and clinical features of long COVID from omicron infection in children and adults. J Infect. 2023;86:e97&#x2013;e99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36803675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng N, Zhao YM, Yan W, Li C, Lu QD, Liu L, Ni SY, Mei H, Yuan K, Shi L, Li P, Fan TT, Yuan JL, Vitiello MV, Kosten T, Kondratiuk AL, Sun HQ, Tang XD, Liu MY, Lalvani A, Shi J, Bao YP, Lu L. A systematic review and meta-analysis of long term physical and mental sequelae of COVID-19 pandemic: call for research priority and action. Mol Psychiatry. 2023;28:423&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9168643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35668159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Kim SW, Chang HH, Kwon KT, Hwang S, Bae S. One year follow-up of COVID-19 related symptoms and patient quality of life: a prospective cohort study. Yonsei Med J. 2022;63:499&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9171672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35619573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Bitna-Ha, Kim SW, Chang HH, Kwon KT, Bae S, Hwang S. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome in patients after 12 months from COVID-19 infection in Korea. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22:93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8793328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35086489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Burden of Disease Long COVID Collaborators , Wulf Hanson S, Abbafati C, Aerts JG, Al-Aly Z, Ashbaugh C, Ballouz T, Blyuss O, Bobkova P, Bonsel G, Borzakova S, Buonsenso D, Butnaru D, Carter A, Chu H, De Rose C, Diab MM, Ekbom E, El Tantawi M, Fomin V, Frithiof R, Gamirova A, Glybochko PV, Haagsma JA, Haghjooy Javanmard S, Hamilton EB, Harris G, Heijenbrok-Kal MH, Helbok R, Hellemons ME, Hillus D, Huijts SM, Hultstr&#xf6;m M, Jassat W, Kurth F, Larsson IM, Lipcsey M, Liu C, Loflin CD, Malinovschi A, Mao W, Mazankova L, McCulloch D, Menges D, Mohammadifard N, Munblit D, Nekliudov NA, Ogbuoji O, Osmanov IM, Pe&#xf1;alvo JL, Petersen MS, Puhan MA, Rahman M, Rass V, Reinig N, Ribbers GM, Ricchiuto A, Rubertsson S, Samitova E, Sarrafzadegan N, Shikhaleva A, Simpson KE, Sinatti D, Soriano JB, Spiridonova E, Steinbeis F, Svistunov AA, Valentini P, van de Water BJ, van den Berg-Emons R, Wallin E, Witzenrath M, Wu Y, Xu H, Zoller T, Adolph C, Albright J, Amlag JO, Aravkin AY, Bang-Jensen BL, Bisignano C, Castellano R, Castro E, Chakrabarti S, Collins JK, Dai X, Daoud F, Dapper C, Deen A, Duncan BB, Erickson M, Ewald SB, Ferrari AJ, Flaxman AD, Fullman N, Gamkrelidze A, Giles JR, Guo G, Hay SI, He J, Helak M, Hulland EN, Kereselidze M, Krohn KJ, Lazzar-Atwood A, Lindstrom A, Lozano R, Malta DC, M&#xe5;nsson J, Mantilla Herrera AM, Mokdad AH, Monasta L, Nomura S, Pasovic M, Pigott DM, Reiner RC, Jr, Reinke G, Ribeiro ALP, Santomauro DF, Sholokhov A, Spurlock EE, Walcott R, Walker A, Wiysonge CS, Zheng P, Bettger JP, Murray CJL, Vos T. Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA. 2022;328:1604&#x2013;1615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampasian V, Elghazaly H, Chattopadhyay R, Debski M, Naing TK, Garg P, Clark A, Ntatsaki E, Vassiliou VS. Risk factors associated with post-COVID-19 condition: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Intern Med. 2023;183:566&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10037203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Kim SW, Chang HH, Kwon KT, Bae S, Hwang S. Significance and associated factors of long-term sequelae in patients after acute COVID-19 infection in Korea. Infect Chemother. 2021;53:463&#x2013;476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8511373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34405592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su S, Zhao Y, Zeng N, Liu X, Zheng Y, Sun J, Zhong Y, Wu S, Ni S, Gong Y, Zhang Z, Gao N, Yuan K, Yan W, Shi L, Ravindran AV, Kosten T, Shi J, Bao Y, Lu L. Epidemiology, clinical presentation, pathophysiology, and management of long COVID: an update. Mol Psychiatry. 2023;28:4056&#x2013;4069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37491461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Acute and postacute sequelae associated with SARS-CoV-2 reinfection. Nat Med. 2022;28:2398&#x2013;2405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9671810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36357676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Casals M, Brito-Zer&#xf3;n P, Mariette X. Systemic and organ-specific immune-related manifestations of COVID-19. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2021;17:315&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33903743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley SE, Karlson EW, Levitan EB, Levy B, McComsey GA, McCorkell L, Nadkarni GN, Parthasarathy S, Singh U, Walker TA, Selvaggi CA, Shinnick DJ, Schulte CC, Atchley-Challenner R, Alba GA, Alicic R, Altman N, Anglin K, Argueta U, Ashktorab H, Baslet G, Bassett IV, Bateman L, Bedi B, Bhattacharyya S, Bind MA, Blomkalns AL, Bonilla H, Bush PA, Castro M, Chan J, Charney AW, Chen P, Chibnik LB, Chu HY, Clifton RG, Costantine MM, Cribbs SK, Davila Nieves SI, Deeks SG, Duven A, Emery IF, Erdmann N, Erlandson KM, Ernst KC, Farah-Abraham R, Farner CE, Feuerriegel EM, Fleurimont J, Fonseca V, Franko N, Gainer V, Gander JC, Gardner EM, Geng LN, Gibson KS, Go M, Goldman JD, Grebe H, Greenway FL, Habli M, Hafner J, Han JE, Hanson KA, Heath J, Hernandez C, Hess R, Hodder SL, Hoffman MK, Hoover SE, Huang B, Hughes BL, Jagannathan P, John J, Jordan MR, Katz SD, Kaufman ES, Kelly JD, Kelly SW, Kemp MM, Kirwan JP, Klein JD, Knox KS, Krishnan JA, Kumar A, Laiyemo AO, Lambert AA, Lanca M, Lee-Iannotti JK, Logarbo BP, Longo MT, Luciano CA, Lutrick K, Maley JH, Marathe JG, Marconi V, Marshall GD, Martin CF, Matusov Y, Mehari A, Mendez-Figueroa H, Mermelstein R, Metz TD, Morse R, Mosier J, Mouchati C, Mullington J, Murphy SN, Neuman RB, Nikolich JZ, Ofotokun I, Ojemakinde E, Palatnik A, Palomares K, Parimon T, Parry S, Patterson JE, Patterson TF, Patzer RE, Peluso MJ, Pemu P, Pettker CM, Plunkett BA, Pogreba-Brown K, Poppas A, Quigley JG, Reddy U, Reece R, Reeder H, Reeves WB, Reiman EM, Rischard F, Rosand J, Rouse DJ, Ruff A, Saade G, Sandoval GJ, Schlater SM, Shepherd F, Sherif ZA, Simhan H, Singer NG, Skupski DW, Sowles A, Sparks JA, Sukhera FI, Taylor BS, Teunis L, Thomas RJ, Thorp JM, Thuluvath P, Ticotsky A, Tita AT, Tuttle KR, Urdaneta AE, Valdivieso D, VanWagoner TM, Vasey A, Verduzco-Gutierrez M, Wallace ZS, Ward HD, Warren DE, Weiner SJ, Welch S, Whiteheart SW, Wiley Z, Wisnivesky JP, Yee LM, Zisis S, Horwitz LI, Foulkes AS RECOVER Consortium. RECOVER Consortium. Development of a definition of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA. 2023;329:1934&#x2013;1946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10214179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Bae S, Chang HH, Kim SW. Long COVID prevalence and impact on quality of life 2 years after acute COVID-19. Sci Rep. 2023;13:11207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10336045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37433819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Cancela-Cilleruelo I, Guerrero-Peral A, Mart&#xed;n-Guerrero JD, Garc&#xed;a-Azor&#xed;n D, Cornejo-Mazzuchelli A, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Barrera V, Pellicer-Valero OJ. Post-COVID-19 symptoms 2 years after SARS-CoV-2 infection among hospitalized vs nonhospitalized patients. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:e2242106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9667330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36378309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao X, Guan Y, Liao Q, Ma Z, Zhang L, Dong J, Lai X, Zheng G, Yang S, Wang C, Liao Z, Song S, Yi H, Lu H. Long-term sequelae of different COVID-19 variants: The original strain versus the Omicron variant. Glob Health Med. 2022;4:322&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9773225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Lee S, Alfaro-Almagro F, Arthofer C, Wang C, McCarthy P, Lange F, Andersson JL, Griffanti L, Duff E, Jbabdi S, Taschler B, Keating P, Winkler AM, Collins R, Matthews PM, Allen N, Miller KL, Nichols TE, Smith SM. SARS-CoV-2 is associated with changes in brain structure in UK Biobank. Nature. 2022;604:697&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9046077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) Clinical management of COVID-19: Living guideline,Jun 23 2022.  [Accessed 18 August 2023].  Available at:  https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-2019-nCoV-clinical-2023.2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35917394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng B, Daines L, Han Q, Hurst JR, Pfeffer P, Shankar-Hari M, Elneima O, Walker S, Brown JS, Siddiqui S, Quint JK, Brightling CE, Evans RA, Wain LV, Heaney LG, Sheikh A. Prevalence, risk factors and treatments for post-COVID-19 breathlessness: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur Respir Rev. 2022;31:220071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9724798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36323418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faverio P, Luppi F, Rebora P, D&#x2019;Andrea G, Stainer A, Busnelli S, Catalano M, Modafferi G, Franco G, Monzani A, Galimberti S, Scarpazza P, Oggionni E, Betti M, Oggionni T, De Giacomi F, Bini F, Bodini BD, Parati M, Bilucaglia L, Ceruti P, Modina D, Harari S, Caminati A, Intotero M, Sergio P, Monzillo G, Leati G, Borghesi A, Zompatori M, Corso R, Valsecchi MG, Bellani G, Foti G, Pesci A. One-year pulmonary impairment after severe COVID-19: a prospective, multicenter follow-up study. Respir Res. 2022;23:65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8934910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35313890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kersten J, Wolf A, Hoyo L, H&#xfc;ll E, Tadic M, Andre&#xdf; S, d&#x2019;Almeida S, Scharnbeck D, Roder E, Beschoner P, Rottbauer W, Buckert D. Symptom burden correlates to impairment of diffusion capacity and exercise intolerance in long COVID patients. Sci Rep. 2022;12:8801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9130688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35614108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durstenfeld MS, Sun K, Tahir P, Peluso MJ, Deeks SG, Aras MA, Grandis DJ, Long CS, Beatty A, Hsue PY. Use of cardiopulmonary exercise testing to evaluate long COVID-19 symptoms in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:e2236057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9557896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36223120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satterfield BA, Bhatt DL, Gersh BJ. Cardiac involvement in the long-term implications of COVID-19. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2022;19:332&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8532434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34686843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Committee Members. Gulati M, Levy PD, Mukherjee D, Amsterdam E, Bhatt DL, Birtcher KK, Blankstein R, Boyd J, Bullock-Palmer RP, Conejo T, Diercks DB, Gentile F, Greenwood JP, Hess EP, Hollenberg SM, Jaber WA, Jneid H, Joglar JA, Morrow DA, O'Connor RE, Ross MA, Shaw LJ. 2021 AHA/ACC/ASE/CHEST/SAEM/SCCT/SCMR guideline for the evaluation and diagnosis of chest pain: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association joint committee on clinical practice guidelines. J Cardiovasc Comput Tomogr. 2022;16:54&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34955448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou LP, Yu LL, Jiang H. Interpretation of the 2022 ACC expert consensus decision pathway on cardiovascular sequelae of COVID-19 in adults: myocarditis and other myocardial involvement, post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection, and return to play. Zhonghua Xin Xue Guan Bing Za Zhi. 2023;51:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36800696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteson JH, Azola A, Barry JT, Bartels MN, Blitshteyn S, Fleming TK, McCauley MD, Neal JD, Pillarisetti J, Sampsel S, Silver JK, Terzic CM, Tosto J, Verduzco-Gutierrez M, Putrino D. Multi-disciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of cardiovascular complications in patients with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) PM R. 2022;14:855&#x2013;878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9347705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35657351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuin M, Rigatelli G, Bilato C, Porcari A, Merlo M, Roncon L, Sinagra G. One-year risk of myocarditis after COVID-19 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Can J Cardiol. 2023;39:839&#x2013;844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9743686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36521730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song WJ, Hui CK, Hull JH, Birring SS, McGarvey L, Mazzone SB, Chung KF. Confronting COVID-19-associated cough and the post-COVID syndrome: role of viral neurotropism, neuroinflammation, and neuroimmune responses. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:533&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8041436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33857435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song DJ, Song WJ, Kwon JW, Kim GW, Kim MA, Kim MY, Kim MH, Kim SH, Kim SH, Kim SH, Kim ST, Kim SH, Kim JK, Kim JH, Kim HJ, Kim HB, Park KH, Yoon JK, Lee BJ, Lee SE, Lee YM, Lee YJ, Lim KH, Jeon YH, Jo EJ, Jee YK, Jin HJ, Choi SH, Hur GY, Cho SH, Kim SH, Lim DH. KAAACI evidence-based clinical practice guidelines for chronic cough in adults and children in Korea. Allergy Asthma Immunol Res. 2018;10:591&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6182199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30306744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morice AH, Millqvist E, Bieksiene K, Birring SS, Dicpinigaitis P, Domingo Ribas C, Hilton Boon M, Kantar A, Lai K, McGarvey L, Rigau D, Satia I, Smith J, Song WJ, Tonia T, van den Berg JW, van Manen MJ, Zacharasiewicz A. ERS guidelines on the diagnosis and treatment of chronic cough in adults and children. Eur Respir J. 2020;55:1901136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6942543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31515408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang YR, Huh JY, Oh JY, Lee JH, Lee D, Kwon HS, Kim TB, Choi JC, Cho YS, Chung KF, Park SY, Song WJ. Clinical characteristics of post-COVID-19 persistent cough in the Omicron era. Allergy Asthma Immunol Res. 2023;15:395&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10186121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37075801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao S, Benzouak T, Gunpat S, Burns RJ, Tahir TA, Jolles S, Kisely S. Fatigue symptoms associated with COVID-19 in convalescent or recovered COVID-19 patients; a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Behav Med. 2022;56:219&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8574547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34665858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aaronson LS, Teel CS, Cassmeyer V, Neuberger GB, Pallikkathayil L, Pierce J, Press AN, Williams PD, Wingate A. Defining and measuring fatigue. Image J Nurs Sch. 1999;31:45&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10081212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoshijima H, Mihara T, Seki H, Hyuga S, Kuratani N, Shiga T. Incidence of long-term post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection related to pain and other symptoms: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2023;18:e0250909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10686440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38019841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cares-Marambio K, Montenegro-Jim&#xe9;nez Y, Torres-Castro R, Vera-Uribe R, Torralba Y, Alsina-Restoy X, Vasconcello-Castillo L, Vilar&#xf3; J. Prevalence of potential respiratory symptoms in survivors of hospital admission after coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): A systematic review and meta-analysis. Chron Respir Dis. 2021;18:14799731211002240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7975482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33729021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik P, Patel K, Pinto C, Jaiswal R, Tirupathi R, Pillai S, Patel U. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PCS) and health-related quality of life (HRQoL)-A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2022;94:253&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34463956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a M, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez J, de-la-Llave-Rinc&#xf3;n AI, Velasco-Arribas M, Fuensalida-Novo S, Ambite-Quesada S, Guijarro C, Cuadrado ML, Florencio LL, Arias-Naval&#xf3;n JA, Ortega-Santiago R, Elvira-Mart&#xed;nez CM, Molina-Trigueros LJ, Torres-Macho J, Sebasti&#xe1;n-Viana T, Canto-Diez MG, Cigar&#xe1;n-M&#xe9;ndez M, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Barrera V, Arendt-Nielsen L. Fatigue and dyspnoea as main persistent post-COVID-19 symptoms in previously hospitalized patients: related functional limitations and disability. Respiration. 2022;101:132&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8678253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34569550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boari GE, Bonetti S, Braglia-Orlandini F, Chiarini G, Faustini C, Bianco G, Santagiuliana M, Guarinoni V, Saottini M, Viola S, Ferrari-Toninelli G, Pasini G, Bonzi B, Desenzani P, Tusi C, Malerba P, Zanotti E, Turini D, Rizzoni D. Short-term consequences of SARS-CoV-2-related pneumonia: a follow up study. High Blood Press Cardiovasc Prev. 2021;28:373&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8080190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33909284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horwitz LI, Garry K, Prete AM, Sharma S, Mendoza F, Kahan T, Karpel H, Duan E, Hochman KA, Weerahandi H. Six-month outcomes in patients hospitalized with severe COVID-19. J Gen Intern Med. 2021;36:3772&#x2013;3777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8341831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34355349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik S, Haldar SN, Soneja M, Mundadan NG, Garg P, Mittal A, Desai D, Trilangi PK, Chakraborty S, Begam NN, Bhattacharya B, Maher G, Mahishi N, Rajanna C, Kumar SS, Arunan B, Kirtana J, Gupta A, Patidar D, Kodan P, Sethi P, Ray A, Jorwal P, Kumar A, Nischal N, Sinha S, Biswas A, Wig N. Post COVID-19 sequelae: A prospective observational study from Northern India. Drug Discov Ther. 2021;15:254&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34719599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera JA, Yang D, Lewis A, Patel P, Medicherla C, Arena V, Fang T, Andino A, Snyder T, Madhavan M, Gratch D, Fuchs B, Dessy A, Canizares M, Jauregui R, Thomas B, Bauman K, Olivera A, Bhagat D, Sonson M, Park G, Stainman R, Sunwoo B, Talmasov D, Tamimi M, Zhu Y, Rosenthal J, Dygert L, Ristic M, Ishii H, Valdes E, Omari M, Gurin L, Huang J, Czeisler BM, Kahn DE, Zhou T, Lin J, Lord AS, Melmed K, Meropol S, Troxel AB, Petkova E, Wisniewski T, Balcer L, Morrison C, Yaghi S, Galetta S. A prospective study of long-term outcomes among hospitalized COVID-19 patients with and without neurological complications. J Neurol Sci. 2021;426:117486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8113108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34000678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Garg I, Iqbal A, Talpur AS, Ma&#xf1;ego AM, Kavuri RK, Bachani P, Naz S, Iqbal ZQ. Long-Term X-ray findings in patients with coronavirus disease-2019. Cureus. 2021;13:e15304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8236307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34211809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozak R, Armstrong SM, Salvant E, Ritzker C, Feld J, Biondi MJ, Tsui H. Recognition of long-COVID-19 patients in a Canadian tertiary hospital setting: a retrospective analysis of their clinical and laboratory characteristics. Pathogens. 2021;10:1246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8537802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34684195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Wu D, Yan W, Wang X, Zhang X, Ma K, Chen H, Zeng Z, Qin Y, Wang H, Xing M, Xu D, Li W, Ni M, Zhu L, Chen L, Chen G, Qi W, Wu T, Yu H, Huang J, Han M, Zhu W, Guo W, Luo X, Chen T, Ning Q. Twelve-month systemic consequences of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in patients discharged from hospital: a prospective cohort study in Wuhan, China. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;74:1953&#x2013;1965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9187317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34390330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F, Tomasoni D, Falcinella C, Barbanotti D, Castoldi R, Mul&#xe8; G, Augello M, Mondatore D, Allegrini M, Cona A, Tesoro D, Tagliaferri G, Vigan&#xf2; O, Suardi E, Tincati C, Beringheli T, Varisco B, Battistini CL, Piscopo K, Vegni E, Tavelli A, Terzoni S, Marchetti G, Monforte AD. Female gender is associated with long COVID syndrome: a prospective cohort study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28:611.e9&#x2013;611.16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellemons ME, Huijts S, Bek LM, Berentschot JC, Nakshbandi G, Schurink CA, Vlake JH, van Genderen ME, van Bommel J, Gommers D, Odink A, Ciet P, Shamier MC, Geurts van Kessel C, Baart SJ, Ribbers GM, van den Berg-Emons RJ, Heijenbrok-Kal MH, Aerts JG. Persistent health problems beyond pulmonary recovery up to 6 months after hospitalization for COVID-19: a longitudinal study of respiratory, physical, and psychological outcomes. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2022;19:551&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8996273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardo MD, Foppiani A, Peretti GM, Mangiavini L, Battezzati A, Bertoli S, Martinelli Boneschi F, Zuccotti GV. Long-term coronavirus disease 2019 complications in inpatients and outpatients: a one-year follow-up cohort study. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8:ofab384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8344801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34386546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty SE, Guo Y, Heath K, Dasmari&#xf1;as MC, Jubilo KG, Samranvedhya J, Lipsitch M, Cohen K. Risk of clinical sequelae after the acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2021;373:n1098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8132065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yomogida K, Zhu S, Rubino F, Figueroa W, Balanji N, Holman E. Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection among adults aged &#x2265;18 years - Long Beach, California, April 1-December 10, 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2021;70:1274&#x2013;1277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8445372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34529639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karaarslan F, Demircio&#x11f;lu G&#xfc;neri F, Karde&#x15f; S. Postdischarge rheumatic and musculoskeletal symptoms following hospitalization for COVID-19: prospective follow-up by phone interviews. Rheumatol Int. 2021;41:1263&#x2013;1271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8114015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33978818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain MA, Hossain KM, Saunders K, Uddin Z, Walton LM, Raigangar V, Sakel M, Shafin R, Hossain MS, Kabir MF, Faruqui R, Rana MS, Ahmed MS, Chakrovorty SK, Hossain MA, Jahid IK. Prevalence of Long COVID symptoms in Bangladesh: a prospective Inception Cohort Study of COVID-19 survivors. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6:e006838</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8671853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34906986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staudt A, J&#xf6;rres RA, Hinterberger T, Lehnen N, Loew T, Budweiser S. Associations of Post-Acute COVID syndrome with physiological and clinical measures 10 months after hospitalization in patients of the first wave. Eur J Intern Med. 2022;95:50&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8612867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34838369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daynes E, Gerlis C, Chaplin E, Gardiner N, Singh SJ. Early experiences of rehabilitation for individuals post-COVID to improve fatigue, breathlessness exercise capacity and cognition - A cohort study. Chron Respir Dis. 2021;18:14799731211015691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8114752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33957805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gawron VJ. Overview of self-reported measures of fatigue. Int J Aerosp Psychol. 2016;26:120&#x2013;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee on the Diagnostic Criteria for Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome; Board on the Health of Select Populations. Institute of Medicine. Beyond myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: redefining an illness. Washington, DC: National Academies Press (US); 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25695122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antoniou KM, Vasarmidi E, Russell AM, Andrejak C, Crestani B, Delcroix M, Dinh-Xuan AT, Poletti V, Sverzellati N, Vitacca M, Witzenrath M, Tonia T, Spanevello A. European Respiratory Society statement on long COVID follow-up. Eur Respir J. 2022;60:2102174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9349784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35144991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melamed E, Rydberg L, Ambrose AF, Bhavaraju-Sanka R, Fine JS, Fleming TK, Herman E, Phipps Johnson JL, Kucera JR, Longo M, Niehaus W, Oleson CV, Sampsel S, Silver JK, Smith MM, Verduzco-Gutierrez M. Multidisciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of neurologic sequelae in patients with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) PM R. 2023;15:640&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36989078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings G, Monaghan A, Xue F, Mockler D, Romero-Ortu&#xf1;o R. A systematic review of persistent symptoms and residual abnormal functioning following acute COVID-19: ongoing symptomatic phase vs. post-COVID-19 syndrome. J Clin Med. 2021;10:5913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8708187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34945213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, Cheng V, Dagens A, Hastie C, O&#x2019;Hara M, Suett J, Dahmash D, Bugaeva P, Rigby I, Munblit D, Harriss E, Burls A, Foote C, Scott J, Carson G, Olliaro P, Sigfrid L, Stavropoulou C. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6:e005427</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, Plaza-Manzano G, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, Arendt-Nielsen L. Time course prevalence of post-COVID pain symptoms of musculoskeletal origin in patients who had survived severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pain. 2022;163:1220&#x2013;1231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34561390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agergaard J, Leth S, Pedersen TH, Harbo T, Blicher JU, Karlsson P, &#xd8;stergaard L, Andersen H, Tankisi H. Myopathic changes in patients with long-term fatigue after COVID-19. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132:1974&#x2013;1981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8102077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34020890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martelletti P, Bentivegna E, Spuntarelli V, Luciani M. Long-COVID Headache. SN Compr Clin Med. 2021;3:1704&#x2013;1706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8136258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34036244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premraj L, Kannapadi NV, Briggs J, Seal SM, Battaglini D, Fanning J, Suen J, Robba C, Fraser J, Cho SM. Mid and long-term neurological and neuropsychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 syndrome: A meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci. 2022;434:120162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8798975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolay H, G&#xfc;l A, Baykan B. COVID-19 is a real headache! Headache. 2020;60:1415&#x2013;1421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32412101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Mitoma F, Vanast WJ, Tyrrell DL. Increased frequency of Epstein-Barr virus excretion in patients with new daily persistent headaches. Lancet. 1987;1:411&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2880216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozen TD. Daily persistent headache after a viral illness during a worldwide pandemic may not be a new occurrence: Lessons from the 1890 Russian/Asiatic flu. Cephalalgia. 2020;40:1406&#x2013;1409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7645599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33146034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sis&#xf3;-Almirall A, Brito-Zer&#xf3;n P, Conangla Ferr&#xed;n L, Kostov B, Moragas Moreno A, Mestres J, Sellar&#xe8;s J, Galindo G, Morera R, Basora J, Trilla A, Ramos-Casals M On Behalf Of The CAMFiC Long Covid-Study Group. Long Covid-19: proposed primary care clinical guidelines for diagnosis and disease management. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:4350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33923972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine JS, Ambrose AF, Didehbani N, Fleming TK, Glashan L, Longo M, Merlino A, Ng R, Nora GJ, Rolin S, Silver JK, Terzic CM, Verduzco-Gutierrez M, Sampsel S. Multi-disciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of cognitive symptoms in patients with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) PM R. 2022;14:96&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34902226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung YH, Ha EH, Park J, Choe KW, Lee WJ, Jo DH. Neurological and psychiatric manifestations of post-COVID-19 conditions. J Korean Med Sci. 2023;38:e83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10027539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36942392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurek M, Rayner C, Freyer A, Taylor S, J&#xe4;rte L, MacDermott N, Delaney BC Delphi panellists. Recommendations for the recognition, diagnosis, and management of long COVID: a Delphi study. Br J Gen Pract. 2021;71:e815&#x2013;e825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8510689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34607799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel UK, Mehta N, Patel A, Patel N, Ortiz JF, Khurana M, Urhoghide E, Parulekar A, Bhriguvanshi A, Patel N, Mistry AM, Patel R, Arumaithurai K, Shah S. Long-term neurological sequelae among severe COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cureus. 2022;14:e29694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9616013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36321004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan N, Lv ZH, Sun CR, Wen YY, Tao TY, Qian D, Tao FP, Yu JH. Post-acute COVID-19 symptom risk in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1112383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9978404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36875356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteside DM, Basso MR, Naini SM, Porter J, Holker E, Waldron EJ, Melnik TE, Niskanen N, Taylor SE. Outcomes in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) at 6 months post-infection Part 1: Cognitive functioning. Clin Neuropsychol. 2022;36:806&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35130818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Li F, Fortunati F, Krystal JH. Association of a prior psychiatric diagnosis with mortality among hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3:e2023282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7527869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32997123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosey MM, Needham DM. Survivorship after COVID-19 ICU stay. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2020;6:60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7362322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32669623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Geddes JR, Husain M, Luciano S, Harrison PJ. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236&#x2009;379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:416&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8023694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng J, Zhou F, Hou W, Silver Z, Wong CY, Chang O, Huang E, Zuo QK. The prevalence of depression, anxiety, and sleep disturbances in COVID-19 patients: a meta-analysis. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2021;1486:90&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33009668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehinejad MA, Azarkolah A, Ghanavati E, Nitsche MA. Circadian disturbances, sleep difficulties and the COVID-19 pandemic. Sleep Med. 2022;91:246&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8277544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34334305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinvararak C, Chalder T. Prevalence of sleep disturbances in patients with long COVID assessed by standardised questionnaires and diagnostic criteria: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Psychosom Res. 2023;175:111535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37898059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourne RS, Mills GH. Sleep disruption in critically ill patients--pharmacological considerations. Anaesthesia. 2004;59:374&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15023109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben&#xed;tez ID, Moncus&#xed;-Moix A, Vaca R, Gort-Paniello C, Minguez O, Santisteve S, Carmona P, Torres G, Fagotti J, Labarca G, Torres A, Gonz&#xe1;lez J, de Gonzalo-Calvo D, Barb&#xe9; F, Targa AD. Sleep and circadian health of critical COVID-19 survivors 3 months after hospital discharge. Crit Care Med. 2022;50:945&#x2013;954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9112507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35234413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Campion JY, Dudouet P, Kaphan E, Bregeon F, Tissot-Dupont H, Guis S, Barthelemy F, Habert P, Ceccaldi M, Million M, Raoult D, Cammilleri S, Eldin C. 18F-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in patients with long COVID. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48:2823&#x2013;2833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33501506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles A, Brodsky MB. Current opinion of presentation of dysphagia and dysphonia in patients with coronavirus disease 2019. Curr Opin Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2022;30:393&#x2013;399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9612417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36004777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoyagi Y, Inamoto Y, Shibata S, Kagaya H, Otaka Y, Saitoh E. Clinical manifestation, evaluation, and rehabilitative strategy of dysphagia associated with COVID-19. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;100:424&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8032217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Park JW, Min K, Lee YS, Song YJ, Choi SH, Kim DY, Lee SH, Yang HS, Cha W, Kim JW, Oh BM, Seo HG, Kim MW, Woo HS, Park SJ, Jee S, Oh JS, Park KD, Jin YJ, Han S, Yoo D, Kim BH, Lee HH, Kim YH, Kang MG, Chung EJ, Kim BR, Kim TW, Ko EJ, Park YM, Park H, Kim MS, Seok J, Im S, Ko SH, Lim SH, Jung KW, Lee TH, Hong BY, Kim W, Shin WS, Lee YC, Park SJ, Lim J, Kim Y, Lee JH, Ahn KM, Paeng JY, Park J, Song YA, Seo KC, Ryu CH, Cho JK, Lee JH, Choi KH. Clinical practice guidelines for oropharyngeal dysphagia. Ann Rehabil Med. 2023;47(Suppl 1):S1&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10405672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37501570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malaty J, Malaty IA. Smell and taste disorders in primary care. Am Fam Physician. 2013;88:852&#x2013;859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24364550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espetvedt A, Wiig S, Myrnes-Hansen KV, Br&#xf8;nnick KK. The assessment of qualitative olfactory dysfunction in COVID-19 patients: a systematic review of tools and their content validity. Front Psychol. 2023;14:1190994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10319418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37408960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan BK, Han R, Zhao JJ, Tan NK, Quah ES, Tan CJ, Chan YH, Teo NW, Charn TC, See A, Xu S, Chapurin N, Chandra RK, Chowdhury N, Butowt R, von Bartheld CS, Kumar BN, Hopkins C, Toh ST. Prognosis and persistence of smell and taste dysfunction in patients with covid-19: meta-analysis with parametric cure modelling of recovery curves. BMJ. 2022;378:e069503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9326326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35896188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartle M, Bateman L, Vernon S. Dissecting the nature of post-exertional malaise. Fatigue. 2021;9:33&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edward JA, Peruri A, Rudofker E, Shamapant N, Parker H, Cotter R, Sabin K, Lawley J, Cornwell WK., 3rd Characteristics and treatment of exercise intolerance in patients with long COVID. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2023;43:400&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37646620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason LA, Holtzman CS, Sunnquist M, Cotler J. The development of an instrument to assess post-exertional malaise in patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis and chronic fatigue syndrome. J Health Psychol. 2021;26:238&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7988339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30354489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh I, Joseph P, Heerdt PM, Cullinan M, Lutchmansingh DD, Gulati M, Possick JD, Systrom DM, Waxman AB. Persistent exertional intolerance after COVID-19: insights from invasive cardiopulmonary exercise testing. Chest. 2022;161:54&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8354807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34389297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotler J, Holtzman C, Dudun C, Jason LA. A brief questionnaire to assess post-exertional malaise. Diagnostics (Basel) 2018;8:66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6165517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30208578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal AK, Garg R, Ritch A, Sarkar P. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. Postgrad Med J. 2007;83:478&#x2013;480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2600095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17621618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmona-Torre F, M&#xed;nguez-Olaondo A, L&#xf3;pez-Bravo A, Tijero B, Grozeva V, Walcker M, Azkune-Galparsoro H, L&#xf3;pez de Munain A, Alcaide AB, Quiroga J, Del Pozo JL, G&#xf3;mez-Esteban JC. Dysautonomia in COVID-19 patients: a narrative review on clinical course, diagnostic and therapeutic strategies. Front Neurol. 2022;13:886609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9198643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35720084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldokla AM, Ali ST. Autonomic function testing in long-COVID syndrome patients with orthostatic intolerance. Auton Neurosci. 2022;241:102997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35679657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein DS. The possible association between COVID-19 and postural tachycardia syndrome. Heart Rhythm. 2021;18:508&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7729277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33316414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayuga KA, Fedorowski A, Ricci F, Gopinathannair R, Dukes JW, Gibbons C, Hanna P, Sorajja D, Chung M, Benditt D, Sheldon R, Ayache MB, AbouAssi H, Shivkumar K, Grubb BP, Hamdan MH, Stavrakis S, Singh T, Goldberger JJ, Muldowney JA, 3rd, Belham M, Kem DC, Akin C, Bruce BK, Zahka NE, Fu Q, Van Iterson EH, Raj SR, Fouad-Tarazi F, Goldstein DS, Stewart J, Olshansky B. Sinus tachycardia: a multidisciplinary expert focused review. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2022;15:e007960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9523592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36074973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zulbaran-Rojas A, Lee M, Bara RO, Flores-Camargo A, Spitz G, Finco MG, Bagheri AB, Modi D, Shaib F, Najafi B. Electrical stimulation to regain lower extremity muscle perfusion and endurance in patients with post-acute sequelae of SARS CoV-2: A randomized controlled trial. Physiol Rep. 2023;11:e15636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10006649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36905161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkowski S, Bogacz K, Rutkowska A, Szczegielniak J, Casaburi R. Inpatient post-COVID-19 rehabilitation program featuring virtual reality-Preliminary results of randomized controlled trial. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1121554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9939639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36815161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palau P, Dom&#xed;nguez E, Gonzalez C, Bond&#xed;a E, Albiach C, Sastre C, Mart&#xed;nez ML, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez J, L&#xf3;pez L. Effect of a home-based inspiratory muscle training programme on functional capacity in postdischarged patients with long COVID: the InsCOVID trial. BMJ Open Respir Res. 2022;9:e001439</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9791108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36549786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n A, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Franco-L&#xf3;pez F, S&#xe1;nchez-Alcaraz BJ, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. Effects of a concurrent training, respiratory muscle exercise, and self-management recommendations on recovery from post-COVID-19 conditions: the RECOVE trial. J Appl Physiol. 2023;134:95&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9829459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36476156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Corral T, Fabero-Garrido R, Plaza-Manzano G, Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, L&#xf3;pez-de-Uralde-Villanueva I. Home-based respiratory muscle training on quality of life and exercise tolerance in long-term post-COVID-19: Randomized controlled trial. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2023;66:101709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9708524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36191860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n A, Franco-L&#xf3;pez F, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, S&#xe1;nchez-Agar JA, S&#xe1;nchez-Alcaraz Mart&#xed;nez BJ, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. Rehabilitation for post-COVID-19 condition through a supervised exercise intervention: A randomized controlled trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32:1791&#x2013;1801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36111386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNarry MA, Berg RM, Shelley J, Hudson J, Saynor ZL, Duckers J, Lewis K, Davies GA, Mackintosh KA. Inspiratory muscle training enhances recovery post-COVID-19: a randomised controlled trial. Eur Respir J. 2022;60:2103101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8900538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35236727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philip KE, Owles H, McVey S, Pagnuco T, Bruce K, Brunjes H, Banya W, Mollica J, Lound A, Zumpe S, Abrahams AM, Padmanaban V, Hardy TH, Lewis A, Lalvani A, Elkin S, Hopkinson NS. An online breathing and wellbeing programme (ENO Breathe) for people with persistent symptoms following COVID-19: a parallel-group, single-blind, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10:851&#x2013;862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9045747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35489367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catal&#xe1;n IP, Mart&#xed; CR, Sota DP, &#xc1;lvarez AC, Gimeno MJ, Juana SF, Rodr&#xed;guez GH, Bajo ED, Gaya NT, Blasco JU, Rinc&#xf3;n JM. Corticosteroids for COVID-19 symptoms and quality of life at 1 year from admission. J Med Virol. 2022;94:205&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34436783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerget B, &#xc7;il G, Araz &#xd6;, Alper F, Akg&#xfc;n M. Comparison of two antifibrotic treatments for lung fibrosis in post-COVID-19 syndrome: A randomized, prospective study. Med Clin (Barc) 2023;160:525&#x2013;530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9981521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37055254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P, Tahmasebi N, Gant V, Gupta R. Long COVID following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: characteristic T cell alterations and response to antihistamines. J Investig Med. 2022;70:61&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8494538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health. Clinical rehabilitation guideline for people with long COVID (coronavirus disease) in Aotearoa New Zealand. Wellington: Ministry of Health; 2022. Revised December 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith ME, Haney E, McDonagh M, Pappas M, Daeges M, Wasson N, Fu R, Nelson HD. Treatment of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: a systematic review for a National Institutes of Health pathways to prevention workshop. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162:841&#x2013;850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26075755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler-Davis S, Platts K, Thelwell M, Woodward A, Harrop D. A mixed-methods systematic review of post-viral fatigue interventions: Are there lessons for long Covid? PLoS One. 2021;16:e0259533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8577752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34752489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S, Whiteson JH, Abramoff B, Azola A, Bartels MN, Bhavaraju-Sanka R, Chung T, Fleming TK, Henning E, Miglis MG, Sampsel S, Silver JK, Tosto J, Verduzco-Gutierrez M, Putrino D. Multi-disciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of autonomic dysfunction in patients with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) PM R. 2022;14:1270&#x2013;1291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36169154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soin A, Soin Y, Dann T, Buenaventura R, Ferguson K, Atluri S, Sachdeva H, Sudarshan G, Akbik H, Italiano J. Low-dose naltrexone use for patients with chronic regional pain syndrome: a systematic literature review. Pain Physician. 2021;24:E393&#x2013;E406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34213865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Membrilla JA, Caronna E, Trigo-L&#xf3;pez J, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Mart&#xed;nez A, Layos-Romero A, Pozo-Rosich P, Guerrero-Peral &#xc1;, Gago-Veiga AB, Andr&#xe9;s-L&#xf3;pez A, D&#xed;az de Ter&#xe1;n J. Persistent headache after COVID-19: Pathophysioloy, clinic and treatment. Neurology Perspectives. 2021;1:S31&#x2013;S36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MaassenVanDenBrink A, de Vries T, Danser AH. MaassenVanDenBrink A, de Vries T, Danser AHJ. Headache medication and the COVID-19 pandemic. J Headache Pain. 2020;21:38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7183387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32334535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, Kang L, Guo L, Liu M, Zhou X, Luo J, Huang Z, Tu S, Zhao Y, Chen L, Xu D, Li Y, Li C, Peng L, Li Y, Xie W, Cui D, Shang L, Fan G, Xu J, Wang G, Wang Y, Zhong J, Wang C, Wang J, Zhang D, Cao B. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Korean Headache Society. Clinical Practice Guideline of Pharmacologic Treatment for Migraine Prevention in Adults 2021.  [Accessed 17 January 2024].  Available at:  https://www.headache.or.kr/m/bbs/board.php?bo_table=3_5_1_1&amp;wr_id=4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farahani RH, Ajam A, Naeini AR. Effect of fluvoxamine on preventing neuropsychiatric symptoms of post COVID syndrome in mild to moderate patients, a randomized placebo-controlled double-blind clinical trial. BMC Infect Dis. 2023;23:197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10064948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37003990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, Zanardi R, Palladini M, Rovere-Querini P, Benedetti F. Rapid response to selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors in post-COVID depression. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2022;54:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34634679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobile B, Durand M, Oli&#xe9; E, Guillaume S, Mol&#xe8;s JP, Haffen E, Courtet P. The anti-inflammatory effect of the tricyclic antidepressant clomipramine and its high penetration in the brain might be useful to prevent the psychiatric consequences of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Front Pharmacol. 2021;12:615695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7985338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33767623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thondala B, Pawar H, Chauhan G, Panjwani U. The effect of non-pharmacological interventions on sleep quality in people with sleep disturbances: A systematic review and a meta-analysis. Chronobiol Int. 2023;40:1333&#x2013;1353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37853577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addison AB, Wong B, Ahmed T, Macchi A, Konstantinidis I, Huart C, Frasnelli J, Fjaeldstad AW, Ramakrishnan VR, Rombaux P, Whitcroft KL, Holbrook EH, Poletti SC, Hsieh JW, Landis BN, Boardman J, Welge-L&#xfc;ssen A, Maru D, Hummel T, Philpott CM. Clinical Olfactory Working Group consensus statement on the treatment of postinfectious olfactory dysfunction. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2021;147:1704&#x2013;1719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asvapoositkul V, Samuthpongtorn J, Aeumjaturapat S, Snidvongs K, Chusakul S, Seresirikachorn K, Kanjanaumporn J. Therapeutic options of post-COVID-19 related olfactory dysfunction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Rhinology. 2023;61:2&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36173148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaira LA, Hopkins C, Petrocelli M, Lechien JR, Cutrupi S, Salzano G, Chiesa-Estomba CM, Saussez S, De Riu G. Efficacy of corticosteroid therapy in the treatment of long- lasting olfactory disorders in COVID-19 patients. Rhinology. 2021;59:21&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33290446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseinpoor M, Kabiri M, Rajati Haghi M, Ghadam Soltani T, Rezaei A, Faghfouri A, Poustchian Gholkhatmi Z, Bakhshaee M. Intranasal corticosteroid treatment on recovery of long-term olfactory dysfunction due to COVID-19. Laryngoscope. 2022;132:2209&#x2013;2216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36054369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wormgoor ME, Rodenburg SC. Focus on post-exertional malaise when approaching ME/CFS in specialist healthcare improves satisfaction and reduces deterioration. Front Neurol. 2023;14:1247698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10722442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38107643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanal-Hayes NE, Mclaughlin M, Hayes LD, Mair JL, Ormerod J, Carless D, Hilliard N, Meach R, Ingram J, Sculthorpe NF. A scoping review of &#x2018;Pacing&#x2019; for management of Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS): lessons learned for the long COVID pandemic. J Transl Med. 2023;21:720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10576275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37838675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS)  [Accessed 8 January 2024].  Available at:  https://www.cdc.gov/me-cfs/index.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amekran Y, Damoun N, El Hangouche AJ. Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome and post-acute COVID-19. Glob Cardiol Sci Pract. 2022;2022:e202213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9629292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36339677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baptista AF, Baltar A, Okano AH, Moreira A, Campos AC, Fernandes AM, Brunoni AR, Badran BW, Tanaka C, de Andrade DC, da Silva Machado DG, Morya E, Trujillo E, Swami JK, Camprodon JA, Monte-Silva K, S&#xe1; KN, Nunes I, Goulardins JB, Bikson M, Sudbrack-Oliveira P, de Carvalho P, Duarte-Moreira RJ, Pagano RL, Shinjo SK, Zana Y. Applications of non-invasive neuromodulation for the management of disorders related to COVID-19. Front Neurol. 2020;11:573718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7724108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33324324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai AD, Boursiquot BC, Melki L, Wan EY. Management of arrhythmias associated with COVID-19. Curr Cardiol Rep. 2020;23:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7685181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33231782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramacciotti E, Barile Agati L, Calderaro D, Aguiar VC, Spyropoulos AC, de Oliveira CC, Lins Dos Santos J, Volpiani GG, Sobreira ML, Joviliano EE, Bohatch J&#xfa;nior MS, da Fonseca BA, Ribeiro MS, Dusilek C, Itinose K, Sanches SM, de Almeida Araujo Ramos K, de Moraes NF, Tierno PF, de Oliveira AL, Tachibana A, Chate RC, Santos MV, de Menezes Cavalcante BB, Moreira RC, Chang C, Tafur A, Fareed J, Lopes RD, Benevenuto Caltabiano T, Hattori B, da Silva Jardim M, Marinho I, Silva Marinho I, Mara Melo Batista L, Rivabem L, Alberto Kenji Nakashima C, Carla Gois Franco A, de Oliveira Pereira RF, Strack Neves GC, de Castro e Souza I, Moraes Ribas B, Ramos Trist&#xe3;o F, Barbosa Santos MV MICHELLE investigators. Rivaroxaban versus no anticoagulation for post-discharge thromboprophylaxis after hospitalisation for COVID-19 (MICHELLE): an open-label, multicentre, randomised, controlled trial. Lancet. 2022;399:50&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8673881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34921756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang TY, Wahed AS, Morris A, Kreuziger LB, Quigley JG, Lamas GA, Weissman AJ, Lopez-Sendon J, Knudson MM, Siegal DM, Kasthuri RS, Alexander AJ, Wahid L, Atassi B, Miller PJ, Lawson JW, Patel B, Krishnan JA, Shapiro NL, Martin DE, Kindzelski AL, Leifer ES, Joo J, Lyu L, Pennella A, Everett BM, Geraci MW, Anstrom KJ, Ortel TL, Ortel T, Wang T, Morris A, Kreuziger LB, Wisniewski S, Wahed A, Anstrom K, Leifer E, Krishnan J, Quigley J, Lamas G, Weissman A, Lopez-Sendon J, Knudson MM, Siegal D, Hoots K, Kindzelski A, Leverty R, Brown HA, Andrade G, Jain N, Feierbach F, Serwatkewich K, Wolf MA, Olson R, Pennella A, Atwood T, Lindblom K, Schutte A, Stone A, Morse M, Lang J, Harding T, Harrington A, Rogers S, Collazo J, Kandray N, Beauchaine M, Anderson J, Britto D, Chavis K, Denning T, Garcia S, Pinnix A, Webb T, Wilson L, Blumer V, Pratt E, Daugherty M, Leverty R, Burnett A, Wisniewski S, Geraci M, Egan JC, George E, Music E, Alameida A, Schreiber J, Sciurba F, Perkins E, Wisniewski S, Hulbert J, Kass D, Myerburg MM, Lyu L, de Brouwer S, Kirwan BA, Perrin E, Shapiro N, Hasek S, Predki B, Martinez M, Barbera S, Sculley J, Peterson J, Illendula S, DeLisa J, Castro L, Huynh N, Uppuluri E, Lee J, Speakman L, Idrees N, Mei C, Pozzolano E, Driscoll T, Skific D, Collins J, Hanna A, Mersc S, Simtion S, Everett B, Hegde S, Kim Y, Galanaud JP, Le Gal G, Rost N, van Diepen S, Singhal A, Becker RC, del Zoppo G, Glynn R, Henke P, Holubkov R, Kerr K, Lee A, Lipman H, Lure F, Vesely S, Wenner D, Punturieri A, Sakovich B, Snyder J, Milliken DJ, Bucheimer J, Mondoro TH, Weinmann G, Troendle J, Joo J, Berdan LG, Aggarwal N, Bernard G, Brown SM, Callaway C, Collins S, Cushman M, Douglas D, Erzurum S, Farrell A, Gelijns A, Ginde A, Glynn S, Goff D, Harrigan R, Harrington R, Hochman J, Homer M, Johnson R, Key N, Kiley J, Koroshetz W, Lane C, LaVange L, Marks GL, Marks P, Mensah G, Nugent D, Patterson A, Rosenberg Y, Shotwell M, Silverman T, Stoney C, Wright C, Yancy C, Nolen T, Thomas S, Walter M, Herring G, Kendrick A, Deese J, Sullivan T, Kasthuri R, Mooberry M, Moll S, Abajas Y, Brightwood A, Stanford K, Finerty L, Alexander A, Chaffins L, Nercesian M, Wahid L, Dolor R, Dreyer G, Der T, Ko E, Archibald A, Renard V, Stafford N, Azuogalanya N, Mohammed O, McPherson C, Choye P, Kim K, Atal N, Mon A, Atassi MB, Garg S, Vrame J, Murawski T, Miller PJ, Khanna A, Wadhwani H, Shah K, Pickmans M, Mayes R, Reeves B, Harris LL, Lawson J, Oliver A, Zhu J, Weinstein L, Lawson M, Beaty N, Monroe R, Johnson R, Stith B, Ciesla M, Patel B, McPherson D, Ostrosky L, Ayad M, Gore M, Thomas N, Udoh-Bradford I, Johnson J, Nichols P, Mubashir T, Rogers R, Mylonakis E, Sherman-Roe A, Fisher J, Al Homssi A, Abid H, Hammons L, Broaddrick S, McKinnell J, Sherman B, Kagihara J, Huynh R, Gonzalez HJ, Billett H, Suchanek M, Townsend N, Sadler V, Anderson M, Beer A, Gruetzmacher C, Schoenling A, Malley B, McVerry B, Rosborough B, Franz C, Schloss D, Barton D, Huang D, Brant E, Shah F, Mayr F, Kitsios G, Haidar G, Barbash I, Moghbeli K, Fitzpatrick M, Talia N, Shetty V, Bain W, Berryman E, Marcin M, Gilliam M, DiFiore S, Gavin W, Ren T, Stearns M, Chalasani P, Testa S, Stuart A, Holsapple A, Prime J, Kay C, Saksa S, Downing M, Castellino A, Sanders P, Paul J, Walborn A, Kim G, Acosta M, Cochran M, Kong N, Gupta N, Pinney SP, Arevalo C, Molignoni K, Forman D, Rettew A, Rupard E, Agostino N, Sheidy J, McLin R, Zainea M, Bykowski A, Parekh A, Provenzano C, Tait D, Ianitelli M, Prentice-Gaytan N, Malek R, Schendel S, Lala V, Hunyadi V, Saghir Z, Paschall E, Gurbel P, Barbour C, Rahi H, Ighani M, Palikhey S, Eacho S, Meisenberg B, Wolfe-Ralph C, Gray K, Cranford S, Powell J, Bryant N, Sanfilippo K, Buettner B, Almiron-Torralba F, Mendoza J, Watson J, Mullick M, Bruinsma M, Rivera NB, Martin N, Morgan Z, Kramer K, Cherabuddi K, Merck L, Holland A, Montero C, James N, Fowler S, Brosnahan S, Gutierrez L, Boa-Hocbo A, Macchiavelli A, Kelly B, Hallam A, White J, Tillman B, Nunez C, Bratcher N, Malvestutto C, Kraut E, Bartosic A, Hill B, Gonzalez O, Hillis C, Salama S, Kaderabek A, Deckard K, Peabody M, AL-Haddadin D, Vasquez M, Widmer K, Sheets M, Meyer D, Gerry T, Whitman M, Amistoso A, Mullarney A, Jezierski A, Anandakrishnan R, David S, Sanchez S, Stutzman S, Denbow M, Lord A, Chacko M, Cotrina M, Gafoor K, Cervellione K, Macdonald D, Kunisaki K, Hassler M, Katsouli A, Darki A, Diaz GE, Luo X, Del Priore J, Schoenecker N, Malhotra V, Quinn D, Pionk E, Winters L, Roberts M, Bruma S, Gardner-Mosley T, Moursi M, Brock S, Alnaji R, Thevanayagam S, Oyanbadejo M, Christie S, Byrd T, Sheth M, Reddy C, Marvin D, Russel S, Fikes W, Bromberg M, Sacher D, Randhawa E, Narewski E, Garfield JL, Mokha J, Galli J, Shenoy K, Vega Sanchez ME, Darnell M, Kaur N, O&#x2019;Corragain O, Desai P, Duffy S, Juhas J, Stein R, Knight C, Kozidis S, Lian KC, Tatsuno B, Nicholas Leo QJ, Guo S, Seto T, Le Y, Rho YS, Yee M, Vazquez J, Hamilton C, Hatzigeorgiou C, Anderson D, Walsh D, Eudy J, Osborn A, Bowles A, Monegro A, Wrona C, Williams J, Boole L, Shauberger M, Effron M, Williams S, Heath T, Dentino A, Gutierrez C, Bello F, Martin J, Hinojosa E, Nwasuruba C, Idell S, Duarte A, Kang C, Stockton L, Devine M, Chowdhury O, Olusola P, Terada R, Herrick C, Dohanich E, Hibbard R, Madhani-Lovely F, Jacobs A, Buckley K, Cruz V, Tan M, Cicero E, Barker L, Donovan B, Peterson V, Nunez-Garcia B, Ronan T, Apodaca E, Flys T, Kaatz S, Lewandowski C, Miller J, George M, Agunwa P, Shah V, Wilson K, Annous Y, Lewis S, Takubo T, Preast M, Tashfeen M, Gardner J, Brunet M, Meena N, DeAguero A, McGinty J, McGuire K, Blok T, Becker K, Pirraglia P, Perez L, Cobb V, Khan A, Srikanthan A, Mills E, Pena J, Krol O, Kountz D, Ullo C, Ende K, Madsen M, Kinsley M, Cohen J, Araromi O, Szymkowiak P, Baweja P, Reed M, Krupica T, Blystone E, Krupp JE, Hahn H, Geyer D, Blamoun J, Gainforth B, Rabidue M, Previti M, Froman D, Hamburg N, Klings E, Shepherd F, Behrooz L, Sloan M, Zheng R, Eberhardt R, Mompoint D, Gaddh M, Gluth A, Von A, Lucas J, Hooda A, Whitten S, Pullman J, Johnson M, White M, Freiman J, Mulrow M, Gannon D, Miller L, Johnson D, Corwin D, Rau E, Cunningham H, Clement M, Springer K, Giambartolomei S, Tran MA, Tobleman W, Sutton C, Holland H, Veres S, Lafferty L, Kutcher M, James G, Solis L, Barinas S, Rajan S, Hyde J, Shell C, Dyer D, Higginbotham T, Nwasuruba C, Hussain K, McCreary T, Ahmad W, Juang G, Rodriguez V, Ross T, Bahou W, Malone L, Chandrasekhar K, Steadham A, Vogel R, Elwing J, Jose A, Foot R, Hummel N, Malhotra S, Pete A, Rezai K, Hoffman M, Bhattacharjee P, Nedeltcheva A, Jain S, Katz D, Medenica I, Dehghan-Paz I, Shammo J, Thomas J, Larson M, Venugopal P, Gezer S, Kim SH, Fariduddin M, Nelson P, Provido V, Bajwa M, Cain C, Aboulafia D, Lambert C, Turner K, Nathan R, Morrison J, Thompson DA, Long S, Craig T, McDonald C, Snelus P, Gordon A, Pritchard A, Jazayeri Y, Sinha S, Baker A, Sujith C, Estrada-Y-Martin RM, Vidales E, Udoh-Bradford I, Aslam M, Doshi P, Akula R, Nichols P, Ashok N, Ul AD, Lepthien B, Dao M, Lepthien B, Cloutier K, Osiyemi O, Vargas A, Campbell C, Menajovsky-Chaves J, Martinez S, Izquierdo M, Nathan R, Van Anglen L, Bronstein M, Hall C, Kleiner E, Blanco A, Bunn J, Roshon M, McCrae K, Knight A, Lammi M, Romaine C, Reddy M, Drescher M, Ornstein D, Leung H, Mercado J, Ward M, Zuckerman R, Henkin S, Johnson H, Windish S, Lesko M, Gobbo P, Godfrey C, Miriovsky M, Kyono W, Tong M, Migdol S, Ilercil A, Leonelli F, Hanna N, Mehrle A, Arnold M, Polasek J, Harris M, Cohen A, Shah M, Jacoby S, Gadhiya A, Horta C, Pradham M ACTIV-4C Study Group. Effect of thromboprophylaxis on clinical outcomes after COVID-19 hospitalization. Ann Intern Med. 2023;176:515&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10064277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36940444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortel TL, Neumann I, Ageno W, Beyth R, Clark NP, Cuker A, Hutten BA, Jaff MR, Manja V, Schulman S, Thurston C, Vedantham S, Verhamme P, Witt DM, D Florez I, Izcovich A, Nieuwlaat R, Ross S, J Sch&#xfc;nemann H, Wiercioch W, Zhang Y, Zhang Y. American Society of Hematology 2020 guidelines for management of venous thromboembolism: treatment of deep vein thrombosis and pulmonary embolism. Blood Adv. 2020;4:4693&#x2013;4738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7556153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33007077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health (NIH) COVID-19 treatment guidelines: coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) treatment guidelines. Bethesda, MD: NIH; 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34003615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh P, Behera D, Gupta S, Deep A, Priyadarshini S, Padhan P. Nintedanib vs pirfenidone in the management of COVID-19 lung fibrosis: A single-centre study. J R Coll Physicians Edinb. 2022;52:100&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36146989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary R, Kumar A, Ali O, Pervez A. Effectiveness and safety of pirfenidone and nintedanib for pulmonary fibrosis in COVID-19-induced severe pneumonia: an interventional study. Cureus. 2022;14:e29435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9587348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36299940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerget B, Cil G, Araz O, Alper F, Akgun M. When and how important is anti-fibrotic therapy in the post-COVID-19 period? Bratisl Lek Listy (Tlacene Vyd) 2022;123:653&#x2013;6958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36039884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi YJ, Seo YB, Seo JW, Lee J, Nham E, Seong H, Yoon JG, Noh JY, Cheong HJ, Kim WJ, Kim EJ, Song JY. Effectiveness of antiviral therapy on long COVID: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Med. 2023;12:7375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10707593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38068427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilunga FP, Appelman B, van Vugt M, Kalverda K, Smeele P, van Es J, Wiersinga WJ, Rostila M, Prins M, Stronks K, Norredam M, Agyemang C. Differences in incidence, nature of symptoms, and duration of long COVID among hospitalised migrant and non-migrant patients in the Netherlands: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet Reg Health Eur. 2023;29:100630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10079482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37261215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Choi T, Al-Aly Z. Molnupiravir and risk of post-acute sequelae of covid-19: cohort study. BMJ. 2023;381:e074572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10126525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37161995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HR, Yoo MG, Kim JM, Bae SJ, Lee H, Kim J. Effectiveness of molnupiravir treatment in patients with COVID-19 in Korea: a propensity score matched study. Infect Chemother. 2023;55:490&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10771951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38014730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Kulzhabayeva D, Rodrigues NB, Di Vincenzo JD, Gill H, Subramaniapillai M, Lui LM, Cao B, Mansur RB, Ho RC, Burke MJ, Rhee TG, Rosenblat JD, McIntyre RS. COVID-19 vaccination for the prevention and treatment of long COVID: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun. 2023;111:211&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10067136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36990297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe A, Iwagami M, Yasuhara J, Takagi H, Kuno T. Protective effect of COVID-19 vaccination against long COVID syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Vaccine. 2023;41:1783&#x2013;1790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9905096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36774332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi S, Lee H, Eum SH, Min JW, Yoon HE, Yang CW, Chung BH. Severity of COVID-19 pneumonia in kidney transplant recipients according to SARS-CoV-2 vaccination. Infect Chemother. 2023;55:505&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10771954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38183395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi WS. Adult immunization policy in Korea. Infect Chemother. 2023;55:317&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10551718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37794577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>