<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37205352</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>medRxiv : the preprint server for health sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>medRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Mixed Methods System for the Assessment of Post Exertional Malaise in Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2023.04.24.23288821</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1101/2023.04.24.23288821</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A central feature of Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS) is post exertional malaise (PEM), which is an acute worsening of symptoms after a physical, emotional and/or mental exertion. PEM is also a feature of Long COVID. Dynamic measures of PEM have historically included scaled questionnaires which have not been validated in ME/CFS. To enhance our understanding of PEM and how best to measure it, we conducted semi-structured qualitative interviews (QIs) at the same intervals as Visual Analog Scale (VAS) measures after a Cardiopulmonary Exercise Test (CPET).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Ten ME/CFS and nine healthy volunteers participated in a CPET. For each participant, PEM symptom VAS (7 symptoms) and semi-structured QIs were administered at six timepoints over 72 hours before and after a single CPET. QI data were used to plot the severity of PEM at each time point and identify the self-described most bothersome symptom for each patient. QI data were used to determine the symptom trajectory and peak of PEM. Performance of QI and VAS data were compared to each other using Spearman correlations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">QIs documented that each ME/CFS volunteer had a unique PEM experience, with differences noted in the onset, severity, trajectory over time, and most bothersome symptom. No healthy volunteers experienced PEM. Scaled QI data were able to identify PEM peaks and trajectories, even when VAS scales were unable to do so due to known ceiling and floor effects. QI and VAS fatigue data corresponded well prior to exercise (baseline, r=0.7) but poorly at peak PEM (r=0.28) and with the change from baseline to peak (r=0.20). When the most bothersome symptom identified from QIs was used, these correlations improved (r=.0.77, 0.42. and 0.54 respectively) and reduced the observed VAS scale ceiling and floor effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">QIs were able to capture changes in PEM severity and symptom quality over time in all the ME/CFS volunteers, even when VAS scales failed to do so. Information collected from QIs also improved the performance of VAS. Measurement of PEM can be improved by using a quantitative-qualitative mixed model approach.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stussman</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS), National Institutes of Health (NIH), Bethesda, MD, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calco</LastName><ForeName>Brice</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID), National Institutes of Health (NIH), Bethesda, MD, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Norato</LastName><ForeName>Gina</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS), National Institutes of Health (NIH), Bethesda, MD, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gavin</LastName><ForeName>Angelique</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS), National Institutes of Health (NIH), Bethesda, MD, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chigurupati</LastName><ForeName>Snigdha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>George Washington School of Medicine and Health Sciences, Washington D.C., United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nath</LastName><ForeName>Avindra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS), National Institutes of Health (NIH), Bethesda, MD, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walitt</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS), National Institutes of Health (NIH), Bethesda, MD, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>medRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101767986</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateIn"><RefSource>BMJ Neurol Open. 2024 Feb 10;6(1):e000529. doi: 10.1136/bmjno-2023-000529</RefSource><PMID Version="1">38352048</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiopulmonary Exercise Test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic Fatigue Syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Measurement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myalgic Encephalomyelitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post Exertional Malaise</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37205352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10187342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.04.24.23288821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2023.04.24.23288821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Unger ER, Lin JS, Brimmer DJ, Lapp CW, Komaroff AL, Nath A, Laird S, Iskander J. CDC Grand Rounds: Chronic Fatigue Syndrome Advancing Research and Clinical Education. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2016. Dec 30;65(5051):1434 1438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28033311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vernon SD, Hartle M, Sullivan K, Bell J, Abbaszadeh S, Unutmaz D, Bateman L. Post-exertional malaise among people with long COVID compared to myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). Work. 2023. Mar 7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36911963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason LA, Dorri JA. ME/CFS and Post-Exertional Malaise among Patients with Long COVID. Neurol Int. 2022. Dec 20;15(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9844405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36648965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stussman B, Williams A, Snow J, Gavin A, Scott R, Nath A, Walitt B. Characterization of Post-exertional Malaise in Patients With Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Front Neurol. 2020. Sep 18;11:1025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7530890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33071931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IOM Report: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK274235/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens S, Snell C, Stevens J, Keller B, VanNess JM. Cardiopulmonary Exercise Test Methodology for Assessing Exertion Intolerance in Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Front Pediatr. 2018. Sep 4;6:242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6131594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30234078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams VS, Morlock RJ, Feltner D. Psychometric evaluation of a visual analog scale for the assessment of anxiety. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2010. Jun 8;8:57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2904728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20529361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Averbuch M, Katzper M. Assessment of visual analog versus categorical scale for measurement of osteoarthritis pain. J Clin Pharmacol. 2004. Apr;44(4):368&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15051743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buisman ETIA, Grens H, Wang R, Bhattacharya S, Braat DDM, Huppelschoten AG, van der Steeg JW. Trends in research on pain relief during oocyte retrieval for IVF/ICSI: a systematic, methodological review. Hum Reprod Open. 2022. Feb 16;2022(1):hoac006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8868119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35224230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Campen CLMC, Rowe PC, Verheugt FWA, Visser FC. Numeric Rating Scales Show Prolonged Post-exertional Symptoms After Orthostatic Testing of Adults With Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Front Med (Lausanne). 2021. Jan 27;7:602894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7874746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33585505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanNess JM, Stevens SR, Bateman L, Stiles TL, Snell CR. Postexertional malaise in women with chronic fatigue syndrome. J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2010. Feb;19(2):239&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20095909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Oosterwijck J, Nijs J, Meeus M, Lefever I, Huybrechts L, Lambrecht L, Paul L. Pain inhibition and postexertional malaise in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: an experimental study. J Intern Med. 2010. Sep;268(3):265&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20412374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook DB, Light AR, Light KC, Broderick G, Shields MR, Dougherty RJ, Meyer JD, VanRiper S, Stegner AJ, Ellingson LD, Vernon SD. Neural consequences of post-exertion malaise in Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Brain Behav Immun. 2017. May;62:87&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28216087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Learmonth YC, Paul L, McFadyen AK, Marshall-McKenna R, Mattison P, Miller L, McFarlane NG. Short-term effect of aerobic exercise on symptoms in multiple sclerosis and chronic fatigue syndrome: a pilot study. Int J MS Care. 2014. Summer;16(2):76&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4106394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25061431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polli A, Van Oosterwijck J, Nijs J, Marusic U, De Wandele I, Paul L, Meeus M, Moorkens G, Lambrecht L, Ickmans K. Relationship Between Exercise-induced Oxidative Stress Changes and Parasympathetic Activity in Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: An Observational Study in Patients and Healthy Subjects. Clin Ther. 2019. Apr;41(4):641&#x2013;655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30665828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Light AR, Bateman L, Jo D, Hughen RW, Vanhaitsma TA, White AT, Light KC. Gene expression alterations at baseline and following moderate exercise in patients with Chronic Fatigue Syndrome and Fibromyalgia Syndrome. J Intern Med. 2012. Jan;271(1):64&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3175315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21615807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason LA, Holtzman CS, Sunnquist M, Cotler J. The development of an instrument to assess post-exertional malaise in patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis and chronic fatigue syndrome. J Health Psychol. 2021. Feb;26(2):238&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7988339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30354489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason LA, Evans M, So S, Scott J, Brown A. Problems in defining post-exertional malaise. J Prev Interv Community. 2015;43(1):20&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4295644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25584525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock KW, Wang XS, Shi Q, Cleeland CS, Fagundes CP, Vernon SD. The utility of patient-reported outcome measures among patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Qual Life Res. 2017. Apr;26(4):913&#x2013;921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5336422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27600520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu L, Valencia IJ, Garvert DW, Montoya JG. Deconstructing post-exertional malaise in myalgic encephalomyelitis/ chronic fatigue syndrome: A patient-centered, cross-sectional survey. PLoS One. 2018. Jun 1;13(6):e0197811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5983853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29856774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtzman CS, Bhatia S, Cotler J, Jason LA. Assessment of Post Exertional Malaise (PEM) in Patients with Myalgic Encephalomyelitis (ME) and Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (CFS): A Patient Driven Survey. Diagnostics (Basel). 2019. Mar 2;9(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6468435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30832336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boruch AE, Lindheimer JB, Klein-Adams JC, Stegner AJ, Wylie GR, Ninneman JV, Alexander T, Gretzon NP, Samy B, Van Riper SM, Falvo MJ, Cook DB. Predicting post-exertional malaise in Gulf War Illness based on acute exercise responses. Life Sci. 2021. Sep 1;280:119701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10214407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34119538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindheimer JB, Alexander T, Qian W, Klein-Adams JC, Lange G, Natelson H B, Cook DB, Hill HZ, Falvo MJ. An analysis of 2-day cardiopulmonary exercise testing to assess unexplained fatigue. Physiol Rep. 2020. Sep;8(17):e14564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7507580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32889791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klimek L, Bergmann KC, Biedermann T, et al. Visual analogue scales (VAS): Measuring instruments for the documentation of symptoms and therapy monitoring in cases of allergic rhinitis in everyday health care. Allergo J Int. 2017;26(1):16&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5288410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28217433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haefeli M, Elfering A. Pain assessment. Eur Spine J. 2006. Jan;15 Suppl 1(Suppl 1):S17&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3454549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16320034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hjermstad MJ, Fayers PM, Haugen DF, Caraceni A, Hanks GW, Loge JH, Fainsinger R, Aass N, Kaasa; European Palliative Care Research Collaborative (EPCRC). Studies comparing Numerical Rating Scales, Verbal Rating Scales, and Visual Analogue Scales for assessment of pain intensity in adults: a systematic literature review. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2011. Jun;41(6):1073&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21621130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotler J, Holtzman C, Dudun C, Jason LA. A Brief Questionnaire to Assess Post-Exertional Malaise. Diagnostics (Basel). 2018. Sep 11;8(3):66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6165517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30208578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kujawski S, S&#x142;omko J, Hodges L, Pheby DFH, Murovska M, Newton JL, Zalewski P. Post-Exertional Malaise May Be Related to Central Blood Pressure, Sympathetic Activity and Mental Fatigue in Chronic Fatigue Syndrome Patients. J Clin Med. 2021. May 26;10(11):2327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8198768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34073494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kujawski S, S&#x142;omko J, Newton JL, Eaton-Fitch N, Staines DR, Marshall-Gradisnik S, Zalewski P. Network Analysis of Symptoms Co-Occurrence in Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021. Oct 13;18(20):10736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8535251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34682478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey R, Yeung ST, Wrightson JG, Millet GY, Culos-Reed SN. Post-exertional Malaise in People With Chronic Cancer-Related Fatigue. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2020. Aug;60(2):407&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32105793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateo LJ, Chu L, Stevens S, Stevens J, Snell CR, Davenport T, VanNess JM. Post-exertional symptoms distinguish Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome subjects from healthy controls. Work. 2020;66(2):265&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32568143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell JW, Plano Clark VL. Designing and conducting mixed methods research, 2nd edition. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezzani A. Cardiopulmonary Exercise Testing: Basics of Methodology and Measurements. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2017. Jul;14(Supplement_1):S3&#x2013;S11. doi: 10.1513/AnnalsATS.201612-997FR.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1513/AnnalsATS.201612-997FR</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28510504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broderick G, Ben-Hamo R, Vashishtha S, Efroni S, Nathanson L, Barnes Z, Fletcher MA, Klimas N. Altered immune pathway activity under exercise challenge in Gulf War Illness: an exploratory analysis. Brain Behav Immun. 2013. Feb;28:159&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23201588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team (2022). R: A language and environment for statistical computing.
R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria. URL https://www.R-project.org/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor R. Interpretation of the Correlation Coefficient: A Basic Review. Journal of Diagnostic Medical Sonography 1990;6:35&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CJ, Hung LY, Kogelnik AM, Kaufman D, Aiyar RS, Chu AM, Wilhelmy J, Li P, Tannenbaum L, Xiao W, Davis RW. A Comprehensive Examination of Severely Ill ME/CFS Patients. Healthcare (Basel). 2021. Sep 29;9(10):1290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8535418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34682970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>May M, Milrad SF, Perdomo DM, Czaja SJ, Fletcher MA, Jutagir DR, Hall DL, Klimas N, Antoni MH. Post-exertional malaise is associated with greater symptom burden and psychological distress in patients diagnosed with Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. J Psychosom Res. 2020. Feb;129:109893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7007968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31884303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beletsky A, Nwachukwu BU, Gorodischer T, Chahla J, Forsythe B, Cole BJ, Verma NN. Psychometric properties of visual analog scale assessments for function, pain, and strength compared with disease-specific upper extremity outcome measures in rotator cuff repair. JSES Int. 2020. May 23;4(3):619&#x2013;624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7479024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32939496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filocamo G, Dav&#xec; S, Pistorio A, Bertamino M, Ruperto N, Lattanzi B, Consolaro A, Magni-Manzoni S, Galasso R, Varnier GC, Martini A, Ravelli A. Evaluation of 21-numbered circle and 10-centimeter horizontal line visual analog scales for physician and parent subjective ratings in juvenile idiopathic arthritis. J Rheumatol. 2010. Jul;37(7):1534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20551105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>