<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38111916</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2227-7390</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>21</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Mathematics (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mathematics (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Mechanistic Model for Long COVID Dynamics.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4541</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/math11214541</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long COVID, a long-lasting disorder following an acute infection of COVID-19, represents a significant public health burden at present. In this paper, we propose a new mechanistic model based on differential equations to investigate the population dynamics of long COVID. By connecting long COVID with acute infection at the population level, our modeling framework emphasizes the interplay between COVID-19 transmission, vaccination, and long COVID dynamics. We conducted a detailed mathematical analysis of the model. We also validated the model using numerical simulation with real data from the US state of Tennessee and the UK.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Derrick</LastName><ForeName>Jacob</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics, University of Tennessee at Chattanooga, Chattanooga, TN 37403, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patterson</LastName><ForeName>Ben</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-7026-1767</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics, University of Tennessee at Chattanooga, Chattanooga, TN 37403, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bai</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mathematics and Statistics, Liaoning University, Shenyang 110036, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics, University of Tennessee at Chattanooga, Chattanooga, TN 37403, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R15 GM152943</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Mathematics (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101766564</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2227-7390</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">92D30</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mathematical modeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">numerical simulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38111916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1951432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10727852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math11214541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">4541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Davis HE; Assaf GS; McCorkell L; Wei H; Low RJ; Re&#x2019;em Y; Redfield S; Austin JP; Akrami A Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. eClinicalMedicine 2021, 38, 101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention: Post-COVID Conditions. Available online: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html (accessed on
1 July 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE; McCorkell L; Vogel JM; Topol EJ Long COVID: Major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat. Rev. Microbiol 2023, 21, 133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall M The four most urgent questions about long COVID. Nature 2021, 594, 168&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34108700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD; VanElzakker MB Long COVID or Post-acute Sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): An overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front. Microbiol 2021, 12, 698169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carfi A; Bernabei R; Landi F For the Gemelli against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group, Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. J. Am. Med. Assoc 2020, 324, 603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C; Huang L; Wang Y; Li X; Ren L; Gu X; Kang L; Guo L; Liu M; Zhou X; et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: A cohort study. Lancet 2021, 397, 220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW; Kim SS; Lindsell CJ; Rose EB; Shapiro NI; Files DC; Gibbs KW; Erickson HL; Steingrub JS; Smithline HA; et al. Symptom duration and risk factors for delayed return to usual health among outpatients with COVID-19 in a multistate health care systems network-United States, March-June 2020. Morb. Mortal. Wkly. Rep 2020, 69, 993&#x2013;998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergwerk M; Gonen T; Lustig Y; Amit S; Lipsitch M; Cohen C; Mandelboim M; Levin EG; Rubin C; Indenbaum V; et al. COVID-19 breakthrough infections in vaccinated health care workers. N. Engl. J. Med 2021, 385, 1629&#x2013;1630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8362591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34320281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massey D; Berrent D; Krumholz H Breakthrough symptomatic COVID-19 infections leading to long COVID: Report from long COVID Facebook group poll. medRxiv 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A; Sehgal K; Gupta A; Madhavan MV; McGroder C; Stevens JS; Cook JR; Nordvig AS; Shalev D; Sehrawat TS; et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat. Med 2021, 27, 601&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cares-Marambio K; Montenegro-Jim&#xe9;nez Y; Torres-Castro R; Vera-Uribe R; Torralba Y; Alsina-Restoy X; Vasconcello-Castillo L; Vilar&#xf3; J Prevalence of potential respiratory symptoms in survivors of hospital admission after coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): A systematic review and meta-analysis. Chronic Respir. Dis 2021, 18, 14799731211002240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7975482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33729021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe nas C; Palacios-Cexnxa D; G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V; Florencio LL; Cuadrado ML; Plaza-Manzano G; Navarro-Santana M Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur. J. Intern. Med 2021, 92, 55&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34167876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Lexoxn S; Wegman-Ostrosky T; Perelman C; Sepulveda R; Rebolledo PA; Cuapio A; Villapol S More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci. Rep 2021, 11, 16144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willi S; L&#xfc;thold R; Hunt A; H&#xe4;nggi NV; Sejdiu D; Scaff C; Bender N; Staub K Patricia Schlagenhauf COVID-19 sequelae in adults aged less than 50 years: A systematic review. Travel Med. Infect. Dis 2021, 40, 101995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7898978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33631340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afzal A; Saleel CA; Bhattacharyya S; Satish N; Samuel OD; Badruddin IA Merits and limitations of mathematical modeling and computational simulations in mitigation of COVID-19 pandemic: A comprehensive review. Arch. Comput. Methods Eng 2022, 29, 1311&#x2013;1337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8356220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34393475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napolitano F; Xu X; Gao X Impact of computational approaches in the fight against COVID-19: An AI guided review of 17,000 studies. Briefings Bioinform. 2022, 23, bbab456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8689952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34788381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padmanabhan R; Abed HS; Meskin N; Khattab T; Shraim M; Al-Hitmi MA A review of mathematical model-based scenario analysis and interventions for COVID-19. Comput. Methods Programs Biomed 2021, 209, 106301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8314871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34392001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J Mathematical models for COVID-19: Applications, limitations, and potentials. J. Public Health Emerg 2020, 4, 9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7386428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32724894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antony B; Blau H; Casiraghi E; Loomba JJ; Callahan TJ; Laraway BJ; Wilkins KJ; Antonescu CC; Valentini G; Williams AE; et al. Predictive models of long COVID. eBioMedicine 2023, 96, 104777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10494314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37672869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia C; Zurbuchen Y; Taeschler P; Ballouz T; Menges D; Hasler S; Adamo S; Raeber ME; B&#xe4;chli E; Rudiger A; et al. Immunoglobulin signature predicts risk of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat. Commun 2022, 13, 446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8789854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35078982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estiri H; Strasser ZH; Brat GA; Semenov YR; Consortium for Characterization of COVID-19 by EHR (4CE); Patel CJ; Murphy SN Evolving phenotypes of non-hospitalized patients that indicate long COVID. BMC Med. 2021, 19, 249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34565368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z; Yin Z; Mi Z; Guo B Long-COVID inducement mechanism based on the path module correlation coefficient. Mathematics 2023, 11, 1368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaff ER; Girvin AT; Bennett TD; Bhatia A; Brooks IM; Deer RR; Dekermanjian JP; Jolley SE; Kahn MG; Kostka K; et al. Identifying who has long COVID in the USA: A machine learning approach using N3C data. Lancet Digital Health 2022, 4, e532&#x2013;e541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9110014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35589549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH; Murray B; Varsavsky T; Graham MS; Penfold RS; Bowyer RC; Pujol JC; Klaser K; Antonelli M; Canas LS; et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat. Med 2021, 27, 626&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cevik M; Tate M; Lloyd O; Maraolo AE; Schafers J; Ho A SARS-CoV-2, SARS-CoV, and MERS-CoV viral load dynamics, duration of viral shedding, and infectiousness: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Microbe 2021, 2, e13&#x2013;e22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33521734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Driessche P; Watmough J Reproduction numbers and sub-threshold endemic equilibria for compartmental models of disease transmission. Math. Biosci 2001, 180, 29&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12387915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korobeinikov A Lyapunov functions and global properties for SEIR and SEIS epidemic models. Math. Med. Biol 2004, 21, 75&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15228100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J Mathematical models for cholera dynamics&#x2014;A review. Microorganisms 2022, 10, 2358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9783556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36557611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Datasets from Tennessee Department of Health. Available online: https://www.tn.gov/health/cedep/ncov/data/downloadable-datasets.html (accessed on
1 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics: Prevalence of Ongoing Symptoms following Coronavirus (COVID-19) INFECTION in the UK. Available online: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/datasets/ (accessed on
1 September 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Census Bureau Quick Facts: Tennessee. Available online: https://www.census.gov/quickfacts/TN (accessed on
1 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arias E; Xu J; Tejada-Vera B; Bastian B U.S. State Life Tables, 2019. Natl. Vital Stat. Rep 2022, 70, 1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35157570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne AW; McEnvoy D; Collins AB; Hunt K; Casey M; Barber A; Butler F; Griffin J; Lane EA; McAloon C; et al. Inferred duration of infectious period of SARS-CoV-2: Rapid scoping review and analysis of available evidence for asymptomatic and symptomatic COVID-19 cases. BMJ Open 2020, 10, 039856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7409948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson B; Wang J How does the latency period impact the modeling of COVID-19 transmission dynamics? Math. Appl. Sci. Eng 2022, 3, 60&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9302022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35873089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kates J; Dawson L; Anderson E; Rouw A; Michaud J; Singer N COVID-19 Vaccine Breakthrough Cases: Data from the States. Kaiser Family Foundation, 30 July 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellwein LM; Tran HT; Zapata C; Novak V; Olufsen MS Sensitivity analysis and model assessment: Mathematical models for arterial blood flow and blood pressure. Cardiovasc. Eng 2008, 8, 94&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18080757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman A; Kuddus MA Modelling the transmission dynamics of COVID-19 in six high-burden countries. BioMed Res. Int 2021, 2021, 5089184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8172286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34124240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization: Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) Situation Reports. Available online: https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/situation-reports (accessed on
1 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan NA; Johnson L Defining long COVID: Going back to the start. Med 2021, 2, 501&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7992371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33786465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ; McIvor C; Whyatt G; Adams A; Harvey O; McLean L; Walshaw C; Kemp S; Corrado J; Singh R; et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. J. Med. Virol 2021, 93, 1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che E; Yakubu AA A discrete-time risk-structured model of cholera infections in Cameroon. J. Biol. Dyn 2021, 15, 523&#x2013;562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H; Yamamoto N Using a partial differential equation with Google Mobility data to predict COVID-19 in Arizona. Math. Biosci. Eng 2020, 17, 4891&#x2013;4904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33120533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Z; Wang J A two-phase fluid model for epidemic flow. Infect. Dis. Model 2023, 8, 920&#x2013;938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10403727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37547262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Koufi A; Koufi NE Stochastic differential equation model of COVID-19: Case study of Pakistan. Results Phys. 2022, 34, 105218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8782735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35096520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni no-Torres D; R&#xed;os-Guti&#xe9;rrez A; Arunachalam V; Ohajunwa C; Seshaiyer P Stochastic modeling, analysis, and simulation of the COVID-19 pandemic with explicit behavioral changes in Bogot&#xe1;: A case study. Infect. Dis. Model 2022, 7, 199&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8718868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35005324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>