<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38112151</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical and electrocardiographic correlates of myocardial dysfunction after COVID-19 in nonhospitalised patients in long-term follow-up. Data from the polish long-covid cardiovascular study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e29331</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e29331</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.29331</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Clinical evidence indicates that COVID-19 is a multiorgan disease that significantly impacts the cardiovascular system. However, little is known about the predictors of myocardial dysfunction after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Therefore, this research aimed to evaluate the clinical and electrocardiographic correlates of myocardial dysfunction after SARS-CoV-2 infection in nonhospitalised patients without previously diagnosed cardiovascular disease. This observational study included 448 patients selected from the database of 4142 patients in the Polish Long-Covid Cardiovascular study. All patients underwent a 12-lead electrocardiogram (ECG); 24-h Holter ECG monitoring, 24/7 ambulatory blood pressure monitoring, echocardiography, and cardiac magnetic resonance imaging. According to the results of diagnostic tests, patients were divided into two groups depending on the occurrence of myocardial dysfunction after COVID-19. Group 1-without myocardial dysfunction after COVID-19-consisted of 419 patients, with a mean age of 48.82 (SD&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;11.91), and Group 2 (29 patients)-with myocardial dysfunction after COVID-19, with a mean age of 51.45 (SD&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;12.92). When comparing the analysed groups, there were significantly more men in Group 2 (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.006). QRS (corresponds to the time of ventricular contraction in an electrocardiographic examination) fragmentation (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.031), arrhythmias (atrial fibrillation, supraventricular extrasystole, ventricular extrasystole) (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.008), and male gender (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.007) were independently associated with myocardial dysfunction after COVID-19. The study showed that myocardial damage after COVID-19 affects men more often and is independent of typical clinical factors and the severity of the disease course. The QRS fragmentation and arrhythmias observed in the ECG indicate the possibility of myocardial dysfunction in patients after COVID-19, which may be a valuable marker for physicians.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Journal of Medical Virology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kapusta</LastName><ForeName>Joanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5082-3641</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Diseases, Rehabilitation, and Physical Medicine, Medical University of Lodz, Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Babicki</LastName><ForeName>Mateusz</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7719-6959</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Wroclaw Medical University, Wroclaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pieniawska-&#x15a;miech</LastName><ForeName>Karolina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology and Pediatrics, The J. Gromkowski Provincial Specialist Hospital, Wroclaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Immunology, Wroclaw Medical University, Wroclaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ka&#x142;uzi&#x144;ska-Ko&#x142;at</LastName><ForeName>&#x17b;aneta</ForeName><Initials>&#x17b;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Functional Genomics, Medical University of Lodz, Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ko&#x142;at</LastName><ForeName>Damian</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine and Experimental Surgery, Medical University of Lodz, Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jankowski</LastName><ForeName>Piotr</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine and Geriatric Cardiology, Medical Centre for Postgraduate Education, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kasprzak</LastName><ForeName>Jaros&#x142;aw D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>I Chair and Department of Cardiology, Medical University of Lodz, Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wejner-Mik</LastName><ForeName>Paulina</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>I Chair and Department of Cardiology, Medical University of Lodz, Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bianek-Bodzak</LastName><ForeName>Agnieszka</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging Techniques, Medical University of Lodz, Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chudzik</LastName><ForeName>Micha&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine and Geriatric Cardiology, Medical Centre for Postgraduate Education, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Hypertension and Family Medicine, Medical University of Lodz, Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>The Medical Centre of Postgraduate Education</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018660" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Pressure Monitoring, Ambulatory</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009202" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiomyopathies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004562" MajorTopicYN="N">Electrocardiography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006321" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011044" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Poland</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myocardial dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myocardial injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nonhospitalised</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">predictors</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38112151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.29331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Moslehi N, Jahromy M, Ashrafi P, et al. Multi-organ system involvement in coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a mega review. J Family Med Prim Care. 2022;11:5014-5023. doi:10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_1570_21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatzis DG, Magounaki K, Pantazopoulos I, Bhaskar SMM. COVID-19 and the cardiovascular system-current knowledge and future perspectives. World J Clin Cases. 2022;10:9602-9610. doi:10.12998/wjcc.v10.i27.9602</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangalore S, Sharma A, Slotwiner A, et al. ST-segment elevation in patients with Covid-19 - a case series. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:2478-2480. doi:10.1056/NEJMc2009020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inciardi RM, Lupi L, Zaccone G, et al. Cardiac involvement in a patient with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:819-824. doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2020.1096</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Osch D, Asselbergs FW, Teske AJ. Takotsubo cardiomyopathy in COVID-19: a case report. Haemodynamic and therapeutic considerations. Eur Heart J Case Rep. 2020;4:1-6. doi:10.1093/ehjcr/ytaa271</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Wang J, Yan Y, Zhang Z, Gong W, Nie S. Clinical characterization and possible pathological mechanism of acute myocardial injury in COVID-19. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9:862571. doi:10.3389/fcvm.2022.862571</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chitsazan M, Amin A, Chitsazan M, et al. Heart failure with preserved ejection fraction in coronavirus disease 2019 patients: the promising role of diuretic therapy in critically ill patients. ESC Heart Fail. 2021;8:1610-1614. doi:10.1002/ehf2.13175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan P. NICE guideline on long COVID. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:129. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00031-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021;11:16144. doi:10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman B, Bluemke DA, L&#xfc;scher TF, Neubauer S. Long COVID: post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 with a cardiovascular focus. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:1157-1172. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehac031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648. doi:10.1136/bmj.n1648</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Mukherjee S. In silico studies on the comparative characterization of the interactions of SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein with ACE-2 receptor homologs and human TLRs. J Med Virol. 2020;92:2105-2113. doi:10.1002/jmv.25987</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Das NC, Patra R, Mukherjee S. In silico analyses on the comparative sensing of SARS-CoV-2 mRNA by the intracellular TLRs of humans. J Med Virol. 2021;93:2476-2486. doi:10.1002/jmv.26776</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patra R, Chandra Das N, Mukherjee S. Targeting human TLRs to combat COVID-19: a solution? J Med Virol. 2021;93:615-617. doi:10.1002/jmv.26387</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Mukherjee G, Mukherjee S. Chemotherapy vs. immunotherapy in combating nCOVID19: an update. Hum Immunol. 2021;82:649-658. doi:10.1016/j.humimm.2021.05.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee S. Toll-like receptor 4 in COVID-19: friend or foe? Future Virol. 2022;17:415-417. doi:10.2217/fvl-2021-0249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Wang Z, Sun H, et al. Thrombosis and coagulopathy in COVID-19: current understanding and implications for antithrombotic treatment in patients treated with percutaneous coronary intervention. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2020;7:599334. doi:10.3389/fcvm.2020.599334</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashton R, Ansdell P, Hume E, et al. COVID-19 and the long-term cardio-respiratory and metabolic health complications. Rev Cardiovasc Med. 2022;23:053. doi:10.31083/j.rcm2302053</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung MK, Zidar DA, Bristow MR, et al. COVID-19 and cardiovascular disease: from bench to bedside. Circ Res. 2021;128:1214-1236. doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.121.317997</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim GB. Myocardial injury in patients with COVID-19. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2020;17:454. doi:10.1038/s41569-020-0408-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CCE, Ali K, Connell D, et al. COVID-19-Associated cardiovascular complications. Diseases. 2021;9:47. doi:10.3390/diseases9030047</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Zhao P, Tang D, et al. Cardiac involvement in patients recovered from COVID-2019 identified using magnetic resonance imaging. JACC: Cardiovasc Imaging. 2020;13:2330-2339. doi:10.1016/j.jcmg.2020.05.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotecha T, Knight DS, Razvi Y, et al. Patterns of myocardial injury in recovered troponin-positive COVID-19 patients assessed by cardiovascular magnetic resonance. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:1866-1878. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehab075</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntmann VO, Carerj ML, Wieters I, et al. Outcomes of cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in patients recently recovered from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:1265-1273. doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2020.3557</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changal K, Veria S, Mack S, et al. Myocardial injury in hospitalized COVID-19 patients: a retrospective study, systematic review, and meta-analysis. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2021;21:626. doi:10.1186/s12872-021-02450-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>2020. Agencja Oceny Technologii Medycznych i Taryfikacji. Polskie zalecenia diagnostyczno-terapeutyczne oraz organizacyjne w zakresie opieki nad osobami zaka&#x17c;onymi lub nara&#x17c;onymi na zaka&#x17c;enie SARS-CoV-2. https://www.aotm.gov.pl/media/2020/07/2020.04.25_zalecenia-covid19_v1.11-1.pdf).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh TA, Metra M, Adamo M, et al. 2021 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:3599-3726. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehab368</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Post-COVID Conditions: Information for Healthcare Providers. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-conditions.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang RM, Badano LP, Mor-Avi V, et al. Recommendations for cardiac chamber quantification by echocardiography in adults: an update from the American Society of Echocardiography and the European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2015;28:1-39e14. doi:10.1016/j.echo.2014.10.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayabuchi M, Matsuki Y, Kidoguchi S, Shigemi K. A method for calculating left ventricular end-diastolic volume as an index of left ventricular preload from the pre-ejection period, ejection time, blood pressure, and stroke volume: a prospective, observational study. BMC Anesthesiol. 2023;23:143. doi:10.1186/s12871-023-02103-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazett HC. An analysis of the time-relations of electrocardiograms. Ann Noninvasive Electrocardiol. 1997;2:177-194. doi:10.1111/j.1542-474X.1997.tb00325.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain R, Singh R, Yamini S, Das M. Fragmented ECG as a risk marker in cardiovascular diseases. Curr Cardiol Rev. 2014;10:277-286. doi:10.2174/1573403x10666140514103451</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieniawska-Smiech K, Kuraszewicz A, Sado J, Smiech K, Lewandowicz-Uszynska A. Assessment of COVID-19 incidence and the ability to synthesise anti-SARS-CoV-2 antibodies of paediatric patients with primary immunodeficiency. J Clin Med. 2021;10(21):5111. doi:10.3390/jcm10215111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akkaif MA, Bitar AN, Al-Kaif L, et al. The management of myocardial injury related to SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis. 2022;9:307. doi:10.3390/jcdd9090307</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z, Shi L, Wang Y, et al. Pathological findings of COVID-19 associated with acute respiratory distress syndrome. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8:420-422. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30076-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng YY, Ma YT, Zhang JY, Xie X. COVID-19 and the cardiovascular system. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2020;17:259-260. doi:10.1038/s41569-020-0360-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindner D, Fitzek A, Br&#xe4;uninger H, et al. Association of cardiac infection with SARS-CoV-2 in confirmed COVID-19 autopsy cases. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:1281-1285. doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2020.3551</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingul CB, Grimsmo J, Mecinaj A, et al. Cardiac dysfunction and arrhythmias 3 months after hospitalization for COVID-19. J Am Heart Assoc. 2022;11:e023473. doi:10.1161/JAHA.121.023473</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peretto G, Sala S, Rizzo S, et al. Arrhythmias in myocarditis: state of the art. Heart Rhythm. 2019;16:793-801. doi:10.1016/j.hrthm.2018.11.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Li X, Chen M, Feng Y, Xiong C. The ACE2 expression in human heart indicates new potential mechanism of heart injury among patients infected with SARS-CoV-2. Cardiovasc Res. 2020;116:1097-1100. doi:10.1093/cvr/cvaa078</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siripanthong B, Nazarian S, Muser D, et al. Recognizing COVID-19-related myocarditis: the possible pathophysiology and proposed guideline for diagnosis and management. Heart Rhythm. 2020;17:1463-1471. doi:10.1016/j.hrthm.2020.05.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varney JA, Dong VS, Tsao T, et al. COVID-19 and arrhythmia: an overview. J Cardiol. 2022;79:468-475. doi:10.1016/j.jjcc.2021.11.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biasco L, Klersy C, Beretta GS, et al. Comparative frequency and prognostic impact of myocardial injury in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 and influenza. Eur Heart J Open. 2021;1:oeab025. doi:10.1093/ehjopen/oeab025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahsoun A, Fakih Y, Zareef R, Bitar F, Arabi M. Corticosteroids in COVID-19: pros and cons. Front Med. 2023;10:1202504. doi:10.3389/fmed.2023.1202504</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abani O, Abbas A, Abbas F, et al. recoverytrial@ndph.ox.ac.uk RCGEa, Group RC Higher dose corticosteroids in patients admitted to hospital with COVID-19 who are hypoxic but not requiring ventilatory support (RECOVERY): a randomised, controlled, open-label, platform trial. Lancet. 2023;401:1499-1507. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(23)00510-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks D, Schulman-Rosenbaum R, Griff M, Lester J, Low Wang CC. Glucocorticoid-induced hyperglycemia including dexamethasone-associated hyperglycemia in COVID-19 infection: a systematic review. Endocr Pract. 2022;28:1166-1177. doi:10.1016/j.eprac.2022.07.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Deng J, Heybati K, et al. Efficacy and safety of corticosteroid regimens for the treatment of hospitalized COVID-19 patients: a meta-analysis. Future Virol. 2022;17:463-489. doi:10.2217/fvl-2021-0244</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bistrovic P, Lucijanic M. Remdesivir might induce changes in electrocardiogram beyond bradycardia in patients with coronavirus disease 2019-the pilot study. J Med Virol. 2021;93:5724-5725. doi:10.1002/jmv.27177</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touafchia A, Bagheri H, Carri&#xe9; D, et al. Serious bradycardia and remdesivir for coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19): a new safety concerns. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:791.e5-791.e8. doi:10.1016/j.cmi.2021.02.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta AK, Parker BM, Priyadarshi V, Parker J. Cardiac adverse events with remdesivir in COVID-19 infection. Cureus. 2020;12:11132. doi:10.7759/cureus.11132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewland TA, Whitman IR, Win S, et al. Prospective arrhythmia surveillance after a COVID-19 diagnosis. Open Heart. 2022;9:e001758. doi:10.1136/openhrt-2021-001758</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angeli F, Spanevello A, De Ponti R, et al. Electrocardiographic features of patients with COVID-19 pneumonia. Eur J Intern Med. 2020;78:101-106. doi:10.1016/j.ejim.2020.06.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrero P, Piazza I, Grosu A, Brambilla P, Sironi S, Senni M. QRS fragmentation as possible new marker of fibrosis in patients with myocarditis. Preliminary validation with cardiac magnetic resonance. Eur J Heart Fail. 2019;21:1160-1161. doi:10.1002/ejhf.1413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barman HA, Atici A, Alici G, et al. The effect of the severity COVID-19 infection on electrocardiography. Am J Emerg Med. 2021;46:317-322. doi:10.1016/j.ajem.2020.10.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siedlecki P, Kurpesa M. Electrocardiographic changes in patients with COVID-19. Folia Cardiol. 2022;17:35-39. doi:10.5603/fc.2022.0005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vita A, Ravenna SE, Covino M, et al. Electrocardiographic findings and clinical outcome in patients with COVID-19 or other acute infectious respiratory diseases. J Clin Med. 2020;9:3647. doi:10.3390/jcm9113647</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Mukherjee S. Taming the storm in the heart: exploring different therapeutic choices against myocardial inflammation in COVID-19. Recent Adv Anti-Infect Drug Discov. 2021;16:89-93. doi:10.2174/2772434416666210616124505</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>