<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33823427</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-7862</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>46</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European neuropsychopharmacology : the journal of the European College of Neuropsychopharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur Neuropsychopharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cognitive impairments four months after COVID-19 hospital discharge: Pattern, severity and association with illness variables.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>39</StartPage><EndPage>48</EndPage><MedlinePgn>39-48</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.03.019</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0924-977X(21)00174-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The ongoing Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic has affected more than 100 million people and clinics are being established for diagnosing and treating lingering symptoms, so called long-COVID. A key concern are neurological and long-term cognitive complications. At the same time, the prevalence and nature of the cognitive sequalae of COVID-19 are unclear. The present study aimed to investigate&#xa0;the frequency, pattern and severity of cognitive impairments 3-4 months after COVID-19 hospital discharge, their relation to subjective cognitive complaints, quality of life and illness variables. We recruited patients at their follow-up visit at the respiratory outpatient clinic, Copenhagen University Hospital, Bispebjerg, approximately four months after hospitalisation with COVID-19. Patients underwent pulmonary, functional and cognitive assessments. Twenty-nine patients were included. The percentage of patients with clinically significant cognitive impairment ranged from 59% to 65% depending on the applied cut-off for clinical relevance of cognitive impairment, with verbal learning and executive functions being most affected. Objective cognitive impairment scaled with subjective cognitive complaints, lower work function and poorer quality of life. Cognitive impairments were associated with d-dimer levels during acute illness and residual pulmonary dysfunction. In conclusion, these&#xa0;findings provide new evidence for frequent cognitive sequelae of COVID-19 and indicate an association with the severity of the lung affection and potentially restricted cerebral oxygen delivery. Further, the associations with quality of life and functioning call for systematic cognitive screening of patients after recovery from severe COVID-19 illness and implementation of targeted treatments for patients with persistent cognitive impairments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021. Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miskowiak</LastName><ForeName>K W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark; NEAD Group, Copenhagen Affective Disorder Research Centre (CADIC), Psychiatric Centre Copenhagen, Copenhagen University Hospital, Rigshospitalet, Blegdamsvej 9, DK-2100 Copenhagen, Denmark. Electronic address: Kamilla.miskowiak@regionh.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnsen</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Copenhagen University Hospital at Bispebjerg, Copenhagen, Denmark; Respiratory Research Unit, Department of Respiratory Medicine, Copenhagen University Hospital at Bispebjerg, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sattler</LastName><ForeName>S M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Copenhagen University Hospital at Bispebjerg, Copenhagen, Denmark; Respiratory Research Unit, Department of Respiratory Medicine, Copenhagen University Hospital at Bispebjerg, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nielsen</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark; NEAD Group, Copenhagen Affective Disorder Research Centre (CADIC), Psychiatric Centre Copenhagen, Copenhagen University Hospital, Rigshospitalet, Blegdamsvej 9, DK-2100 Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kunalan</LastName><ForeName>K</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Copenhagen University Hospital at Bispebjerg, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rungby</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, Bispebjerg University Hospital, Denmark; Copenhagen Center for Translational Research, Copenhagen University Hospital, Bispebjerg and Frederiksberg, 2400 Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lapperre</LastName><ForeName>T</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonology, University Hospital Antwerp, Belgium; Laboratory of Experimental Medicine and Paediatrics, University of Antwerp, Antwerp, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Porsberg</LastName><ForeName>C M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Copenhagen University Hospital at Bispebjerg, Copenhagen, Denmark; Respiratory Research Unit, Department of Respiratory Medicine, Copenhagen University Hospital at Bispebjerg, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Eur Neuropsychopharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9111390</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0924-977X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003718" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Denmark</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010351" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Discharge</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="Y">trends</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="Y">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive impairment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors report no conflicts of interest in relation to the current manuscript. Outside of the present work, KWM reports having received consultancy fees from Janssen-Cilag and Lundbeck; JR reports having received consultancy fees from Novo Nordisk, Boehringer-Ingelheim and Astra-Zeneca; CP reports having received consultancy honararia and unrestricted grants from Astra Zeneca, Novartis, Sanofi, GSK, TEVA, ALK, Chiesi and Pharmaxis in the past three years; TL, SJ, SLN, KK and SMS report no conflicts of interest outside of the present work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33823427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.03.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0924-977X(21)00174-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Achar A., Ghosh C. COVID-19-associated neurological disorders: the potential route of CNS invasion and blood-brain relevance. Cells. 2020;9(11):2360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7692725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33120941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attix D.K., Story T.J., Chelune G.J., Ball J.D., Stutts M.L., Hart R.P., Barth J.T. The prediction of change: normative neuropsychological trajectories. Clin. Neuropsychol. 2009;23:21&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18720272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avula A., Nalleballe K., Narula N., Sapozhnikov S., Dandu V., Toom S., Glaser A., Elsayegh D. COVID-19 presenting as stroke. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;87:115&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32360439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Army Individual Test Battery . War Department, Adjutant General's Office; Washington, DC: 1944. Manual of Directions and Scoring.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broadbent D.E., Cooper P.F., FitzGerald P., Parkes K.R. The Cognitive Failures Questionnaire (CFQ) and its correlates. Br. J. Clin. Psychol. 1982;21:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7126941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celli B.R., MacNee W., Force A.E.T. Standards for the diagnosis and treatment of patients with COPD: a summary of the ATS/ERS position paper. Eur. Respir. J. 2004;23:932&#x2013;946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15219010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couzin-Frankel J. The mystery of the pandemic's 'happy hypoxia. Science. 2020;368:455&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32355007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desforges M., Le Coupanec A., Dubeau P., Bourgouin A., Lajoie L., Dube M., Talbot P.J. Human coronaviruses and other respiratory viruses: underestimated opportunistic pathogens of the central nervous system? Viruses. 2019;12(1):14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7020001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31861926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dube M., Le Coupanec A., Wong A.H.M., Rini J.M., Desforges M., Talbot P.J. Axonal transport enables neuron-to-neuron propagation of human coronavirus OC43. J. Virol. 2018;92 e00404-00418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29925652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duff K. Evidence-based indicators of neuropsychological change in the individual patient: relevant concepts and methods. Arch. Clin. Neuropsychol. 2012;27:248&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3499091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22382384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrenreich H.E., Weissenborn K., Begemann M., Busch M., Vieta E., Miskowiak K. Erythropoietin as candidate for supportive treatment of severe COVID-19. Mol. Med. 2020;16(1):58. 26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7297268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32546125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu J., Korteweg C. Pathology and pathogenesis of severe acute respiratory syndrome. Am. J. Pathol. 2007;170:1136&#x2013;1147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1829448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17392154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualtieri C.T., Morgan D.W. The frequency of cognitive impairment in patients with anxiety, depression, and bipolar disorder: an unaccounted source of variance in clinical trials. J. Clin. Psychiatry. 2008;69:1122&#x2013;1130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18572982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampshire, A., Trender, W., Chamberlain, S.R., Jolly, A., Grant, J.E., Patrick, F., Miazibuko, N., Williams, C., Barnby, J.M., Hellyer, P., Mehta, M.A., 2020. Cognitive Deficits in People Who Have Recovered From COVID-19 Relative to Controls: An N=84,285 Online Study. Preprints.org.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8298139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34316551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J., Kremer S., Merdji H., Clere-Jehl R., Schenck M., Kummerlen C., Collange O., Boulay C., Fafi-Kremer S., Ohana M., Anheim M., Meziani F. Neurologic features in severe SARS-CoV-2 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020;382:2268&#x2013;2270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7179967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32294339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins R.O., Gale S.D., Weaver L.K. Brain atrophy and cognitive impairment in survivors of acute respiratory distress syndrome. Brain Inj. 2006;20:263&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16537268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins R.O., Weaver L.K., Collingridge D., Parkinson R.B., Chan K.J., Orme J.F., Jr Two-year cognitive, emotional, and quality-of-life outcomes in acute respiratory distress syndrome. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 2005;171:340&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15542793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hota S.K., Barhwal K., Singh S.B., Ilavazhagan G. Differential temporal response of hippocampus, cortex and cerebellum to hypobaric hypoxia: a biochemical approach. Neurochem. Int. 2007;51:384&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17531352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C., Huang L., Wang Y., Li X., Ren L., Gu X., Kang L., Guo L., Liu M., Zhou X., Luo J., Huang Z., Tu S., Zhao Y., Chen L., Xu D., Li Y., Li C., Peng L., Li Y., Xie W., Cui D., Shang L., Fan G., Xu J., Wang G., Wang Y., Zhong J., Wang C., Wang J., Zhang D., Cao B. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. The Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen J.H., St&#xf8;ttrup M.M., Nayberg E., Knorr U., Ullum H., Purdon S.E., Kessing L.V., Miskowiak K.W. Optimising screening for cognitive dysfunction in bipolar disorder: validation and evaluation of objective and subjective tools. J. Affect. Disord. 2015;187:10&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26301477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joergensen K. first ed. Dansk Psykologisk Forlag; Viborg, Denmark: 2012. Danske Normer Til Neuropsykologiske Tests.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juniper E.F., O'Byrne P.M., Guyatt G.H., Ferrie P.J., King D.R. Development and validation of a questionnaire to measure asthma control. Eur. Respir. J. 1999;14:902&#x2013;907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10573240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kremer S., Lersy F., de Seze J., Ferre J.C., Maamar A., Carsin-Nicol B., Collange O., Bonneville F., Adam G., Martin-Blondel G., Rafiq M., Geeraerts T., Delamarre L., Grand S., Krainik A., Caillard S., Constans J.M., Metanbou S., Heintz A., Helms J., Schenck M., Lefebvre N., Boutet C., Fabre X., Forestier G., de Beaurepaire I., Bornet G., Lacalm A., Oesterle H., Bolognini F., Messie J., Hmeydia G., Benzakoun J., Oppenheim C., Bapst B., Megdiche I., Henry Feugeas M.C., Khalil A., Gaudemer A., Jager L., Nesser P., Talla Mba Y., Hemmert C., Feuerstein P., Sebag N., Carre S., Alleg M., Lecocq C., Schmitt E., Anxionnat R., Zhu F., Comby P.O., Ricolfi F., Thouant P., Desal H., Boulouis G., Berge J., Kazemi A., Pyatigorskaya N., Lecler A., Saleme S., Edjlali-Goujon M., Kerleroux B., Zorn P.E., Matthieu M., Baloglu S., Ardellier F.D., Willaume T., Brisset J.C., Boulay C., Mutschler V., Hansmann Y., Mertes P.M., Schneider F., Fafi-Kremer S., Ohana M., Meziani F., David J.S., Meyer N., Anheim M., Cotton F. Brain MRI findings in severe COVID-19: a retrospective observational study. Radiology. 2020;297:E242&#x2013;E251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32544034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert, N.J.S.C., 2020. COVID_19 "Long Hauler" Symptoms Survey Report.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lersy F., Benotmane I., Helms J., Collange O., Schenck M., Brisset J.C., Chammas A., Willaume T., Lefebvre N., Solis M., Hansmann Y., Fabacher T., Caillard S., Mertes P.M., Pottecher J., Schneider F., Meziani F., Fafi-Kremer S., Kremer S. Cerebrospinal fluid features in COVID-19 patients with neurologic manifestations: correlation with brain MRI findings in 58 patients. J. Infect. Dis. 2021;223(4):600&#x2013;609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7798956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33249438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y.C., Bai W.Z., Hashikawa T. The neuroinvasive potential of SARS-CoV2 may play a role in the respiratory failure of COVID-19 patients. J. Med. Virol. 2020;92:552&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32104915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd A., Pickard A.S. The EQ-5D and the EuroQol group. Value Health. 2019;22:21&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30661629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucchese G., Floel A. Molecular mimicry between SARS-CoV-2 and respiratory pacemaker neurons. Autoimmun. Rev. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7252083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32361194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L., Jin H., Wang M., Hu Y., Chen S., He Q., Chang J., Hong C., Zhou Y., Wang D., Miao X., Li Y., Hu B. Neurologic manifestations of hospitalized patients with Coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Neurol. 2020;2020(6):683&#x2013;690. 77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7149362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miskowiak K.W., Burdick K.E., Martinez-Aran A., Bonnin C.M., Bowie C.R., Carvalho A.F., Gallagher P., Lafer B., Lopez-Jaramillo C., Sumiyoshi T., McIntyre R.S., Schaffer A., Porter R.J., Purdon S., Torres I.J., Yatham L.N., Young A.H., Kessing L.V., Vieta E. Assessing and addressing cognitive impairment in bipolar disorder: the International Society for Bipolar Disorders Targeting Cognition Task Force recommendations for clinicians. Bipolar Disord. 2018;20:184&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29345040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miskowiak K.W., Petersen J.Z., Ott C.V., Knorr U., Kessing L.V., Gallagher P., Robinson L. Predictors of the discrepancy between objective and subjective cognition in bipolar disorder: a novel methodology. Acta Psychiatr. Scand. 2016;134:511&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27644707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriguchi T., Harii N., Goto J., Harada D., Sugawara H., Takamino J., Ueno M., Sakata H., Kondo K., Myose N., Nakao A., Takeda M., Haro H., Inoue O., Suzuki-Inoue K., Kubokawa K., Ogihara S., Sasaki T., Kinouchi H., Kojin H., Ito M., Onishi H., Shimizu T., Sasaki Y., Enomoto N., Ishihara H., Furuya S., Yamamoto T., Shimada S. A first case of meningitis/encephalitis associated with SARS-Coronavirus-2. Int. J. Infect. Dis. 2020;94:55&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath A. Neurologic complications of coronavirus infections. Neurology. 2020;94(19):809&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32229625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natoli S., Oliveira V., Calabresi P., Maia L.F., Pisani A. Does SARS-Cov-2 invade the brain? Translational lessons from animal models. Eur. J. Neurol. 2020;27(9):1764&#x2013;1773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32333487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ott C.V., Bjertrup A.J., Jensen J.H., Ullum H., Sjaelland R., Purdon S.E., Vieta E., Kessing L.V., Miskowiak K.W. Screening for cognitive dysfunction in unipolar depression: validation and evaluation of objective and subjective tools. J. Affect. Disord. 2015;190:607&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26583350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ott C.V., Knorr U., Jespersen A., Obenhausen K., Roen I., Purdon S.E., Kessing L.V., Miskowiak K.W. Norms for the screen for cognitive impairment in psychiatry and cognitive trajectories in bipolar disorder. J. Affect. Disord. 2021;281:33&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33285390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxley T.J., Mocco J., Majidi S., Kellner C.P., Shoirah H., Singh I.P., De Leacy R.A., Shigematsu T., Ladner T.R., Yaeger K.A., Skliut M., Weinberger J., Dangayach N.S., Bederson J.B., Tuhrim S., Fifi J.T. Large-vessel stroke as a presenting feature of Covid-19 in the young. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020;382(20):e60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7207073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32343504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purdon S. Edmonton; Alberta, Canada: 2005. The Screen for Cognitive Impairment in Psychiatry: Administration and Psychometric Properties.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman R., Rajalakshmi R., Surya J., Ramakrishnan R., Sivaprasad S., Conroy D., Thethi J.P., Mohan V., Netuveli G. Impact on health and provision of healthcare services during the COVID-19 lockdown in India: a multicentre cross-sectional study. BMJ Open. 2021;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7817386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33468529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly M.C., Zbrozek A.S., Dukes E.M. The validity and reproducibility of a work productivity and activity impairment instrument. Pharmacoeconomics. 1993;4:353&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10146874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasannejad C., Ely E.W., Lahiri S. Long-term cognitive impairment after acute respiratory distress syndrome: a review of clinical impact and pathophysiological mechanisms. Crit. Care. 2019;23:352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6852966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31718695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenton C. Occupational Medicine; Oxford, England: 2008. The MRC Breathlessness Scale.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18441368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toscano G., Palmerini F., Ravaglia S., Ruiz L., Invernizzi P., Cuzzoni M.G., Franciotta D., Baldanti F., Daturi R., Postorino P., Cavallini A., Micieli G. Guillain-Barre syndrome associated with SARS-CoV-2. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020;382(26):2574&#x2013;2576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7182017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32302082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L., Dyer A.H., Jones K., Dunne J., Mooney A., Gaffney F., O'Connor L., Leavy D., O'Brien K., Dowds J., Sugrue J.A., Hopkins D., Martin-Loeches I., Ni Cheallaigh C., Nadarajan P., McLaughlin A.M., Bourke N.M., Bergin C., O'Farrelly C., Bannan C., Conlon N. Persistent fatigue following SARS-CoV-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS One. 2020;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troyer E.A.K., J. N., Hong S. Are we facing a crashing wave of neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19? Neuropsychiatric symptoms and potential immunologic mechanisms. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;87:34&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7152874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinkers C.H., van Amelsvoort T., Bisson J.I., Branchi I., Cryan J.F., Domschke K., Howes O.D., Manchia M., Pinto L., de Quervain D., Schmidt M.V., van der Wee N.J.A. Stress resilience during the coronavirus pandemic. Eur. Neuropsychopharmacol. 2020;35:12&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32446705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y., Xu X., Chen Z., Duan J., Hashimoto K., Yang L., Liu C., Yang C. Nervous system involvement after infection with COVID-19 and other coronaviruses. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;87:18&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32240762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z., Kang H., Li S., Zhao X. Understanding the neurotropic characteristics of SARS-CoV-2: from neurological manifestations of COVID-19 to potential neurotropic mechanisms. J. Neurol. 2021;267(8):2179&#x2013;2184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7249973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32458193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H., Lu S., Chen J., Wei N., Wang D., Lyu H., Shi C., Hu S. The landscape of cognitive function in recovered COVID-19 patients. J. Psychiatr. Res. 2020;129:98&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7324344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32912598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>