<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37287442</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-185X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of rheumatic diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Rheum Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Serositis and lymphopenia are common features of systemic lupus erythematosus following SARS-CoV-2 infection: A case report and literature review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2267</StartPage><EndPage>2271</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2267-2271</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1756-185X.14767</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) can affect a number of human systems, including the respiratory, cardiovascular, neurological, gastrointestinal, and musculoskeletal systems. These symptoms persist long after the acute infection has healed and is called "long COVID". Interestingly, there have been a series of reports that SARS-CoV-2 infections trigger the development of various autoimmune diseases such as systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE), inflammatory arthritis, myositis, vasculitis. Here, we report a novel case of SLE characterized by persistent pleural effusion and lymphopenia following SARS-CoV-2 infection. This is the first case in the Western Pacific region to our knowledge. Furthermore, we reviewed 10 similar cases including our case. By looking at the characteristics of each case, we found that serositis and lymphopenia are common features of SLE following SARS-CoV-2 infection. Our finding suggests that patients with prolonged pleural effusion and/or lymphopenia after COVID-19 should be checked for autoantibodies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Asia Pacific League of Associations for Rheumatology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kioi</LastName><ForeName>Yoshiyuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2127-3545</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine and Clinical Immunology, Suita Municipal Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yorifuji</LastName><ForeName>Hideki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7035-9359</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine and Clinical Immunology, Suita Municipal Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Higami</LastName><ForeName>Yuichi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine and Clinical Immunology, Suita Municipal Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katada</LastName><ForeName>Yoshinori</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2467-9770</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine and Clinical Immunology, Suita Municipal Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Rheum Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101474930</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-1841</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012700" MajorTopicYN="Y">Serositis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008231" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lymphopenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010996" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pleural Effusion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000740" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anemia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013921" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thrombocytopenia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SLE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lymphopenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serositis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37287442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.14767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Phillips S, Williams MA. Confronting our next National Health Disaster - long-haul Covid. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:577-579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid - mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Sawalha AH, Lu Q. COVID-19 and autoimmune diseases. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2021;33:155-162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacchi MC, Tamiazzo S, Stobbione P, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection as a trigger of autoimmune response. Clin Transl Sci. 2021;14:898-907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacharias H, Dubey S, Koduri G, D'Cruz D. Rheumatological complications of Covid 19. Autoimmun Rev. 2021;20:102883.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahemed S, Zimba O, Gasparyan AY. COIVD-19 and the clinical course of rheumatic manifestations. Clin Rheumatol. 2021;40:2611-2619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinosa G, Prieto-Gonz&#xe1;lez S, Llevadot M, et al. The impact of SARS-CoV-2 coronavirus infection in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus from a single center in Catalonia. Clin Rheumatol. 2021;40:2057-2063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perl A. Systems biology of lupus - mapping the impact of genomic and environmental factors on gene expression signatures, celluar signaling, metabolic pathways, hormonal and cytokine imbalance, and selecting targets for treatment. Autoimmunity. 2010;43:32-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caza T, Oaks Z, Perl A. Interplay of infections, autoimmunity, and immunosuppression in systemic lupus erythematosus. Int Rev Immunol. 2014;33:330-363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClain MT, Heinlen LD, Dennis GJ, et al. Early events in lupus humoral autoimmunity suggest initiation through molecular mimicry. Nat Med. 2005;11:85-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aringer M, Costenbader K, Daikh D, et al. 2019 European league against rheumatism/American College of Rheumatology classification criteria for systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis. 2019;78:1151-1159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aringer M, Costenbader K, Daikh D, et al. 2019 European league against rheumatism/American College of Rheumatology classification criteria for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2019;71:1400-1412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy WJ, Longo DL. A possible role for anti-idiotype antibodies in SARS-CoV-2 infection and vaccination. N Engl J Med. 2022;386:394-396. doi:10.1056/NEJMcibr2113694</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodruff MC, Ramonell RP, Nguyen DC, et al. Extrafollicular B cell responses correlate with neutralizing antibodies and morbidity in COVID-19. Nat Immunol. 2020;21:1506-1516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoso ME, Hundal J, Feterman D, et al. Concomitant new diagnosis of systemic lupus erythematosus and COVID-19 with possible antiphospholipid syndrome. Just a coincidence? A case report and review of intertwining pathophysiology. Clin Rheumatol. 2020;39:2811-2815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Aoud S, Morin C, Lorriaux P, et al. COVID-19 presenting as lupus erythematosus-like syndrome. Disaster Med Public Health Prep. 2021;15:e12-e15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slimani Y, Abbassi R, El Fatoiki F-Z, et al. Systemic lupus erythematosus and varicella-like rash following COVID-19 in a previously healthypatient. J Med Virol. 2021;93:1184-1187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonometti R, Sacchi MC, Stobbione P, et al. The first case of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) triggered by COVID-19 infection. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2020;24:9695-9697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gracia-Ramos AE, Saavedra-Salinas MA. Can the SARS-CoV-2 infection trigger systemic lupus erythematosus? A case-based review. Rheumatol Int. 2021;41:799-809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hali F, Jabri H, Chiheb S, Hafiani Y, Nsiri A. A concomitant diagnosis of COVID19 infection and systemic lupus erythematosus complicated by a macrophage activation syndrome: a new case report. Int J Dermatol. 2021;60:1030-1031. doi:10.1111/ijd.15592</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamani B, Moeini Taba SM, Shayestehpour M. Systemic lupus erythematosus manifestation following COVID-19: a case report. J Med Case Reports. 2021;15:29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assar S, Pournazari M, Soufivand P, Mohamadzadeh D. Systemic lupus erythematosus after coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19) infection: case-based review. Egypt Rheumatol. 2022;44:145-149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajmusa M, Akbar RA. Systemic lupus erythematosus manifestation following COVID-19 infection: a coincidental or causal relation. Yemen J Med. 2022;1:46-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis MJ, Jawad AS. The effect of ethnicity and genetic ancestry on the epidemiology, clinical features and outcome of systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatology. 2017;56:i67-i77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boddaert J, Huong DLT, Amoura Z, Wechsler B, Godeau P, Piette JC. Late-onset systemic lupus erythematosus: a personal series of 47 patients and pooled analysis of 714 cases in the literature. Medicine. 2004;83:348-359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascolini S, Vannini A, Deleonardi G, et al. COVID-19 and immunological dysregulation: can autoantibodies be useful? Clin Transl Sci. 2020;14:502-508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amezcua-Guerra L, Rojas-Velasco G, Brianza-Padilla M, et al. Presence of antiphospholipid antibodies in COVID-19: case series study. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;80:e73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castillo-Mart&#xed;nez D, Torres Z, Amezcua-Guerra LM, Pineda C. Are antiphospholipid antibodies just a common epiphenomenon or are they causative of immune-mediated coagulopathy in COVID-19? Clin Rheumatol. 2021;40:3015-3019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujii H, Tsuji T, Yuba T, et al. High levels of anti-SSA/Ro antibodies in COVID19 patients with severe respiratory failure: a case-based review. Clin Rheumatol. 2020;39:3171-3175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahemed S, Gasparyan AY, Zimba O. Comorbidities in rheumatic diseases need special consideration during the COVID-19 pandemic. Rheumatol Int. 2021;41:243-256.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>