<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37773635</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical Features and Follow-up of Referred Children and Young People With Long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1093</StartPage><EndPage>1099</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1093-1099</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000004081</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Patient-level data on the clinical features and outcomes of children and young people referred for possible long coronavirus disease (COVID) can guide clinicians on what to expect in managing patients and advising families.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A Post-Acute COVID Clinic for persons &lt;21 years of age was established in October 2020. Intake was standardized and management was tailored to presenting symptoms. Data were abstracted from the charts of all patients evaluated through December 2021, and the study cohort consisted of patients who had a history of confirmed severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection, had &#x2265;1 symptom persisting for &#x2265;12 weeks and had no pre-existing diagnosis that explained the symptoms. A structured follow-up interview was conducted in early 2022.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 104 patients were referred, 81 of whom met inclusion criteria. The median age was 14 years (interquartile range, 13-16), and most were female, White/Caucasian and had commercial health insurance. Patients reported previously good health but over half reported moderate-to-severe disability at their first visit. Two clusters of presenting symptoms-fatigue with multiple symptoms, and fatigue and headache with cardiopulmonary symptoms-were identified. Extensive routine testing did not affirm alternative diagnoses. Incident conditions-most commonly anxiety, depression and/or panic disorder; migraines; and autonomic dysfunction-were diagnosed on clinical grounds. Telephone interviews (N = 55) revealed that 78% of patients were improved by about 6 months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Within the limits of a single-center, referral-based, observational cohort, this study provides reassurance to patients and parents in that most cases of long COVID were self-limited. Extensive evaluations may be more useful in ruling out alternative diagnoses than in affirming specific physiologic disturbances.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weakley</LastName><ForeName>Kathryn E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Norton Children's, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Louisville School of Medicine, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schikler</LastName><ForeName>Allegra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Louisville School of Medicine, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Green</LastName><ForeName>Julianne V</ForeName><Initials>JV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Norton Children's, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Louisville School of Medicine, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blatt</LastName><ForeName>Daniel B</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Norton Children's, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Louisville School of Medicine, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barton</LastName><ForeName>Shanna M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Norton Children's, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Louisville School of Medicine, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Statler</LastName><ForeName>Victoria A</ForeName><Initials>VA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Norton Children's, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Louisville School of Medicine, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feygin</LastName><ForeName>Yana</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Louisville School of Medicine, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marshall</LastName><ForeName>Gary S</ForeName><Initials>GS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8731-6926</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Norton Children's, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Louisville School of Medicine, Louisville, KY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37773635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000004081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-202312000-00022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>S&#xf8;rensen AIV, Spiliopoulos L, Bager P, et al. A nationwide questionnaire study of post-acute symptoms and health problems after SARS-CoV-2 infection in Denmark. Nat Commun. 2022;13:4213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KG, Brokstad KA, et al.; Bergen COVID-19 Research Group. Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med. 2021;27:1607&#x2013;1613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID [published correction appears in Nat Med . 2021 Jun;27(6):1116]. Nat Med. 2021;27:626&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funk AL, Kuppermann N, Florin TA, et al.; Pediatric Emergency Research Network&#x2013;COVID-19 Study Team. Post-COVID-19 Conditions Among Children 90 Days After SARS-CoV-2 Infection [published correction appears in JAMA Netw Open . 2022 Aug 1;5(8):e2231131]. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:e2223253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kompaniyets L, Bull-Otterson L, Boehmer TK, et al. Post-COVID-19 Symptoms and Conditions Among Children and Adolescents - United States, March 1, 2020-January 31, 2022. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71:993&#x2013;999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikkenborg Berg S, Dam Nielsen S, Nygaard U, et al. Long COVID symptoms in SARS-CoV-2-positive adolescents and matched controls (LongCOVIDKidsDK): a national, cross-sectional study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2022;6:240&#x2013;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Pinto Pereira SM, Shafran R, et al.; CLoCk Consortium. Physical and mental health 3 months after SARS-CoV-2 infection (long COVID) among adolescents in England (CLoCk): a national matched cohort study [published correction appears in Lancet Child Adolesc Health . 2022 Jul;6(7):e21]. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2022;6:230&#x2013;239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashkenazi-Hoffnung L, Shmueli E, Ehrlich S, et al. Long COVID in children: observations from a designated pediatric clinic. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:e509&#x2013;e511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blankenburg J, Wekenborg MK, Reichert J, et al. Comparison of mental health outcomes in seropositive and seronegative adolescents during the COVID19 pandemic. Sci Rep. 2022;12:2246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garai R, Kriv&#xe1;csy P, Herczeg V, et al. Clinical assessment of children with long COVID syndrome [published online ahead of print, 2022 Dec 7]. Pediatr Res. 2023;93:1616&#x2013;1625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao S, Lee GM, Razzaghi H, et al. Clinical features and burden of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection in children and adolescents. JAMA Pediatr. 2022;176:1000&#x2013;1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabacof L, Tosto-Mancuso J, Wood J, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome negatively impacts physical function, cognitive function, health-related quality of life, and participation. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;101:48&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Long COVID or post-COVID conditions. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html . Accessed December 13, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: What do the latest data show? Kaiser Family Foundation. Available at: https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/long-covid-what-do-latest-data-show/ . Accessed March 8, 202323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sneller MC, Liang CJ, Marques AR, et al. A longitudinal study of COVID-19 sequelae and immunity: baseline findings. Ann Intern Med. 2022;175:969&#x2013;979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hope AA, Evering TH. Postacute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection. Infect Dis Clin North Am. 2022;36:379&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robineau O, Zins M, Touvier M, et al.; Sant&#xe9;, Pratiques, Relations et In&#xe9;galit&#xe9;s Sociales en Population G&#xe9;n&#xe9;rale Pendant la Crise COVID-19&#x2013;S&#xe9;rologie (SAPRIS-SERO) Study Group. Long-lasting symptoms after an acute COVID-19 infection and factors associated with their resolution. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:e2240985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Say D, Crawford N, McNab S, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 outcomes in children with mild and asymptomatic disease. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2021;5:e22&#x2013;e23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke KEN, Jones JM, Deng Y, et al. Seroprevalence of infection-induced SARS-CoV-2 antibodies - United States, September 2021-February 2022. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71:606&#x2013;608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrino R, Chiappini E, Licari A, et al. Prevalence and clinical presentation of long COVID in children: a systematic review. Eur J Pediatr. 2022;181:3995&#x2013;4009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Pittet LF, Curtis N. How common is long COVID in children and adolescents?. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:e482&#x2013;e487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Ayuzo Del Valle NC, et al. Long-COVID in children and adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Sci Rep. 2022;12:9950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikkenborg Berg S, Palm P, Nygaard U, et al. Long COVID symptoms in SARS-CoV-2-positive children aged 0-14 years and matched controls in Denmark (LongCOVIDKidsDK): a national, cross-sectional study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2022;6:614&#x2013;623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvakumar J, Havdal LB, Drevvatne M, et al. Prevalence and characteristics associated with post-COVID-19 condition among nonhospitalized adolescents and young adults. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6:e235763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Allin B, Nugawela MD, et al.; CLoCk Consortium. Long COVID (post-COVID-19 condition) in children: a modified delphi process. Arch Dis Child. 2022;107:674&#x2013;680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker LS, Greene JW. The functional disability inventory: measuring a neglected dimension of child health status. J Pediatric Psychol. 1991;16:39&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashikar-Zuck S, Flowers SR, Claar RL, et al. Clinical utility and validity of the functional disability inventory among a multicenter sample of youth with chronic pain. Pain. 2011;152:1600&#x2013;1607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health and Human Services, Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health. National Research Action Plan on Long COVID, 200 Independence Ave SW, Washington, DC 20201. 2022. Available at: https://www.covid.gov/assets/files/National-Research-Action-Plan-on-Long-COVID-08012022.pdf . Accessed January 2, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. Available at: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188 . Accessed January 14, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, et al.; WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. WHO clinical case definition working group on post-COVID-19 condition. a clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawson RG, Jurs PC. New index for clustering tendency and its application to chemical problems. J Chem Inf Comp Sci. 1990;30:36&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rousseeuw PJ. Silhouettes: a graphical aid to the interpretation and validation of cluster analysis. J Comput Appl Math. 1987;20:53&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RDocumentation. diana: DIvisive ANAlysis Clustering. Available at: https://www.rdocumentation.org/packages/cluster/versions/2.1.4/topics/diana . Accessed January 23, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufman L, Rousseeuw PJ. Finding Groups in Data: An Introduction to Cluster Analysis. John Wiley; 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostev K, Smith L, Koyanagi A, et al. Post-COVID-19 conditions in children and adolescents diagnosed with COVID-19 [published online ahead of print, 2022 May 14]. Pediatr Res. 2022;1&#x2013;6. doi:10.1038/s41390-022-02111-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41390-022-02111-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borch L, Holm M, Knudsen M, et al. Long COVID symptoms and duration in SARS-CoV-2 positive children - a nationwide cohort study. Eur J Pediatr. 2022;181:1597&#x2013;1607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, et al. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms, and recommendations [published online ahead of print, 2023 Jan 13]. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reese JT, Blau H, Casiraghi E, et al.; N3C Consortium. Generalisable long COVID subtypes: Findings from the NIH N3C and RECOVER programmes [published online ahead of print, 2022 Dec 21]. EBioMedicine. 2022;87:104413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wacks M, Wortley E, Gregorowski A, et al. Fifteen-minute consultation: managing post-COVID-19 syndrome (long COVID) in children and young people [published online ahead of print, 2023 Apr 20]. Arch Dis Child Educ Pract Ed. 2023;edpract-2022-324950. doi:10.1136/archdischild-2022-324950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/archdischild-2022-324950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteside DM, Naini SM, Basso MR, et al. Outcomes in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) at 6 months post-infection part 2: psychological functioning. Clin Neuropsychol. 2022;36:829&#x2013;847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramoff BA, Dillingham TR, Brown LA, et al. Psychological and cognitive functioning among patients receiving outpatient rehabilitation for post-COVID sequelae: an observational study. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2023;104:11&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen NW, Stiles LE, Shaik R, et al. Characterization of autonomic symptom burden in long COVID: a global survey of 2,314 adults. Front Neurol. 2022;13:1012668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan AC, Ebinger JE, Wei J, et al. Apparent risks of postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome diagnoses after COVID-19 vaccination and SARS-Cov-2 infection. Nat Cardiovasc Res. 2022;1:1187&#x2013;1194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu E, Xie Y, Al-Aly Z. Long-term neurologic outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28:2406&#x2013;2415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Azorin D, Layos-Romero A, Porta-Etessam J, et al. Post-COVID-19 persistent headache: a multicentric 9-months follow-up study of 905 patients. Cephalalgia. 2022;42:804&#x2013;809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lester TR, Herrmann JE, Bannett Y, et al. Anxiety and depression treatment in primary care pediatrics. Pediatrics. 2023;151:e2022058846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eigenbrodt AK, Ashina H, Khan S, et al. Diagnosis and management of migraine in ten steps. Nat Rev Neurol. 2021;17:501&#x2013;514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR. Postural tachycardia syndrome (POTS). Circulation. 2013;127:2336&#x2013;2342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies. Beyond Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Available at: https://nap.nationalacademies.org/catalog/19012/beyond-myalgic-encephalomyelitischronic-fatigue-syndrome-redefining-an-illness . Accessed January 14, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siberry VGR, Rowe PC. Pediatric long COVID and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: overlaps and opportunities. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2022;41:e139&#x2013;e141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bussi&#xe8;res EL, Malboeuf-Hurtubise C, Meilleur A, et al.; PRISME-COVID Team. Consequences of the COVID-19 pandemic on children&#x2019;s mental health: a meta-analysis. Front Psychiatry. 2021;12:691659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson K, Kristoffersen DT, Dell&#x2019;Isola A, et al. Post-covid medical complaints following infection with SARS-CoV-2 omicron vs delta variants. Nat Commun. 2022;13:7363.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>