<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35571551</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2233-8276</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Asia Pacific allergy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Asia Pac Allergy</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long-COVID severe refractory cough: discussion of a case with 6-week longitudinal cough characterization.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e19</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e19</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e19</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5415/apallergy.2022.12.e19</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long coronavirus disease (COVID) refers to an array of variable and fluctuating symptoms experienced after acute illness, with signs and symptoms that persist for 8-12 weeks and are not otherwise explicable. Cough is the most common symptom of acute COVID-19, but cough may persist in some individuals for weeks or months after recovery from acute phase. Long-COVID cough patients may get stigmatised because of the public fear of contagion and reinfection. However, clinical characteristics and longitudinal course of long-COVID cough have not been reported in detail, and evidence-based treatment is also lacking. In this paper, we describe a case of long-COVID severe refractory cough with features of laryngeal hypersensitivity and dysfunction. We characterized cough using patient-reported outcomes and engaged in continuous cough frequency monitoring. Through the case study, we discuss potential mechanisms, managements, and clinical implications of long-COVID refractory cough problems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022. Asia Pacific Association of Allergy, Asthma and Clinical Immunology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Yu Ri</ForeName><Initials>YR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5749-2040</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Allergy and Clinical Immunology, Asan Medical Center, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>Ji-Yoon</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2339-7878</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Allergy and Clinical Immunology, Asan Medical Center, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Ji-Hyang</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4286-3114</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Allergy and Clinical Immunology, Asan Medical Center, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Small</LastName><ForeName>Peter M</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5403-8985</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hyfe, Inc and University of Washington, Department of Global Health, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chung</LastName><ForeName>Kian Fan</ForeName><Initials>KF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7101-1426</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Heart and Lung Institute, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Woo-Jung</ForeName><Initials>WJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4630-9922</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Allergy and Clinical Immunology, Asan Medical Center, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Asia Pac Allergy</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101561954</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2233-8276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cough</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypersensitivity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest: The authors have no financial conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35571551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9066079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5415/apallergy.2022.12.e19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Song WJ, Hui CKM, Hull JH, Birring SS, McGarvey L, Mazzone SB, Chung KF. Confronting COVID-19-associated cough and the post-COVID syndrome: role of viral neurotropism, neuroinflammation, and neuroimmune responses. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:533&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8041436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33857435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid-mechanisms, risk factors, and management. BMJ. 2021;374:n1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F Gemelli Against C-P-ACSG. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Won HK, Song WJ. Impact and disease burden of chronic cough. Asia Pac Allergy. 2021;11:e22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8103004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34007832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Won HK, Kang SY, Kang Y, An J, Lee JH, Lee SM, Kwon JW, Kim MH, Jo EJ, Lee SE, Kim SH, Kim SH, Chang YS, Kim SH, Lee BJ, Cho SH, Birring SS, Song WJ. Cough-related laryngeal sensations and triggers in adults with chronic cough: symptom profile and impact. Allergy Asthma Immunol Res. 2019;11:622&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6658400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31332974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon JW, Moon JY, Kim SH, Song WJ, Kim MH, Kang MG, Lim KH, Lee SH, Lee SM, Lee JY, Kwon HS, Kim KM, Kim SH, Kim SH, Jeong JW, Kim CW, Cho SH, Lee BJ Work Group for Chronic Cough tKAoAA, Clinical I. Reliability and validity of a Korean version of the leicester cough questionnaire. Allergy Asthma Immunol Res. 2015;7:230&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4397362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25749761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson P, Wang G, McGarvey L, Vertigan AE, Altman KW, Birring SS, Panel CEC. Treatment of unexplained chronic cough: CHEST guideline and expert panel report. Chest. 2016;149:27&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5831652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26426314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morice AH, Millqvist E, Bieksiene K, Birring SS, Dicpinigaitis P, Domingo Ribas C, Hilton Boon M, Kantar A, Lai K, McGarvey L, Rigau D, Satia I, Smith J, Song WJ, Tonia T, van den Berg JWK, van Manen MJG, Zacharasiewicz A. ERS guidelines on the diagnosis and treatment of chronic cough in adults and children. Eur Respir J. 2020;55:1901136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6942543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31515408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song DJ, Song WJ, Kwon JW, Kim GW, Kim MA, Kim MY, Kim MH, Kim SH, Kim SH, Kim SH, Kim ST, Kim SH, Kim JK, Kim JH, Kim HJ, Kim HB, Park KH, Yoon JK, Lee BJ, Lee SE, Lee YM, Lee YJ, Lim KH, Jeon YH, Jo EJ, Jee YK, Jin HJ, Choi SH, Hur GY, Cho SH, Kim SH, Lim DH. KAAACI evidence-based clinical practice guidelines for chronic cough in adults and children in Korea. Allergy Asthma Immunol Res. 2018;10:591&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6182199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30306744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabald&#xf3;n-Figueira JC, Keen E, Rudd M, Orrilo V, Blavia I, Chaccour J, Galvosas M, Small P, Lapierre SG, Chaccour C. Longitudinal passive cough monitoring and its implications for detecting changes in clinical status. ERJ Open Res. 2022 Forthcoming.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9108969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35586452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maat RC, R&#xf8;ksund OD, Halvorsen T, Skadberg BT, Olofsson J, Ellingsen TA, Aarstad HJ, Heimdal JH. Audiovisual assessment of exercise-induced laryngeal obstruction: reliability and validity of observations. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2009;266:1929&#x2013;1936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19585139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vertigan AE, Kapela SM, Kearney EK, Gibson PG. Laryngeal dysfunction in cough hypersensitivity syndrome: a cross-sectional observational study. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2018;6:2087&#x2013;2095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29729441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorent N, Vande Weygaerde Y, Claeys E, Guler Caamano Fajardo I, De Vos N, De Wever W, Salhi B, Gyselinck I, Bosteels C, Lambrecht BN, Everaerts S, Verschraegen S, Schepers C, Demeyer H, Heyns A, Depuydt P, Oeyen S, Van Bleyenbergh P, Godinas L, Dupont L, Hermans G, Derom E, Gosselink R, Janssens W, Van Braeckel E. Prospective longitudinal evaluation of hospitalised COVID-19 survivors 3 and 12 months after discharge. ERJ Open Res. 2022;8:00004&#x2013;02022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8994962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35415186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGarvey LP, Birring SS, Morice AH, Dicpinigaitis PV, Pavord ID, Schelfhout J, Nguyen AM, Li Q, Tzontcheva A, Iskold B, Green SA, Rosa C, Muccino DR, Smith JA, Smith JA COUGH-1 and COUGH-2 Investigators. Efficacy and safety of gefapixant, a P2X3 receptor antagonist, in refractory chronic cough and unexplained chronic cough (COUGH-1 and COUGH-2): results from two double-blind, randomised, parallel-group, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trials. Lancet. 2022;399:909&#x2013;923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35248186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran VT, Porcher R, Pane I, Ravaud P. Course of post COVID-19 disease symptoms over time in the ComPaRe long COVID prospective e-cohort. Nat Commun. 2022;13:1812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8983754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35383197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, Wang Q, Ren L, Wang Y, Hu P, Guo L, Liu M, Xu J, Zhang X, Qu Y, Fan Y, Li X, Li C, Yu T, Xia J, Wei M, Chen L, Li Y, Xiao F, Liu D, Wang J, Wang X, Cao B. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398:747&#x2013;758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Bitna-Ha, Kim SW, Chang HH, Kwon KT, Bae S, Hwang S. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome in patients after 12 months from COVID-19 infection in Korea. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22:93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8793328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35086489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buttery S, Philip KEJ, Williams P, Fallas A, West B, Cumella A, Cheung C, Walker S, Quint JK, Polkey MI, Hopkinson NS. Patient symptoms and experience following COVID-19: results from a UK-wide survey. BMJ Open Respir Res. 2021;8:e001075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8572361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34732518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taribagil P, Creer D, Tahir H. &#x2018;Long COVID&#x2019; syndrome. BMJ Case Reports CP. 2021;14:e241485</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8057566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33875508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>