<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35359346</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2359-7232</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Season>Oct-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Discoveries (Craiova, Romania)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Discoveries (Craiova)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 and the mental health implications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e140</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e140</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e140</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.15190/d.2021.19</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) or more commonly known as Long COVID-19, is the term given to persistent symptoms 12 weeks from the initial presentation of COVID-19 infection. Several multi-organ symptoms have been reported by patients. Some common symptoms include headaches, fatigue, memory impairment and mental health complications such as anxiety and depression. People with previous psychiatric diagnosis are at greater risk of developing longer mental health implications from persistent COVID-19 symptoms. Additionally, healthcare workers are at increased risk of being long haulers leading to burnout and exhaustion. The objective of this review article is to provide comprehensive evidence from existing literature on various symptoms reported by patients experiencing Long COVID-19 and the rate of occurrence of such symptoms in different populations. A long-term disease surveillance is required to further understand the persistent symptoms or the long-term impact of this infection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021, Walia N. et al., Applied Systems and Discoveries Journals.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walia</LastName><ForeName>Namrata</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lat</LastName><ForeName>Jessica Olivia</ForeName><Initials>JO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ateneo School of Medicine and Public Health, Philippines.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tariq</LastName><ForeName>Rabeet</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liaquat National Hospital and Medical College, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tyagi</LastName><ForeName>Surbhi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International School of Medicine, Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qazi</LastName><ForeName>Adam Manzoor</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Hospital for Sick Children, Toronto, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salari</LastName><ForeName>Syeda Wajiha</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rawalpindi Medical University, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jafar</LastName><ForeName>Amina</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>King Edward Medical University, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kousar</LastName><ForeName>Tasneem</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foundation University Medical College, Rawalpindi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bieniek</LastName><ForeName>Sherrie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Larkin Community Hospital, South Miami, Florida, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Romania</Country><MedlineTA>Discoveries (Craiova)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101665061</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2359-7232</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-haulers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health.</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multi-organ</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interests: The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35359346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8959835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15190/d.2021.19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Symptoms of COVID-19 Outpatients in the United States. Pullen Matthew F, Skipper Caleb P, Hullsiek Kathy H, Bangdiwala Ananta S, Pastick Katelyn A, Okafor Elizabeth C, Lofgren Sarah M, Rajasingham Radha, Engen Nicole W, Galdys Alison, Williams Darlisha A, Abassi Mahsa, Boulware David R. Open forum infectious diseases. 2020;7(7):ofaa271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7337847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33117855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of Asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 Infection : A Narrative Review. Oran Daniel P, Topol Eric J. Annals of internal medicine. 2020;173(5):362&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7281624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32491919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC COVID Data Tracker. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Accessed May 7, 2021. CDC. https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/ https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Why the Patient-Made Term 'Long Covid' is needed. Perego Elisa, Callard Felicity, Stras Laurie, Melville-J&#xf3;hannesson Barbara, Pope Rachel, Alwan Nisreen A. Wellcome Open Research. 2020;5:224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: An overview. Raveendran A V, Jayadevan Rajeev, Sashidharan S. Diabetes &amp; metabolic syndrome. 2021;15(3):869&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characteristics of and Important Lessons From the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Outbreak in China. Wu Zunyou, McGoogan Jennifer M. JAMA. 2020;323(13):1239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32091533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk of mortality in patients infected with SARS-CoV-2 variant of concern 202012/1: matched cohort study. Challen Robert, Brooks-Pollock Ellen, Read Jonathan M, Dyson Louise, Tsaneva-Atanasova Krasimira, Danon Leon. BMJ (Clinical research ed.) 2021;372:n579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7941603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33687922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. December 18, 2020. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (UK) 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Post-acute COVID-19 Syndrome (Long COVID). Al-Jahdhami Issa, Al-Naamani Khalid, Al-Mawali Adhra. Oman medical journal. 2021;36(1):e220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7838343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33537155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. Greenhalgh Trisha, Knight Matthew, A'Court Christine, Buxton Maria, Husain Laiba. BMJ (Clinical research ed.) 2020;370:m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chronic COVID syndrome: Need for an appropriate medical terminology for long-COVID and COVID long-haulers. Baig Abdul Mannan. Journal of medical virology. 2021;93(5):2555&#x2013;2556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33095459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent Symptoms in Patients After Acute COVID-19. Carf&#xec; Angelo, Bernabei Roberto, Landi Francesco. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autonomic dysfunction in &#x2018;long COVID&#x2019;: rationale, physiology and management strategies. Dani Melanie, Dirksen Andreas, Taraborrelli Patricia, Torocastro Miriam, Panagopoulos Dimitrios, Sutton Richard, Lim Phang Boon. Clinical Medicine. 2020;21(1):e63-e67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute covid-19 in primary care. Knight Matthew, Vancheeswaran Rama. BMJ. 2021:n3080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NIH launches new initiative to study "Long COVID". Accessed May 6, 2021. National Institutes of Health. https://www.nih.gov/about-nih/who-we-are/nih-director/statements/nih-launches-new-initiative-study-long-covid https://www.nih.gov/about-nih/who-we-are/nih-director/statements/nih-launches-new-initiative-study-long-covid</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Open Funding Opportunities. Accessed May 8, 2021. National Institutes of Health. https://covid19.nih.gov/funding/open-funding-opportunities. https://covid19.nih.gov/funding/open-funding-opportunities.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection: Caring for the 'long-haulers'. Vehar Susan, Boushra Marina, Ntiamoah Prince, Biehl Michelle. Cleveland Clinic journal of medicine. 2021;88(5):267&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33941600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PCS) and health-related quality of life (HRQoL)-A systematic review and meta-analysis. Malik Preeti, Patel Karan, Pinto Candida, Jaiswal Richa, Tirupathi Raghavendra, Pillai Shreejith, Patel Urvish. Journal of medical virology. 2022;94(1):253&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34463956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nalbandian Ani, Sehgal Kartik, Gupta Aakriti, Madhavan Mahesh V., McGroder Claire, Stevens Jacob S., Cook Joshua R., Nordvig Anna S., Shalev Daniel, Sehrawat Tejasav S., Ahluwalia Neha, Bikdeli Behnood, Dietz Donald, Der-Nigoghossian Caroline, Liyanage-Don Nadia, Rosner Gregg F., Bernstein Elana J., Mohan Sumit, Beckley Akinpelumi A., Seres David S., Choueiri Toni K., Uriel Nir, Ausiello John C., Accili Domenico, Freedberg Daniel E., Baldwin Matthew, Schwartz Allan, Brodie Daniel, Garcia Christine Kim, Elkind Mitchell S. V., Connors Jean M., Bilezikian John P., Landry Donald W., Wan Elaine Y. Nature Medicine. 2021;27(4):601-615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID and chronic COVID syndromes. Halpin Stephen, O'Connor Rory, Sivan Manoj. Journal of medical virology. 2021;93(3):1242&#x2013;1243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33034893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overview: COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19: Guidance Accessed May 7, 2021. NICE. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188 https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE guideline on long COVID. Venkatesan Priya. The Lancet. Respiratory medicine. 2021;9(2):129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A Proposed Framework and Timeline of the Spectrum of Disease Due to SARS-CoV-2 Infection: Illness Beyond Acute Infection and Public Health Implications. Datta S Deblina, Talwar Amish, Lee James T. JAMA. 2020;324(22):2251&#x2013;2252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33206133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Defining Post-COVID Symptoms (Post-Acute COVID, Long COVID, Persistent Post-COVID): An Integrative Classification. Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C&#xe9;sar, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a Domingo, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V&#xed;ctor, Cuadrado Mar&#xed;a L., Florencio Lidiane L. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2021;18(5):2621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-discharge persistent symptoms and health-related quality of life after hospitalization for COVID-19. Garrigues Eve, Janvier Paul, Kherabi Yousra, Le Bot Audrey, Hamon Antoine, Gouze H&#xe9;l&#xe8;ne, Doucet Lucile, Berkani Sabryne, Oliosi Emma, Mallart Elise, Corre F&#xe9;lix, Zarrouk Virginie, Moyer Jean-Denis, Galy Adrien, Honsel Vasco, Fantin Bruno, Nguyen Yann. The Journal of infection. 2020;81(6):e4&#x2013;e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sixty-Day Outcomes Among Patients Hospitalized With COVID-19. Chopra Vineet, Flanders Scott A, O'Malley Megan, Malani Anurag N, Prescott Hallie C. Annals of internal medicine. 2021;174(4):576&#x2013;578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7707210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Carvalho-Schneider Claudia, Laurent Emeline, Lemaignen Adrien, Beaufils Emilie, Bourbao-Tournois C&#xe9;line, Laribi Sa&#xef;d, Flament Thomas, Ferreira-Maldent Nicole, Bruy&#xe8;re Franck, Stefic Karl, Gaudy-Graffin Catherine, Grammatico-Guillon Leslie, Bernard Louis. Clinical microbiology and infection : the official publication of the European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases. 2021;27(2):258&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incidence of symptomatic, image-confirmed venous thromboembolism following hospitalization for COVID-19 with 90-day follow-up. Salisbury Richard, Iotchkova Valentina, Jaafar Sarah, Morton Joshua, Sangha Gavinda, Shah Akshay, Untiveros Paraskevi, Curry Nicola, Shapiro Susan. Blood advances. 2020;4(24):6230&#x2013;6239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7757009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33351117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postdischarge thrombosis and hemorrhage in patients with COVID-19. Patell Rushad, Bogue Thomas, Koshy Anita, Bindal Poorva, Merrill Mwanasha, Aird William C, Bauer Kenneth A, Zwicker Jeffrey I. Blood. 2020;136(11):1342&#x2013;1346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32766883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute and Post-Acute Neurological Complications of COVID-19. Al-Ramadan Ali, Rabab'h Omar, Shah Jawad, Gharaibeh Abeer. Neurology international. 2021;13(1):102&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33803475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurologic Manifestations of Hospitalized Patients With Coronavirus Disease 2019 in Wuhan, China. Mao Ling, Jin Huijuan, Wang Mengdie, Hu Yu, Chen Shengcai, He Quanwei, Chang Jiang, Hong Candong, Zhou Yifan, Wang David, Miao Xiaoping, Li Yanan, Hu Bo. JAMA Neurology. 2020;77(6):683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7149362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuropsychological and neurophysiological correlates of fatigue in post-acute patients with neurological manifestations of COVID-19: Insights into a challenging symptom. Ortelli Paola, Ferrazzoli Davide, Sebastianelli Luca, Engl Michael, Romanello Roberto, Nardone Raffaele, Bonini Ilenia, Koch Giacomo, Saltuari Leopold, Quartarone Angelo, Oliviero Antonio, Kofler Markus, Versace Viviana. Journal of the neurological sciences. 2021;420:117271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurological and neuropsychiatric complications of COVID-19 in 153 patients: a UK-wide surveillance study. Varatharaj Aravinthan, Thomas Naomi, Ellul Mark A, Davies Nicholas W S, Pollak Thomas A, Tenorio Elizabeth L, Sultan Mustafa, Easton Ava, Breen Gerome, Zandi Michael, Coles Jonathan P, Manji Hadi, Al-Shahi Salman Rustam, Menon David K, Nicholson Timothy R, Benjamin Laura A, Carson Alan, Smith Craig, Turner Martin R, Solomon Tom, Kneen Rachel, Pett Sarah L, Galea Ian, Thomas Rhys H, Michael Benedict D. The lancet. Psychiatry. 2020;7(10):875&#x2013;882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7316461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32593341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The emerging spectrum of COVID-19 neurology: clinical, radiological and laboratory findings. Paterson Ross W, Brown Rachel L, Benjamin Laura, Nortley Ross, Wiethoff Sarah, Bharucha Tehmina, Jayaseelan Dipa L, Kumar Guru, Raftopoulos Rhian E, Zambreanu Laura, Vivekanandam Vinojini, Khoo Anthony, Geraldes Ruth, Chinthapalli Krishna, Boyd Elena, Tuzlali Hatice, Price Gary, Christofi Gerry, Morrow Jasper, McNamara Patricia, McLoughlin Benjamin, Lim Soon Tjin, Mehta Puja R, Levee Viva, Keddie Stephen, Yong Wisdom, Trip S Anand, Foulkes Alexander J M, Hotton Gary, Miller Thomas D, Everitt Alex D, Carswell Christopher, Davies Nicholas W S, Yoong Michael, Attwell David, Sreedharan Jemeen, Silber Eli, Schott Jonathan M, Chandratheva Arvind, Perry Richard J, Simister Robert, Checkley Anna, Longley Nicky, Farmer Simon F, Carletti Francesco, Houlihan Catherine, Thom Maria, Lunn Michael P, Spillane Jennifer, Howard Robin, Vincent Angela, Werring David J, Hoskote Chandrashekar, J&#xe4;ger Hans Rolf, Manji Hadi, Zandi Michael S. Brain : a journal of neurology. 2020;143(10):3104&#x2013;3120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32637987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Headaches During COVID-19: My Clinical Case and Review of the Literature. Belvis Robert. Headache. 2020;60(7):1422&#x2013;1426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7273035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32413158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seizures Related to Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19): Case Series and Literature Review. Ashraf Muddasir, Sajed Sulaiman. Cureus. 2020;12(7):e9378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7444990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32850246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Generalized status epilepticus as a possible manifestation of COVID-19. Abdulsalam Mohammad A, Abdulsalam Ahmad J, Shehab Diaa. Acta neurologica Scandinavica. 2020;142(4):297&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7405327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32779768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Individual differences and changes in subjective wellbeing during the early stages of the COVID-19 pandemic. Zacher Hannes, Rudolph Cort W. The American psychologist. 2021;76(1):50&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32700938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The psychiatric impact of COVID-19 on healthcare workers. Cabarkapa Sonja, King Joel A, Ng Chee H. Australian journal of general practice. 2020;49(12):791&#x2013;795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33254202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Mental Health Implications of COVID-19. Pearson Geraldine S. Journal of the American Psychiatric Nurses Association. 2020;26(5):443-444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32815433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Depression and anxiety in healthcare professionals during the COVID-19 pandemic. Weibelzahl S, Reiter J, Duden G. Epidemiology and infection. 2021;149:e46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7900665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33557984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC. Post-COVID Conditions: Information for Healthcare Providers Accessed May 7, 2021. CDC. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/ clinical-care/post-covid-conditions https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/ clinical-care/post-covid-conditions</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Sudre Carole H, Murray Benjamin, Varsavsky Thomas, Graham Mark S, Penfold Rose S, Bowyer Ruth C, Pujol Joan Capdevila, Klaser Kerstin, Antonelli Michela, Canas Liane S, Molteni Erika, Modat Marc, Jorge Cardoso M, May Anna, Ganesh Sajaysurya, Davies Richard, Nguyen Long H, Drew David A, Astley Christina M, Joshi Amit D, Merino Jordi, Tsereteli Neli, Fall Tove, Gomez Maria F, Duncan Emma L, Menni Cristina, Williams Frances M K, Franks Paul W, Chan Andrew T, Wolf Jonathan, Ourselin Sebastien, Spector Tim, Steves Claire J. Nature medicine. 2021;27(4):626&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Huang Chaolin, Huang Lixue, Wang Yeming, Li Xia, Ren Lili, Gu Xiaoying, Kang Liang, Guo Li, Liu Min, Zhou Xing, Luo Jianfeng, Huang Zhenghui, Tu Shengjin, Zhao Yue, Chen Li, Xu Decui, Li Yanping, Li Caihong, Peng Lu, Li Yong, Xie Wuxiang, Cui Dan, Shang Lianhan, Fan Guohui, Xu Jiuyang, Wang Geng, Wang Ying, Zhong Jingchuan, Wang Chen, Wang Jianwei, Zhang Dingyu, Cao Bin. Lancet (London, England) 2021;397(10270):220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistence of symptoms and quality of life at 35 days after hospitalization for COVID-19 infection. Jacobs Laurie G, Gourna Paleoudis Elli, Lesky-Di Bari Dineen, Nyirenda Themba, Friedman Tamara, Gupta Anjali, Rasouli Lily, Zetkulic Marygrace, Balani Bindu, Ogedegbe Chinwe, Bawa Harinder, Berrol Lauren, Qureshi Nabiha, Aschner Judy L. PloS one. 2020;15(12):e0243882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7732078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anxiety and depression in COVID-19 survivors: Role of inflammatory and clinical predictors. Mazza Mario Gennaro, De Lorenzo Rebecca, Conte Caterina, Poletti Sara, Vai Benedetta, Bollettini Irene, Melloni Elisa Maria Teresa, Furlan Roberto, Ciceri Fabio, Rovere-Querini Patrizia, Benedetti Francesco. Brain, behavior, and immunity. 2020;89:594&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7390748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. Halpin Stephen J, McIvor Claire, Whyatt Gemma, Adams Anastasia, Harvey Olivia, McLean Lyndsay, Walshaw Christopher, Kemp Steven, Corrado Joanna, Singh Rajinder, Collins Tamsin, O'Connor Rory J, Sivan Manoj. Journal of medical virology. 2021;93(2):1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psychological Distress After Covid-19 Recovery: Reciprocal Effects With Temperament and Emotional Dysregulation. An Exploratory Study of Patients Over 60 Years of Age Assessed in a Post-acute Care Service. Janiri Delfina, Kotzalidis Georgios D, Giuseppin Giulia, Molinaro Marzia, Modica Marco, Montanari Silvia, Terenzi Beatrice, Carf&#xec; Angelo, Landi Francesco, Sani Gabriele. Frontiers in psychiatry. 2020;11:590135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7693440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33304286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bidirectional associations between COVID-19 and psychiatric disorder: retrospective cohort studies of 62&#x2008;354 COVID-19 cases in the USA. Taquet Maxime, Luciano Sierra, Geddes John R, Harrison Paul J. The lancet. Psychiatry. 2021;8(2):130&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psychiatric and neuropsychiatric presentations associated with severe coronavirus infections: a systematic review and meta-analysis with comparison to the COVID-19 pandemic. Rogers Jonathan P, Chesney Edward, Oliver Dominic, Pollak Thomas A, McGuire Philip, Fusar-Poli Paolo, Zandi Michael S, Lewis Glyn, David Anthony S. The Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;7(7):611-627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7234781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Psychological Experience and Intervention in Post-Acute COVID-19 Inpatients. Rossi Ferrario Silvia, Panzeri Anna, Cerutti Paola, Sacco Daniela. Neuropsychiatric disease and treatment. 2021;17:413&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7884934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33603379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Planning for the Post-COVID Syndrome: How Payers Can Mitigate Long-Term Complications of the Pandemic. Jiang David H, McCoy Rozalina G. Journal of general internal medicine. 2020;35(10):3036&#x2013;3039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7375754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32700223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Long-Term Mental Health Effects of COVID-19. Iqbal Syed Z., Li Benjamin, Onigu-Otito Edore, Naqvi Mohammad Faraz, Shah Asim A. Psychiatric Annals. 2020;50(12):522-525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors associated with mental illness in hospital discharged patients infected with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China. Liu Dong, Baumeister Roy F., Veilleux Jennifer C., Chen Caixia, Liu Wenjun, Yue Yongjie, Zhang Shi. Psychiatry Research. 2020;292:113297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7355324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32707218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent neurologic symptoms and cognitive dysfunction in non-hospitalized Covid-19 "long haulers". Graham Edith L, Clark Jeffrey R, Orban Zachary S, Lim Patrick H, Szymanski April L, Taylor Carolyn, DiBiase Rebecca M, Jia Dan Tong, Balabanov Roumen, Ho Sam U, Batra Ayush, Liotta Eric M, Koralnik Igor J. Annals of clinical and translational neurology. 2021;8(5):1073&#x2013;1085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33755344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covid-19 Story Tip: Researchers May Have Unclouded the Mystery of COVID-19 &#x2018;Brain Fog&#x2019;. Johns Hopkins Medicine Newsroom.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covid-19 Story Tip: Researchers May Have Unclouded the Mystery of COVID-19 &#x2018;Brain Fog&#x2019; Accessed May 27, 2021. Johns Hopkins Medicine Newsroom. https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/news/newsroom/news-releases/covid-19-story-tip-researchers-may-have-unclouded-the-mystery-of-covid-19-brain-fog. https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/news/newsroom/news-releases/covid-19-story-tip-researchers-may-have-unclouded-the-mystery-of-covid-19-brain-fog.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selective Neuronal Mitochondrial Targeting in SARS-CoV-2 Infection Affects Cognitive Processes to Induce 'Brain Fog' and Results in Behavioral Changes that Favor Viral Survival. Stefano George B, Ptacek Radek, Ptackova Hana, Martin Anders, Kream Richard M. Medical science monitor : international medical journal of experimental and clinical research. 2021;27:e930886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7845145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33487628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>