<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38013408</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2713-4148</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>67</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical and experimental pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Exp Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19 among infants: key clinical features and remaining controversies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>16</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-16</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3345/cep.2023.00794</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Infants aged &lt;1 year represent a seemingly more susceptible pediatric subset for infections. Despite this, coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) infection has not been proven as more serious in this age group (outside the very early neonatal period) than in others. Indeed, a considerable number of asymptomatic infections have been recorded, and the symptoms and morbidity associated with COVID- 19 differ minimally from those of other respiratory viral infections. Whether due to an abundance of caution or truly reduced susceptibility, infections in infants have not raised the same profile as those in other age groups. In addition to direct severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 diagnostic tests, laboratory markers that differentiate COVID-19 from other viral infections lack specificity in infants. Gastrointestinal presentations are common, and the neurological complications of infection mirror those of other respiratory viral infections. There have been relatively few reports of infant deaths. Under appropriate precautions, breastfeeding in the context of maternal infections has been associated with tangible but infrequent complications. Vaccination during pregnancy provides protection against infection in infants, at least in the early months of life. Multi-inflammatory syndrome in children and multi-inflammatory syndrome in neonates are commonly cited as variants of COVID-19; however, their clinical definitions remain controversial. Similarly, reliable definitions of long COVID in the infant group are controversial. This narrative review examines the key clinical and laboratory features of COVID-19 in infants and identifies several areas of science awaiting further clarification.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cimolai</LastName><ForeName>Nevio</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, The University of British Columbia and Children's and Women's Health Centre of British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Exp Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101761234</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2713-4148</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Child</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>Conflicts of interest</b>
. No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38013408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10764668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3345/cep.2023.00794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">cep.2023.00794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dong Y, Mo X, Hu Y, Qi X, Jiang F, Jiang Z, et al. Epidemiology of COVID-19 among children in China. Pediatrics. 2020;145:e20200702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32179660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakwa FL, Thomas R, van Kwawegen A, Ntuli N, Seake K, Kesting SJ, et al. An outbreak of infection due to severe acute respiratory corona virus-2 in a neonatal unit from a low and middle income setting. Front Pediatr. 2022;10:933982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9366465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35967580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Servidio AG, Visentin G, Conti R, Cozzi G, Travan L, Bua J, et al. Mild COVID-19 in hospitalised infants younger than 90 days. Acta Paediatr. 2023;112:483&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9878078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36513613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. A comprehensive analysis of maternal and newborn disease and related control for COVID-19. SN Compr Clin Med. 2021;3:1272&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7968576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33754135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellini T, Rotuio GA, Caruggi S, Carta S, Bonato I, Piccotti E. Characteristics of COVID-19 patients up to 6 months of age admitted to a pediatric emergency department. Acta Paediatr. 2022;111:272&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8653029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34704279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schober T, Caya C, Barton M, Bayliss A, Bitnun A, Bowes J, et al. Risk factors for severe PCR-positive SARS-CoV-2 infection in hospitalized children. BMJ Pediatr Open. 2022;6:e001440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9358955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36053578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar J, Kumar P, Saini SS, Sundaram V, Mukhopadhyay K, Dutta S, et al. Clinical characteristics &amp; outcome of SARS-CoV-2 infected neonates presenting to paediatric emergency. Indian J Med Res. 2022;155:189&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35859443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>More K, Chawla D, Murki S, Tandur B, Deorari AK, Kumar P, et al. Outcomes of neonates born to mothers with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) &#x2013; National Neonatology Forum (NNF) India COVID-19 Registry. Indian Pediatr. 2021;58:525&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8253678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33742609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devin J, Marano R, Mikhael M, Feaster W, Sanger T, Ehwerhemuepha L. Epidemiology of neonatal COVID-19 in the United States. Pediatrics. 2022;150:e2022056297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35996224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobbs CV, Woodworth K, Young CC, Jackson AM, Newhams MM, Dapul H, et al. Frequency, characteristics and complications of COVID-19 in hospitalized infants. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2022;41:e81&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8828316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34955519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pich&#xe9;-Renaud PP, Panetta L, Farrar DS, Moore-Hepburn C, Drouin O, Papenburg J, et al. Clinical manifestations and disease severity of SARS-CoV-2 infection among infants in Canada. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0272648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9401116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36001553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinzani R, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection in children: a 24 months experience with focus on risk factors in a pediatric tertiary care hospital in Milan, Italy. Front Pediatr. 2023;11:1082083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9981971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36873632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawlowska M, Pokorska-&#x15a;piewak M, Talarek E, Mania A, Hasiec B, &#x17b;wirek-Pytka E, et al. Clinical course and severity of COVID-19 in 940 infants with and without comorbidities hospitalized in 2020 and 2021: the results of the National Multicenter Database SARSTer-PED. J Clin Med. 2023;12:2479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10095202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37048562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. The semantics of airborne microbial spread and environmental relevance: back to Anderson and Cox. Environ Res. 2021;193:110448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33212132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Disinfection and decontamination in the context of SARS-CoV-2-specific data. J Med Virol. 2022;94:4654&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9350315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35758523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Environmental and decontamination issues for human coronaviruses and their potential surrogates. J Med Virol. 2020;92:2498&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7307025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Features of enteric disease from human coronaviruses: implications for COVID-19. J Med Virol. 2020;92:1834&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7283829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32462689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding BR, Vora F. Report of a confirmed SARS-CoV-2 positive newborn with delivery despite negative SARS-CoV-2 testing on both parents. AJP Rep. 2021;11:e80&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8208836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34150353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaiba LA, Hadid A, Abdulghani SH, Hussain SA, Shah PS. SARS-CoV-2 exposure from health care workers to infants: effects and outcomes. Am J Perinatol. 2023;40:799&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10125677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34450672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imran S, Gupta R, Sharma R, Mukhopadhyay S, Yadav S. Perinatal transmission of SARS-CoV-2 infection and its clinical attributes: a single-center study from Western Uttar Pradash. Cureus. 2023;15:e35824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10075277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37033580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez Colomer B, S&#xe1;nchez-Luna M, de Alba Romero C, Alarc&#xf3;n A, Ba&#xf1;a Souto A, Camba Longueira F, et al. Neonatal infection due to SARS-CoV-2: an epidemiological study in Spain. Front Pediatr. 2020;8:580584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7644848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33194912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim SB, See KC, Law KB, Kamaruddin NIM. Characteristics and outcomes of SARS-CoV-2 positivity in neonates born to mothers with COVID-19 in Klang Valley, Malaysia: a retrospective observational study. IJID Reg. 2022;5:146&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9540684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36245891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gale C, Quigley MA, Placzek A, Knight M, Ladhani S, Draper ES, et al. Characteristics and outcomes of neonatal SARS-CoV-2 infection in the UK: a prospective national cohort study using active surveillance. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2021;5:113&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7818530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Don&#xe1; D, Montagnani C, Di Chiara C, Venturini E, Galli L, Lo Vecchio A, et al. COVID-19 in infants less than 3 months: severe or not severe disease? Viruses. 2022;14:2256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9612333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36298812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudak ML, Flannery DD, Barnette K, Getzlaff T, Gautam S, Dhudasia MB, et al. Maternal and newborn hospital outcomes of perinatal SARS-CoV-2 infection: a national registry. Pediatrics. 2023;151:e2022059595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11292484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36995183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydo&#x11f;an S, Zenciroglu A, &#x4aa;itli R, Dilli D, &#xd6;zdem S. Evaluation of newborns diagnosed with COVID-19: a single-center experience. Am J Perinatol. 2023;40:567&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35790179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cozzi G, Cortellazzo Wiel L, Amaddeo A, Gatto A, Giangreco M, Klein-Kremer A, et al. Prevalence of SARS-CoV-2 positivity in infants with bronchiolitis: a multicentre international study. Arch Dis Child. 2022 Jun 15;:archdischild-2021-323559. doi: 10.1136/archdischild-2021-323559. [Epub]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35705371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevisanuto D, Cavallin F, Cavicchiolo ME, Borellini M, Calgaro S, Baraldi E. Coronavirus infection in neonates: a systematic review. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2021;106:330&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32943533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liguoro I, Pilotto C, Bonanni M, Ferrari ME, Pusiol A, Nocerino A, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection in children and newborns: a systematic review. Eur J Pediatr. 2020;179:1029&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7234446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32424745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panetta L, Proulx C, Drouin O, Autmizguine J, Luu TM, Quach C, et al. Clinical characteristics and disease severity among infants with SARS-CoV-2 infection in Montreal, Quebec, Canada. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3:e2030470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7737086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33315110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mithal LB, Machut KZ, Muller WJ, Kociolek LK. SARS-CoV-2 infection in infants less than 90 days old. J Pediatr. 2020;224:150&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32565095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha S, Ahmed ANU, Kumar Sarkar P, Bipul MRA, Ghosh K, Wasik Rahman S, et al. The direct and indirect impact of SARS-CoV-2 infection in neonates: a series of 26 cases in Bangladesh. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2020;39:e398&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7654949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin I, Irving SA, Arriola CS, Campbell AP, Li DK, Dawood FS, et al. Incidence rates of medically attended COVID-19 in infants less than 6 months of age. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2023;42:315&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9990480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36602338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman P, Uka A, Buettcher M, Foug&#xe8;re Y, Piebani M, Relly C, et al. Neonates with SARS-CoV-2 infection: spectrum of disease from a prospective nationwide observational cohort study. Swiss Med Wkly. 2022;152:w30185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35748304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uslu Yuvac&#x131; H, Aslan MM, K&#xf6;se O, Akdemir N, Toptan H, Cevrio&#x11f;lu AS, et al. Evaluation of the presence of SARS-COV-2 in the vaginal fluid of reproductive-aged women. Ginekol Pol. 2021 Mar 10; doi: 10.5603/GP.a2021.0018. [Epub]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33751509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber E, Kovo M, Leytes S, Sagiv R, Weiner E, Schwartz O, et al. Evaluation of SARS-CoV-2 in the vaginal secretions of women with COVID-19: a prospective study. J Clin Med. 2021;10:2735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8234022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34205751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen SY, Murra M, Henning Pedersen L, Rohi Kalil M, Hvidman L, Helmig RB, et al. Comparatively low rates of COVID-19 in women admitted in labor and their newborns prior to routine vaccination of pregnant women: insight from Denmark. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med. 2023;36:2229933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37408109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes MC, Jones S, Strehlau R, Baba V, Ditse Z, da Silva K, et al. Active intrapartum SARS-CoV-2 infection and pregnancy outcomes. Am J Perinatol. 2022;39(S 01):S42&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36307090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso D, Costa S, Sanguinetti M, Cattani P, Posteraro B, Marchetti S, et al. Neonatal late onset infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2. Am J Perinatol. 2020;37:869&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7356068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32359227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eghbalian F, Monsef Esfahani A, Jenabi E. COVID-19 virus in a 6-day-old girl neonate: a case report. Clin Pediatr. 2020;59:1288&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32698615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gen&#xe7;eli M, Metin Akcan &#xd6;, Pekcan S, Akin F, &#xd6;zdemir M, Kili&#xe7; AO, et al. Outcomes ofCOVID-19 infections in children: a single-center retrospective study. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2022;57:2533&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9349843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35855567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayed M, Alsaffar Z, Bahzad Z, Buhamad Y, Abdulkareem A, AlQattan A, et al. Coronavirus infection in neonates: neurodevelopmental outcomes at 18 months of age. Can J Infect Dis Med Microbiol. 2023;2023:6140085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9829449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36632169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capozza M, Salvatore S, Baldassarre ME, Inting S, Panza R, Fanelli M, et al. Perinatal transmission and outcome of neonates born to SARS-CoV-2 positive mothers: the experience of 2 highly endemic Italian regions. Neonatology. 2021;118:665&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8678243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34628414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raba AA, bobaker A, Elgenaidi IS, Daoud A. Novel coronavirus infection (COVID-19) in children younger than one year: a systematic review of symptoms, management and outcomes. Acta Paediatr. 2020;109:1948&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32557789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodin P. Why is COVID-19 so mild in children? Acta Paediatr. 2020;109:1082&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32212348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaiba LA, Altirkawi K, Hadid A, Alsubaie S, Alharbi O, Alkhalaf H, et al. COVID-19 disease in infants less than 60 days: case series. Front Pediatr. 2021;9:674899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8311174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34322461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urstemova K, Bozhbanbayeva N, Cetinkaya M, Manzhuova L, Yeraliyeva L, Issayeva A. Features of the clinical course of coronavirus infection in newborn children. Georgian Med News. 2022;331:101&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36539140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Tang J, Xie R, Li W, Chen J, Guo Y, et al. Clinical and epidemiological features of 46 children &lt;1 year old with coronavirus disease 2019 in Wuhan, China: a descriptive study. J Infect Dis. 2020;222:1293&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32761128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee M, Pal J, Mondal T, Ghosh T, Nayek K. Clinical profile and short-term outcome of SARS-CoV-2-infected neonates from a government medical college in West Bengal, India. J Trop Pediatr. 2022;68:fmac002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8822412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35045183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xe1;vila-Aliaga C, Torres-Marcos E, Paucar-Zegarra R, Hinojosa-P&#xe9;rez R, Espinoza-Vivas Y, Mendoza-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez E, et al. Clinical and epidemiological characterization in the follow-up of newborns with COVID-19: a descriptive study. Medwave. 2021;21:e8500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34910718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamid S, Woodworth K, Pham H, Milucky J, Chai SJ, Kawasaki B, et al. COVID-19-associated hospitalizations among U.S. infants aged &lt;6 months - COVID-NET, 13 States, June 2021- August 2022. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71:1442&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9707352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36355608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca D, Perkins E, Tingay DG, European Society of Pediatric and Neonatal Intensive Care COVID-19 Paediatric and Neonatal Registry Group; European society of pediatric and neonatal intensive care covid-19 paediatric and neonatal registry (EPICENTRE) group - group authorship; European Society of Pediatric and Neonatal Intensive Care COVID-19 Paediatric and Neonatal Registry Group and European society of pediatric and neonatal intensive care covid-19 paediatric and neonatal registry (EPICENTRE) group - group authorship Community Versus Vertically Acquired Neonatal SARS-CoV-2 Infection: The EPICENTRE Cohort Study. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2023;42:685&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10348412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37463390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leibowitz J, Krief W, Barone S, Williamson KA, Goenka PK, Rai S, et al. Comparison of clinical and epidemiologic characteristics of young febrile infants with and without Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus-2 infection. J Pediatr. 2021;229:41&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7546714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33045235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solis-Garcia G, Guti&#xe9;rrez-V&#xe9;lez A, Pescador Chamorro I, Zamora-Flores E, Vigil-V&#xe1;zquez S, Rodr&#xed;guez-Corrales E, et al. Epidemiology, management and risk of SARS-CoV-2 transmission in a cohort of newborns born to mothers diagnosed with COVID-19 infection. Ann Pediatr. 2021;94:173&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33521167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaei R, Bokharaei-Salim F, Khanaliha K, Kiani SJ, Marjani A, Garshasbi S, et al. Prevalence of SARS-CoV-2 infection in neonates born to mothers or relatives with COVID-19. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22:730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9454391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36076173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzpatrick T, Wilton AS, Chung H, Guttmann A. SARS-CoV-2 infection among maternal-infant dyads in Ontario, Canada. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2120150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8353536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34369993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumitriu D, Emeruwa UN, Hanft E, Liao GV, Ludwig E, Walzer L, et al. Outcomes of neonates born to mothers with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection at a large medical center in New York City. JAMA Pediatr. 2021;175:157&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7551222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33044493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawar R, Gavade V, Patil N, Mali V, Girwalkar A, Tarkasband V, et al. Neonatal multisystem inflammatory syndrome (MIS-N) associated with prenatal maternal SARS-CoV-2: a case series. Children. 2021;8:572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8305422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34356552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbayiyev S, &#x15e;im&#x15f;ek GK, Ceran B, Ak&#x131;n M&#x15e;, Kanmaz Kutman HG, Canpolat FE. Could red cell distribution width be used for predicting cardiac injury in neonates with COVID-19? J Med Virol. 2022;94:5739&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35938314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benenson-Weinberg T, Gross I, Bamberger Z, Guzner N, Wolf D, Gordon O, et al. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 in infants younger than 90 days presenting to the Pediatric Emergency Department: clinical characteristics and risk of serious bacterial infection. Pediatr Emerg Care. 2023 Apr 11; doi: 10.1097/PEC.0000000000002940. [Epub]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37039445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan P, Malik A, Isath A, Bandyopadhyay D, Goel A, Parton L, et al. Nationwide analysis of the outcomes and mortality of hospitalized infants with concomitant diagnosis of COVID-19. Am J Perinatol. 2023 Sep 8; doi: 10.1055/a-2149-8810. [Epub]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37549883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansari NS, Watson DC, Campbell DM, Sarhan MA, Bitnun A, Gauda EB. SARS-CoV-2 infection in young infants during the Omicron wave: a case series. Biomed Hub. 2023;8:10&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9892994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36747882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakhaei MHA, Moghadam SS, Yaghhoubi S. COVID-19 symptomatic newborns with possible postpartum transmission of SARS-CoV-2. Case Rep Pediatr. 2022;2022:7394175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9532159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36204324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Q, Shi Y. Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) and neonate: what neonatologists need to know. J Med Virol. 2020;92:564&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32115733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Bernardo G, Giordano M, Zollo G, Chiatto F, Sordino D, De Santis R, et al. The clinical course of SARS-CoV-2 positive neonates. J Perinatol. 2020;40:1462&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7335929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32632198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo Y, Mo J, Liang RY, Xiao GY, Li Y, Wei QF. A case report of neonatal coronavirus disease 2019. Zhongguo Dang Dai Er Ke Za Zhi. 2022;24:1266&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9678062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36398554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatura SNN. Severe COVID-19 with late-onset sepsis-like illness in a neonate. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2022;106:1098&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8991361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35168194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannix MK, Blood D, Gomez-Duarte OG, Davidson L. Necrotizing enterocolitis in a 34-week premature infant with COVID-19. Case Rep Infect Dis. 2021;2021:1442447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8703157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34956682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brehm R, Narayanam L, Chon G. COVID-19-associated parotitis in a 10-week-old male. Cureus. 2022;14:e31054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9720032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36475193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azeka E, Arshad A, Martins C, Dominguez AC, Siqueira A, Silveira Loss A, et al. Dilated cardiomyopathy in a newborn, a potential association with SARS-CoV-2. Front Pediatr. 2021;9:674300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8377194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34422715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulaziz-Opiela G, Sobieraj A, Sibrecht G, Bajdor J, Mrozi&#x144;ski B, Kozlowska Z, et al. Prenatal and neonatal pulmonary thrombosis as a potential complication of SARS-CoV-2 infection in late pregnancy. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24:7629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10146603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37108791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidatt M, Sghair YM, Ghaddour T, Ahmed MS, Kader FA, Habib L, et al. Neonatal necrotizing enterocolitis due to COVID-19: a case report. J Neonatal Perinatal Med. 2023;16:165&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36591662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsico C, Capretti MG, Aceti A, Vocale C, Carfagnini F, Serra C, et al. Severe neonatal COVID-19: challenges in management and therapeutic approach. J Med Virol. 2022;94:1701&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9011600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34812530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaveh M, Sadatinejad SM. Management of neonatal sepsis with COVID-19 infection in a premature neonate &#x2013; a case report. J Neonatal Nurs. 2023;29:409&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9343744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35935164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goussard P, Venkatakrishna S, Frigati L, Janson J, Schubert P, Verster J, et al. Chronic lung disease in children due to SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia: case series. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2023;58:2111&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10424808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37133220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung EW, Zachariah P, Gorelik M, Boneparth A, Kernie SG, Orange JS, et al. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome related to COVID-19 in previously health children and adolescents in New York City. JAMA. 2020;324:294&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7281352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32511676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riphagen S, Gomez X, Gonzalez-Martinez C, Wilkinson N, Theocharis P. Hyperinflammatory shock in children during COVID-19 pandemic. Lancet. 2020;395:1607&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7204765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32386565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swann OV, Holden KA, Turtle L, Pollock L, Fairfield CJ, Drake TM, et al. Clinical characteristics of children and young people admitted to hospital with COVID-19 in United Kingdom: prospective multicenter observational cohort study. BMJ. 2020;370:m3249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7488201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32960186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stemberger Mari&#x107; L, Trkulja V, Petrovi&#x107; D, Lah Tomuli&#x107; K, Bartulovi&#x107; I, Te&#x161;ovi&#x107; G, et al. Incidence and clinical phenotype of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children after two SARS-CoV-2 pandemic waves: a Croatian prospective nationwide study. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2023;42:e229&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10289067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37054396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godfred-Cato S, Tsang CA, Giovanni J, Abrams J, Oster ME, Lee EH, et al. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in infants &lt;12 months of age, United States, May 2020-January 2021. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:601&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8408805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33872279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guernsey D 3rd, Pfeffer M, Kimpo J, Vazquez H, Zerzan J. COVID-19 and serious bacterial infection in febrile infants less than 60 days old. West J Emerg Med. 2022;23:754&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9541991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36205666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrpisheh S, Farhadi R, Ghaffari Saravi V, Dastourian F, Memarian A. Evaluation of clinical manifestations of coronavirus delta variant in neonates admitted to a hospital in northern Iran during the sixth wave: a case series. J Neonatal Nurs. 2023 Apr 18; doi: 10.1016/j.jnn.2023. 04.008. [Epub]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10110928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37362911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bechor Ariel T, Ariel B, Lahav Y, Yana M, Ben-Acon M, Sharon N. Clinical outcomes and laboratory values of infants with COVID-19 among several maternal variables: a retrospective cohort. Isr Med Assoc J. 2023;25:387&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37381930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakuma H, Takanashi JI, Muramatsu K, Kondo H, Shiihara T, Suzuki M, et al. Severe pediatric acute encephalopathy syndromes related to SARS-CoV-2. Front Neurosci. 2023;17:1085082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10008884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36922927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mascarenhas D, Goyal M, Haribalakrishna A, Nanavati R, Ish P, Kunal S. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in neonates (MIS-N): a systematic review. Eur J Pediatr. 2023;182:2283&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9986661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36877274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaiba LA, More K, Hadid A, Almagharbi R, Al Marri M, Alnamnakani M, et al. Multisystemic inflammatory syndrome in neonates: a systematic review. Neonatology. 2022;119:405&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9148888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35512651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurokawa M, Kurokawa R, Lin AY, Capizzano AA, Baba A, Kim J, et al. Neurological and neuroradiological manifestations in neonates born to mothers with coronavirus disease 2019. Pediatr Neurol. 2023;141:9&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9741496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#x105;troba SJ, Bryda J. Meningoenphalitis and postinflammatory hydrocephalus in the course of COVID-19 disease in newborn &#x2013; the potential role of acetazolamide as add-on therapy to the standard treatment. Ann Agric Environ Med. 2022;29:595&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36583330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinaei R, Nejadbiglari H, Sinaei R, Zeinaly M, Pezeshki S, Jafari M. Finding positive SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR in cerebrospinal fluid of two pediatric patients with severe COVID-19: a brief case report. BMC Pediatr. 2023;23:49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9885917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36717816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tetsuhara K, Akamine S, Matsubara Y, Fujii S, Kashimada W, Marutani K, et al. Severe encephalopathy associated with SARS-CoV-2 Omicron BA.1 variant infection in a neonate. Brain Dev. 2022;44:743&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9273474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35835638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagda A, Sawant V, Rajput K, Malik S, Singh V, Kondekar S. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in neonates due to severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2: an emerging entity. Indian J Child Health. 2021;8:401&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>More K, Aiyer S, Goti A, Parikh M, Sheikh S, Patel G, et al. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in neonates (MIS-N) associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection: a case series. Eur J Pediatr. 2022;181:1883&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8759431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35031848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelbari M, Tilouche S, Hannachi S, Bouguila J, Hannachi N, Boughammoura L. Fulminant encephalitis caused by SARS-CoV-2 in a two-month-old infant. Indian J Pediatr. 2023;90:101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9702610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36441385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha S, Pal P, Mukherjee D. Neonatal MIS-C: managing the cytokine storm. Pediatrics. 2021;148:e2020042093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34433686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brum AC, Glasman MP, De Luca MC, Rugilo CA, Urquizu Handal MI, Picon AO, et al. Ischemic lesions in the brain of a neonate with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:e340&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34288632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragoso DC, Marx C, Dutra BG, da Silva CJ, da Silva PM, Martins Maia Junior AC, et al. COVID-19 as a cause of acute neonatal encephalitis and cerebral cytotoxic edema. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:e270&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33902082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildiz H, Yarci E, Bozdemir SE, Ozdinc Kizilay N, Mengi S, Beskardesler N, et al. COVID-19-associated cerebral white matter injury in a newborn infant with afebrile seizure. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:e268&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33902081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cursi L, Calo Carducci FI, Chiurchiu S, Romani L, Stoppa F, Lucignani G, et al. Severe COVID-19 complicated by cerebral venous thrombosis in a newborn successfully treated with remdesivir, glucocorticoids, and hyperimmune plasma. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:13201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8701660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34948814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiff J, Brennan C. COVID-19 presenting as a bulging fontanelle. Am J Emerg Med. 2021;43:81&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7843070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33548683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sethuraman C, Holland J, Priego G, Khan F, Johnson R, Keane M. Bulging anterior fontanelle caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2023;42:e4&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9725740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36476525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eghbalian F, Sami G, Bashirian S, Jenabi E. A neonate infected with coronavirus disease 2019with severe symptoms suspicious of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in childhood. Clin Exp Pediatr. 2021;64:596&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8566797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34530521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mierzewska-Schmidt M, Ciaston M, Kuchar E, Ploski R, et al. The case of fatal acute hemorrhagic necrotizing encephalitis in a two-month-old boy with COVID-19. Int J Infect Dis. 2022;116:151&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8683211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34929359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firestein MR, Shuffrey LC, Hu Y, Kyle M, Hussain M, Bianco C, et al. Assessment of neurodevelopment in infants with and without exposure to asymptomatic or mild maternal SARS-CoV-2 infection during pregnancy. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6:e237396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10087058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37036706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuffrey LC, Firestein MR, Kyle M, Fields A, Alc&#xe1;ntara C, Amso D, et al. Association of birth during COVID-19 pandemic with neurodevelopmental status at 6 months in infants with and without in utero exposure to maternal SARS-CoV-2 infection. JAMA Pediatr. 2022;176:e215563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8728661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34982107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ungar SP, Solomon S, Stachel A, Demarco K, Roman AS, Lighter J. Impact of prenatal SARS-CoV-2 infection on infant emergency department visits and hospitalization. Clin Pediatr. 2022;61:206&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34903074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goulding A, McQuaid F, Lindsay L, Agrawal U, Auyeung B, Calvert C, et al. Confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection in Scottish neonates 2020-2022: a national, population-based cohort study. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2023;108:367&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10313998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36609412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf6;tzinger F, Santiago-Garcia B, Noguera-Juli&#xe1;n A, Lanaspa L, Lancella L, Cal&#xf2; Carducci F, et al. COVID-19 in children and adolescents in Europe: a multinational, multicenter cohort study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2020;4:653&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7316447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32593339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohagheghi P, Hakimelahi J, Khalajinia Z, Sadeghi Moghadam P. COVID-19 infection in Iranian newborns and their mothers: case series. Tanaffos. 2021;20:172&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8710223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34976089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halasa NB, Olson SM, Staat MA, Newhams MM, Price AM, Pannaraj PS, et al. Maternal vaccination and risk of hospitalization for COVID-19 among infants. N Engl J Med. 2022;387:109&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9342588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35731908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosdin L, Wallace B, Lanzieri TM, O&#x2019;Malley Olsen E, Lewis EL, Chang DJ, et al. Six-month outcomes of infants born to people with SARS-CoV-2 in pregnancy. Pediatrics. 2022;150:e2022059009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9761394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36317478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fattahi P, Abdi S, Saeedi E, Sirous S, Firuzian F, Mohammadi M, et al. In-hospital mortality of COVID-19 in Iranian children and youth: a multi-centre retrospective cohort study. J Glob Health. 2022;12:05048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9653210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36370421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte-Neto AN, Caldini EG, Gomes-Gouv&#xea;a MS, Kanamura CT, de Almeida Monteiro RA, Ferranti JF, et al. An autopsy study of the spectrum of severe COVID-19 in children: From SARS to different phenotypes of MIS-C. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;35:100850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33937731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamazaki-Nakashimada MA, M&#xe1;rquez-Gonz&#xe1;lez H, Miranda-Novales G, Neme D&#xed;az GA, Prado Duran SA, Lu&#xe9;vanos Vel&#xe1;zquez A, et al. Characteristics and outcomes of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children: A multicenter, retrospective, observational cohort study in Mexico. Front Pediatr. 2023;11:1167871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10233130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37274824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buja LM, Wolf DA, Zhao B, Akkanti B, McDonald M, Lelenwa L, et al. The emerging spectrum of cardiopulmonary pathology of the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): report of 3 autopsies from Houston, Texas, and review of autopsy findings from other United States cities. Cardiovasc Pathol. 2020;48:107233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7204762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32434133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Septimiu-Radu S, Gadela T, Gabriela D, Oancea C, Rosca O, Lazureanu VE, et al. A systematic review of lung autopsy findings in elderly patients after SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Clin Med. 2023;12:2070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10004532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36902856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Octavius GS, Wijaya JH, Tan AO, Muljono MP, Chandra S, Juliansen A. Autopsy findings of pediatric COVID-19: a systematic review. Egypt J Forensic Sci. 2022;12:32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9281196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35855892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khairwa A, Jat KR. Autopsy findings of COVID-19 in children: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Forensic Sci Med Pathol. 2022;18:516&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9434090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36048325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatnagar J, Gary J, Reagan-Steiner S, Estettter LB, Tong S, Tao Y, et al. Evidence of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 replication and tropisms in the lungs, airways, and vascular epithelium of patients with fatal coronavirus disease 2019: an autopsy case series. J Infect Dis. 2021;223:752&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7928839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33502471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goussard P, Schubert P, Parker N, Myburgh C, Rabie H, van der Zalm MM, et al. Fatal SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variant in a young infant: autopsy findings. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2022;57:1363&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9088365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35243813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stram MN, Seifert AC, Cortes E, Akyatan A, Woodoff-Leith E, Borukhov V, et al. Neuropathology of pediatric SARSCoV-2 infection in the forensic setting: novel application of ex vivo imaging in analysis of brain microvasculature. Front Neurol. 2022;13:894565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9170881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35685741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konopka KE, Nguyen T, Hlavaty L, Rayes O, Schmidt CJ, Dahl J, et al. Utility of CDC screening guidelines and autopsy findings in identifying decedents who die of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Am J Forensic Med Pathol. 2021;42:118&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8115420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33833197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulale UK, Kashamba T, Strysko J, Kyokunda LT. Fatal SARS-CoV-2 and Mycobacterium tuberculosis coinfection in an infant: insights from Botswana. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14:e239701</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8061865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33883111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Almeida Monteiro RA, Duarte-Neto AN, Ferraz da Silva LF, de Oliveira EP, do Nascimento ECT, Mauad T, et al. Ultrasound assessment of pulmonary fibroproliferative changes in severe COVID-19: a quantitative correlation study with histopathological findings. Intensive Care Med. 2021;47:199&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7779089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33392642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Jiang Q, Xia X, Liu K, Yu Z, Tao W, et al. Individual variation of the SARS-CoV-2 receptor ACE2 gene expression and regulation. Aging Cell. 2020;19:e13168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32558150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dioguardi M, Cazzolla AP, Arena C, Sovereto D, Caloro GA, Dioguardi A, et al. Innate immunity in children and the role of ACE2 expression in SARS-CoV-2 infection. Pediatr Rep. 2021;13:363&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8293341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34287338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Solidifying diagnostics in SARS-CoV-2 research. Am J Obstet Gynecol MFM. 2022;4:100514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8516160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34656735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Not all viral culture approaches are equal. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e1787&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33104181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim L, Wilson C, Tham D, Corden M, Jani S, Zhang M, et al. The characteristics of SARS-CoV-2-positive children in Australian hospitals: a PREDICT network study. Med J Aust. 2023;218:460&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10953026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37087105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haraschchenko T, Umanets T, Pololskiy V, Kaminska T, Marushko Y, Podolskiy V, et al. Epidemiological, clinical, and laboratory features of children with SARS-CoV-2 in Ukraine. J Mother Child. 2023;27:33&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10405021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37545134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardelid P, Favarato G, Wijlaars L, Fenton L, McMenamin J, Clemens T, et al. SARS-CoV-2 tests, confirmed infections and COVD-19-related hospital admissions in children and young people: birth cohort study. BMJ Pediatr Open. 2022;6:e001545</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9437731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36053647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Co-detections versus coinfections in the context of SARS-CoV-2 diagnostics. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2022;77:542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34695212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Complicating infections associated with common endemic human respiratory coronaviruses. Health Secur. 2021;19:195&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33186086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob R, Padeh G, Kaplan O, Koppel JH, Porat D, Weiser G, et al. Bacterial infections and clinical outcomes among febrile infants up to 90 days old with SARS-CoV-2 infection: a multicenter cohort study. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2023;42:905&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37406214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krogstad P, Contreras D, Ng H, Tobin N, Chambers CD, Bertrand K, et al. No infectious SARS-CoV-2 in breast milk from a cohort of 110 lactating women. Pediatr Res. 2022;92:1140&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9586866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35042956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis EL, Smoots AN, Woodworth KR, Olsen EO, Roth NM, Yazdy M, et al. Breast milk feeding of infants at birth among people with confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection in pregnancy: SET-NET, 5 States, March 29, 2020-December 31, 2020. Am J Public Health. 2022;112(S8):S787&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9612185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36288521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvatore CM, Han JY, Acker KP, Tiwari P, Jin J, Brandler M, et al. Neonatal management and outcomes during the COVID19 pandemic: an observation cohort study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2020;4:721&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7377726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32711687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shlomai NO, Kasirer Y, Strauss T, Smolkin T, Marom R, Shinwell ES, et al. Neonatal SARS-CoV-2 infections in breastfeeding mothers. Pediatrics. 2021;147:e2020010918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33850028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briana DD, Malamitsi-Puchner A. Breastfeeding provides a protective hug and the benefits have outweighed the risks during the COVID-19 pandemic. Acta Paediatr. 2023;112:1177&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36945791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Reanalysis of quarantine for coronavirus disease 2019 with emerging data. Am J Obstet Gynecol MFM. 2021;3:100291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33451605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. In pursuit of the right tail for the COVID-19 incubation period. Public Health. 2021;194:149&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7997403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33915459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. More data are required for incubation period, infectivity, and quarantine duration for COVID-19. Travel Med Infect Dis. 2020;37:101713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7185007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32353629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control  Multisystem inflammatory syndrome (MIS): information for healthcare providers about multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) [Internet]  Atlanta (GA): 2023 [cited 2323 Apr 2]. Available from:  https://www.cdc.gov/mis/mis-c/hcp_cstecdc/index.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molloy EJ, Nakra N, Gale C, Dimitriades VR, Lakshminrusimha S. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) and neonates (MIS-N) associated with COVID-19: optimizing definition and management. Pediatr Res. 2023;93:1499&#x2013;508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9436161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36050390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royal College of Paediatrics and Child Health  . London: Royal College of Paediatrics andChild Health; 2023. Guidance: paediatric multisystem inflammatory syndrome temporally associated with COVID-19 [Internet] [cited 2023Apr 14].Available from:  https://www.rcpch.ac.uk/sites/default/files/2020-05/COVID-19-Paediatric-multisystem-%20inflammatory%20syndrome-20200501.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dufort EM, Koumans EH, Chow EJ, Rosenthal EM, Muse A, Rowlands J, et al. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children in New York State. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:347&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7346766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32598830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Mast cell biology and linkages for non-clonal mast cell activation and autoimmune/inflammatory syndrome induced by adjuvants. SN Compr Clin Med. 2020;2:2310&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaki SA, Hazeem AA, Rashid A. Giant coronary aneurysm in an infant with multisystem inflammatory syndrome. Heart Views. 2022;23:108&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9542971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36213433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diwakar K, Gupta BK, Uddin MW, Sharma A, Jhajra S. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome with persistent neutropenia in neonate exposed to SARS-CoV-2 virus: a case report and review of literature. J Neonatal Perinatal Med. 2022;15:373&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34459420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappanayil M, Balan S, Alawani S, Mohanty S, Leeladharan SP, Gangadharan JP, et al. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in a neonate, temporally associated with prenatal exposure to SARS-CoV-2: a case report. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2021;5:304&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33675696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaund Borkotoky R, Banerjee Barua P, Paul SP, Heaton PA. COVID-19-related potential multisystem inflammatory syndrome in childhood in a neonate presenting as persistent pulmonary hypertension of the newborn. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:e162&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33464010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xe1;mez-Gonz&#xe1;lez LB, Esc&#xe1;rcega-Ju&#xe1;rez Ana Silvia AS, Aguilar-Soto DE, Colmenero Rasc&#xf3;n M, Garc&#xed;a Espinosa AC, YamazakiNakashimada MA. Multisystem inflammatory syndrome in neonates associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection, a different entity? J Neonatal Perinatal Med. 2023;16:169&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36314218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zambrano LD, Wu MJ, Martin L, Malloch L, Chen S, Newhams MM, et al. Risk factors for multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children: a case-control investigation. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2023;42:e190&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10265536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37000922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan L, Pl&#xf6;tz FB, van den Hoogen A, Latour JM, Degtyareva M, Keuning M, et al. Neonates and COVID-19: state of the art. Pediatr Res. 2022;91:432&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8712275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34961785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodansky A, Sabatino JJ, Jr, Vazquez S, Chou S, Novak T, Moffitt KL, et al.  A distinct cross-reactive autoimmune response in multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) medRxiv [Preprint] 2023 [cited 2023 Apr 2]. Available from:  https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2023.05.26.23290373v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.05.26.23290373v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klavina L, Smane L, Kivite-Urtane A, Vasilevska L, Davidsone Z, Smitins E, et al. Comparison of characteristics and outcomes of multisystem inflammatory syndrome, Kawasaki disease and toxic shock syndrome in children. Medicina (Kaunas) 2023;59:626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10056689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36984627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Applying immune instincts and maternal intelligence from comparative microbiology to COVID-19. SN Compr Clin Med. 2020;2:2670&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33195997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wachman EM, Snyder-Cappione J, Devera J, Boateng J, Dhole Y, Clarke K, et al. Maternal, infant, and breast milk antibody response following COVID-19 infection in early versus late gestation. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2023;42:e70&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9935237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36729773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibroci E, Liu X, Lieb W, Jessel R, Gigase FAJ, Chung K, et al. Impact of prenatal COVID-19 vaccination at delivery and neonatal outcomes: results from a New York City cohort. Vaccine. 2023;41:649&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9749885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36526507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathy GS, Rath TS, Behera S, Lekha KS, Kar D, Pendyala S. Effects of COVID-19 vaccination during pregnancy on the obstetric and neonatal outcomes in a tertiary health care center. J Mother Child. 2023;27:72&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10323967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37409659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorgensen SCJ, Hernandez A, Fell DB, Austin PC, D&#x2019;Souza R, Guttmann A, et al. Maternal mRNA COVID-19 vaccination during pregnancy and delta or omicron infection or hospital admission in infants: test negative design study. BMJ. 2023;380:e074035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9903336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36754426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danino D, Ashkenazi-Hoffnung L, Diaz A, Erps AD, Eliakim-Riaz N, Avni YS, et al. Effectiveness of BNT162b2 vaccination during pregnancy in preventing hospitalization for SARSCoV-2 in infants. J Pediatr. 2023;254:48&#x2013;53.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9568274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36252864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerbo O, Ray GT, Fireman B, Layefsky E, Goddard K, Lewis E, et al. Maternal SARS-CoV-2 vaccination and infant protection against SARS-CoV-2 during the first six months of life. Nat Commun. 2023;14:894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9974935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36854660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Immunophenotyping of SARS-CoV-2 and vaccine design. Vaccine. 2022;40:3985&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35717108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhikari EH, Lu P, Kang YJ, McDonald AR, Pruszynski JE, Bates TA, et al. Diverging maternal and cord antibody functions from SARS-CoV-2 infection and vaccination in pregnancy. J Infect Dis. 2023 Oct 10;:jiad421. doi: 10.1093/infdis/jiad421. [Epub]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10873180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37815524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. A minimalist strategy towards temporarily defining protection for COVID-19. SN Compr Clin Med. 2020;2:2059&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7501512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32984765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ockene MW, Russo SC, Lee H, Month&#xe9;-Dr&#xe8;ze C, Stanley TL, Ma IL, et al. Accelerated longitudinal weight gain among infants with in utero COVID-19 exposure. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2023;108:2579&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10505544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36988326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy S, Jha VN, Ranjan B. A case series of coagulopathy in preterm or growth-restricted term neonates born to mothers with antenatal SARS-CoV-2 infection: neonatal post-COVID-19 coagulopathy? J Family Med Prim Care. 2022;11:7483&#x2013;490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10041319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36993065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Microvascular hypertensive disease, Long COVID, and end-organ pathology. Hypertens Res. 2023;46:2247&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37443258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derespina KR, Kaushik S, Plichta A, Conway EE, Jr, Bercow A, Choi J, et al. Clinical manifestations and outcomes of critically ill children and adolescents with coronavirus disease 2019 in New York City. J Pediatr. 2020;226:55&#x2013;63.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7363610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32681989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoji K, Asai Y, Akiyama T, Tsuzuki S, Matsunaga N, Suzuki S, et al. Clinical efficacy of remdesivir for COVID-19 in children: a propensity-score-matched analysis. J Infect Chemother. 2023;29:930&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10259089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37315843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman DL, Aldrich M, Hagmann SHF, Bamford A, Camacho-Gonzalez A, Lapadula G, et al. Compassionate use of remdesivir in children with severe COVID-19. Pediatrics. 2021;147:e2020047803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33883243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimolai N. Passive immunity should and will work for COVID19 for some patients. Clin Hematol Int. 2021;3:47&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8432400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34595467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadian YS, Ali M, Kumar C, Kajal P. Surgical neonates with coronavirus infectious disease-19 infection: an experience with five cases at high-volume tertiary care centre of India. Afr J Paediatr Surg. 2022;19:228&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9615953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36018203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>