<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36483107</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2220-3249</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Musculoskeletal complications in long COVID-19: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>485</StartPage><EndPage>495</EndPage><MedlinePgn>485-495</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5501/wjv.v11.i6.485</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) has crippled humanity since early 2020. Various sequelae of COVID-19 have been reported in different body systems. Musculoskeletal symptoms are widely reported during COVID-19 infection, but musculoskeletal complications in long COVID-19 are underreported. However, post-COVID-19 survivors have reported complaints of persisting or new-onset fatigue, myalgia, arthralgia, arthritis, muscle weakness, <i>etc</i> in clinical practice. The well-known detrimental effects of steroids on the musculoskeletal system coupled with their over-the-counter availability can also be anticipated since they were the cornerstone of life-saving management in this pandemic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine the musculoskeletal complications in long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We performed a systematic review of 'systematic reviews and meta-analyses'.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 63 articles screened, 24 articles were included. Two articles specifically discussed children and adolescents. One article discussed rehabilitation intervention. No article addressed rehabilitation of musculoskeletal issues in long COVID-19 in particular. Fatigue was the most common musculoskeletal complication.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Fatigue is found to be very common along with myalgia and arthralgia. There were no studies on rehabilitation intervention in musculoskeletal complications specifically. Considering the lacuna in literature and the needs of the current situation, further studies are warranted to standardize effective rehabilitation interventions in musculoskeletal complications. More homogenous studies are needed. Studies on functional impairment due to musculoskeletal involvement are essential.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2022. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swarnakar</LastName><ForeName>Raktim</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi 110029, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jenifa</LastName><ForeName>Shoibam</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi 110029, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wadhwa</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi 110029, Delhi, India. wadhwadr@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101608353</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2220-3249</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Musculoskeletal complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-COVID-19 syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report having no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36483107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9724204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5501/wjv.v11.i6.485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization.  Data at WHO. [cited 1 September 2022]. Available from: https://www.who.int/data .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludvigsson JF. Case report and systematic review suggest that children may experience similar long-term effects to adults after clinical COVID-19. Acta Paediatr. 2021;110:914&#x2013;921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33205450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbarialiabad H, Taghrir MH, Abdollahi A, Ghahramani N, Kumar M, Paydar S, Razani B, Mwangi J, Asadi-Pooya AA, Malekmakan L, Bastani B. Long COVID, a comprehensive systematic scoping review. Infection. 2021;49:1163&#x2013;1186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8317481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34319569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, Cheng V, Dagens A, Hastie C, O'Hara M, Suett J, Dahmash D, Bugaeva P, Rigby I, Munblit D, Harriss E, Burls A, Foote C, Scott J, Carson G, Olliaro P, Sigfrid L, Stavropoulou C. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal FM, Lam K, Sounderajah V, Clarke JM, Ashrafian H, Darzi A. Characteristics and predictors of acute and chronic post-COVID syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;36:100899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8141371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34036253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollbracht C, Kraft K. Feasibility of Vitamin C in the Treatment of Post Viral Fatigue with Focus on Long COVID, Based on a Systematic Review of IV Vitamin C on Fatigue. Nutrients. 2021;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8066596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings G, Monaghan A, Xue F, Mockler D, Romero-Ortu&#xf1;o R. A Systematic Review of Persistent Symptoms and Residual Abnormal Functioning following Acute COVID-19: Ongoing Symptomatic Phase vs. Post-COVID-19 Syndrome. J Clin Med. 2021;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8708187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34945213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Florencio LL, Cuadrado ML, Plaza-Manzano G, Navarro-Santana M. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Intern Med. 2021;92:55&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34167876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik P, Patel K, Pinto C, Jaiswal R, Tirupathi R, Pillai S, Patel U. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PCS) and health-related quality of life (HRQoL)-A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2022;94:253&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34463956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Ling S, Lui LMW, Lee Y, Gill H, Teopiz KM, Rodrigues NB, Subramaniapillai M, Di Vincenzo JD, Cao B, Lin K, Mansur RB, Ho RC, Rosenblat JD, Miskowiak KW, Vinberg M, Maletic V, McIntyre RS. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun. 2022;101:93&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global Prevalence of Post COVID-19 Condition or Long COVID: A Meta-Analysis and Systematic Review. J Infect Dis. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Kessel SAM, Olde Hartman TC, Lucassen PLBJ, van Jaarsveld CHM. Post-acute and long-COVID-19 symptoms in patients with mild diseases: a systematic review. Fam Pract. 2022;39:159&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8414057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34268556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkodaymi MS, Omrani OA, Fawzy NA, Shaar BA, Almamlouk R, Riaz M, Obeidat M, Obeidat Y, Gerberi D, Taha RM, Kashour Z, Kashour T, Berbari EF, Alkattan K, Tleyjeh IM. Prevalence of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome symptoms at different follow-up periods: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28:657&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8812092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, Plaza-Manzano G, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, Arendt-Nielsen L. Time course prevalence of post-COVID pain symptoms of musculoskeletal origin in patients who had survived severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pain. 2022;163:1220&#x2013;1231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34561390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q, Zheng B, Daines L, Sheikh A. Long-Term Sequelae of COVID-19: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of One-Year Follow-Up Studies on Post-COVID Symptoms. Pathogens. 2022;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8875269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35215212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>d'Ettorre G, Gentilini Cacciola E, Santinelli L, De Girolamo G, Spagnolello O, Russo A, Tarsitani L, Ciccozzi M, Mastroianni CM, d'Ettorre G, Ceccarelli G. Covid-19 sequelae in working age patients: A systematic review. J Med Virol. 2022;94:858&#x2013;868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34655247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behnood SA, Shafran R, Bennett SD, Zhang AXD, O'Mahoney LL, Stephenson TJ, Ladhani SN, De Stavola BL, Viner RM, Swann OV. Persistent symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infection amongst children and young people: A meta-analysis of controlled and uncontrolled studies. J Infect. 2022;84:158&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8604800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34813820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen NN, Hoang VT, Dao TL, Dudouet P, Eldin C, Gautret P. Clinical patterns of somatic symptoms in patients suffering from post-acute long COVID: a systematic review. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2022;41:515&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8830952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Ayuzo Del Valle NC, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, Villapol S. Long-COVID in children and adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Sci Rep. 2022;12:9950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9226045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35739136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Gawad M, Zaghloul MS, Abd-Elsalam S, Hashem M, Lashen SA, Mahros AM, Mohammed AQ, Hassan AM, Bekhit AN, Mohammed W, Alboraie M. Post-COVID-19 Syndrome Clinical Manifestations: A Systematic Review. Antiinflamm Antiallergy Agents Med Chem. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35346011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almas T, Malik J, Alsubai AK, Jawad Zaidi SM, Iqbal R, Khan K, Ali M, Ishaq U, Alsufyani M, Hadeed S, Alsufyani R, Ahmed R, Thakur T, Huang H, Antony M, Antony I, Bhullar A, Kotait F, Al-Ani L. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and its prolonged effects: An updated systematic review. Ann Med Surg (Lond) 2022;80:103995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9197790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35721785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maglietta G, Diodati F, Puntoni M, Lazzarelli S, Marcomini B, Patrizi L, Caminiti C. Prognostic Factors for Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Clin Med. 2022;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8948827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35329867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healey Q, Sheikh A, Daines L, Vasileiou E. Symptoms and signs of long COVID: A rapid review and meta-analysis. J Glob Health. 2022;12:05014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9125197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35596571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Almeida K, Nogueira Alves IG, de Queiroz RS, de Castro MR, Gomes VA, Santos Fontoura FC, Brites C, Neto MG. A systematic review on physical function, activities of daily living and health-related quality of life in COVID-19 survivors. Chronic Illn. 2022:17423953221089309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9006095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35404175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fugazzaro S, Contri A, Esseroukh O, Kaleci S, Croci S, Massari M, Facciolongo NC, Besutti G, Iori M, Salvarani C, Costi S Reggio Emilia COVID-19 Working Group. Rehabilitation Interventions for Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome: A Systematic Review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9104923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35564579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan P. NICE guideline on long COVID. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> A clinical case definition of post COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus (6 October 2021). [cited 6 July 2022]. Available from: https://reliefweb.int/report/world/clinical-case-definition-post-covid-19-condition-delphi-consensus-6-october-2021 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi N. Long covid: How to define it and how to manage it. BMJ. 2020;370:m3489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32895219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Z, Yang M, Lai CL. Long COVID-19 Syndrome: A Comprehensive Review of Its Effect on Various Organ Systems and Recommendation on Rehabilitation Plans. Biomedicines. 2021;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34440170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV WHO Clinical Case Definition Working Group on Post-COVID-19 Condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:e102&#x2013;e107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang MY, Zhao R, Gao LJ, Gao XF, Wang DP, Cao JM. SARS-CoV-2: Structure, Biology, and Structure-Based Therapeutics Development. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2020;10:587269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7723891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33324574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M, Kleine-Weber H, Schroeder S, Kr&#xfc;ger N, Herrler T, Erichsen S, Schiergens TS, Herrler G, Wu NH, Nitsche A, M&#xfc;ller MA, Drosten C, P&#xf6;hlmann S. SARS-CoV-2 Cell Entry Depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and Is Blocked by a Clinically Proven Protease Inhibitor. Cell. 2020;181:271&#x2013;280.e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disser NP, De Micheli AJ, Schonk MM, Konnaris MA, Piacentini AN, Edon DL, Toresdahl BG, Rodeo SA, Casey EK, Mendias CL. Musculoskeletal Consequences of COVID-19. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2020;102:1197&#x2013;1204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32675661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan LK, Deadwiler B, Haratian A, Bolia IK, Weber AE, Petrigliano FA. Effects of COVID-19 on the Musculoskeletal System: Clinician's Guide. Orthop Res Rev. 2021;13:141&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8464590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34584465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, Billig Rose E, Shapiro NI, Files DC, Gibbs KW, Erickson HL, Steingrub JS, Smithline HA, Gong MN, Aboodi MS, Exline MC, Henning DJ, Wilson JG, Khan A, Qadir N, Brown SM, Peltan ID, Rice TW, Hager DN, Ginde AA, Stubblefield WB, Patel MM, Self WH, Feldstein LR IVY Network Investigators; CDC COVID-19 Response Team; IVY Network Investigators. Symptom Duration and Risk Factors for Delayed Return to Usual Health Among Outpatients with COVID-19 in a Multistate Health Care Systems Network - United States, March-June 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69:993&#x2013;998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer KP, Thompson Bastin ML, Montgomery-Yates AA, Pastva AM, Dupont-Versteegden EE, Parry SM, Morris PE. Acute skeletal muscle wasting and dysfunction predict physical disability at hospital discharge in patients with critical illness. Crit Care. 2020;24:637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7640401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33148301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Persistent Symptoms in Patients After Acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paneroni M, Simonelli C, Saleri M, Bertacchini L, Venturelli M, Troosters T, Ambrosino N, Vitacca M. Muscle Strength and Physical Performance in Patients Without Previous Disabilities Recovering From COVID-19 Pneumonia. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;100:105&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs LG, Gourna Paleoudis E, Lesky-Di Bari D, Nyirenda T, Friedman T, Gupta A, Rasouli L, Zetkulic M, Balani B, Ogedegbe C, Bawa H, Berrol L, Qureshi N, Aschner JL. Persistence of symptoms and quality of life at 35 days after hospitalization for COVID-19 infection. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0243882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7732078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK - Office for National Statistics [Internet]. [cited 14 July 2022]. Available from: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/7july2022 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau HM, Lee EW, Wong CN, Ng GY, Jones AY, Hui DS. The impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome on the physical profile and quality of life. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2005;86:1134&#x2013;1140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15954051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, Rivera SC, McMullan C, Chandan JS, Haroon S, Price G, Davies EH, Nirantharakumar K, Sapey E, Calvert MJ TLC Study Group. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med. 2021;114:428&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varghese J, Sandmann S, Ochs K, Schrempf IM, Fr&#xf6;mmel C, Dugas M, Schmidt HH, Vollenberg R, Tepasse PR. Persistent symptoms and lab abnormalities in patients who recovered from COVID-19. Sci Rep. 2021;11:12775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8211641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34140539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, Kang L, Guo L, Liu M, Zhou X, Luo J, Huang Z, Tu S, Zhao Y, Chen L, Xu D, Li Y, Li C, Peng L, Xie W, Cui D, Shang L, Fan G, Xu J, Wang G, Zhong J, Wang C, Wang J, Zhang D, Cao B. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazato Y, Morioka S, Tsuzuki S, Akashi M, Osanai Y, Tanaka K, Terada M, Suzuki M, Kutsuna S, Saito S, Hayakawa K, Ohmagari N. Prolonged and Late-Onset Symptoms of Coronavirus Disease 2019. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2020;7:ofaa507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33230486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher A, Balfanz P, Cornelissen C, M&#xfc;ller A, Bergs I, Marx N, M&#xfc;ller-Wieland D, Hartmann B, Dreher M, M&#xfc;ller T. Follow up of patients with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): Pulmonary and extrapulmonary disease sequelae. Respir Med. 2020;174:106197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33120193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re'em Y, Redfield S, Austin JP, Akrami A. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin D, Margalit I, Nehme M, Bordas-Mart&#xed;nez J, Pistelli F, Yahav D, Guessous I, Dur&#xe0;-Miralles X, Carrozzi L, Shapira-Lichter I, Vetter P, Peleato-Catalan D, Tiseo G, Wirtheim E, Kaiser L, Gudiol C, Falcone M, Leibovici L On Behalf Of The LongCOV Research Group. Patterns of Long COVID Symptoms: A Multi-Center Cross Sectional Study. J Clin Med. 2022;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8875229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35207171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos PK, Sigoli E, Bragan&#xe7;a LJG, Cornachione AS. The Musculoskeletal Involvement After Mild to Moderate COVID-19 Infection. Front Physiol. 2022;13:813924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9040683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35492595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphreys H, Kilby L, Kudiersky N, Copeland R. Long COVID and the role of physical activity: a qualitative study. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e047632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7948149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardemil CV, Balachandran N, Kambhampati A, Grytdal S, Dahl RM, Rodriguez-Barradas MC, Vargas B, Beenhouwer DO, Evangelista KV, Marconi VC, Meagley KL, Brown ST, Perea A, Lucero-Obusan C, Holodniy M, Browne H, Gautam R, Bowen MD, Vinj&#xe9; J, Parashar UD, Hall AJ. Incidence, Etiology, and Severity of Acute Gastroenteritis Among Prospectively Enrolled Patients in 4 Veterans Affairs Hospitals and Outpatient Centers, 2016-2018. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e2729&#x2013;e2738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9195496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32584956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoong CWS, Amin MNME, Tan TC, Lee JE. Viral arthralgia a new manifestation of COVID-19 infection? Int J Infect Dis. 2021;104:363&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7813485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33476761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhiny R, Al-Jumaili AA, Yawuz MJ. What might COVID-19 Patients Experience after Recovery? A Systematic Review. 2021 Preprint. Available from: PPR: PPR358497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9384593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35881153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen MS, Kristiansen MF, Hanusson KD, Danielsen ME, &#xc1; Steig B, Gaini S, Str&#xf8;m M, Weihe P. Long COVID in the Faroe Islands: A Longitudinal Study Among Nonhospitalized Patients. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73:e4058&#x2013;e4063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7799340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33252665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Schneider C, Laurent E, Lemaignen A, Beaufils E, Bourbao-Tournois C, Laribi S, Flament T, Ferreira-Maldent N, Bruy&#xe8;re F, Stefic K, Gaudy-Graffin C, Grammatico-Guillon L, Bernard L. Follow-up of adults with noncritical COVID-19 two months after symptom onset. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:258&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra N, Chowdhury M, Singh AK, Ma K, Kumar A, Ranjan P, Desai D, Wig N. Clinical predictors of long COVID-19 and phenotypes of mild COVID-19 at a tertiary care centre in India. Drug Discov Ther. 2021;15:156&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34234065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, Ghanima W, Olsen MK, Gilboe HM, Einvik G. Persistent symptoms 1.5-6 months after COVID-19 in non-hospitalised subjects: a population-based cohort study. Thorax. 2021;76:405&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosn J, Piroth L, Epaulard O, Le Turnier P, Mentr&#xe9; F, Bachelet D, Laou&#xe9;nan C French COVID cohort study and investigators groups. Persistent COVID-19 symptoms are highly prevalent 6&#xa0;months after hospitalization: results from a large prospective cohort. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:1041.e1&#x2013;1041.e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8107834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34125067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono K, Kishimoto M, Shimasaki T, Uchida H, Kurai D, Deshpande GA, Komagata Y, Kaname S. Reactive arthritis after COVID-19 infection. RMD Open. 2020;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7722270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32763956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapkota HR, Nune A. Long COVID from rheumatology perspective - a narrative review. Clin Rheumatol. 2022;41:337&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8629735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34845562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derksen VFAM, Kissel T, Lamers-Karnebeek FBG, van der Bijl AE, Venhuizen AC, Huizinga TWJ, Toes REM, Roukens AHE, van der Woude D. Onset of rheumatoid arthritis after COVID-19: coincidence or connected? Ann Rheum Dis. 2021;80:1096&#x2013;1098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33648960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berkta&#x15f; BM, G&#xf6;k&#xe7;ek A, Hoca NT, Koyuncu A. COVID-19 illness and treatment decrease bone mineral density of surviving hospitalized patients. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2022;26:3046&#x2013;3056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35503607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kottlors J, Gro&#xdf;e Hokamp N, Fervers P, Bremm J, Fichter F, Persigehl T, Safarov O, Maintz D, Tritt S, Abdullayev N. Early extrapulmonary prognostic features in chest computed tomography in COVID-19 pneumonia: Bone mineral density is a relevant predictor for the clinical outcome - A multicenter feasibility study. Bone. 2021;144:115790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7720732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33301962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerkman JN, Daffertshofer A, Gollo LL, Breakspear M, Boonstra TW. Network structure of the human musculoskeletal system shapes neural interactions on multiple time scales. Sci Adv. 2018;4:eaat0497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6021138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29963631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahouth S, Chuang K, Olson L, Rosenthal D. COVID-19 related muscle denervation atrophy. Skeletal Radiol. 2021;50:1717&#x2013;1721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7847416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33517510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agergaard J, Leth S, Pedersen TH, Harbo T, Blicher JU, Karlsson P, &#xd8;stergaard L, Andersen H, Tankisi H. Myopathic changes in patients with long-term fatigue after COVID-19. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132:1974&#x2013;1981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8102077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34020890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam B, Ahmed M, Islam Z, Begum SM. Severe acute myopathy following SARS-CoV-2 infection: a case report and review of recent literature. Skelet Muscle. 2021;11:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8058144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33883014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonorino KC, Cani KC. Early mobilization in the time of COVID-19. Rev Bras Ter Intensiva. 2020;32:484&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7853669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33470350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wade DT. Rehabilitation after COVID-19: an evidence-based approach. Clin Med (Lond) 2020;20:359&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32518105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swarnakar R, Yadav SL. Rehabilitation in long COVID-19: A mini-review. World J Methodol. 2022;12:235&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9350732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36159093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>