<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39252604</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1293</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>HIV medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>HIV Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID among people with HIV: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/hiv.13708</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">People with HIV might be at an increased risk of long COVID (LC) because of their immune dysfunction and chronic inflammation and alterations in immunological responses against severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2; coronavirus disease 2019 [COVID-19]). This systematic review aimed to evaluate the association between HIV infection and LC and the prevalence and characteristics of and risk factors for LC among people with HIV.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Multiple databases, including Embase, PubMed, PsycINFO, Web of Science, and Sociological Abstracts, were searched to identify articles published before June 2023. Published articles were included if they presented at least one LC outcome measure among people with HIV and used quantitative or mixed-methods study designs. For effects reported in three or more studies, meta-analyses using random-effects models were performed using R software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We pooled 39&#x2009;405 people with HIV and COVID-19 in 17 eligible studies out of 6158 publications in all the databases. It was estimated that 52% of people with HIV with SARS-CoV-2 infection developed at least one LC symptom. Results from the random-effects model showed that HIV infection was associated with an increased risk of LC (odds ratio&#x2009;2.20; 95% confidence interval 1.25-3.86). The most common LC symptoms among people with HIV were cough, fatigue, and asthenia. Risk factors associated with LC among people with HIV included a history of moderate-severe COVID-19 illness, increased interferon-gamma-induced protein 10 or tumour necrosis factor-&#x3b1;, and decreased interferon-&#x3b2;, among others.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The COVID-19 pandemic continues to exacerbate health inequities among people with HIV because of their higher risk of developing LC. Our review is informative for public health and clinical communities to develop tailored strategies to prevent aggravated LC among people with HIV.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). HIV Medicine published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British HIV Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xueying</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6788-0688</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Promotion, Education, and Behavior, Arnold School of Public Health, University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>South Carolina SmartState Center for Healthcare Quality, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of South Carolina Big Data Health Science Center, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Fanghui</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Promotion, Education, and Behavior, Arnold School of Public Health, University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>South Carolina SmartState Center for Healthcare Quality, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of South Carolina Big Data Health Science Center, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giang</LastName><ForeName>William A</ForeName><Initials>WA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Promotion, Education, and Behavior, Arnold School of Public Health, University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaur</LastName><ForeName>Amandeep</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Arnold School of Public Health, University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoming</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Promotion, Education, and Behavior, Arnold School of Public Health, University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>South Carolina SmartState Center for Healthcare Quality, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of South Carolina Big Data Health Science Center, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>NH</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R21AI170159-01A1</GrantID><Agency>University of South Carolina</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>HIV Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100897392</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1464-2662</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIV/AIDS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta&#x2010;analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39252604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hiv.13708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Spinelli MA, Deveau T&#x2010;M, et al. Postacute sequelae and adaptive immune responses in people with HIV recovering from SARS&#x2010;COV&#x2010;2 infection. Aids. 2022;36(12):F7&#x2010;F16. doi:10.1097/qad.0000000000003338</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingery JR, Safford MM, Martin P, et al. Health status, persistent symptoms, and effort intolerance one year after acute COVID&#x2010;19 infection. J Gen Intern Med. 2022;37(5):1218&#x2010;1225. doi:10.1007/s11606&#x2010;021&#x2010;07379&#x2010;z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Antar AAR. Long COVID in people living with HIV. Curr Opin HIV AIDS. 2023;18(3):126&#x2010;134. doi:10.1097/coh.0000000000000789</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamanzi P, Mulundu G, Mutale K, Mumba C, Ngalamika O. HIV and inflammatory markers are associated with persistent COVID&#x2010;19 symptoms. Immun Inflamm Dis. 2023;11(5):e859. doi:10.1002/iid3.859</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deveau TM, Munter SE, et al. Chronic viral coinfections differentially affect the likelihood of developing long COVID. J Clin Invest. 2023;133(3):e163669. doi:10.1172/JCI163669</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzitelli M, Trunfio M, Sasset L, et al. Factors associated with severe COVID&#x2010;19 and post&#x2010;acute COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome in a cohort of people living with HIV on antiretroviral treatment and with undetectable HIV RNA. Viruses. 2022;14(3):493. doi:10.3390/v14030493</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pujari S, Gaikwad S, Chitalikar A, Dabhade D, Joshi K, Bele V. Long&#x2010;coronavirus disease among people living with HIV in western India: an observational study. Immun Inflamm Dis. 2021;9(3):1037&#x2010;1043. doi:10.1002/iid3.467</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meiring S, Tempia S, Bhiman JN, et al. Prolonged shedding of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2) at high viral loads among hospitalized immunocompromised persons living with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), South Africa. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;75(1):e144&#x2010;e156. doi:10.1093/cid/ciac077</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcaide ML, Nogueira NF, Salazar AS, et al. A longitudinal analysis of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 antibody responses among people with HIV. Front Med (Lausanne). 2022;9:768138. doi:10.3389/fmed.2022.768138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang RR, Gui X, Zhang YX, Xiong Y, Gao SC, Ke HN. Clinical characteristics of COVID&#x2010;19 patients with HIV coinfection in Wuhan, China. Expert Rev Respir Med. 2021;15(3):403&#x2010;409. doi:10.1080/17476348.2021.1836965</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Xie N, Hu X, et al. Epidemiological, Virological and serological features of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID&#x2010;19) cases in people living with human immunodeficiency virus in Wuhan: a population&#x2010;based cohort study. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73(7):e2086&#x2010;e2094. doi:10.1093/cid/ciaa1186</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donadeu L, Tiraboschi JM, Sc&#xe9;vola S, et al. Long&#x2010;lasting adaptive immune memory specific to SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 in convalescent coronavirus disease 2019 stable people with HIV. Aids. 2022;36(10):1373&#x2010;1382. doi:10.1097/qad.0000000000003276</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Mahoney LL, Routen A, Gillies C, et al. The prevalence and long&#x2010;term health effects of long Covid among hospitalised and non&#x2010;hospitalised populations: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;55:101762. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2022.101762</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes SE, Haroon S, Subramanian A, et al. Development and validation of the symptom burden questionnaire for long covid (SBQ&#x2010;LC): Rasch analysis. BMJ. 2022;377:e070230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, Nicholson T, Akrami A, et al. A core outcome set for post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 condition in adults for use in clinical practice and research: an international Delphi consensus study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10(7):715&#x2010;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Sun J, Patel RC, et al. Associations between HIV infection and clinical spectrum of COVID&#x2010;19: a population level analysis based on US national COVID cohort collaborative (N3C) data. Lancet HIV. 2021;8(11):e690&#x2010;e700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roff SR, Noon&#x2010;Song EN, Yamamoto JK. The significance of interferon&#x2010;&#x3b3; in HIV&#x2010;1 pathogenesis, therapy, and prophylaxis. Front Immunol. 2014;4:498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurence J. Why aren't people living with HIV at higher risk for developing severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID&#x2010;19)? AIDS Patient Care STDS. 2020;34(6):247&#x2010;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Lu S, Tang AF, et al. Markers of immune activation and inflammation in individuals with postacute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection. J Infect Dis. 2021;224(11):1839&#x2010;1848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Sans HM, Forman CA, et al. Plasma markers of neurologic injury and inflammation in people with self&#x2010;reported neurologic postacute sequelae of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2022;9(5):e200003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulthei&#xdf; C, Willscher E, Paschold L, et al. The IL&#x2010;1&#x3b2;, IL&#x2010;6, and TNF cytokine triad is associated with post&#x2010;acute sequelae of COVID&#x2010;19. Cell Rep Med. 2022;3(6):100663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post&#x2010;acute COVID&#x2010;19 sequelae. Cell. 2022;185(5):881&#x2010;895.e20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bol&#xed;var S, Anfossi R, Humeres C, et al. IFN&#x2010;&#x3b2; plays both pro&#x2010;and anti&#x2010;inflammatory roles in the rat cardiac fibroblast through differential STAT protein activation. Front Pharmacol. 2018;9:1368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariani MK, Dasmeh P, Fortin A, et al. The combination of IFN &#x3b2; and TNF induces an antiviral and immunoregulatory program via non&#x2010;canonical pathways involving STAT2 and IRF9. Cells. 2019;8(8):919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs LD, Cookfair DL, Rudick RA, et al. Intramuscular interferon beta&#x2010;1a for disease progression in relapsing multiple sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 1996;39(3):285&#x2010;294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghi A, Tahmasebi S, Mahmood A, et al. Th17 and Treg cells function in SARS&#x2010;CoV2 patients compared with healthy controls. J Cell Physiol. 2021;236(4):2829&#x2010;2839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meckiff BJ, Ram&#xed;rez&#x2010;Su&#xe1;stegui C, Fajardo V, et al. Imbalance of regulatory and cytotoxic SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2&#x2010;reactive CD4+ T cells in COVID&#x2010;19. Cell. 2020;183(5):1340&#x2010;1353.e16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, Leavy OC, Richardson M, et al. Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1&#x2010;year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10(8):761&#x2010;775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasi M, De Biasi S, Gibellini L, et al. Ageing and inflammation in patients with HIV infection. Clin Exp Immunol. 2017;187(1):44&#x2010;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams ME, Ipser JC, Stein DJ, Joska JA, Naud&#xe9; PJ. Peripheral immune dysregulation in the ART era of HIV&#x2010;associated neurocognitive impairments: a systematic review. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2020;118:104689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groff D, Sun A, Ssentongo AE, et al. Short&#x2010;term and long&#x2010;term rates of postacute sequelae of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection: a systematic review. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(10):e2128568.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>