<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35765566</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2693-5015</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Research square</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Res Sq</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A pilot randomized controlled trial of supervised, at-home, self-administered transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS) to manage long COVID symptoms.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">rs.3.rs-1716096</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.21203/rs.3.rs-1716096/v1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Although the coronavirus disease 19 (COVID-19) pandemic has now impacted the world for over two years, the persistent secondary neuropsychiatric effects are still not fully understood. These "long COVID" symptoms, also referred to as post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC), can persist for months after infection without any effective treatments. Long COVID involves a complex heterogenous symptomology and can lead to disability and limit work. Long COVID symptoms may be due to sustained inflammatory responses and prolonged immune response after infection. Interestingly, vagus nerve stimulation (VNS) may have anti-inflammatory effects, however, until recently, VNS could not be self-administered, at-home, noninvasively. Methods We created a double-blind, noninvasive transcutaneous auricular VNS (taVNS) system that can be self-administered at home with simultaneous remote monitoring of physiological biomarkers and video supervision by study staff. Subsequently, we carried out a pilot (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;13) randomized, sham-controlled, trial with this system for four weeks to treat nine predefined long covid symptoms (anxiety, depression, vertigo, anosmia, ageusia, headaches, fatigue, irritability, brain fog). No in-person patient contact was needed, with informed consent, trainings, ratings, and all procedures being conducted remotely during the pandemic (2020-2021) and equipment being shipped to individuals' homes. This trial was registered onClinicalTrials.gov under the identifier: NCT04638673. Results Four-weeks of at-home self-administered taVNS (two, one-hour sessions daily, delivered at suprathreshold intensities) was feasible and safe. Although our trial was not powered to determine efficacy as an intervention in a heterogenous population, the trends in the data suggest taVNS may have a mild to moderate effect in reducing mental fatigue symptoms in a subset of individuals. This innovative study demonstrates the safety and feasibility of supervised self-administered taVNS under a fully contactless protocol and suggests that future studies can safely investigate this novel form of brain stimulation at-home for a variety of neuropsychiatric and motor recovery applications.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Badran</LastName><ForeName>Bashar W</ForeName><Initials>BW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9376-6440</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huffman</LastName><ForeName>Sarah M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dancy</LastName><ForeName>Morgan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Austelle</LastName><ForeName>Christopher W</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bikson</LastName><ForeName>Marom</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>City College of the City University of New York: The City College of New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kautz</LastName><ForeName>Steven A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>George</LastName><ForeName>Mark S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04638673</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>IK6 RX003075</GrantID><Acronym>RX</Acronym><Agency>RRD VA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U54 GM104941</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Res Sq</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101768035</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2693-5015</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateIn"><RefSource>Bioelectron Med. 2022 Aug 25;8(1):13. doi: 10.1186/s42234-022-00094-y</RefSource><PMID Version="1">36002874</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><CoiStatement>Competing interests. MB has equity in Soterix Medical. All other authors declare that they have no relevant competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35765566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9238186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.3.rs-1716096/v1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">rs.3.rs-1716096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ciotti M, Ciccozzi M, Terrinoni A, Jiang W-C, Wang C-B, Bernardini S. The COVID-19 pandemic. Crit Rev Clin Lab Sci. 2020;57(6):365&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32645276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohrabi C, Alsafi Z, O&#x2019;neill N, Khan M, Kerwan A, Al-Jabir A, et al. World Health Organization declares global emergency: A review of the 2019 novel coronavirus (COVID-19). Int J Surg. 2020;76:71&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7105032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32112977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascarella G, Strumia A, Piliego C, Bruno F, Del Buono R, Costa F, et al. COVID-19 diagnosis and management: a comprehensive review. J Intern Med. 2020;288(2):192&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32348588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuki K, Fujiogi M, Koutsogiannaki S. COVID-19 pathophysiology: A review. Clin Immunol. 2020;215:108427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7169933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struyf T, Deeks JJ, Dinnes J, Takwoingi Y, Davenport C, Leeflang MM, et al. Signs and symptoms to determine if a patient presenting in primary care or hospital outpatient settings has COVID-19. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. 2021(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8407425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33620086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva Andrade B, Siqueira S, de Assis Soares WR, de Souza Rangel F, Santos NO, dos Santos Freitas A, et al. Long-COVID and post-COVID health complications: an up-to-date review on clinical conditions and their possible molecular mechanisms. Viruses. 2021;13(4):700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB. Long COVID or post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): An overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Frontiers in microbiology. 2021:1494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid&#x2014;mechanisms, risk factors, and management. bmj. 2021;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troyer EA, Kohn JN, Hong S. Are we facing a crashing wave of neuropsychiatric sequelae of COVID-19? Neuropsychiatric symptoms and potential immunologic mechanisms. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;87:34&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7152874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfefferbaum B, North CS. Mental health and the Covid-19 pandemic. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(6):510&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32283003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghimi N, Di Napoli M, Biller J, Siegler JE, Shekhar R, McCullough LD, et al. The neurological manifestations of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2021;21(9):1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8237541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34181102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullen W, Gulati G, Kelly BD. Mental health in the COVID-19 pandemic. QJM: An International Journal of Medicine. 2020;113(5):311&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32227218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baptista AF, Baltar A, Okano AH, Moreira A, Campos ACP, Fernandes AM, et al. Applications of Noninvasive Neuromodulation for the Management of Disorders Related to COVID-19. Front Neurol. 2020;11:1248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7724108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33324324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilloni G, Bikson M, Badran BW, George MS, Kautz SA, Okano AH, et al. Update on the Use of Transcranial Electrical Brain Stimulation to Manage Acute and Chronic COVID-19 Symptoms. Front Hum Neurosci. 2020;14:595567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7689057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33281589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adair D, Truong D, Esmaeilpour Z, Gebodh N, Borges H, Ho L, et al. Electrical stimulation of cranial nerves in cognition and disease. Brain Stimul. 2020;13(3):717&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7196013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32289703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badran BW, Alfred BY, Adair D, Mappin G, DeVries WH, Jenkins DD, et al. Laboratory administration of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS): technique, targeting, and considerations. JoVE (Journal of Visualized Experiments). 2019(143):e58984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6867597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30663712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badran BW, Brown JC, Dowdle LT, Mithoefer OJ, LaBate NT, Coatsworth J, et al. Tragus or cymba conchae? Investigating the anatomical foundation of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS). Brain Stimul. 2018;11(4):947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6607436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29895444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badran BW, Dowdle LT, Mithoefer OJ, LaBate NT, Coatsworth J, Brown JC, et al. Neurophysiologic effects of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS) via electrical stimulation of the tragus: A concurrent taVNS/fMRI study and review. Brain Stimul. 2018;11(3):492&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6487660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29361441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badran BW, Mithoefer OJ, Summer CE, LaBate NT, Glusman CE, Badran AW, et al. Short trains of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS) have parameter-specific effects on heart rate. Brain Stimul. 2018;11(4):699&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6536129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29716843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badran BW, Yu AB, Adair D, Mappin G, DeVries WH, Jenkins DD, et al. Laboratory Administration of Transcutaneous Auricular Vagus Nerve Stimulation (taVNS): Technique, Targeting, and Considerations. J Vis Exp. 2019(143).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6867597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30663712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peuker ET, Filler TJ. The nerve supply of the human auricle. Clin Anat. 2002;15(1):35&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11835542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frangos E, Ellrich J, Komisaruk BR. Non-invasive access to the vagus nerve central projections via electrical stimulation of the external ear: fMRI evidence in humans. Brain Stimul. 2015;8(3):624&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4458242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25573069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farmer AD, Strzelczyk A, Finisguerra A, Gourine AV, Gharabaghi A, Hasan A, et al. International Consensus Based Review and Recommendations for Minimum Reporting Standards in Research on Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (Version 2020). Front Hum Neurosci. 2020;14:568051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8040977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33854421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C-H, Yang M-H, Zhang G-Z, Wang X-X, Li B, Li M, et al. Neural networks and the anti-inflammatory effect of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation in depression. J Neuroinflamm. 2020;17(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7017619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32050990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Popovi&#x107; ZB, Bibevski S, Fakhry I, Sica DA, Van Wagoner DR, et al. Chronic Vagus Nerve Stimulation Improves Autonomic Control and Attenuates Systemic Inflammation and Heart Failure Progression in a Canine High-Rate Pacing ModelCLINICAL PERSPECTIVE. Circulation: Heart Failure. 2009;2(6):692&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19919995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch V, Zeman F, Heckel A, Menne F, Ellrich J, Eichhammer P. The effect of transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation on pain perception&#x2013;an experimental study. Brain Stimul. 2013;6(2):202&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22621941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austelle CW, O&#x2019;Leary GH, Thompson S, Gruber E, Kahn A, Manett AJ, et al. A Comprehensive Review of Vagus Nerve Stimulation for Depression. Neuromodulation. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8898319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35396067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng D, Liu X, Wang Y, Wang J. The effect of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation on HRV in healthy young people. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(2):e0263833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8830655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardesch JJ, Buschman HP, van der Burgh PH, Wagener-Schimmel LJ, van der Aa HE, Hageman G. Cardiac responses of vagus nerve stimulation: intraoperative bradycardia and subsequent chronic stimulation. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2007;109(10):849&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17825483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gratz I, Deal E, Spitz F, Baruch M, Allen IE, Seaman JE, et al. Continuous non-invasive finger cuff CareTaker&#xae; comparable to invasive intra-arterial pressure in patients undergoing major intra-abdominal surgery. BMC Anesthesiol. 2017;17(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5361833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28327093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreisberg E, Esmaeilpour Z, Adair D, Khadka N, Datta A, Badran BW, et al. High-resolution computational modeling of the current flow in the outer ear during transcutaneous auricular Vagus Nerve Stimulation (taVNS). Brain Stimul. 2021;14(6):1419&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8608747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34517143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badran BW, Alfred BY, Adair D, Mappin G, DeVries WH, Jenkins DD, et al. Laboratory administration of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS): technique, targeting, and considerations. Journal of visualized experiments: JoVE. 2019(143).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6867597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30663712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George MS, Nahas Z, Bohning DE, Lomarev M, Denslow S, Osenbach R, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation: a new form of therapeutic brain stimulation. CNS Spectr. 2000;5(11):43&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18188148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman F, Van Maanen M, Vervoordeldonk MJ, Tak P. Balancing the autonomic nervous system to reduce inflammation in rheumatoid arthritis. J Intern Med. 2017;282(1):64&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28547815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drewes A, Brock C, Rasmussen S, M&#xf8;ller H, Brock B, Deleuran B, et al. Short-term transcutaneous noninvasive vagus nerve stimulation may reduce disease activity and pro-inflammatory cytokines in rheumatoid arthritis: results of a pilot study. Scand J Rheumatol. 2021;50(1):20&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33047630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan H, Garzoni L, Liu HL, Cao M, Desrochers A, Fecteau G, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation for treatment of inflammation: systematic review of animal models and clinical studies. Bioelectronic Med. 2016;3(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5756070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29308423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X-zJ, Thomas PG, editors. New fronts emerge in the influenza cytokine storm. Seminars in immunopathology. Springer; 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5580809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28555383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tornero C, Pastor E, Garzando MDM, Ordu&#xf1;a J, Forner MJ, Bocigas I, et al. Non-invasive Vagus Nerve Stimulation for COVID-19: Results From a Randomized Controlled Trial (SAVIOR I). Front Neurol. 2022;13:820864-.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9028764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35463130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>