<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36719069</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Functional neurological disorder in people with long COVID: A&#xa0;systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1505</StartPage><EndPage>1514</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1505-1514</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15721</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Acute health events, including infections, can trigger the onset of functional neurological disorder (FND). It was hypothesized that a proportion of people with long COVID might be experiencing functional symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A systematic review of studies containing original data on long COVID was performed. The frequency and characteristics of neurological symptoms were reviewed, looking for positive evidence suggesting an underlying functional disorder and the hypothesized causes of long COVID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">In all, 102 studies were included in our narrative synthesis. The most consistently reported neurological symptoms were cognitive difficulties, headaches, pain, dizziness, fatigue, sleep-related symptoms and ageusia/anosmia. Overall, no evidence was found that any authors had systematically looked for positive features of FND. An exception was three studies describing temporal inconsistency. In general, the neurological symptoms were insufficiently characterized to support or refute a diagnosis of FND. Moreover, only 13 studies specifically focused on long COVID after mild infection, where the impact of confounders from the general effects of severe illness would be mitigated. Only one study hypothesized that some people with long COVID might have a functional disorder, and another eight studies a chronic-fatigue-syndrome-like response.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Neurological symptoms are prevalent in long COVID, but poorly characterized. The similarities between some manifestations of long COVID and functional disorders triggered by acute illnesses are striking. Unfortunately, the current literature is plagued by confounders, including the mixing of patients with initial mild infection with those with severe acute medical complications. The hypothesis that long COVID might in part correspond to a functional disorder remains untested.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teodoro</LastName><ForeName>Tiago</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurosciences Research Centre, Institute of Molecular and Clinical Sciences, St George's, University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jiaying</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurosciences Research Centre, Institute of Molecular and Clinical Sciences, St George's, University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gelauff</LastName><ForeName>Jeannette</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Edwards</LastName><ForeName>Mark J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurosciences Research Centre, Institute of Molecular and Clinical Sciences, St George's, University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Eur J Neurol. 2023 May;30(5):1165-1166. doi: 10.1111/ene.15751</RefSource><PMID Version="1">36802122</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Eur J Neurol. 2023 Sep;30(9):2949-2950. doi: 10.1111/ene.15911</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37294977</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003291" MajorTopicYN="Y">Conversion Disorder</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086582" MajorTopicYN="N">Anosmia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional neurological disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurological symptoms</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36719069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Overview | COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19 | Guidance | NICE. Accessed September 13, 2021. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng188</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19: Evaluation and management of adults following acute viral illness-UpToDate. Accessed February 19, 2022. https://www.uptodate.com/contents/covid-19-evaluation-and-management-of-adults-following-acute-viral-illness?search=long%20covid&amp;source=search_result&amp;selectedTitle=1~150&amp;usage_type=default&amp;display_rank=1#H2804110166</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Why we need to keep using the patient made term &#x2018;Long Covid&#x2019;. BMJ. Published October 1, 2020. Accessed June 6, 2022. https://blogs.bmj.com/bmj/2020/10/01/why-we-need-to-keep-using-the-patient-made-term-long-covid/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pezzini A, Padovani A. Lifting the mask on neurological manifestations of COVID-19. Nat Rev Neurol. 2020;16(11):636-644. doi:10.1038/s41582-020-0398-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur KT, Miller EH, Glendinning MD, et al. COVID-19 neuropathology at Columbia University Irving Medical Center/New York Presbyterian Hospital. Brain. 2021;144(9):2696-2708. doi:10.1093/brain/awab148</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekelis K, Missios S, Ahmad J, et al. Ischemic stroke occurs less frequently in patients with COVID-19: a multicenter cross-sectional study. Stroke. 2020;51(12):3570-3576. doi:10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.031217</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson A, Hallett M, Stone J. Assessment of patients with functional neurologic disorders. Handb Clin Neurol. 2016;139:169-188. doi:10.1016/B978-0-12-801772-2.00015-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venturelli S, Benatti SV, Casati M, et al. Surviving COVID-19 in Bergamo province: a post-acute outpatient re-evaluation. Epidemiol Infect. 2021;149:e32. doi:10.1017/S0950268821000145</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattioli F, Stampatori C, Righetti F, Sala E, Tomasi C, De Palma G. Neurological and cognitive sequelae of COVID-19: a four month follow-up. J Neurol. 2021;268(12):4422-4428. doi:10.1007/s00415-021-10579-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera JA, Yang D, Lewis A, et al. A prospective study of long-term outcomes among hospitalized COVID-19 patients with and without neurological complications. J Neurol Sci. 2021;426:117486. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2021.117486</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miskowiak KW, Johnsen S, Sattler SM, et al. Cognitive impairments four months after COVID-19 hospital discharge: pattern, severity and association with illness variables. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2021;46:39-48. doi:10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.03.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puchner B, Sahanic S, Kirchmair R, et al. Beneficial effects of multi-disciplinary rehabilitation in postacute COVID-19: an observational cohort study. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2021;57(2):189-198. doi:10.23736/S1973-9087.21.06549-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampshire A, Trender W, Chamberlain SR, et al. Cognitive deficits in people who have recovered from COVID-19. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;39:101044. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsen S, Sattler SM, Miskowiak KW, et al. Descriptive analysis of long COVID sequelae identified in a multidisciplinary clinic serving hospitalised and non-hospitalised patients. ERJ Open Res. 2021;7(3):205-2021. doi:10.1183/23120541.00205-2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouraud C, Bottemanne H, Lahlou-Lafor&#xea;t K, et al. Association between psychological distress, cognitive complaints, and neuropsychological status after a severe COVID-19 episode: a cross-sectional study. Front Psych. 2021;12:725861. doi:10.3389/fpsyt.2021.725861</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B, Peters JB, Brink M, et al. Comprehensive health assessment 3 months after recovery from acute coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73(5):e1089-e1098. doi:10.1093/cid/ciaa1750</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez R, Balanz&#xe1;-Mart&#xed;nez V, Luperdi SC, et al. Long-term neuropsychiatric outcomes in COVID-19 survivors: a 1-year longitudinal study. J Intern Med. 2022;291(2):247-251. doi:10.1111/joim.13389</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dressing A, Bormann T, Blazhenets G, et al. Neuropsychological profiles and cerebral glucose metabolism in neurocognitive long COVID-syndrome. J Nucl Med. 2022;63(7):1058-1063. doi:10.2967/jnumed.121.262677</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydin S, Unver E, Karavas E, Yalcin S, Kantarci M. Computed tomography at every step: long coronavirus disease. Respir Investig. 2021;59(5):622-627. doi:10.1016/j.resinv.2021.05.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold JE, Okyay RA, Licht WE, Hurley DJ. Investigation of long COVID prevalence and its relationship to Epstein-Barr virus reactivation. Pathogens. 2021;10(6):763. doi:10.3390/pathogens10060763</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestre-Mu&#xf1;iz MM, Arias &#xc1;, Mata-V&#xe1;zquez E, et al. Long-term outcomes of patients with coronavirus disease 2019 at one year after hospital discharge. J Clin Med. 2021;10(13):2945. doi:10.3390/jcm10132945</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munblit D, Bobkova P, Spiridonova E, et al. Incidence and risk factors for persistent symptoms in adults previously hospitalized for COVID-19. Clin Exp Allergy. 2021;51(9):1107-1120. doi:10.1111/cea.13997</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021;397(10270):220-232. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32656-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osikomaiya B, Erinoso O, Wright KO, et al. &#x2018;Long COVID&#x2019;: persistent COVID-19 symptoms in survivors managed in Lagos state, Nigeria. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):304. doi:10.1186/s12879-020-05716-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Duarte &#xc1;, Rivera-Izquierdo M, Guerrero-Fern&#xe1;ndez de Alba I, et al. Sequelae, persistent symptomatology and outcomes after COVID-19 hospitalization: the ANCOHVID multicentre 6-month follow-up study. BMC Med. 2021;19:129. doi:10.1186/s12916-021-02003-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran VT, Riveros C, Clepier B, et al. Development and validation of the long COVID symptom and impact tools: A set of patient-reported instruments constructed from patients': Lived experience. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;74(2):278-287. doi:10.1093/cid/ciab352</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kersten J, Baumhardt M, Hartveg P, et al. Long COVID: distinction between organ damage and deconditioning. J Clin Med. 2021;10(17):3782. doi:10.3390/jcm10173782</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor AK, Kingstone T, Briggs TA, et al. &#x2018;Reluctant pioneer&#x2019;: a qualitative study of doctors' experiences as patients with long COVID. Health Expect. 2021;24(3):833-842. doi:10.1111/hex.13223</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fung WKW, Sa'di Q, Katzberg H, et al. Functional disorders as a common motor manifestation of COVID-19 infection or vaccination. Eur J Neurol. 2023;30(3):678-691. doi:10.1111/ene.15630</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball HA, McWhirter L, Ballard C, et al. Functional cognitive disorder: dementia's blind spot. Brain. 2020;143(10):2895-2903. doi:10.1093/brain/awaa224</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teodoro T, Edwards MJ, Isaacs JD. A unifying theory for cognitive abnormalities in functional neurological disorders, fibromyalgia and chronic fatigue syndrome: systematic review. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89(12):1308-1319. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2017-317823</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martillo MA, Dangayach NS, Tabacof L, et al. Postintensive care syndrome in survivors of critical illness related to coronavirus disease 2019: cohort study from a new York City critical care recovery clinic. Crit Care Med. 2021;49(9):1427-1438. doi:10.1097/CCM.0000000000005014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heesakkers H, van der Hoeven JG, Corsten S, et al. Clinical outcomes among patients with 1-year survival following intensive care unit treatment for COVID-19. JAMA. 2022;327(6):559-565. doi:10.1001/jama.2022.0040</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koedel U, Fingerle V, Pfister HW. Lyme neuroborreliosis-epidemiology, diagnosis and management. Nat Rev Neurol. 2015;11(8):446-456. doi:10.1038/nrneurol.2015.121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickie I, Davenport T, Wakefield D, et al. Post-infective and chronic fatigue syndromes precipitated by viral and non-viral pathogens: prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2006;333(7568):575. doi:10.1136/bmj.38933.585764.AE</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards MJ, Adams RA, Brown H, Pare&#xe9;s I, Friston KJ. A Bayesian account of &#x2018;hysteria&#x2019;. Brain. 2012;135(Pt 11):3495-3512. doi:10.1093/brain/aws129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas JW, Bender FL, Ballou S, et al. Frequency of adverse events in the placebo arms of COVID-19 vaccine trials: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(1):e2143955. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.43955</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastie CE, Lowe DJ, McAuley A, et al. Outcomes among confirmed cases and a matched comparison group in the long-COVID in Scotland study. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):5663. doi:10.1038/s41467-022-33415-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball HA, Swirski M, Newson M, Coulthard EJ, Pennington CM. Differentiating functional cognitive disorder from early neurodegeneration: a clinic-based study. Brain Sci. 2021;11(6):800. doi:10.3390/brainsci11060800</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huys ACML, Bhatia KP, Edwards MJ, Haggard P. The flip side of distractibility-executive dysfunction in functional movement disorders. Front Neurol. 2020;11:969. doi:10.3389/fneur.2020.00969</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Togo F, Lange G, Natelson BH, Quigley KS. Attention network test: assessment of cognitive function in chronic fatigue syndrome. J Neuropsychol. 2015;9(1):1-9. doi:10.1111/jnp.12030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballering AV, van Zon SKR, Olde Hartman TC, Rosmalen JGM. Lifelines Corona research initiative. Persistence of somatic symptoms after COVID-19 in the Netherlands: an observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022;400(10350):452-461. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(22)01214-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies M. Long COVID patients travel abroad for expensive and experimental &#x2018;blood washing&#x2019;. BMJ. 2022;378:o1671. doi:10.1136/bmj.o1671</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>