<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37595619</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1439-1309</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Die Rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rehabilitation (Stuttg)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Occupational Stress of Long Covid Rehabilitants and Return to Work After Pneumological Rehabilitation].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>369</StartPage><EndPage>378</EndPage><MedlinePgn>369-378</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/a-2105-5810</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The Long Covid syndrome, a condition that is induced by SARS-CoV-2, affects patients in their social and professional life due to persistent symptoms and functional deficits. Medical rehabilitation aims to reduce participation incapacity and restore the ability to work. So far, it is not known what happens to the occupational situation of people affected by Long Covid after pneumological rehabilitation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The overall study is designed as a multicentric and prospective observational study with a mixed-method design. Covid-19 rehabilitation patients undergoing pneumological rehabilitation aged between 18 and 65 years were recruited. The questionnaire data of persons that were employed at baseline were evaluated. The written survey took place at the beginning and at end of rehabilitation and, additionally, after six months. The data collected included terms such as return to work, occupational stress and changes, subjective prognosis of gainful employment (SPE scale) and occupational performance and working ability (WAI).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The sample comprised N=173 participants (68.2% female) and the average age was 52.5 years. 85.5% of the rehabilitation patients were fit for work six months after rehabilitation and returned to a job. Absenteeism, subjectively perceived performance, and work ability improved statistically significantly over time (p&lt;0.01). The risk of early retirement still existed six months after rehabilitation in 41.3% of the study participants. The participation limitations were statistically significantly reduced during the follow-up with a medium effect size (ES=0.60, p&lt;0.01). In the logistic regression, the WAI proved to be a significantly protective predictor of return to work, while cognitive corona symptoms and high levels of cognitive fatigue proved to be risk factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The majority of rehabilitation patients are gainfully employed six months after pneumological rehabilitation, although persistent symptoms and a reduced ability to work are also reported even after rehabilitation. In the rehabilitation of employed persons, work-related elements, for example clarification of work-related questions and preparation for occupational demands (e.&#x2009;g. concentration, stress, physical demands), could support a sustained return to work.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rutsch</LastName><ForeName>Mercedes</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitationsforschung, Institut f&#xfc;r Sozialmedizin und Epidemiologie, Universit&#xe4;t zu L&#xfc;beck.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deck</LastName><ForeName>Ruth</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitationsforschung, Institut f&#xfc;r Sozialmedizin und Epidemiologie, Universit&#xe4;t zu L&#xfc;beck.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>ger</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><VernacularTitle>Berufliche Belastungen von Long-Covid-Rehabilitand*innen und R&#xfc;ckkehr zur Arbeit nach einer pneumologischen Rehabilitation.</VernacularTitle><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Rehabilitation (Stuttg)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0401273</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0034-3536</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062707" MajorTopicYN="N">Return to Work</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005858" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Germany</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073397" MajorTopicYN="Y">Occupational Stress</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger"><AbstractText Label="HINTERGRUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Das durch SARS-CoV-2 verursachte Long Covid-Syndrom beeintr&#xe4;chtigt Betroffene aufgrund von anhaltenden Symptomen und Einschr&#xe4;nkungen im sozialen wie beruflichen Leben. Die medizinische Rehabilitation zielt darauf ab, Teilhabeeinschr&#xe4;nkungen zu reduzieren und die Erwerbsf&#xe4;higkeit der Betroffenen wiederherzustellen. Bislang ist nicht bekannt, wie sich die berufliche Situation von Long Covid-Betroffenen nach einer pneumologischen Rehabilitation entwickelt.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODIK" NlmCategory="METHODS">Die Gesamtstudie ist als multizentrische, prospektive Beobachtungsstudie im Mixed-Method-Design angelegt. Rekrutiert wurden Covid-19-Rehabilitand*innen in der pneumologischen Rehabilitation im Alter von 18 bis 65 Jahren. In dieser Auswertung wurden die Fragebogendaten von zur Baseline erwerbst&#xe4;tigen Personen ber&#xfc;cksichtigt. Die schriftliche Befragung fand am Anfang und Ende der Rehabilitation sowie nach sechs Monaten statt. Erhoben wurden u.&#x2009;a. Return to Work, berufliche Belastungen und Ver&#xe4;nderungen, subjektive Prognose der Erwerbst&#xe4;tigkeit (SPE) und berufliche Leistungs- sowie Arbeitsf&#xe4;higkeit (WAI).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ERGEBNISSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Die Stichprobe umfasst N=173 Teilnehmer*innen (68,2% weiblich) und ist im Durchschnitt 52,5 Jahre alt. 85,5% der Rehabilitand*innen waren sechs Monate nach der Rehabilitation arbeitsf&#xe4;hig und kehrten an einen Arbeitsplatz zur&#xfc;ck. Die Fehlzeiten, die subjektiv empfundene Leistungsf&#xe4;higkeit und Arbeitsf&#xe4;higkeit verbesserten sich im zeitlichen Verlauf statistisch signifikant (p&lt;0,01). Die Gefahr einer fr&#xfc;hzeitigen Berentung besteht auch noch sechs Monate nach der Rehabilitation bei 41,3% der Studienteilnehmer*innen. Die Teilhabeeinschr&#xe4;nkungen reduzieren sich im Follow-up statistisch signifikant und mit mittlerer Effektst&#xe4;rke (ES=0,60, p&lt;0,01). In der logistischen Regression erwies sich der WAI als signifikant protektiver Pr&#xe4;diktor auf die R&#xfc;ckkehr zur Arbeit, kognitive Corona-Symptome und hohe Werte der kognitiven Fatigue erwiesen sich als Risikofaktoren.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SCHLUSSFOLGERUNGEN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Der Gro&#xdf;teil der Rehabilitand*innen ist ein halbes Jahr nach einer pneumologischen Rehabilitation erwerbst&#xe4;tig, obwohl auch &#xfc;ber die Rehabilitation hinaus von anhaltenden Symptomen und einer beeintr&#xe4;chtigten Arbeitsf&#xe4;higkeit berichtet wird. In der Rehabilitation Erwerbst&#xe4;tiger k&#xf6;nnten berufsbezogene Elemente, beispielsweise die Kl&#xe4;rung beruflicher Fragen und Vorbereitung auf berufliche Anforderungen (z.&#x2009;B. Konzentration, Stress, k&#xf6;rperliche Anforderungen), einen nachhaltigen Return to Work unterst&#xfc;tzen.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><CoiStatement>Die Autorinnen/Autoren geben an, dass kein Interessenkonflikt besteht.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37595619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2105-5810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>