<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35295965</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2471-2531</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Season>Mar-Apr</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pain reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pain Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Transient hypoalgesia after COVID-19 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e990</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e990</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e990</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PR9.0000000000000990</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Loss of smell or taste are often-cited complications during COVID-19 disease, but there is no clear evidence for affection of the peripheral nervous system.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Here, we report a 48-year-old man presenting with persistent dysgeusia and hypoalgesia of the lower legs, hands, and cheeks after COVID-19 infection in Spring 2020.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Upon clinical examination 7 months after the infection, the patient could not feel pain after pinprick stimuli. Quantitative sensory testing revealed increased thermal detection thresholds at the face but no changes at the foot. Electrical C-fiber stimulation elicited lower pain ratings at the distal leg compared with the proximal leg, but overall higher pain ratings than in healthy control subjects. The axon flare reaction in response to histamine and acetylcholine was almost absent with no pain sensation. Skin punch biopsy revealed a reduced intraepidermal nerve fiber density at the lower leg, and transient receptor potential vanilloid 1 and calcitonin gene-related peptide immunoreactivity were similar to a healthy control. Symptoms and positive tests improved 5 months later.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In summary, we describe a case of hypoalgesia after COVID-19 disease. Studies investigating long-COVID syndrome should test not only for painful neuropathic symptoms but also for hypoalgesia, especially in patients with prolonged dysgeusia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of The International Association for the Study of Pain.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Becker</LastName><ForeName>Juliane</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Anesthesiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Papagianni</LastName><ForeName>Aikaterini</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology, University Hospital of W&#xfc;rzburg, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Herrmann</LastName><ForeName>Eva</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Anesthesiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>N&#xf6;ller</LastName><ForeName>Frank</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology, University Hospital of W&#xfc;rzburg, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sommer</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology, University Hospital of W&#xfc;rzburg, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rittner</LastName><ForeName>Heike L</ForeName><Initials>HL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Anesthesiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pain Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101683899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2471-2531</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Axon flare</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">C fiber</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quantitative sensory testing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to declare. The study was in part funded by German Research Foundation (DFG, Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft; FOR 2690, CS and KFO5001, HR and CS).Sponsorships or competing interests that may be relevant to content are disclosed at the end of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35295965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8920299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PR9.0000000000000990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PAINREPORTS-D-21-0088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hartmannsberger B, Doppler K, Stauber J, Schlotter-Weigel B, Young P, Sereda MW, Sommer C. Intraepidermal nerve fibre density as biomarker in Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease type 1A. Brain Commun 2020;2:fcaa012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7425304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32954280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joint Task Force of the E, the PNS. European Federation of Neurological Societies/Peripheral Nerve Society Guideline on the use of skin biopsy in the diagnosis of small fiber neuropathy. Report of a joint task force of the European Federation of Neurological Societies and the Peripheral Nerve Society. J Peripher Nerv Syst 2010;15:79&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20626771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonas R, Namer B, Stockinger L, Chisholm K, Schnakenberg M, Landmann G, Kucharczyk M, Konrad C, Schmidt R, Carr R, McMahon S, Schmelz M, Rukwied R. Tuning in C-nociceptors to reveal mechanisms in chronic neuropathic pain. Ann Neurol 2018;83:945&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29659054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsson P, Haroutounian S, Polydefkis M, Nyengaard JR, Jensen TS. Structural and functional characterization of nerve fibres in polyneuropathy and healthy subjects. Scand J Pain 2016;10:28&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28361768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karuppan MKM, Devadoss D, Nair M, Chand HS, Lakshmana MK. SARS-CoV-2 infection in the central and peripheral nervous system-associated morbidities and their potential mechanism. Mol Neurobiol 2021;58:2465&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7805264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33439437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke Z, Oton J, Qu K, Cortese M, Zila V, McKeane L, Nakane T, Zivanov J, Neufeldt CJ, Cerikan B, Lu JM, Peukes J, Xiong X, Kr&#xe4;usslich H-G, Scheres SHW, Bartenschlager R, Briggs JAG. Structures and distributions of SARS-CoV-2 spike proteins on intact virions. Nature 2020;588:498&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7116492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32805734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirchner A, Stefan H, Schmelz M, Haslbeck KM, Birklein F. Influence of vagus nerve stimulation on histamine-induced itching. Neurology 2002;59:108&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12105316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud MM, Abuohashish HM, Khairy DA, Bugshan AS, Khan AM, Moothedath MM. Pathogenesis of dysgeusia in COVID-19 patients: a scoping review. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci 2021;25:1114&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maier C, Baron R, T&#xf6;lle TR, Binder A, Birbaumer N, Birklein F, Gierthm&#xfc;hlen J, Flor H, Geber C, Huge V, Krumova EK, Landwehrmeyer GB, Magerl W, Maih&#xf6;fner C, Richter H, Rolke R, Scherens A, Schwarz A, Sommer C, Tronnier V, &#xdc;&#xe7;eyler N, Valet M, Wasner G, Treede D-R. Quantitative sensory testing in the German Research Network on Neuropathic Pain (DFNS): somatosensory abnormalities in 1236 patients with different neuropathic pain syndromes. PAIN 2010;150:439&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20627413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer-Frie&#xdf;em CHGJ, Baron R, Sommer C, &#xdc;&#xe7;eyler N, Enax-Krumova EK. Pain during and after COVID-19 in Germany and worldwide: a narrative review of current knowledge. PAIN Rep 2021;6:e893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7819701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33490851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moutal A, Martin LF, Boinon L, Gomez K, Ran D, Zhou Y, Stratton HJ, Cai S, Luo S, Gonzalez KB, Perez-Miller S, Patwardhan A, Ibrahim MM, Khanna R. SARS-CoV-2 Spike protein co-opts VEGF-A/Neuropilin-1 receptor signaling to induce analgesia. PAIN 2021;162:243&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7737878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33009246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rukwied R, Thomas C, Obreja O, Werland F, Kleggetveit IP, Jorum E, Carr RW, Namer B, Schmelz M. Slow depolarizing stimuli differentially activate mechanosensitive and silent C nociceptors in human and pig skin. PAIN 2020;161:2119&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlereth T, Brosda N, Birklein F. Spreading of sudomotor axon reflexes in human skin. Neurology 2005;64:1417&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15851733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiers SRP, Wangzhou A, Sankaranarayanan I, Tatsui CE, Rhines LD, Li Y, Uhelski ML, Dougherty PM, Price TJ. ACE2 and SCARF expression in human dorsal root ganglion nociceptors: implications for SARS-CoV-2 virus neurological effects. PAIN 2020;161:2494&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7572821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares FHC, Kubota GT, Fernandes AM, Hojo B, Couras C, Costa BV, Lapa JDdS, Braga LM, Almeida MMd, Cunha PHMd, Pereira VHH, Morais ADSd, Teixeira MJ, Ciampi de Andrade D, Collaborators&#x201d; PitPI. Prevalence and characteristics of new-onset pain in COVID-19 survivors, a controlled study. Eur J Pain 2021;25:1342&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33619793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z, Kang H, Li S, Zhao X. Understanding the neurotropic characteristics of SARS-CoV-2: from neurological manifestations of COVID-19 to potential neurotropic mechanisms. J Neurol 2020;267:2179&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7249973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32458193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>