<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39361178</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1568-5608</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Inflammopharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Inflammopharmacology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Glucocorticoid treatment during COVID-19 infection: does it affect the incidence of long COVID?</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10787-024-01576-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Long COVID (LC) is a frequent complication of COVID infection. It usually results in cognitive impairment, myalgia, headache and fatigue. No effective treatment has been found yet. We aimed to explore the effect of glucocorticoid (GC) treatment during COVID-19 infection on the later development of LC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We examined electronic health records from Clalit Health Services for documentation of COVID-19, GC treatment, and LC frequency. Background diagnoses, demographic data, hospitalization rates, and the use of anti-COVID drugs were recorded.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">1,322,599 cases of COVID-19 infection met the inclusion criteria; 13,530 patients (1.02%) received GC treatment. 149,272 patients, 11.29% of COVID-19 patients were diagnosed with LC. Age and female gender were prognostic risk factors for LC (OR 1.06 for age, OR 1.4 for female gender; p value&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.0001). Background psychiatric diagnoses, migraine, backache and irritable bowel syndrome were predisposing conditions for LC (OR 2.7, p value&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.0001). Higher BMI was associated with a greater probability of LC (OR of 1.25 for obese population). COVID patients who received GC were diagnosed with LC more frequently: 2294 cases (16.95%) compared to 146,978 cases (11.23%) in the non-GC group; (adjusted OR of 1.28&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.07, 95% CI, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.0001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">GC treatment during COVID-19 is correlated with the development of LC. In vivo and animal models may be used to explore the mechanism of this correlation. Future directions include prospective studies as well.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Specktor</LastName><ForeName>Polina</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9555-8044</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Carmel Medical Center, Mikhal St 7, 3436212, Haifa, Israel. polinasp@clalit.org.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hadar</LastName><ForeName>Dana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Carmel Medical Center, Mikhal St 7, 3436212, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cohen</LastName><ForeName>Hilla</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Carmel Medical Center, Mikhal St 7, 3436212, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Inflammopharmacology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112626</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0925-4692</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glucocorticoids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypothalamic&#x2013;pituitary&#x2013;adrenal (HPA) axis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post COVID</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39361178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10787-024-01576-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10787-024-01576-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arbel R, Sagy YW, Hoshen M, Battat E, Lavie G, Sergienko R, Friger M, Waxman JG, Dagan N, Balicer R, Ben-Shlomo Y, Peretz A (2022) Nirmatrelvir use and severe Covid-19 outcomes during the Omicron Surge. N Engl J Med 387:790&#x2013;798. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2204919</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2204919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36001529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azzolini E, Levi R, Sarti R, Pozzi C, Mollura M, Mantovani A, Rescigno M (2022) Association between BNT162b2 vaccination and long COVID after infections not requiring hospitalization in health care workers. JAMA 328(7):676</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.11691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35796131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9250078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beiner E, Lucas V, Reichert J, Buhai DV, Jesinghaus M, Vock S, Drusko A, Baumeister D, Eich W, Friederich HC, Tesarz E, Beiner J, Lucas V, Reichert J, Buhai DV, Jesinghaus M, Vock S, Drusko A, Baumeister D, Eich W, Friederich HC, Tesarz J (2023) Stress biomarkers in individuals with fibromyalgia syndrome: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Pain 164(7):1416&#x2013;1427</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000002857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36728497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellastella G, Cirillo P, Carbone C, Scappaticcio L, Maio A, Botta G, Tomasuolo M, Longo M, Pontillo A, Bellastella A, Esposito K, De Bellis A (2022) Neuroimmunoendocrinology of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Biomedicines 2:1&#x2013;11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchman LA (2001) Side effects of corticosteroid therapy. J Clin Gastroenterol 33(4):289&#x2013;294</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00004836-200110000-00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11588541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ (2023) Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol 21(3):133&#x2013;146. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2 . (Epub 2023 Jan 13)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9839201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Den Eede V, Filip GM, Van Houdenhove B, Cosyns P, Claes SJ (2007) Hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis function in chronic fatigue syndrome. Neuropsychobiology 55(2):112&#x2013;120. https://doi.org/10.1159/000104468</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000104468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17596739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estiri H, Strasser ZH, Brat GA, Semenov YR, The Consortium, Covid- Ehr, Patel CJ, Murphy SN (2021) Evolving phenotypes of non-hospitalized patients that indicate Long COVID. BMC Med 19(249):1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannibal KE, Bishop MD (2014) Chronic stress, cortisol dysfunction, and pain: a psychoneuroendocrine rationale for stress management in pain rehabilitation. Phys Ther 94(12):1816&#x2013;1825</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20130597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25035267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4263906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenna HA, Poon AW, de los Angeles CP, Koran LM (2011) Psychiatric complications of treatment with corticosteroids: review with case report. Psychiatry Clin Neurosci 65(6):549&#x2013;560. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1440-1819.2011.02260.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1819.2011.02260.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22003987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liaquat H, Shupp B, Rollins S, Schneider Y, Matin A (2021) Comparison of the impact of chronic corticosteroid therapy on critical care outcomes of COVID-19 patients with and without history of chronic liver disease. Sci Rep 11(1):1&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-98778-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-98778-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maamar M, Artime A, Pariente E, Fierro P, Ruiz Y, Guti&#xe9;rrez S, Tobalina M, D&#xed;az-Salazar S, Ramos C, Olmos JM, Hern&#xe1;ndez JL (2022) Post-COVID-19 syndrome, low-grade inflammation and inflammatory markers: a cross-sectional study. Curr Med Res Opin 38(6):901&#x2013;909. https://doi.org/10.1080/03007995.2022.2042991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03007995.2022.2042991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35166141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackay A (2021) A paradigm for post-Covid-19 fatigue syndrome analogous to ME/CFS. Front Neurol 12(August):1&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2021.701419</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2021.701419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie R, O&#x2019;Fallon A, Dale J, Demitrack M, Sharma G, Deloria M, Garcia-Borreguero D, Blackwelder W, Straus SE (1998) Low-dose hydrocortisone for treatment of chronic fatigue syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. JAMA. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.280.12.1061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.280.12.1061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9757853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namazi N (2022) The effectiveness of dexamethasone as a combination therapy for COVID-19. Acta Pharm 13(72(3)):345&#x2013;358. https://doi.org/10.2478/acph-2022-0030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/acph-2022-0030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV (2022) A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9 . (Epub 2021 Dec 21)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Murthy S, Diaz JV et al (2020) Association between administration of systemic corticosteroids and mortality among critically Ill patients with COVID-19: a meta-analysis. J Am Med Assoc 324(13):13. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.17023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.17023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, Myles P, Williams T, Gokhale KM, Taverner T, Chandan JS, Brown K, Simms-Williams N, Shah AD, Singh M, Kidy F, Okoth K, Hotham R, Bashir N, Cockburn N, Lee SI, Turner GM, Gkoutos GV, Aiyegbusi OL, McMullan C, Denniston AK, Sapey E, Lord JM, Wraith DC, Leggett E, Iles C, Marshall T, Price MJ, Marwaha S, Davies EH, Jackson LJ, Matthews J, Camaradou KL, Calvert M, Haroon SSubramanian A, Nirantharakumar K, Hughes S, Myles P, Williams T, Gokhale KM, Taverner T, Chandan JS, Brown K, Simms-Williams N, Shah AD, Singh M, Kidy F, Okoth K, Hotham R, Bashir N, Cockburn N, Lee SI, Turner GM, Gkoutos GV, Aiyegbusi OL, McMullan C, Denniston AK, Sapey E, Lord JM, Wraith DC, Leggett E, Iles C, Marshall T, Price MJ, Marwaha S, Davies EH, Jackson LJ, Matthews J, Camaradou KL, Calvert M, Haroon S (2022) Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat Med 28(8):1706&#x2013;1714. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-01909-w . (Epub 2022 Jul 25)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01909-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9388369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, Pujol JC, Klaser K, Antonelli M, Canas LS, Molteni E, Marc Modat M, Cardoso J, May A, Ganesh S, Davies R, Nguyen LH, Drew DA, Astley CM, Joshi AD, Merino J, Tsereteli N, Fall T, Gomez MF, Duncan EL, Menni C, Williams FMK, Franks PW, Chan AT, Wolf J, Ourselin S, Spector T, Steves CJ (2021) Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med 27(4):626&#x2013;631. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01292-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7611399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Dercon Q, Luciano S, Geddes JRJR, Husain M, Harrison PJPJ (2021) Incidence, Co-Occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: a 6-Month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med 2021(18):E1003773. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1003773</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1003773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas N, Gurvich C, Huang K, Gooley PR, Armstrong CW (2022) The underlying sex differences in neuroendocrine adaptations relevant to myalgic encephalomyelitis chronic fatigue syndrome. Front Neuroendocrinol 66(November 2021):100995. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yfrne.2022.100995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yfrne.2022.100995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35421511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsigos C, Chrousos GP (2002) Hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis, neuroendocrine factors and stress. J Psychosom Res 53(4):865&#x2013;871. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-3999(02)00429-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-3999(02)00429-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12377295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utrero-Rico A, Ruiz-Ruig&#xf3;mez M, Laguna-Goya R, Arrieta-Ortubay E, Chivite-Lacaba M, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Cuadrado C, Lalueza A, Almendro-Vazquez P, Serrano A, Aguado JM, Lumbreras C, Paz-Artal E (2021) A short corticosteroid course reduces symptoms and immunological alterations underlying long-COVID. Biomedicines 9(11):1&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines9111540</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines9111540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waljee AK, Rogers MA, Lin P, Singal AG, Stein JD, Marks RM, Ayanian JZ, Nallamothu BK (2017) Short term use of oral corticosteroids and related harms among adults in the united states: population based cohort study. BMJ 12:357. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe A, Iwagami M, Yasuhara J, Takagi H, Kuno T (2023) Protective effect of COVID-19 vaccination against long COVID syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Vaccine 41(11):1783&#x2013;1790. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vaccine.2023.02.008 . (Epub 2023 Feb 8)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2023.02.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36774332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9905096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wensveen F, &#x160;estan M, Turk Wensveen T, Poli&#x107; B (2019) &#x2018;Beauty and the Beast&#x2019; in infection: how immune-endocrine interactions regulate systemic metabolism in the context of infection. Eur J Immunol 49:982&#x2013;995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eji.201847895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31106860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wulf Hanson S, Abbafati C, Aerts JG, Al-Aly Z, Ashbaugh C, Ballouz T, Blyuss O, Bobkova P, Bonsel G, Borzakova S, Buonsenso D, Butnaru D, Carter A, Chu H, De Rose C, Diab MM, Ekbom E, El Tantawi M, Fomin V, Frithiof R, Gamirova A, Glybochko PV, Haagsma JA, Vos T (2022) Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA 328(16):16</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>