<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36987476</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of SARS-CoV-2/COVID-19 on Provision of Medical Care to Patients With Systemic Autoimmune Rheumatic Disease and the Practice of Rheumatology.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e35402</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e35402</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e35402</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.35402</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The SARS-CoV-2 pandemic has had a significant impact on the healthcare field&#xa0;that resulted in changes to the way safe and effective medical care is delivered. The effects range from service disruption including ambulatory clinic closure due to both patient and provider concerns, to lack of capacity in hospital services. In rheumatology, there were other effects including viral infection-related autoantibody production, concerns about the use of systemic immunosuppression in the presence of an infectious&#xa0;pandemic and even concerns for viral infection-induced flares of rheumatic disease. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) led to the rapid adoption of innovative technologies that permitted the introduction and increased use of telemedicine via a number of platforms. Rapid discoveries and innovations led to the development of diagnostic and therapeutic agents in the management of COVID-19. Scientific advancement and discoveries around COVID-19 infection, symptoms, autoantibody production, chronic sequela and the repurposing of rheumatic immunosuppressive agents led to improved survival and an expanded role for the rheumatologist. Rheumatologists may sometimes be involved in the diagnosis and management of the hospitalized COVID-19 patient. In the ambulatory clinic, a rheumatologist also helps to differentiate between symptoms of long COVID and those of systemic autoimmune rheumatic disease (SARD). Rheumatologists must also grapple with the concerns related to immunosuppressive therapy and the risk of COVID-19 infections. In addition, there are concerns around vaccine effectiveness in people with SARD and those on immunosuppressive medications. Although the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic and the effects on healthcare resulted in difficulties, both patients and providers have risen to the challenge. The long-term outcome of COVID-19 for the medical system and rheumatologists in particular is not yet fully understood and will need further study. This review concentrates on the changing role of the rheumatologists, improved understanding of rheumatic disease and immunosuppressive therapies in the wake of the pandemic and how this has led to an improvement in the care of patients with COVID-19.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023, Bankole et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bankole</LastName><ForeName>Adegbenga A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology, Virginia Tech Carilion School of Medicine, Roanoke, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nwaonu</LastName><ForeName>Jane</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Virginia Tech Carilion School of Medicine, Roanoke, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saeed</LastName><ForeName>Jahanzeb</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Carilion Clinic, Roanoke, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoantibody</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmune rheumatic disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid long haul syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covid-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cytokine strom</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health policy and economics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunosuppressive therapies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myalgic encephalomyeritis/chronic fatigue syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telemedicine (tm)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccine science and policy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36987476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10040147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.35402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Coronavirus disease (COVID-19). Weekly Epidemiological Updates and Monthly Operational Updates.  [
Sep;
2022 
]. 2022. https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/situation-reports https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/situation-reports</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interrupting COVID-19 transmission by implementing enhanced traffic control bundling: implications for global prevention and control efforts. Yen MY, Schwartz J, Chen SY, King CC, Yang GY, Hsueh PR. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2020;53:377&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32205090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19: transmission, prevention, and potential therapeutic opportunities. Lotfi M, Hamblin MR, Rezaei N. Clin Chim Acta. 2020;508:254&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7256510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32474009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International travel to and from the United States.  [
Sep;
2022 
]. 2022. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/travelers/international-travel-during-covid19.html https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/travelers/international-travel-during-covid19.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID data tracker. US Department of Health and Human Services, CDC. 2023. https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/ https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reduced emergency department utilization during the early phase of the COVID-19 pandemic: viral fear or lockdown effect? Barten DG, Latten GH, van Osch FH. Disaster Med Public Health Prep. 2022;16:36&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7503047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32782063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delay or avoidance of medical care because of COVID-19-related concerns &#x2014; United States, June 2020. Czeisler M&#xc9;, Marynak K, Clarke KE, et al. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69:1250&#x2013;1257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7499838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32915166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covid-19 &#x2014; implications for the health care system. Blumenthal D, Fowler EJ, Abrams M, Collins SR. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:1483&#x2013;1488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32706956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of COVID-19 outbreak in an Italian cohort of patients with systemic sclerosis. Del Papa N, Sambataro G, Minniti A, et al. Ther Adv Musculoskelet Dis. 2020;12:1759720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7522815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33029203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on outpatient providers in the United States. Chatterji P, Li Y. Med Care. 2021;59:58&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33136711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trends in outpatient care delivery and telemedicine during the COVID-19 pandemic in the US. Patel SY, Mehrotra A, Huskamp HA, Uscher-Pines L, Ganguli I, Barnett ML. JAMA Intern Med. 2021;181:388&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7670397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33196765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early impact of CMS expansion of Medicare telehealth during COVID-19. Verma S. Health Affairs. 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telemedicine in the era of COVID-19. Portnoy J, Waller M, Elliott T. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2020;8:1489&#x2013;1491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7104202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32220575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of COVID-19 on vulnerable patients with rheumatic disease: results of a worldwide survey. Mehta B, Jannat-Khah D, Fontana MA, et al. RMD Open. 2020;6:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7722380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33011680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The natural history, pathobiology, and clinical manifestations of SARS-CoV-2 infections. Machhi J, Herskovitz J, Senan AM, et al. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2020;15:359&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7373339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32696264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, et al. J R Soc Med. 2021;114:428&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>New-onset IgG autoantibodies in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Chang SE, Feng A, Meng W, et al. Nat Commun. 2021;12:5417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34521836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 and autoimmune diseases. Liu Y, Sawalha AH, Lu Q. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2021;33:155&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7880581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33332890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE NICE. Vol. 18. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence; 2020. COVID-19 Rapid Guideline: Managing the Long-Term Effects of COVID-19. NICE Guideline, No. 188; p. 33555768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The neurological manifestations of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Moghimi N, Di Napoli M, Biller J, et al. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2021;21:44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8237541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34181102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et al. eClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Problems in defining post-exertional malaise. Jason LA, Evans M, So S, Scott J, Brown A. J Prev Interv Community. 2015;43:20&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4295644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25584525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS)&#x2014;a systemic review and comparison of clinical presentation and symptomatology. Wong TL, Weitzer DJ. Medicina (Kaunas) 2021;57:418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8145228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33925784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: rheumatologic/musculoskeletal symptoms in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors at 3 and 6&#xa0;months. Karaarslan F, G&#xfc;neri FD, Karde&#x15f; S. Clin Rheumatol. 2022;41:289&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8553494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34713356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Complexities in the relationship between infection and autoimmunity. Root-Bernstein R, Fairweather D. Curr Allergy Asthma Rep. 2014;14:407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3926441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24352912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covid-19 and autoimmunity. Ehrenfeld M, Tincani A, Andreoli L, et al. Autoimmun Rev. 2020;19:102597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7289100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32535093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The intersection of COVID-19 and autoimmunity. Knight JS, Caricchio R, Casanova JL, et al. J Clin Invest. 2021;131:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34710063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathogenesis and prevention of rheumatic disease: focus on preclinical RA and SLE. Deane KD, El-Gabalawy H. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2014;10:212&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4090326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24514912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A flare of systemic lupus erythematosus disease after COVID-19 infection: a case of lupus cerebritis. Khalid MZ, Rogers S, Fatima A, Dawe M, Singh R. Cureus. 2021;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8325872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34350072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rheumatological complications of Covid 19. Zacharias H, Dubey S, Koduri G, D'Cruz D. Autoimmun Rev. 2021;20:102883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8256657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34237419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 and immunological dysregulation: can autoantibodies be useful? Pascolini S, Vannini A, Deleonardi G, et al. Clin Transl Sci. 2021;14:502&#x2013;508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32989903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anti-cardiolipin IgG autoantibodies associate with circulating extracellular DNA in severe COVID-19. Bertin D, Brodovitch A, Lopez A, et al. Sci Rep. 2022;12:12523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9305055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35869087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical and autoimmune characteristics of severe and critical cases of COVID-19. Zhou Y, Han T, Chen J, et al. Clin Transl Sci. 2020;13:1077&#x2013;1086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32315487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>New onset of autoimmune diseases following COVID-19 diagnosis. Gracia-Ramos AE, Martin-Nares E, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Molina G. Cells. 2021;10:3592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8700122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34944099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Presence of antiphospholipid antibodies in COVID-19: a case series study. Amezcua-Guerra LM, Rojas-Velasco G, Brianza-Padilla M, et al. Ann Rheum Dis. 2021;80:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Establishing the prevalence of common tissue-specific autoantibodies following severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2&#xa0;infection. Richter AG, Shields AM, Karim A, et al. Clin Exp Immunol. 2021;205:99&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34082475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autoantibodies neutralizing type I IFNs are present in ~4% of uninfected individuals over 70 years old and account for ~20% of COVID-19 deaths. Bastard P, Gervais A, Le Voyer T, et al. Sci Immunol. 2021;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8521484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34413139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High prevalence of antinuclear antibodies and lupus anticoagulant in patients hospitalized for SARS-CoV2 pneumonia. Gazzaruso C, Carlo Stella N, Mariani G, Nai C, Coppola A, Naldani D, Gallotti P. Clin Rheumatol. 2020;39:2095&#x2013;2097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7251560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32462425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unique autoantibody prevalence in long-term recovered SARS-CoV-2-infected individuals. Lingel H, Meltendorf S, Billing U, et al. J Autoimmun. 2021;122:102682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8214939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34214763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Red cell-bound antibodies and transfusion requirements in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Berzuini A, Bianco C, Paccapelo C, et al. Blood. 2020;136:766&#x2013;768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7414594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32559762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 infection as a trigger of autoimmune response. Sacchi MC, Tamiazzo S, Stobbione P, et al. Clin Transl Sci. 2021;14:898&#x2013;907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8212749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antineutrophil cytoplasmic antibodies and their association with clinical outcomes in hospitalized COVID-19 patients. Kadkhoda K, Laurita K. Cell Death Discov. 2021;7:277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8491172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>How COVID-19 induces cytokine storm with high mortality. Hojyo S, Uchida M, Tanaka K, Hasebe R, Tanaka Y, Murakami M, Hirano T. Inflamm Regen. 2020;40:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7527296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33014208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawasaki-like disease: emerging complication during the COVID-19 pandemic. Viner RM, Whittaker E. Lancet. 2020;395:1741&#x2013;1743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7220168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32410759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coagulopathy and antiphospholipid antibodies in patients with Covid-19. Zhang Y, Xiao M, Zhang S, et al. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7161262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32268022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telerheumatology: a systematic review. McDougall JA, Ferucci ED, Glover J, Fraenkel L. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2017;69:1546&#x2013;1557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5436947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27863164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opportunities and barriers of telemedicine in rheumatology: a participatory, mixed-methods study. Muehlensiepen F, Knitza J, Marquardt W, et al. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:13127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8701397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34948737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telemedicine in rheumatology at the advent of the COVID-19 pandemic. Gkrouzman E, Wu DD, Jethwa H, Abraham S. HSS J. 2020;16:108&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33041724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A review of patient satisfaction and experience with telemedicine: a virtual solution during and beyond COVID-19 pandemic. Nanda M, Sharma R. Telemed J E Health. 2021;27:1325&#x2013;1331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33719577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telemedicine in rheumatology: a reliable approach beyond the pandemic. Cavagna L, Zanframundo G, Codullo V, Pisu MG, Caporali R, Montecucco C. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2021;60:366&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7499691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32893293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rheumatology patient satisfaction with telemedicine during the COVID-19 pandemic in the United States. Mortezavi M, Lokineni S, Garg M, Chen YL, Ramsey A. J Patient Exp. 2021;8:23743735211008825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8205414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34179440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19: Understanding risk. Information for specific groups.  [
Sep;
2022 
]. 2022. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/need-extra-precautions/index.html https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/need-extra-precautions/index.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relapse is almost universal after withdrawal of immunosuppressive medication in patients with autoimmune hepatitis in remission. van Gerven NM, Verwer BJ, Witte BI, et al. J Hepatol. 2013;58:141&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22989569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characteristics associated with hospitalisation for COVID-19 in people with rheumatic disease: data from the COVID-19 Global Rheumatology Alliance physician-reported registry. Gianfrancesco M, Hyrich KL, Al-Adely S, et al. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79:859&#x2013;866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7299648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32471903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Immunosuppression as a risk factor for COVID-19: a meta-analysis. Tassone D, Thompson A, Connell W, et al. Intern Med J. 2021;51:199&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33631862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 in patients with rheumatic diseases in northern Italy: a single-centre observational and case-control study. Fredi M, Cavazzana I, Moschetti L, Andreoli L, Franceschini F. Lancet Rheumatol. 2020;2:0&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7302769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The shifting landscape of lupus nephritis management: a review. Bankole AA, Nwaonu JN. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8815326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35154930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High levels of immunosuppression are related to unfavourable outcomes in hospitalised patients with rheumatic diseases and COVID-19: first results of ReumaCoV Brasil registry. Marques CD, Kakehasi AM, Pinheiro MM, et al. RMD Open. 2021;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7844930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33510041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rethinking high-risk groups in COVID-19. Vishnevetsky A, Levy M. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2020;42:102139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7175875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32388461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antecedent immunosuppressive therapy for immune-mediated inflammatory diseases in the setting of a COVID-19 outbreak. Veenstra J, Buechler CR, Robinson G, et al. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2020;83:1696&#x2013;1703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32735965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk of COVID-19 infection in patients with rheumatic disease taking disease-modifying anti-rheumatic drugs. Yousefghahari B, Navari S, Sadeghi M, et al. Clin Rheumatol. 2021;40:4309&#x2013;4315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8164488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34052904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Experiences of patients with rheumatic diseases in the United States during early days of the COVID-19 pandemic. Michaud K, Wipfler K, Shaw Y, et al. ACR Open Rheumatol. 2020;2:335&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32311836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SARS-CoV-2 infection in patients with autoimmune rheumatic diseases in northeast Italy: a cross-sectional study on 916 patients. Zen M, Fuzzi E, Astorri D, et al. J Autoimmun. 2020;112:102502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32527675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The rheumatologist's role in the battle against COVID-19: insights from the front line and challenges for the future. Koutsianas C, Chatzidionysiou K. Mediterr J Rheumatol. 2020;31:247&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7656125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33196000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therapeutic options for the 2019 novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV) Li G, De Clercq E. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2020;19:149&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32127666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therapeutic advances in COVID-19. Murakami N, Hayden R, Hills T, et al. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2023;19:38&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9574806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36253508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chloroquine is a potent inhibitor of SARS coronavirus infection and spread. Vincent MJ, Bergeron E, Benjannet S, et al. Virol J. 2005;2:69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1232869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16115318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stokkermans TJ, Goyal A, Trichonas G. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; 2022. Chloroquine and hydroxychloroquine toxicity.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30725771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Repurposed antiviral drugs for Covid-19 &#x2014; interim WHO Solidarity Trial results. Pan H, Peto R, Henao-Restrepo AM, et al. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:497&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33264556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of chloroquine or hydroxychloroquine in COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Kashour Z, Riaz M, Garbati MA, et al. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2021;76:30&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cytokine storm in COVID-19-immunopathological mechanisms, clinical considerations, and therapeutic approaches: the REPROGRAM Consortium position paper. Bhaskar S, Sinha A, Banach M, et al. Front Immunol. 2020;11:1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7365905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32754159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The efficacy, safety and cost-effectiveness of hydroxychloroquine, sulfasalazine, methotrexate triple therapy in preventing relapse among patients with rheumatoid arthritis achieving clinical remission or low disease activity: the study protocol of a randomized controlled clinical trial (ESCoRT study) Zhao J, Zhou W, Wu Y, Ji P, Yang L, Yan X, Zhang Z. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2021;21:83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7934358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33663487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Circulating levels of interleukin-6 and interleukin-10, but not tumor necrosis factor-alpha, as potential biomarkers of severity and mortality for COVID-19: systematic review with meta-analysis. Udomsinprasert W, Jittikoon J, Sangroongruangsri S, Chaikledkaew U. J Clin Immunol. 2021;41:11&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7602765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33128665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interleukin-6 is a biomarker for the development of fatal severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 pneumonia. Santa Cruz A, Mendes-Frias A, Oliveira AI, et al. Front Immunol. 2021;12:613422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7930905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33679753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elevated interleukin-6 is associated with severity of COVID-19: a meta-analysis. Zhu J, Pang J, Ji P, Zhong Z, Li H, Li B, Zhang J. J Med Virol. 2021;93:35&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7283812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32470146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tocilizumab in patients hospitalized with Covid-19 pneumonia. Salama C, Han J, Yau L, et al. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:20&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7781101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33332779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effective treatment of severe COVID-19 patients with tocilizumab. Xu X, Han M, Li T, et al. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2020;117:10970&#x2013;10975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32350134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of single tocilizumab administration in an 88-year-old patient with severe COVID-19 and a mini literature review. Ould Ouali C, Ladjouzi N, Tamas K, et al. Geriatrics (Basel) 2022;7:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8872498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35200527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tocilizumab in hospitalized patients with severe Covid-19 pneumonia. Rosas IO, Br&#xe4;u N, Waters M, et al. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:1503&#x2013;1516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7953459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33631066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inflammasome signaling and regulation of interleukin-1 family cytokines. Chan AH, Schroder K. J Exp Med. 2020;217:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7037238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31611248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inhibition of interleukin-1&#x3b2; and reduction in atherothrombotic cardiovascular events in the CANTOS trial. Everett BM, MacFadyen JG, Thuren T, Libby P, Glynn RJ, Ridker PM. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76:1660&#x2013;1670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33004131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blocking IL-1 to prevent respiratory failure in COVID-19. van de Veerdonk FL, Netea MG. Crit Care. 2020;24:445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7411343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32682440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross-talk between IL-1 and IL-6 signaling pathways in rheumatoid arthritis synovial fibroblasts. Deon D, Ahmed S, Tai K, et al. J Immunol. 2001;167:5395&#x2013;5403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11673558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corticosteroids in the treatment of severe sepsis and septic shock in adults: a systematic review. Annane D, Bellissant E, Bollaert PE, et al. JAMA. 2009;301:2362&#x2013;2375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19509383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of high versus low dose of dexamethasone on clinical worsening in patients hospitalised with moderate or severe COVID-19 pneumonia: an open-label, randomised clinical trial. Taboada M, Rodr&#xed;guez N, Varela PM, et al. Eur Respir J. 2022;60:2102518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8678498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34916266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association between administration of systemic corticosteroids and mortality among critically ill patients with COVID-19: a meta-analysis. Sterne JA, Murthy S, Diaz JV, et al. JAMA. 2020;324:1330&#x2013;1341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7489434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32876694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tocilizumab plus dexamethasone versus dexamethasone in patients with moderate-to-severe COVID-19 pneumonia: a randomised clinical trial from the CORIMUNO-19 study group. Hermine O, Mariette X, Porcher R, et al. eClinicalMedicine. 2022;46:101362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8949640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35350097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The JAK/STAT signaling pathway: from bench to clinic. Hu X, Li J, Fu M, Zhao X, Wang W. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6:402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8617206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34824210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Janus kinase 1/2 inhibitor ruxolitinib in COVID-19 with severe systemic hyperinflammation. La Ros&#xe9;e F, Bremer HC, Gehrke I, et al. Leukemia. 2020;34:1805&#x2013;1815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7282206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32518419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>JAK inhibition as a new treatment strategy for patients with COVID-19. Seif F, Aazami H, Khoshmirsafa M, Kamali M, Mohsenzadegan M, Pornour M, Mansouri D. Int Arch Allergy Immunol. 2020;181:467&#x2013;475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32392562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of Janus kinase inhibitors on risk of cardiovascular events in patients with rheumatoid arthritis: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Xie W, Huang Y, Xiao S, Sun X, Fan Y, Zhang Z. Ann Rheum Dis. 2019;78:1048&#x2013;1054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31088790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term use of immunosuppressive medicines and in-hospital COVID-19 outcomes: a retrospective cohort study using data from the National COVID Cohort Collaborative. Andersen KM, Bates BA, Rashidi ES, et al. Lancet Rheumatol. 2022;4:0&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8592562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34806036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Increased risk for severe COVID-19 in patients with inflammatory rheumatic diseases treated with rituximab. Schulze-Koops H, Krueger K, Vallbracht I, Hasseli R, Skapenko A. Ann Rheum Dis. 2021;80:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32591357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rituximab impairs B cell response but not T cell response to COVID-19 vaccine in autoimmune diseases. Bitoun S, Henry J, Desjardins D, et al. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2022;74:927&#x2013;933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9011892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34962357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The use of COVID-19 vaccines in patients with SLE. Tang W, Gartshteyn Y, Ricker E, Inzerillo S, Murray S, Khalili L, Askanase A. Curr Rheumatol Rep. 2021;23:79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8586600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34767100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaccine effectiveness against SARS-CoV-2 infection and severe outcomes among individuals with immune-mediated inflammatory diseases tested between March 1 and Nov 22, 2021, in Ontario, Canada: a population-based analysis. Widdifield J, Kwong JC, Chen S, et al. Lancet Rheumatol. 2022;4:0&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9009845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35441151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humoral responses after second and third SARS-CoV-2 vaccination in patients with immune-mediated inflammatory disorders on immunosuppressants: a cohort study. Wieske L, van Dam KP, Steenhuis M, et al. Lancet Rheumatol. 2022;4:0&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8930018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35317410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>