<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39382470</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0971-5916</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>159</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Indian journal of medical research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Indian J Med Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID syndrome: An unfolding enigma.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>585</StartPage><EndPage>600</EndPage><MedlinePgn>585-600</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.25259/IJMR_1449_23</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10.25259/IJMR_1449_23</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Post-acute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) disease (COVID-19), called as long COVID syndrome, is a major global public health issue after recovery from COVID-19. The disease occurs in symptomatic patients irrespective of illness severity. The symptoms continue after four wk of recovery from acute illness and persist beyond three months. Risk factors for long COVID include older age, female gender, multiple co-morbidities including diabetes mellitus, prior chronic respiratory illnesses, hospitalized patients with severe disease, especially receiving assisted ventilation, high viral load, reactivation of Epstein Barr (EB) virus and human herpes virus 6 (HH6), circulating auto antibodies against various organs and type I interferon. The prevalence varies from 10 to 20 per cent, and most data have been reported from high-income countries. Any system can get involved in long COVID. The symptoms include fatigue, cognition impairment, cough and dyspnoea, anosmia, hair loss and diarrhoea, among others. While there are no laboratory tests for confirmation of diagnosis, reduced complement C7 complexes at six months, and a two-gene biomarker including FYN and SARS-CoV-2 antisense ribonucleic acid (RNA) are emerging as potentially useful biomarkers for long COVID. There should be no alternative disease to explain various symptoms. Vaccination against SARS-CoV-2 and early use of oral antiviral nirmatrelvir within the first five days in patients with acute mild disease having various risk factors for progression to severe disease help in preventing long COVID. Several clinical trials are underway for the treatment of long COVID and the results of these are eagerly awaited. Physical and mental rehabilitation at home, at community level or in the hospital setting as appropriate is essential in patients with long COVID.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Surendra Kumar</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine, Jamia Hamdard Institute of Molecular Medicine, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohan</LastName><ForeName>Alladi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Sri Venkateswara Institute of Medical Sciences, Tirupati, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Upadhyay</LastName><ForeName>Vishwanath</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine, Jamia Hamdard Institute of Molecular Medicine, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Indian J Med Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0374701</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0971-5916</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute sequelae of severe acute respiratory syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevalence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39382470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11463850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25259/IJMR_1449_23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.25259/IJMR_1449_23</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahmed H, Patel K, Greenwood DC, Halpin S, Lewthwaite P, Salawu A, et al. Long-term clinical outcomes in survivors of severe acute respiratory syndrome and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus outbreaks after hospitalisation or ICU admission: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Rehabil Med. 2020;52:jrm00063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32449782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patient Led Research  Report: What does COVID-19 recovery actually look like?  Available from:  https://patientresearchcovid19.com/research/report-1/, accessed on November 16, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou R, Herman E, Ahmed A, Anderson J, Selph S, Dana T, et al. Long COVID definitions and models of care : a scoping review. Ann Intern Med. 2024;177:929&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38768458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan NA, Johnson L. Defining long COVID: Going back to the start. Med. 2021;2:501&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7992371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33786465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM. Chronic COVID syndrome: Need for an appropriate medical terminology for long-COVID and COVID long-haulers. J Med Virol. 2021;93:2555&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33095459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins V, Sohaei D, Diamandis EP, Prassas I. COVID-19: From an acute to chronic disease? Potential long-term health consequences. Crit Rev Clin Lab Sci. 2021;58:297&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33347790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A&#x2019;Court C, Buxton M, Husain L. Management of post-acute COVID-19 in primary care. BMJ. 2020;370:m3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  Post COVID-19 condition (Long COVID)  Available from:  https://www.who.int/europe/news-room/fact-sheets/item/post-covid-19-condition, accessed on January 29, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control (CDC) and Prevention  Post-COVID conditions: Information for healthcare providers.  Available from:  https://archive.cdc.gov/#/details?url=https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-conditions.html, accessed on August 10, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health  COVID-19 research. What is Long COVID?  Available from:  https://public4.pagefreezer.com/browse/NIH%20COVID-19%20Research/18-07-2024T11:42/https://covid19.nih.gov/covid-19-topics/long-covid, accessed on January 29, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Directorate General of Health Sciences. Ministry of Health and Family Welfare, Government of India  National comprehensive guidelines for management of post-COVID respiratory sequelae.  Available from:  https://www.mohfw.gov.in/pdf/NationalComprehensive
GuidelinesforManagementofPostCovidSequelae.pdf, accessed on January 29, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, Shi X, Fritsche LG, Mukherjee B. Global prevalence of post COVID-19 condition or long COVID: A meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis. 2022;226:1593&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballering AV, van Zon SKR, Olde Hartman TC, Rosmalen JGM. Lifelines Corona Research Initiative Persistence of somatic symptoms after COVID-19 in the Netherlands: an observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022;400:452&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9352274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35934007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics  Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK: 1 April 2021.  Available from:  https://www.ons.gov.uk/
peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditions anddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowing coronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/1april2021, accessed July 22, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Choi T, Al-Aly Z. Post acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection in the pre-delta, delta, and omicron eras. N Engl J Med. 2024;391:515&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39018527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, Madhavan MV, McGroder C, Stevens JS, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27:601&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong AC, Devason AS, Umana IC, Cox TO, Dohnalov&#xe1; L, Litichevskiy L, et al. Serotonin reduction in post-acute sequelae of viral infection. Cell. 2023;186:4851&#x2013;4867.e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11227373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37848036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli M, Pujol JC, Spector TD, Ourselin S, Steves CJ. Risk of long COVID associated with delta versus omicron variants of SARS-CoV-2. Lancet. 2022;399:2263&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35717982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deeks SG. Early clues regarding the pathogenesis of long-COVID. Trends Immunol. 2022;43:268&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8901423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35272932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkataramani V, Winkler F. Cognitive deficits in long Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2022;387:1813&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36351274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Li X, Gu X, Zhang H, Ren L, Guo L, et al. Health outcomes in people 2 years after surviving hospitalisation with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10:863&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9094732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35568052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng F, Dai C, Cai P, Wang J, Xu L, Li J, et al. A comparison study of SARS-CoV-2 IgG antibody between male and female COVID-19 patients: A possible reason underlying different outcome between sex. J Med Virol. 2020;92:2050&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32383183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F, Tomasoni D, Falcinella C, Barbanotti D, Castoldi R, Mul&#xe8; G, et al. Female gender is associated with long COVID syndrome: A prospective cohort study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2022;28:611.e9&#x2013;611.e16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampasian V, Elghazaly H, Chattopadhyay R, Debski M, Naing TKP, Garg P, et al. Risk factors associated with post-COVID-19 condition: A systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Intern Med. 2023;183:566&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10037203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Sivan M, Perlowski A, Nikolich J&#x17d;. Long COVID: a clinical update. Lancet. 2024;404:707&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39096925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S, Martin EM, Reuken PA, Scholcz A, Ganse-Dumrath A, Srowig A, et al. Long COVID is associated with severe cognitive slowing: a multicentre cross-sectional study. EClinicalMedicine. 2024;68:102434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10839583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38318123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scaramuzzo G, Ronzoni L, Campo G, Priani P, Arena C, La Rosa R, et al. Long-term dyspnea, regional ventilation distribution and peripheral lung function in COVID-19 survivors: a 1&#x2005;year follow up study. BMC Pulm Med. 2022;22:408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9643983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36352423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamberini L, Mazzoli CA, Prediletto I, Sintonen H, Scaramuzzo G, Allegri D, et al. Health-related quality of life profiles, trajectories, persistent symptoms and pulmonary function one year after ICU discharge in invasively ventilated COVID-19 patients, a prospective follow-up study. Respir Med. 2021;189:106665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8531241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34717097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng B, Daines L, Han Q, Hurst JR, Pfeffer P, Shankar-Hari M, et al. Prevalence, risk factors and treatments for post-COVID-19 breathlessness: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur Respir Rev. 2022;31:220071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9724798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36323418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Casta&#xf1;eda A, Lu P, Geraghty AC, Song E, Lee MH, Wood J, et al. Mild respiratory COVID can cause multi-lineage neural cell and myelin dysregulation. Cell. 2022;185:2452&#x2013;2468.e16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9189143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35768006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Wang F, Shen Y, Zhang X, Cen Y, Wang B, et al. Symptoms and health outcomes among survivors of COVID-19 infection 1 year after discharge from hospitals in Wuhan, China. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2127403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34586367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Yang C, An X, Xiong Y, Shang Y, He J, et al. Follow-up study on COVID-19 survivors one year after discharge from hospital. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;112:173&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8434916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34520845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, Wang Q, Ren L, Wang Y, et al. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: A longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398:747&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoucri SM, Purpura L, DeLaurentis C, Adan MA, Theodore DA, Irace AL, et al. Characterising the long-term clinical outcomes of 1190 hospitalised patients with COVID-19 in New York City: a retrospective case series. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e049488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8182750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34083350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathyamurthy P, Madhavan S, Pandurangan V. Prevalence, pattern and functional outcome of post COVID-19 syndrome in older adults. Cureus. 2021;13:e17189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8369971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34422503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darcis G, Bouquegneau A, Maes N, Thys M, Henket M, Labye F, et al. Long-term clinical follow-up of patients suffering from moderate-to-severe COVID-19 infection: A monocentric prospective observational cohort study. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;109:209&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8278829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter RS, Nieters A, Kr&#xe4;usslich HG, Brockmann SO, G&#xf6;pel S, Kindle G, et al. Post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 six to 12 months after infection: population based study. BMJ. 2022;379:e071050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9557001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36229057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastie CE, Lowe DJ, McAuley A, Winter AJ, Mills NL, Black C, et al. Outcomes among confirmed cases and a matched comparison group in the Long-COVID in Scotland study. Nat Commun. 2022;13:5663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9556711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36224173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastie CE, Lowe DJ, McAuley A, Winter AJ, Mills NL, Black C, et al. Author correction: Outcomes among confirmed cases and a matched comparison group in the long-COVID in Scotland study. Nat Commun. 2022;13:6540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9626587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36319644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deuel JW, Lauria E, Lovey T, Zweifel S, Meier MI, Z&#xfc;st R, et al. Persistence, prevalence, and polymorphism of sequelae after COVID-19 in unvaccinated, young adults of the Swiss Armed Forces: a longitudinal, cohort study (LoCoMo) Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:1694&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9411260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36030795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe5;hlberg M, Reistam U, Fedorowski A, Villacorta H, Horiuchi Y, Bax J, et al. Post-COVID-19 tachycardia syndrome: A distinct phenotype of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Am J Med. 2021;134:1451&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8356730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34390682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottlieb M, Wang RC, Yu H, Spatz ES, Montoy JCC, Rodriguez RM, et al. Severe fatigue and persistent symptoms at 3 months following severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infections during the pre-delta, delta, and omicron time periods: A multicenter prospective cohort study. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76:1930&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10249989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36705268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arjun MC, Singh AK, Roy P, Ravichandran M, Mandal S, Pal D, et al. Long COVID following Omicron wave in Eastern India &#x2013; A retrospective cohort study. J Med Virol. 2023;95:e28214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9874641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36224705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav AK, Mukherjee G, Vasisht K, Bobdey S. Long COVID among moderate to severe COVID-19 cases in India during second wave of COVID-19. Asia Pac J Public Health. 2022;34:846&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9483130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36114710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel N, Goyal N, Spalgais S, Mrigpuri P, Varma-Basil M, Khanna M, et al. Initial COVID-19 Severity and long-COVID manifestations: An observational analysis. Thorac Res Pract. 2023;24:22&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10765190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37503595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain A, Gupta P, Mittal AA, Sengar NS, Chaurasia R, Banoria N, et al. Long-term quality of life and work ability among severe COVID-19 survivors: A multicenter study. Dialogues Health. 2023;2:100124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10010834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36968307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair CV, Moni M, Edathadathil F, A A, Prasanna P, Pushpa Raghavan R, et al. Incidence and characterization of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized COVID-19 survivors to recognize syndemic connotations in India: Single-center prospective observational cohort study. JMIR Form Res. 2023;7:e40028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10131721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36920842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair P, Nair CV, Kulirankal KG, Corley EM, Edathadathil F, Gutjahr G, et al. Characterization and predictive risk scoring of long COVID in a south Indian cohort after breakthrough COVID infection; a prospective single centre study. BMC Infect Dis. 2023;23:670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10563355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37814234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik S, Haldar SN, Soneja M, Mundadan NG, Garg P, Mittal A, et al. Post COVID-19 sequelae: A prospective observational study from Northern India. Drug Discov Ther. 2021;15:254&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34719599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarte KI, Catahay JA, Velasco JV, Pastrana A, Ver AT, Pangilinan FC, et al. Impact of COVID-19 vaccination on the risk of developing long-COVID and on existing long-COVID symptoms: A systematic review. E Clinical Medicine. 2022;53:101624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9417563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36051247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xe8;nech-Montoliu S, Puig-Barber&#xe0; J, Badenes-Marques G, Gil-Fortu&#xf1;o M, Orrico-S&#xe1;nchez A, Pac-Sa MR, et al. Long COVID prevalence and the impact of the third SARS-CoV-2 vaccine dose: A cross-sectional analysis from the third follow-up of the Borriana Cohort, Valencia, Spain (2020-2022) Vaccines (Basel) 2023;11:1590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10611325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37896992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Bowe B, Xie Y. Long COVID after breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat Med. 2022;28:1461&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9307472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35614233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: Putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond) 2021;53:737&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baillie K, Davies HE, Keat SBK, Ladell K, Miners KL, Jones SA, et al. Complement dysregulation is a prevalent and therapeutically amenable feature of long COVID. Med. 2024;5:239&#x2013;253.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38359836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia-Hasler C, Br&#xfc;ningk SC, Hoch T, Fan B, Muzio G, Thompson RC, et al. Persistent complement dysregulation with signs of thromboinflammation in active long covid. Science. 2024;383:eadg7942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38236961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menezes SM, Jamoulle M, Carletto MP, Moens LP, Meyts I, Maes P, et al. Blood transcriptomic analyses reveal persistent SARS-CoV-2 RNA and candidate biomarkers in post-COVID conditions. Lancet Microbe. 2024;5:100849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38677304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Boon GJAM, Barco S, Endres M, Geelhoed JJM, Knauss S, et al. The Post-COVID-19 Functional Status Scale: A tool to measure functional status over time after COVID-19. Eur Respir J. 2020;56:2001494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudroff T. The challenges of post-COVID-19 fatigue research. Front Psychol. 2023;14:1120928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10083308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37051605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladds E, Rushforth A, Wieringa S, Taylor S, Rayner C, Husain L, et al. Developing services for long COVID: lessons from a study of wounded healers. Clin Med (Lond) 2021;21:59&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33479069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. NICE guideline  COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19.  Available from:  https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/NG188, accessed on January 29, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chee YJ, Fan BE, Young BE, Dalan R, Lye DC. Clinical trials on the pharmacological treatment of long COVID: A systematic review. J Med Virol. 2023;95:e28289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9878018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36349400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonilla H, Peluso MJ, Rodgers K, Aberg JA, Patterson TF, Tamburro R, et al. Therapeutic trials for long COVID-19: A call to action from the interventions taskforce of the RECOVER initiative. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1129459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10034329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36969241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z, Gao W, Bao H, Feng H, Mei S, Chen P, et al. VV116 versus nirmatrelvir-ritonavir for oral treatment of Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2023;388:406&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9812289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36577095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Kelly B, Vidal L, McHugh T, Woo J, Avramovic G, Lambert JS. Safety and efficacy of low dose naltrexone in a long covid cohort: An interventional pre-post study. Brain Behav Immun Health. 2022;24:100485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9250701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35814187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudha TYS, Sasanka KSBSK, Thangaraju P, Kuotsu R, William AG. Identification of spectrum of persistent post-COVID-19 symptoms and their duration in Central India: A pilot study. J Family Med Prim Care. 2022;11:7850&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10040991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36994011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentilotti E, G&#xf3;rska A, Tami A, Gusinow R, Mirandola M, Rodr&#xed;guez Ba&#xf1;o J, et al. Clinical phenotypes and quality of life to define post-COVID-19 syndrome: A cluster analysis of the multinational, prospective ORCHESTRA cohort. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;62:102107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10466236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37654668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Notarte KI, Macasaet R, Velasco JV, Catahay JA, Ver AT, et al. Persistence of post-COVID symptoms in the general population two years after SARS-CoV-2 infection: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Infect. 2024;88:77&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38101521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>