<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33948596</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2692-8205</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>bioRxiv : the preprint server for biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>bioRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>SARS-COV-2 induced Diarrhea is inflammatory, Ca <sup>2+</sup> Dependent and involves activation of calcium activated Cl channels.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2021.04.27.441695</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1101/2021.04.27.441695</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diarrhea occurs in 2-50% of cases of COVID-19 (&#x223c;8% is average across series). The diarrhea does not appear to account for the disease mortality and its contribution to the morbidity has not been defined, even though it is a component of Long Covid or post-infectious aspects of the disease. Even less is known about the pathophysiologic mechanism of the diarrhea. To begin to understand the pathophysiology of COVID-19 diarrhea, we exposed human enteroid monolayers obtained from five healthy subjects and made from duodenum, jejunum, and proximal colon to live SARS-CoV-2 and virus like particles (VLPs) made from exosomes expressing SARS-CoV-2 structural proteins (Spike, Nucleocapsid, Membrane and Envelope). Results: 1) Live virus was exposed apically for 90 min, then washed out and studied 2 and 5 days later. SARS-Cov-2 was taken up by enteroids and live virus was present in lysates and in the apical&gt;&gt;basolateral media of polarized enteroids 48 h after exposure. This is the first demonstration of basolateral appearance of live virus after apical exposure. High vRNA concentration was detected in cell lysates and in the apical and basolateral media up to 5 days after exposure. 2) Two days after viral exposure, cytokine measurements of media showed significantly increased levels of IL-6, IL-8 and MCP-1. 3) Two days after viral exposure, mRNA levels of ACE2, NHE3 and DRA were reduced but there was no change in mRNA of CFTR. NHE3 protein was also decreased. 4) Live viral studies were mimicked by some studies with VLP exposure for 48 h. VLPs with Spike-D614G bound to the enteroid apical surface and was taken up; this resulted in decreased mRNA levels of ACE2, NHE3, DRA and CFTR. 4) VLP effects were determined on active anion secretion measured with the Ussing chamber/voltage clamp technique. S-D614G acutely exposed to apical surface of human ileal enteroids did not alter the short-circuit current (Isc). However, VLPS-D614G exposure to enteroids that were pretreated for &#x223c;24 h with IL-6 plus IL-8 induced a concentration dependent increase in Isc indicating stimulated anion secretion, that was delayed in onset by &#x223c;8 min. The anion secretion was inhibited by apical exposure to a specific calcium activated Cl channel (CaCC) inhibitor (AO1) but not by a specific CFTR inhibitor (BP027); was inhibited by basolateral exposure to the K channel inhibit clortimazole; and was prevented by pretreatment with the calcium buffer BAPTA-AM. 5) The calcium dependence of the VLP-induced increase in Isc was studied in Caco-2/BBe cells stably expressing the genetically encoded Ca2+ sensor GCaMP6s. 24 h pretreatment with IL-6/IL-8 did not alter intracellular Ca2+. However, in IL-6/IL-8 pretreated cells, VLP S-D614G caused appearance of Ca <sup>2+</sup> waves and an overall increase in intracellular Ca <sup>2+</sup> with a delay of &#x223c;10 min after VLP addition. We conclude that the diarrhea of COVID-19 appears to an example of a calcium dependent inflammatory diarrhea that involves both acutely stimulated Ca2+ dependent anion secretion (stimulated Isc) that involves CaCC and likely inhibition of neutral NaCl absorption (decreased NHE3 protein and mRNA and decreased DRA mRNA).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donowitz</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tse</LastName><ForeName>Chung-Ming</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dokladny</LastName><ForeName>Karol</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rawat</LastName><ForeName>Manmeet</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horwitz</LastName><ForeName>Ivy</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Chunyan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kell</LastName><ForeName>Alison</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Ruxian</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Sun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Chenxu</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsai</LastName><ForeName>Shang Jui</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cox</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gould</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>In</LastName><ForeName>Julie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bradfute</LastName><ForeName>Steven</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zachos</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas C</ForeName><Initials>NC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kovbasnjuk</LastName><ForeName>Olga</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>bioRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101680187</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2692-8205</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33948596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8095203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.04.27.441695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2021.04.27.441695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>