<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38572864</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>96</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Two- and 3-year outcomes in convalescent individuals with COVID-19: A prospective cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e29566</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e29566</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.29566</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As the long-term consequences of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) have not been defined, it is necessary to explore persistent symptoms, long-term respiratory impairment, and impact on quality of life over time in COVID-19 survivors. In this prospective cohort study, convalescent individuals diagnosed with COVID-19 were followed-up 2 and 3 years after discharge from hospital. Participants completed an in-person interview to assess persistent symptoms and underwent blood tests, pulmonary function tests, chest high-resolution computed tomography, and the 6-min walking test. There were 762 patients at the 2-year follow-up and 613 patients at the 3-year follow-up. The mean age was 60 years and 415 (54.5%) were men. At 3 years, 39.80% of the participants had at least one symptom; most frequently, fatigue, difficulty sleeping, joint pain, shortness of breath, muscle aches, and cough. The participants experienced different degrees of pulmonary function impairment, with decreased carbon monoxide diffusion capacity being the main feature; results remained relatively stable over the 2-3 years. Multiple logistic regression analysis demonstrated that female sex and smoking were independently associated with impaired diffusion capacity. A subgroup analysis based on disease severity was performed, indicating that there was no difference in other parameters of lung function except forced vital capacity at 3-year follow-up. Persistent radiographic abnormalities, most commonly fibrotic-like changes, were observed at both timepoints. At 3 years, patients had a significantly improved Mental Component Score compared with that at 2 years, with a lower percentage with anxiety. Our study indicated that symptoms and pulmonary abnormalities persisted in COVID-19 survivors at 3 years. Further studies are warranted to explore the long-term effects of COVID-19 and develop appropriate rehabilitation strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors. Journal of Medical Virology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Huqin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, Beijing Institute of Respiratory Medicine and Beijing Chao-Yang Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guan</LastName><ForeName>Lujia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, Beijing Institute of Respiratory Medicine and Beijing Chao-Yang Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Tingyu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Research Center, Beijing Institute of Respiratory Medicine and Beijing Chao-Yang Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Haomiao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, Beijing Institute of Respiratory Medicine and Beijing Chao-Yang Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xuefeng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9922-9627</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Pathology, Urology, and Radiation Oncology, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xuyan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, Beijing Institute of Respiratory Medicine and Beijing Chao-Yang Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jieqiong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, Beijing Institute of Respiratory Medicine and Beijing Chao-Yang Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Research Center, Beijing Institute of Respiratory Medicine and Beijing Chao-Yang Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tong</LastName><ForeName>Zhaohui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5341-6857</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, Beijing Institute of Respiratory Medicine and Beijing Chao-Yang Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2021YFC0863600</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Science and Technology of the People's Republic of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023YFC0872500</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Science and Technology of the People's Republic of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022-1-1061</GrantID><Agency>Capital's Funds for Health Improvement and Research</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82200007</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Ggyfz202329</GrantID><Agency>Reform and Development Program of Beijing Institute of Respiratory Medicine</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018771" MajorTopicYN="N">Arthralgia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID&#x2010;19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long&#x2010;term outcomes</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38572864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.29566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>WHO. Coronavirus disease (COVID&#x2010;19) dashboard; 2023. https://covid19.who.int Accessed June 6, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh SJ, Baldwin MM, Daynes E, et al. Respiratory sequelae of COVID&#x2010;19: pulmonary and extrapulmonary origins, and approaches to clinical care and rehabilitation. Lancet Respir Med. 2023;11(8):709&#x2010;725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballouz T, Menges D, Anagnostopoulos A, et al. Recovery and symptom trajectories up to two years after SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection: population&#x2010;based, longitudinal cohort study. BMJ. 2023;381:e074425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahlgren C, Forsberg G, Divanoglou A, et al. Two&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up of patients with post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 condition in Sweden: a prospective cohort study. Lancet Regional Health &#x2010; Europe. 2023;28:100595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosa RG, Cavalcanti AB, Azevedo LCP, et al. Association between acute disease severity and one&#x2010;year quality of life among post&#x2010;hospitalisation COVID&#x2010;19 patients: coalition VII prospective cohort study. Intensive Care Med. 2023;49(2):166&#x2010;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley SE, Karlson EW, et al. Development of a definition of postacute sequelae of SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection. JAMA. 2023;329(22):1934&#x2010;1946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2010;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi B, Sudry T, Flaks&#x2010;Manov N, et al. Long covid outcomes at one year after mild SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection: nationwide cohort study. BMJ. 2023;380:e072529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jassat W, Reyes LF, Munblit D, et al. Long COVID in low&#x2010;income and middle&#x2010;income countries: the hidden public health crisis. The Lancet. 2023;402(10408):1115&#x2010;1117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastie CE, Lowe DJ, McAuley A, et al. Natural history of long&#x2010;COVID in a nationwide, population cohort study. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):3504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Li X, Gu X, et al. Health outcomes in people 2 years after surviving hospitalisation with COVID&#x2010;19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Respir&#xa0;Med. 2022;10(9):863&#x2010;876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Shi L, Jiang Z, et al. The phenotype and prediction of long&#x2010;term physical, mental and cognitive COVID&#x2010;19 sequelae 20 months after recovery, a community&#x2010;based cohort study in China. Mol Psychiatry. 2023;28(4):1793&#x2010;1801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bello&#x2010;Chavolla OY, Ferm&#xed;n&#x2010;Mart&#xed;nez CA, Ram&#xed;rez&#x2010;Garc&#xed;a D, et al. Prevalence and determinants of post&#x2010;acute sequelae after SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 infection (Long COVID) among adults in Mexico during 2022: a retrospective analysis of nationally representative data. Lancet Regional Health &#x2010; Americas. 2024;30:100688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart I, Jacob J, George PM, et al. Residual lung abnormalities after COVID&#x2010;19 hospitalization: interim analysis of the UKILD Post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 study. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2023;207(6):693&#x2010;703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Chen L, Guo L, et al. Long&#x2010;term radiological and pulmonary function abnormalities at 3&#x2010;year post COVID&#x2010;19 hospitalization: a longitudinal cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2024;22:2301612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlemmer F, Valentin S, Boyer L, et al. Respiratory recovery trajectories after severe&#x2010;to&#x2010;critical COVID&#x2010;19: a 1&#x2010;year prospective multicentre study. Eur Respir J. 2023;61(4):2201532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beigel JH, Tomashek KM, Dodd LE, et al. Remdesivir for the treatment of Covid&#x2010;19&#x2010;final report. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(19):1813&#x2010;1826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansell DM, Bankier AA, MacMahon H, McLoud TC, M&#xfc;ller NL, Remy J. Fleischner society: glossary of terms for thoracic imaging. Radiology. 2008;246(3):697&#x2010;722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revel MP, Parkar AP, Prosch H, et al. COVID&#x2010;19 patients and the radiology department&#x2014;advice from the European Society of Radiology (ESR) and the European Society of Thoracic Imaging (ESTI). Eur Radiol. 2020;30(9):4903&#x2010;4909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chommeloux J, Valentin S, Winiszewski H, et al. One&#x2010;year mental and physical health assessment in survivors after extracorporeal membrane oxygenation for COVID&#x2010;19&#x2010;related Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2023;207(2):150&#x2010;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enright PL, Sherrill DL. Reference equations for the six&#x2010;minute walk in healthy adults. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1998;158(5 Pt 1):1384&#x2010;1387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bestall JC, Paul EA, Garrod R, Garnham R, Jones PW, Wedzicha JA. Usefulness of the Medical Research Council (MRC) dyspnoea scale as a measure of disability in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Thorax. 1999;54(7):581&#x2010;586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigmond AS, Snaith RP. The hospital anxiety and depression scale. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 1983;67(6):361&#x2010;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng N, Zhao YM, Yan W, et al. A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of long&#x2010;term physical and mental sequelae of COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic: call for research priority and action. Mol Psychiatry. 2023;28(1):423&#x2010;433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorent N, Vande Weygaerde Y, Claeys E, et al. Prospective longitudinal evaluation of hospitalised COVID&#x2010;19 survivors 3 and 12 months after discharge. ERJ Open Res. 2022;8(2):00004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamp JC, Werlein C, Plucinski EKJ, et al. Novel insight into pulmonary fibrosis and long COVID. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2023;207(8):1105&#x2010;1107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cazzoletti L, Zanolin ME, Dorelli G, et al. Six&#x2010;minute walk distance in healthy subjects: reference standards from a general population sample. Respir Res. 2022;23(1):83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferte JB, Boyer FC, Taiar R, et al. Impact of resistance training on the 6&#x2010;minute walk test in individuals with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2022;65(3):101582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberst G, Claud&#xe9; F, Laurent L, et al. Result of one&#x2010;year, prospective follow&#x2010;up of intensive care unit survivors after SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 pneumonia. Ann Intensive Care. 2022;12(1):23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Liu X, Zhou Y, et al. 3&#x2010;month, 6&#x2010;month, 9&#x2010;month, and 12&#x2010;month respiratory outcomes in patients following COVID&#x2010;19&#x2010;related hospitalisation: a prospective study. The Lancet Respir&#xa0;Med. 2021;9(7):747&#x2010;754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Liu J, Peng P, et al. Dynamic changes of pulmonary diffusion capacity in survivors of non&#x2010;critical COVID&#x2010;19 during the first six months. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;43:101255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frija&#x2010;Masson J, Debray MP, Gilbert M, et al. Functional characteristics of patients with SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 pneumonia at 30 days post&#x2010;infection. Eur Respir J. 2020;56(2):2001754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo X, Jian W, Su Z, et al. Abnormal pulmonary function in COVID&#x2010;19 patients at time of hospital discharge. Eur Respir J. 2020;55(6):2001217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Li X, Huang L, et al. Lung&#x2010;function trajectories in COVID&#x2010;19 survivors after discharge: a two&#x2010;year longitudinal cohort study. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;54:101668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngai JC, Ko FW, Ng SS, To KW, Tong M, Hui DS. The long&#x2010;term impact of severe acute respiratory syndrome on pulmonary function, exercise capacity and health status. Respirology. 2010;15(3):543&#x2010;550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie L, Liu Y, Fan B, et al. Dynamic changes of serum SARS&#x2010;coronavirus IgG, pulmonary function and radiography in patients recovering from SARS after hospital discharge. Respir Res. 2005;6(1):5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, et al. 1&#x2010;year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID&#x2010;19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398(10302):747&#x2010;758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post&#x2010;COVID&#x2010;19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis. 2021;53(10):737&#x2010;754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, et al. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6(9):e005427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Anna SE, Asnaghi R, Caramori G, et al. High&#x2010;resolution computed tomography quantitation of emphysema is correlated with selected lung function values in stable COPD. Respiration. 2012;83(5):383&#x2010;390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laniado&#x2010;Laborin R. Smoking and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). parallel epidemics of the 21 century. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2009;6(1):209&#x2010;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe A, So M, Iwagami M, et al. One&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up CT findings in COVID&#x2010;19 patients: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Respirology. 2022;27(8):605&#x2010;616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsakok MT, Watson RA, Saujani SJ, et al. Reduction in chest CT severity and improved hospital outcomes in SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2 omicron compared with delta variant infection. Radiology. 2023;306(1):261&#x2010;269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon SH, Lee JH, Kim BN. Chest CT findings in hospitalized patients with SARS&#x2010;CoV&#x2010;2: delta versus omicron variants. Radiology. 2023;306(1):252&#x2010;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Li J, Liu H, et al. Long&#x2010;term bone and lung consequences associated with hospital&#x2010;acquired severe acute respiratory syndrome: a 15&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up from a prospective cohort study. Bone Res. 2020;8:8.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>