<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">33634830</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1651-2081</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of rehabilitation medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Rehabil Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of neuromuscular electrical stimulation on the recovery of people with COVID-19 admitted to the intensive care unit: A narrative review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>jrm00164</StartPage><MedlinePgn>jrm00164</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2764</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2340/16501977-2805</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rehabilitation of patients with COVID-19 after prolonged treatment in the intensive care unit is often complex and challenging. Patients may develop a myriad of long-term multiorgan impairments, affecting the respiratory, cardiac, neurological, digestive and musculoskeletal systems. Skeletal muscle dysfunction of respiratory and limb muscles, commonly referred to as intensive care unit acquired weakness, occurs in approximately 40% of all patients admitted to intensive care. The impact on mobility and return to activities of daily living is severe. Furthermore, many patients experience ongoing symptoms of fatigue, weakness and shortness of breath, in what is being described as "long COVID". Neuromuscular electrical stimulation is a technique in which small electrical impulses are applied to skeletal muscle to cause contractions when voluntary muscle contraction is difficult or impossible. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation can prevent muscle atrophy, improve muscle strength and function, maintain blood flow and reduce oedema. This review examines the evidence, current guidelines, and proposed benefits of using neuromuscular electrical stimulation with patients admitted to the intensive care unit. Practical recommendations for using electrical muscle stimulation in patients with COVID-19 are provided, and suggestions for further research are proposed. Evidence suggests NMES may play a role in the weaning of patients from ventilators and can be continued in the post-acute and longer-term phases of recovery. As such, NMES may be a suitable treatment modality to implement within rehabilitation pathways for COVID-19, with consideration of the practical and safety issues highlighted within this review.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burgess</LastName><ForeName>Louise C</ForeName><Initials>LC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedic Research Institute, Bournemouth University, BH8 8EB Bournemouth, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Venugopalan</LastName><ForeName>Lalitha</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Badger</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Street</LastName><ForeName>Tamsyn</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alon</LastName><ForeName>Gad</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jarvis</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wainwright</LastName><ForeName>Thomas W</ForeName><Initials>TW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Everington</LastName><ForeName>Tamara</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swain</LastName><ForeName>Ian D</ForeName><Initials>ID</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Sweden</Country><MedlineTA>J Rehabil Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088169</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1650-1977</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002986" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004599" MajorTopicYN="N">Electric Stimulation Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006760" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitalization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007362" MajorTopicYN="N">Intensive Care Units</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronavirus infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">critical care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscular atrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular electrical stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<i>The authors have no conflicts on interest to declare.</i>
</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33634830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8814855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/16501977-2805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zaim S, Chong JH, Sankaranarayanan V, Harky A. COVID-19 and multiorgan response. Curr Probl Cardiol 2020; 45: 100618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32439197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahase E. Covid-19: What do we know about &#x201c;long covid&#x201d;? BMJ 2020; 370: m2815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32665317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intensive Care National Audit and Research Centre . ICNARC report on COVID-19 in critical care. 2020. 
Jul
17. Available from: https://www.icnarc.org/Our-Audit/Audits/Cmp/Reports.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Faculty of Intensive Care Medicine . Clinical guide for the management of critical care for adults with COVID-19 during the coronavirus pandemic; 2020. 
Sep
11. Available from: https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5e6613a1dc75b87df82b78e1/t/5f999cd5b3df86542e85d0ab/1603902680560/AdultCriticalCare-COVID-19-October2020.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation (2020) . Clinical Management of COVID-19: interim guidenace, 2020. 
May
27. Available from: https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/332196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The RECOVERY Collaborative Group, Horby P, Lim WS, Emberson JR, Mafham M, Bell JL, et al. . Dexamethasone in Hospitalized patients with covid-19 &#x2013; preliminary report. N Engl J Med 2020; 10.1056/NEJMoa2021436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2021436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32678530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carfi A, Bernabei R, Landi F, Gemelli Against C-P-ACSG. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA 2020; 10.1001/jama.2020.12603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.12603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermans G, Van Mechelen H, Clerckx B, Vanhullebusch T, Mesotten D, Wilmer A, et al. . Acute outcomes and 1-year mortality of intensive care unit-acquired weakness. A cohort study and propensity-matched analysis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2014; 190: 410&#x2013;420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24825371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan E, Dowdy DW, Colantuoni E, Mendez-Tellez PA, Sevransky JE, Shanholtz C, et al. . Physical complications in acute lung injury survivors: a two-year longitudinal prospective study. Crit Care Med 2014; 42: 849&#x2013;859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3959239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24247473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nussbaum EL, Houghton P, Anthony J, Rennie S, Shay B, Hoens AM. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation for treatment of muscle impairment: critical review and recommendations for clinical practice. Physiother Can 2017; 69: 1&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5683854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29162949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura K, Nakano H, Naraba H, Mochizuki M, Hashimoto H. Early rehabilitation with dedicated use of belt-type electrical muscle stimulation for severe COVID-19 patients. Crit Care 2020; 24: 342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7294763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32539827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Health and Care Excellence . Electrical stimulation to improve muscle strength in chronic respiratory conditions, chronic heart failure and chronic kidney disease. Interventional procedures guidance [IPG677]. 2020. Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ipg677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schepens T, Verbrugghe W, Dams K, Corthouts B, Parizel PM, Jorens PG. The course of diaphragm atrophy in ventilated patients assessed with ultrasound: a longitudinal cohort study. Critical Care (London, England) 2015; 19: 422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4671211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26639081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvan E, Arentson-Lantz E, Lamon S, Paddon-Jones D. Protecting skeletal muscle with protein and amino acid during periods of disuse. Nutrients 2016; 8: 404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4963880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27376322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Luo J, Zhou J, Zhu X. Intervention effect of neuromuscular electrical stimulation on ICU acquired weakness: a meta-analysis. Int J Nurs Sci 2020; 7: 228&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7355203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32685621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Roig M, Karatzanos E, Nanas S. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation for preventing skeletal-muscle weakness and wasting in critically ill patients: a systematic review. BMC Med 2013; 11: 137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3668245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23701811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wageck B, Nunes GS, Silva FL, Damasceno MC, de Noronha M. Application and effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation in critically ill patients: systematic review. Med Intensiva 2014; 38: 444&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25060511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke D, Gorman E, Stokes E, Lennon O. An evaluation of neuromuscular electrical stimulation in critical care using the ICF framework: a systematic review and metaanalysis. Clin Respir J 2016; 10: 407&#x2013;420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25353646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piva S, Fagoni N, Latronico N. Intensive care unit-acquired weakness: unanswered questions and targets for future research. F1000Res 2019; 8: F1000 Faculty Rev-508</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6480958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31069055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry SM, Puthucheary ZA. The impact of extended bed rest on the musculoskeletal system in the critical care environment. Extrem Physiol Med 2015; 4: 16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4600281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26457181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Routsi C, Gerovasili V, Vasileiadis I, Karatzanos E, Pitsolis T, Tripodaki, E, Markaki V, et al. . Electrical muscle stimulation prevents critical illness polyneuromyopathy: a randomized parallel intervention trial. Critical Care (London, England) 2010; 14: R74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2887197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20426834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kho ME, Truong AD, Zanni JM, Ciesla ND, Brower RG, Palmer JB, Needham D M. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation in mechanically ventilated patients: a randomized, sham-controlled pilot trial with blinded outcome assessment. J Crit Care 2015; 30: 32&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4268169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25307979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutsioumpa E, Makris D, Theochari A, Bagka D, Stathakis S, Manoulakas E, Sgantzos, Met al. . Effect of transcutaneous electrical neuromuscular stimulation on myopathy in intensive care patients. Am J Crit Care 2018; 27: 495&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30385541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite MA, Osaku EF, Albert J, Costa CRLM, Garcia AM, et al. . Effects of Neuromuscular Electrical Stimulation of the Quadriceps and Diaphragm in Critically Ill Patients: A Pilot Study. Crit Care Res Pract. 2018. Jul 8;2018:4298583. doi: 10.1155/2018/4298583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/4298583.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6079614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30123586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patsaki I, Gerovasili V, Sidiras G, Karatzanos E, Mitsiou G, Papadopoulos E, Christakou A, Routsi C, Kotanidou A, Nanas S. Effect of neuromuscular stimulation and individualized rehabilitation on muscle strength in Intensive Care Unit survivors: A randomized trial. J Crit Care 2017; 40: 76&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28364678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YH, Hsiao HF, Li LF, Chen NH, Huang CC. Effects of Electrical Muscle Stimulation in Subjects Undergoing Prolonged Mechanical Ventilation. Respir Care 2019; 64: 262&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30723168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dall&#x2019; Acqua AM, Sachetti A, Santos LJ, Lemos FA, Bianchi T, Naue WS, Dias AS, Sbruzzi G, Vieira SR; MoVe- ICU Group . Use of neuromuscular electrical stimulation to preserve the thickness of abdominal and chest muscles of critically ill patients: a randomized clinical trial. J Rehab Med 2017; 49: 40&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28101565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura K, Kihata A, Naraba H, Kanda N, Takahashi Y, Sonoo T, Hashimoto H, Morimura N. Efficacy of belt electrode skeletal muscle electrical stimulation on reducing the rate of muscle volume loss in critically ill patients: a randomized controlled trial. J Rehab Med 2019; 51: 705&#x2013;711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31544949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zampieri S, Mosole S, Lofler S, Fruhmann H, Burggraf S, Cvecka J, et al. . Physical exercise in aging: nine weeks of leg press or electrical stimulation training in 70 years old sedentary elderly people. Eur J Transl Myol 2015; 25: 237&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4748981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26913162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakanishi N, Oto J, Tsutsumi R, Yamamoto T, Ueno Y, Nakataki E, et al. . Effect of electrical muscle stimulation on upper and lower limb muscles in critically ill patients: a two-center randomized controlled trial. Crit Care Med 2020; 10.1097/CCM.0000000000004522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0000000000004522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32897665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen RC, Li XY, Guan LL, Guo BP, Wu WL, Zhou ZQ, Huo YT, Chen X, Zhou LQ. Effectiveness of neuromuscular electrical stimulation for the rehabilitation of moderate-to-severe COPD: a meta-analysis. Int J Chronic Obstr Pulm Dis 2016; 11: 2965&#x2013;2975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5135061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27932876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill K, Cavalheri V, Mathur S, Roig M, Janaudis-Ferreira T, Robles P, Dolmage TE, Goldstein R. Neuromuscular electrostimulation for adults with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2018; 5: CD010821&#x2013;CD010821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6494594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29845600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCaughey EJ, Jonkman AH, Boswell-Ruys CL, McBain RA, Bye EA, Hudson AL, Collins DW, Heunks LMA, McLachlan AJ, Gandevia SC, Butler JE. Abdominal functional electrical stimulation to assist ventilator weaning in critical illness: a double-blinded, randomised, sham-controlled pilot study. Critical Care (London, England) 2019; 23: 261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6657036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31340846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akar O, G&#xfc;nay E, Sarinc Ulasli S, Ulasli AM, Kacar E, Sariaydin M, Solak &#xd6;, Celik S, &#xdc;nl&#xfc; M. Efficacy of neuromuscular electrical stimulation in patients with COPD followed in intensive care unit. Clin Respir J 2017; 11: 743&#x2013;750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26597394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attia J, Ray JG, Cook DJ, Douketis J, Ginsberg JS, Geerts WH. Deep vein thrombosis and its prevention in critically ill adults. Arch Intern Med 2001; 161: 1268&#x2013;1279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11371254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook D, Crowther M, Meade M, Rabbat C, Griffith L, Schiff D, et al. . Deep venous thrombosis in medical-surgical critically ill patients: prevalence, incidence, and risk factors. Crit Care Med 2005; 33: 1565&#x2013;1571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16003063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook D, Attia J, Weaver B, McDonald E, Meade M, Crowther M. Venous thromboembolic disease: an observational study in medical-surgical intensive care unit patients. J Crit Care 2000; 15: 127&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11138871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minet C, Potton L, Bonadona A, Hamidfar-Roy R, Somohano CA, Lugosi M, et al. . Venous thromboembolism in the ICU: main characteristics, diagnosis and thromboprophylaxis. Crit Care 2015; 19: 287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4539929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26283414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson FA, Jr, Spencer FA. Risk factors for venous thromboembolism. Circulation 2003; 107: I9&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12814980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi G, Lee JJ, Jamil A, Gunnam V, Najafi H, Memar Montazerin S, et al. . Venous thromboembolism among hospitalized patients with COVID-19 undergoing thromboprophylaxis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Med 2020; 9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7463975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32756383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nopp S, Moik F, Jilma B, Pabinger I, Ay C. Risk of venous thromboembolism in patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Res Pract Thromb Haemost 2020; 10.1002/rth2.12439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rth2.12439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33043231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porfidia A, Valeriani E, Pola R, Porreca E, Rutjes AWS, Di Nisio M. Venous thromboembolism in patients with COVID-19: systematic review and meta-analysis. Thromb Res 2020; 196: 67&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7420982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan SS, Radford S, Kow CS, Zaidi STR. Venous thromboembolism in critically ill COVID-19 patients receiving prophylactic or therapeutic anticoagulation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Thromb Thrombolysis 2020; 50: 814&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32748122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kushner A, West WP, Pillarisetty LS. Virchow triad. StatPearls. Treasure Island, Florida, 2020. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK539697/#:~:text=The%20three%20factors%20of%20Virchow&#x2019;s,presence%20of%20a%20hypercoagulable%20state.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakkos SK, Warwick D, Nicolaides AN, Stansby GP, Tsolakis IA. Combined (mechanical and pharmacological) modalities for the prevention of venous thromboembolism in joint replacement surgery. J Bone Joint Surg Br 2012; 94: 729&#x2013;734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22628585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thachil J, Tang N, Gando S, Falanga A, Cattaneo M, Levi M, et al. . ISTH interim guidance on recognition and management of coagulopathy in COVID-19. J Thromb Haemost 2020; 18: 1023&#x2013;1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9906133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32338827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Health and Care Excellence . The geko device for reducing the risk of venous thromboembolism. 2014. 
[cited 2020 Jan 27 Jan]; Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/mtg19/chapter/1-Recommendations.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Summers JA, Clinch J, Radhakrishnan M, Healy A, McMillan V, Morris E, Rua T, Ofuya M, Wang Y, Dimmock PW, Lewis C, Peacock JL, Keevil SF. The geko&#x2122; electro-stimulation device for venous thromboembolism prophylaxis: a NICE medical technology guidance. Appl Health Econ Health Policy 2015; 13: 135&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4376951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25403719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes R, Madden LA, Chetter IC. Fibrinolytic effects of peroneal nerve stimulation in patients with lower limb vascular disease. Blood Coagul Fibrinolysis 2016; 27: 275&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26397885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jingwei L ZZ, Xuesong L, Hui J, Ning L, Wenbo W. Clinical observation of neuromuscular electrical stimulation in prevention of deep venous thrombosis after total hip replacement. Chin J Bone Joint Injury 2017; 32: 615&#x2013;616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broderick BJ, Breathnach O, Masterson E, Breen PP, GOL. Hemodynamic performance of NMES in the early post operative period following orthopaedic surgery. Conf Proc IEEE Eng Med Biol Soc 2011; 2011: 7630&#x2013;7633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22256105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broderick BJ, O&#x2019;Briain DE, Breen PP, Kearns SR, Olaighin G. A pilot evaluation of a neuromuscular electrical stimulation (NMES) based methodology for the prevention of venous stasis during bed rest. Med Eng Phys 2010; 32: 349&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20171135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker A, Maass A, Bain D, Chen LH, Azzam M, Dawson H, et al. . Augmentation of venous, arterial and microvascular blood supply in the leg by isometric neuromuscular stimulation via the peroneal nerve. Int J Angiol 2010; 19: e31&#x2013;e37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2949997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22477572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess LC, Immins T, Swain I, Wainwright, TW. Effectiveness of neuromuscular electrical stimulation for reducing oedema: a systematic review. J Rehab Med 2019; 51: 237&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30834452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainwright TW, Burgess LC, Middleton RG. A feasibility randomised controlled trial to evaluate the effectiveness of a novel neuromuscular electro-stimulation device in preventing the formation of oedema following total hip replacement surgery. Heliyon 2018; 4: e00697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6072917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30094367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badger J, Taylor P, Papworth N, Swain I. Electrical stimulation devices for the prevention of venous thromboembolism: preliminary studies of physiological efficacy and user satisfaction. J Rehabil Assist Technol Eng 2018; 5: 2055668318800218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6453094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31191954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahadori S, Immins T, Wainwright TW. The effect of calf neuromuscular electrical stimulation and intermittent pneumatic compression on thigh microcirculation. Microvasc Res 2017; 111: 37&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28077312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojima M, Takegawa R, Hirose T, Ohnishi M, Shiozaki T, Shimazu T. Hemodynamic effects of electrical muscle stimulation in the prophylaxis of deep vein thrombosis for intensive care unit patients: a randomized trial. J Intens Care 2017; 5: 9&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5237178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28101364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindstrom B, Holmdahl C, Jonsson O, Korsan-Bengtsen K, Lindberg S, Petrusson B, et al. . Prediction and prophylaxis of postoperative thromboembolism &#x2013; a comparison between peroperative calf muscle stimulation with groups of impulses and dextran 40. Br J Surg 1982; 69: 633&#x2013;637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6181844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browse NL, Negus D. Prevention of postoperative leg vein thrombosis by electrical muscle stimulation. An evaluation with 125I-labelled fibrinogen. Br Med J 1970; 3: 615&#x2013;618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1701744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5507464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainwright TW, Burgess LC, Middleton RG. A single-centre feasibility randomised controlled trial comparing the incidence of asymptomatic and symptomatic deep vein thrombosis between a neuromuscular electrostimulation device and thromboembolism deterrent stockings in post-operative patients recovering from elective total hip replacement surgery. Surg Technol Int 2020; 36: 289&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32250444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doran FS, White HM. A demonstration that the risk of postoperative deep venous thrombosis is reduced by stimulating the calf muscles electrically during the operation. Br J Surg 1967; 54: 686&#x2013;689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4952352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dejode LR, Khurshid M, Walther WW. The influence of electrical stimulation of the leg during surgical operations on the subsequent development of deep-vein thrombosis. Br J Surg 1973; 60: 31&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4685916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajibandeh S, Hajibandeh S, Antoniou GA, Scurr JR, Torella F. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation for the prevention of venous thromboembolism. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2017; 11: CD011764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6486105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29161465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajibandeh S, Hajibandeh S, Antoniou GA, Scurr JR, Torella F. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation for thromboprophylaxis: A systematic review. Phlebology 2015; 30: 589&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25567877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravikumar R, Williams KJ, Babber A, Moore, HM, Lane TRA, Shalhoub Jet al. . Neuromuscular electrical stimulation for the prevention of venous thromboembolism. Phlebology 2018; 33: 367&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28610546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sosnowski K, Mitchell ML, White H, Morrison L, Sutton J, Sharratt J, Lin F. A feasibility study of a randomised controlled trial to examine the impact of the ABCDE bundle on quality of life in ICU survivors. Pilot Feasibil Studies 2018; 4: 32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5765639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29372070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos FV, Cipriano G, Jr., Vieira L, Guntzel Chiappa AM, Cipriano GBF, Vieira P, et al. . Neuromuscular electrical stimulation combined with exercise decreases duration of mechanical ventilation in ICU patients: a randomized controlled trial. Physiother Theory Pract 2018; 10.1080/09593985.2018.1490363: 1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30321084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffell LD, Donaldson NN. A Comparison of FES and SCS for neuroplastic recovery after SCI: historical perspectives and future directions. Front Neurol 2020; 11: 607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7344227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32714270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latronico N, Bolton CF. Critical illness polyneuropathy and myopathy: a major cause of muscle weakness and paralysis. Lancet Neurol 2011; 10: 931&#x2013;941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21939902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schweickert WD, Pohlman MC, Pohlman AS, Nigos C, Pawlik AJ, Esbrook CL, et al. . Early physical and occupational therapy in mechanically ventilated, critically ill patients: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2009; 373: 1874&#x2013;1882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9906655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19446324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasotakis G, Schmidt U, Perry D, Grosse-Sundrup M, Benjamin J, Ryan C, et al. . The surgical intensive care unit optimal mobility score predicts mortality and length of stay. Crit Care Med 2012; 40: 1122&#x2013;1128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22067629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo-Ayala E, Khan BA, Farber MO, Ely EW, Boustani MA. Interventions to improve the physical function of ICU survivors: a systematic review. Chest 2013; 144: 1469&#x2013;1480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3817929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23949645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kho ME, Martin RA, Toonstra AL, Zanni JM, Mantheiy EC, Nelliot A, et al. . Feasibility and safety of in-bed cycling for physical rehabilitation in the intensive care unit. J Crit Care 2015; 30: 1419 e1411&#x2013;1415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26318234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms J, Kremer S, Merdji H, Clere-Jehl R, Schenck M, Kummerlen C, et al. . Neurologic features in severe SARSCoV-2 infection. N Engl J Med 2020; 382: 2268&#x2013;2270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7179967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32294339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munshi L, Del Sorbo L, Adhikari NKJ, Hodgson CL, Wunsch H, Meade MO, et al. . Prone position for acute respiratory distress syndrome. a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2017; 14: S280&#x2013;S288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29068269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwatsu K, Yamada S, Iida Y, Sampei H, Kobayashi K, Kainuma M, Usui A. Feasibility of neuromuscular electrical stimulation immediately after cardiovascular surgery. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2015; 96: 63&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25218214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segers J, Hermans G, Bruyninckx F, Meyfroidt G, Langer D, Gosselink R. Feasibility of neuromuscular electrical stimulation in critically ill patients. J Crit Care 2014; 29: 1082&#x2013;1088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25108833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badger J, Taylor P, Swain I. The safety of electrical stimulation in patients with pacemakers and implantable cardioverter defibrillators: a systematic review. J Rehabil Assist Technol Eng 2017; 4: 2055668317745498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6453072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31186945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal S, Chughtai M, Sultan AA, Khlopas A, Sodhi N, George NEet al. . Impact of neuromuscular electrical stimulation (NMES) on 90-day episode costs and post-acute care utilization in total knee replacement patients with disuse atrophy. Surg Technol Int 2017; 31: 384&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29316600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens-Lapsley JE, Balter JE, Wolfe P, Eckhoff DG, Schwartz RS, Schenkman M, et al. . Relationship between intensity of quadriceps muscle neuromuscular electrical stimulation and strength recovery after total knee arthroplasty. Phys Ther 2012; 92: 1187&#x2013;1196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3432951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22652985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>